song.
Heaven.
We Let's see.
>> You can do it. You can do both sides at
once here off the center.
>> Oh, we'll do both sides at once. Oh, and
then we'll go around the side. Okay.
Good morning.
>> Hi.
>> Hello, sweethearts.
Hello. Hello. Hi. Hi guys. Hi. Hi all
you people.
Look at the Santa there.
Mhm.
Thank you.
Good morning.
>> Hi. Hi.
>> Hi.
Hello.
Nice to see you.
>> Did I get everybody? You hope.
Thank you, doctor. Hi. Good
>> to see you again.
>> All these familiar faces.
>> Oh, I'm sorry.
>> Ah. Hi.
>> Hi. Hi.
>> Hi, Dr. Hkins.
>> Hello.
>> Yeah. Now, who else do we miss? Anybody?
Oh, wow. Look at all our extremely
famous familiar faces.
Oh, hi.
Hi.
>> Oh, look.
Who is your husband?
>> Dermat.
>> Is this your This is the husband.
>> Yeah, the husband.
>> Oh, okay.
Lucky man. She's a wonderful lady. She's
a wonderful lady. I knew she had a
husband. I don't know who he was, you
know.
>> Yeah. Hello, Dr. Hopkins. So good to see
you, D.
>> And Patty, God bless you.
>> Thank you.
>> Here we are from Canada.
>> Yes.
>> Here's Marian, our German translator.
>> Yes. Good morning. Good morning.
>> Cornelia, the publisher.
>> Oh, good morning.
>> Good morning. And he has a physician, a
doctor. She runs a hospital. They do
fasting.
>> And Michael Debake his wife is a
patient.
>> You do it fasting. If you do it slow
enough, it's okay.
>> This way, not this way, doc.
>> And now the best announcement and the
last announcement is that Dr. Hawkins
new book, Transcending the Levels of
Consciousness, is available and in the
bookstore. And there are a lot of copies
for all of you that haven't done all
your Christmas shopping yet. That's now
glory and excelsius deal.
Glory be to God and
on earth good will to men. Yeah.
At Christmas time that's what it means.
Peace on earth, goodwill to men, and the
rest of it is so much tinsel,
but enjoyable tinsel. Enjoyable
because we're all children at heart.
We're all children at heart. You realize
that on Christmas, open up the present.
Uh the other thing perhaps of interest
is um this coming year we we only
scheduled six uh of these all day
conferences
on the alternate month every other
Wednesday uh on Wednesday nights
on the alternate month the second
Wednesday of the month the second
Wednesday of the month on the alternate
months
uh we'll meet informally at St. Andrew's
Episcopal Church Meeting Hall
uh 6:30 to 8:30, which means it'll
probably be like 6:00 to 9:00. It is
absolutely there's absolutely no charge,
no cost involved and um we'll use the
meeting hall there
uh which will hold quite a few people.
So, it's an evening meeting for people
who work during the day. a lot of people
have moved to Sedona that to be involved
in the work and so that will be the core
group and it'll be more classic satsang
you know uh informal and we'll just
discuss
uh questions at considerable depth
perhaps so it's more or less for people
who are somewhat sophisticated about the
work it's not really a class for
beginners
uh th this group here has advanced in
consciousness There's 100 points. 100.
This group as a group started at 400 and
went up to 500. Uh that's rather
uh nice.
All right. So
we start you see the the ego eventually
discovers the mind discovers that
there's something beyond itself. That's
the 400s.
Uh the enthusiasm of the 300s you tackle
uh intellectual work and then you
discover that there's something beyond
mind and that starts the spiritual
quest.
spiritual questically
is difficult and not easy to do and um
so therefore anybody who gets involved
in spiritual work I take my head off to
them uh it's arduous
to make it less arduous is the purpose
of writing transcending the levels of
consciousness
uh to make it to facilitated
so we're having it at St. Andrews and
the director there Mary Proski is very
pleased to have us
uh and I've invited members of the the
congregation who wish to come over uh
come to the class it because classic uh
Christianity the reason I be the reason
I became an atheist uh was because of
some of the characteristics of classic
Christianity
uh you got obsessed with sin and guilt
and avoiding sin and being somewhat was
scrupulous by nature and obsessive
compulsive and uh
difficult to live with within myself.
It created an invariable tension. So
Christianity tells you it's wrong to
hate your brother-in-law for screwing
you over 30 years ago, but it doesn't
tell you really how to get off it.
So what I said to Mary is this would be
the practical how to make
uh Christianity uh you know because the
Christian church if it was a Buddhist
church we'd make Buddhism work but but
anyway
anyway how to make a spiritual ideal uh
an experiential reality an experiential
reality
experiential
um one way to look at the ego is that it
is itself a virtual reality virtual
reality that it has no intrinsic reality
But experiential
it certainly seems to be so.
So that's um the only important thing I
want to decide today.
All right.
See you next month. No no.
Oh we had good wonderful and funny
things happen. This month's National
Geographic magazine is about Buddhism.
December's issue and in it is Sedona
Tyran Auto
outreach of Buddhism and it shows them
praying in Sedona Tyran Auto. Yesterday
I was over there to get my u what we
call a drive fixed up and I said wow
that's something and they were all
excited about it you know so Sedona you
know is sort of known as a spiritual
center where else would your tyrant auto
be in national geographic for having
having a meeting of Buddhists there
and some of the people in the picture
had been to you know our classes so I
could see people who had been to classes
there they So don't attire an auto.
All right. So that's just what I wanted
to remind myself St. Andrews.
Um
all right.
Uh today's lecture goes on to
uh what is actually chapters I guess 16
and 17
in uh truth versus falsehood
uh religion and spirit religious and
spiritual truth. Huh. How many people
are here for the first time?
Okay.
All right. Now today in in order to do
uh to cover what we have to cover we
won't have much time for the to cover
the basic materials as we have in the
past. I presume that people that are
here read read uh and somewhat familiar
with it. So we will only put up three or
four slides uh just to recall the
structure out of which all of this arose
and uh I'll say a few words about
kinesiology.
Kinesiology is only affirmative. It's
like having an altimeter
uh or a barometer. It's it has a
pragmatic usefulness.
You don't need it.
anything you need to know via that
mechanism I've done and written. There's
nothing else you really need to know.
So, um
I'll just revise how it originated. I
attended a class on it and uh an
excellent teacher who wrote your body
doesn't lie and uh he was a great
teacher. So I went back to the clinic
where we had very large holistic
holistic orientation largest psychiatric
clinic
psychiatric practice in the United
States for some 25 years. So we looked
for everything that would could possibly
help a patient misdiagnosis.
So we were open to every kind of alter
alternative medicine
and we had um considering our patient
population of hopeless had already seen
everybody in the world uh recoveries
were indeed miraculous.
So I came back to the staff and
demonstrated kinesiology. We thought we
could find uh you know I can find out
whether your your psycho psychosis is
due to mercury poisoning or not. Uh, it
takes I'll tell you how long it takes to
make a diagnosis that all the world's
experts can't make. Um, he's got mercury
poisoning. Yes, he's got mercury
poisoning in the brain. So, if we keate
him out, he'll recover.
That's how long it takes.
That's how long it takes. It's very,
very simple. Okay. So, there's no point
to make a big deal out of it.
Kinesiology then is just a mechanism
that corroborates
what people once the third eye of the
Buddha body opens up all that you learn
through kinesiology is obvious you can
look at the image of somebody on
television the nightly news I can look
at his face and I'll tell you what he
calibrates right away uh you don't want
to have this guy around your house
the word killer emerges in my mind you
know and then you find out. Yes, he
killed four people. He said, and he
claims he's innocent, but the
knowingness is that he's not innocent.
So, all right. So, it's useful for
research. It's useful for corroboration.
It is not essential to enlightenment at
all.
So, if it doesn't work for you, forget
it.
We are planning to do a teaching
uh DVD on on it. It's going to be done
by uh
done by our staff here, chief of staff.
We're going to have her do that one. And
all right, so that's enough for
kinesiology. It's a very simple thing.
Uh and there are people that are experts
at it. I'm not an expert at kinesiology.
I don't know anything about it. I just
know. True or false? That's all I know.
Yes or no? That's all I know.
There are experts at it and they have
videotapes that are wondrous to behold.
I mean, there's all kinds of tricks. You
go like this and the guy goes weak and
you go like this and he goes strong and
you go like this and he goes strong
again. I mean, it's very complicated. I
am not a chiologist.
Don't claim to be. All I know is truth
and falsehood. Truth makes your arm go
strong and falsehood makes your body go
weak. And uh it has to do with brain
physiology and the fact that
uh consciousness is an infinite field.
Consciousness is an infinite field.
Uh it is a priority. A priority prior to
all that exists within the physical
domain.
Out of consciousness which is infinitely
powerful arises all of creation. Out of
the Godhead arises divinity whose
expression is the universe. Huh?
In seeing that you see that
creation and evolution are one in the
same thing that evolution is creation.
What did you think it was going to look
like?
Uh but from nothing to everything.
But everything isn't complete yet. So
everything is still in a progression. So
therefore to really see that evolution
and creation are one of the same thing
uh makes it easy. The other thing to see
right from the beginning and save
yourself many years of many lifetimes
is that everything is occurring
spontaneously as a consequence of that
which it is.
There is no external cause for anything.
Everything manifests its own
potentiality when local conditions are
favorable.
The caterpillar becomes the pupa becomes
the butterfly
etc.
Nothing is causing anything to happen at
all.
Now there's a reason I always try to
keep track of what's going on in science
too.
so that I know what I'll forget when I
go over the other side. So,
the first book I wrote was called Truth
Versus Falsehood. Truth versus
falsehood.
Uh, no, it was called Power Versus
Force, right?
The years are going by
called Power versus Force. And uh
so the statement I just made uh we said
force goes from here to there. It's
limited and it exhausts itself. It has
to be fed constant energy.
Power the effects of power are the
consequence of that which power is.
Power just stands there and does nothing
and influences everything
uh around. Huh.
quite a bit of difference.
Spiritual integrity then is power. It's
powerful
and it radiates out and things around it
change as a consequence. However,
there's a new scientific theory
which calibrated at 480.
And if I could read this guy's name,
I'll tell you who it is.
Heracapos.
H A R O K A P O S.
A new scientific theory supplanting
Newton
that
motion in the universe is not the result
of force but of power. Interesting
that the power which radiates out of the
essence of uh the universe you know
manifests.
Uh so I thought that's interesting.
say
because you don't have to become stupid
to become enlightened.
>> Thank God.
>> Now you tell me
>> you can also think and be intelligent
that there is a link. You follow
Newtonian
uh to quantum mechanics, the Heisenberg
principle. And now what did I say his
name was? Heracopulolis.
>> Heraculus.
>> He's never going to become famous if you
can't say his name. I mean Einstein was
easy. Heracopulolis
calibrates at 480. And Newton is was
Newton's theory is about 450. Newton's
um uh concept of causality is about 450
455.
>> All right. So Newtonian science is at
450 and this guy's at 480. That's worth
noticing, huh? So he's coming closer and
closer
to reality. I just thought that was
interesting that you wouldn't be able to
live the day without knowing about Mr.
Heracapos.
Another thing of interest, I keep you up
to date on what's happening is uh you
the US is not doesn't calibrate the
highest of all the countries in the
world. No, Singapore is at 440.
Singapore is the consequence of a benign
dictatorship. I discovered it. I said to
Brock, "Are all the dictators such sobs?
Isn't there a kindly dictator?
I mean, do they all have to torture
people to death and fry them and rape
them and kill them? So Brock did the
research and came up no Singapore
uh emerged out of a benign very
enlightened kind of a man and Singapore
calibrates at 440. Huh, that's
interesting. The US is at I don't know
what the US is still at.
>> No, 421. Uh, the US is still at 421.
It's at 422,
423.
United States is 440,
421,
420. Anyway, it's around there.
It'll get you in the ballpark. Yeah.
All right. So, we we mentioned that
we'll have uh uh informal meetings and
if you want the dates, they'll be on the
u on the
>> in the website.
Uh I can give them to you if you want.
An interesting thing going on in the
world. I have to get rid of this card of
things I must say
of significance is the recent meeting of
the Islamic nations, 35 of them, uh led
by King Abdul Dalah of Saudi Arabia
uh to renounce the violent extremism
that is really a negation of the basic
teaching of Islam. So I think that's why
probably one of the most hopeful things
I think I have seen in recent history
that now
u they're getting together and say no
that that kind of violence and all is a
distortion
distortion.
All right. So, we took care of all the
important things. So, don't attire an
autoacopulolis.
Okay.
So, now we'll continue as we usually do.
Yeah. The
we now are up to about 75 slides. We're
going to show about we got 10 or 12 new
ones. And eventually you're going to put
together sort of an oversized book I
think with the slides on this side and a
page of explanation on this side because
it recapitulates everything in the
easiest way. It starts off with a map of
consciousness and the evolution of
consciousness
over great periods of time. So the
calibrated scale is pragmatic, useful,
and frankly we can find out things
within an instant that that all the
governments of the world with all their
millions of dollars can't find out. In
fact, some of it was published in truth
versus falsehood. We held it back so it
was safe to say it. And there was a lot
we did not say in truth versus falsehood
that the public wouldn't be able to
handle it. But practically everything we
said there has emerged. you know the
offer food scandal all the things that
showed up on the radar a long time ago.
So it's extremely useful. Now in
translating the levels of consciousness
what we did is we took each level and
then from the psychological viewpoint
spiritual psychological spiritual
emotional viewpoint showed how to
transcend each level. So, it's a
practical uh how-to manual.
And the reason uh
yeah
all right so let's let's go on to the
next one
that's glide. Everybody's familiar with
that slide, right? Everybody understands
that slide and we go into it in detail.
This brings up interestingly another law
which I had overlooked. Uh in Italy
there was an economist
um there was an economist
um
Poretta Poretta everybody any Italian
economist Poretta back in the late 1800s
he he discovered that 80% of the land in
Italy was owned by 20% of the people and
he set up what's known as the 20 the law
of 2080
probably 80% of the stock in the United
States state is owned by 20% of the
stockholders. 80% of the power is
wielded by 20% of the people. And I just
be I just discovered that this weekend
and I thought, isn't that odd?
Is Isn't that odd? Practically the same
as we've been talking about for some
years now.
Practically the same. Yeah.
Approximately 20% of the world then uh
has has the has the power and uh this is
the 78%.
Okay. So we go to the next thing
transcending the levels of consciousness
uh was really I wrote it at uh Susan's
uh inspiration. She kept saying you need
a to explain things practically. people
were interested in the practical how to
and so at her inspiration and urging we
did it and I'm glad I did. So here you
got Petta's law approximately you know
when he says 2080 he means approximately
approximately uh
1/5
wags the tail of the four fifth. Okay.
So, we'll move on. That's just to recall
the nature of the world we live in. The
nature of the world we live in
to get off be feeling guilty about the
ego. We just I always like to recall how
it evolved.
Life appeared
when conditions were favorable. The
light of divinity when it interacted
with matter spawned the energy fuel
called life. Life only can originate
from life. Life
can only originate from life. Uhuh.
Resist.
Life can only re originate from life.
Life can only originate from life. It
cannot originate from non-life.
You never saw a dead animal get up and
start to bark. Right? Life emerges from
life.
That takes care of mechanistic
reductionism.
>> This is I gotta get you up there where
they can hear you.
>> Oh, mechanistic reductionism. Good
golly. No wonder the microphone blew
out.
Anyway, we see this is the evolution of
the ego. Uh it it was essential to life.
So when life spawned out of matter, the
energy of divinity, the energy field of
in the form of consciousness in its
interaction with manner spawned life.
In order to survive, life had to become
predacious. It had to have like
laboratory test equipment biologically
to tell what's edible, what's not
edible, what's good for life, what's
adverse to life. Kinesiology is a subtle
form of it. That which is pro-life,
supports life, makes you go strong. That
which is anti-life does not support
life. Makes you go weak.
So the first organism already discovered
this and out of that arose that aspect
of the ego we call the experiencer. The
experiencer samples everything around is
safe, not safe,
edible, non-edible. So then we see the
evolution
through great eons of time through the
whole animal kingdom and we see from the
very lowest level the bacteria is still
the very lowest we could find at one
prozzoa
and then on up through the animal
kingdom my favorite friend the octopus
the komodo dragon you just don't want to
hang out with them
you want to Be sure to put your shoes on
when you go into Kimod Dragon's cage.
Yeah. Then we come up through the whole
animal kingdom and we come up from that
which sort of survives by
um the death of others and we come up to
the benign herbivore.
This occurs at calibration level 200 in
the animal kingdom the same as it does
in the human kingdom. in the human
kingdom is the same as the animal
kingdom. Below 200 is predacious
and above 200 is is peaceful and
herbivorous.
Herbiviverous. Okay.
And then we come up to the exceptional
things up. These are the the family
dogs. We know research shows that having
a pet increases all the good aspects of
life. healthier, better heart function,
less suicide rate.
There's enormous benefits in having a
pet. Having a pet. Uh
so then we get up to the higher levels,
the monkeys, the gorillas, and then we
get up to the very high levels.
Um the African parrot. Let's see what
how's broccoli doing.
Let me see how broccoli. Broccoli is
over
Wow.
Broccoli's over 400.
Broccoli's over 385.
Broccoli's over 380.
385. Broccoli's up to 380.
>> Got a way to go yet.
I don't know. I'll be sitting at home
all alone. All of a sudden, Broccoli
gets on the phone. Hello. Hello. Glad.
Well, I'm sorry. I got to go now. Click.
Then it makes it sound like the phone's
going off.
So there's intelligence there.
Intelligence, intelligent design. The
intelligence in the design is so
obvious. You've got to be to
reject intelligent design as a basic
principle of the universe. I mean, you
really got to be dumb. Really, really
dumb to not see the intelligence.
I mean, here's a parrot talking to you
and you don't see the intelligence. I
mean then you got Coco and of course the
dog and the cat
uh represents some emanation very
similar to the human heart at 500.
Okay, we'll move on. So that covers
again the very basics. So therefore you
don't have to feel guilty about the ego.
You just have to to domest domesticate
it. It's it's important to do that
because here is the big shift in brain
function. uh that occurs at
consciousness level 200. There's no
point in faulting people uh
who um
are not integrous
because their brain simply doesn't get
it. Their brain simply doesn't get it.
Well,
the skeptic is stuck here.
can't get here because there isn't any
atheric brain.
He can't process. He doesn't see the
spiritual reality.
To anybody over 200, the fact that
there's intelligence
intrinsic to creation is so stunningly
obvious that you know it's stunningly
obvious. But to people with this kind of
a brain, it is not obvious. they are
stuck with mechanistic reductionism.
Yeah. If it's not specific, if I can't
identify it, it's not real. And you see
this because here we're dealing with
different energies. We're dealing with
etheric energies.
At consciousness level 200 is the
emergence of the atheric brain.
The atheric brain
and individual karma.
Below level 200 there's group karma and
above 200 is individual karma. Let's see
if that's correct. Affirm it. Make sure
they didn't change it while I was out
for lunch. What I just said is a fact.
Below 200 is group karma. Wow.
People below 200 are coming in here with
a group karma. Therefore, you see major
group experiences on this planet. Whole
cultures get wiped out. Volcanoes t
tornado all kinds of things. whole
groups get wiped out.
Group karma, individual karma then
is based on the aetheric energy and the
atheric body.
>> I'm sorry. Let me see if I can fix it.
>> Oh, fix that microphone. Help. Help.
Help.
>> Help. Help. Help. Help.
>> Okay, I think we're okay.
Instant karma. Okay. So
the brain physiology you see it's easier
to forgive people. Socrates said man can
only can choose the good. He he
perceives that as the good. So killing
you is what he perceives as the highest
good. He still is operating from the
highest good. So how do you forgive
people like that? You do it by realizing
this. You realize between Socrates and
this chart that takes care of the whole
resentment, forgiveness, hatred. Is that
okay? You got any hatreds left?
Resentments,
blames.
Any blamers? Let's hear blame. Blame.
Blame.
You know what's wrong with this world is
all the effing blamers out there.
They're the ones.
That's a righteous plan.
How now neatly the mind can
pull us in. Huh? All blames are terrible
except the righteous blame. All wars are
terrible except the righteous war. You
know, righteous blame, righteous
resentment. Okay. All right. So you need
this kind of apparatus to process
uh and to bypass emotion. You need an
etheric brain. See here the animal
emotion is very rapid. You got an
emotional reaction. Now that's in your
memory. How he screwed you over the so
20 years ago.
Uh now you see him differently. He only
did what he thought uh he had to do
because that's who he was at the time.
And now very fast you say so let it go
already. Live and let live.
Okay. So you become over 200 then
differentiates a major step in
evolution. Okay. Let's go to the next.
So this is sort of recapitulating for
the new people here. Uh but you can't
reinforce this often enough. The rate of
happiness is not due to anything out
there. That would be coming from cause.
No, it's coming from essence. The rate
of happiness is directly
directly aligned with your level of
consciousness and not anything else.
Not anything else.
I used to live on millionaires row and
they committed suicide and got drunk and
got divorced and killed each other the
same as everybody else.
Didn't seem to help much.
Didn't seem to help much. All right. So
happiness then is not caused by
conditions out there any more than
unhappiness is unhappiness or happiness.
So we'll move it on. We'll move on. Mhm.
Next one. Then we'll have completed
pretty much the prelims.
Oh yes. Okay. So the now we're getting
to the lecture for today.
As I say, it's covered in chapters 15,
16, last two chapters, I think, of truth
versus salt
in which
we discovered sort of a a practical
science of truth. And we began to use it
to analyze everything in history and in
the world. And then we used it to
understand theology and religion and
spirituality.
So we start out then
uh the world religions, the so-called
sons of Abraham,
um
Christianity,
Islam, Judaism, those are the three
brothers that came out of historically
out of Abraham.
Uh, of course they've been uh having
difficulties with each other ever since.
But uh
the basic idea was all right. It was
just the way it was applied. So if we
start now looking to see what
scale of truth, how do all these things
calibrate?
Because the better we understand things,
the better we can integrate them, accept
them, and also get off making things
wrong.
The first century of Christianity,
the way the first followers of the way
calibrated at 980.
The apostles all calibrated in the 900s,
the very high 900s.
The relics, the St. theater under the
in
>> St. Peters. Yeah, the relics. Anyway,
the rugs calibrate over 900. That's very
unusual, isn't it? The relics of St.
Peter under the it's under the altar in
the Basilica of St. Peters in Rome
calibrates over 900.
So the apostles calibrated 900. Now many
centuries later they discovered the the
writings of the gnostic agnostics
uh and they're at 510.
Now the interesting thing about
Christianity is prior to the council of
nya it calibrated extremely high and
after the council of na it dropped
considerably.
It dropped from
as you can see prior to the council of
nya Christianity was now was at 8:40
after the council of nya
in 325 AD it had dropped to 485 huh
rather dramatic could I just disconnect
myself from the world
let's see is this rig still going
>> y
>> all
All right. It dropped to 45. That's the
most catastrophic thing other than what
happened with Muhammad.
Uh it's almost like that which is
powerfully virtuous and truthful
pulls to it all its enemies.
It's like truth becomes such a
danger to falsehood that falsehood pulls
itself up and sneaks in the door
somehow.
You know, the Buddhist said he was beset
by demons.
And in my own spiritual evolution,
I was beset by demons and then some.
Uh it's so you know it said you pull up
pull up its opposite. You tend to pull
up its
It's the enemies of truth. Huh? Very
often the enemies of truth cleverly
conceal themselves in sheep's clothing.
Discernment, the opening of third eye is
the capacity to see the wolf under the
sheep's clothing.
So at the council of Nya then
what happened I believe is
you see the the way the Bible came about
was really uh uh there were many books
of the Bible
many of the many of the books are not in
the current Bible
they met periodically and voted on it.
It's a very extensive history. The
history of the Bible of course is very
extensive and I'm not a religious
historian so I can't give you the
details but I know what did happen is
the Old Testament got included with the
New Testament and
Revelations got included in the New
Testament
and that brought it down. Huh.
the in the New Testament
what happened was the introduction of
that particular book which calibrates at
90 or 70 or something like that brought
down the calibration level of the whole
new testament and brought down
Christianity
prior to the council of na 840 after the
council council of na 485
so that's something for religious
historians to puzzle out I myself don't
know that much about it.
Catholicism then
is Eastern Orthodox, Coptic and Roman
Catholic. Eastern Orthodox currently
calibrates about 490 which is higher
than it would the Council of Na. Coptic
is at 475
and Roman Catholicism of course has been
the dominant dominant Christianity for
many centuries. The papacy itself
calibrates at 570.
The last pope calibrated at 570. This
pope calibrates about 565 between 565
and 570 which uh is a small variation
and not particularly relevant. So we
found that 570 is ideal for the head of
a world church. The Dalai Lama also
calies at 570.
Above 570,
you can't really handle the worldly
things that have to be handled. Below
570, you don't have the power to
withstand the attack that comes to you
just by virtue of uh your office.
Uh so the papacy at 570 has withtood the
test of time. There were several popes
along the way, the notorious ones who
calibrated well below 200. Uh
you might say there were false popes,
a poor pope.
Yeah,
fake popes. The college of cardinals,
you see, is very arodited 490. 490 is
really as bad as far as the intellect
will take you. the faith and liturgy.
You see, this comes out of the
intellect, but faith and lit faith and
liturgy comes out of the heart. And
again, you're back over 500 to 535.
Faith and liturgy then is the main core
of of of the
spiritual truth. The clergy also
calibrate around 490. The Jesuit order,
the church worldwide Catholicism is
currently around 450 somewhere around
there,
which is far above 200. Far above 200.
It's had difficulties and they've
straightened out some of the
difficulties, which will probably bring
its calibrations back up higher again.
Ah
now postreformation you see
so what happened was you've got the
church uh world dominant and then there
was um
complaints complaints about
errors made ecclesiastic errors and that
started the reformation of course and
out of the postreformation then you see
many of the mo most prominent religions
in in America and around the world. You
see the Amish at 375,
bornagain Christians, Christian Science,
uh, Episcopalian. This is where we're
going to be meeting on the alternate
months,
u evangelical,
fundamentalist, Christian, LDS,
and new thought.
Those are postreformation.
You have Pentecostal Protestantism.
Protestantism is at 510. Five
Protestantism
is at 510.
The Puritans, on the other hand, seem to
be overly moralistic. They didn't quite
do quite as well.
The Quakers are very peaceful people.
making it all real in the in the
everyday world is the Salvation Army at
and Unity Church at over 500. Unity
Village itself is over 500.
And we of course have had the pleasure
of being there a number of times as
their guest and being on the advisory
council
of Unity Church's uh work on
consciousness etc. Huh. So
Christianity then is about onethird of
the world. I forget in America it's
certainly a sizable and now we see the
surfacing of course of the whole
contention about Christmas which is
pretty ridiculous. But anyway it gives
contentious people something to do and
protest about.
I mean you really hard up for something
to protest about when you got to pull up
Christmas from the bottom of the basket.
I mean, you got to pull up Santa Claus
and beat him up. You're really getting
down there, you know? All the little
children. Macy's Day Parade. I mean,
really.
Yeah. What What's our favorite Christmas
movie? The with
>> Scrooge. What's his name?
>> Scrooge.
>> Scrooge. Scrooge. Scrooge. Yeah.
Scrooge.
>> Yeah. The Scroogeites come out of the
woodwork.
Can you imagine in your deathbed, you
know, you're going to face God any
second?
The problem with life is too many people
are too far from death.
Those
of you who've had near-death experiences
know what I'm talking about. All this BS
drops away like the stupidest crap in
the world.
And there you are facing the infinite.
And when the ego goes out, you know, it
went out when I
gave up life itself and walked through
the door. It also gave up the near death
experience instead of it's very similar
when you turn off the TV at night. You
ever turn off the TV and the whole
screen just goes like that and
disappears?
Well, that's the way it is.
Everything, all your mind, everything
you ever thought, all of your history. I
mean,
what what strikes you is the fantastic
e, the pomposity of it. The pomposity of
it. The pomposity of it. Like an idiot
trying to tell the king how to run the
government. Yes.
All right. Yes, that's a good idea.
uh the idiocy of the ego.
Um
so then you learn to take it with a
grain of salt and realize it is a
virtual reality. In today's world we
have uh the downside is the media the
programming by the media is is so
staggering promotion advertising
politicalization
you know the modern man you could you
know when I grew up you could live a
whole lifetime where I where I grew up
you could live a whole lifetime and
maybe read the headlines once in a
You didn't need to know anything about
the world. And who was interested
anyway? It was harvest time. It was hay
time. It was planning time.
Who cared about that? You need to break
fix the brakes on the 29 model A Ford.
And they wanted $6. My father called
them highway robbers. $6 to replace the
brakes. I'll do it myself. He bought
them for $3 and did it himself.
In today's world, you're just at the
mercy of an input that is overwhelming.
And uh you know, people give me gadgets
sometimes and I always take out the
instructions and I have a whole a drawer
full of gadgets people have given me
with the instructions still with them.
Letter to the editor said that today's
technology has gotten so advanced that
things are becoming almost useless.
takes two to three hours to read the
instruction manual.
Well, you sort of give up. Well, I gave
up years ago. If it's if it doesn't just
go off and on, I'm not interested in it.
So,
off and on. And
Susie's pretty good at that. She can
handle a SUV. And you know, in a new in
a new car, I counted there are 100
switches from the driver's seat.
Yeah. So, you need that one for
transporting everybody back and forth.
I sat in it and I counted them. There
are 100 switches.
It does mysterious things. You're
counting the switches and all of a
sudden you see the mirrors changing
around.
The the rear view mirrors going in and
out like this. This seat is pulsating.
Your back is going like this.
vibrational things. Then a voice comes
out of the roof of the car and speaks to
you.
It's time to change your oil.
I said to Susie, "Jesus, I didn't know
you're supposed to put oil in this
thing.
Put oil in it." All right. So
that's Christianity of which we're all
familiar and the non-Christian world is
familiar as well.
Then the second great wing or we could
start with the oldest wing Judaism. We
should have started here because
historically of course it predates all
the others and the Judaism has withtood
all the ravages of time. Judaism is
really I mean for a standup religion
it's really been shot at bombed exploded
drowned stabbed and it still goes on.
Uh, hassidism is 605 extremely high.
Hassidism
is the conscious awareness of the
divinity of all that exists. The
constant reminding yourself of the
divinity of all that exists. Messianic
includes
uh the inclusion of Jesus Christ as is
also a 605
as a great prophet or as a
representative of God.
reconstructionist,
conservative. Most of the Jewish people
I've known in my life are conservative
re or reform.
Conservative or reform
and uh orthodox at 545. So you see
Judaism stands up extremely well. It has
stood up over the centuries despite
everything.
Uh and it represents a very high level
of truth. Huh? Very high level of truth.
Uh, I myself had millions of Jewish
friends back east and I even got to do
the seder. I mean, I read the service.
They gave me a yarmaka and I had a white
thing over them and I sat there and read
the whole service. It was wonderful.
Then we went to a fantastic place for
dinner,
Lower East Side, traditional Jewish
dinner. It started at 7 10:30. We were
only up to about the sixth or seventh
course.
It was great. Yeah. So, I learned to
love the people.
All right. Now, Islam is the most recent
one. And of course, it only arose
at the time of Muhammad. Muhammad um
Muhammad
stated that he got it as sort of a
dictation. from the Archangel Gabriel.
At that time, Muhammad was at 700 and
the Quran, the original Quran calibrated
at 700.
He was at age 35.
Age 35.
At age 38,
he crashed from 700 to about
185 or something. 135, I forget. He had
um temporal lobe epilepsy.
Temporal lobe epo epilepsy is peculiar.
It often has religious delusions and
various
uh problems with it. Anyway,
so Muhammad at 700 dictated the original
Quran,
a thing of great beauty and inspiration.
And this is what I said that which is
power powerfully for the good pulls its
enemy. And its enemy came at him and it
came through the temporal load epilepsy
subsequent to which he became warlock
warlike
in Islam fell dramatically.
However, the original truth is
maintained by the mystics.
The Sufism is at 700. In all religions,
the mystics are always calibrate the
highest.
Then you have today's Sunnites and
Shiites
uh at about 250.
The difficulty with Islam was the
emergence first of all of Muhammad's
great fall.
Yeah.
Oh. Yes. 130 it was. Yes. Uhhuh. He took
up the sword. The difficulty was in
mistransating the Quran. You can also do
it with the Bible. The
the spiritual sword means the sword of
truth. I came not to bring you peace but
to bring you truth. The sword of truth.
To mix up the sword of truth with the
sword of war is the problem in the
misinterpretation of the Quran. Yeah.
and
say katab
say katub and wahab are the two things
that brought it down. Wahabism emerged
300 years ago
and a misinterpretation of the Quran
and the further decline was supported by
a famous author named Sed Katab QB who
wrote a book called In the Shades of the
Quran
in which all that goes on in today's
Islamic terrorism was justified
and that eulogized
and praised death, death,
death and destruction.
So that when you see bin Laden who was a
follower of Wahabism, come on. He
calibrates at 90. I calibrated his
lecture in which he says the difference
is
you worship life and we worship death.
that calibrates at 90 to worship death.
Calibrates at 90.
All right. So that is the basic the
basic problem in today's uh world in
which Islamic terrorism
colors everything.
If you don't think it's important, just
go to the nearest airport. You got to
dig your shoes off. You got to wait in
line. They can take everything away from
you. It's totally changed our world. So
having nothing to do at all with the
basis of it, it still has changed our
world. Huh? So Islam then sufism
just as it is the mystics of of Judaism
and the mystics of Christianity, the
great saints are all the always the
mystics.
U
so here we see Wahabism.
Now Wahab himself
um calibrated at 20.
It's like the PA pulls out of the
audience a psychotic who attacks the PA
and hates that which is beautiful,
divine, and good.
Therefore, as you evolved, evolve in
your spirituality,
you eventually reach very high places.
And therefore, we'll pay attention to
that. In fact, I intend to write a
little manual about it.
What to watch for?
Because there are certain chinks that
evil comes in all the time. What is
that? That's the energy of that which
would seek to rule. Yeah. And therefore
truth is its enemy. It hates truth. It
hates anything having to do with love or
divinity etc. Yeah.
That's enough to make you paranoid.
Somebody said to me that that
realization is enough to make you
paranoid. I says it should.
Why do you suppose they have incense at
the altar?
You think it's celebration like flowers?
What do you think the incense is for?
>> Anybody know?
Huh?
>> Take away the evil spirit.
>> You got it.
>> What place would that which is anti-
good anti it would like to be best would
be right at the altar at the time of
communion wouldn't that communion
Christian community communion calibrates
760 or something. So it's at that point
that the demonic energies are pulled. So
therefore as you evolve spiritually
there are certain traps that we have to
watch for all the time. And you see
gurus fall right and left. Another one
who I knew I spent time with a number of
gurus who later went down all over the
internet. The newest one all over the
internet
money power sex
it pulls them all down. pump pump
having lots of followers, lots of money.
All right. So, Judaism then is you see
highly integrous. You see how Islam fell
because primarily because of this guy
Wahab. This guy Wahab was where the
demon got in through the cracks. Uhhuh.
And jihad is his expression.
Say Katab
was at 420
and he crashed to 75. So you see the
downside of
of Islam is extremely low and extremely
dangerous.
Calibration 90 will slowly boil you in
oil
and enjoy your screams. It does. We see
it on trial right now.
You see that energy on trial right now.
That's right. We have now is a great
teaching time and we see one of the
perpetrators of this energy field here.
This energy field here
is now on trial. And you see the
attitude towards authority. The world
has no right to judge him. The world
world has no right over you and God
doesn't exist. So what
we saw that with uh that other guy has
been on trail for 35 years. Juskovich.
Who was the guy's name?
>> Yeah.
>> Yes. They all have the same tilt of
their head.
>> Even God has no right to judge me.
They're above God.
They're greater than God. Wow.
To think you're greater than God then is
insanity. It's called It's called
malignant messianic narcissism.
Malignant messianic narcissism.
Society suffers from malignant egoistic
narcissism. All the people that are very
sensitive and we must change everything
so their little feelings don't get hurt.
Remove God from the money.
remove God from the money.
Where am I? I said, "I was going to send
you $1,000, but I didn't want to
contaminate you with all the in God we
trust on the green bills, so I didn't
close them."
Oh, yeah.
On the other hand, a person can't help
it when they're dominated. You might
say, they can't help it in pursuing the
good. So, I'm sure in Socrates eyes to
eliminate all reference to God and
Christmas
and uh Santa Claus is what that person
perceives as the highest good.
Curiously, that guy is in some trouble
because he calibrates over 200. Yeah, if
you calibrate at 190, 190,
you'd excuse him as an idiot, but no,
he's over 205 or something. So, that
means now you got responsibility.
There's helpability and then there's
accountability. They're not the same.
You can be accountable and responsible,
but not culpable.
But when you're over 200 and now you're
also culpable, that means you then have
to pay the price. Okay.
So, what's the next when do we uh I want
to keep track of the time.
>> We have about 10 minutes.
>> We have 10 minutes. All right. Now
because it covers today's world, I think
it's very pertinent pertinent. The
interaction of the sons of Abraham is
what our current world is all about,
isn't it?
>> Palestine and Israel
and
the war with al-Qaeda, etc. the impact
on all of society.
And then uh and then on top of it,
you've got the political fallout
within the secular world. You got the
political fallout of what is really a
religious war, a religious war. And you
have apologists.
It's really squeezing yourself to become
apologists for these people here, but
they're there. They live in Hollywood,
too.
Run over and embrace Saddam. Oh boy. Oh
boy. Embrace somebody who calibrates at
90. All right.
You're either a saint or a fool to do
that, right?
Well, the mind believes what it's
programmed with. And therefore to add to
Socrates dictim that we all choose only
the good, you have to realize that all
of us are programmed.
We're programmed like never before in
history. We're programmed round the
clock. You can't even watch a race a
race. What do you call the NASCAR?
The NASCAR.
The car is covered with advertising.
Isn't it? I think it's a car. No, it's a
spark plug. It's a gasoline thing. I
hate looking at NASCAR races.
They're like racing billboards.
You can't go to the men's room without
getting bombarded.
You can't go to the ladies. You have to
take my word for it.
You go to the men's room and here's a
big advertisement. You got nothing else
to do while you're going. So, they know
that.
Eat at Joe's Barbecue. Third and
You're getting programmed even when you
know you're what? You know
your guard's down. You got to go and
there you are. You just got programmed.
Did anybody ask you? No.
So you see the basic innocence of the
mind. The basic innocence is that the
ego in and of itself is unable to
discern truth from falsehood.
Decard rest internal versus rest
external.
Rest internal is the mind, the way you
see the world. Rest external is the way
the world is.
The way the world is. And there's an
intrinsic dichotomy.
It's almost impossible for people under
200. It's impossible to see the truth
the way it is. Therefore, culpability is
different below 200 and over 200.
Culpability below 200 is that of
ignorance.
Mhm.
Therefore, as you get over 200, you have
to be a little more meticulous because
now you're answerable and culpable.
Yeah. You're no longer considered a
spiritual idiot.
That's the good news.
We'll say the bad news the letter. Yeah.
All right. So the interaction of these
three things is today's world. Is it
not? Israel Judaism. People say I don't
like if you mention politics. You have
to mention politics. Why? Because
politics is the secular fallout of
religion. Is it not?
>> All of politics is nothing but religion.
you got uh
its expression within the world. So in
doing truth versus falsehood, that was
the purpose in chapter nine to go
through the world in all of its details
from the Eiffel Tower to political
parties to
elections whatever and see how does this
filter out in everyday world. It's one
thing as an abstract theory. It's
another thing. How does it actually
filter out in the world? So, these are
the sons of Abraham, how they filter
out. Anybody got any questions? Because
then we're going to take a break.
Anybody got any questions about what
we've said? Might as well handle it now.
>> Yeah. The uh the calibrations up there,
are they the current practices of those
churches or the original?
>> Uh if you ask what is the calibration of
the current uh church? Catholicism has
to be updated a little bit because they
went through a whole thing about clergy
pedophilia and all that and probably
came back up again now. Um, if you ask
what is the level of a current day
church worldwide?
Let's do college of cardinals. Okay,
we have permission to ask what I'm
asking.
What I'm holding in my cal 485. What I'm
holding in my cal 490.
when I'm calibrate holding my caliber
488 489 college cardinals currently 488
okay
yep
that's pretty high area edition I mean
that's 488 is very high area edition
that's that's not stupid you know 48
it's very high any other question yes go
ahead
>> when someone falls they're above 200 and
they falls below 200
Do they still have an etheric brain and
individual carbon?
>> I never asked that.
>> Gee, that is a question. Persons over
>> 200 and they fall.
>> Yes. All right. So they evolve to the
point where they have the athetheric
brain. We can ask this question. Now
they make a very bad choice. Choose that
which is nonintigous. And they fall. The
atheric brain remains resistant.
>> Disappears. It
>> you pull the plug.
You might say it's a certain radiation
and then when that radiation's not
there, it disappears. There's a
radiation. You know, we get all kinds of
emails and letters and gifts and things.
And before I open the package, I got
what it is. I mean, I get the the
radiation of it. You get the energy
precedes it, right? And if it's dead, I
say, "Let's calibrate it before we open
it. Make sure it's okay to open.
Sometimes we just put it in the
dumpster. No.
>> So would that person notice the loss?
>> I don't know, sweetheart.
>> I have never killed anybody, so I don't
know.
I mean, I imagine you'd feel pretty
dejected, wouldn't you?
>> I should say so. Yeah.
>> I think that's why some people turned to
drugs, too, is because they were in a
high place. They made a bad choice and
now drink drugs gives them a certain
state of artificial euphoria.
And of course, the reason the 12step
program works is you got the euphoria
without the drug and therefore all you
were seeking all along was the euphoria
and therefore sobriety tends to persist.
Yeah. Anybody else?
>> Yes.
>> Is there another term for that? The
radiant transcendence.
>> Another name for what?
You say that energy that comes through
that affects
>> it's a radiance. Yes. The radiance of
divinity within. Yeah.
The radiance of divinity within.
Uh
it's exhibited by
that which you have become determines.
That which you are
need not say anything
positioned thusly in the current you
automatically rotate this way. Yeah,
effortless. That's the new scientific
theory
if we're
things are not a consequence of the
energy of causation.
Yeah. But of power,
it's because of the power.
Because of the spiritual power of that
which you are, you draw to yourself
that which is aligned with divinity
and the miraculous happens
all the time. Why not?
It's hard to go a day without a miracle
happening.
>> Didn't we have a miracle yesterday?
She's still weeping from it.
And when you get
the essence out of which it comes,
you weep. And that's why in the high
500s, you spend a lot of time weeping.
It just can't be helped.
You're in an airport, couple look at
each other, you see the love, and all of
a sudden you break out in tears. You
cry. When you cry all the time, that's
the mid high
500s. When you're crying all the time,
you know you're in the 500s.
You don't have to calibrate yourself.
Otherwise, you're just a crybaby.
>> Mohammad have channeled a work at a
higher level in his own consciousness
because he had a lower consciousness
channel the 700 work. Maybe he never on
some
>> Muhammad is a whole study in itself to
track Muhammad's evolution. uh his
karmic inheritance
but at 700 he was in a botific state.
Now I've never heard any other
I've never gotten any information from
anything I would call an other.
um with the exception of when I was in
the pits of hell and I asked God for
help and I got hit by a huge energy
which I think was an archangel.
It it was
>> it was Yes. It was an archangel cruising
by
heard this pathetic squeal and just paid
attention for one second.
Instantly
they calibrate 6,000 and up. An
archangel even thinks of you. So somehow
an archangel must have thought of me
somewhere. There was some good karma
somewhere and that's why I am where I am
today standing here instead of dead.
All right, we're going to take a break
for how long?
>> Uh 15 minutes. We'll return at um 11:30.
>> We'll return at 11:30.
>> Um there are refreshments in the last
building. Please announce that there's
refreshments in the last building.
>> There's refreshments in the last
building.
I have to watch out.
The power of love gets so extreme that
it just blows you out of the linear. And
nonlinear I all I do is sit here and
look at you.
Oh yeah.
You feel love is very very powerful.
All right. Where were we?
Where we were? We'll resume there. We
just finished with the sons of Abraham
and um we got a lot of slides to do yet.
So we cannot deli deli. I like that
deli.
And we're going to go to the oriental
world religions.
Hinduism is the oldest 10,000 BC.
Enlightenment already was a dominant
energy in 10,000 BC. The ancient Aryan
cultures,
those are the world's great religions.
In fact, the world's oldest most formal
religion is Shiva Isism. Shiva Isism is
the world's oldest religion. It was
thousands of years old before the modern
sons of Abraham. Yeah.
Ancient
Dvidian. You see they all calibrate
uh the tr eternal truth of the rishies
dervidian 9005 Aryan 910
vidanta even currently 855.
So you see the tremendously high energy
fuels
that came out of the Hindu religion.
Hinduism is extremely interesting.
The reason I avoid going to India is
because I would never return.
I've done that trip and
they burn your body and the gats by the
side of the Genjis.
God.
So, um,
what was I going to say? Yes.
So the the great truths emerged first on
the planet and uh
long long ago. Yeah.
Out of those arose of course the fabled
uh yogas, the great uh yogas
of which what I teach the closest would
be
J h a n a yoga
>> jana
>> yoga
>> jana yoga. Yes, that's the closest
non-duality.
Um the pursuit of the ultimate truth,
the pathway of non-duality
is the closest uh thing to what we
teach. Huh? You might say ours is a
modern day version. Modern day version
of Janna yoga
bakti of devotion at 9:35
Raja
yoga
uh karma yoga selfless service selfless
service
that is open to all of mankind is is it
not to be a selfless service
before you leave the house, you close
the squirrel trap because he might get
caught in there. He'd spend the whole
day all by himself until he got home.
So, you have to close the squirrel trap.
It's just you got to do it, right? You
walk by the bug, he's going like this,
and you can't help it. You just got to
stop and turn him over, and then he
walks away. And now you feel happy.
Oh yeah.
Selfless service. Uhhuh.
Condundalini yoga
is 510.
Condalini yoga is less because it's like
there's an intentionality behind it. I I
don't recommend
trying to force the condundolini energy.
It's unwise. artificial means of trying
to achieve the cities on their own.
First of all, the fact that you want to
be able to do a certain city, no matter
what it is, is already indicative of the
spiritual ego, is it not?
>> You take classes on how to fly. Give me
a break, will you?
When you're able to fly, you fly.
And it happens without you thinking
about it. So,
condundalini yoga,
I don't believe in trying. I'll tell you
why. Because the condundolini energy,
the aetheric energy, as you advance, it
automatically rises.
Uh, as you see the beetle and you turn
him over,
the condolini energy is risen. You
understand? You don't have to do
anything artificial. artificial
exercises. I don't believe in
to make your energy get higher.
Either you're a kindly person or you're
not. If you're kindly towards all of
life, you don't have to do strange
things to try and force the energy.
If you force the energy prematurely,
it's a dangerous I think dangerous thing
to do. It means that you as a being are
not ready for it yet.
Yeah. Artificially, it's the attraction
of the spiritual ego. Spiritual ego.
Mhm.
Forcing the condalini energy.
Ka yoga.
This is sahaj marge. And this is happy
yoga. Happy yoga is start is a good
place to start. Many people start with
happy yoga. And uh I don't believe in
the glamorization of these yogas. You
get these slick spiritual magazine
enlightenment or something. It's called
and it all shows a diiahanous beautiful
woman on the front where she's
meditating like this but there's flowers
and music and bubbles and all kinds of
crap.
She's always diaphous.
You never see an elderly wrinkled old
lady.
You know that? Do you ever get a a slick
spiritual magazine?
She looks about 83. She's well
overweight. She's not too good-look. Her
hair is sort of a mess. Does she ever
You ever see her?
How about middle-aged men? You see any
middle-aged men meditating in there?
It's the impact of the media, right?
Impact of the media.
Somebody missing an Aruba has to be a
slim-l looking blonde, right?
Middle-aged duck waller with tattoos
you'd never hear about.
Says of his color, not not white. You
know, you never hear about him.
So, you see how that invades the
spiritual domain. Huh?
All right, we could talk a lot about the
yogas, but because our own pathway of
non-duality is one of the classic uh the
way of devotion towards truth, uh we
won't speak about it because that's what
we talk about all the time.
Harry Krishna
of course is very well known. Subat is
less well known instead of vidanta at
550 is well known. Sikism is relatively
well known at 600.
I think it's tempting to become a sick
because I love their turbons.
I'd be like to be a sick just for a
week. You walk around with that turban.
It's really cool, isn't it? You know,
and Janism is sort of arduous.
And one of our best friends in Korea has
a meditation center. Rat Raos on
Janism, you're not supposed to. You're
always walking around that you might
step on a bacteria or something. So
I figure let God worry about the
bacteria.
They wear masks so they won't breathe in
an insect and kill it, you know. So that
I think those are people who were once
careless of life, careless of life. And
now to get the lesson, they are very
careful of life. Uh at one time you were
disregarded the value of life and you
stomped it to death and now you see the
sacredness of all of life and now you
very carefully try not to step on an
ant.
I sure did not step on an amp because of
obsessive impulsive, not because I'm a
I don't want his death on my uh
same thing. Try not to kill people if
you can. It's a bad camera.
Now we come to one of the great great
ones of which is we're very familiar
here in Sedona. We have a Buddhist stupa
here and a very active spiritual
um Buddhas is very active in Sedona.
Uh so you have Mahayana the way of the
greater vehicle and you have Hinana
and you have Zen
Lotus Land. So
um I was a consultant to all these
things at one time you know in back east
for about a decade. I was a consultant
to the Episcopal Dasis, the Catholic
Dasis,
um the nuns who all lived in seclusion.
What do you call them? So, clustered
nuns.
>> Clustered nuns. Yes.
>> Anyway, uh to them, and then also the
Zen monastery,
also the ministerial council. So I did a
lot of counseling with ministers and
various peoples and very often the the
monastery would send in somebody
is he in samati or catatonia.
So we wrote that in the book how to
differentiate pathologic mental states
from spiritual states because to the
unsophisticated person they can look the
same whether a person is in catatonia
or in a state of somati because when you
go into a high state
uh that got me off of well no it didn't
get me off the rock did it I sat in a
rock in Sedona and I was in a state of
incredible bliss you know and time went
by and people went by and the sun came
up and the sun went
And uh
now you can get into a state like that.
Now the police could have come along and
dragged me away. See
there's a fellow sitting there spaced
you know and take you to the hospital.
So I kept surrendering all this. So they
take you to the hospital and they're
going to give you a shot of thorazine.
So they give you a shot of thorazine.
It's not going to affect my spirit
anyway. So nothing got me off the rock.
except I had things to do and out of
love for others I got off the rock. So
it was the only thing got me off the
rock was love. The love for others
enable me to function again. All right.
So those are the great yogas.
We're familiar with these.
Now there's a slight different there's a
difference between hinana and mahayana
but that's an artificial separation
because you can't be enlightened just
for yourself. It automatically affects
the world. Mahayana such as the current
um
what's his name? The um head of the
Tibetan
>> Daly Lama. Yeah. Yeah. He's concerned
with the salvation of all of mankind.
That's Mahayana. Hinana is more cons
you're concerned with your own
enlightenment.
Zen is really in a world of its own. I
could spend the entire day talking about
Zen.
Um talking about Zen and the people I've
known and uh
it's a style in a way. Zen in a way is a
style. Uh you can do Zen meditation
while you're walking around and talking
just as I am now. The zenmed meditative
state is continuous. The talking has
nothing to do with the state
doesn't interrupt it. In the beginning
it does interrupt it. And when you get
up from meditation it disappears. So
samadei certain states. So currently
there's no great teachers of zeni
states. None of them calibrate over 500.
Uh because the state of samadei is not
the state of enlightenment. It's not
saturator. Yeah. So you can go into
great states but then see so in the
beginning
the state comes on when you're in a
tense meditative state but then as you
open your eyes it disappears
after a while you can open your eyes and
the state continges but then when you
get up and begin to walk around it
disappears
then at a very advanced state nothing
interferes with it.
There's a period of time of adjustment a
number of some years where there wasn't
possible to function in the world
and then the state returns
capacity to function but has nothing to
do with your own reality and that which
you are. It doesn't affect it
like
like a frog jumping about on the top of
the lake has nothing to do with the
stillness of the lake. So, it's the frog
jumping around speaking today.
I have nothing to do with it. I Whatever
the frog says, I say to myself, "Wowy."
Cool, man. Cool. You know, all right.
So, the Zen monastery inana
Lotus Land has a anal analogous to
Christianity.
As we pointed out, Jesus Christ taught
salvation. And the Buddha tried taught
enlightenment. Lotus land
is in the approximation of the two. The
Buddha of infinite mercy acts as the
like the savior. He is your advocate. He
is your advocate. Lotus land is the same
as heaven. So the view of it is that the
ne negativity of this world is so severe
that reaching enlightenment here is very
unlikely and statistically that is a
fact. practically never happens.
Whole centuries go by and not one single
enlightened being
on the planet sometimes for hundreds of
years. And um because the negativity
here is so severe. So
the idea of lotus land Buddhism is
through good karma. When you leave the
body next time, you land in a celestial
realm. And from the celestial realm,
then where you're not surrounded by all
this intense negativity, you can
transcend on to full enlightenment. Huh.
And there your advocate would be
avalakasara or something like that. Is
that his name?
>> Yeah.
That's a mouthful. Whatever he is, he's
there.
Speaks for you. Speaks for you. just as
Christ does uh in heaven. And as you
know, we've said that there uh is not
just one heaven. There are multiple
regions of heaven. This is sacriiggious.
It'll get me read out of any religion
because I like to have an exclusive
pipeline.
Each one, each religion is exclusive
pipeline. When they say you can only get
to heaven if you do so and so have 14
wives or whatever they do it means to
their section their neighborhood. So the
celestial realm is in the 600s and it
has it has realms. So when you leave the
body you gravitate to that which you are
automatically. I mean you don't have to
be a genius to see that that you
automatically
flow to the altitude
of that which you are because like goes
to like in the other dimension so there
are multiple heavens multiple heavens
I'm sure there are heavens where the
Vikings went
and Valhalla and various
places there's probably even a place
where they've got 90 virgins, whatever
it is.
You go there, know there's 70 virgins.
70 virgins. And what they don't tell you
is the 70 virgins are 900 years old and
they hate men.
That's why they're still virgins.
And you find out, oops, that was a
mistake. Well, then you reincarnate.
I think I'll become a Protestant next
time. You know,
Lotus Land Buddhism then is very similar
to Christian heaven. Tantric is tricky
and I don't recommend tantric unless
you're extremely sophisticated because
the tantric sometimes gets involved with
energies and the manipulation of
energies
and it's and it thereby becomes linear
thereby becomes linear when you start
manipulating energies on the other side
you're dealing with the linear so you
brought yourself down and therefore
Tibetan and Tantric have their downside
an is 405
and I don't know why it calibrates that
way. I'm not that familiar with it.
Another eastern religion of course is
Shinto, the sun god,
uh descendant of the sun god. You see
what happens to it. So Shinto starts out
relatively integrous at 350 but then
when you include the Samary code it
drops to 190
and
code it drops to 180.
This Japanese in invasion of Manuria
when I was a kid the world's always been
at war since I've been on this planet
anyway when I was young. The Japanese
were slaughtering people in Manuria. The
slaughter of Nank King and it came out
of this code here which eliminates mercy
as a weakness.
Therefore,
as the prisoners surrender, you
slaughter them.
That's why it's dangerous. That's why
al-Qaeda and all those because they're
exactly the same way. If you surrender
instead of mercy, they cut your head off
slowly with a saw
and videotape the proceeding.
So you can see being kindly to those
people isn't going to do much good
because in being kindly you're going to
get your head saw off because they
despise that as weakness. So that code
is the same as this code here. Those who
surrender deserve to die by virtue of
the fact that they're cowards and
therefore they slaughter the rapid and
king. Slaughter people in the tens of
thousands.
Teaoism is to flow with the flow of
life. To go how it goes. To go how it
goes. To let it be. The Beatles song let
it be. Calibrated quite high. Sympathy
for the devil calibrated quite low.
Let it be calibrated quite high.
Let it be is teoism. Yeah. Yeah. To bend
with the current like the reed so that
you're not you don't break. Uhhuh. Other
religions. Baja has an appeal from the
beginning because it included women on
an equal basis with men and a lot of the
traditional religions
of the clergy and everybody are men. You
know, so that was the attraction of Baja
was that men and women were equal.
Native American religion is unique in
that it didn't have a great uh savior, a
great spokesman.
The Buddhism had the Buddha.
Christianity had Jesus Christ, etc.
Islam had Muhammad. Native Americanism
arose spontaneously of its own, not by
any authority. So they don't worship
authority. It's just obvious if you got
all your marbles there that all arises
out of divinity that all of life is
divine. So you before you kill the
antelope
>> or after you kill the analopee you thank
God for for the sacrifice because that
is u
out of the rig vida which calibrates in
the 900s. Each thing surrenders it in
surrendering its in fulfilling its
karmic destiny.
Then by its death it subserves
the life that is higher. It becomes it
earns the right to transcend.
Therefore when you eat the cow the cow
in its sacrifice
to humanness earns the right to
karmically return eventually as a human.
It is earned karmically
by its own sacrifice. Huh?
So that's the rig vita which calibrates
at 900.
Each gives its life and thereby ascends
to the life that is higher than it is.
Yes. And therefore over a great
trajectory of time the lowest eventually
becomes the highest.
It earns karmic merit.
And seeing through certain eyes, you see
that the animal willingly does surrender
and sacrifice itself to the higher. But
you have to be able to see that
it does in its spirit sacrifice itself
to thee, oh Lord. Do I worship
and surrender my life?
And by surrendering your life is the
very last step before the gates open
and
divinity shines forth
to thee. O Lord do I surrender life
itself. That's the last thing to be
surrendered.
Final doorway. There is nothing left.
All is still. All is silent. There's no
other there.
The only thing remaining is life.
And you realize that this too, oh Lord,
must I surrender.
And then is the experience of an a a
sudden and very severe feeling of dying.
And you realize that you are dying. And
you are dying for the first time ever.
You you can't die until this moment.
And then
the splendor
shines forth and the mind is silent
forever.
Takes years to learn how to talk again.
Talk.
So this intrinsic reality is intuitively
intuited by the native Americans
who therefore is reflecting the wisdom
of the rig vida at 900. The same thing
is repeated verbally in the rig vida
many thousand years ago. So we move to
the next slide.
Divinity and avatars. Huh?
Here we say angels are 500 and up and
that angels can also appear in the
physical domain in a human body.
We have permission to ask that.
That's who picked me up when I the truck
broke down in the highway.
Yep. Thank you.
Some people
actually sort of channel angelic
energies.
Here I am all alone million miles of
nowhere broken down in my old truck
which I still have on a busy
intersection
and I forget had to get to the airport
for a plane. Something bizarre. Anyway,
there you are broken down in one of
these major
metropolitan intersections
over by your lonesome in this old truck
and the car pulls over. How can I help
you? I said, I don't know. It seems to
me like the I know what it was. The tire
tire blew and uh I couldn't make the
jack work or I didn't own a jack. I
forget which.
He says, "Well, I'll take it off for you
and I'll take it down the next ramp off.
There's a place I can fix it." This guy
out of nowhere. Takes off my tire, puts
it in his truck, drives up down the
ramp, does the circle back, comes back
all the way around, maybe 45 minutes
later, and puts it back on my truck.
That kind of thing has happened
repeatedly in my life.
And if you channel you you calibrate,
was that an angel?
The man I'm holding in mind, God bless
him, was an angel. Wow.
So, some angels choose apparently
to uh reincarnate
and they are a great source of
benevolence in the world. Over and over
this kind of a thing has happened to me.
inexplicable.
If it happened a few times, you could
say that's chance. But when it's a
repetitive pattern, it's not chance.
It's a repetitive P pattern.
So turning, you see what happens when
you turn over beetles that are falling
on their back.
That's all that happened to me. I was a
beetle
on my back. Along came an angel and
flipped me over and I was on my way
again.
Karma. Yeah.
Angels 500 and over, archangels 50,000
and up. The Buddha nature is 1,000.
Buddha nature as voidness
is 980. Native American great spirit 850
plus
deity itself 720. I'm talking about the
terms now. Yahwa
and Jehovah. Jehovah. I don't know
historically why Jehovah's 205 has to do
with the world the way it was in those
years.
The word God as an intellectual concept
is 460.
All right. That's why the Buddha
recommended not to utilize the
terminology at all because everybody's
got their own conception of God and that
holding that conception will be a block
in the experiencing of the ultimate
reality because the ultimate reality
first of all is nonlinear and not
definable. So any concept you have about
God has got to be false to begin with
as an intellectual concept. The Buddha
said it you know do not talk about it.
The Buddha however as we see calibrated
extremely high.
Therefore the Buddha
was
let's use the term God realized
resist. See, he says, "Don't use the
word God." The false conclusion that
Buddhists make is therefore he didn't
experience divinity as godness. Oh yes,
he did. Otherwise, he wouldn't calibrate
a thousand. Of course, he knew it was
God. And he said, "But but if he used
the term, so when I tell you what
happens if you lay down your life, the
infinite presence reveals itself."
I don't use the word God either
because there's no word there. It's just
a profound
there is no word for it. See that's why
the Buddha said don't use that word but
the Buddha is at a thousand.
So, we got through this. Uh, this has to
do with a Hebrew
history. Why Jehovah is at 205.
Uh, I don't know. And Yaywa is at 460.
I'm not a biblical scholar
because what's usually called religious
spiritual research is really
archaeologic research. It's archaeologic
where Jesus walked and all where Jesus
walked. Now it all calibrates about I
don't want to tell you where it
calibrates any anyway. So
God
calibrates infinity. God the father the
creator the almighty.
Maker of heaven and earth.
Ruler of the universe.
Maker of all things visible and
invisible.
Omnipotent. Omnisient and omnipresent.
The supreme, the source of all life and
existence.
The essence is the holy spirit referred
to as Allah.
In early Hindu referred to divinity as
an
u expressed as Shiva, Krishna and Brahma
triune and Vishna Vishna.
Durga is Farah Rama,
God of Moses and Abraham.
So, we're all talking about the same
thing despite all this different
languaging. All this different
languaging,
they're all referring to that which is
infinite. Out of which arises all of
creation
and creation is continuous and ongoing,
has no beginning, has no end. Yeah.
Okay. Next one.
Ah, so
the highest level possible,
let's see if that's still So the highest
level possible for a human within the
human domain is a thousand.
The human domain is not a good place to
be if you're over a thousand. Resist,
you know, because you f fry your nervous
system.
Oh, I've lost my voice.
>> Yeah, you bumped it. Okay.
>> Okay. All right. So, this indicates the
presence of divinity within the human
domain calibrates at a thousand. So, was
the Buddha enlightened? I mean, were
they were these both the same? They're
all the same. They all calibrated a
thousand. The 12 Christian apostles
calibrate about 90 n just less than
Jesus Christ.
The name of God as home.
Huh?
It's 970.
Such an anonymous translation of
punelli's
what we call it. It has an error in it.
It designates as a
is only about 470. Okay. Am
is over 400, 420, 430, 440, 460.
a is an error
such an translation of
zapisms.
All right. The 12 Christian apostles
then in the bones of St. Peter in the
basilica in Rome still calibrate in the
high 900s to this very day.
Okay. John the Baptist
9:30
Moses himself 910
Abraham the father of all the great the
three great religions St. fall extremely
high. Muhammad at the time he dictated
the Quran was at 700 and then later
unfortunately
do I think too you see that which is
negative looks for an opening. It very
often people get taken over by a lower
astral entity. It happens during
intoxication, brain injury, and I think
temporal lobe epilepsy was the energy
that that which hates truth managed to
get in uh and contaminate. Okay, what's
next?Allelu
Hallelujah.
Hallelujah.Allelu
Hallelu
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.