So
here
Let's go back to the SC. I want to just
uh make sure I mention all these for
people who haven't been to these
lectures before. Those who have been
here before or have truth versus false
already. I put it in there.
Truth is always true.
That which emanates from the self with a
capital S or by divine incarnation
uh is always the same. It comes on as an
inner radiance knowingness. It's silent,
nonverbal, is exquisite. It's
transformative
and it's always the same. Therefore,
the great sages of ancient India of
ancient India
uh five or six
thousand years BC
the great Aryan sages out of which came
the Hindu religions and viata etc. uh
whatever their experience of the truth
is the same as it is in in the present
day.
Truth is does not exclude anybody. It's
nonsecreative. It's nonsecular.
It's non sectarian.
It doesn't have any secrets.
Does the sky have any secrets?
Does the sun radiating forth have any
secrets?
for $250. I will whisper in your ear.
I see you've been there, huh? I think it
was $250
from John Trumpet. Okay, that's $ 250.
Take it for a second with it. $250
secret. What's the purpose of secret?
The purpose of secret is to control,
isn't it? Why would you want to keep
anything secret, right?
If it takes you to love, what love wants
to share.
You want to share with people. You can
rationalize charging by saying if they
get it for free, they won't value it.
That's a clever rationalization of
people who charge money so they don't
feel guilty about it.
You could have some other requirement.
not necessarily monetary,
but you would see the quick loss of
interest in many of these organizations
if the requirement was not a monetary
one.
Available should be open, available,
written, verbal,
videos, audios, lectures, books,
whatever. Integrity of the purpose.
There's nothing to gain or lose.
If nobody listens to the lecture, that's
fine with me.
Everybody listens to the lecture, that's
If there's nobody here, I wouldn't have
to make the trip.
All right? So, why is this? It's because
through any of these meditative or
contemplative styles, eventually you
become the field. The field that is
complete and total in itself. It has
nothing to gain. It's not lacking
anything. It just is.
That which is has no needs or nothing to
gain. The fact that three people come to
your lecture or 30,000 is all the same.
It's all the same. It's all the same.
Why? Because your obligation is to
yourself and to God. The reason we're
going to talk about 8:50 this afternoon
is I don't want to go back on the other
side and you didn't mention it.
It's the obligation to divinity and
seeing divinity as expressed as the life
as human life. So out of your love for
life and your obligation and your love
for God, you you want to share all that
you you know for the benefit of all.
Say,
if you got to the top of a certain
mountain, it's your obligation to share
with the new climbers what to expect up
there. Sometimes, I can't believe it.
Here's a group that goes up there with a
guide. This guy, I'd sue the pants off
him. Takes them up to 12 or 14,000 ft
with no oxygen.
And and an experienced guide.
Oh god. So if you're going to make a
long climb, a teacher should tell you
what it's like, what the north slope is
like, what hours you can do that. And
you're not going to get much strength
unless you get a supplementary oxygen
over 12,000 14,000 ft. So these people
barely survive. And you know, the death
rate of people trying to get to the top
of Everest is extremely high. I forget
how many die every year. 19 or 20 or
something. Uh
>> yeah. So therefore, a guide should tell
you what to look out for along the way.
Just like when your father taught you
how to drive or your mother as as it may
be in today's world. Uh my father taught
me never trust the other driver. Always
presume he's drunk and stupid.
Just because his left turn indicator is
going doesn't mean he's going to turn
left. He could just as well turn right.
He got confused left and right. So
happily I never had a serious accident.
And I was a cab driver for many years
and I've driven like a million miles. So
all right. So we we have an obligation.
I'm the gain and lose. Uh truth is not
the expos it's not sectarian independent
of opinion. Uh we're not interested to
say what people's opinion is. Has no
positions on anything. Truth is not
anti- anything. Why? Because falsehood
is not the opposite of truth. It's the
absence.
No requirements or demands. You don't
have to take any oaths, sign up for
anything. No required memberships. You
don't have to swear on on top of
something. Uh non-controlling.
A teacher has no interest in the
personal lives of individuals unless
they bring them up for discussion within
a spiritual context. I mean, of what
interest would it be to a spiritual
teacher? what your sex life is, what how
you cut cut your hair, what you wear.
You know what I'm saying?
Why should a spiritual teacher is
talking about a whole different
dimension have any interest in your
personal life? I mean, who cares?
You know, a person could say, "Look, I
have a compulsive sexuality and I'm just
driving me nuts." That's a different
thing. See, but I'm not telling him,
look, don't have sex with about 30, 40
people in a row like that. uh it's not
my place to be telling him. I'll tell
you why. Another reason because I rob
him of the karmic merit. Do you
understand? If I do a thing through
threat, intimidation, and and by
swinging my weight around, I've just
deprived him of the karmic benefit of
having seen that for himself and chosen
to transcend that. You know, when he
says, "I don't want to be run by list
anymore. It's driving me crazy." And I
say, 'Well, if you want to be a member
of our group here, uh, you can't have
sex there. Now, he's conforming out of
fear of my authority, but he's he's
gained no karmic merit.
>> He's doing it out of fear of my
opinion of him, etc. See, so I don't
like, you know, there's no point to
control people because you deprive them
of karmic merit.
Therefore, hitting bottom is a necessary
step for many people and we all have hit
bottom or none of us would be in this
room. We've all hit bottom a lot of
times.
A lot of times or you know seemingly
minor issue but we anguished over them
and made a change of direction. So a
change of direction. So non-controlling
therefore
no interest in the personal lives
the way they dress. What difference
would it make how a person wears a hat,
whether they have a beard, sexualize,
rich or poor, family patterns, whether
they want to have group sex or what? I'm
not going to tell them don't have group
sex. I mean, it's their problem
if you got the time for group sex. I
don't know.
>> All right. free of force or
intimidation.
I mean, if you don't come to these
lectures, we're not going to put a
rattlesnake in your mailbox. You know
what I mean?
We don't want to brainwash anybody.
We don't want people going into
agilation of leaders, the great ba haha,
bong bong, you know, and who needs all
that theatrical ritual?
You don't need to brainwash people with
indoctrinations
or intrusions into their private life.
So, we'll go into the next one.
Uh we have to hurry through to be
through. We're not going to bind anybody
with any contracts, pledges, etc. And uh
there's reasons for that. Uh it may seem
reasonable to you in this lifetime, but
you know when you take a vow and swear
by a follower or something like that,
you know that you're responsible for
that for many many lifetimes,
20 lifetimes from now. You don't know
what what's happening in your life. You
are held by the bond you just made. So
it may seem opportunistic and convenient
in this lifetime but how's it going to
be when you've you know gone down many
many and there's a four of us got
together one time
we'd all made the same pledge in the
same lifetime in the same place and we
all have the same consequence.
Okay.
Therefore truth doesn't want to do
anything. It allows freedom, not
non-binding
commonality.
Who people are within the spiritual
community is dependent on just who they
are. You know, it's not dependent on
titles. This is master so and so. This
is double master so and so. This is
triple master so and so.
This is super master so you know what I
mean? People get ranked up. You know
what I'm saying? And then all the gar
the the stuff that you put on yourself
goes with that. You get to be the hunk.
So the theatrical glamorization is
seductive. Seductive. A lot of people
think they're very religious.
They've been seduced into the theater.
the theater of religiosity.
There's whole cultures, in fact, ones we
have Greek problems with, who are
seduced as a whole culture into the
theater
of extreme religiosity.
Doesn't help me.
Somebody prostrates himself on the floor
and then blows up my neighbors in the
bus. Save me all the frustration and
have a little kindness and consideration
for other human beings please. Thank
you.
>> That's for sure.
>> All the theatrics doesn't mean anything.
It's racial. So the a true teacher
avoids that glamorization which is a
seduction. This is a seduction and it's
an explo exploitation of people. It's
putting a Hollywood twist on stuff.
Materialistic truth is we don't need
worldly wealth. self-fulfilling
self doesn't need adherence followers
doesn't want to sign up members
uh detached non-involvement in world
affairs
um I haven't marched in any parades
I haven't carried any placards
I don't intend to
the world will have to save itself
mahari says
The world you think you see out there
doesn't even exist. It's a rejection
from your own perception.
And the best thing to do is to surrender
it to God. Surrender the world to God.
Uhhuh. Why? Because don't people don't
even know what the world is about. Why
would you want a medal in which you have
this last idea what it's all about?
What's the purpose of human life in this
world in the first place?
Is it to be Shambala? Is it to be a
celestial realm?
There's supposed to be a celestial realm
calibrated at 600. It's in another
dimension called heaven.
>> No. The purpose of this world is I see
it. Let me see if what the way I'm
seeing is correct before I share it. The
way I'm seeing it is the way it is. Is
this? Yes. Better be.
I've been counting on it, folks.
Purpose of this world is maximum karmic
opportunity.
You can expand here at a tremendous
rate. There are other dimensions, but
you don't have a choice. What choices do
you have in a celestial realm where
everybody's at 600? You got any choice?
>> No.
>> No. If everybody's heavenly and
blissful, you're stuck in heavenly
blissful, aren't you?
Okay. After
450,000 years, it dawns on you there's
some beyond celestial. Oh,
there's some beyond 600. Okay. Now, the
purpose of this dimension then is here.
You saw through the evolution of
consciousness.
This is the place to maximize the
evolution of your consciousness. This is
the most wonderful environment for
undoing negative karma and gaining
positive karma. This is the maximal
environment where you have every
gradation and every opportunity
where you're attracted by this and have
an aversion to this.
Uh this is the world of maximum
opportunity
without walking into a battlefield of a
riddle of bullets for the sake of God,
mother, country, wife, and children, for
the sake of the king or whatever. How
are you going to cross over 200?
How are you going to cross over 200?
You can't do it just in your head. There
comes the day when you got to walk into
the bullets. I'm willing to die for what
I believe. Bang. You're now over 200.
As I've said, women have done it for
generations through childbirth. The risk
of death from childbirth is extremely
high. How anybody even lived through it
to get the fourth or fifth? Well, my
family Bible, it goes back, you know, it
always lists all the wives this guy had
and all the little children that that
you know the still births etc. So the
chance of getting of surviving child
birth was frankly very small child
fever, hemorrhage, eclampsia, all the
things that we try to treat now. So the
woman is facing almost you know very
likely death very if you get pregnant
enough times in the 17 1800s sooner or
later it'll get you. So after Mary she
survived three kids but the fourth one
put her under. Therefore the Bible Bible
says that great uncle Henry then married
the Katrina and she has but out of her
children how many died. So the woman
faces uh the fear of death uh in
childhood in childbirth all the time.
Traditionally the man has done it you
know in war. So
this is a world of maximum karmic
opportunity.
It's in war that you learn certain
things that you cannot live outside of
war. Unless you're actually facing
really being blown up really really that
bond that goes between you, your fellow
mates, your service to your country, the
service to the queen, to the king, to
whatever uh just can't happen
unless you can actually literally
hemorrhage to death in childbirth. You
don't cross over for the sake of life,
for the sake of this child, for the sake
of this baby. You risk your life. You
have to actually do it. The pain of
childbirth is a real real real thing.
Many of us have never been able to cross
these great barriers except by
identification with mankind in general.
Uh Susan mentions during child birth
that she thought of all all the women
throughout all the time who were faced
with this crisis and the fact that they
did it right gave you the power and the
strength. I myself remember severe
conditions and I said
I picture the civil war all these guys
laying on the battlefield with their leg
blown off this guy's hands blown off
this guy's face is just blown off.
Somehow the human the human can
transcend that can handle it. So
through travail like the great tsunamis
let's say through great travail then we
bond with other others as humanity.
Otherwise it's just a speech. All kinds
of jerks get up there and make peace
speeches and love and all that crap
don't you why? Because that bonding has
to be of the heart, you know, where we
went to
when we went to uh tattoo in Scotland. I
remember, you know, as a hundred bag
pipers come through all at once. The
scirrel, it just
does something just beyond the personal.
And what is grabbed is the heart of
humanity.
The sound of the bagpipe at 510 or 520.
When you hear that coming over the hill,
the chill goes up your spine because
this is certain death walking. You
better win or you will die. Huh? So, but
the courage to do that then comes from
the bonding with all of humanity.
We all bond with each other as humanity
on an impersonal basis. And it's our
love for each other that goes out
through the heart of our oneness with
all humanity. That's what's lifts the
sea and all the prayer circles and all
are very good. But unless you feel that
commonality of identification with all
of mankind and all humankind, then you
can't lift them. You can't lift the
level of the sea. So on this coming day
when unity wants us all to pray
together, you know, that's what we do.
So you reaffirm your bonding
uh your love for mankind
which is like the collective heart of
mankind and the power of that collective
heart is what keeps us all surviving
because human life is extremely
difficult.
Human life is extremely difficult.
Anybody disagree?
Yes. All right. So, all right. It it's
then the owning the owning of the
oneness of the heart of human humanness
itself. When we own that, we become
that. We become the power of it. And
when we become the power of it, we have
we have the power to transform it. You
can't bring about peace without owning
the heart of
humanity as that who you are. So we'll
meet again later.
What time do we
>> So,
>> well, we tried to
um undemonize the ego so that you can be
friendly with it, own it, and handle it
without riddling yourself with anxiety
and guilt and shame and despair and self
flagagillation,
which is why there's so few of
enlightened people in the world.
Anybody wants to plow through all that?
Good God.
Oh yes.
We were talking about freedom of speech.
First of all, it's overblown. It's not
the highest calibration virtue that
there is. Freedom of speech doesn't
calibrate, you know, like 900 something.
Truth and integrity calibrates much
higher than free speech.
The downside of moral relativism is the
abuse of free speech, you know,
and the decline through moral relativism
of um the level of integrity in the
United States is u part of the uh
judicial
actions.
The most uh important one was
interpreting
uh
behavior as symbolic speech. That was
the ruling that took the bottom out.
All right. So if uh I forget what the
exact um
uh court uh what what the what it was.
Somebody in the audience will probably
remember. But anyway,
the ruling was
um that the person's physical expression
behavior
was symbolic speech and speech is
freedom. See?
>> All right. So, if you interpret behavior
as symbolic speech, you just took the
bottom out of your society.
>> All right. That means the Kucks clan is
okay, right?
hanging black people. I mean, that's
just symbolic speech, isn't it? Right?
Burning crosses,
burning down black churches. I mean,
that's just all symbolic speech, isn't
it?
So, you get what the downside of moral
relativism is.
The other side of moral relativism is
its misunderstanding of egalitarianism.
Egalitarianism, which calibrates around
265,
then becomes the rationalization and
excuse
that all people are equal from an
egalitarian viewpoint.
Frankly, they ain't.
They aren't equal in this domain at all.
That people will just soon kill you as
look at you. You know, you know, if
you're going to give a serial killer
equal rights with your local minister,
then you're a little bit off in your
little bit off in the upper story. But
that's the rationalization. See?
>> All right. So, if action behavior then
is symbolic speech and there's to be no
restraint on speech, I can do anything I
want. Huh? And if there is no absolute
then
and no morality and no ethics. So in the
book I call this you know the mad
hatter's tea party. I call it the
morality of amorality.
They get out there and pontificate
against morality. That's the new
morality called amorality.
And if you really want to understand it,
you read Herbert Marcus and you will see
why your kids that you sent to college
came home weird.
And if you believe what that guy wrote,
man, you are mental already
and somewhat deranged and programmed,
you know.
So moral relativism then is is a um
expressed in rhetoric and it's caused
much confusion in society. Equal
justice egalitarianism is the ideal.
Yes. But then under that ideal comes
behaviors that are beyond the pale. And
so you see the decline of freedom of
speech.
Free speech in the United States today.
Let's say let's do
as a political concept calibrates over
260 265. All right. Free speech as
exercised in the United States today
through the media etc. calibrates over
180 185 190 calibrates at 190.
At best it's only 20 and something.
at 200 and something. I don't want to
die for just for free speech.
I mean, so some jerk can get up on a
soap box and blow off. I'm not going to
sacrifice my life for free speech. It
calibrates at 265. I mean, it's a
nicity,
but it's overheralded.
There are things more important than the
libertineism of being able to spout off
any kind of malicious rhetoric you want.
See,
That's my free speech.
>> All is in divine order.
Where is the guy?
>> He just looked over to you. That's why
everybody laughed.
>> See if he's got a wristband on him.
Those
suckers always gets in for free. Turns
himself into a chipmunk.
All is in divine order. That's a good
affirmation to hold. All is in divine
harmony and all is in divine order. All
right. If all is in divine order, then
the world is perfect as it is. Correct.
>> Yeah. Right. All right. Uh otherwise
there'd be no point point to get born
here.
If this was a celestial realm at 600,
everything was absolutely perfect.
There'd be no purpose to human life. You
don't need to incarnate to, you know,
find that out.
Uh so we forgot that was the word I
couldn't think of. Symbolic symbolic
speech. Yes.
And um the third thing was
I don't remember what the third thing
was now.
I usually put down a couple of words of
things I want to make sure to mention
today.
We're going to handle the void though.
That's necessary.
And then we're going to finish with the
slides. Or let's do the slides and then
we'll get to the void. Okay. All right.
Um, well, we did these already. I think
we did these. Didn't we do them?
>> Y.
>> Uh,
let's go back to the last slide. I want
to make sure I did them.
>> You did.
>> I mean, I don't want to lie in bed
saying, "Gee, you didn't do the third
slide."
>> That's it.
>> Huh?
>> This is the last slide.
>> Oh, okay.
>> All right. So, you don't get
positionalized. You stay out of the uh
you stay out of the political realm.
Equality
re is the irreverence for all of life
and it's exherely
avoid that which is dilotarious rather
than opposing it. So that's the
principle to be pro chocolate you don't
have to be anti vanilla. In our current
society they think to be pro this you
got to be anti that.
uh non-temporal life is eternal and life
cannot be destroyed. There is no such
thing as death. Death is an illusion.
We've done it many a time before
audiences.
And like
the principle of the indestructibility
of matter or of energy, for some reason,
mankind never noticed the
indestructibility
of life itself. Right? Let's see. Life
it cannot be destroyed. It is an
impossibility. It is an impossibility
for death to occur. So stop worrying
about it. Okay?
Non-temporal
and it's beyond proof. That which is
provable is within the linear Newtonian
domain. Uh that which is of a higher of
nature is not provable.
It's demonstrable. It's reportable.
You can declare it as uh an inner
experience.
Uh you can track it. You can confirm it.
But you cannot prove it.
You know, you cannot prove it
because proof ends at calibration level
499. 500 and up, you're in a different
paradigm. The reason, you know,
conferences on science and spirituality
or science and religion uh don't get
anywhere. or they all circle around in
the 450 range of intellectualization is
because spiritual reality starts at 500.
Well, talking from 500 on is subjective.
Subjective is the no in the academic
world. So, you can't have an academic
uh conference on science and religion
and talk about the truth of religion
because it would not be allowable in the
Newtonian paradigm, Newtonia of
subjectivity.
So there's all kinds of learned journals
and they discuss the problem of the
first person subjective whether it
should be allowable within scientific
data.
How can you discuss science and
consciousness and and not even know
whether the subjective is uh admissible,
academically re respectable? So they
those things go nowhere. They go they're
well-intentioned.
All right. Mystical.
Mystical means non-logical, not
explicable and beyond the Newtonian
paradigm. It means subjective and
experiential.
What a mother feels for her children
cannot be proven.
She's willing to walk across and walk
through hell for them, but you can't
prove it. You can demonstrate it, but
it's not provable. It's mystical. It's
spontaneous. It comes within from
within.
As the as the linear disappears,
as you remove your investment of
interest and energy
in value from
the linear,
what emerges then is the dominant
dominance of the context which is
nonlinear and that's called mystical.
the mind becomes silent and in its place
is what could be called
oh I don't know the capacity for
knowingness it's silent it doesn't know
anything but it has the capacity
uh without definition in the spiritual
teacher is classically called the
parushia the self with a capital s the
presence within is what initiates the
speakingness the teacher has nothing to
do with the speakingness. The teacher
just witnesses the speakingness and uh
the teacher doesn't know what's going to
be said till till it's said.
I never know what's going to be said.
It's just amazing a lot of times.
Yeah. is ineffable, not capable of
definition
because in the nonlinear there is no u
predicate, no noun, there's no verb and
there's no adjective. So there's no
structure for languaging and mentation
is usually symbolic mentation. So it
cannot really be mentalized and that's
why it's very difficult to express
difficult to express and it leads to
confusion. All right. So, uh, I think
we'll we'll cut out from that and I'll
go on date 50. I want to go on date 50
because I have an obligation to do that
and I don't want to get hit by a bus and
I didn't explain.
You got to go back again, Junior.
You forgot the 850, baby. Oh jeez.
It's important. Why? Because you have a
group here of very spiritually oriented
people. And classically, you know, the
Zen, Zen has a certain magic allure too,
a certain glamour to Zenism.
Uh, you know, it became popular then it
became sort of a thing. Uh, but any
serious spiritual student will
eventually end up probably with Suzuki's
uh classic on Zen or Hoang Po uh Hang
Po.
The difficulty with the classics,
so-called non-dualistic classics of the
Zen tradition
is that the pathway of negation takes
you to the void. All right? Now, the
void is not the ultimate space at all.
The void is 850.
The pathway of negation then negates the
reality of all that is linear.
the mistake that it makes and it was
made by a well-known guru in this
community some years ago. It led to the
downfall of the whole enterprise
was the confusion that love is an
attachment.
If you're going to negate everything,
you're going to negate the value of
relationship etc etc emotion.
The teaching that love is an attachment
and a limitation and therefore has to be
surrendered is an error.
It's misinterpreting divine love and
personal love. Personal love between a
me and a you and if I don't have you
baby I'm going to kill myself or you
etc. gets frantic and that's a
clingingness a dependency and an
attachment.
Love, however, is also a distinct and
overwhelming quality of the presence of
divinity. All right?
So, if you do Suzuki or Hang Po, any of
them, you'll find that what they're
talking about is a calibrated level at
850.
850 is the void.
Void,
nonlinear,
impressive,
eternal, with no beginning and no
ending. Surely
this has to be it. One thinks as one
enters the void.
It's stunningly overwhelmingly profound
without beginning or end. Eternal,
nonlinear,
profound, silent, still and peaceful.
It's foreverness.
And it has a quality of divinity and
that's nonlinearity
all presence and eternal.
All right.
The experience within of the phenomena
you see because when I when you do the
very highest calibration level possible
you come up with a th00and not 850. So
850 is not
Washington DC. That's not this capital
that you were traveling for
the pathway negation because it's so
popular and I get you know letters from
people that got to the void and now what
the abyss falling off into the abyss of
nothingness.
This you should know about beforehand.
Not once you get to the top of the
mountain at 16,000 ft and you can't
breathe.
You should know that before you take off
for the mountain. All right. So what you
hear today will be embedded in a
frequency and a vibration in within your
aura.
The knowingness came in this life life
lifetime
uh out of nothingness at age three
around in there out of nothingness out
of a void out of oblivion because I left
the last lifetime in the void.
Then there was nothingness then
reemergence at age three in a in an
embodiment. Oh jeez. Suddenly out of
nothing and nowness and oblivion, bang,
there was a sudden confrontation with
existence.
Horrible.
It was like you lived all your life in a
black cave and suddenly somebody seek
turned on cleague lights.
Stunning, shocking,
the phenomena of existence.
I was not pleased.
Plus, that was bad enough. But there's
this this body sitting in this little
wagon went with the deal. Not only do
you have an existence, but there's the
thisness goes with the damn thing.
Then
when the shock of existence wore off,
suddenly up out of nowhere came the fear
of non-existence.
At age three, there was no thinking
about this. It was a knowingness,
non-verbal knowingness. But if I exist,
it might have come about that I might
not have come into existence. So up came
the fear of non-existence.
The presentation in this life was the
ultimate reality. Existence or
non-existence.
The implication of the void is the
reality of non-existence which is an
absurdity.
If the void of nothingness was the
absolute reality, there would no be
nobody to tell you about it. You get it?
There'd be nobody to tell you that
nothingness is nothing is what the
ultimate reality is because there'd be
nothing to tell you that.
No, there's a somethingness that tells
you that nothingness is the ultimate
reality.
All right? So, as you keep with, you
know, through the evolution of
consciousness,
transcend the levels of consciousness.
H
letting go of the identification with
linearity.
If you follow the pathway of negation,
you will end up at the void. Yeah. All
right. Once you're in the void, you know
you're in the void because it's very
very profound. It's not just a maybe.
It's you know it's the void.
Now in this in this lifetime around 12
or 14 somewhere
I had this long paper out Wisconsin and
sticks no electricity on the highway and
uh million miles of nowhere it's dark
cold and blizzardy
and um the bicycles falling over the
newspapers are blowing across the frozen
uh land. I was not happy with this whole
deal.
And the snow banks were very high. So
there's a crust over the snowbank. So
the wind the wind was just ferocious. So
I thought, I'm gonna get out of this
wind. So I knocked a hole through the
crust and dug out there. And I just
climbed out of the wind. And no sooner
did I climb out of the wind. I wasn't
near it wasn't near death. I was nowhere
near death. I was in good shape, just
freezing cold. But as soon as I got out
of the wind, a sus I was suffused with
an incredible warmth
and then silence and an incredible
presence.
Incredible and profound
beyond all description
with no beginning and no end.
And it was myself,
the knowingness that I existed before
all universes
and after all universes.
That which I am will prevail. That which
I am was before all universes
and will be after all universes have
disappeared.
That is the truth. Lord God, resist.
That is the truth. Lord God, resist. At
level 10,00. That's your reality.
That's your reality.
Death is impossible. It's always existed
because that which you are is not
different than the source of your
existence.
This lasted for some time beyond all
time. Like the dirty depths of hell
which are eternal, this was also
eternal. Out of this eternal, exquisite.
Uh it was beyond bliss because in bliss
there is someone who is experiencing
bliss.
This is a love of profound power. It's
exquisitly gentle like this touch of a
of a soft kitty fur. And it's enormously
and infinitely powerful simultaneously.
And only a person who's been there will
know this and which I will tell you now.
It's like rock.
How can that which is infinitely gentle,
exquisitly loving, it's like infinitely
powerful like steel and rock at the same
time that's exquisitly gentle. That's
how you know it. Okay?
That's how you know it. It has not only
profound divine love that melts any
thinkingness,
but it has an immense innate power
simultaneously.
And when you experience it, you'll know
what I mean by a rocklike steel infinite
power. It's love, but it is also
infinitely powerful.
So,
I've really had this experience before.
And because I wasn't home for dinner,
etc., Uh my father came home. He found
came home found I wasn't home. Went on
the 29 model 8 Ford Roadster,
my favorite car, 29 Model A Ford
Roadster, and tracked down the paper
route to found where find me where I
was, you know. So there I was. Next
thing I know, there's somebody shaking
my knee, you know, and it's my father
looking at me. And I look at him and I
You don't have to breathe either. I
mean, everything comes to a stop.
Uh, I doubt the breathing was even going
on because when it recurred at level 600
in bliss, you don't have to breathe or
anything. Anyway, I don't think I was
even breathing. So, the
my father who I I I loved a lot
is shaking my knee. Christ. And he's
he's looking at me and I'm
nonresponsive.
At this point, I had to decide to
breathe and re-energize
being with the body or not.
Frankly, I didn't want to. But if I
didn't, my father would have been
stricken with a lifetime of guilt that
he allowed his son to he would assume
freeze to death and die in a snowbank. I
couldn't hit my father with a lifetime
of guilt.
So, I breathed. Huh.
No love love prevails. You do things for
love you wouldn't do even re own the
body. So there had been the experience
of the infinite presence of love. So
when the pathway of negation was resumed
in this lifetime
uh it was it came with the teaching to
negate the qualities of beauty and love
uh uh because they were limitations
and so I went back back into the void
went back into the void
I don't know what age through my 30s
probably anyway I went back into the
void of nothingness This only this time,
this time I realized the error. This
time the void
the void was void of the presence of
divine love.
Therefore, I knew it's
it is very much like empty space. Empty
space or sky. You can imagine what what
does empty space feel like? Feels like
nothing, right?
But the radiance of divinity was what
was missing. Ah so
therefore I negated ne negated the the
void. It was difficult to get out of it.
It took hours. In fact I found a thought
somewhere and I kept giving energy to
the one thought which led to a second
thought which led to it and I gradually
retreated back out of the void. Huh?
When the highest state recurred later,
it was the radiance of love and
void like the void is void except with
the radiance of infinite beauty and love
in which everything shines forth its
divinity.
You know the ultimate state because
everything scintillates
as a presentation. It radiates its
divinity as a knowingness. And all that
exists knows of the knowingness of
everything else that exists. Every rock,
every tree, everything that is is aware
that everything else is conscious of
every everything is aware of the
consciousness awareness of everything
else because of the oneness and the
unity. So the ultimate state is not
void.
It's oneness, allness, infinite love.
All right? So to own your Buddha nature
can lead you mistakenly into a
nothingness
because the Buddha nature as defined
very often and understood especially in
the western world probably in the
eastern world too is nothingness
voidness.
The presence of God is unity oneness and
the radiance of love. It is nonlinear.
It is infinite. It has no beginning and
it has no ending.
It is very very profound.
Its divinity is stunning. It's like a
stunning that radiates out to you. The
color of things isn't that the color is
the color radiates its colorness to you.
The bark of the tree shines forth its
sparkness to you. It's almost like
you're living in a childhood cartoon
where the trees talk and the grass waves
at you and the flowers dance. It's very
much like that. Very much like that.
Very much without the cartoon quality,
but the incredible radiance of the
perfection of existence shines forth
profound.
So h
should through the pathway indigation
you end up in the void now you've heard
what it is and what to do about it you
know with conviction
of that which knows and I share with you
now you know that that is the fate that
is a state to be transcended that is not
the ultimate state all right
as I mentioned earlier
hanging Po that writing of finding poe
which is about oh 7th to 9th century I
forget where anyway uh he was at 850 and
the writing is at 850 but hanging po
himself transcended that after being in
the void he then subsequently went to
960 he didn't get stuck in it huh but I
don't think he wrote anything after that
consequently David he says for God's
sake
I said hang po for you buddy I will be
sure to mention it this trip by God.
So I made up with the Buddha that you
know enlightenment is not between two
thoughts as prior and I made up with
Huang Poe. So fellas, okay,
the only way to know that is to know it
via the knowingness itself. And the
knowingness is what speaks to you now.
It's not a person speaking to you. It's
the knowingness is speaking to you uh of
its own. Of its own.
So okay, that's that obligation. Cross
that one off there.
Okay. God did that one.
Oh yes.
And the other thing we try to
recontextualize the ego is um
so that you begin to understand uh
humor. You see, uh, humor is of divine
origin and, uh, humor
is characteristic to me of liberation
and and and and genuine spiritual
teaching because you can't hold in mind
the the the linear, the nonlinear, and
the various contexts in which it's uh
held without breaking you up. I mean,
it's hysterical.
You see what people think, you see what
people believe, you see what the reality
is. And you realize that life is an
endless practical joke in a way. You
know,
I think the great therapists are Jack
Benny and uh Red Sullivan. Uh who was
the black guy that practically burned
himself up? Huh? Richard.
>> Oh, Richard Prior. We adore all those
people. See, why? Because they knew how
to laugh at themsel. I think Richard
Prior did more for uh you know
decreasing color uh whatever antagonist
there were than anybody because if you
can laugh at yourself, nobody can hold
what you just laughed at yourself about
against you, you know, and prior would
just break you up, you know, just break
you up. Uh you can't listen to prior and
have any prejudice left against black
people. Uh so all the all the great uh
comedians then hold us hold up a mirror
of the human condition for us to see
ourself in that so that we can laugh at
ourself and by laughing at oursel we
forgive ourself and forgive others. We
can see
you know the ambiguity of the human
condition and how we're all prisoners of
it. So through then the heart the same
as the heart of that you hear with bag
pipes which is your oneness with all
humanity the humorist presents us uh
with
with uh what it means to be human so
that we can see oursel in that mirror
and laugh at the faces that we're making
in the mirror you know and that's what
he does so I think the humorous humorist
uh is very spiritually evolved most of
them calibrate you know 480 and up all
the great comedian medians caliber about
480. They're all about 480
which means highly acute. Highly acute,
you know, highly acute. And when you
listen to comedians talk amongst
themselves, they never say that's funny
or laugh at it. They all say that's a
good one.
That's a good one. They recognize the
essence of its power. That's a good one
because they're seeing what that does
reveal about mankind. Well, mankind, you
know, so the humorous. So to
uh bring forth your own capacity for
humor is healing.
See the way to get over being sensitive,
vulnerable, or having your feelings
hurt. The way to get over pride,
defensiveness, and all the paranoia that
goes with that is to sit down and write
down your downside.
Write everything down you can think
about yourself
and then own it.
Now, what can you say about me?
I'm stupid, fat, and ugly. Right.
>> Who is that? That guy at Chicago where
he was a jock jock
shock jock.
>> Manow.
>> Mancow.
>> Mancow. Yeah.
>> Well, when you do go on Mancow's
program, there's Mancow who himself is a
is a troop. And then he's got a couple
of helpers and one of them one of them
is just u sort of dumb and stupid and
that's his role.
He accepts that he's dumb and stupid
and you know he'll come on in the middle
of Mantel making some comment and Mantel
will say man that is dumb and stupid and
he said thank goodness and you know what
I mean.
said this guy who's dumb and stupid by
owning his dumbness and stupidity. It's
not an act. He is that dumb and stupid.
He makes more money than all the people
would laugh at his stupidity.
I'm sure he makes 150 grand enough, you
know. Uh he makes a lot of money from
being stupid. So by owning your downside
then owning your downside and your
limitation you have the capacity to
transcend that sensitive because what
makes us sensitive is the prevalence of
the narcissistic ego. The narcissistic
ego then is the source of our vanity and
it's why do we don't want to admit
anything negative about ourself.
Therefore, I don't like to use pjorative
terms. And my argument with traditional
religion is using pjorative terms for
what is really just the inheritance of
our animal nature. Now that you you've
labeled it sin and and uh
uh made it a porative object of disgrace
and shame and guilt. Now you want people
to own it.
You own it. I don't want to own it.
after he was slathering it all over with
guilt and shame and sin and wickedness
and penance. How many times do I got to
have do the rosary for what I inherited
from my ancestors? I mean, you know what
I mean?
All right. So, uh, where were we? I
wanted to get those things out of the
way. So, we'll go back. We want to
finish the slides. We're going to stop
at I think at 3:00 we'll have chanting.
At 3 o'clock, we'll do have Nico do the
Lotus Sutra in Sanskrit
and then we'll take a break after that.
Then after that we'll uh we'll do
questions and answer and sign things. We
did something at Unity uh that I I'd
like to sort of do if we can but we may
not be able to do it and wander through
the audience uh and for spontaneous
questions but we'll line up and do them
and if we have time we'll do that. All
right. So that's the way the rest of the
thing. All right. So we we're in
transcending the levels of
consciousness. Now I'm taking each
level. The bodest one is shame. What is
the attraction? What keeps people in
shame and is is the attraction of this
and the aversion to this?
The attraction is that it's
self-punitive. Yeah. Uh we just got
through saying we all been programmed by
traditional religion to punish yourself
for this you know the downside of your
animal ego which is called sin.
Therefore there's an aversion to self
forgiveness instead of asking for God's
forgiveness. So the way you overcome it
then is I'm willing to forgive myself
and I surrender my judgment about this
to to God, you know, and God is judgment
is mine, sayith the Lord, not yours.
Because if I give you judgment, you're
going to beat yourself up with it.
That's just what you do.
If I give you judgmentalism, you're
going to use it as a weapon to attack
yourself and others. Therefore, judgment
is mine, said the Lord. Don't you worry
about it. I'll handle it.
You get to feel depressed and punish
yourself. The aversion is to choose life
which would take you out of this. You
like to be judgmental instead of
surrendering to God's mercy.
The negativity, the ego feeds off of it.
You want to shrink and hide and the up.
You don't want to be visible. You see
yourself as worthless.
And the way out of that is to affirm the
gift of life itself.
The shame-based person has a rigid view
of themsself
and refuses to become more flexible,
chooses to condemn themsself rather than
to forgive. The person say, "Well, I
can't forgive myself." The answer to
can't is a loaded gun.
You can't. Oh, yes, I can.
If you don't, I'm going to blow your
brains out. Okay, I forgive myself.
So that the gun to the temple reveals
that it isn't that we can't, but we
don't want to. We won't. Why? Because
the ego gets so much juice. These these
are all positions of the ego. What
propagates the ego is the pleasure it
gets out of all these positions.
All right. The the ego has no source of
energy except the animal life energy. It
doesn't have the condalini energy.
Consequently, it it juices hatred,
juices injustice,
juices all these things because it gets
energy out of them. So this is the
experiencer
uh probe of the beginning of life.
It doesn't get energy condundolini
energy from a divine source. It only
gets animal energy. And how does it get
it? It gets it by juicing every ego
position. Every ego position. Then what
is the person addicted to? You're
addicted to the ego. What about the ego?
You mean to tell me you've got to work
through the whole ego and its whole
evolution throughout history? You're not
going to live that long.
Whatever you're stuck with, what you're
addicted to, you only have one
addiction,
one stuckness, and that is you love the
juice you get out of an ego position.
It isn't that you're juicing shame or
guilt or anger or hatred. You're juicing
the ego's satisfaction.
And therefore the question is am I
willing to give up the satisfaction
that I'm extracting and juicing out of
this physician. One of the hardest one
is being the victim.
Anybody who does therapy knows you got a
chronic victim in the office. Boy, they
are tough. I mean they just love the
injustice collecting and
being the victim. All of us within about
two seconds can think of at least half a
dozen things we are the victim of
being born a human. That's a big
starter, ain't it?
Bunyions, ulcers,
dropsy, weak eyes, got to wear glasses,
nearsighted.
When I if I'll give you the litany of
all I've been through in this lifetime,
I could wallow in self-pity. You know
what I'm saying?
stigmatism, nearsightedness, skinny,
ectomorph, not allowed on the team
because your bones aren't strong enough.
And it goes down from there.
Migraine, headaches, dudal ulcer,
pancreatitis.
Right now I got what? What's the name of
that? Ohas.
>> Huh?
>> Aoperosis. No, no, I got a worse one
than that. Graves disease.
Graves disease. Graves disease. You
know, I went into heart failure and
puffed up all over from heart failure.
Graves disease. I mean, I can't even
remember them all. Deticulitis.
All right.
Judgmentalism, negativity. So, we we
say, "Well, I don't like this." But you
do because your ego juices it because
that's its only source of energy. Here
you people are very rigid. It's very
hard to get people to forgive themsel.
And I like the 12step groups because
what Bill Wilson taught was what's
required about the past is a decent
regret. A decent regret.
>> Yeah. Don't go into an ego display of
wallowing with sackcloth and ashes and
going on your knees all the way to the
cathedral
with the hair shirt flagagillating
yourself and eating dirt and dust in the
meantime.
What is this world? A theater or
something like that?
No. A decent self- regret. How can you
get away with a decent self-regret?
because that which you were at the time
was limited. Therefore, Socrates dictim
is that all men are innocent by a virtue
of the fact. They don't have any choice
except to choose the good. Man can only
choose the good. You don't have an
option.
Hypothetically, you do. But hypothetical
is idiot. Only the idiots believe in
hypothetical. There's no reality of the
hypothetical. You can't live with that.
The real is what you live with.
You can't do anything. You're programmed
to choose what you can perceive to be
the good.
You can't do anything else.
You think the goodest thing is to go to
Everest without carrying oxygen with
you, then die up there because that's
what you believe is the right thing to
do. Karma is karma. You know what I'm
saying?
Want to die up there, die up there. I
don't know. Anyway, we all choose what
we what the option that at the time
appears to be the good. So, we were at
the effect of who or what we were at
that time. The other phrase I like is it
seemed like a good idea at the time.
That's the truth. Seemed like the right
thing to do at the time.
I mean, what else could I do but shoot
him? You know what I mean?
seemed like the right thing to do at the
time.
There was that bank and it had all that
money in it.
That's one of the funniest comments,
right? As they keep robbing banks
because that's where the money is. All
right.
We're attracted to punishing oursel and
others. We're addicted to pain and
suffering because that's how the ego
gets a payoff. It justifies negativity
and we don't want to surrender the
secret pleasure. You see the word secret
people. The reason that they're so tough
to get off it in psychotherapy
is that they don't want to face the
secret. The secret pleasure they being
out of the victim. They juice it for all
it's worth. The biggest competition in
this world is not for success. It's for
victimhood.
The competition for being top victim of
the year is really strong.
All right.
Punish self and others by being
judgmental. And to refuse mercy, you see
because the mercy of God,
God is infinitely compassionate,
infinitely merciful, infinitely
forgiving, infinitely loving. So you
have to deny that to justify and
continue self flagagillation to justify
your negativity.
Here we project our feelings. They are
the cause of what we feel. And that's
the aversion is to take responsibility.
If something hurts your feelings, they
didn't do it. You chose to have your
feelings hurt.
You can say it to somebody else and
their feelings aren't hurt. So how come
yours are? It's your option.
If the word God over the court building
offends you,
should we change the world or should we
change you? Change yourself instead of
the world. So egotism says we have to
change the world. Humility says maybe I
better change how I see that.
Uh choose perception and here you see
the essence. So this is the way a thing
looks. This is how it is. That's the
differentiation between decarts rest
coatons and rest externa. R cognatons
rest interna is the way you see the
world.
Rest externa is the way the world is in
reality. Therefore, what you think you
see is perception. And then there's what
is. Because of the dualistic
construction of the the mind, the mind
is unable to differentiate truth from
both sid falsehood.
We're not to be faulted for it or made
that way. The hardware does not it
cannot choose what software it's going
to get programmed with.
And I think we've I've programmed this
group before. Eminem,
you just got it
within a second. Did you have a chance
to choose? I don't want to be programmed
by that trademark, that image. You had
no choice.
>> You've already got it in your software.
You understand that? You see, the human
mind then is unable to discern
appearance from essence. It's unable to
it's intrinsically innocent. So the
course of miracles teaches
to see the in in the inner innocence
of the self. The holiness of the self is
its intrinsic innocence. That beyond its
being programmed is the innocence of the
hardware. The hardware is the child
within us.
The sound of
Scottish bag pipes coming over the hill.
We talked about before.
It's the heart of the warrior 510.
Something like that.
It makes people weep.
You you watch a hundred
uh scotch
black black guard coming along the bag
pipes and everybody in the audience
8 10,000 people have tears in their
eyes. Why is this? They're not from
Scotland.
Not from sentimentality.
It's because it stirs this profound
love. All right. Why is it necessary to
know this? Because this love
is the love of the child completely
trusting
the innocent child completely and
profoundly trusts his parents. The heart
of the child is innocent.
The heart of the child.
So when you hear the sound of the bag
pipes, you begin to cry because it's the
heart of the child. It's the heart of
the child. its profound trust in
what it envisioned uh true authority
was. You see,
and the way the
messianic
dictator enlists the crowds to follow
him like
over the side of the cliff. Sigh. Sigh.
Is because he knows how to ensnare the
heart of the child.
The weakness of the
citizen is within the citizen is the
trusting heart of the child who trusted
his parents beyond all question
and is now called forth in the name of
their motherland or their fatherland.
the fatherland or the motherland
brings up now the loyalty and innocence
and trustingness of the heart of the
child which is then ravaged by the
dictator
in the name of the fatherland. You march
off and become cannon fodder. They go
over the top. They go over the top into
machine gun fire. As fast as they come
over the top, the bodies fall all over.
This bunch comes up all mowed down. The
next one comes up. Mowed down. Mowed
down. Mowed down. Mowed down. Tens of
millions mowed down. The vulnerability
is the innocence of the heart of the
child. You see that? How it's
manipulated into patriotism. And now for
the fatherland, the motherland, for
chairman Mayo, for Karl Mars, for god
knows what. For the revolution. For the
revolution.
Everybody's got a revolution. Keep your
revolution to yourself.
Substitute evolution for revolution.
Change yourself and not the world. Let
God worry about the world. See, somehow
the world got along without you this
far. And I guess they can continue on
without me.
>> I shifted to a care
>> what
>> I shifted to apathy. Do you care?
>> I can't hear anything.
I don't give a crap about apathy.
This is a dumb subject. I don't want to
even get into this one.
Oh,
I can't anyway. I can't handle this
subject.
Actually, the truth is I won't handle
the subject.
I see myself as victim. See self as a
co-player in life.
Uh apathy is a defeist attitude.
Uh it's lack of taking responsibility.
Why is it a spiritual violation? Sloth.
Sloth is a one of the seven cardinal
sins. Why? Because it's a lack of
respect for the divine gift of life
itself.
If you don't pick up the newspapers on
the sidewalk, it's a negation of your
worth and that of everyone else.
Because
the appropriate action is to have
reverence for life itself, including
your own life.
Uh
apathy ends up is I can't help it. Uh
they're causing it. The the excuse is
outside.
and responsibility. Responsibility
in my own life, I had the opposite
extreme. The worst sin my family's view
was to be spoiled.
I'll tell you, I was not spoiled.
That's the other extreme.
All right. So, the attraction of empathy
is I can't do anything about it. I mean
you know this that and you can think of
all the excuses you see yourself as
victim
uh indifference instead of caring
defeist instead of optimist you
rationalize an excuse because you're
helpless this is helpless and hopeless
which is a denial uh spiritual error
because it negates your self-worth
as a creation as your life is a gift
from God to to see to choose to revere
to respect your life. The life in this
body I respect. I take the medication
for this. I take the medication for that
because this life is a gift and the
purpose is to serve God to the fullest
extent. Yeah.
So you can't here you see yourself as
helpless. Here you begin to see that
you're able and it only comes through a
willingness. So the the only power out
of this situation is is the will
you surrender to God and say dear God I
of myself don't not do not have the
energy or the knowhow
uh to transcend this level now then you
surrender to divine will and then divine
will is what energizes you because you
don't have enough energy coming out of
the ego because the ego is already
getting too much payoff from being
hopeless. us. So this comes out of a
negation of selfworth and this is an
affirmation of your self-worth
to see your life as a gift from God.
Here you see yourself as weak here as
potentially strong.
This is self-sabotaging. This is
self-endorsement
in indolence and sloth. As we say, it's
called one of the one of the seven
cardinal sins because it's a reputation
of the value of the gift of life itself
whose source is divinity. So it's a
negation of the reality of divinity as
its expression as your own life.
All right. So is there another one to
apathy?
Ah the attraction of pessimism,
unworthiness.
Uh
you can justify passivity, self-p pity
and excuse. Sink lower, succumb.
You can see the self. You can see the
indulgence of that. That is an
indulgence. Yes. The aversion then is to
the upside to trust faith and hope to
accept help, compassion, and move on.
There's a a rock band that play that
played a song called Move On.
It's time to let go of that self-pity
and move on. Move on. Get over let's get
over it with the Eagles, I think.
>> Yeah. Let's get over it, man. Like we
heard you lost both legs in your left
ear and now you're blind and in a
wheelchair. So, get over it. Listen,
I've gotten over things that bad, I'll
tell you. And uh you just do you just
get over it. And of course, we have some
great uh people that came from the
pictures of Hollywood uh that have been
the example of that. People paralyzed
from the neck down and they stood for
what can be done with the human will.
Uhhuh. So we picture
you know using Freudian concepts we tend
to become like what we hold in the
so-called ego ideal. The ego ideal is
people that we respect that we look up
to whose value is unquestioned
and we hold up hold them up within
oursel as an image to identify with.
People who are a failure
have a hostility towards success.
You know, they write anti-America,
anti-W Walmart, anti- the court, anti-
the president. Uh
they have a hostility. They don't
understand that the way you become
successful is you become like those who
are successful. If you want to become
successful, you don't revile successful
people. You picture how did they become
that way and pattern yourself in that
way through identification. So all of us
within spiritual work you know held a
spiritual ideal a teacher a spiritual
figure somebody who is inspiring
who speaks to us who we can relate to
uh you know even if it's just the
soldier walking into battle I look at
the guy and I could tell despite terror
by God he's going to do it. I already
got it from the heart. I already got got
it.
And intuitively he gets that I got it.
So all of us who get what the reality of
other people uh is feed back to that
person that reality and it's through you
that the evolution of consciousness
occurs.
When you get
the divinity of the essence of that
which everyone is and you affirm it like
you do in the heart for the warrior, you
know what the warrior is doing as he
walks over the hill into a sure hail of
bullets, you know what the hell you know
damn well what he's doing.
So when you own that in the heart or the
woman screaming her head off before they
had anesthesia for childbirth, half
bleeding to death and her blood pressure
going crazy. When we identify with that,
we strengthen man's way out. So what can
we do for mankind
is own our own reality and acknowledge
it and reverberate it to it in others.
Those who are valorous own their valor
within yourself. Give it strength and
recognition. And in that way all of
humanity becomes valorous. And that's
how we all evolve together.
So, I'll take a break and Nico is going
to do
Nico
uh a rare chance. A rare chance.
The Lotus Sutra chanted in
Sanskrit calibrates over 700. A rare
opportunity to have an adept with us was
capable of doing that.
How about that today?
>> Okay.
All right.
You okay?
without
Foreign
speech. Foreign speech. Foreign speech.
day. Down.
Doing
Fore! Foreign! Foreign!
They go home
me.
So,
Big Deep breath.
Allelujah.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.
Hallelu