soul
here.
Thank you,
>> Robert.
>> Maybe we just have to be closer to the
speaker. Yeah. All right.
>> Oh, hello, David. Um,
>> where did my Kleenex go?
>> Right here.
>> Give me back my Kleenex.
>> You saw her. She took it, didn't she?
>> Go ahead.
>> My question is in the body, can you feel
the truth
uh energetically
in vibration, in the knowing
>> without the testing?
in the body. Can you do what? Feel the
presence with
>> feel the vibration whether it's a yes or
no in the body.
>> Feel that in the body?
>> Uh yes. With with exercise you can
you become practiced at it the same as
anything else.
And um people use other techniques you
know besides the one that we use. The
one we use is because it's easy to
demonstrate.
There's many that you can do by
yourself. Yeah. Mhm.
>> And I wanted
>> I tell you a simple one anybody can do.
I forgot to put it in the book, too. You
pick up a dictionary. See? All right.
I'll put the dictionary about the same
height as you are. See? Use your arms.
All right. Now, I hold Abraham Lincoln
in mind and I lift the dictionary.
Now, I hold Bin Laden in mind and I lift
the dictionary. And you'll see that with
one energy in your mind, you li easily
lift it. With the others, you've become
weaker.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> And I wanted to thank you because
um you've given the intellectual
words to the knowing
>> languaging. Sure.
>> Yes. Mhm.
>> And I've thought I was crazy for so many
years
because I was trying to explain
nonlinear in linear terms and I had
great difficulty and I want to thank you
for the words.
>> That's thank you so much.
>> Hi Dr. Hug.
>> Yes.
Um, in the past you've said that under
level 600, uh, we need a savior.
>> Under 600, what?
>> Under when we're under the level 600
>> that we need a savior.
>> Well,
yes, under 540 you do anyway. Yeah.
>> How should we actualize that in our
lives? Should we
hold a savior in mind or pray to a
savior or um
>> Yes.
>> All the above.
>> If you acknowledge the divinity
of a great avatar, see, and then you
acknowledge uh you acknowledge the
divinity and uh you pray to that
whatever you want to pray to.
You can pray to God directly. Huh?
>> Right. So, in
>> which case your savior will be assigned
to you in heaven.
>> Is that true? Let's see. That's true.
Yeah. I just knew that too. But if you
haven't got anybody, somebody will be
very happy to sponsor you.
And if we get to the level of 540 here
and we die, you've said before that we
come under the wings of our savior.
>> Mhm.
>> And then that elevates us to a level of
600.
>> I didn't say that.
>> So we still reincarnate after that every
not not necessarily. No. uh everything
we've ever gotten is that reincarnation
is an option. Option option
option.
It's a gift,
>> right?
>> And it's an option which if you were
within a certain range karmically,
you may choose that as an option.
Do the 91st Psalm and don't worry about
it. Okay.
Okay, thank you.
>> You can call on Krishna too.
>> Krishna said, "All who call upon me and
acknowledge my divinity are dear to me.
They are mine." Same thing the 91st
Psalm says.
>> What's up?
>> In the book uh truth versus falsehood,
you stated that the brain and and
thinking this is somewhat of a sensory
phenomena.
>> Yeah. The Buddha said the brain is
another six sense.
Western would say there's five senses.
He said that the brain is the sense
organ of the mind.
>> Now, how did in the book you also state
Muhammad had temporal lobe epilepsy
which was a consequence of the fall or
his fall was a consequence of that. How
is that possible? I would think at level
700 that you're kind of beyond that
sensory
>> organ or whatever it is.
>> You ever hear of karma?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> You see, as you evolve, there are
temptations on every level.
>> Temptations on every level.
Power over others. I remember when power
over others came to me.
>> A silent knowingness in a very high
space high passage. In fact, I could see
who'd been through the passage and who
said yes and who said no.
>> Knowing this was now that you've evolved
past karma, personal karma, you're not
answerable.
All power is yours. Own it. That's the
luciferic temptation.
I forgot to warn the class about that.
So, I'm glad you brought it up.
>> But it seems like that it's an
impersonal thing that the temporal lobe
epilepsy is not a conscious choice that
he said I want epilepsy so I could roll
with the sword. I mean
>> I said what happened to him
was I would guess concompetent. Let me
just ask it was conccommatant
not caused by. So you're coming from a
Newtonian thing wasn't caused by.
>> He confused the sword of truth and the
sword of steel.
Jesus Christ made that clear. He said,
"I didn't come to bring peace. I intend
to bring you the sword." The sword of
what? Truth.
For a literal mind, which can't grasp at
that level. It thinks a sword is a steel
sword. So
he gave up the sword of truth and chose
the sword of steel.
And the world has lived by their sword
of steel ever since. a drastic fall. All
right.
The higher you get, the more severely
you're tested
>> because that which holds dominion is
very reluctant to relinquish it.
Many are the gurus who have gone up and
fallen. numerous numerous
because at each level
the knowingness that all power was mine
now own it.
I'd already gone beyond.
>> Mhm.
>> What the world would I want power over
others for being complete in total and
finished you completely all that is?
It would be a drag, wouldn't it?
So something within annoyingness is sort
of laughed at. All power is yours
like it's a it's an external quality
like it's a quality.
Uh the presence is complete and total.
It is the power. So what would you want
power for when you're you're it?
>> Makes sense to me.
>> It's like offering money to the richest
man on earth. I mean, what did you need
it for?
>> That's
good.
>> So, the temptation, the luciferic
temptation, which I'd run into in other
forums by other people. I once wanted to
uh give away a certain spiritual
technique.
>> The teacher I'm talking to who had once
been in the high five 70
uh
I wanted to give it. I said, "Think of
all the monks. Think of all the people
struggling with sin and this technique
would unhook them. I wanted to teach it
around for free. The minute I said for
free, he went into a he went into a
rage.
Total transformation. This man who I'd
known very well for some years. Suddenly
out of him came an energy like the doors
of hell opened.
>> An entity spoke to me through him.
So Jesus Christ and the Buddha are just
a bunch of astrals.
>> Sounds pretty crazy.
>> He fell for it.
>> So is the luciferic temptation always so
obvious or is it obvious at all?
>> Oh, I just told you what it is.
So I mean it seems real blatant when it
comes from doctor but in real not real
when you're walking the path is it
always like since you've explained it
yes I I understand it but is it always
going to be in that form that
>> you heard it from me so you know it now
you know it and now you're karmically
responsible and culpable because you've
heard it. So when you have power over
others and you're an advanced teacher
and they want to throw themselves at you
and do this and that and the other,
>> you know that this is an abuse of power
because you've heard that and many of
the great gurus who have fallen
existent today.
>> Great.
>> Well, I wanted to thank you guys both
you guys. It's a wonderful time to be
alive.
Thanks.
To want power is to negate the reality
of it being intrinsic to your own self
with a capital S. The self is all power.
What would you want it from somebody
else? Yeah.
>> I don't have a question.
I just wanted to come up here.
>> That's infinite
infinite wisdom.
>> Infinite wisdom.
>> Thank you so much.
>> It's my honor. I appreciate it.
>> Maybe I do have a question. Would you
sign my recipe?
>> Sign your
sign a lady's hand the neck of her hand.
She didn't wash it for a month. She said
>> got pretty dirty.
>> She didn't care.
>> Thank you.
>> All right. Thank you, sir. Yes.
>> Mhm.
Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hello.
>> Um, I'm curious about indigo children
and children of the light.
>> Are they Are they taught by Jesus
Christ?
>> Taught? No. I I don't know.
>> By that Buddha?
>> I don't know.
>> By Krishna?
>> No.
>> Why are you asking me?
>> Well,
>> I I teach pathway to enlightenment, not
a diversion syndrome. Oh, it's that's a
diversion.
>> Yes.
>> Oh, okay. Are you selling hugs?
>> Huh?
>> Can I buy a hug for a dollar?
>> No, I'll take your hand for free.
>> Thank you.
>> He had to quit that when his bones got
brittle.
>> He can't give out hugs right now.
>> Yeah, they're stronger than they were.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello.
>> A friend of mine's been using
kinesiology for about 20 years. And a
few months ago, she started getting
really high readings up in the 700s,
once even up in the 900s.
>> And she felt like at the time she felt
like she was in an expanded presence,
but then later she got that um her
spiritual ego was obviously in the way.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah.
>> And
>> that's why I say never calibrate
yourself,
>> right?
>> It's not possible. She was c it what she
also got was that she was influencing
the answers though using other people
through kinesiology. Is that possible?
>> Oh yes a manipulation of others. There's
a guy who will calibrate your every 15
minutes for a couple hundred a month.
>> Good lord.
>> He's on the internet.
So help me God. It says every 15 minutes
for like $250 a month or something. So
when you're in this when you feel like
you're in expanded presence, how do you
and then you're getting these really
high readings? Is that the indicator?
How do you how do you know that you're
not influencing things?
>> First of all, what's the motivation for
the calibration in the first place?
>> Okay.
>> How am I doing? How am I doing? That's
all egotism. So the narcissistic ego
>> out of vanity, pride, and all that is
going to give you a false answer.
>> I tell people, never calibrate yourself.
Who the hell cares what it is? Exactly.
I mean, you know what direction you're
on.
>> All right. You're responsible karmically
for how you set your compass.
>> Okay.
>> That's all you're responsible for.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> That way you avoid error.
>> Okay. Thanks. I appreciate it.
>> Uhhuh.
If in doubt, ask your mother. She'll
tell you,
>> the divine mother. Yeah.
>> The divine mother shows to every mother.
You know, maternal love is of divine
origin.
>> Uh you addressed this before, but either
I didn't get it or I need more help. Um,
sometimes when the spiritual energy gets
really big,
uh, sometimes when the spiritual energy
gets really big, I get afraid, which
tends to shut it down. Uh,
>> how do you know it's spiritual energy
then? Because spiritual energy you're
not afraid of.
>> Well,
>> the ego's energy you're afraid of. The
source of fear is not spirit, it's ego.
>> Okay.
>> Well, there is energy there
>> and then the ego gets afraid.
>> Yeah. Uh,
>> okay.
>> Letting go is a familiar way. It's it's
a fear of letting go of some position.
Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah, it is.
>> What'll happen to you if you let go of
the position?
>> Well, I'm afraid I'm going to die.
>> Okay, that's okay. Go ahead.
>> Yeah.
>> So, what's wrong with dying?
Uh,
>> so what's the big deal?
>> Just missed it. Like
>> Okay.
>> You ever been out of body?
>> No, I never have.
>> Knowingly, anyway.
>> Too bad. Too bad.
>> Yeah.
>> The minute you leave the body,
infinite at homeness.
You think this is at home. It's weird.
The minute you're out of body, you look
at the body laying there and my god, how
could how you could even be attracted to
it? It's a dumb looking thing laying
there. It has no attraction, no value,
no interest.
And if karmically you're supposed to get
back in it reluctantly, bang, you go
back in it. I never heard of anybody
being happy being back in the body
having been out there.
What you would want with the thing is
unbelievable. It's because it has a
linear teaching function.
Your natural state because you've spent
enormous in worldly concepts time
free of a body. The minute you leave,
you're back home.
This you've gotten used to because
you're stuck with it. But
the minute you're out of it
and people fear that
let go and surrender your body to God
and if it keeps walking on great if it
doesn't it doesn't lucky you.
>> Thank you.
>> It's nothing but death you're afraid of
me. Nothing serious.
>> Nothing serious. Just death.
Well,
if it was a reality, I'd tell you to
avoid it at all cost.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Is it correct understanding that
the power of integrity could make up for
almost a lifetime of negativity?
>> Well, you're speaking in linear terms of
causality. Um
the intention. Yes, the intention
because
choice is always before you. And you can
choose this way for 92 years and in one
second change by your intention. Oh God,
I ask
for your help in one second.
How long can you stay in a bad state?
Eternity.
I was in a bad state for eternity.
Forever
with no hope ever of release.
Ever.
Eternity went on through eons.
Out of the eons of hopelessness and
despair,
beyond any possible source of help, a
voice within said, "If there is a God, I
ask him for help.
Then
in a tenth of a second, the depths of
hell,
the doors to the magnificence of the
presence of God as creator,
the source and essence of all of life
shown forth
through all the fuses in the mind which
didn't really speak for about 30 years.
So even after
experientially eternity the option of
choice remains
in my case karmically the option was
still there
at least there was one more
having blown it completely.
So I think anytime that a person chooses
and says dear God I do turn to thee for
guidance and help you and for salvation
instantly
Krishna says all who call upon me are
mine. The 91st psalm says all who
acknowledge my sovereignty I will
protect they will be mine. See so that
promise is freestanding. It's not
positionalized.
You understand what I'm saying?
>> You can choose at any time.
>> So you can be
open to that at any moment. So that
totally changes where we are in the
electromagnetic field over here. You're
over in hell in the dark darkness. You
say, "Oh, dear God, if you exist, I ask
for your help.
Send me to the other side of the
electromagnetic field." Jeez,
what a shock. I'm still recovering.
>> All right.
>> Thank you, Peter.
>> I just wanted to meet you.
>> Yes, indeed. ask.
>> You look like an athlete type. Are you
an athlete?
>> You look streamline like a submarine or
something.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> I did. I was just so excited to be here.
I just wanted to meet you all personally
and thank everybody for being so nice.
>> You that green cut sports sports sports
look. Yeah.
Hi.
>> I've been listening to your radio show,
the monthly radio show. I really enjoy
it. So, I'm uh my first time here. So,
I'm one of those longtime listeners,
first- time callers.
>> Um this is a request about the technique
which uh we've witnessed today and I've
heard you do it in your lectures uh
calibrating
various things. of you calibrated truth
versus soul. So in many movies and
things
and I request if you could calibrate for
me something innocuous like how much
cash I'm carrying or what year I was
born.
>> That's a spiritual question.
>> It was just to gauge the
>> because your intention is incorrect sir.
>> Okay.
>> Your intention is is incorrect.
And uh just the second thing was on
beyond the ordinary you were talking
about
the date of your death is sort of
imprinted when you're born.
>> Yeah.
>> And somebody had asked you about extreme
sports and how they do them and
>> their date of their death is is already
known. And you had said that you could
actually die before your date of your
death.
>> No, I didn't say that.
>> Okay. No, it you see life is a gift of
God. Therefore, to risk it unnecessarily
for the cheap adrenaline kick is
disrespect for
the divinity of your own origin.
>> Yeah. My question actually isn't about
the extreme sports. I don't do that. But
uh
>> is it um
>> well I was looking at it from nonlinear
dynamics, right? Yeah. Let's see.
Because the 26 decimal point, if you
punch your computer enough times, will
come up and it will throw out an answer
that's totally out of the field. Yeah.
>> So, so like for instance, all the Jews
and and the people in Hiroshima and
Nagasaki, were they actually destined to
die?
>> They did, didn't they?
>> Well,
>> I guess they were.
>> So, it was almost inevitable what was
going to happen. Either in Europe there
was going to be a plague or it was
almost like imprinted into the universe
before like 20
>> collective karma. Collective karma.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. So that means when you
>> you look at the history of mankind
and tell me what you think its destiny
is going to be.
>> The barbarian hords came and slaughtered
people slaughtered the innocent which
they do now in Africa instead when they
bring they slaughter the children chop
their arms and legs off. How you going
to undo that karma? Tell me, sir.
>> Chopping the arms and legs off of
children.
>> You're picking raspberries and the
volcano goes off and you die and you're
innocent.
>> Somehow you just happen to camp right
below a volcano and it goes off, right?
>> Okay.
>> So, in essence, sometimes then what I
was thinking is that
well, free will is kind of a funny thing
then because it's almost like uh
>> it's an intellectual concept. It's a
hypothetical.
Like if you're destined to die and like
all those people in Hiroshima Nagasaki
were going to die that day no matter
what. I don't even know a force of
nature that
>> didn't say no matter what
because collective intention could have
changed it.
>> So you could change the date of your
death.
>> Oh yeah. The people collectively
>> okay
>> had acknowledged uh their their debt. So
it's not in
>> the people the people in Pearl Harbor
had not done anything to Japan had they?
>> No.
>> 3,000 you know 2400 innocent people were
blown out all the hell right on a Sunday
morning while they were playing tennis.
That's a karmic debt.
>> So it's not fully set then is what
you're saying.
>> Otherwise there'd be no point to human
existence. If the purpose of this
incarnation is the evolution of
consciousness, the undoing of negative
karma and the occurring of positive
karma, then predestination would make
make this lifetime of no value.
>> So what does it mean then if you
calibrate as your date of your death is
set when and it says true? But that's
not true. You're saying
>> I said the exact timing of your death is
preset. Why? Because if you take a
videotape of a movie and the end the
hero dies, the ending started the movie
but but the end is already innate within
the tape.
>> Okay.
>> I don't want to take up too much time.
>> Your your inlet can conjure up questions
and conundrums by the thousands. But
that's sort of missing the forest for
the trees. You pay too much attention.
>> No, I get what you're saying about the
forest trees, but sometimes, you know,
in your lectures, they come up a lot.
The trees come up a lot. You talk a lot
about the trees.
>> All right. You're a tree person.
I'm a forest person. I like to live in
the forest.
The trees can take care of themselves.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Thanks, Robert.
You ready?
>> Are you ready? Okay.
>> Uh, that was off camera, huh?
>> Go ahead. Yes. Go ahead.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, Dr. Hawkins, uh,
there is no calibrated level of
consciousness in the vegetital kingdom.
Is there in the mineral?
>> I don't know.
>> Yeah,
I guess.
>> Oh, yes. I think the mineral is the
about 200. Yeah.
>> Uh
>> I'm not sure about them. I don't know. I
I'd have to do it some other time.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Then I guess when I've been in nature in
the forest, I've had inspiring
situations and healings,
transformations. So what is that process
if there's no scale of consciousness in
the forest?
I didn't say there's no scale of
consciousness. You just asked me if I
knew what dirt was or chlorophyll. I
never calibrated chlorophyll
>> like the trees and
>> Well, it's not that it's yourself, is it
not?
You're in a peaceful surrounding. So,
you experience the peace of the presence
within and you're distracted from it
during ordinary mentation.
>> No, not infrequently. You're walking
through the
woods thinking of nothing and all of a
sudden time stops.
Time stops and it's just startling the
presentation of the exquisitness of
perfection and all its stunning beauty.
>> It is
>> stunning.
>> So the source is the divine.
>> The perfection of all its the perfection
of all of creation stands forth when the
mind stops.
The radiance,
the perfection of all that stands,
everything exists,
has an innate intrinsic beauty and
perfection. At a certain level, the
stunning exquisite beauty of everything
makes it hard to function in the world.
>> Because you're like close to the tears.
>> Yeah.
Therefore, reverence for existence and
the creator of such perfection shines
forth automatically of its own.
>> You know,
there's a dead tree on my property. You
see, everybody wants to saw it down. Why
do you want to saw it down? Because it's
dead. To their mind, it's dead. The
thing is an absolute perfection. It
would take the greatest sculpture on
earth to create the absolute perfection
and balance. Why would I want to take it
down?
>> Nature will handle it 20, 30, 40 years.
It'll slowly
I don't have to chop it down.
>> No.
>> All right.
>> Thank you.
>> You're the perfection of all exists.
>> We'll hit it perfectly.
Tilt the roof in the right direction.
>> Nice to see you.
>> Hello there.
>> That's a different That's a pragmatic
view.
>> All right.
>> Yes.
>> Dr. Hawkins, my teacher. It's great to
be here again. I was here in February.
>> In May, I had an experience that felt
rather voidlike. And I'm just starting
to have some more sort of happiness and
joy come back in, but I'm pretty darn
confident I'm not in the 800s. So I'm
wondering if there are many voids or
kindergarten voids.
>> She had a very high experience.
>> Yes.
>> And she felt like she was in a void.
>> Right. And so she's asking if uh if
there's, you know, if the void is
one that you would recognize or if
there's other smaller ones.
>> Yeah. Like little little ones because
I'm pretty sure I'm I'm not in the 800s.
I open a door and shut.
>> No, that's true. Yes.
>> Uh interesting on storm stories on the
Weather Channel. Every once in a while
there'll be of a woman who's uh one I'm
thinking of is picked up by in the in
the eye of the the storm.
>> Yeah.
>> Tornado. Yeah. And goes 30 or 40 feet in
the air.
>> And she said and I went into a state of
profound peace.
>> Yeah.
>> Profound peace. Suspended 30 or 40 feet
in the air by a hurricane.
I was uplifted into a state of profound
peace. She just transcended the whole
experience and experienced the presence
of her own self. Is it very interesting?
>> Now, I had no joy or bliss during this
time. It's just starting to come in.
>> I had a sense of just nothingness. I
used I followed my husband around like a
little doggy. And if I sat in a chair,
that's all that's all that mattered. I
just sat in the chair. I could sit in a
chair all day.
>> Yeah. Well, that was a good state. Don't
worry about it.
>> Oh, you know, my ego was in terror. In
fact, I even called out here. I was so
desperate and frightened about it. But
gradually, and I'd have to listen to the
curio to try to find some joy. Um,
everything was just flat. Um, it was
like all the magic was gone. But I was
just observing.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Um, but now it's starting to come back
in again. Yeah.
>> You have to let go to be attached to
that state.
>> That's so nice though.
>> Yeah. Because eventually very profound
states arise
>> and you find that unwittingly you you
you start becoming attached to it and
considering that to be home.
>> That's why the average teacher gets up
to like 720. The big teachers get up to
720 740 like that and then stay there
the rest of their life.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Thank you.
>> Because now you become attached that
becomes home. See?
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> Don't worry about it.
>> All right.
>> It's a good sign. Good sign.
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> That's a good setting. Good woman.
>> Thank you both for the truth. I
experience what you talk about when you
talk about the children or a child's
caricature where everything seems alive.
I walk down the street or I drive down
the street and I see all these branches
and they're in the waves and we're just
having a great time and I'm pulling the
hair back and the flowers and it's uh
it's it's it feels wonderful. Lately,
I've been noticing though that things
like natural things like trees will seem
to me suspended in space like they're
suspended in a kind of viscosity. Um I
look between the branches of the trees
and I look like I have never seen so
much space there. How come I never saw
there was so much space between the
flowers? It's like I'm in a moving ocean
and like they're big seaweed trunks
coming up and I want to swim through
those trunks to the space. It's
beckoning me. Does that make any sense?
>> Yeah, sure.
>> So space beckons you or calls you or
>> Okay.
>> All right. And but I don't feel that
when I look at net it
>> because revelation is is like
invitational. Mhm.
>> It's like an invitational
uh revelation.
>> But I don't have that sense with natural
thing with man-made things. Is that
something that that comes later or never
comes
>> almost 3D?
>> Yeah. When I open the door in the
morning and this is I experience it then
I read about it. I feel
>> you first see it in nature. You first
see it in nature. Yes. You first see it
in nature.
>> Okay.
>> Later on you see the beauty of the trash
can and the but that's later.
>> Okay. All right. Great. Thank you. Thank
you.
>> You're walking down an alley and it
looks like an impressionistic painting
all of a sudden. There it is. The
perfection of the presentation. It's
perfect.
And those are man-made. Mhm.
Trash cans are man-made. Yeah.
By divine inspiration, of course.
>> Is this thing still working?
>> Yeah. kind of it's the
>> what's the single most important quality
needed for total surrender to God?
>> The spiritual will the invocation of the
spiritual will. The person's personal
will will calibrate at the same level as
their level of consciousness.
The invocation of spiritual spiritual
will
the surrender to thee oh lord uh opens
the door to
uh spiritual will which calibrates
around 850. So
the willingness to surrender
um the resistance
for one thing. Yeah.
It can never be disappointed.
Why? Because if you surrendered it to
will your will to God, it makes no
difference whether it occurs or does not
occur.
If you're disappointed, it means you've
not surrendered your will to God.
So disappointment is not possible
because surrendering your will to God
surreners the intentionality by which
you're trying to control the next
discoveries or events in your life.
Completely sterning to God can never
lead to disappointment.
>> Sometimes it feels like it's this close
and sometimes it feels miles away.
you keep well keep wanting to or keep
letting go. Surrendering your will about
it.
You haven't completely surrendered it.
When you completely surrendered it,
whether the body goes on, that's fine.
And if the body doesn't go on, that's
fine.
>> You see what I'm saying?
>> All right. If you surrender your will to
God and then pray to get well.
You just defeated the premise.
You know, either it'll heal or it won't
heal. It won't heal, so you be crippled
and fall over. So,
why should I be disappointed?
Thanks.
Yeah.
>> Library here.
>> Oh, she brought all these her friends
and relatives, cousins. Yes. Speak up
and all.
>> Yes. Okay. Go ahead.
>> Um, yeah,
>> I'm from Wisconsin. I flew here last
night, but I my
>> Where in Wisconsin? I am I live in
Madison?
>> Oh yes. You're the campus.
>> Um actually I work at Mandota Mental
Health.
>> Oh yes.
>> Institute.
>> Very well.
>> And that book and the book you're
signing right now is the CEO of Mandota.
I gave it to him as a gift. And
>> Wisconsin always had the best way of
handling the criminally insane to my
estimation.
>> We do a very good job.
>> Yes.
after. And that's very true.
>> After somebody's killed 14 children in a
row, in Wisconsin, they don't let them
out. They keep them.
>> You got it.
>> That's true.
>> In in Florida, they let him out right
away.
>> That's true, too.
>> No. In Minnesota State Hospital was for
the hopelessly criminally insane, you
know, and I thought it's the only
option that you're forced to take.
You're forced to quarantine people who
are like malignant and can't help
themsel. You know, it's not punitive.
They cannot help themsel.
They can't help themselves.
>> Just like you don't let a
>> tiger in with your rabbits. He can't
help himself. He's going to eat them
rabbits, you know.
>> Uh yeah, pretty quick.
>> And enjoy it.
>> Yeah, that's interesting. So, go ahead.
Yeah. Um, my question is is when I I'm
an artist, too. I work at Modota, but
I'm also an artist and like if I hear
beautiful music or as I was driving
here, all of a sudden I get real teeyed
and I'm like, I got to drive. But I
>> because the surroundings are so
beautiful or I'll paint something.
>> Yes.
>> Which I never think about what I'm
painting. I just paint it and I guess
it's later when you really look at it
and you're like,
>> who did that?
>> I don't remember doing that. You know,
you just it's kind of
just kind of comes out of you and
>> spontaneous creativity. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> It's the muse. The muse
>> and painting is painted by the muse.
Musc the muse.
>> The muse.
>> Look it up.
>> Okay,
that answers that question.
The inspiration, the artistic
inspiration
of creativity
rises out of it. It doesn't arise in a
linear logical way like the left brain
sequencing of logic. It emerges
full-blown almost as you know. Mhm.
>> Yeah.
>> Cool. Well, that that works for me.
>> I'm glad to be here.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
You tell her that you were born.
>> No.
>> Yes.
>> Hi.
>> I really wanted to ask something,
but I'm trying not to be selfish, so I'm
going to ask about the people that I
take care of.
How would you I have two little kids.
How would you
impart the
I went to church when I was little so I
know about God and you know some of this
other stuff wasn't working but it was
okay. So, how do you do that without
ending up with all the guilt and uh
>> how do you do it what
>> how do you raise uh or influence to
small children uh without uh implying
the guilt of the
>> without having to take them to a church
>> per se you know I don't want to take
them to like well you you become don't
forget they're going to imitate their
parents so you become what you want them
to be so when you're considerate for
others they imitated.
And then if they're not considerate of
others, you say you've got to remember
it to be considerate of others. You see,
you teach them to be like yourself.
>> But what about God and divinity and that
sort of stuff?
>> Do they have to know that at age three
already?
>> I don't know.
I've got one that's 10 and one that's
five. My 10-year-old likes to watch your
tapes.
>> Oh, yes. Well, you tell them what you
know about it, what you understand it to
be.
in your own words. You're
>> But I'm not gonna
>> No, then they'll make up their own mind.
>> But I I just don't want to
>> something that I'm supposed to be doing
that I'm not doing. You know, if I don't
take them to church and I don't do that,
am I neglecting them or
>> kids don't come with a manual? You just
>> Well, you know,
>> they just don't come with a man.
>> I know that. Why do you think I'm
asking?
>> That's why I'm asking.
>> Just pray. pray for divine guidance and
>> I just don't want to get into the sin
and the guilt and all that stuff.
>> Yeah, you want to avoid the downside of
traditional religion, right?
>> Yes.
>> All right. So, pick a non-traditional
religion. Pick something more upbeat,
more new age. I mean, no, not new age,
but something like unity or
>> religious science, something that's
upbeat, doesn't you know,
>> instead of emphasizing not love, they
emphasize love. So
you train them through what you are and
you teach them through what you admire
and think would be the best for them.
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> And then I have just one other really
quick question.
I
not lately, but like when you were
talking about the bag pipes, I um I've
been in the mountains at Lake Isabella
in the mist and somebody was playing a
bag pipe and it's a beautiful thing, but
I will just start crying. stuff just
comes out of my face and it's happening
a lot lately.
>> And I had heard I'd watched some of your
videos and you had told this lady she
was saying that she worries and you told
her to really worry cuz she wasn't
worrying hard enough.
>> So should I just cry really hard and set
aside a day or
>> why do you want to stop the crying?
>> I think it it makes my I my family
uncomfortable.
>> Well, there's the crying of joy. Okay.
When I said a tattoo, you know, 10,000
people sat there with tears in their
eyes. It was the tear of joy, a
presentation of the oneness of all of
life as human humanity.
>> It just happens all day.
>> So that's joy. Well, there's you go
through a period where you cry all the
time.
>> Okay. So just
>> I'd sit in an airport and I' a couple
look at each other with a glance of
love. Instantly
the tears of joy would come up. There's
a period which is understood in
monasteries, you know. Sometimes you cry
for a year or two, couple years. Every
all beauty makes you cry. All love makes
you cry. All tenderness makes you cry.
The innocent boy of a puppy can make you
cry. All of that makes you cry.
>> So just go ahead.
>> I wouldn't worry about it. Would you?
>> I'd like to do it, but I just have too
much money. I mean, I don't think it's
really a problem.
>> I just don't want to make the people my
family. Well, your family's going to
think you're weird anyway.
She cries with love. She cries with
tenderness. She
They're going to think you're far out.
>> You're a woman. You can get by with it.
Don't worry.
>> Your family You're seriously spiritual.
I can guarantee your family's going to
think you're losing it.
>> Okay.
>> So, let them think you're losing it.
Yeah.
>> All right. Okay. I have the time now.
Thank you. And thanks. It's so nice to
be here.
>> Thank you.
>> Now, you're you inspire your children by
that which you are. And you take them to
classes and places that emphasize the
upside of spirituality.
>> Yeah.
>> The symphony,
>> new thought. Well, you see the impact
uh uh on children of exposure to beauty
and religious truth is it changes the
neuronal patterning. Their neuronal
patterning is different if you've been
exposed to classical music
and uh religion and truth and beauty.
The neuronal patterning see because the
brain creates more neurons constantly
than it needs. So it's constantly
weeding out what is not used. Uh
therefore
uh the research we did if you're brought
up in a home in which God is respected
and religion or whatever the religion is
and appreciation for aesthetics and
beauty, the chances of criminality drop
by something like 90%. And then if you
add playing chess, it drops another 1%.
Okay.
>> It's hard to listen to classical music,
appreciate beauty of nature, sing in the
choir, play chess, and still commit
crime. It's not hard to, you know, you
just can't do it.
>> Dr. Hawkins, when I was a young man, I
guess 13 or 14, I experienced a period
of intense, profound peace and joy
followed by a short time after. It's
very sad that I was no longer in that
peace and joy. And the impression of
people around me was probably I was
crazy. So I decided to grow up and I
became a psychiatrist of course
and and as a psychiatrist looking back
at myself I was like well it didn't look
like manic depressive illness cuz he was
too peaceful and uh I don't think he was
crazy but I wanted a second opinion. Uh
>> on yourself?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh there is no psychiatric abnormality
that creates peace. There is many.
That's my impression.
>> There's no no psychiatric thing.
>> No, there's an imitation through apathy
indifferency, but they're not really in
peace.
>> No, what you experience was a normal
phenomena. And then
u if you become interested in how it
evolves and make a study of it uh or
pursue any kind of spiritual
pathway, it will most likely recur
periodically too.
That sounds good. I like that kind of
crazy.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> It'll be cur. You're still practicing?
>> Yeah.
>> Uhhuh. Good for you.
>> Yeah. I did it for 50 years.
>> Hi,
>> Dr. Har.
If I my memory is correct, you concluded
last month's lecture with a comment that
enlightenment is now a thousand times
easier
>> Yes.
>> than it used to be.
>> Thousand times more likely.
>> More likely. All right. Could you
elaborate on that a little bit?
>> No.
>> But you stand by it, right?
It's a fact.
It's partly because of the work that we
do that is presented here. It's partly
because of this work. It's never been
defined
with great clarity,
without mystification,
without encumbrance.
See, nobody's ever pulled out what is
the core in the essence with
clarification.
The advancement of consciousness
collectively of mankind is constantly
advancing.
And then you take advanced teachings
with an adv advanced people, their
chances of reaching enlightenment are a
thousand times what they were at one
time. I mean, how many lifetimes do you
think it takes to battle guilt over sin?
And the sin is intrinsic
biochemically, anatomically,
physiologically, and genetically into
the body.
Man, you you're gonna be stuck a long
long time.
How many lifetimes are you stuck?
The average this is it's possible to
answer this. To transcend the limitation
of identification of the elements of the
body usually takes over 500 incarnations
infinite number could take an infinite
number. Could be you never transcend
identification of yourself as an animal.
>> Well, that's
>> I like your earlier comment better.
You're not speaking about you.
An animal doesn't want to transcend. The
very fact that you want to transcend the
limitations of the ego means that that
you're not caught in it because no
animal wants to transcend being what it
is.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Yeah.
No, we we just don't notice the
evolution of consciousness. because it
was at 190 for millennia, then it came
to 205. Now it's 207.
So, you know, already you're you're
boyed up by the collective. You don't
have to plow through the tremendous
negativity that existed before.
You used to get fired for being
integris. Now you get promoted.
>> Thank you.
>> Oh, yeah.
um in reference to uh sorry in reference
to oaths and pledges
>> in reference to what
>> oaths. Oaths
>> oaths and pledges that you make within
an incarnation. Um I have made some uh
karmic oaths uh um
>> spiritual oaths uh yogic oaths to um a
particular practice and organization and
um I guess it's within my best interest
continue karmically in my best interest
for my karma let me put it that way to
continue with these uh practices and um
because I did take these oaths and and
pledges correct just continue with them
I mean even if I no even if I don't want
to I should continue because I
karmically am bound at this point
because I did take the oath and and I
did pledge my um my life to the
practices of this particular yogic path.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So it is within my I should be
doing this. In other words, I should
continue karmically doing
>> I can't give you shoulds or shoulds.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Let's say we have permission
to ask about the her agreement.
We have permission to ask about her
agreement. I don't want to ask what her
agreement is. Her agreement
uh was over 200 resistant.
>> You're not bound by an agreement that
Calvary is less than 200.
>> Thank you.
That's that's a that's a blow, but I'll
accept that. Okay.
>> Let's see. Let's say generically we are
not bound by a commitment to the absence
of truth. Resist. How could you be bound
by commitment to the absence of truth?
>> Okay.
Okay.
>> This is amazing.
>> Therefore, therefore the person would
think I am bound by my commitment uh to
an illusion. Okay. So that would be uh
an error. One is not bound by a
commitment to an illusion. Resist.
>> Okay. If you bind yourself to serve the
Lord God, Jesus Christ, Krishna, etc.,
that which has validity, then you're
you're pretty much stuck.
>> I want to be stuck there. That's that's
that's okay. That kind of stuff's okay.
But a particular uh yogic practice,
you're you're saying, okay, it's not
>> okay. Thank you.
>> That's just my understanding of it. If
it's integrous, then you follow it
through to the best of your ability.
>> Well,
>> now the Now, did the pledge have any
downside to it?
>> No, just practice to the best of your
ability. That's exactly what it says.
>> And that's a very light-hearted thing.
>> The best of my ability. That's what it
>> So five minutes a day is the best of
your ability. That's all.
>> Okay.
>> I'll do it for a minute a day. That's
the best of my ability because I lost
interest in it.
>> All right. Okay. Thank. Yeah. Okay.
>> So, you didn't vow to serve some higher
entity.
>> No.
>> Oh, okay. So, you're in safe.
>> It's it's towards self realization.
Yeah.
>> Okay. I'm not going to worry about it.
I'm going to do it to the best of my
ability.
>> I pledge allegiance to the flag and to
the country.
>> When you join the ilks, you you pledge
to the flag and God,
>> you know.
>> Okay. I'll be fine. Probably illegal
now, but when I joined the Elks, you
pledged your lead to God and flag or
something like that.
>> Yeah, probably illegal nowadays.
>> Hey, thank you, doctor.
>> It was the good will of it all. It's the
goodwill. So, your intention was
goodwill.
>> Yeah.
Dr. H. Dr. Hawkins.
A person who's approaching death with
dementia goes into a coma
>> and lingers for not as long as Terry
Shyo, but let's say lingers for 5 days,
seven days
>> at what point
does the spirit leaves the body? The
moment of death.
>> At what point? At what time does a
spirit or soul leave the body?
>> What at what point does the does the
soul leave the body? If they're in
dementia,
>> it's possible for the soul.
Let's see if I can phrase this
correctly.
>> It's possible for the soul to
vacate the body prior to the death of
the physicality. Resist. Yes.
I knew a very famous man
who was dying of um I forget what all
lacks lack oxygen to the brain see and
he would sort of lapse into sleepy semi
coma and he would go over on the other
side and visit various heavens and
realms then come back and be awake or so
for a day or so then he sort of laps out
and go back. So when I got I saw him,
he'd say, you know, my father has many
mansions
and I visited a number of them.
Like he's trying to decide where he
wants to go when he leaves eventually.
Kiologic research
>> that pulls it off. I have to put it
>> uh is that there's multiple heavens.
That's why any any dominion, any
denomination that claims exclusivity to
heaven, you know, suffers from on the
one end megalamania, but on the other
because they're not aware of the
reality. The reality is that there's
multiple heavens. So if you believe that
you have to do this in order to go to
heaven, when you leave the physicality,
you gravitate to that which you are. So
they have like a dimension of that
energy field which is limited to them.
You got to have 13 wives and 32 children
in order to get there. See and and to
get to this heaven you got to be
celibate and as you have six you don't
get into this heaven. So
there's various strata. Let's see if
what I'm saying is correct. What I'm
saying is correct. Okay.
So without knowing it, they're telling
the truth. When they say
you have to abide by us to get to
heaven, it means that they are the sole
pipeline to that area of heaven. See
what I'm saying?
>> All right. You don't have 13 wives and
62 children. You don't get to the seven
because this is the pipeline to the
heaven.
But heaven with a capital H, they are
not in control of. So, anybody who says
they have control of your access to
heaven with a capital H.
>> No, no, it's not that. It's it's
basically my stepmother is in a coma
right now.
>> Yes.
>> And it's causing great constrnation to
my father.
>> Yes. What does he want to do?
>> Uh he
you know when he is in her presence two
days ago it
>> he was in her presence all day and she
was predicted to die at 8:00 in the
morning.
>> Yeah. It's 4 days later and she's still
hanging on and it's very painful for
him. This is the love of his life.
>> Yes.
>> It's exceptionally painful for him to
see her in the final stages.
>> Well, does he want to just let her want
want to let her go?
>> Yeah, she he does. He wanted her. Oh,
the plug's been pulled.
>> All right. She signed the thing for it
and he signed the thing for it. Pull the
plug. Let her go.
>> But his my question is is where does her
soul reside at the present time? Oh, I
think
>> which you answered it still with a B.
>> She's gone over already. Oh, intuitively
that got I have permission to ask this.
She's gone over already. Oh, she's gone
over a long time ago.
>> Okay.
>> The family's always worrying about
person with Alzheimer's. You know, they
aren't even there anymore.
>> Exactly.
>> I see all all the all the psychiatric
referrals in the whole county all the
way from Prescott to through Cottonwood
and Cambia. I must have seen a thousand
of them. 10 nursing homes. So the
family's wa waing wa and poor mama she's
got Alzheimer's and the whole routine
and you know I go and see her and her
mother I say how are you Elizabeth? Oh
fine. I said how are they treating you
here? Fine. How's the food? Okay.
What day is it today? Oh I don't know.
How would I know a thing like that? How
old are you, Granny? Oh come on. on a
woman who's going to tell you her age.
You know what you're saying?
Is she suffering? No.
>> Okay.
>> The suffering is in the witness.
>> Always.
>> Oh, Granny can't remember anything
anymore. So,
so much the better. The less you
remember is the better it is. Don't you
think?
I remember I saw my grandmother in 99,
you know, in a nursing home in 99. And
uh and I went to see her. She's pushing
along with one of these things, you
know, and uh and I'm telling her,
"Granny, granny this and that and and uh
I'm a what? How did it come about?" I
said, "Uh, you recognize me? I'm a
doctor." And uh she said, "Oh, I've got
a grandson. He's a psychiatrist in New
York."
I said, "Granny, granny, it's me." Oh.
And then she started to cry. Granted
video
but my feeling is that they uh you go
over the spirit is already leaving see
and you just have the self which is like
a simple child within it has no
complaints you talk to any real
Alzheimer's patient now there's agitated
Alzheimer's and various things like that
but they have another disorder that's
causing the agitation not the
Alzheimer's
then we go shriek and holler and carry
on but That's not the Alzheimer's
itself. See, so anyway, it's one of
those things of a personal choice. You
know, how long he wants to just be to
vigil. You know, his his job is to be a
vigil at the moment.
That's one of the things you when you
get married, you commit to that.
He's he's being the witness in the vigil
for her. And her spirit knows that, too.
But he's there for her. Thank you very
much.
>> She knows it.
>> I'm watching.
>> You ask me open-ended questions. That's
>> Yes.
>> I was wondering if you could help me
with something. It might not seem too
spiritual, but um um I have a habit that
I'd like to change, and it seems really
difficult. I'm basically kind of a
messy, chaotic person.
>> Sort of a what?
>> Messy and chaotic.
>> Messy, chaotic.
>> Yeah. And I'd like to be more tidy.
>> Why do you want to be tidy?
>> Well, I think I have this idea that it's
more beautiful and more functional
>> pragmatic,
>> right? And that it's more spiritual
like, you know, cleanliness.
>> Wired that way. I don't know.
>> But are there any enlightened people
that would be like slobs?
I'm just wondering because you think
cleanliness is close to godliness. You
hear this all the time all your life and
I go, "Oh,
>> oh, it may just be the way you are
neur neurologically and energetically
and
it being precise and all that was worth
it, you'd be doing it. So obviously it's
not worth it.
>> It's something nice. You think you
really would like to be able to ought to
be like that."
>> Yeah.
>> But as a fact you aren't.
I've noticed I try so hard and I, you
know, I'm like I get embarrassed. People
come over and some people are, you know,
fine.
>> Well, yeah.
>> And they go, "Oh my god."
>> You tell them, "Look, I'm a mess pot. I
just grew up that way." And me potism,
that's all.
>> We like you from who they are. Don't
worry about it.
There is maybe an attention deficit
disorder subtly operated.
>> There is a medication that does overcome
that ADD attention deficit disorder
is responsive to there's a new
non-impetamine kind of
>> strea
yeah that so you could have a mild ADD
attention deficit disorder in which the
way you track stuff neurologically
And sometimes something like uh what he
mentioned or coffee uh will increase
that neuronal capacity. It's a neural I
think it's probably neuronal more than
anything.
>> Coffee.
>> Well, caffeine any kind of stimulant. Uh
strata is a new non it's you not a
narcotic or a stimulant
strate. But I think you could have adult
ADD which is
mild neurological impairment.
It's like some people cross letters. You
know, when I want to write four, I write
R. For many years,
>> I go to write a four and I write an R.
So, you know,
>> as long as I'm not figuring out people's
income tax, it works.
>> You could give just a clinical trial,
see if it helps or it doesn't help
though. But
>> helps fine. But doesn't you live with
it?
>> Okay. Well, thank you for so much.
>> You have to give a brain surgery to cure
it. That's all.
>> Doing brain surgery. Yeah.
Can't leave your scalpels and crap in
there.
Let the heist in your skull. Yeah. Yeah.
Hi.
>> Can you calibrate a spiritual
organization that I'm part of called the
Avatar Course and Harry Palmer?
>> I don't think we ever did that one.
Uh
I don't know. I'd have to think about
it. Uh it seems to me we did it one
time.
>> Yeah.
>> It isn't that is that the followup to
EST? No, the follow is called something
else. the avatars where you this much
money and you get a and this much money
and you get this much money.
>> I have a question about that.
>> Well, it's called avatar.
>> Yes. The
>> you know what an avatar is
>> someone who is awake.
>> No.
>> In the world.
>> An avatar is the founder of the world's
great religions. Krishna, Jesus Christ,
Buddha, Zuraster.
So what is it they they could be
teaching you?
>> Well, um
>> how to be a avatar
be like the savior club. I mean the
Jesus Christ miracle club sort of. I
mean you know what I'm saying? You're
getting the point of uh
>> Yeah. I guess
>> exaggeration of it.
>> It's helped me a great deal.
>> Huh.
>> It's helped the course has helped me a
great deal.
>> Yeah. It's a very good course in a way.
Mhm. Um I just feel conflicted because
it's helped me a great deal in terms of
you know personal responsibility and
looking at belief systems and everything
like that but I they charge a lot like a
large sum of money and so I feel
conflicted.
>> Well we taught the basic principles of
spiritual integrity today then it's up
to you decide.
>> I'll teach it to you for nothing.
What do you want to know?
It's free. Ask
>> what?
>> I don't know. I guess should I continue
with this?
>> Oh, that's a different thing. You see,
we're all evolving. We're all learning.
And we check out all kinds of things,
especially early in the spiritual game.
You know, we go and get a psychic
reading. We get tea leaves. We throw the
ruins, you know, we do divination and
holy smoke and all kinds of crap.
We wonder speakers on the other side
who've been alive for 5,000 years and
they tell you be kind to your
grandmother. Okay, I don't need to pay
$25 to be kind to my grandmother, you
know.
No, you follow it to its karmic uh
fulfillment. All of them have something
good. I'll tell you why they work.
Because when you pay money for it,
something that I tell you now for free,
you'll do because you spent the whole
weekend doing it. The value most of
those limited trainings
is not that they're telling you
something. I can flip any book,
spiritual book in any library and flip
you the same thing on a page. Says right
there, now if you pay $500 to spend the
weekend doing it over and over, the only
difference is now you're going to do it.
you before you heard it. I heard that
being kind to everyone and gracious to
everyone and goodwill etc. You heard
that. All right. If you spend the whole
weekend workshop doing that, then you're
going to get the momentum to do it. So,
I think the value of those training
workshops is that you it gets you to do
what you would otherwise say, well, I
know that, but you won't do it.
Here's a group enthusiasm. So when you
leave the training for the weekend,
you're high on being kind to old ladies
or whatever it is. See,
and now you're in the practice of being
kind to old ladies. See,
you knew that your whole lifetime. You
just never did it. So I think the value
of a workshop is it gets you to actually
get off your butt and do it.
Therefore, it's very, very serviceable.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Serviceable.
Hello.
>> Uhoh. Uh
>> oh. Right.
I've I've been trying to do what you
said and I've made some attempts to
um surrender every thought and every
image as it comes up. Um but I'm not
able to really function very well as I'm
doing that. Um I can maybe stand up a
little bit, but I kind of like
Frankenstein. I kind of lobomize when
I'm when I'm trying to do that. I can't
really do anything. Um when you were
doing that were you able to function in
the physical world very well doing that?
You say you were doing like a 24 hours a
day. What level of functionality did you
have?
>> Well, you start out practicing it during
the meditative state. Then when you get
up from the meditation, you sort of
continue the process
uh at a slightly diminished level you
might say as you go about. You find from
with experiment how much you can be into
the field and not into the content of
the field and still focus. There comes a
certain point where you have to
sacrifice the content and that's the
world. So you walk away from the world.
You just walk away like
>> and and you you did that for 24 hours a
day for a pretty long period of time
before you transition.
>> Contemplative or meditative?
>> Contemplative.
>> Contemplative was a way of life
uh that came out of various spiritual
experiences. Yes. Mhm.
It became a way of life.
I've learned to relate on a onetoone
basis now.
But the other goes on continuously
doesn't interrupt it. There's a period
where to come into the world interrupts
the other state. Now the other state is
continuous
even though you function in the world.
See
in the beginning no it isn't that way to
function in the world takes you out of
the state
>> and rather than leave the state you
leave the world
then over some years is the capacity
that one doesn't leave that state
one can be in a hard argument you
haven't really left that state it's just
the persona participating in the
worldliness you know but it's not who
you are
you
not what you're going to sign up for.
You know, in the middle of an argument,
you know, somebody say, "Are you willing
to stand up for being right?" The answer
is no. Frankly, no.
It's irrelevant. But the other person's
going to feel rejected if you say it's
irrelevant.
So, participation then is
depending on where you are. Mhm.
Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> I'm not saying you should walk away from
the world. I was saying what I did.
>> Mhm.
U I have these roommates that I've been
uh I've been living with them for about
three and a half
>> I have these roommates that I've been
living with for about three and a half
years and they belong to a spiritual
organization. They're very dedicated to
it. And in the book, Truth Versus
Falsehood, it calibrates at 195.
And I was just uh I was just wondering
if is there danger? And I mean, these
are people I'm exposed to to this
organization quite often. Is there is
there any danger in living with these
people,
>> people who get committed to these
things, you know, I figure it's their
thing.
I'm not going to buy into it, and I
don't want to interfere with with my
life.
Uh, if they insist I buy into it, I'd
leave them. But I mean, whatever they
want to do, you know, if they belong to
the Kos clan on weekends, but I don't
want to do it during the week. You know
what I'm saying?
>> Is there anything I can do to help?
>> Uh, they don't need your help.
>> Is is the organization subject to any
kind of change in calibration to go down
or
>> rise? I don't know. How I mean, how does
their participation in whatever they're
into affect your life?
>> Uh, well, it seems to get into a lot of
political areas,
they're they're foreigners from from
another country, and it's not a country
that is free or has any political
freedom, and there's a lot of political
strife.
>> Well, why do you want to live with them?
>> Well, they seem okay. I mean they they
see
>> I don't know why you're asking me then
>> well I mean the person what they what
they're for what is is is not good but
but
>> what they're for is is evil they seem
>> and you're living with them huh you want
my advice you know what my advice is
don't you
>> they seem like nice people I mean
>> yeah they're all nice people Ben L's a
nice person too
I you know some of the most evil peace
in the are charming.
In fact, they're exquisitly charming.
In fact, that's where they reside.
Exquisitely charming.
That's the tongue of the outer, is it
not? Exquisitly charming.
The fact that they're charming is why
I'd be scared of them.
Now your intuition is telling you
something's s about it
>> or you wouldn't be asking
>> yeah your intuition is telling you no
you be with them for a certain period of
time then you yourself will be evolving
in a certain way and it either works to
stay in tandem with them or not
you know people want to have fun and rob
banks I'll go along with them for a
while
but then one of them kills a teller I
just parted company with
I'm one to rob a bank for money but not
hurt somebody, you know. I mean, there's
a limit. See? So, you just decide how
far you can go along with it.
>> Yeah. It would make me uncomfortable,
too. Yeah.
>> Thanks.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> The fact that it's a question shows that
he knows the answer already.
>> Yeah.
Hi.
>> Hey. Hi.
>> I have a question about a book, Doc.
I think I'm on.
>> It's called The Disappearance of the
Universe. I believe you calibrated this,
but I
>> am not sure of that. And I want to
>> 255 somewhere. It's around 250. Yeah.
>> Okay. That's what I wanted to find out.
Um,
>> is it a new way to salvation,
deliverance?
>> It's what?
>> Well, it claims to explain the course in
miracles.
>> Oh, okay.
>> My course miracles calibrates at 600.
So, it's explanation at 250 doesn't
impress me too much.
>> Exactly. Yeah. Exactly. That was my
thought.
>> It's like the Da Vinci code or
something, you know. I mean, it's Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> And now they come out with Da Vinci non
code.
>> Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
>> Okay. Anyway, it's an interesting thing.
>> It's an interesting thing. But
>> probably had some visitor from elsewhere
that told them all this. Huh?
>> Uh, some friends gave me this book and
>> No, no. What the book is about?
>> The book?
>> Yeah.
>> I didn't hear you.
>> I'm sorry.
>> Visitors.
>> Yes. Yes. It's It's uh two visitors from
somewhere else explaining the course in
miracles to the writer.
>> Yeah. Well, who needs the explanation?
>> Uh, oh, go ahead. Go ahead. I don't get
the intention of the book, but that's
all right. Okay.
>> Um, my
>> uh thought about the intention of the
book is to dilute the course in
miracles.
>> My experience with the course is it
doesn't need explanation.
>> No, these things are all
>> they're all ripoffs.
>> That's these things are ripoffs. See,
once you do the the Da Vinci Code, then
there's about eight eight different
takeoffs. They all have the Da Vinci
Code in the title. See, so this is a
takeoff on the course of miracles. Okay.
>> Okay. This man wrote this book from a
from a book business aspect. He went to
seven different publishers across the
world. He infiltrated this ima
to get that book out there. I mean, it
came out in our publishers weekly all
about him. It was a commercial
>> endeavor on this man's part to put the
book out there and he did a massive
commercial. It was
>> it was, you know, massive.
>> I wasn't aware of that thing.
>> Yeah. No, because you're not in the book
business. We are. I hear that. So the if
if the book explained the course of
miracles calibrated at 700 be
interesting
>> but because it calibrates at 250 I would
say you know it's somebody trying to
play off it.
>> Yeah.
>> And even if it's correct I don't believe
it.
>> All right. Thank you very much. Mhm. You
see that that's another you know
entities.
See the course of miracles was was by
inner knowingness in interdictation
because I knew her
the same as Alice Bailey. See
>> interdictation is one thing. Visiting
entities is something else of a
different dimension.
>> Different dimension.
>> A different dimension. Entities. I went
I've gone all the way from the very
ultra pits of hell to the most advanced
stage you can do in a body. And there
was never an any other along the way.
Never an other.
>> Never.
>> Never a visitor, never a vision, never a
floating spirit, never a teacher going
woo woo woo.
There was a knowingness
that flowed flowed
um from within.
>> Always from within though.
>> Yes. When the temptation came to me, all
power is yours. You now you know that
you're beyond all tempt all all karmic
consequence.
All power is yours. It came forth as an
inner knowingness. See, because what
you've done is you've hit a certain
level of consciousness, and that's the
temptation of its opposite.
Jesus Christ sweat blood over that one.
>> Yeah.
>> The Buddha felt like his bones were
broken.
>> Of course, I haven't hit that from
around 800 and up. I'm watching it. You
get all kinds of physical complaints,
which I didn't tell the audience about.
But at about 750, you know, 750 is
comfortable. about 800 you start getting
all kinds of agonizing pains and you you
know your aura is like burning.
What this means is that due to spiritual
purification you've pulled up something
from the unconscious in some lifetime or
from 800 and up you're clearing the
collective karma. I needed from 800 and
up you're clearing the collective. All
right. So you've pulled up from the
archetype.
You've pulled up from the Yungian. What
did Jung call it? The universal
consciousness. The
>> collective.
>> Yeah.
>> Collective.
>> Collective and right.
>> Unqu. So to a certain level, you're
pulling a personal karma, but you're not
going to find the answer looking through
self-examination of why you're feeling
so awful right now. See, because you've
just pulled up something from the
collective unconscious.
>> Yeah. I told you the worst thing I had
was the spleen of the spiritual warrior
in writing truth versus falsehood. See,
because I hadn't paid much attention to
the world for many years. Now I got to
go back into the world, re-examine the
world, and I went to some kind of
indignant shock. See?
>> Mhm.
>> I can't believe this when I hear the
things that are said in public
television bleeding lies to calibrate,
you know, it's 70 and it's like this,
you know, and and the spiritual warrior
would come up with indignation.
>> Yeah.
>> Which created guilt about judgmentalism.
So I had to pray intensely about all
that and clarify it and transcend it.
That wasn't mine. That wasn't mine
personally.
>> No,
>> I personally have never had any interest
in politics personally.
>> Yeah. Well,
>> yeah. I mean, I've cheered every
president, whoever it is, you know.
>> Why? Because he's president of the
United States. You know, FDR raises
Nixon.
>> He's president of the United States.
That's good enough for me.
>> Yeah, understand.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> So, we'll have to hustle through now at
the end.
>> We got enough time. We got It's good to
see you again.
>> Good to see you. What's the temperature
back home? Did you say
>> 112?
>> Yeah. 115 114 this whole week
>> for 10 days.
>> Oh boy.
>> Hello.
>> Um well, I had a lot of silly questions
when I started out here. Now I just
would like to just um say um I guess cuz
I was so obsessed in the sense with
politics as uh a keen interest and I
just want to thank you for um rekindling
my interest in uh making spirituality my
passion instead of uh this uh strange
world that I was in before. So, I just
like to thank you.
>> Hi.
>> I wanted to get your advice on how one
should go about dealing with an
alcoholic in one's life.
>> Join Elan.
>> I'm sorry.
>> You just join Elanon.
>> Elanon's for people that have a family
member in
It's my business partner and it's really
affecting our company and our people and
uh I try not to interfere and I've
really given that up but at the same
time I see our employees falling into
traps and being unhappy.
>> So what what options do you have?
>> I could walk away.
>> Yes.
>> Um or I could force him to walk away.
And again I don't want to interfere.
>> And what?
>> But again I don't want to interfere.
>> Force him to walk away.
Yes.
>> Well, I don't know. I'd have to know the
legal uh financial tiein. You know, when
you say he's a partner, I mean, you
know, you may not have so many options.
That's I'm going to ask you what legally
what's the option? You know, morally you
got any kind of an option. You can walk
away or kick them out either way, right?
Most people if they have a problem with
alcohol close to them in their life or
go to Elanon which is a 12step group for
people that are in a fix like you you
know because this way you can move
you're going to have guilt this way
you're going to move you're going to
have fear this way you're going to have
anxiety
>> so I would go to Elan him
>> so you go to Ellen you go to Ellen
yeah
>> no I didn't say Helen gone I said Ellen
It may be helpable, may not be helpable.
Then there's ways of raising a person's
bottom
and what your obligation is there.
Mhm.
You know, everybody in the company has
noticed that you got a developing
alcohol problem. You you're probably the
last one to know it. We really ought
think that you ought to really be aware
of that. That everybody's pretty aware
of it. Yeah, nobody minds if you have an
alcohol problem as long as you're taking
responsibility and doing something for
it. But you're not going to drink away
our company and my and my partnership
and everything else and destroy
everybody's life while you have a very
good time.
>> I mean, you got to be frank and honest,
digress.
>> Yes.
>> Well, thank you.
>> Alan is helpful because it gives you
like a group reinforcement and clarifies
the okayess of whatever choice you have
to make. because you're going to be
forced into a choice because alcoholism
is progressive. It's going to get worse
rather than better.
>> Thank you.
>> Before he wipes you out into bankruptcy,
it'd be good to do something,
>> but that could be your karma.
>> You're bad.
>> I know he's got a real problem. I'm
trying to lighten his heart. Lighten a
little bit. I just wanted to thank you
guys from the bottom of my heart and uh
which is verbally inexplicable.
And um my beautiful mother came from
Minnesota this last week. We spent four
days together and we made a nice batch
of banana bread and um um a friend and I
had some last night and he approved of
it and uh
>> this in Minnesota.
>> Well, actually we made it out here. We
made it out here. So
>> Oh. Oh. But um but the recipe was
>> soda bread
>> is actually so fun to give this to you
guys.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Wow. Thanks a lot.
>> That Irish soda bread.
>> Thank you.
>> No, it's banana bread.
>> Actually, it's kind of my own
concoction, but it's been it's been
tested and it's uh I like it.
>> It's kind of my little thing that I
make. So,
>> thank you very much.
>> Cool. Thanks. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
>> We got a third ship fast. Anybody left?
Yeah, we have.
>> Run, run, run, run, rabbit, run,
chicken, run.
>> I went through the wall over there a
minute ago.
>> I was exploring
mystery spaces there. Um, my question is
the void you spoke of that you came out
of at three years old. You were aware
that you were in a void.
>> Yes.
When you're in the void, do you realize
there's a way out
>> or is it
>> There is no thought in the void.
>> There's no thought at all. So, it just
you just suddenly something comes to you
that makes you figure way out of it.
>> I guess I don't understand it.
>> You bite into this and you say, "No, not
that's not it."
>> If you what?
>> Excuse me. I missed.
>> You shouldn't get what you said.
>> As stunning as it is,
there's something.
If you've heard somebody speak as I
spoke today,
you'll intuitively know that it's
lacking something.
As incredible as it is, and you can stay
there for eons.
The knowingness that there's something
beyond it would only be if the
vibrational frequency of that
knowingness is in your aura. And then it
will make known to you that there is yet
something beyond this.
>> See, because
1,00 is not voidness or nothingness.
1,000 is allness. In fact, it's beyond
allness. Allness is only 950 or
something like that. 1,00
is allness. oneness, universality,
infinite love and divinity.
It's the realization that is divinity
that hits a thousand.
>> Okay?
>> I can remember the amazing
revelation that what you're witnessing
is divinity
making known to you its divinity.
Once you own the divinity of the
infinite state, that is 1,00.
To see allness, everythingness,
beingness, and infinity is about 950 or
something like that. No, 1,000 is when
you see the divinity, the radiance of
almighty God as creator shining forth in
all that exists.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> The radiance is unmistakable.
the the void has the uh the magnificence
of infinity and nothingness, but it
doesn't have the radiance of the
presence of divinity.
>> So, you're not aware
>> as infinite love.
>> Mhm.
>> So, you're not aware that you're missing
anything. You think that's it.
>> You're not thinking in the void.
>> It's a knowingness that comes about as a
consequence of the field of having heard
otherwise.
>> Okay?
>> Otherwise, you'll think it's the it's
the end state.
Thank you.
>> You'll remember it.
>> Pardon me.
>> It'll be remembered for you.
>> Okay.
>> Because you heard it.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Okay. We have four more.
>> I think
he has some.
>> Okay. I don't know if this is a question
or a statement, but um
I remember uh I was born to uh ministers
and u what
>> born to ministers
uh pastor a pastor of a church.
>> Oh yeah, I did.
>> So as a kid obviously you're always
asked what you're going to ask when you
go to heaven and meet the Christ.
>> Uh and there's an inner realization of
of the inner teacher outside now. And
this makes this question so important to
me. Um
I have a friend of mine that we he's
here today. He's he's he's going to ask
a question next. But uh we we have been
together uh through many realizations
including at one point uh going through
a a moment where the idea of sin
completely vanished and uh like a light
hid and it felt like everything became
clear, concepts became apparent,
everything seemed to spark out of its
own. No no no thought required. and uh
we have done the course of miracles on
our own and then we'll go into these
conversations where it's almost like our
thoughts go back and forth back and
forth and all of a sudden it's like I
only have sound effects like and then
you're there and then we just stare at
each other and I was wondering if you
can expand on the idea of a friend and
that significance in the journey what
does if there's any relationship to what
what happens why why is that together
why is that connection to that person so
strong.
>> Okay. And why is the connection to
>> they're handling spiritual um they're
having spiritual u experiences together.
>> We're in the same mindset at the same
time.
>> So
>> back and forth. And he's asking why is
there such a spiritual connection as
well?
>> Because you're both doing the course of
miracles.
>> But it goes in levels like together like
Ramana Maharshi teachings all of a
sudden becomes apparent to both of us.
Is there something that happens between
>> two people? I mean, is there something
that you can tell me more about that?
>> Well, you probably have a catalytic
effect on each other. That's all
positive catalytic effect, you know.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> A good thing. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> A spiritual compound.
Mhm.
>> Um
the question I have is I hear you
speaking of um your experience
of divinity, your experience of allness
and all these different states and my
question is simply
who experiences it? If
it isn't an experience, it's a
condition. It's a state.
There's nobody there that witnesses it
or experiences that it it's because it
is selfulgant. It is of its own complete
and total. So there's no
person who becomes enlightened. What
happens is that which was is removed and
replaced by something by a condition. So
I call this state a condition. a
condition that replaces ordinary
thinkingness of a you know a dualistic
this and a that.
There's no this and that.
It can't be language because language
itself is dualistic with a subject and a
predicate and a verb.
Because is isness is the closest.
That which is is complete by virtue of
its own existence. It requires no
adjectives, no verbs, no
it's not describable in sentence because
in a sentence there's a subject and a
predicate.
That which is total and complete within
itself
is not really explicable.
This is just ways of of explaining what
the mind experiences.
>> So is it is I mean when you is it just
you're what you're telling me is that
because of language is just that's just
the best explanation verbalization that
could be done. It's just that's not the
actual
>> Well, if you bite into a piece of
chocolate, you can't really describe
that to another person.
can't be described.
>> Has to be experienced.
>> It's experiential and purely subjective.
Yes.
But it's very
uh stunningly apparent.
It's not subtle or mysterious. It's very
It very much is what it is.
So it removes all doubt.
You'd have to leave the truth of that
which you are to ask what you are. Not
possible to get an answer
because to ask the question, you've
already negated the truth. You
understand? It's secularity.
>> What do you want me to do? Isn't that
something?
>> Just sign the cover. Maybe
>> I didn't know where these came from.
Suddenly they appeared.
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins,
>> good looking guy on the front there,
dude.
Is he a Hollywood star?
>> Yeah. What?
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins, for one who deals with
children and even some young adults who
enjoy violent movies and video games
that both calibrate very low, how does
one help wean these people away from
those influences or at least lessen
their negative impact?
you try the best you can to keep them
away from it. All all current research
shows that exposure to violence creates
violence.
Um the latest research I show was out of
psychiatric news. I think that uh the
mere witnessing of violence
uh potentiates violence and the reason
oh yes the reason is the mind of the
child cannot differentiate fantasy from
reality. So if a child sees a fantasy of
violence in a cartoon, that's the same
as if he witnessed it in real life. His
brain does not differentiate fantasy
from fact.
Mhm. The way to have a violent kid is to
put him in front of the TV set and
brainwash him for the first five years
of his life. I can guarantee you where
he's going to go. Then then when he gets
beyond that, you get him a video game
called Killer Too. You know,
you track down women and shoot them
right before you shoot them, take their
money, then kill them. They got video
games that program you
pavlovian conditioning. Kill, kill,
kill, kill, kill, break, break, break,
kill, kill, kill. Thousands and
thousands of times you do that all while
your brain neurons are connecting with
each other. Thousands and thousands and
tens of thousands of times.
Jesus Christ. And then you say, "What's
the cause of violence in the children?"
Bad parenting, give me a break.
Bad parenting is that they didn't fry
the TV set and get it out of the house.
No, that's the latest research that the
exposure to violence, the child's mind
cannot differentiate real violence from
fantasy violence. Doesn't know the
difference between cartoon murder and
real murder.
And the more it witnesses violence, the
more it becomes violent,
which of course would make sense
naturally. You become that which you
witness
witness cruelty, you become cruelty.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> That's the Liz research, you know, just
about a week ago.
>> Yep. We're done.
>> No,
>> that's Liz research about a week ago. So
the
I'll be quick if I'm the last one.
>> It's a 10 part question. No, it's just
one question.
>> Just wonder if you if you can elaborate
on how free will or choice meshes with
this predetermined destiny that you've
talked about.
>> I didn't say predestination
and I didn't say predestination.
>> I said destiny.
>> You don't have a predestiny. You have
karmic propensity within which you have
choice. That's the purpose of human
incarnation is the jaws to have choice.
If there weren't any choice, there'd be
no point. You'd be wasting your time.
You might as well commit suicide and get
over.
Get back to reality. Floating through
space. You know where you belong.
Now what I said that the exact timing of
your exit is preset.
That's the only thing. The rest is not
preset. The timing of your death is
preset at the moment you're born, but
not the means that you have the option.
You can drink yourself to death. You can
throw yourself off a roof.
Mhm. The Grand Canyon is a favorite sort
place to exit. When one year nine people
fell over, I mean, is that wow wow wow?
Nine people fell over the edge of the
Grand Canyon. I mean, that what's the
karma of that?
It's like going up to 14,000 ft with no
oxygen. Huh?
So to reverence
one's life as a gift from God means that
you then become
um responsible for it. What do you call
responsible for your gifts? Uh the the
whatchamacalls.
>> The steward.
>> The steward. Yes. You become the steward
of the gift. And the gift of life itself
is to
reverence life in all of its expression,
including your own. And out of gratitude
for your own existence, you know, you
treat it with respect.
Therefore,
seeing how close you can get to death
for the thrill of it is not integrous.
And it calibrates below 200. thing
because to tempt to to play with the
flame is eventually you get singed. Uh
it shows a disrespect for the value and
sanctity of life. See if you did that
with a rabbit you'd say that guy's some
c cruel so and you know and yet it's
okay to do it with yourself. Why is it
okay to do with yourself with your life?
with what you would not do with your own
dog.
What I put send my dog up to 16,000 ft
with no oxygen. No way.
No way. I have more respect for life,
you know, for your own life. The
sanctity of life. Reinforce the sanctity
of life because that way you reflect the
sanctity of of life back to itself. And
life is aware when it's recognized. When
the divinity in life is recognized, it
radiates back the knowingness of the
recognition of the divinity of its the
source of its existence
because creation is ongoing at all
times. The presence of God within form
is nonlinear but present
exist. So divinity exists with all
within all that exists but in a
nonlinear form.
It's not the nonlinear within the linear
that gives the linear a sense of
reality.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> There we are.
All present are God's gift to me. Thank
you Lord for these wonderful people.
Amen.
They're they're God's gift to me.
And where could you ever come across
name that wonderful?
>> We got banana breadlu.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
Halle
Hallelujah.
Hallelu