So this has an impact.
So people below 200 are unable to do kinesiology or do it correctly for one primary, one main reason.
Forget about ideomotor impulses and all the rest of that.
It has to do with your brain physiology.
The brain's physiology completely changes at 200.
Up to 200, you're run by the animal brain.
We've done this in previous lectures, and it's in the books, and the current book, and the next book, too, probably, for recall.
But below 200, then, the animal is experiential.
And when life emerged in this planet, animal life has no means of energy.
It has to obtain energy.
Chlorophyll came in first.
Chlorophyll was here for billions of years,
out of which arose the oxygen in the atmosphere.
Carbon dioxide, it eats the carbon, gives the oxygen back.
The animals came along, and they needed the oxygen.
What a nice balance.
The animals, plants, you're eating carbon out of the CO2.
And the animals come along, and they got some oxygen.
The thing is, the earliest life, the bacteria, have no source of energy inside of them.
They don't have a backpack.
Nobody packed their mother, the mother didn't pack them any lunch.
So they're on their own to forage and get, or forage and get.
So the experience of life.
The answer is always aligned with foraging and getting.
It's always foraging out there.
Looking at everybody, watching the TV, checking out the blog sites, reading the headlines,
watching everybody's expression, looking for sales and bargains.
Memorial Day, what is this, Memorial Day?
Labor Day, oh.
Stay off the road, folks, stay off the road.
More people die, you know, on the Labor Day or Memorial Day.
Drunken drivers, more drunken drivers die.
You know, in one holiday, than all the people who died in the Iraqi War.
One holiday kills more people than all the soldiers in the Iraqi War.
Just do the alcohol on the highway.
How to not get killed.
So the aspect then of the ego, the experiencer, has to always forage and sample everything.
It has to see, is this edible?
Can I eat this?
Is this poisonous?
So protoplasm learns early to recoil from that which is an animal.
From that which is inimical to life.
That which is inimical to life makes your arm go weak.
When she looked at it, I don't know what happened to it.
The poison particles, she went weak.
Protoplasm, it's innate to life.
Animal life knows what will kill it and it stays away up to a certain level.
So that's the job of the experiencer is survival.
It has to get energy out there.
It has to get chemicals.
It's got to get energy.
So the experiencer is out to get and juice all of life to survive.
That's where it gets its energy.
The ego gets its energy out of being right.
There he is.
The little bacteria of the ego now is satisfied and that will feed him for a long time.
I mean, one nasty blog site will keep you going for years probably.
Look at all the fun and controversy.
You get to put your picture on there and all.
It's funny, very funny.
Anyway, that's the nature of the ego then, is acquisitive.
Information, emotional feeding.
This is the mechanism of the brain then.
So the animal brain then is, you see, the input.
There's the input out there and then it relays to the thalamus.
Very fast.
Very fast to the emotional center.
Give me that.
And then the hippocampus, the memory remembers, boy, that was good stuff.
Going back to that place, they got the best cheeseburgers.
And then the slow part is through the prefrontal cortex.
So when man emerged then, man emerged.
Let's see.
It was just on the History Channel the other night.
That's where I get my education.
Three and a half million years ago or was it three and a half billion?
Million or billion, don't make any difference.
Million, billion, one of those numbers.
Arose, what was her name?
Lucy.
Lucy is the oldest living humanoid.
So off comes the hominid.
And, of course, the celebration was getting up on hind legs.
This left two that you don't need for walking.
Uh-oh.
So now these two can feed the ego, the experiencer as probes and information gatherer.
And then with the emergence of the thumb, you're able to handle tools.
So you've got curiosity, learning, and tool capacity.
The emergence of the thumb.
So life then emerges.
And if you calibrate the level of consciousness of all of life as we did throughout the archeologic ages,
then you see that life got up to about level 90.
And by the time of the birth of the Buddha, it was up to about 100 at the time of birth of Christ.
Slowly rose over the centuries to 190 where it stayed until the late 80s.
Suddenly jumped to 205, now 207.
So now 207.
So this is the way the brain handles things.
And you notice it's slow through the cerebral cortex.
So when the cortex was added, it was added onto the old animal brain.
So now, below 200, intelligence is used to serve the animal instincts.
How to kill you better, how to get even, how to make more money, how to raid your bank account,
how to make, they call you for your bank number because you just won money or something,
and then raid it out.
Clever.
So that, the thing is this cortex came in like this.
They came in late in the game and they didn't remove the animal and replace it with the cortex.
They put it on the front of the animal and now you've got a really dangerous animal.
An animal that can really think, man, you're in trouble.
Nuclear bombs and God knows what all.
Now, interesting here, you see, is the fast relay is to the emotion.
Screw you.
This morning was Bush hates blacks.
The reason they're having this problem is because Bush hates blacks.
Yeah, right.
Who do you appoint Secretary of State, idiot?
Oh, never mind.
Don't think, see.
This is slow because the person reacts with anger, grabs the nearest tools he can to throw at somebody like a monkey.
He just grabs anything, throws the ammunition.
Because this, see, this is slow to the cortex, slow.
Afterwards, he gets home and he thinks that wasn't such a smart thing to say.
Maybe on TV or anything.
Maybe that wasn't the smartest.
And you see the kids pushing these baskets and they're smiling at the camera.
Yeah, then the police are going to find out who they are, yeah.
So, so quick angry and blow up and so late smart.
So quick to emotionally react.
And then later.
Later think.
Okay.
Over 200 now.
You see the fast track is to the cerebral cortex.
And it's delayed to the emotion.
So you think first before you react.
See?
Yeah, the most important thing that happens at 200 is the emergence of the Kundalini energy.
The spiritual energy now flows for the first time.
Also, we just learned recently.
Outside the opening of the third eye of the Buddhic body.
It was a very high spiritual.
You know, you have to be up 700 or something.
No, it says the third eye of discernment begins opening at level 200.
Don't have to wait until you're a Buddha to discern appearance from essence.
So at level 200 now, you're beginning to relinquish the ego gain enough to get a sense of reality.
So we call that a sense of reality.
A sense of reality.
The fast track is now to the cerebral cortex.
Then to the emotions.
And then you have the emergence here of the etheric brain.
So at 200, the Kundalini energy now shifts your whole brain physiology from left brain to right brain.
The emergence of this particular energy is the so-called Kundalini energy.
And it's accompanied by the emergence of the etheric brain.
The etheric brain.
Not a physical brain.
An etheric brain.
So the etheric brain doesn't emerge.
We have permission to ask this in front of this audience.
The etheric brain emerges at level 200.
It's all energy.
Not protoplasm.
It's not within the linear Newtonian paradigm.
The etheric brain is pure energy.
It's an energy system.
But it's not protoplasm.
It's not physical.
It's the emergence of the etheric body.
And, of course, importantly, spiritually, the soul of the etheric brain.
Okay?
Very, very important.
And, of course, here we see below 200, we see all the different physiology.
We were saying, you know, aside from kinesiology, you can calibrate things by many other things.
Because here, below 200, you have left brain dominance.
Your world is linear.
And you're subject to stress and address.
You're subject to stress and adrenaline.
And it's fight or flight.
Fight or flight.
Alarm, resistance, exhaustion.
And you see a depression of the thymus, decrease of killer cells, less immunity.
Less immunity.
So what could all the people do down there in Gulfport or wherever that is?
They all ought to do the thymic thump.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
That'll instantly take you out of this world.
This whole energy system.
So it creates thymic stress, which has to do with balancing your acupuncture system.
It has to do with immunity.
People who are stressed out are more vulnerable to disease.
So the prediction of an epidemic is increased by the likelihood.
Because these people are stressed out.
I'm sure they're stressed out.
And they probably all go weak.
Disrupts your acupuncture meridians.
Yeah.
And brings in disease.
Negative kinesiologic response.
So the differentiation here is one of brain physiology.
The kinesiologic response then has to do with brain dominance.
Also, this decreases the neurotransmitters, such as serotonin.
And very major difference from right brain dominance, which is nonlinear.
See, this is aligned with the linear experiential.
Ego.
The experiencer of the ego.
This is aligned with the spirit.
Right brain dominance is nonlinear.
It's aligned with context.
So when you go into a contemplative lifestyle, you're shifting over to this side of your brain.
You don't want to have to come to a judgment about everybody I pass on the street.
Do I?
An emotional reaction.
An aversion.
An attraction.
Whatever.
I witness them as humanity passing by.
See?
I witness them.
And I pick up the energy of that stream of people.
All right.
So you can remain in peaceful equanimity, which releases endorphins.
Endorphins then are pleasurable.
Positive emotions.
They support the thymus.
Increases the killer cells out there.
They're the good guys that knock off the bacteria.
You have greater immunity.
So a person in a high state and a person in a low state can walk through the same contaminated
water.
One will get an infection and die, and the other will have diarrhea for two or three
days.
Yes, you really have greater immunity.
Greater immunity.
Don't drink the water.
If you do, pray.
Pray a lot.
Greater immunity.
Healing.
Balanced acupuncture system.
Positive kinesiologic response.
So this is pro-life.
This is pro-life.
And her arm will go strong.
The other thing that this blogger did was, you know, accuses me of calibrating these
things.
You'll notice I don't calibrate anything.
I've never calibrated anything.
She doesn't.
They're blaming the wrong culprit.
If anybody should be hung.
So anyway.
Thank you.
different classes with other styles of demonstration. It emerges of its own. Neither I nor she calibrates
anything. That would be a pomposity. That would be owning yourself as the cause. It's
a pomposity. I think there's a you doing a that. There's neither a me nor a her. There's
the phenomena emerging out of the propensity that in a class like this, with a subject
like this, those would be the conditions that would increase the likelihood of the
emergence of intelligence. Intelligence. I believe in intelligent design. It comes to
certain things and then I call it stupid design. The atheists have a cop out there with intelligent
design and they're not taking it. They're trying to turn it down. They turn it down
because they think it's the leading edge of theology trying to creep into the science
class. I thought, here these guys have got a nice cop out. They can satisfy both sides
but they don't want peace. Why? Because they get too much gain from conflict. Why should
anybody want peace? Palestine, Israel, anything. Peace is the last thing those people want
because then they have to shut up and be nobody. Unless you're really retarded, you can hardly
fail to see the intelligence throughout the animal kingdom and evolution, etc.
In fact, it's the most stunning thing. Before you start worrying about being spiritual,
start watching the Discovery Channel, the History Channel, because if you do nothing
but witness deep-sea life, it's incredible ingenuity. It's incredible intelligence. It
makes electricity, flashes little lights, pretends to be other things. It's incredibly
creative. If you don't witness the progressive intelligence of life, then you shouldn't be
writing denunciations of anything.
You should go back to school. Start over. Incredible intelligence of all of life. It's
incredible ingenuity. Some of it comically funny. A little bobbing of a little light
in there and 2,000 feet down there, it's got a little light bobbing like this to attract
people. It reads things by electricity. The shark reads you by electricity. Because every
time you move your muscle, you create electricity. The shark reads that. It reads things by electricity.
The shark reads you by electricity. Because every time you move your muscle, you create
electricity. The shark reads that.
So we could use a shark for kinesiology. In other words, you understand there's many
ways to pick up energy fuels. I'm sure we could train a porpoise in no time to differentiate
truth from falsehood.
Okay, next. Oh, dear heavens to me. Here I was going to tell him the secret of the universe.
I knew it on the way here. I can't remember what the hell it was. I had it written down
someplace. This is the secret of the universe. I knew it on the way here. I can't remember
what the hell it was. I had it written down someplace. This is the secret of the universe.
So I tried to read it out loud to feel it as intense as you can. The expression of the
universe is where the hell's the second page?
Serenity says, at this point, do the serenity prayer. Anybody here know the serenity prayer?
How many know the serenity prayer? Yeah. Who knows it? Can somebody say it for us.
Go ahead. Change the things I can. Curious to change the things I can. The wisdom, the
own difference.
Grant me this right to accept the things I cannot change.
If you're in the middle of a disaster,
the courage is to change the things I can.
I can make efforts.
And the wisdom to know the difference.
So you're really praying for the capacity
to see the difference between appearance and essence.
Because once I see the essence, I'm at peace.
How to differentiate.
So God grant me the wisdom to discern the difference
between appearance and essence
is what that prayer is about.
Of course, that's the great prayer of the 12-step movement.
And I forget the origin of that prayer.
But it's used in AA all the time.
And of course, AA demonstrates these principles.
There is no such thing as a justified resentment
in 12-step groups.
You want to understand how fast people get spiritual reality?
I'll tell you how fast it is.
In 12-step groups, you either follow it or you die.
It's amazing how fast you get it.
It's responsible to say to a guy,
look, you want to give up the resentment
and you want to go out and drink it.
You got your choice.
You want to forgive the guy or not.
I'm not giving him a son of a bitch.
He doesn't deserve it.
So the basic principle, there are no justified resentments.
In other words, you got to be willing to surrender
the juice you're getting out of it.
So the first principle in 12-step groups
is to surrender your life to God as you understand him.
Surrender your life.
You have a higher power as you understand him.
And then out of that humility,
you're willing to surrender the juice
you're getting out of the resentment.
And of course, they have a gun to their head.
Otherwise, you die.
Resentments kill more recovering alcoholics
than anything else.
Resentments kill more recovering alkies
You got your choice.
Surrender it to God or croak.
And it's a slow death, slow death.
So, all right.
We've covered sort of some of the basics
which may have sounded a little bit off
from what we were usually talking about.
But I think you have to stay current
with what's happening.
And I also want to demonstrate.
Spirituality means to stand up for truth.
It doesn't mean to passively lie down
and allow yourself to become a victim
and think that you're being pious and holy with all that.
Piety and holiness means also to stand for the truth.
And because truth is also strength,
strength and commitment.
So, I'm going to start with that.
So, when you commit to the truth,
then you stand for the truth.
It's up to your wisdom how and when to express it.
But nevertheless, we stand for that which we believe in.
Otherwise, we are people without principles.
Without principles, one is weak and an easy knockover.
So, the value of mores and principles,
spiritual principles, religious principles,
logic, reason, is it gives you strength to your character.
And in times of great stress, that's when you're going to need that character.
When you need it, it's there because it's habitual, you know.
Of course, some people grew up in very fortunate environments
where commitment to the truth is a very strong principle.
In the world I grew up in, lying was probably the worst of all.
Nobody thought of murder or anything like that.
So, the ordinary person, lying was the most grievous thing.
You'd rather die than lie.
Besides, it would put a spot on your soul that God could see.
I mean, spots on your soul.
So, anyway, the world I grew up in, as I say, was somewhat politicized.
But it's true.
I grew up with a respect for truth and alignment with truth.
And that is the basis of integrity.
So.
Serenity comes out of the certainty that you come.
There's a certainty that comes from the knowingness of your alignment
and the absoluteness of that alignment.
That gives you a strength and a power and a courage to stand up against anything.
And with that, you can walk into the bullets.
And when you walk into the bullets, you go all the way to the top.
So, now we will reconvene at what time?
Two, right?
Thank you so much.
Okay, we're all assembled.
We're going to start.
This year, we gave monthly lectures, you know.
Next year, we thought we'd cut it down to half a day every other month.
And we're going to devote it primarily just to discussion, question and answer.
We presented all the didactic material.
I'll probably start it with, you know, commentary on what's current or coming up or something.
But I thought we're going to spend more traditional, what do they call it, satsang, right?
Where you sit with the group.
And you discuss questions and answers.
And I liked it when we wandered through the audience and chatted with people more or less informally.
But that depends on whether Robert can work it out or not.
So, does that meet with approval?
That's what you get for asking a question.
Yeah, we'll see what we can do about it.
We thought we'd leave it up to the group.
But I thought we want to spend more time with spontaneous, spontaneous clarification, spontaneous question and answer.
You know, personal response, you know, you're stuck in this and how do I get off of it?
I'm not seeing something.
So, we work together, sort of.
And when I've done that, it's been sort of fun, you know, sort of more informal.
And less didactic.
But I leave it up to everybody, you know, the vote.
I go with the vote, however it is.
We'll email you.
So?
What did you say?
We'll email you.
Huh?
Oh, yes.
Put it on your blog site.
Blog.
Got to be said correctly.
Blog site.
Now I've got a blog site.
Oh, big time.
Okay.
Let's return to the activity of the day.
Uh-huh.
Is that where we ended?
I don't remember if we ended there.
No, we wanted to do, we did brain function, right?
Did we do consciousness and rate of...
Did we do consciousness and rate of happiness?
I don't know where we are.
Oh, we did brain function.
Okay.
We'll do societal problems.
Then I think we'll...
Then we'll skip the maps of the world, and we'll skip to 33, consciousness and rate of happiness.
Is that okay?
23, 24, then we'll skip to 33.
Okay.
We intend to put all the charts together from all the lectures and all the books and put it together and make it available in sort of an oversized books.
You know, a lot of people like the charts.
So we'd have a chart on this side and an explanation on this side, which would be sort of...
Because it's hard to see everything on the board and comprehend it, and to have it all together would be sort of fun, nice.
All right.
So this is just to reflect that happiness is an intrinsic quality, not dependent on anything out there.
And you see the level of consciousness, and we correlate this with social problems.
Oh, happiness is another chart.
We correlate this...
We correlate this with social problems.
You see the rate of unemployment at the bottom here.
50 is usually the federal prison population.
Unemployment is 97%.
Rate of poverty is 65%.
That's because they're good thieves.
Otherwise, it would be...
Rate of happiness, however, is zero.
Zero.
Rate of criminality, 98%.
It's pretty much a criminal level of mentality.
Where you shoot at the people.
People coming to rescue you, you know?
Here's a helicopter coming to rescue you, and you shoot at it.
I mean, that's...
All right.
Rate of unemployment, as you go higher, is still 75%.
Poverty is 40%.
Happiness is 2%.
Rate of criminality drops from 98% to 91%.
91%.
Then, 100 to 200, you see the rate of unemployment is still 50%.
And then, you see the rate of unemployment is still 50%.
Poverty is about a quarter.
Happiness is still relatively rare, only 15%.
And 50% are still into criminality.
If the cop is not looking, they'll cop it.
Okay.
Then, 200 to 300, you're coming up...
The rate of unemployment suddenly drops to only 8%.
You know?
Wow.
So, this is a big jump right here.
Oh, that's because you went over 200.
Yeah, there should be a line here denoting.
So, below 200, unemployment is 50%.
Over 200, unemployment is only 8%.
So, again, you see 200 is the level that demarcates a profound difference
in brain physiology, brain psychology, happiness, employment, criminality.
Very critical level.
200 to 300, unemployment is only 8% now.
Poverty is down to 1.5%.
Happiness, at least 40% of people think they're happy.
And criminality drops to 99%, yeah?
Now, we're here, we get to the 300s, which is good natured enthusiasm, and unemployment
is 7%.
And they're probably on unemployment checks.
Rate of poverty is only 1%.
Happiness, at least 50% are happy already.
And only 5% are still into criminality.
Now, here we go.
We hit the level of the intellect, the 400s.
This is the level of science, medicine, technology, college education.
2% unemployment.
Poverty, 0.5, very rare.
Happiness, the majority, 70%.
Criminality drops to 2%.
I don't know what they're up to.
I should get some of these folks in.
What are you up to?
Maybe that's Enron or something.
I don't know what the 2% is doing.
I guess caught up in greed, right?
Then at 500, you see, this is the linear domain of the, the linear domain.
This is where we shift brain physiology.
And now we, now the basic reality is non-linear.
500 and up is the energy field of love and the spiritual reality.
You see, the rate of unemployment is 0%, 0, 0.
The rate of poverty, 0.
Happiness, 98%.
0.
98%.
Criminality, 0.5.
I don't know who they are.
All right.
So, then at 600, you see, these are all 0.
Happiness is, of course, 100%.
And criminality is not even a thinkable option, not even thinkable.
You don't need laws to control people because they wouldn't even think of it in the first
place.
I mean, to kill somebody for their money wouldn't even be, you know, kind of a thought,
an option.
Move to the next, huh?
You can see the necessity for law from 200 down because you see what happens with anarchy.
This is Chomsky's, Chomsky, Noam Chomsky is an anarchist, you know, atheist anarchist.
So we have here a Chomsky demonstration of anarchy.
How anybody could rationalize that?
Yeah.
You could rationally choose anarchy, we have it in the Gulf Coast right now.
That's what anarchy looks like, is the people at the bottom are let loose, predatory.
So anarchy is really not Shangri-La.
Somebody wrote me, how come I didn't lump Chomsky in with the Dalai Lama?
Because he's for peace.
Yeah.
Oh, God.
So anyway, an atheist, all right, rate of happiness.
So here we have it again, no, the other way, yes, here we have it again.
At these various levels, you see, guilt, it blocked 30, four, only 4%, probably because
they're in denial or something, and so you see the correlation is not with wealth, fame,
any worldly gain.
Good looks, it's about 100% aligned completely with level of consciousness.
See because relativism or social relativism is that there's something out there causing
a this, and as we see from the calibrated levels of consciousness, there's no is that
causing a this.
There's this being what it is.
Yeah.
It acts to itself as a consequence of that which it is.
So projecting causality externally, of course, is the difficulty with Marxism, a perpetrator
victim than the evil capitalist, et cetera, and the evil government, the evil law, the
evil law and order.
But we see what happens when you remove it.
What happens when you remove those things is pathetic indeed, they're pathetic indeed.
Pathetic indeed.
They shoot down.
The rebel government is coming to rescue them.
So, all right.
Let's move on.
So much for anarchy.
Anybody here still an enthusiast for anarchy, a Chomsky fan?
I don't want to offend any Chomsky fans, but they should leave.
The audience, immediately.
Oh yeah.
So why do people get stuck in these positionalities?
This is generally the dualities of attraction and aversion.
To be, to, nonattachment.
Attachment means to let go all attachments, all attractions, and all aversions.
You're neither attracted to it, nor do you have an aversion to it.
You know, if you die, you die.
So, you're not attracted to it, neither do you resist it.
Whatever will be, will be.
So, the Beatles had a song, Let It Be, right?
Let It Be.
I calibrated that once.
It was very high, I forget.
The stones responded to that with Let It Bleed.
People ask me, because the stones, I calibrated at different levels in different places.
Well, I was at Woodstock, you know, and it was, yeah, I was at Woodstock.
All the mud and the rain, and the only food got in was a big trickle watermelon.
And there was the LSD Rescue Squad.
And I was a member of the LSD Rescue Squad.
So, somebody freaked out.
We talked them down and stuffed them with vitamin B3 to try and offset it, you know, rather than tranquilizers, et cetera.
And the only person I really saw very upset was the old lady who lived there.
I got there.
Frank Yeager's farm, you know.
And I got there a day early and parked across the street.
And the next morning, we got up.
The trees were full of people, hippies.
And all of a sudden, I got up.
All over her porch, there were hippies on the ground, hippies hanging in the trees.
Tied blankets from one branch to another, and there was a hippie.
Well, I was rescuing people.
So, the lady panicked.
So, I went over to talk to her.
And I told her, these were peace people.
It's peaceniks.
The weekend was love, music, and peace.
Well, that wouldn't attract 450,000 people.
I don't know what would.
Plus, whoever, you know, the bands they had.
So, I...
I told the lady, these are, they're all here for peace.
They're all for peace.
And she felt a little better.
So, I had to reassure her a couple of times over the weekend.
But I was the only one that had fresh water.
She gave me water in return.
Everybody else drank water that had so much chlorine in it, it would really gag you.
I mean, it was chlorine.
And I thought, well, I'll go back to Max Yeager's farm next year.
Because it's going to be watermelons for miles.
Watermelons for miles.
Watermelon seeds everywhere to go.
Then, after that Altamont, there was the East Village Other.
It was an avant-garde newspaper, a great paper.
East Village Other had great art in it.
And it was very intuitive.
What the East Village Other talked about would surface in society a couple of months later.
Just like song lyrics will pick up a trend before it surfaces in the daily news, you know.
And I remember the advertisement.
They advertised Altamont, and around the advertising were bullets.
Uh-oh.
Now, in the early days, the Fillmore East or something, people smoked grass, and they'd sit around and went home, and were very peaceful.
But then, slowly, we saw a change.
People began to get drunk.
And alcohol is a whole different energy than smoking pot.
It's impossible to get violent on pot, but it's easy to get violent on alcohol.
So, when I saw Altamont, the bullets, plus the appearance now of Altamont,
and the appearance now of alcohol at rock concerts, I said, I don't think I'm going to go.
Didn't go.
And of course, that's where he sang Sympathy for the Devil, and they murdered the motorcycle guys who were protective at Woodstock,
and now killed the guy right in front of the stage.
So, at that time, the Stones, Let It Bleed, Sympathy for the Devil, and Murder, you know, their energy was down.
And I forget what it calibrated, blow 200.
Then, they came out of that.
And we're in it.
Yeah.
We're in the 300s, because they've got a great rapport with their audience, you know.
And the group hung together with a group commitment to each other.
The Beatles all went off on their own hook, you know.
They were more intellectual, et cetera.
But the Stones hung out as a group.
So, I think the Stones more currently calibrated over 300 or 350 or something, which is enthusiasm.
And they sure got a lot of enthusiasm, you know.
So, a thing may calibrate differently depending on difference.
You know what I'm saying?
If you're worshiping the devil and getting murdered in front of the, while the music
goes on, that's going to sort of bring your calibration down a little.
Yeah, Let It Be is surrendering it to God, you know.
It's pretty much like the first step in the 12-step groups.
Let It Be means to surrender to as it is.
Yeah.
Let's go.
Next one.
So.
Well, it keeps the attention.
Yeah.
Well, the attractions and the aversions going then.
This experiencer cutting edge of the ego, which is our inheritance from the animal evolution
of life on this planet, essential to life, but no longer necessary, and a deterrent to
spiritual evolution.
But what keeps us stuck then in the domain of the ego, which spiritual people struggle
with to overcome?
First of all, the one attraction is we cling to it because it's easy.
And it's familiar.
And you've got to change, and change is going to take effort.
So you decide, I'm not going to curse anymore.
I'm not going to curse anymore.
But you've got to remember that takes effort, you know.
I want to try to be kindly instead of greedy.
Well, getting the best of the deal gets to be a habit.
There's certain cultures, especially in New York, where if you don't get the best of the
deal, you're ashamed to come home.
Yeah.
Even Steven means you just lost out, you know.
I gave him a fair deal.
Oh, that's the best you could do?
So we cling to the familiar.
You can see that.
First of all, it's easy.
It doesn't take effort.
Also, we have pride.
Everybody secretly thinks that their view of the world is correct.
And to change would require humility.
Humility is a challenge to the narcissistic core of the ego.
The last thing we need to do is to change.
The last thing the ego wants to hear about is humility.
And it, because it holds its position, the narcissistic ego is subject to humiliation.
So the ego confuses humility and humiliation.
That which is humble is immune to humiliation.
I'm fat, ugly, and stupid, so?
And a bullhunk besides.
What can you say?
And I flunked out of grade school.
Yep.
That's it.
I flunked out of grade school.
And I'm lazy.
I sure am, man.
I don't move unless I got it.
I mean, what can you say to a guy like that?
Nothing.
You know what I'm saying?
And as I noted, the black comedians, my favorite was the guy who...
Richard Pryor.
Huh?
Pryor, yeah.
I've mentioned him before.
I mean, he took the wind out of anti-colored prejudice.
He just took the wind out of it, you know?
I mean, what could you say after what he said about it?
He just took the stereotype.
And, you know, turned it into shreds.
You felt like an idiot, you know, jumping for an old stereotype when he just destroyed
it altogether.
So what you accept about yourself makes you immune.
And if you're sensitive or your feelings get hurt, you sit down and write out all the worst
things you can think about yourself and own it and feel that that's just fine.
Once you feel it's just fine, then you stop worrying about it.
So letting go of pride, then.
Anger, the confusion of anger with strength.
See the animal puffs up with anger, the gorilla pounces his thing, birds swell, to try and
intimidate, which works in the jungle.
What is the...
The mouse meets the elephant and the elephant challenges the elephant.
And the elephant says, I'm the king of the jungle and I challenge you to a fight.
And the mouse says, well, I'd like to.
But I've been sick.
So you puff up with anger and that's the illusion of strength.
What is strength?
Strength is standing for truth when confronted with adversity.
It's standing for integrity.
You stand for the truth.
You don't run from it.
Neither do you challenge it.
Neither do you swell up.
You just say, that's the way it is.
And of course, you are dead wrong.
Okay.
So the ego, of course, always wants to win and has an aversion to losing.
And here you have the narcissistic ego of the blogger because he wants to be somebody
and not...
And he dreads being nobody.
It's better to be somebody than to be nobody.
So people will go to any extreme to be somebody.
They shot John Lennon, the guy who shot John Lennon.
His only motivation was envy and he wanted to be somebody.
Now, he didn't shoot the guy just so you can be somebody.
To be somebody, he shot Lennon dead in the west side of New York City in the very famous
apartment building.
I forget the name of the...
Oh, the Dakota, yeah.
And the Dakota is a very famous apartment building, west side of the park, yeah.
And I used to...
There's twin towers.
The other tower was a psychoanalyst who was a supervising analyst of mine from Mount Sinai.
And I went to a meeting or a party there with him one evening.
So there's the two towers.
He's got this one at the top.
Twin towers, yeah.
So the penthouse, you could walk out on this terrace.
And the terrace had a wall, brick wall, so the wall was only this wide and went around
the place.
It was only about this high.
I should give you, freaks, just looking down, 62 stories or whatever it is.
And his cat would walk around this parapet.
I couldn't even watch him.
He says, oh, he knows where he is.
Sure-footed cat walking around.
Very funny.
Yeah.
All right.
So importance, people are willing to do anything, even kill a celebrity and thereby gain notoriety.
Of course, gain and loss is so obvious.
Money of course becomes an addiction.
The addiction to money, some people have so much money they don't know what to do with
it.
And the addiction to it.
Back east, I knew all the people who were there.
Great.
They had the greatest money.
They had the greatest fortunes.
They're all third and fourth generation.
And very exclusive enclave.
The world doesn't even know about them.
Anyway, they were all, what do you call it, babies and?
Huh?
Just one baby.
Just one baby, yeah.
And lived in big estates, you know.
And then I would visit them, big 50-roomed little Georgians and all.
And a lot of them, as they got older, would have a little apartment.
They'd have the kitchen and a bedroom.
And a little sitting room.
They'd be these three little rooms.
Here's this huge estate covering many acres.
And they lived in these three rooms for years.
And I'd say, what's in that building.
They'd say, Jesus, I don't know.
I haven't been there in 10 years.
A friend of mine lived in a big Georgian down on, on the, on Mill River Road in Upper
Vokeville.
And she lived in a huge Georgian, you know.
again, came into money, and I was asking, I was visiting her one time, and I said, what's
that? And she said, well, that's the dining room. And I said, what's on that? And she
says, I don't know. I've never been past the dining room. That was the kitchen, the
servants' quarters, the whole big, huge wing of this giant Georgian house. She says, I
don't know. I've never been past the dining room. That's funny. Okay. So she just took
money for granted. All right. So we desire, the ego keeps desiring excitement. This is
the excitement of thinkingness. The experiencer is out there using every thought and passing
opinion. The ego, of course, is run by wantingness and has a fear that it won't get. It loves
status and hates being a nobody. It wants to be noticed and hates the idea of being
ignored. It wants to express its opinion. It loves the soapbox and doesn't want to just
shut up.
Shut up and be ordinary. It craves and it dreads. So it controls to save the world instead
of surrendering it. It likes novelty. It hates boredom. It likes thrill. It's afraid it might
miss out. It's very aggressive and is afraid of being passive. Wants to be the in-group.
Wants to be elite. Correct. Politically correct. Wants to be in the in-group. Wants to be fashionable.
Picks up the latest meme.
Whatever the punch word is in order to show that they're very hip. They want to be fashionable.
They want to be right. Superior. The funniest thing about elitism is that what they're elite
about is their egalitarianism. What makes them superior is that they are politically
for egalitarianism, which means that everybody is equal.
So if you're the champion of equality, this makes you superior. You get the inference, right?
All right. So superior. It wants to speak up rather than to shut up. It's stubborn.
Would rather die than give in. Wants to be famous rather than anonymous.
As soon as you see a terrorist incident, you see the groups rushing to claim credit. Claim credit.
You'd think they'd want to escape in the other direction, not be known who blew it up.
But you see the groups rushing to claim fame for blowing up a busload of kids.
All right. So the attraction is to resist, to defend, to be special, to be more, to own things.
Here we have the magicalness of owning, which is a whole lecture in itself.
Oh, there is, you know, in reality, there is no such thing as owning.
It's not possible to own anything. First of all, everything belongs to God.
You have temporary stewardship. You have the right of control by legal agreement.
But you can't own anything. How could you own it?
You would have to be like an octopus and suck it into yourself so that it becomes you, you know?
But once you've done that, you've destroyed it so you can't own it anymore because you just ate it.
Okay, so the thought of own gives everything a specialness, a uniqueness.
You see, that's why my, the word my, is so magical.
You see, that's just a watch. That's just a watch.
Not the minute I own it, it's my watch.
Now it's very special. Now it's my favorite watch. Good God.
You see what happens.
The illusion of owning, then, is a mentalization.
You can't own anything. You can use it.
You have temporary stewardship of it, even this body.
Do I own it? I don't own it. It just is there.
At age three, I discovered the rotten thing.
I was perfectly happy in oblivion.
All of a sudden, smash-o. The light goes on.
And I realize I exist. God, my.
As soon as the realization of existence came up out of nothingness,
immediately arose the fear of nonexistence.
If you exist, you see, then the fear is you will not exist.
Immediately, the fear of death arises.
And to make matters worse, there was this little body, the roll call me, in this wagon.
Not only do you exist, therefore, you have to face the terror of nonexistence.
But a body went with it.
It's taken me 75 years to recover from it.
Ah, yes.
So you own. And that, of course, has to do with control.
Rather than realize the reality is that of stewardship.
Everything belongs to God. Nothing belongs to you.
And when you leave here, you're going to take nothing with you.
The body arose from the dust, and it returns to the dust.
You're not going to take it with you.
So, what can you take with you?
You can only take with you what you are.
Ah.
What you have become is the transcendent reality
that leaves the body and then is in a more familiar domain.
As people go out of the body, you know, out-of-body experience,
as we said before, their calibration doesn't change.
The reason is they know it all along. They know it all the time.
The minute you come into a body, you forget that.
The minute you go out-of-body, that is your natural state.
That's your natural state.
Because you know it all the time and just, you know,
repress it when you're in a physical body,
your consciousness doesn't go up.
Out-of-body consciousness remains the same.
Near-death experience, that's something else.
Near-death experience is transformative.
The infinite presence is so exquisite
that, ah,
ah,
one is never the same again.
Okay, so we move on.
Okay, so that's the illusion of ownership.
Here we have a trait. You want to be unique.
People want to change the world.
They change it, they mean they want to change it
to what they want it to become.
They change the world so it conforms with their idea of it.
And to do that, they'll work with facts and lie and steal.
Ah, this one, the attraction is to condemn people.
The aversion is to forgive them.
As I was saying, World War II is over 60 years
and yet here's this guy on TV.
He's just, he ain't going to forgive them.
Because they don't deserve it.
So his illusion is if he forgives, the other person has a gain.
But he doesn't realize that the one who gains by the forgiveness is him.
He's the one that gains by the forgiveness.
But he doesn't want to give the gift.
He sees it as giving away a gift.
Here you see the difficulty of forgiveness.
The difficulty of the narcissistic ways of the world.
The current, what I can see, sort of the decline.
Trying to blame responsibility out there.
You know, condemn, blame.
And instead of owning responsibility.
This wants to hold on to everything.
Has an aversion to letting go.
And the ego wants to dominate.
It is aligned with the content.
Whereas reality, what it doesn't want to do is surrender it.
So, God grant me the serenity to accept the things I cannot change.
And turn it over to God is just what the ego doesn't want to do.
It wants to dominate and hold on to it.
Because it's aligned with the content.
When you turn it over to God, you're surrendering it to the field.
Which is the same as the course of miracles.
When you ask the Holy Spirit for a miracle, you're asking to see it differently.
You're asking the Holy Spirit to transcend your fixation on the linear to see the non-linear.
And within the non-linear, you see that it's all perfectly fine.
Everything is fine.
So, this is involved with dominating the content.
It wants abundance rather than frugality.
Doesn't like frugality.
It would prefer to be a martyr rather than just accepting.
It has attracted to being the victim.
This is the value.
This is moral relativism and social relativism.
In which everybody is the victim of something out there.
Everybody is the victim of something out there.
Just victimization itself is a contextualization, you see.
The wind comes and things are knocked over.
But to see yourself as a victim,
is different than seeing yourself as the participant.
You're a participant.
You're not the victim of it, you see.
And surrendering it to God does bring the miraculous.
When I first came to Arizona, I got it.
I still have a 64 Willis three-quarter ton pickup truck.
And that was my only vehicle.
So I left the East.
I threw my tools in the back.
I said goodbye to everything and walked away.
Drove out here.
And there I am on the southern border.
North of Mexico.
And I still didn't have any idea of distance.
I had no idea how, you know, the great distance in the West.
So I'm in this little truck by myself.
And I really don't have any water or anything, you know.
And I'm exploring out there.
And I thought, well, in another few miles I'll come to a town.
I drove for an hour.
There was never any town.
Drove for another hour.
There's still no town.
You can drive for hours down there and see no town.
And finally I parked.
And the truck went on fire.
So I got no water.
I'm dehydrated.
And I'm exhausted.
And the truck is on fire.
And inside the cab, the smoke is shooting.
You can't see.
There's no way you can see where the fire is coming from.
And I had heat exhaustion.
So I knew I couldn't walk 20 feet from the truck, much less walk to the nearest town or water, seeing as I had already driven an hour and didn't see any anyway.
So I just got ready to go.
So I just got ready to die.
And I thought, oh, great.
I'll leave.
Fine.
So I sit there waiting to leave.
I've done it a number of times.
You know, your death is a certainty.
And so you say, okay, let's go.
So next thing I know, annoyingness, I've never heard any other.
I've never in all my spiritual experience.
There's never been an other, you know, like a voice or a vision or a spirit teacher or something.
But from within came an annoyingness.
And the annoyingness was, take the screwdriver.
I had a glove compartment.
But the front was old and fell off.
So here was just these tools.
You may not realize it, but a glove compartment is just lined with cardboard.
You think that's steel in there or something.
That's just cardboard.
So the annoyingness was to take the screwdriver and jam it through the bottom of the glove compartment.
So I did.
Like that.
Then the annoyingness came.
There was about this much coffee in the bottom of a Styrofoam cup.
Poured through the hole.
So I'm not going to resist it.
I poured it through the hole.
Kissed the one out.
Good God.
The fire was an electrical fire from the cigarette lighter.
And that was the exact locus of the fire, which would not be knowable via left brain.
Plus the electrical harness of that old truck has been redone about 80 times.
And it looks like a crazy snarl.
You'd never figure it out.
I didn't have the energy to lift the hood, much less do that.
So out of the annoyingness came to pour that in there.
So life went on.
A little disappointed, but so be it.
The annoyingness that arises from within.
Okay.
What happened to our projectionist?
All right.
So letting go of control then, letting go of wanting to control, or even to survive,
opened the door to annoyingness.
So I did not see myself as the victim of drought and all those things.
I was a participant in the event.
People like revenge rather than forgiveness.
They'd rather hate than forgive.
They'd rather blame than take responsibility.
People thrive on conflict.
They hang into the past instead of surrendering to the present.
The fear, the basic fear is control, the basic fear.
See, grief is hanging onto the past, the crest of the wave that has just passed.
You're clinging to that.
That's the past.
Fear is the anticipation of the rising crest of the wave.
So fear lives in the future.
Guilt lives in the past.
Huh?
And all fears, all fears, when we get to the thing on fear, we'll do it.
All fears eventuate as fear of physical death.
All fears.
No matter what your fear is.
And you get to that knowing this by doing the, and then what?
I'm afraid that I won't get a raise.
Yes.
And then what?
And then I'll be broke.
Yes.
And then what?
And then I'll lose the job.
And then I'll be unemployable.
And then what?
And then the wife will leave me.
And then I'll be homeless.
And then what?
And then you'll starve to death.
If you do the, if you take every, and then what?
And surrender it to God.
All right, so you're unemployed.
I've been unemployed.
You'll have no money.
I've been penniless long periods of time.
You'll be poor, penniless, and then eventually you'll die.
So you do the, and then what?
And then what?
If I don't get what I want, and then what?
And then I'll be disappointed.
And then what?
So each, and then what, brings up a consequence.
And as you surrender the consequence, which is the resistance, the obstruction, you will
always end up with the fear of physical death.
All fears, if you follow them through, you'll end up, and then I'll die.
Fear of physical death.
Once you surrender the fear of physical death to God, then the whole stack of fears collapses.
There's temerity, there's, you know, timorous, this and that.
But you're not controlled by fear.
Somebody says, if you do so and so, you may die.
You say, so?
So?
They're trying to intimidate you with that.
You stand up for truth.
Let me kill you for that.
So?
So once you don't have any fear of death, now you're fearless.
Fearless.
So the mind hangs on to its fears because it equates them with survival.
Because to the bacteria, to the origination of the ego's life, in the evolution of consciousness,
getting was critical and essential to life.
You had to get in order to survive.
Therefore, your ego is the same.
It thinks if I don't get blank, you just fill in the blank with what you want, then you
won't survive.
So you have to remind yourself I'm more than a bacteria.
If I don't get those essential amino acids, you have to remind yourself that you are not
a bacteria.
Why?
Because your survival is not based on getting.
Your survival is based on your karmic inheritance and the field, the contextual field, which
automatically is the consequence.
What keeps you alive is not the ego.
What keeps you alive is the field.
It's because of the spiritual field that your ego reminds you to take your vitamins.
So, your survival is not up to the linear ego, because it's only activated by the spirit.
By the spirit.
It's because of the self that you remember to take your vitamins, and you think if it
wasn't for the ego, I'd die of avataminosis.
You know what I'm saying?
No.
Because of the spirit.
The capital S.
The capital S is why the small S looks after you.
It's the big S that's your mother.
That's your mother right there, to see to it that you take your vitamins.
You know what I'm saying?
Survival.
So your survival is not up to the ego at all.
In the middle of the desert with the truck on fire, to what did I owe my survival?
Mine was useless.
The intellect was useless.
There was no possibility of linear processing.
The whole situation in the physical domain, if you ever saw what the wiring looked like
under my old truck, it's not even discernible by an electrician.
There's only one guy that can repair it, and I have to drive all the way down the cottonwood.
Yeah, who is the best automotive electrician around?
But anyway.
So even he can't figure it out.
So it wants to blame rather than take responsibility.
It thrives on conflict.
It clings to the past.
It fears the future.
It lacks excuses.
It tends to go into denial rather than to admit.
And it's impatient and doesn't want to wait.
Take the next one.
Waiting when you're uncomfortable is difficult.
So the anger of the people waiting to be rescued is the impatience.
The impatience.
All right.
The only way out of it is by constant surrender, constant surrender.
The locus of these things is the self.
The origin is the animal instincts.
You see impaired reality testing below consciousness level 200.
Intention here of the ego is to get, and the duration is transitory.
You see the hormonal thing here is different from adrenaline.
Emotions, passion, and attraction.
You see the propensity to become frantic, impaired, not be able to think right, become
self-destructive, to gain control.
And finally, if all that collapses, to go into depression.
Depression, rage, and then hatred.
So the quality and the, you see, the attraction and the aversion.
To forgive and choose love or resentment and getting even is difficult.
So we'll drop, we'll go to the next one.
The quality.
So we'll start.
Transcending the levels of consciousness is really written at Susan's prompting.
And finally I got into it.
And as I got into it, I really began to enjoy it.
And I'm now extremely pleased.
Very, very practical.
I want you to take each level.
And at the end of each chapter, there is a summary.
These are the summaries, starting with the dualities of shame.
What we talked about before are the general attractions and aversions of the ego itself.
Now we're going to talk about each level.
So in the book, we start at the bottom.
We have a chapter on each, chapter on shame, guilt, each thing.
And we examine each one, you know, from the viewpoint of many years in psychoanalysis
and psychiatry and group therapy.
Also spiritual experiences and spiritual groups.
And my own transformational experience.
Plus consciousness research.
So try to put together a way to approach each level from multiple angles simultaneously.
Each one sheds additional light.
Shame, you see, is satisfied by being self-punitive.
That's sackcloth and ashes and penance.
And the aversion is to self-forgiveness.
For one thing, a person feels too guilty.
It's always well to remember the admonition.
Judgment is mine, saith the Lord.
So you can see it's an egoistic position to assume that you're capable of making such a judgment.
The attraction is to be self-punitive.
The attraction of shame is depression.
You'd say, well, depression, people can't be attracted to that.
They do indeed.
Because the alternate is to choose life.
The alternate is to choose life.
And stop hanging out in depression.
Choose life, then, is a decision.
A decision.
No matter what, I choose life.
The attraction here is to be judgmental against yourself.
Whereas the aversion is to surrender yourself to God's mercy.
Allah the All-Merciful.
To God the All-Merciful.
Who, of course, if He's infinite and profound,
of course sees the weakness and frailties of the human condition.
Any good psychiatrist sees that.
You don't have to be God, you know.
That the human is limited.
Every human is the victim of their own ego.
Every human is intrinsically innocent, naive,
because of the very nature of it.
The nature of the human mind.
We give it comparison.
The human mind is like the hardware of the computer.
And it'll play any software you put in it.
You can program people and brainwash them in a matter of seconds.
That's what a meme is. M-E-M-E.
It's a catchy saying that gets picked up,
and it's cute, and it's in, and it's hip, etc.
And everybody now lives by it.
Nobody stops to examine whether it has any truth in it or not, you see.
Alright.
So, the attraction is to punish yourself,
hang out in depression, be judgmental,
rather than surrender judgment to God.
The attraction of shame is the negativity,
and the resistance is to letting go of the position.
At all times, it is good and well to remember
that life is a gift,
and that you are the steward of that gift.
You are the steward of that gift.
Steward, so.
All gifts.
I was told that when I was young.
Just a boy.
And I really didn't like other kids too much,
so they took me to the psychologist.
And she said, well, he's got a very high IQ,
and he'll have to get used to it.
Just born that way.
Born that way.
So, here are you.
The attraction is to be negative.
You don't want to let go of your position.
You want to shrink and hide,
instead of being visible.
You see yourself as worthless,
as firm, the gift of life.
So, whatever assets you're born with,
so that was an asset that the priest said,
it's a gift from God,
and it's your responsibility
to utilize it for the good of mankind,
life, others, etc.
So now, instead of saying to be egoistic about,
on the contrary,
it was now a responsibility.
So, if you have musical ability,
if you have athletic ability,
if you have good looks,
if you have money with capacity
to be really super nasty,
the world can use you.
That's your gift.
You're a liar.
I'm the best in the world.
Do you want to hire me?
That was his gift, being glib.
Yeah.
All right.
So, if you see your assets then,
instead of a source of pride or egotism,
instead of being the ego,
now you see it's a responsibility.
Great wealth.
It's a heavy duty responsibility.
I know people of great wealth,
and frankly,
their anxiety was how to best use it for mankind.
They really were concerned about it.
They built whole empires.
You know, Rockefeller,
all these great foundations have a huge staff of people
who just research the most propitious
and beneficial way to use this for the good of mankind.
People don't realize that rich people can,
you know, feel a great deal of responsibility,
obligation to the world.
To see it then as a gift instead of yourself is worth,
you know, affirm that your life itself is a gift,
and how can you best use it to be of service
to yourself and others.
You know, it's the Dalai Lama,
no, the skinny Indian guy.
Gandhi said, you know.
Or was it the Dalai Lama?
I don't know.
It wasn't the skinny foreigner.
Said it is not enough, you know,
to just seek enlightenment on your own
and to pray for yourself.
On the contrary,
but to use whatever you can
for the betterment of mankind in the meantime.
So that's Mahayana rather than Hinayana,
in which enlightenment is for the good of all.
Yeah, they're the good of all.
So your enlightenment,
whatever talents you have,
IQ, genius, good looks, strength, physicality,
the capacity for endurance,
and the capacity to break through barriers,
that's your gift.
And so you give thanks for the gift.
You're grateful.
That keeps you humble.
That way you can be rich, famous, handsome,
and good-looking like me.
Not have it go to your head.
It doesn't go to my head, does it?
However you are,
you see the gift in it,
and then you are thankful and acknowledge the gift.
You say, thank you, God,
for that disaster.
Without it,
I would never have become humble enough
to realize such and such.
Therefore,
no matter what happens in life,
in due time,
with reflection,
wisdom will show you
that it was something to be thankful for.
I am thankful for every event
that has ever occurred in my life,
although at the time,
it was exquisite,
painful, shameful,
guilt-provoking,
anxiety-provoking.
But in retrospect,
you will see
that every experience serves.
It's because of your intention
to see in what way that it serves
that it's revealed to you
in what way it serves.
If nothing else,
catastrophe shows
that your life is totally dependent on God
and not on the human ego,
because the human ego
in the middle of the desert
with no water in the truck on foot,
no fire,
is pretty powerless.
Pretty powerless.
So, alright.
Those lessons.
Here the view of shame is a rigid,
doesn't want to change it
and become correctable,
doesn't want to accept the gift of life,
doesn't want to be responsible
that he is now the steward of his life
and to stop wallowing in guilt and shame.
It chooses to condemn itself
rather than forgive.
It seeks mortification
rather than affirming self-worth.
It likes to denigrate itself
instead of honoring itself.
You see, once you see your life
is a gift from God,
you have to honor that.
I honor thy presence in me, O Lord,
and I do give thanks.
And thereby you sanctify your life.
When you sanctify your life,
you've already brought in
a different spiritual context
and your experiences of life
now become confirmatory of that reality.
So instead of saying,
I am a worthless worm,
I don't go for wormism.
Why?
Because it's rejecting the gift of God.
It's rejecting God's gift as life.
I am a worthless worm.
How can you stand me, God?
It's playing a game with divinity.
Self-hatred instead of self-forgiveness.
To be severe with yourself instead of benign.
To be imbalanced and see both sides.
So we'll move to the next,
and we'll get as far as we can
within a few minutes.
The next slide.
Next slide, please.
Okay.
You blame yourself instead of the ego.
To identify with the ego, you see,
you can say the mind thought that
or the ego thought that,
but I myself don't know
because the inner self is innocent.
Instead of blaming the ego,
you blame the self.
You exaggerate your faults.
You take a partial selective view.
How could I have been so stupid?
Instead of a balanced view,
you see yourself as loser instead of corrected.
You saw yourself as losing
instead of learning a painful lesson.
Yeah, you lost on that one,
but you're not going to bet on that one again.
The end of the road.
This is it.
We're at the end.
It's all over.
It doesn't say that
loss is the beginning of the new.
You cannot begin the new
until you let go of the old.
Here, of course,
you see yourself unlovable,
which is, again,
a violation of truth
and a negation of your worth
as a child of God.
Here, you think the error is unforgivable.
Here, you see the error is a lesson.
Lesion.
Now, that's correct, too.
That is a lesion.
That was a hell of an error, I tell you.
This was a hell of an error, I tell you.
Hey, that's good.
Lesion.
Anyway.
Anybody can spell it correctly.
I mean, anyway.
Narcissistic concern.
Here, you're concerned for others.
Instead of,
oh, help me, help me,
it's how can I help you?
And by helping them,
you're the one that gets saved.
Indulgence.
Instead of letting go,
self is the center of life.
Self is a participant in life.
Focus on the self instead of others.
I should have done this.
And the reality is,
you are not.
You are not.
You are not able to.
We'll go to the next slide.
I should have this or should have that is dealing from the hypothetical.
The hypothetical is always wrong.
Any time you hear your mind saying,
you should have or ought to have,
negate it.
There isn't such a thing.
If you could have,
you would have.
The fact that you didn't is because you couldn't.
There you see,
at the time,
I had a sore in my foot.
I couldn't run any faster.
If you could have run faster,
you would have, right?
Yeah.
Guilt and shame then,
guilt and hate go together
because it's judgmental
and you end up punishing either you
or projecting it outwards.
It's the refusal of mercy
and the secret pleasure of guilt.
See, self-punishment is a secret,
is a secret pleasure.
Here you project your feelings
instead of taking responsibility.
Here you choose perception
and with the spirit you choose to see the essence.
Guilt and hate is due to a rigid narrow view
instead of seeing both sides.
You're walking in your brother's moccasins,
then you can see
what it would be like to walk in his moccasins.
Here you see penance and self-indulgence as attractive
instead of being of service to others.
What good does it do others
to say the rosary all morning?
Tell me that.
Hmm?
Other than you get sore knuckles.
But how did you help the world?
Of what service were you?
Okay.
You cling to your position
instead of asking God for a miracle.
Here you have a willingness to change.
Here there's this attraction to act out
instead of transcending.
And here people enjoy,
in guilt and hate people enjoy being mean.
And here they enjoy being gracious and selfless,
to be small and mean
with yourself or others.
You see, it's being small and mean with yourself,
you know,
which is a denial of
the divinity of life within you,
your soul, your being,
and loving towards divinity.
What's the next one that we're not going to get to do?
Guilt and hate, is that more of it?
Hate?
Ah, we'll do it quickly and then we'll stop.
Then I won't have to feel guilty that I didn't finish it.
You need to be right rather than be wrong.
You see yourself as hopeless
instead of flexible,
instead of, you know,
instead of transcending it, you wallow in it.
Guilt and hate can lead to very malignant and cruel behavior
instead of being benign and merciful.
Yeah?
It's stingy instead of generous.
It projects responsibility
instead of choosing to be the author.
Guilt and hate are very vengeful,
comes from smallness, very grasping,
and it's the refusal to be
benevolent and merciful
and choose to be bigger than that.
Yeah?
All right.
So we stop there for today because
as I said, I'd feel guilty if I didn't get past that one.
I'd be ashamed of myself,
have to attack myself and get depressed.
All right.
So what happens next now?
Three o'clock.
We're going to have...
Yeah.
Nico's going to chant.
Everybody relax.
Let your chair support you
and pretend it's the whole universe, okay?
Buddha said,
sit upright and chant this sutra.
And a common moral says,
time without beginning,
but instead chant this sutra
for profound realization
that this last moment
is the beginning.