avatars and the great spiritual teachers.
How much time have we got left
and what slide are we on?
15 minutes? Let me see how far we are.
Where are we? What number are we on?
We're at... What number is this?
Avatars and great
spiritual teachers.
Oh, I better hustle along. Okay.
I don't know whether lollygag or
hustle. Try to look at my watch.
Why? Because we could spend the whole day
talking about any one of these.
Just grab one. We could spend the whole
day. Here's the Rig Veda that we mentioned before.
It's 7.05.
All right.
I can't read that well.
A Course in Miracles is well known.
I've written that the workbook
is at 600.
The textbook is at 550
because it gets into
a little duality in the workbook.
These are very
ancient. Apocrypha
and Bodhidharma Zen
teachings at almost 800.
The Bhagavad Gita
at
910. See, these came out of the
ancient Vedas.
The Book of Kells
at 570.
Everybody familiar with the Book of Kells?
The illuminated manuscript done
by the Irish priests.
We went to Dublin.
We went to see the
Book of Kells.
The first time I was there many years ago, there was quite a few
of them. Now they have exactly
one copy.
Every day they turn one page.
Instead, they've made
copies that they illuminate
on the wall. But a lot of those
illuminated manuscripts calibrate
well over 700. I remember
we went to see it and when we started
to look at this one on the wall, we all started to cry.
Just looking at it.
Looking at it made you cry.
That particular illustration
calibrated over 700.
The Book of Mormon
at 405.
The Cloud of Annoying,
extremely well known, mystical.
705.
The mystical always calibrates
the highest in all
the world's religions.
The Dead Sea Scrolls
are historically exciting.
Spiritually, only at
260. The Dhammapada
at 840.
The Diamond Sutra
at 700.
The Doctrine and Covenant
Pearl of Great Christ at
455 of Mormonism.
Genesis in the
Lomza Bible at 660.
Gnostic Bible
Gospels are 400.
Gospels of St. Luke,
St. Thomas are
all in the high 600s.
This is the Holy
Bible of the Sikhs.
505.
The Heart Sutra,
780. Let's see.
The one
that Nico
chants here is
what is that? Seven and something.
Can you read that?
The Lotus Sutra, especially
when it's chanted in Sanskrit.
Alright, so the Heart Sutra.
The teachings of Wang Po
require
explanation.
Have we got time for the explanation?
Yes. See, Wang Po,
if you read, Wang Po was
one of my favorites.
Wang Po, the Zen teachings
of Wang Po calibrates at 850.
And he taught
the pathway of negation, to negate
the reality of the
linear, to let go of any
attachment to the linear, because the linear
is transitory, an illusion.
If you practice it assiduously,
you will end up in the void.
is the void.
And I spoke of the void, I think
in the current book that just came out.
And I speak about it again
in some length in the future, in the book
that came out next year.
Duosional non-duality.
The pathway of negation
will take you to nothingness.
850 is
the void.
Many Buddhist
practitioners have made
the error of thinking the void is the ultimate
reality. It is not. And Arhat
calibrates at 800.
The void is nothingness.
In as much as the ultimate reality
is allness, nothingness.
Nothingness is an error.
The negation of
linearity, what happens
there is that God
as love has been negated.
By negating love.
If you see love in
the ego's idea of love
as an attachment, then
the pathway of negation
would take you to invalidate love.
If you invalidate
love and let go of all attachment
to all linearity, you will end up
in the void. The void
is not a thousand. The void is
850. Uh-oh.
Tell you one thing about the void.
It is profoundly impressive.
It is very easy.
To conclude, that this is
the ultimate state taught
by the Buddha of nothingness.
Voidness, no-thingness.
Nothing means no-thing.
It means non-linear. No-thing.
It doesn't mean non-existent.
No.
Because, I went into
the void again. I started in this
lifetime. I came in in the void.
Then day three,
it was shockingly, went back and
came back into existence.
I was not happy about it.
Not only did you exist, but
you had a physical body.
Also, if you
exist, comes the terror of non-existence.
First of all, the trauma
of realizing you exist, then the
fear of non-existence.
Because at 850, you haven't
transcended that duality of
existence versus non-existence.
So, you've got to
come back. If all you've got, the
farthest you ever got was 850, when you come back,
you come back at 850 and start from scratch.
From nothingness.
The ultimate divinity
is profoundly love.
So, this lifetime,
again, back into
the void. The void is infinitely
impressive.
Infinitely impressive.
It's infinite. It's eternal.
It is extremely profound.
Except that
as an adolescent in the snowbank,
I'd experienced the presence of God
as profound love.
That's its most major
characteristic.
Lack of thingness.
There was no thingness.
But the radiance of love was like
just profound.
The radiance of love
shone forth.
And in the void,
that was missing.
It was, by comparison,
sterile. Profound.
Unending. No beginning.
No end.
Had to back out of it.
Refuse it.
Because love is a quality of
divinity. If you negate
the reality of love,
you just negated divinity,
didn't you?
Yeah. There's an error.
There was a local teacher that I know extremely well
made that error.
He said that love was an attachment.
Those people all end up
flat. Into the flat
nothingness. Devoid of love.
Now, love
is a quality of divinity.
All right.
Huang Po, when he wrote,
he did,
he did write it, but at the time
he taught, it was quoted
in
aphorisms of
Zen teachings of Huang Po.
At that time, he calibrated it at 50.
Huang Po discovered the error.
Just as I discovered it.
And he went past 850, and by the time
he died, he was at 960.
But between the time he was
at 850 and the time he was at 960,
he didn't write anything.
Which I can understand.
That's the
natural state.
Natural state.
So he never said anything
after he reached that state.
And it's trackable.
But he was 960
when he left the planet.
So he discovered the error himself.
That's how they do the good karma.
Heart Sutra.
Huang Po's teachings. The Kabbalah.
605.
Now you see how the Kabbalah is being brought down
with some kind of
popularization. Yeah.
The King James Bible, we read it.
We have quite a section on the Bible.
We get to spend a lot of time this morning
talking about both the Bible and the
Koran. The King James
Bible calibrates much less
than the Lompsa Bible,
which is from the Aramaic.
The Lompsa Bible,
minus the Old Testament,
and minus the Book of
Revelations. The Book of Revelations calibrates
around 70. It was somebody's lower astral
hallucination. Calibrates
at 80. So the worst thing that
happened in the Council of Nicaea was the
conclusion of
Revelations by John. John
calibrated at 70, and the
Book of Revelations calibrated at 70.
That brought down the calibration of the whole
Bible. That's
why Christianity
was very high until
after the Council of Nicaea.
Alright.
We've already spoken about that, haven't we?
About the lower astral vision
of John. It's very common.
A lot of people in Sedona have had it.
They have. Some well-known
leaders who crashed, too.
Your etheric body,
you can go to
astral realms,
and there,
people think they're possessed by
extraterrestrials, etc.
Actually, what happens is they
experience that.
They experience that in a lower astral realm.
Then when they come back in the body,
they'll tell you,
it was very real. They experimented
with my eyes and took my heart out
and put it back in, etc.
They're convincing
because subjectively, experientially,
that's what they did experience.
They're not lying.
All these people of, what do they call it,
extraterrestrial possession,
they're not lying.
No. In an altered state,
they went to a lower astral realm
and that's what went on there.
Then they came back in the body and reported it.
They were in a lower astral
realm, reality.
One was a well-known teacher in Sedona
who did that, plus negating love.
All right, so the Bible then
included that.
Lao Tzu's teachings
are extremely high. The Lotus Sutra,
which we're going to hear this afternoon.
These are great books
of Judaism.
The New Testament
we've already spoken about.
So the highest version
of the New Testament
is the Lamsa edition
from the Aramaic
with the deletion of
the Book of Revelations.
If you do that, it comes up to
something like 880 or something.
Extremely high.
All right.
The Nicene Creed
calibrates extremely high.
Higher than I expected it to, 895.
Psalms from the
Lamsa Bible are 650.
The Ramayana, the
of Omar Khayyam.
I sent my soul into the
afterlife, some
message
to come back.
And my soul returned
to me and said, I myself
am heaven and hell.
That's the most
famous quote at
about 600.
Rig Veda we've already spoken of.
The Talmud is extremely high.
Tibetan Book of the Dead,
575. The Torah.
The concept of the Trinity
at 945.
Again, you see the Trinity in
Buddhism, I mean in Hinduism.
Arama.
The Upanishads are extremely high.
970.
Vedanta,
the Vedas,
these are all extremely high.
And the Zohar, which is mystical
Judaism,
at 905.
That's all the time we have for that?
You've got one minute.
We're trying to cover all this
and we'll do more this afternoon.
And we'll have time for
questions and answers.
The reason I'm looking forward to having
a small group that meets
just one evening every other month
is it'll be spontaneously just
question and interaction, discussion of
the implications of much of what we've
talked about.
And so therefore, all these things
have, when they're
contextualized correctly,
you can see how innocuous
they are.
Yet you can see that your chances of enlightenment
are zero if you follow them.
So it's not like we're knocking them.
It's not like we're knocking them.
It's just that,
all that we teach then
is contextualized
from the viewpoint
of having
enlightenment as one's ultimate goal.
Understand?
Everything we say is from the context.
Many things are swell,
but not if you're seeking
enlightenment.
You can go and get your aura read,
you can do the beads,
you can do the cards,
you can do all the Swami stuff.
There's nothing wrong with that.
But if you're on your way,
if your goal is enlightenment,
it is a great deterrent.
You can blow many, many, many lifetimes
following all that.
And all of us here have done it.
All of us here have done it.
We've all checked it out.
And then something
within our soul said,
okay, you've checked it out.
Now let's get serious.
So our intention then
is these are for the people
who've been around,
we've all been around in many lifetimes,
plus we've often done it together.
Let's see that.
We have often swooped in together,
this whole group.
We've been together a long time.
So we've checked it all out.
Now that we've gratified
our childish curiosity
about the runes and the stones
and sacred readings and ooh la la ooh.
The hearts and the flowers
and all that.
The slick looking gurus,
someday I'm going to come in
in my real guru outfit
and I'm going to do smoke
and various tricks that I've learned
over many a lifetime.
I've learned a lot of tricks
over many lifetimes.
I can make things materialize
and dematerialize.
Alright, so we'll be back
at what time for lunch?
We'll be back at 2 o'clock.
2 o'clock. We'll resume at 2 o'clock.
Ready to go on.
Well, I was going to start
the afternoon with the problematic
hermeneutics of relativistic epistemology.
Comical and yet critical
to our existence.
Anyway, I did leave some
reprints of moral relativism
which is a printout from
the Philadelphia Trumpet
because moral relativism
is the
as the Pope said
the primary problem of society
in which wars and things
are the automatic fallout.
Why try to attack war
when the cause is
relativistic moralism
and that's the problem.
So I agree with the current Pope.
I'm sure the Pope
is glad to hear that.
How'd he do
without me? I don't know.
The new book.
There's an error on page 342.
All books have errors.
I buy a book, commercial book
and it never has errors.
Every book we do is read by
32 people 32 times
and there's always a misprint.
I don't know.
Oh, humility. Thank you, Lord.
Sonia, the chief editor.
Two of us have read it
about 43 times.
On page 342, the reason it's important
is because usually it's just
a typo, but this changes.
It says
you know, your calibrated level
of consciousness, your spiritual destiny,
your karmic destiny
is set by intention.
And then it says, however,
when you're, you know,
it's like setting the compass on the ship
and every little wave that tips you
this way or that way
does not change
your ultimate destiny.
The word do not was left out of there.
It says don't fret over
every little annoyance.
If you've picked peace, page 342.
Anyway.
It says somewhere on the left,
second paragraph I think,
we forgot do not.
You've set your compass.
You've decided on enlightenment.
Every time you get annoyed with something
or a little guilt with something
doesn't mean you've fallen off the course.
You do not change
your overall compass.
The compass is changed by a spiritual decision,
not by every little wave.
So do not was left out of there
and I don't want to obsess
the compulsive people going home
and beating themselves up
because the word do not,
they'll think, he said, oh you are off.
You see what I say about making mistakes?
I thought it was 342.
Anyway, do not was left out.
Now I can sleep
comfortably.
We always say a little something
about this subject here.
We've done this one before.
I'm going to do it a little differently this time.
Look at the top.
Look at the...
Come around this way.
Look at the top picture.
Look at the top.
Now resist.
Look at the bottom picture.
We're going to repeat what we've done before.
Look at the top picture.
You go strong.
Look at the bottom picture.
Look at the bottom picture
and think the sound ah.
Think the sound ah.
You know,
skeptics think you're faking kinesiology.
You don't fake it because
it's all non-verbal.
She looks at that, goes strong.
She looks at that, goes weak.
I say make a sound in your mind
and she goes strong.
You know what I'm saying?
It's a very simple thing.
That's all I wanted to say about it.
So now we'll go to the next...
Where were we before lunch?
We have to move fast.
Okay.
Other teachings, schools and traditions.
Now when we published the book
we had to decide whether we want to please everybody
or tell the truth.
So throughout the book it warns you
that we're not writing this to please everybody.
We're just telling you
what the numbers came up.
The numbers that came up
is all that we're saying.
The hundredth monkey phenomena
is not just illusory.
It comes out at 2.05.
Everybody familiar with the hundredth monkey phenomena?
Huh?
The monkeys on one island.
There were a bunch of islands
with monkeys on them.
The missionaries or somebody
taught the monkeys on one island
to wash their potatoes before they ate them.
The monkeys would take it
and wash the potatoes.
Within I forget a decade
the monkeys on other islands completely separated
began to wash their potatoes before they ate them.
It was like picked up in the collective.
That's called
the hundredth monkey phenomena.
So when you go to clear things in yourself
there's no point in feeling badly
because the collective unconscious
you've already picked up
a lot of the hundredth monkey phenomena.
You got it? See?
We're intelligent monkeys.
So we've already picked up
through the hundredth monkey phenomena
what Jung called the collective unconscious.
And when you're doing
very intense very advanced spiritual work
you become dismayed
that stuff is coming up in you
that you cannot recall in your personal life.
It's because beyond a certain level
you're picking it up from the collective
belief system of
the unconscious belief system
of all mankind.
Okay, what does this say?
Gnosticism is 200.
Atheism is below 200.
Atheism is arrogant.
It means I know, I know there is no God.
I mean you can see the arrogance of that.
Gnosticism is honest.
I have myself
I'm unable to decide
divinity is a reality or not.
And
I myself went through very intense
first I started out
as an atheist and then I became more
sophisticated and became an agnostic.
I got straight A in theology
all the time I was an atheist agnostic.
Anti-creationism
calibrates at 150.
Anti-evolutionism
150.
Archangel channelers usually calibrate
about 190.
Astrology is problematic.
Depends on what kind of astrology you're talking about.
It came out higher than I thought.
210 and then some
variations of it are 405.
This has to do with causality.
And what we mentioned this morning
that phenomena
in other words a planetary
constellation is not causing
things to happen.
It's that they're both
energized in such a way
that they're in synchronicity.
And when Mercury's
going over your backyard it's very likely
your bunions will hurt more than
when Neptune is
drinking
your soup.
Biofeedback
202.
Bodywork 205.
Well the body and the planet is at 200.
The earth is at 200.
The body is at 200. That's like neutral.
Neither good nor bad.
Neither the body nor the body.
So the body is the product of the world
of the physicality.
From ashes you dust your eyes
and from dust you return.
From 200 you go to the body
and 200 goes back to 200.
Alright.
Bodywork 205.
The concept of codependency
at 190
is less than 200 because
it confuses love.
Many things are done out of love
and it sort of eliminates
love from the equation.
Anytime you serve other ones
it's not necessarily codependency.
You can do it out of love.
So codependency
has a certain validity
when it's used correctly.
Creationism is at 200.
Crystals at 210.
Druids at 450.
Ekankar 230.
Enneagrams
390.
Est.
How many here did Est?
Quite a few of us did, yeah.
It was at 400.
And Est just didn't allow you
to blame anything out there.
If you were late
it's because you decided to be late.
It wasn't because the streetcar got in your way.
You had to take responsibility
for your own actions.
That would have
quite a positive effect in today's world
would it not?
In which cause is always
put out there as blame
instead of just accepting
the fact that it was your own error.
Ethical culture
at 350.
During the time I was an agnostic and an atheist
I checked a lot of these things out
like ethical culture.
Ways of reaching truth that avoided
the terminology of God.
Falun Gong
105. Doesn't do too good.
Feng Shui can be anywhere
from 185 to 210.
Like astrology it depends on
what it's about
and why it's used.
Fire walking is at 200.
Freemasonry at 510.
Freethinker at 350.
Now the founders of the constitution
were freethinkers.
They were deists and theists
but they were freethinkers.
Freethinkers.
And that's why our constitution
is really quite liberal.
Let the congress not establish
a religion
nor prohibit the free exercise
which the enemies of religion
always manage to delete.
And you see the lack of integrity
and that's why people in that political position
calibrate below 200.
Don't you see that's dishonest.
The phrase is neither establish nor prohibit
the free exercise thereof.
So purposely to chop off
this half means to be
dishonest.
Dishonest puts you below 200.
Alright so that's easy to see.
Fundamentalism 200.
I forgot what fundamentalism is.
Hatha yoga
is good stuff at 260.
Holotropic breathing
at 202.
Huna is
what is it?
123.
260.
The I Ching in the 400s.
The keys of Enoch.
160.
Kirlian photography
came out at 160
which is a surprise to me.
I've got Kirlian photographs
at my fingertips and all.
We were all into it for a while.
We'd do all kinds of things.
We'd chant and all that
and then we'd go and see our fingertips again.
It was really an attraction
for a while.
Knights Templar, what does that say?
400?
Well it's of interest
recently because
of the Da Vinci Code
and all the focus on that.
And then Kung Fu
and seeing metaphysics.
Numerology
at 210.
Qigong, 240.
Rebirthing, that's quite an exercise.
250.
Reiki in the 300s.
Rolfing, it says
it's only 205.
So things that are strictly physical
don't get too far beyond the 200s.
Rosicrucians
at 405.
Soul midwifery
at 240.
Superstition at 200.
Not necessarily bad.
Sometimes it incorporates
that which is within the collective.
Telepathy at 250.
It means it's a fact.
And Theosophy
which has a great tradition.
Universalist Church.
And the White Brotherhood
at 560
from the Celestial Realm.
White Magic, 203.
Wu Den, 275.
Anybody got any questions
about any of those things?
It's relatively clear.
The White Brotherhood
is really a Celestial Realm.
I have permission
to do the White Brotherhood.
They're over 560.
570.
Unconditional Love
is a Celestial Realm.
The work, let's see,
the translator of transmissions
from that realm was
Alice Bailey.
And of course
the book that I think
is useful
is the one on Glamour.
What you find attractive out there
you think the attractiveness
is out there.
What it points out
is that you project
that specialness onto it.
Now you're craving
what you think is out there.
What's out there is just you
and what you put out there.
If you think, you know...
The white meaning purity.
Yes, purity.
I mean it's a great place to go
if you leave and
invite it to join the White Brotherhood.
It would be a great honor.
It means they have
detained themselves from going further
to serve mankind
for the time being.
All of them
are sufficiently advanced
if they wanted they could go on
but they wouldn't then
be involved in human affairs.
So for the sake of humanity
they detain their own
these are things that all calibrated
below 200.
Some of them get so much publicity
and they've come up in classes
so many times
that we finally did them all.
Al-Qaeda as we said this morning
is at 90.
The Atheist Movement is at 190.
Christian Identity Movement
is at 110.
Aum Shinriko
cult is
not surprisingly
at 85.
Aztec, like the Mayan religion,
calibrates extremely low.
Worshipping,
death,
tearing out the hearts of maidens,
etc.
doesn't calibrate too high.
Channeling itself
calibrates itself as a phenomena
under 200.
Crop circles it says
are not extraterrestrial.
Cults abound
and they calibrate from 50 to 160.
Let's remember many of them
where they all took LSD
and poisoned themselves
and shot themselves.
So cults can be quite negative.
Divination in and of itself
is 185.
The DNA code theology
is at 160.
That's all fantasy.
Easter Island statues
have an interesting history
of the Easter Island.
I can't go into it now
but if you're interested in it,
you can.
Easter Island statues
were worshipped.
Worshipping the golden calf
you might say.
They ate up all the wood
or vegetation or something
and all starved to death
so they turned against God
and destroyed the statues of God
that they thought were God
when actually they brought it
upon themselves.
Therefore, worshipping the golden calf
calibrates very low.
Is that real?
Actually, no.
Fortune telling at 185.
These all come out of Mesopotamia.
Full moon gatherings
because it gets into the
ooh la la.
The romance of the magicalness
of it all
doesn't do too well.
Goddess movement for the same reason.
Heaven's gate cult
we would expect to be 160.
Indigo,
the whole indigo
like the incoming fifth generation
are all fictional.
There's one problem.
Very big selling books
the naive person
thinks they're talking about
spiritual reality
and they're all novels.
Da Vinci Code
or what was the one
Redfields wrote?
Celestine Prophecy.
All this thing about
indigo children being
some kind of special thing.
Those are all
Incan religion
was at 85.
Incoming fifth world
the whole that's all the same.
So that's spiritual
fiction.
Now there was recently a big
program on the Da Vinci Code
and in it they pointed out
that it was fiction.
So if you point out what I'm saying is fiction
then it's over 200.
But if you try to present it as reality
then it goes below 200.
Islamic fascism
at about 60.
Left behind ideology
anything that predicts
future catastrophes
always calibrates low.
In my understanding
of consciousness
the future cannot be foretold.
It's not possible.
First of all it has no reality.
If it has no reality
how can you foretell what's going to happen
in a non-reality?
Because events are decided
and every decision you make
is already changing your future
and collectively you're changing the future.
There would be no point
if you think about it
if you really think about it
there would be no point to this incarnation
if the future were already determined.
You'd be a dumb robot repeating
yeah see no.
The reason this
human life is so valuable karmically
is because it's a world
of great
karmic opportunity.
It's a recycling center.
Well you goofed before
and now you get a chance to choose again, right?
If the future was determined
there would be no free will
therefore there would be no karma
there would be no responsibility
therefore you don't need a savior
you don't need a Buddha
there'd be no point in spiritual work, would there?
It would negate its own obvious purpose.
The man religion as we said
was quite new ageism
calibrates about 185
the reason is the glamorization
the glamorization
to the innocent adolescent
within all of us
and its appeal to magic
solar temple ideology
I don't know what that is
something of the solar temple
is some kind of energy
plasma energy orbs
is another 160 fantasy
polygamous sex are about 135
and it's predicted
polygamous sex
are in the news as usual.
We're the extraterrestrial people
right wing fundamentalist
Christian
at its worst is 95
it becomes
inquisitional
secularism
is at 165
because it denies the reality of divinity
is the Shroud of Turin
real?
We always have gotten no
star children like indigo children
and fifth incoming
people from the future
etc is fantasy
at 145
star people is 145
star seed family
so all these ideologies
because people take them as real
Are UFOs real?
No.
Therefore UFO religions
because they're based on the unreal
all calibrate low
Urantia book has come up many a time
and it comes out at 150
no matter what you do with it
we tried calibrating in the morning
it's 150
we tried it at night
after a glass of milk
it's still 150
I can't help it
if you hold the book
it's 150
Wicca is 160
we have to hurry
is the word from higher
Calibration of verses of the Old Testament
a lot of people are disturbed
at the Old Testament
if you break it down
like this
how many verses are extremely high
what you see is that
60% calibrate over 200
that means 40%
are below 200
the same thing happens with the Koran
this happens through translations
translations
don't forget the books of the Bible
were taken by vote
about different documents
different people with different positionalities
and
if it won the vote
which is not really the way we establish
truth
the Koran is the same thing
30% calibrate below 200
so if you interpret the sword
as the sword of truth
or the sword of steel
you've got quite a big difference
and the interpretation of the Koran
by this is the most influential
guy here
calibrates at 90
other references to God
Scandinavian, gods of war
pagan gods of Rome
all calibrate less than 100
that's where you're not supposed to worship
the golden calf
places of spiritual interest
do we have to stop in 5 minutes
yes
got it
alright
we're going to go 5 minutes
and then the rest of the charts
will do in the next lecture
the Alhambra of course
is of Muslim origin
Angkor Wat
what is that 660
this mountain is where
Ramana Maharshi
has spent his life
still has an ashram there
never left it
Basilica of Saint Peter in Rome
current Bethlehem
that's what man has done
at the time that Jesus Christ
walked the earth
I forget what it was
450 yeah right
ok
Bethlehem current is 175
so if you want to do a
pilgrimage to the holy land
I'd suggest Chicago
which calibrates at 440
Toronto
Toronto calibrates very high
Toronto and Chicago
the kid who wants
to find himself by joining the Taliban
remember
it'd be better if he went to Chicago
he would have found himself there
the relics of the Buddha
which we as a class went out and calibrated
one day was over 900
Notre Dame at 790
of course
the flying buttresses are so classic
we finally got to the cathedral of Saint John
the Divine in New York City
the largest cathedral in the world
and it's at what 530
it hasn't been there long enough
it's constructed all the power of all the prayer
a catholic chapel
is usually around 560
sharp cathedral at 790
the relics of the Christian saints
crystal cathedral in Los Angeles
a stunning structure
Dharamsala in India
at 330
the Ganges River
we've commented before
has been sanctified by thousands
for so long that it is actually over 500
the great Buddha that was blown up
by the Taliban
calibrated at 555
the great Buddha of Kyoto
is still at 780
Jewish synagogues
and temples
all of these calibrate over 500
the Kaaba in Mecca
at 530
the great temple at Karnak
Lhasa, Tibet
Lourdes is interesting
at 510
the Kaaba much higher than I thought it would
I thought it's one of those mystical
magical places
sign up and we'll take you on a tour there
and I've been there
but it's 510
the attic of Nisargadatta Maharaj
calibrates very high
Mecca and Medina
have of course come down over the years
because of all the conflict
a mosque itself
innately is at 495
the Church of Nativity
which is so famous
look at the
Pieta
how high it is
and that's why that which hates beauty
and the sacred attacks it
it attacks it
there was outside of Sedona
a sand sculpture for years
by a local sand sculptor
and he had the 12 apostles
and Jesus
beautiful sand sculpture
just a couple of miles north
up the road to the flag
on the right hand side
he'd fix it
and a couple of months later
you'd see Jesus was beheaded again
you see
that's why as you evolve
the demons that come at you
are looking for your weakness
because that which hates
truth and divinity and beauty
looks where they can bring you down
because you have become their enemy
if you start lecturing on truth
then everything that is untrue
will see you as some kind of an enemy
the pyramids of Egypt
the chapel of Saint-Chapelle
in Terrace
in a stunning place
and very difficult to get into
was over 700
St. Pat's Cathedral
you know which we all are familiar
and the relics of St. Peter
under the floor of the basilica
as we mentioned was 910
Sakya Monastery
in Tibet
Shinto Shrine
the Sphinx came out higher than I thought too
Stonehenge at 599
was higher than I expected
Strasbourg Cathedral
at 715
Taj Mahal
the incredible beauty
brings it up extremely high
Unity Village which we have had the great pleasure
to visit is over 500
the Vatican is at 570
Washington National Cathedral
which was very impressive
I mean this is a 100%
Gothic Cathedral
right here in
the US of A
it just sort of knocks you out
Washington DC
and there is one of the great cathedrals of Europe
transplanted here
Westminster Abbey
which is a magical place
Westminster Abbey is a magical place
I spoke there in 1971
in Dean's Yard
of Westminster Abbey
and we got a chance to go back there
and they had just closed
we wanted to calibrate all these places
and we were there
and we got there
just as Westminster Abbey closed
so I told the guard
the last time I spoke here
was in 1971
and I just wanted to go in
and pay my respects
well go ahead
don't take too long
so Westminster Abbey of course
is very impressive
and when you go through the section
of all the great names of history
you see all the great literary names of history
and there they are laid out on top of their coffins
and not only that
but the graves are under the floor
so you're walking on very famous people's bodies
underneath there
Shakespeare, oops sorry
so now at 2.30 we stop
alright so that's all the slides for today
and something happens now
what happens at 2.30
we have everybody
ok so that's all the slides
we've got more but we'll save them for next time
at this time I'd like you to meet
it's the last meeting of the
lecture for the year
the staff that makes all this possible
I'd like all the staff to come up
all the staff that works with us
for us
Sonia
our chief editor Sonia
ok now we need to make a special
announcement to the columbos
where are the columbos
we have a couple from
from
Las Vegas
we need Las Vegas up here
and we need Canada up here
come here Toronto
this is what it takes
to put on a lecture
to make the work happen
and this is just the visible ones
there are others here too
that don't show up
on photographic film
if you know what I mean
who's going to introduce them
anybody
this is Tom I know he's Tom
because it says right there it's Tom
Susie you going to introduce everybody
well I don't have a mic
here's Gabe
give her a mic
start right there from the end
we'll go right across
hi Gail Edwards Decker
Robert Decker
Dale
Lou
Joe
Lonnie
Paul
Lisa
Tom
Louris
Laura
some of them teach study groups online
other of them contribute in other ways
to help us put on lectures for you
and so we just want all of you
to acknowledge them
and without them we wouldn't be able to do
these wonderful lectures for you
and Susan
and Doc
thank you
and this is what it takes
to put on a lecture
and all the people
that we hardly ever get a chance to acknowledge
in public
ok now we have Miko Champ for you
and then we will have a short break
and we will resume
back here
at 3 o'clock
remember to
line up on this side
if you want your books signed
or this side if you want your books signed
if you have any questions
this side for only books only
so
I know there will be quite a few today
since the book just came out
so we will see you in a little bit
and Miko let me get you set up
you said that Jesus
brought salvation to mankind
salvation yes
and I would like to know
salvation from what
and by which means
by which means did he do so?
man in and of himself
is incapable of transcending
his own limitations
by the
beneficence of the savior
who is your
who speaks for you at the right hand
at the father
salvation
man left to himself
is incapable of it
because of the very structure of the ego
also you forget
you've got an inheritance
karmic inheritance of the collective unconscious
of mankind all together
so the chance of you on your own
reaching salvation
enlightenment or whatever you want to call it
is very very limited
and he did so by
the Buddha taught enlightenment
it's a different thing
salvation somebody speaks for you
enlightenment you transcend all the levels
for which you would need a savior
thank you very much
what do I do with this wonderful box?
just sign it
who is this about?
it's like a box of weenies
or something
hello
just by us being here
do we protect ourselves from
spiritual downfall?
just by being where?
here
in a spiritual class?
yes of course
you wouldn't be here if you weren't in there
sitting in spiritual integrity
so therefore your enlightenment is already in tegris
the person who is dedicated to spiritual truth
is already way above 200
below 200 you got to worry about
what's going to happen to you
below 200 you got worries
over 200
it's just a matter of time
hi
you've been mentioning unconscious programming
a lot the last few months
like with your osteoporosis
with what?
your osteoporosis
you pick up from the collective
is there anything that we should be doing
in particular to
offset that besides the course of miracles
is there like a specific
something we should hold in mind?
as you become alert to being programmed
you can tell when you're being programmed
and refuse it
but unwittingly one gets programmed
I think as I demonstrated
pig nose
alright now forget that
you've already been programmed with the nose of a pig
you see
pig nose
you didn't have
nobody said
now I want you to decide whether or not
you want to include this in your memory bank
it happened without your permission
therefore that's the intrinsic innocence
that's the intrinsic innocence
that you can be programmed
against your own will
so we just accept it
or we
say we're only subject to what we hold in mind
that's correct
and
but you're going to be clearing things
the reason I bring this up is because
you're going to be clearing things
that you in your personal recollection
don't remember
and yet you obviously picked it up someplace
because you're manifesting it
I thought osteoporosis
is for little bent over ladies
yeah
and like specifically
for calibrating things
when we're doing calibrations
does the unconscious beliefs
come into play when we're
doing calibrations
no because you're bypassing it
kinesiology in consciousness
research calibrates at 600
so the 600
is the interface between the linear
and the non-linear
whatever you're believing doesn't influence it
so we don't have to specifically
say
to clear anything before we calibrate
I don't think so generally speaking
no
if you don't get a
response that you think is
appropriate you could go
ha ha ha ha ha ha ha
clear yourself and then
recalibrate it
also it's best
to ask do I have permission to calibrate this
as you'll see during
the lectures sometimes we get
something really tacky
and we'll ask do we have permission and it says no
ok good
thank you
good questions
I have a question about
chinks or the traps
about what? about the traps on the pathway
say it real slow
the traps on the pathway
traps on the pathway
oh yes
for example when you're in this state
when everybody falls in love with you
or vice versa
on every level there's
the traps
having known a couple of people that
crashed very badly
I'll tell you what their specific
problem was
one of them I wrote up already in the lecture
confused personal love
with divine love
is a serious mistake
because personal love is an attachment
you then cancel
the reality of love itself
and you
end up in the void
divine love is not an attachment
it's an overall condition
a state
it's one of the qualities of divinity
that's one
that's a certain mistake
the mistakes that generally befall
the gurus one after another
is money fame and sex
same thing over and over again
so and so is
having holy sex with a whole crowd of people
on video I mean
you know what I mean
this person lost their noodles or what
or they're working people for money
they're working people for
they're trying to sign up followers
I'll give you 50 bucks for every follower you sign up for me
you know what I mean
there are people
that calibrate in the high 200s
I mean quite in the high 200s
that people think are the walking
savior of mankind they calibrate 290
so would it be best
let's say when you're there
to disregard a personal
relationship or even take
the oath of celibacy
to you know
or something to
that's the only way some people can handle it
is by celibacy
you see because love
is a way of being with someone
a way of being with someone
if you validate
the value of their love they validate
so you are with them but not attached
to them
you don't have to get into combative
control issues
would there be like any downside when you're taking
the oath you know
when you're taking what
the oath when you're taking
ok we have to stick to the questions I know this
you're asking too many questions
don't take any oaths
also not the oath of celibacy
don't take any oaths I said
ok
about root beer
gambling whiskey
women jumping from
roofs do not take any
oaths ok
I got it because the oath that you take in one
lifetime can be the trip
what trips you up in the next
because you don't remember the oath
yeah four of us at one
time all missing the left thumb what do you think
that's accidental
Merry Christmas
yeah yeah
if you could please
stick to one question
we're waiting lined out
okie doke we'll move it
please stick to one
when a spiritual
teacher folds five or six hundred points
how can he keep on teaching
I mean doesn't he know doesn't he feel
the difference it's a mystery
to me no they don't know the ones that I have known
didn't know it
somebody would say look there's no energy
around his heart chakra
I see why he's so
preoccupied with money I say you reach
such a state or you spend all your time
suing your followers
it was a guru that a
bunch of us followed out here
he turned around and sued all of his followers
you know what I'm saying
sued the county that he shouldn't be taxed
because he's a
church yeah I'm a church too
yeah right
when I heard that
someone fell five hundred six hundred
points I was
stunned that they could even
it is stunning isn't it
so I've told this class
what to watch out for
in the five hundreds you're going to be very attractive
to people people complete strangers
are going to walk up to you and say I want to go to bed with you
I know this sounds crazy
but I want to go to bed with you
knock on the door walks in the office
I know this is going to sound bizarre
but I want to go to bed with you
it did sound bizarre
there was a period of time when I got
a position a couple of times a week
you could spend your whole time in bed
so they have no idea that they've gone down
they don't realize
the one that I knew in Sedona
I never realized
there's a preoccupation with money
power over others
cult leaders who tell you
everything about your
life what you can do
you want to change your job you've got to get his permission
egotism
so the egotism
power over others
the glamour of having followers
theatrical drama
magical tricks
they all come out of India
India you know magical tricks have been around
for thousands of years
you know the Indian rope trick
making smoke come out of your mouth
divine ashes and all that
you know what ashes
calibrate at
two hundred
what do you think a thousand
ashes from dust to dust
ashes which burns up
is two hundred
so anyway
you say to yourself
well these traps are so obvious
how could anybody possibly
alright it may be some karmic propensity
I don't know
but it comes at you looking for where your weakness is
tempting you with money
tempting you with power
tempting you with followers
tempting you with theatrics
but the miraculous happens of its own
there's nobody that does the miraculous
I've witnessed the miraculous
there was no this causing of that
so you're going to get followers
that you can perform the miraculous
unfortunately
the image of Jesus
is so much based on his
performing of the miracles
well in that day and age
there wasn't much spiritual erudition
so of course they were attracted to the phenomena
but the phenomena are irrelevant
the truth of who Jesus Christ was
got nothing to do with miracles
but people go ooh and ahh
over the miraculous
the miraculous is one of the cities
s-i-d-d-h-i-s
and when that energy
is around you the miraculous happens
spontaneously
good questions
Merry Christmas Susan
thank you
hi doc
this is going to be embarrassing
since the October get together
my life in my 65 years
has been the most disruptive
beautiful and painful
I've experienced I think
I left here
after the lecture in October
with four days
of like walking around
one degree from orgasm
every time
I would meditate
or contemplate
the same thing would come back
it's also the tingling
I'm understanding it's Kundalini
also the total confusion in the brain
I've been unable to function
unable
my home's a sanctuary for abandoned cats
I feel responsible for them
I've not been able to function
so I know the part of the answer
or all the answer is total surrender
which is what I have tried to do
but maybe
you've got some other answers
for me that help me function
in this time
no
okay
seriously are there any books
or anything on this
you've got 65 cats don't you
yes
they're all well and happy
yes they are
what more do you want
they need to be fed
I've hardly been able to function
this is weakening
I knew a guy that couldn't even
make Mrs. cats happy
so seriously there's no acupuncture
or anything that can help
okay
that's true
65 happy cats and she's complaining
if I can keep one cat happy
I think I'm doing good
hi Dr. Hawkins
yes
can you speak up here in your presence
I just want to thank you so much
I saw you in May
and you've changed my life
I just want to thank you
I'm glad it had a good effect
I have a question
I'm in a graduate psychotherapy program and
I graduate in what
psychotherapy
so I find myself now
after being exposed to your work
feeling frustrated
or finding myself judgmental
of people in my program
that haven't been exposed to your teachings
I'm making them wrong
because they haven't been exposed to your work
I'm wondering how to work with that
that's a hard one to come across
as you evolve spiritually
the spleen of the spiritual warrior comes up
you become indignant at the evil in the world
the blatant lying
you know what the constitution says
do not establish a religion
nor prohibit the free practice thereof
so where does
the anti-Christmas
BS come from
you know what I mean
it's hard not to be indignant about it
spiritual pride comes up
so anyway
you have to accept
what Socrates said
that everyone is doing what they think
is the right thing to do
thank you
I thought
Michael Newdow calibrates at 205 or something
not 80, not 90
he keeps coming up
to the Supreme Court
hoping to knock God out of here someplace
Charisma is God
but he seems to be
in his understanding of it
so Socrates' dictum is
if this man, he's over 200
so if he's over 200 he may be mistaken
but he's doing what he feels
called upon to do
so it's part of the evolution of mankind
to hear such voices
yeah
Hi Dr. Hawkins
my question
has to do about grief
a dear
friend of mine, a priest who was really influential
in my life in college passed away
a priest friend of yours passed away?
yes
you know going through your work
and contemplating non-attachment
and everything
my question is the first couple days
I didn't really feel anything
and then we did a practice counseling session
at my school and I was just overwhelmed
and weeping as I held him in mine
and there's definitely not a depressed
or attached longing
for him to be here
it's just an overwhelming
grief
yeah and kind of a couple with gratitude
joy of just even thinking of him
feelings of loss
yeah so my question is
how
has to do with the experience of grief
as you progress
in other words often I even think of you Susan
when you pass
that kind of thing
that's just my question
how to handle grief
yeah
let's see
page 91
okay
thank you
it's not the easiest thing
it's more emotional
and it's such a common experience
all of mankind's experience grief
all of mankind's
experience grief
you mentioned before
it was all non-verbal the feeling of it
and you mentioned grief can be many lifetimes of grief
or something
yes every negativity you pull up
has been accumulated throughout all of
your human
incarnations
so it's the collective
grief that you're letting go of
that you've collected all these lifetimes
see many times we didn't process
out a thing we just suppressed it
and then it comes up again later
but now there's more of it
because you've suppressed it so often
just allow it
to flow and don't resist it
don't call it grief don't call it anything
there's something coming up
and you stop resisting it whatever it is
you just let go resisting it
the longest run I had was 10 days
around the clock non-stop
10 days that energy came up
I forget which one it was
so you're
releasing all the accumulated
of all of that
thank you
over these years out of this
vale of tears
hi I just came to say thank you
yes
you got it it's a vibrational frequency
in the aura
hi doctor yes
my question is
the Holy Spirit
and Kundalini
are those two
semantic ways
to refer to the same thing
yes
thank you
did you want to sign that
did you want to sign that oh yes
yes you see because you become
a suitable vessel it begins to flow through you
and as every
you know stated in lectures it used to flow out
the heart go down
pour into some accent
the wheels are still turning on the overturned car
and then around
the bend the next bend a couple of miles
beyond was another accident
same way
this energy unasked of its own
began to flow out
that happened often
for a long time
and the energy performed
what the world would call the miraculous
from a linear
expectation the chances were zero
this energy does it
of its own
no intention there's no this
causing of that
the energy flows to where it's needed
performs its magic
and
you're the witness
now that's another downfall
because he brought up the downfalls
on the way is to
personalize
the city the energies
to personalize it
and think it's you
it's not you that's causing it at all
the miraculous
anybody who claims
the miraculous is
the consequence of the
effect of that energy
in the scientific domain
I spoke of it this morning
or whatever his name is
instead of causality
of being
an expression
of force
it's an expression
of power
which is what I've explained all along
the infinite field of consciousness
is infinitely powerful
and that which you are
automatically aligns itself within the field
of consciousness
so
you can't do anything to you
God doesn't do something to you
thank you
that which is attracted to fire gets burned up
by the consequence of that which it is
and God doesn't punish you by
burning you up
you jumped into the fire yourself
can I have a picture
of both of you
yes
I was just going to say
smile for the birdies you collected
how would you describe
compassion
compassion is the inclusion
of the equality of all that exists
so that instead of
identifying with an isolated
individual
that you identify
with the unfolding of life
itself
compassion is
intuiting the sacredness of all of life
the divinity of all
creation
thank you
you see the sacredness of all that exists
I mean
it stands out
when you reach a certain level
it stands out from everything
it makes it difficult to function
for a while frankly
I have trouble with this concept
of the lack of
relationship between cause and effect
particularly in the case of
a pool where one billiard ball hits another one
it seems like there is a clear
Newtonian design
but I can see that in human beings
in human relations
I find it difficult to accept
in a pure physical sense
can you help me to
get over that hurdle
you mean in the physical
or the human
one billiard ball hitting another
there is a clear cause and effect
no there is no clear cause and effect
you are projecting that belief system
onto it
well that is probably true
how do I get over that
oh ok
got any hints
yes
what you see is emergence
of potentiality
into actuality
when the conditions are appropriate
alright
half unfolded rose
is anything going to cause it
to unfold to a full rose
you can't cause it
no matter what you do
it has within it the potential
under appropriate conditions
warmth, sun and light
each thing is unfolding
alright
the potentiality of this can
is that it is going to be tipped up in the air
or I can just dump it on the ground
and say it is bad for you
you know what I mean
so there is an infinite number of choices
so local conditions
are going to influence
the likelihood
of its emergence into an actuality
if you sort of meditate on emergence
you will see everything
is the emergence of a potentiality
your being up on the stage
is not caused by anything
you held it as a value
and my being here was held as a value
consequently
we emerged in the scene
you know at the same time
you know
nothing caused me to come here
and nothing caused you to be here
nothing caused you to ask a question
nothing caused me to answer it
well the intention then
is
one of the upcoming classes
that we are going to do
on the alternate months
is you know a dream I have
to be the teacher
with no exchanges of money
we don't have to hire a place
that you can just have free exchange
of dialogue
and I thought that is what is ideal
you can walk around barefoot
and just dialogue with people
you don't have to rent a hall
or anything
and so in the modern world though
you got to have insurance
and you got to have a staff
and you got big maintenance
and clean up afterwards
and parking places
and it is very big
so you hold in mind
what you hold in mind tends to manifest
maybe you can see it that way
so having held that in mind
is the ideal setting
what is happening is
currently is about to emerge
so it is the emergence
of potentiality
I know what he means
he has been scientifically
educated
in science
I have two questions
what is the harmonic conversions
I don't know anything about it
what is it
I don't know
oh I don't know
the consciousness of humanity went up
oh the timing of it
was concordant
the harmonic concordance
at that time
it wasn't caused by it
so what caused it
nothing caused it
did you just listen to the last gentleman
ok
very quickly
are you related
the potentiality existed within mankind
ok
and it happened at the most propitious time
all the people praying
all the people forgiving
there was at the time
back in the 80's
I think it was
whenever it was
people held hands all around the highways
people prayed all over the world
at the same time
and the consciousness level of mankind
jumped as a result
do you have any suggestions
how to overcome the ego
to be special or overcome negativities
with the ego
do the course of miracles
ok
it deals with specialness
one of the downfalls
of gurus
is specialness
even the term guru
is no longer
in the book
we had no one using the term
about the time of the Beatles
the term guru fell
glamour, money
thank you very much
the guy wants lots of followers
what do you want lots of followers for
haven't you got enough problems
I can't answer the email now
thank you very much
Merry Christmas
yeah
I was sure
I was going to get some help today
with an issue I've been working on
for the last year
but I got a call at lunch time
that made me request
if I could trade my question for a prayer
my
stepson has been struggling
along his own
karmic path as it is
with addictions etc
and last night
his father committed suicide
your stepson committed suicide
no his father did
the stepson's father
yeah
so I was wondering if
now or at some time
and I also asked the people here
if they could pray for
people why
one has a drug problem
the stepson has a drug problem
and his father committed suicide
so if we could have some kind of unity prayer
oh yes
what kind of prayer would you hold in mind
I would hold that
Evan my stepson is
given strength
to continue along his
path some strength
what about his own karmic
option and choice
do you want us to cheat him out of his karmic inheritance
I don't
of his own he makes the decision
however we can create the field
in which the likelihood of us choosing positive
is supported by all of us collectively
that would be good
so let us all collectively hope for the best
for the people that you mentioned
and it's up to the will of God
up to the old lord
and the karmic inheritance
of all the people
and we apologize for interjecting
our volition
to the matter which is probably not of our
concern
we do appeal to thee
for thy divine mercy
Amen