And so each one represents a level of consciousness.
We first presented the levels of human consciousness,
and we see that integrity, the major one to worry about is 200.
Once you get over 200, the rest is certain.
People are already worrying about what their level of consciousness is.
The only thing of any concern is whether you're over 200 or not,
because the rest has a thousand karmic propensities
and has to do with motivation, has to do with a multitude of factors.
Intention, however, drives you through the levels of consciousness
and the work that's involved.
In this lifetime, it was extraordinary, the amount of work at times,
and at the other times, extraordinary in that they were spontaneous
and not preceded by any work.
So there's no predictable cause and effect.
A person says, I've been doing these mudras,
I've been doing these hand positions,
I've been doing these breathing exercises,
I've been doing the meditating, and I'm not getting anywhere.
You know, instantly his consciousness level just jumped.
He was trying to artificially control, you understand?
Artificially control your level of consciousness
instead of just letting it be that which you have become.
You become that which is kindly, considerate, humorous.
See the humor in life.
It's a great blessing.
Some people cry in agony all the way to the chopping block.
Oh, me, they're chopping my head off today, you know.
Easy come, easy go.
As an old head chopper, I was telling them,
it's only going to hurt for a second.
It's only going to hurt for a second.
Don't worry about a thing.
That's the truth.
What I just stated is the truth.
I wasn't lying.
In one second, no more pain, no more suffering.
There's a body and this dopey head rolling around.
The French peasants are jumping up and down with glee.
That's why they call them peasants.
That's what the French aristocracy thought.
Peasant.
So each one then is a way of perceiving the world, perceiving yourself.
It has to do with a certain level of energy and power.
It has to do with the degree to which the kundalini energy,
has become dominant.
And of course, there's the classic chakra system,
in which the spiritual energy is envisioned as flowing up the chakra system.
Which again, is really analogous rather than a literality.
Nobody ever measured it, except us.
I was going to say, nobody ever measured it,
and then I realized we're measuring it all the time, aren't we?
So the level of consciousness, then, is what the number denotes.
It does not mean better than.
Because what appeals to you, at a given time in life,
may be quite different than what appeals to you,
and becomes meaningless later.
Probably the spiritual teachers,
with the most popular impact,
are those that probably calibrate in the mid-200s,
not in the 700s.
We go, ooh and ahh at 700.
But it's the people who teach goodwill,
honesty,
you know, I'm a fan of the Boy Scouts,
the Boy and Girl Scouts,
and the Scouts calibrate around 460, or somewhere around there.
The Scouts calibrate around over 450,
460,
455.
The Scouts calibrate at 455.
So instead of going all the way to India and seeking Guru Ba-Ba-Drum-Drum,
I suggest you join the Scouts.
The Scouts are at 455,
and that Guru who used to be high, is now,
you know, at 140,
and sleeps with everybody.
So,
have holy sex, right.
Things that people can sell themselves, hysterical.
So, an integrous teaching of a lower number.
So what you see often attracts people to more advanced teachers
is the glamour of the more advanced teacher.
It's just the glamour.
Spirituality, like anything else, can become a glamour,
like popularity, like money, like titles.
They're just glamourized.
Oh, he calibrates at 70 to 95.
Except you don't know what the hell he's talking about.
That's the problem.
It's not too helpful if you don't know what the person means.
You know, Ramana Maharishi says,
there's no point in lamenting the world,
or intervening, or trying to do something about it,
because the world you see doesn't even exist.
It's all perception.
Well, that's true in the level 700.
But it'd be a spiritual error not to do something to help the world
when you're calibrating at 260.
And you have your choice between service towards others or selfishness.
The world you see doesn't even exist,
but that is so at that level.
It is not so at 250.
Katrina, or Kachina, or whatever the name of that horror hurricane was,
tornado, whatever that thing was,
knocked down a zillion people.
Yes.
So your perception of it then is reflection of your level of consciousness.
And what you feel called to do depends on that.
You cannot be false to yourself.
You have to be true to yourself.
You see yourself as a fellow human.
I should do what I can to be helpful.
Then that's what you're called upon to do at that level.
If you're at a different level,
and you see this karmic consequence,
a group karma,
and nothing to do with individuals or causality or anything like that,
then you can do nothing about it.
But it's not so until it's so.
It's not so until it's so.
So we can't be false to ourself.
Your own self be true means,
however you see it,
is what your obligation is.
So our karmic obligation is dependent on
our culpability
and responsibility are two different things.
Responsibility is one thing.
Culpability is another.
Responsibility is a karmic given.
If you take somebody's life, you owe a life.
That's independent of culpability.
Culpability has to do with the degree of awareness.
If the child pulls out a gun from his parents' dresser drawer
and shoots somebody,
his culpability is zero.
But he is accountable.
And he will have to pay back the life in another life.
What I just said is true.
He owes a life.
Karmically, you owe a life because you took a life.
However, the culpability may be zero.
And even the courts recognize
the degree of responsibility.
And the imbecile, the so-called retarded person, etc.,
is seen to be operating under impaired responsibility.
And therefore, their culpability is less.
However, they are still accountable.
So if you make a pledge, you're accountable.
If this is what you pledge,
then this is what you give
if you leave that particular group.
That's the oath you took.
So you see,
we've tried to include some,
probably the most easily recognized.
There are some more popular,
which I have on another list,
currently alive.
And they are popularizers of spirituality.
Popularizers.
And very often they're a good place to start.
Because they get you excited about the whole subject.
Give you a place to start.
Some of them are extremely well known, you know.
Pot and Jelly, 715.
How do you pronounce his name?
Patanjali or Pot and Jelly?
Nobody here knows.
We in Dyer calls them Pot and Jelly.
And I was thinking of them as Patanjali.
All right, so,
we see Father Pio.
Father Pio, you know,
one of the ways he exhibited the cities was
by location.
To be several places at once.
And of course that would sound very odd to a skeptic.
And the skeptic dictionary didn't approve of Father Pio.
Because such a thing is beyond linear probability.
Beyond linear probability.
I've never been two places at once.
But you can disappear time.
Yes.
You can disappear distance.
By letting go, resisting the experiencing of time.
I used to do it routinely.
Driving from Phoenix to Sedona.
Which is very boring after you've done it a couple hundred times.
And by letting go, resisting the subjective experiencing of time.
Which you do continuously.
Not as a thought.
But you feel the experiencing of time.
And you let go, resisting it.
Because you're impatient to get to Sedona.
It's late at night, etc.
If you constantly let go, resisting the experiencing of time,
time disappears.
And all of a sudden within a minute you're in Sedona.
It's like you leave Phoenix at 10.01 and at 10.03 you're in Sedona.
Subjective experiencing.
I used to do it routinely.
So you can use these kind of techniques.
The letting go of resisting.
Of anything that you find onerous or difficult.
The letting go of resisting of anything.
Even the subjective experiencing of time itself.
You can even let go of resisting your own existence.
That's one you can save.
Let go of resisting your own experience.
Because the delusion is, if you don't keep recreating it,
you will come to an end.
And that's what it means that the self is reborn every split second.
That unless you intend the continuation of your own existence,
you will come to an end.
That's a fact.
That you, what you think is the you, will come to an end.
Ecstatically to an end.
Ecstatically.
Alright, so you can disappear time.
Now you can see you can disappear the resistance to anything.
The world is your oyster.
Anything you want you can let go of resisting having money.
Let's do that.
Let go of resisting having money.
Let go of resisting the wanting to have money.
Be crazy to have money.
Go insane to have money.
Let go of resisting it.
And finally you say, no one needs money, right?
So who needs it anyway?
You let go of it.
And then suddenly your aunt leaves you a million.
I tell this story in the book about Greta.
You know what I told Greta?
Who came over from Ireland without a nickel.
I don't know how far she got in school.
Sixth grade.
Went to work for one of the most famous rich families in the country.
Lived in the Locust Valley around where I live.
And they hired her as a bookkeeper, as a housekeeper.
And Greta was so integrous and so dedicated to the family and the children.
I think I told this story before.
That at dinner time the old man would give her tips on the stock market.
Take your hundred dollars Greta and invest it in a Zanza.
It would triple within a week, of course.
Because it was insider training, illegal nowadays.
I had somebody come to me one time and he says,
Look, give me $10,000 and I'll make it go up ten times within 48 hours.
Because I know what this company is going to do.
I turned it down.
I was pure and poor.
What did you do with my teachers?
So at each level you get attracted to certain things.
So which teacher is meaningful to you is many factors including many unknown karmic factors.
We see that Father Pugh represents first of all the background of Catholicism.
So some of the teachers represent the emergence and most mystics emerge beyond many of them.
A large number that are well known to the world.
Emerged out of various religions.
The highest level of awareness is always the mystic.
Even though the mystic is a member of a certain religious organization or whatever.
The mystic who shoots over a level 600 does so by becoming the truth from within.
And may or may not hang around the religion.
In which this arose later on.
But it's merely the setting.
Because there's mystics in every religion.
Every major religion.
The mystic is one in whom who has followed the evolution of consciousness such as we've described.
And now the truth shines forth of its own radiance from within.
It's not acquired as a book learning or a memorization.
It has nothing to do with liturgy.
It has nothing to do with ecclesiastic approval.
It has to do with an inner awareness.
People who have done severe physical exertion to the point of exhaustion.
I give the example I've given.
Susan has had the experience.
You push yourself to the absolute limit beyond which you cannot go.
That could be an endeavor such as walking barefoot across the desert.
Whatever it is.
You push yourself to the limit beyond which you cannot go.
And now you refuse the limit.
And you shoot past the impossible.
And you move into the incredible.
And that's what I call the Roger Bannister effect.
You push the human endurance past to the level that science says you cannot.
And then you refuse.
You refuse with an iron like savage will.
And that's when it's time to get yang.
The time to get yang is when you run up the mountain.
You run up against the I can't.
And that's when you crash through the I can't.
Instantly you're in a different dimension which is effortless.
All the boxes that you couldn't lift anymore are now weightless.
I remember being in that warehouse exhausted after 12 hours of work and that heat.
I cannot lift another box.
And there was like gritting your teeth and all of a sudden it was effortless.
The body was like feather.
The boxes lifted themselves.
And dawn, it went all night long.
Dawn was there and they said, you haven't been to bed yet?
No.
The same happens when you go into a state of ecstasy where you can dance effortlessly hour after hour.
And those cities are available to any spiritual student.
They arise as an opportunity to exceed the limitation.
Because the limitation is the belief system.
If you're only subject to what you hold in mind, then you have a belief that you're limited.
That you can only lift so many boxes.
That you've been so many hours without food.
You've been so many hours without water.
And that it's not physically possible to continue on.
That's a lie.
It is possible to continue on.
Not you as a person, but your beingness can go on because your beingness is unlimited.
It can keep on working and working and working.
So these are things we hear about.
Father Pio's miraculous things.
We hear about the great saint, Saint Patrick, that launched Christianity in Ireland.
Of course, he's very famous.
And corned beef and cabbage was named that.
Yogananda is extremely well known.
Autobiography of a yoga.
And he has a place started in California.
Some of the other teachers come from other cultures.
And we're not familiar with them.
However, their writings are extremely familiar to many people.
I met Yogananda himself.
And he was a fun guy.
And he used to take these orange hats and throw them in the audience.
During the lecture.
Because there would be a crowd around him.
And the crowd knew that his energy was in the orange hats.
So he had a pile of orange hats.
He'd wear one for five minutes.
And then he'd throw it in the audience.
And everybody would take it home because they knew his energy was in there.
His energy at that time was 655.
But met Yogananda anyway.
It was fun.
So what I'm trying to say is the spiritual evolution is progressive.
It should bring you into progressive joy.
It's not the same thing as piety.
Piety and saintliness is a very nice thing.
Especially when you're on TV.
And the robes sway nicely.
And your sandals go clip-clop.
Now those are distortions of reality.
Because spiritual integrity is very, very, normally, honestly, that which is.
It doesn't have to pretend to be anything else.
It is exactly what it is.
And it's so completely satisfied with that which it is.
It doesn't have to imitate that which it is.
Which it is not.
So one thing we'd say about these teachers, then,
is that they all represent an intrinsic integrity
with nothing to gain, nothing to sell, no desire to control anybody.
The Buddha recommended enlightenment
as a way to avoid the pain of reincarnation
and going through the pain and misery of humanness.
Getting born and dying, sickness, old age, poverty and death.
And I'm recommended too.
Because at a certain point you don't care about sickness, old age, poverty and death.
You know, it's irrelevant.
You've got an apple for dinner, what more do you want?
You've got a cot to sleep on, there's a wooden box.
And the only thing is the big desert centipedes do crawl around
and give you a little heebie-jeebies once in a while.
But other than that, poverty is perfectly fine, you know.
And whatever you need arises out of the occasion.
It arises not as a matter of causality.
It emerges as a consequence of the occasion.
So we're going to stop now so that we have more to talk about later.
We're going to make the afternoon a little shorter as far as the lecture goes.
So we have more time for questions and answers.
I would like to see us eventually move into workshops
that are a lot of interaction with the people here.
A lot of, you know, it grabs you to, you want me to explain more about that?
You say, what's that?
What's more about that?
In which we become more spontaneously interactive with each other, you know.
And get away from this artificiality that the teacher up there
and us down here, you know what I'm saying?
And it's actually all of us here, isn't it?
So I'd really like people to, I'd really, the best way I'd like to teach
would be to wander through the audience and people spontaneously bring up
what is coming up in the field, you see.
Because you people are the field and all these heads here
are picking up the thoughts and the feelings.
So it's, you know, the teacher is what's sitting in the chair.
The teacher, this is just the responder to the teacher.
So the way I'd like to teach is wander through the audience
and people just pop up with whatever they got and they answer back.
That will drive Robert crazy, but the man in the wall says the mechanics of that
are difficult and the TV people, of course, they also say that's difficult
to handle the mechanics.
Jesus didn't have that problem.
The great saints of old didn't have to get focused on TV
and turn up the volume on the recorder, you see.
But they served a different function.
But now that you see the speed of spiritual evolution is very rapid.
And one is mass media, one is people here by the thousands.
That which was only heard by a dozen favorite people years ago.
Now it's available to everyone.
So I'll conclude with this finality.
The chances of becoming enlightened today are over 1,000 times greater than in the past.
Over 1,000 times.
Let's just confirm that.
Over 1,000 times. Resist.
So you can get off the excuse that it's very, very rare.
And therefore it doesn't apply to me.
It's okay for me to not be enlightened because it hardly ever happens.
That was then.
Now is now. Get busy.
We're all here because we're all here because we're all here because we're all here.
Serious spiritual work, it's hard to remain serious.
Why? Because you're constantly confronted by absurdity.
You know, absurdity.
Perception versus essence.
So when you put the two together, you get humor, you know.
Yep. Where were we?
Oh, yes, right.
Integra spiritual teachers.
Well, there's great popularization of spiritual fiction.
And the naive students and people who are interested in spirituality
think that's what spirituality is.
You know, best sellers.
And the thing that I don't like about them is they don't make it clear that it's fiction.
And they state it as though it's true.
Suddenly a saint appears next to you, you see.
And that's, you know, it's a writer's fiction.
It's not a reality.
That is not the reincarnation of St. Patrick or something like that.
So there's all kinds of spiritual fiction.
And people get it confused.
And the spiritual fiction is also the lure for the child within
who likes the imaginative and the fantastic.
So the more fantastic the climb, the bigger the sales, you'll notice.
Jesus and Mary were married and their children became the aristocracy of France
and all such BS.
The trouble is the naive seeker considers that truth, you know.
And so there's an interesting book out called Odd Gods.
Odd Gods by James Lewis.
Odd Gods and the Cult Phenomena.
It's a pretty thick book.
The thing I like it...
That is funny, isn't it?
It is a pretty thick book, yeah.
Books of spiritual truth are slim.
What I like about it is he gives you many examples.
And by the examples, you get the drift of it, how it comes about.
And you can see what it attracts.
It attracts the innocent child with us.
Within us who like magic and fantasy and the fantastic.
So many things that are called, considered by the populace, the spiritual,
are really, you know, the fantastic.
Harry Potter books, at least, you know, it's clear from the beginning
you're talking about a trueness story.
But these books, you know, I know that people take it serious
because some highly intelligent people write me long dissertations about this.
Yeah.
About what's the one with the painting from my...
Da Vinci.
Da Vinci, yeah, right.
No end of the Da Vinci crap I got.
Emails and stuff.
I mean, no end, you know.
So that's why I calibrated some of it for the book
because I want to point out to people there's spiritual fiction
and there's spiritual reality, you know.
The reality doesn't sound as appealing as the fantasy and the fiction.
Which appeals to the romantic.
So within us all is the child and the child's curiosity,
the child's naivety, impressionability, and people become misled.
So where were we on the slides?
We were someplace or other.
Yes.
And so we wanted to go over those.
These, of course, this is 144, plus I got another 20 here,
which I've lost someplace.
They're more contemporary.
But this should do, you know.
You just take one and follow it through,
and that'll take you to 605,
so you don't need another book until you get past 605.
If you just do the one thing consistently.
All right, so the thing, the magic of spiritual work
is actually consistency.
Sincerity, of course, integrity.
But the consistency with which you do it.
So you could say, well, I heard, you know, from the doc the other day
that if you just let go, resisting, experiencing the passage of time,
you go outside of time.
But it may take a while to do that.
You may continually do it and continually do it.
It doesn't mean the first time you do it, it's going to work this fast.
But if you persist in it, let go resisting the passage of time,
let go resisting it, let go resisting the passage of time,
let go resisting it, let go resenting it,
you go outside of time.
And within no time at all,
you find yourself back in Sedona on the scene.
So all of these things take a certain persistence.
Why? Because there's a certain karmic momentum.
I don't call it, you're not determined by karma,
I call them propensities,
which you inherit once you have an etheric body,
which is your spiritual history encapsulated, you might say,
in a vibrational form,
is a propensity.
But it's not predetermination.
Karma doesn't mean predetermination.
Karma means propensity.
Because the evolution of consciousness is over very long periods of time.
Very long periods of time.
And the evolution of one's consciousness,
consciousness,
at a certain point, as I say,
is that you remember previous lives,
it may happen spontaneously,
or there's various techniques.
The only time I think it's really important,
past life recall,
is if you are stuck with something.
And I say the way to get out of a stuckness
is see what's happening in your life,
let's say you're the victim of,
or picture yourself as the victim of,
what you pray for is the one within you
who did that to others.
Don't bother praying for yourself,
it's a waste of time.
People are always cheating me,
I'm always getting, you know,
I get them home and there's only ten eggs in the carton.
If you're always being shortchanged,
and always being taken advantage of by others,
then what you pray for
is the one in you who shortchanges others.
Always give it a 180.
Always presume that all the stuff in your life
you don't want is the karmic consequence
of you having done it to others.
You don't have to believe it,
I'm not asking you to believe it,
I'm just asking you to try it,
because it's a fact.
Everybody's rude to me.
Alright, so, now you don't recall
the one in you who's rude to others,
for one thing you don't recall that lifetime maybe,
but the other thing you don't realize,
is that we collectively inherit
the collective consciousness of mankind.
Carol Young was correct,
there's a collective unconscious,
so even though you personally don't remember
such a belief system,
nevertheless, you live in our society
in which you're getting programmed constantly.
Alright, I never in my life believed in osteoporosis
affecting myself or men in general.
I thought it was for little old ladies bent over.
Alright, if you're only subject
to what you hold in mind,
then how can you get osteoporosis
unless you believed in it?
I personally never believed in it
as being the potential to afflict
this person here,
who was all very vigorous.
And I was a star dancer,
you know what I'm saying?
I was a star dancer.
I could dance any dance, yeah.
That came out of a lifetime too once.
Anyway, you pick it up.
You say, I don't remember ever believing in it.
Yes, but you sat through a TV commercial
all about osteoporosis
and taking this, that, and the other thing.
You picked it up, you picked it up.
Alright, so just presume
that whatever is coming down in your life
you picked up somewhere.
Why is it so?
Well, how do things come about?
They come about by the power of mind,
that which you hold in mind
as a belief system.
You see, the physical body is incapable
of experiencing its own existence.
It's only because of the senses
that you're aware of what goes on in the body.
You're not experiencing the body,
you're experiencing the sensations of the body.
How do you know the body is there?
Because of the feelings.
So you're not even experiencing the body,
you're experiencing the senses.
That's why the Buddha called the brain a sense organ.
Even the feelings have no capacity
to experience themselves.
It's because there's something greater
than the feelings
in which they can be experienced.
And that is in consciousness itself.
The body is insentient.
Do you know the body cannot experience anything?
The body is not capable of experiencing anything.
Experience is of a different dimension,
a higher dimension.
The body is not able to experience
even that it exists.
It's because of feelings.
And feelings are then,
because that's an awareness of the mind.
The mind can't know what it's thinking.
It's only because the mind
is in something greater than itself
which illuminates what the mind is thinking
called consciousness.
That which you are then is the infinite
out of which all the sequence occurs.
What is held in mind then begins to manifest
within the physical body.
So if I develop osteoporosis,
therefore I have picked it up somewhere
in our culture,
I've picked it up from the collective mind,
or I'm holding it from some previous lifetime, yes?
So the way to get unhooked from some karmic probability
or potentiality likelihood,
if it keeps recurring in your life,
just give it an okay that it's likely
a karmic propensity.
And therefore do a 180 on it.
Everybody's shortchanging you,
then you have to apologize
and ask for forgiveness for the one in me.
Why?
Because I picked up an identification
with the collective,
and the one who cheats others is part of you
by virtue of the collective unconscious,
by virtue of the fact you identify yourself
as a human.
Wham!
You just pulled in the entire karma
of being human.
So there's the personal experience,
there's the personal past life,
which can be very, very specific,
by the way, very specific.
Once you learn how to rerun them,
it's amazing how specific they are.
You see exactly what happened
and the exact why of it,
and now you're empowered to undo of it,
undo of it.
And I remember,
I don't know whether this, you know,
share any past lives with you at all,
but anyway,
I remember one time,
I could never dance,
I was Mr. Clubfoot,
and I was too inhibited.
And one time in sort of a high state,
I suddenly recalled a lifetime
as a temple dancer.
Instantly I could dance.
Instantly I became an expert dancer.
I could dance any kind of dance,
and I still can.
Interpretive, ballet, disco,
western.
I was president of the country western dance club,
you know, I was a dancing fool.
So once I learned how to dance,
this frustration of my whole life,
I went dancing all the time.
So undoing the one karmic thing
unleashed the capacity to dance.
So how would you have the talent
to be able to do all that kind of dancing?
Where would you get the talent?
Well, I was a very good temple dancer.
I was a very excellent temple dancer.
And I can still do temple dancing for you,
but anyway,
it came out of that lifetime.
So then once you're freed of it,
you can tell right away
you just got freed of it.
You just like know it.
That's sort of interesting.
So I'll tell you a few lifetimes
once in a while just for fun.
Probably the most important one.
I forget the circumstances in which I recall it.
I was shackled to oars.
I was a slave on a slave ship.
And shackled with chains to the oar.
And this guy who sets the beat,
you know, I wasn't able to keep up with it.
And he came over and started beating me.
So he's beating me.
And I'll never forget the smell of that galley.
God, it stunk because
you got water running down behind you.
You're chained, you see, to this bar.
And everybody just, you know,
relieves themselves and the water
rushes in from the sea and washes it out.
And I reached the point of absolute exhaustion.
And I knew.
And I was holding on.
Holding on, holding on, holding on.
And this guy was never going to stop beating on me.
And suddenly it came to me out of nowhere
in just that lifetime
that I'm not a slave.
I'm not captured.
And I let go of life, my physical life.
Instantly went into spirit and I was free.
I cannot be enslaved because that which I am
is beyond the physical.
And that knowingness came to me in that instant
that I could let go.
And there I was, free
of all that pain and suffering and agony.
What a happy spirit, yes.
Free, free, forever free.
Okay, now we're going back to the spiritual teachers.
And so those things come to you spontaneously
at a certain level.
And if you're stuck with something,
presume that there's something behind that stuckness.
And with a little research,
you can sometimes find your way out of it.
And it sort of comes to you as a sudden flash.
You can say, dear God,
I don't know why I'm stuck with this.
And dear God, you see,
it's like your mudra,
your way of being is a prayer.
You ask God for the miracle
of seeing what lies behind this.
Sometimes you get a vision.
Sometimes you get a rerun.
Sometimes it's just a remark somebody says.
I got an insight into something that came up
just at lunchtime.
It just came up spontaneously.
Whoa, I can see why that happens.
Whoa.
It was not the consequence of logical thought.
So being receptive,
making your life for prayer,
is a very yin position,
yin position, yin position,
in which you are open to divine inspiration.
And it's like a quality of divinity
that it cannot refuse.
It isn't arbitrary.
It's like it can't refuse
the invitation when that supplication
is at a deep level of humility
and absolutely genuine,
absolutely genuine.
So that's the power of the yin.
The life, the worldly life imagines
that the power all belongs to the yang,
to the masculine.
No, the power belongs to the yin.
A yin by this attraction
can kill a thousand men.
What did you do to kill them?
I stood back,
and I allowed them to be themselves,
and they slaughtered each other,
did they not?
So there's no point in
emphasizing the advantage of one sex or the other,
because they both have their own intrinsic style.
Masculinity is a style,
and femininity is a style,
but they're of equal power,
as any man knows.
All she does is go,
but honey,
wow,
his day has just got changed.
Puts away the golf bags,
gets out the lawn mower,
my mother-in-law is coming,
and look at the lawn.
Okay, honey, don't be worried.
All she did is raise an eyebrow,
isn't that right?
She raised one eyebrow,
she changes the world.
He's up there pushing and trying to make it all happen,
and she just goes,
so much for my view of the masculine and the feminine.
All right, so we'll go back to the written word here.
We're going to stop a little earlier today than usually,
because we're going to get more time for questions and discussions.
So I was just ruminating, you know,
I got to meet some of the people here.
And Robert Monroe,
Monroe is the Monroe Institute,
teaches you in all your state of consciousness
where you can go out of the body.
I went out of the body spontaneously
long before it was popular.
Nobody wrote about near-death experiences or out of body.
In fact, I was in psychoanalysis at the time,
and I was deathly ill.
All of a sudden, I was out there in the middle of space.
The complete sense of who you are is there,
except for the physicality.
You look at the physicality,
and I'll tell you it's very boring and not too attractive looking there.
I don't know, every time you're out of body,
you look at the physical body and you're like,
anyway,
it's a really nothing experience.
But out of body, you know, you can think, feel, see.
All the senses are operative.
And I told you about the time I went to the Monroe Institute
and learned how to go out of body at will.
And I docked back in the body upside down,
180 degrees out of phase.
I'm looking out the back of my head at the floor,
and I had to come out this way and go back in that way.
Journeys out of the body.
Journeys out of the body is a fun, fun book.
Because nobody knew anything about such phenomena at that time.
Near-death experience or out of body was not heard of.
And Monroe began to spontaneously experience this.
And he would have these amorous adventures,
and then he'd come back in his body with his wife,
and he'd be stricken with guilt.
It's a very funny book.
And he'd gotten into some lower astral realms
and various places like that.
So when we did the Monroe,
and learned how to go out of body,
you had to come back in the body at a whistle.
It was like,
because people would get involved in various adventures
in various astral realms.
And so you had to make sure you were safe
before they let you out there.
So they would train you how to get out there,
but then you were trained at the sound of this whistle
to come back in the body.
And that's how I shot back in the body
and discovered I was upside down.
The interesting thing about Monroe,
who I think is deceased now,
he had the greatest voice I ever heard.
If you ever get a chance to get a tape
or something by Robert Monroe,
he had a sound of intrinsic peace within his voice
that was just amazing.
Just spoke from a level of absolute inner peace.
Really a mystical, incredible gift he had.
Yeah.
So the Muktananda I met, Monroe I met,
the others are really from different cultures,
different cultures,
and different times.
And this is probably the best known
because of Wayne Dyer,
Patanjali, he calls him.
Father Pio is extremely well known also.
The last pope was at 570.
I think this pope was at 565.
Approximately the same.
The last pope was 570,
which is a saintly beneficence towards all.
Sort of a wholeness and oneness.
And he was, of course, quite saintly.
Plotinus is also extremely well known.
Huang Po, I think I spoke to you before.
The difficulty with Huang Po,
if you follow him literally,
to negate the reality of the linear,
we've already covered,
you will end up at the void,
which calibrates at 850.
And the void is not where you want to end up.
Many naive Buddhists,
in fact we get emails from,
end up at 800,
which is the void.
This is the belief system,
this is the outcome of a belief system,
that the ultimate reality is nothingness.
That is a trap, you know.
So he taught, you know,
to let go of belief,
any belief or attachment in the linear.
Thereby you end up in,
he presumed, in the non-linear.
At the time he wrote it,
he was at 850.
And what he was talking about,
I have gotten complaints from email
about people who landed in the void,
and now what?
No, the void is not the absolute state
of nothingness.
The absolute state is allness, allness.
The thing that differentiates the two
is that the ultimate state
is filled and pervaded and predominant
predominantly,
predominantly exquisite love
of an incredible quality beyond description.
It's no thingness
but with the quality of divinity.
See, the qualities of divinity.
We have a slide on that at the end.
After he reached that state
in which he wrote
The Pathway of Negation,
he himself discovered the error
and went on to 960 before he died.
But he never wrote anything after that.
So the last thing he wrote
is The Pathway of Negation at 850.
But then he himself went on.
It's very hard to write at those higher levels.
So he may have,
I don't know how long before he died,
but he discovered the ultimate truth.
The ultimate truth calibrates at 1000.
Nothingness, the void, calibrates at 850.
But we've already mentioned that,
and I think I explained it in the book
that's coming out soon.
The error of a misunderstanding Hoang Po.
Robert Powell, of course,
is extremely well known.
All these Swamis are well known.
Ramakrishna is extremely well known.
I remember Ramakrishna's state.
I went into the state that Ramakrishna described.
And as I went into it,
I knew Ramakrishna.
I was all alone in the chapel
here in Sedona at midnight.
In those days they didn't lock the chapel.
The music stayed on all night.
The candles were on all night.
There weren't all the tourists that there are now.
The chapel was unlocked at night.
So I went in there to meditate
and went into an ecstatic state.
Ecstatic state in which you could dance forever.
You could dance for hours.
The dancing was
because of the exquisite joy of ecstasy.
It was the energy field of ecstasy
and it makes you tireless.
You could dance for hours.
So I danced all by myself in front of the altar
to express my joy to God.
Ecstasy. Tireless.
That was the state described by Ramakrishna.
Swami Ram Dass is not as well known by others,
but I have a number of books by him.
And this is a different Sai Baba,
not Sathya.
He's a different Sai Baba.
Lisa Sonella I met out in California.
I believe he was
a psychiatrist, I think,
and wrote about kundalini energy.
He wrote about kundalini energy.
Satya Dhananda also.
I got to meet a number of these people.
So Joseph Smith, you know,
started the major church.
Rudolf Steiner, well known.
Master Suzuki, of course,
popularized Zen.
Suzuki is the one that really made it well known
in the United States.
Mother Teresa is 710.
And this is another saint.
Saints, very often at higher levels of consciousness,
people stop being socially active.
So the majority drop out of society.
A few manage to retain a function within the world.
This is an adjustment that's hard to describe.
It's an adjustment that it seems to happen
by virtue of a divine commitment.
It's like a contract made prior to this lifetime
in which the fulfillment of this potential
was part of the agreement,
or the contract, or the, yeah, whatever.
Without that, one disappears from the world.
And most of the people who go over 600 leave the body.
50%, once they reach 600,
leave the body.
And when you hit 600, you'll know what that means.
You're invited to leave.
It's like invitational freedom.
And it's recurred, you know,
a number of times over the years,
one time it happened right in the middle of a lecture.
I got to the end of the aisle,
and the invitation to leave was very strong.
You could just leave.
So you never know when it's gonna happen.
So whether you continue on in the world or not
is really not up to any personal self.
There's nobody that thinks about it
and weighs the pros and cons
and decide I will do this or that.
It's more or less the fulfillment of a potentiality.
So out of gratitude for divinity,
for the awareness that has emerged
out of this awareness itself,
out of gratitude to God,
one then shares that for the good of that which God loves,
which is all of us.
Let's see, where were we?
We were at, did you change this thing on me?
What did you do now?
Look what you've done.
Oh, Monroe.
We had Monroe.
We went down this.
I'm a Krishna.
I get wandering off onto various people I've met.
Just a few of them I didn't meet, you see.
And Socrates, I'm looking forward to rejoining.
Mother Teresa, of course,
was capable of the miraculous
because she looked at the very pits
of the lowest level at which humanity can go
and had the heart, the courage to look it in the face.
Very few people can look it in the face.
Most people can't even stand television or TV.
They can't even stand television depictions of it,
much less look into the heart and soul of it.
And I used to see that in patients brought in,
bound up in wet cloths and all that.
And the question would arise within consciousness,
what God do you wish of me?
And there would be an opening of that soul,
would open itself up.
And in that second,
the moment had just occurred.
And you could see the soul within was healed.
And now whether there was a social recovery or not
was irrelevant because the moment had arisen.
Yeah.
So that's what Mother Teresa did, you see.
And many of these are extremely well known.
Evelyn Underhill, Vivekananda, Alan Watts.
The White Brotherhood, of course,
was written about by Alice Bailey.
And Yaktusraya.
A well-known teacher.
So we can go to the next one, yes.
Is this the next one?
This is the first one.
Are we going backwards or something?
Huh?
Did I talk about these people?
Yes.
James Allen, you know,
he's written a number of books written by Dove Press.
Ramesh Bhalsakar,
I got to spend some time with out in California
about a week or so.
And Eva Sand is well known.
Wallace Black Elk.
Yeah.
Jacob Bohm.
Richard Bucky.
This he wrote, Cosmic Consciousness.
I think he was a physician.
Eric Butterworth, extremely well known.
And this is the origin of Calvinism.
You know, Confucius.
The Dalai Lama, like the Pope,
calibrates about the same.
To be the head of a world church,
you can't be really too high
because all that would not be very interesting.
But 570, you're as saintly as you can get
and still function in the world.
So the Dalai Lama functions in the world.
If he went on to 600,
he would disappear from society.
These are all well-known teachers.
Meister Eckhart, of course,
is extremely well known.
He calibrated over 700.
He seems to me he gets too much into
discussion of the philosophy of theology
instead of the experiential.
The experiential.
To me, the reality is the experiential.
It can be phrased subsequent to the experiential
rather than describing it first.
It seems to me the description should arise
out of the experiential.
What it is to suddenly go from frozen
with the impossibility of dancing,
suddenly.
All movement is spontaneous.
In fact, I remember,
oh yes, I remember the patterns
that come to me back then.
As a spiritual dancer,
what I did was I danced out a pattern.
The pattern was already in my mind.
The body merely imitated the pattern
which preexisted the movement.
So it came about spontaneously
as an acting out of the pattern.
I can remember now as a temple dancer,
what held in mind was not the dance steps
like choreography.
No choreography.
The knowingness of the pattern.
And I become the pattern.
Much like a chromosomal,
the chromosomal spiral about itself
is a spontaneous event.
Non-linear, in other words.
All right.
So, Charles Fillmore.
The Fillmores were very familiar with their work.
Of course, we were on the,
what you would call a committee of the,
I don't know, steering committee of something.
Unity.
Unity, yes.
Yes.
Consciousness research and all.
So we get to go to Unity
and it's a wonderful place to be.
And we examined the original writings of the Fillmores
and calibrated them.
Remember?
We went up in the private library.
Everything was locked and sacrosanct.
The librarian was just sort of speechless.
She wanted us,
so she kept pulling these things out.
And what beautiful handwriting.
I mean, my mind is a scrawl.
But this is like script, you know.
Beautiful handwriting and we calibrated that.
Let's see if we can recapitulate.
I'm holding, okay, I'm holding,
what I'm holding in mind calibrates over 800,
850, 900.
We got about 900.
That as originally written by the Fillmores.
The original, if you ever get a chance to see it,
I don't know if they let people see it.
That inspiration that came out of the heart of Christianity
radiated out at that incredibly high level,
which they then brought down into the 500s,
which is the level of the heart.
So they then were able to communicate
through the world at the level of 500,
which is comprehensible.
You can't really communicate with the world at 900 too well.
Nobody knows what you're talking about.
So Emmett Fox, of course, is a great teacher,
and Mahatma Gandhi,
we wrote about he stood off the British Empire.
The British Empire at the time they confronted Gandhi
was coming from prideful militarism
and calibrated about,
I forget what it calibrated now,
I wrote it in the book.
190, I think, right, pride.
Anyway, Gandhi calibrated 760.
So this is what I mean by standing up for truth.
You see, he didn't wimp out.
Sometimes what's called spirituality to me
is just wimping out.
Gandhi didn't wimp out.
He stood for truth against the entire British Empire,
the most powerful empire the world had ever seen.
When I was born, Britannia ruled the waves.
One-third of the globe was under the dominion
of the British Empire.
And this skinny little 90-pound Indian,
they were called colored,
stood up against the entire British Empire
and defeated it.
Spiritual strength, then, is of the heart.
It's not wimping out.
It's standing up for that which you know to be the reality.
So he stood up against the British Empire,
defeated the entire British Empire.
Didn't that knock you out?
This 90-pound skinny little guy
knocked over the entire British Empire,
its sovereignty.
That was very interesting historically.
And Joel Goldsmith is an extremely well-known writer.
Manly Hall collected some really wonderful things.
Ernest Holmes is also in religious science.
And Vernon Howard.
These are all very well-known names.
Aldous Huxley, the great saints, Karmapa.
I visited the Karmapa.
I was in the presence of the Karmapa,
but did not meet him personally.
Gopi Krishna, of course, his story is well-known.
This is one of the reasons I tell people,
don't try to force the Kundalini.
And Kriyananda, Brother Lawrence,
you know, is the prayer of the heart.
Brother Lawrence, it's in a little booklet.
It was done, I think, in the 1600s.
The practice of the presence of God,
to merely be constantly conscious
of the presence of God within.
A very powerful little book.
And simplicity, without getting into any kind of thinkingness.
These are, of course, two are both well-known to us.
Non-linear, Vedanta, the 700s.
Thomas Burton, extremely well-known.
And here's Moses de Leon of Granada,
who was a rabbi at 720.
And Mukherjee, I like his name, Mukherjee,
at 475.
Have we got another slide?
Is that the next slide?
Or is that the last slide?
That's the last slide.
No, we need the next.
There's two slides on spiritual teachers.
We did them both?
Oh, come on now, you fool.
Okay, let's go ahead then.
All right, we were going to talk about,
yes, what keeps people stuck.
This is the book we're going to have out
at our next meeting, hopefully.
Transcending the Levels of Consciousness.
Susan was one of the main inspirations for that.
She says, the do-it-ness, the do-it-ness.
You've got to write about the do-it-ness.
And so we went back over the calibrated levels of consciousness
and looked at what is holding them in place.
What do they mean?
Usually they're held in attraction and aversion.
So to be spiritually free means
you're not at the effect of attractions or aversions.
Neither attractions nor aversions.
And attractions and aversions are to,
predominantly to the linear.
Money, no money. Health, no health.
Wishing things to be different than they are.
So complete surrender at great depth.
Surrender at great depth
is the letting go of all attractions or aversions.
That way you are completely free.
You're completely clear.
You're not run by attractions or aversions.
Now,
here are the general,
the attraction is in the left-hand column
and the aversion is in the right-hand column.
Most people prefer control.
The idea of giving up control is anathema.
Plus it brings up all kinds of fear.
The fear of surrendering control
then means
letting go, having your life run by the ego.
Now,
the presumption is that you're alive because of the ego.
And the truth is you're alive in spite of the ego.
That your survival is not based on the ego
but the self with a capital S.
It's not the small self
that tells you to look out
and not run off the road.
It's because your self with a capital S
is loving you to the degree that your small self
pays attention.
It's because of the big self that your small self
remembers to take your vitamins.
If it wasn't for my ego,
I wouldn't take my vitamins.
But it's because of your big self
that your small self remembers
that you've got to take your vitamins.
So the pleasure then is being in control
and we're,
our whole society is,
we're all control freaks.
Everybody has to control everything all the time.
And if they don't,
it makes them feel uncomfortable.
Uncomfortable.
Alright.
Also, the anticipated pleasure of stuckness
is it's, it's, it's habit.
You're familiar with it.
And it's easier to hang in with what you know,
what you've been doing rather than change.
Which brings uncertainty and strangeness.
I can remember walking out of the house
with no food and no money.
And I'd written, of course, the miracles that all your,
all your needs would be provided for.
So I said,
well, so it is.
Sure enough.
Around lunchtime, somebody that I knew said,
did you have lunch yet?
I said, no.
He says, yeah, I can't eat all this.
And that's the way it went,
around the clock, day after day.
I never,
but I literally saw anything.
Everything happened,
miraculous, just constantly presented.
So we want to stick in with,
for a feeling of control.
Actually, familiarity and habit
gives you a feeling of control.
Because we're uncertain about what may happen.
We want to cling to the old
instead of being afraid of the,
this also seems to take effort.
The easy way is to stick with the old
and it's hard.
It's easy to hate people,
it's hard to forgive them.
Why is it hard?
Because of the resistance.
It isn't hard to forgive people.
The difficulty is the resistance,
the clinging to wanting to be right
and wanting them to be wrong.
So the,
these,
the effort is not in
these actual steps,
but in overcoming the resistance to them.
People would rather ignore
and not look at a problem
rather than look at it
because they might get upset.
Well, learn to enjoy being upset.
It's fun to be upset.
You get to be real theatrical
and do your whole thing,
stamp up and down, cry.
It's fun.
So go ahead and be upset, please.
For instance, I can't stop being upset
and I tell them,
your problem is you're not upset enough.
You got to get more upset.
I want you to get more upset.
Cry harder, longer, gnash your teeth,
throw yourself on the floor,
have a tantrum.
Boom, boom, boom.
Pretty soon it runs out.
It runs out.
See?
Because when you choose to be this way,
then it loses its power over you.
It only has power
when you ignore it.
Ignoring and resisting it
gives it energy.
Disowning it, of course,
is what we...
We want to disown things
rather than take responsibility
because of guilt.
So if you look at what's blocking the thing,
what is the underlying feeling?
I don't want to take responsibility
because then I would feel guilt.
Then ask yourself,
yes, and why would you feel guilty?
And so you keep on doing it step by step
and eventually it falls apart.
And that's what I'm talking about.
I don't want to be upset.
I want to take responsibility.
Always own what goes on.
Ask what's within you.
If you hear a glass fall off the table,
the question in my mind is
what within myself is that expressing?
Take responsibility for everything that happens.
Something within is expressing itself,
see?
The idea that I can't do a thing,
the truth of it is I won't,
and we've talked about
your banister effect that you can break through the barriers the idea that I
can't do a thing usually means that you won't since I can't let go hating so and
so if I say if we put a loaded gun to your head now could you yeah I could so
that points out it's not that you can't it's that you won't whatever you're
holding you're holding because you won't let it go not because you can't anybody
here think they're the victim of can't well we got one honest person we don't
like to take a look at the fact that we won't because it makes us feel guilty
but you look underneath the eye why is it why is it we are saying we I can't why
is it we say I can't so each the way you advance your consciousness as you go
layer by layer by layer you know because then I would feel anxiety and why would
you feel
anxiety
, because then I would feel prideful and then so you go down the stack and you
undo a stack so what's holding a thing in position is us is always a stack it's
a group of feelings below 200 the truth is I don't want to and people would
rather be repetitious rather than learn in a way that applies to yours truly too
we get all kinds of electronic equipment that you can't learn this car we got a
new car this year we get a new car every five or ten years and it's got a hundred
switches from the driver's seat so help me God I counted a hundred switches to
go across here they go across the top they control everything you can dim and
make your taillights brighter and lower you can make them dance and move and
everything why would old folks be interested in a car like this where's the on-off switch
and the brake that's all I need to know and the gas pedal and the rest of this is some
kind of a mental derangement why because his resistance is to learning he
doesn't want to go into left brain linearity he'd rather be in the more
beautiful space of everything this at once rather than limit himself to a
linear sequential see because this kind of learning is sequential there's a lot
kind of learning however that is not sequential and not linear and that is
spiritual learning
spiritual learning we want to hang on to homeostasis and stability rather than
go shift shift off balance it we like to use the past as an excuse and fail and
fail to acknowledge that the present is the change agent its present is the
change agent willpower is another peculiar one I don't have any willpower
what you mean is willingness
so much is made of willpower and we like to heap guilt on people for not
having used willpower and the the personal will is only as strong as one's
level of consciousness so if your person calibrates at 175 their willpower is
about 175 pedophilia all these things that run below 200 willpower doesn't do
them any good at all is not strong enough at 150 how much willpower you got
you know saying
you try to keep it down them listening only half a dozen kids a week and I'm
saying that's about as far as you get with it
I treated a lot of the arrested for you know 11 sexual assault everyone I ever
treated admitted 150 300 and I'd say how many have you actually get probably
three four hundred five hundred because it's the way of life
you molest one or two kids a week in the year you've got a hundred right two
kids a week you got a hundred at the end of the year with the likelihood of
willpower it isn't strong enough willpower that's the secret of the 12
step groups the secret of deep humility and any spiritual work the personal will
is at the same level as the person's level of consciousness people below 200
willpower doesn't do a criminal any good because he hasn't got any willpower he's
got about rock hot cracker tasty bás Window contexts & raw mejores just got about Nicしょうsworth no it takes an interim to get us in control with full suspicion
infinite power. So, when you surrender to God and say, Lord God, of my own, I am unable
to control or change this behavior, it's a form of insanity. When you ask God's help
and surrender at great depth, you pull in divine will, which when it enters the human
is at 850. You surrender the personal will, turn it over to divinity. Personal will at
150 can't do it. The will of God at 850 can do it. So, by surrendering to God, you're
empowered by the power of divinity and not the personal will. The only recoveries I ever
saw from those kind of behaviors, and there was very few of them over the years, were
people who completely and totally surrendered to a 12-step program. And they stopped that
kind of antisocial behavior. And they did it by maintaining the will of God. And they
were living their spiritual alignment. That's the same with trying rather than doing. Remember,
estimated a big deal out of that. You were never allowed to use the word try. There is
no such thing as try. You're either gonna do it, or you're not gonna do it. There is
no such thing as trying. Trying is an excuse for not doing it. We're gonna do it tomorrow
instead of doing it now. We procrastinate because we're afraid of failure. And we pretend
that it's a good thing. It's a good thing. It's a bad thing. That's just the way it's
going to be. Keep trying. I don't think it's going to work that way forever. I think it's
because we're afraid to be honest and we're unwilling and resistant because we
prefer that to acceptance all right next one next acceptance the acceptance then
is without God's help the pursuit of enlightenment is not likely going to be
successful in fact it won't be successful resist won't be that's
stronger than I thought can't be done by the personal will personal will is weak
full enlightenment you're talking about calibration levels 850 and up at least
700 and up over 600 the personal will can't do that because it requires really
stringent self-control stringent sacrifice so it seems like sacrifice and
great effort that's beyond the human will and in this lifetime some of the
experiences I mean it's a lot of work but it's a lot of work but it's a lot of
pain and some went on for years frankly could not cannot be done by the human
will just can't be done by the human will to go through surgery without
anesthesia etc it's not within the human will surrender Lord God I myself cannot
handle this and then surrendering every resistance to pain as it arose right
you've got to be stay on the edge of the knife the minute you resist the pain
it's agony the minute you surrender the pain you lift it into a
state. I was sad when the surgery was over. It was like you were lifted by the
angels into a beatific state and the surgery is going on meantime. But the
minute you resist you're in trouble. The true nature of divinity, this is to
clarify, in fact I got a question this morning in the email about a question
within Buddhism. It's somebody who claims to be an arhat and differs with the
traditional interpretation of the Pali Canon. And only by calibrating could I
tell is that teacher that he's citing truly knowledgeable or not knowledgeable?
I didn't know what the question was. All I could do is calibrate the factors
involved and then after I got through calibrating the factors involved,
I
sent him an email and asked in what way does this teacher differ from the
traditional teaching, which emphasizes that calibrating levels of consciousness
is not a personal view. It's not a personal view. I mean who cares what the
number is, you know. You ask it because it's a teaching mechanism. It's a way of
confirmation. So I got that the teacher he was citing was extremely high and did
much, more correctly interpreting the truth than a traditional interpretation
that's popular about the Pali Canon and what it means. The Arhat calibrates at 800
and seeing into oneself nature, which is constantly quoted in Buddhism, is 845.
The void, as we've said is 850. Oneness, nothingness, consciousness, and lovingness,
these are the four things that carnalrhytm and dharma, and the one point here is that
you, as a person, is one as well as all other beings, and your existence, you are
the result of an incarnation of the Lord, as understood by the Buddha. And in this
practice, you don't have to be demon-movement in the human being. The way to be an
Consciousness, awareness, omniscience, omnipresence, and omnipotence, and allness are all at 850.
See, those are the qualities of divinity, but they are not the essence of divinity.
Traditionally, God is described as omniscient, omnipresent, etc.
Those are the qualities of God, but not the essence of God.
Omnipotence, then, is the infinite power of God.
And when you experience it, it is absolutely tremendous.
However, Jesus Christ, the Buddha, and the great avatars are at 1,000.
All right, the creator divinity and God are at infinity.
So the highest degree that is possible to experience the presence of God in this earthly realm, then, is at 1,000.
We call that incarnation.
Now, the Buddha teaches...
Yes, the question is, enlightenment is always differentiated somewhat from, let's say, the state of Christ consciousness, which is divinity incarnate.
Was the Buddha's ultimate state nothingness, as it's often quoted?
No.
This says, the Buddha experienced the allness, the infinite oneness, as divinity.
He said, don't use the term divinity, because there's so much misinformation.
There's so much information about it, that you will send the person into a belief system.
Avoid the word.
But he himself experienced, otherwise, the Buddha couldn't be at 1,000.
So, the Buddha nature, then, you see what's happening in the translation.
He says, don't use the term God, because you'll throw people into a belief system.
The same as the 12-step groups.
You talk about a higher power, because everybody's got some kind of a thing going about God.
So, the Buddha was doing something similar.
He was saying, don't call it God.
He called it the Buddha's nature.
The Buddha nature is not voidness or nothingness.
It's allness.
And, therefore, the Buddha, like Christ or Krishna, experienced the presence of God as his own reality.
I don't think that's ever been said before.
The Buddha experienced the presence of God, much as I experienced.
As infinite.
As infinite love, resist.
The Buddha also was Christed, you see.
Otherwise, he couldn't calibrate at 1,000.
It's not nothingness, or the Buddha would calibrate it at 50.
So, that's never been said before, and that might get me ridden out of the core,
but that's what we have to say about it today.
Now, we have to break again?
Yes, we're breaking a little early, so we'll have more time for question and answer.
As I said, we're going to experiment more with audience participation in the future.
Yes?
What?
Yes, Nico, that's what I was going to say.
All right, so we're going to take a break now where Nico's going to chant,
and then after we reconvene, we'll do the questions and answers.
So, Nico's going to chant 15 minutes earlier than usual.
As you know, he does the Lotus Sutra in Sanskrit, which calibrates at 700.
He has the ultimate t-shirt on today.
Okay.
So, today, I didn't bring my robes.
I don't have any robes.
Do I have beads?
Okay, so now people can ask any questions they wish.
Try to keep it simple through one question, if possible.
You write that guilt is a byproduct of thought.
Let's see. Let's start over again.
You write in your book,
that guilt is a byproduct of thought.
A byproduct?
Guilt is a byproduct of thought.
Yes, yes, yes.
And my question is,
The Course in Miracles talks about how all thought creates form at some level.
Yes.
And so as...
It is form.
Right.
It doesn't create form. It is form.
Okay.
And so as form or guilt arises, is there,
and as the presence arises,
is there a kind of transmutation that takes place?
From the lower energy frequency to the higher,
with a kind of almost transmutation of coming out and letting go of resistance?
Is there a transmutation of the lower to the higher?
No, the lower doesn't become the higher.
It's replaced by the higher.
Okay.
Because the initial response is based on perception.
And surrendering perception to God and asking to have the truth revealed to you,
removes the linear.
Then you see the nonlinear.
Okay.
So that the innocence,
the basic innocence,
which the Course talks about,
becomes apparent.
That's why I like Socrates' statement,
because it makes it more apparent that everyone is innocent
because they firmly believe that which they are pursuing.
Yeah.
Okay.
And so responsibility is limited
because the nature of the human mind is such that intrinsically,
it's unable to discern truth from falsehood.
All right.
It's not built for it.
It's not capable of it.
And is there a physical desire to move this energy through the body in order to affect that?
I don't believe in moving energies through the body.
Okay.
Thank you.
If you want a picture breathing up the energy to a higher chakra,
that's probably harmless.
But it's the intention behind it, not the breathing itself.
Yes?
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Our study group has chosen the topic of, here, the energy.
Humility to discuss.
And I was wondering if you could say something to us about radical humility.
Well, I know more about humility than anybody walking under your planet.
After you've hit bottom, you know what humility means, huh?
Well, humility really ensues from the reality of the understanding of the limitations of the human mind.
It isn't so much a spiritual prostration, you know, you're not spiritually prostrating yourself with ashes and sackcloth.
It's more just honesty.
So humility comes out of intrinsic honesty.
In and of itself, you can't tell who's telling the truth.
You know, let's take something currently in the media.
You have no way of knowing it.
Well, what's the truth?
No way.
Unless you're not a calibrator.
Then you know right away who's telling the truth.
But the mind, in and of itself, is not able to comprehend that.
So out of accepting the reality comes the humility.
Out of the reality.
That, to me, would be the highest form of acceptance.
Would be through understanding the nature of the human mind, you automatically become humble.
Because you cannot tell truth from falsehood on its own.
It takes a jury of 12 people.
And they spend months.
And at the end of that time, they don't know whether they're right or not.
And of course, DNA testing.
Everyone, DNA testing, they took off 165 people off death row across the United States.
165 people falsely condemned to death.
And it was the wrong person.
And scientific research shows that visual identification in crime scenes is 50% an error.
They line people up.
He's the one that did it.
The chances are 50-50 that person is correct.
50-50.
I'd hate to have my life hanging on 50-50, wouldn't you?
With somebody that's nearsighted and was half-bombed at the time they looked at you.
He's the one.
My God.
I remember.
So even under the best of circumstances, swearing an oath, the error is 50%.
Even though somebody's life is hanging on.
I mean, I'm not saying that's a lie.
I'm not saying that's a lie.
But I'm saying that's a lie.
I don't care.
Never.
So even under the best of circumstances, swearing an oath, the error is 50%.
Even though somebody's life is hanging on it.
So that shows you how limited.
So once you see the limitation of the human mind, then humility is just an automatic consequence
of seeing what its limitation is.
I don't use a lawn mower to level a field.
Because it's just not capable of doing the job.
It feels like when in your day, though, the ego is automatically in the knowing as you're coming across someone,
and humility is not something that enters your mind.
Well, humility is like what I'm telling you about, contemplation.
It's part of one's attitude, that all information and everything you think are all presumptions.
They're all tentative.
So you hold thinkingness as tentative, but not as authoritative.
It's tentative. All evidence is tentative.
Perception is just tentative evidence.
Hello.
If you're going above 600 and you're leaving the body,
would there be any possibility that you have to come back again and reincarnate?
Would you have to come back again after hitting?
If you're on the level of 600, would you have to come back for any reason?
Not for the reasons one would presume, not because it's a have-to due to negative karma,
not because you identify with the linear, but instead you see the options of the non-linear.
So it's a choice, I think, made between yourself and divinity.
Because friends of mine who are doing some kinesiologic testing got the Dramana Maharshi,
was reincarnated and attended one of your lectures.
I remember meeting him.
So it's not true?
We don't know.
He said the world you see is illusion, you know,
although there's no point trying to save the world,
because the world you see doesn't even exist, you know, it's all in your head.
That takes humility to accept that.
And it's only a belief system until it becomes true within one's own spiritual evolution.
And then you see that all you're seeing is perception going,
all you're seeing is a run of perception, like TV images.
Yeah, he never left that mountain.
And I like Susan's sign too.
Dr. Hawkins, my question is that today one of the students asked me if I would come up here and ask the question.
And throughout the whole day I had severe anxiety.
I don't want to know, what is this anxiety?
What is this anxiety?
I mean, this is the most loving group on earth, and I'm in the presence of divinity in this group,
and yet I have this humongous anxiety to come up and ask a question and sit here and let people look at me.
Oh.
You have to presume that you're safe.
You have to presume that everybody's thoughts about you are benign.
You have to presume that everybody's happy that you're here.
Yeah?
So what you presume turns out to be a reality.
Everybody's pleased that you're here and that you're speaking as you're speaking.
I'm pleased.
Are you pleased?
It's stage anxiety.
It's stage fright.
Oh.
I had stage fright when I was in kindergarten.
When I was in kindergarten, they had a class play.
And I was supposed to be a rabbit.
And I was supposed to hide behind this tree.
So it was a big cardboard tree.
And on a cue, I was supposed to hop, hop, hop, hop, hop, hop, and then hop behind the tree.
Right.
And I wouldn't come out.
Oh.
Yeah.
And the cue lady kept saying, I didn't need to come out.
But I couldn't.
My heart was beating fast, you know.
Right.
Being looked at.
I think that's what it is.
Other people looking at me.
All right.
I want everybody to shut your eyes.
Shut your eyes.
Everybody agree?
Just for a minute.
Shut your eyes.
Nobody's looking at you.
Okay.
Is that better?
I guess not.
Because I think I'm looking at myself.
I think I'm judging myself every minute that possibly, you know, I'm not, well, I guess
I put a value judgment on myself.
Well, imitate a person who has, what are we calling this issue, Scott?
What have we been calling it before?
Stage fright.
All right.
Imitate a person who has stage fright.
Imitate it.
Yeah, you're not scared enough, you idiot.
Because I wasn't.
Yeah.
So.
If you don't stay calm, I'm going to kill you.
Oh.
All of a sudden, the anxiety kind of released.
I mean, I stood in line, it released a little bit.
And now.
It seemed like it released more.
Yeah.
So, I don't know how, why, how, what happened?
You accepted the worst possible scenario, and you saw it was illusion.
Oh, is that what happened?
Yeah.
Wow.
The way to undo a fear or a phobia, or anything like that, keep going, and then what?
And then what?
They're going to look at me, yeah, and then what?
Then they're going to laugh at me, and then what?
And then they're going to think I'm stupid, and then what?
And then what?
And then I'll make a fool out of myself.
And then you keep accepting it.
You say, so I'm making a fool out of myself.
Who gives a, you know?
Right.
Once you accept the bottom line, it all goes away.
That's why eventually accepting the inevitability of death usually knocks about 95% of the other fears out of the box.
Because all of them are symbolic of physical death.
I'll be poor, then what?
Then I won't have any money.
Then I'll get kicked out.
Then I won't have any place to live.
Then I'll starve to death.
And then what?
And it's always, and then I'll die.
So once you get down to the bedrock underneath all fears, it's the fear that I'll die.
I'm not going to have everybody's approval here, therefore I'll die, see?
Once you, you know, the worst thing that's happened to you is you topple over right now.
You're not so lucky, you're still breathing.
Okay.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you so much, Doc.
I mean, this really helped me.
Yeah.
A great deal.
You're carried.
Thank you so much, and thank you, Susan.
Bye, Sarah.
Thank you so much.
This is lost music.
And I took it, and I wanted you to sign it.
Oh, we'll send it back.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you so much.
I think facing stage fright is very hard.
It took a lot of courage.
God bless you.
Thank you.
I was so scared I forgot what she asked.
I had to pray about what she was going to ask me.
Hi, Susan.
Hi.
That experience you spoke about this morning when you had the temptation that power,
that power is yours, own it.
That what?
Sorry, go ahead.
The experience when you attempted that power is yours, all power is yours, own it.
Own it.
Oh, yes, yes.
What calibration level does that occur at?
Oh, that's probably over 850, yeah.
Okay, I have permission to ask about the silent communication.
It was over 800, 840, 850, 860.
Yeah, it comes in around 850 there.
Well, if the consciousness is still open,
to the Luciferic, at that calibration,
then wouldn't it be wise if one's intent was to go above that level?
Well, of course.
The person's aim is for enlightenment.
But enlightenment isn't that easily acquired.
And everywhere along the way there's a challenge.
That's the challenge there.
That's why Christ sweat blood in the Garden of Eden.
Christ sweat blood.
The Buddha felt like his bones were broken, see?
So, that which is the antithesis of truth sees you as a great danger.
As long as you're an ordinary sinner and you go to church and all that crap, you're no nothing.
And once you start really getting up there, you see what happens is your power is so enormous,
you become now a major threat.
The demons start looking for your weakness.
And the fallen gurus, we once did a lecture on them,
the temptation now comes in and finds the weakness in your armor.
Sexual seduction, flattery, money, having lots of followers, lots of wealth, pomp, circumstance.
The glamour of that.
Sooner or later, they're going to find your weakness.
The pretty girl says, I love you, let's make love, yes.
Love is holy, let's be holy.
Let's have holy sex, you know what I mean?
They fall into it right and left.
So, they look.
So, that's due to lack of preparation at the lower level.
It's lack of a teacher warning you.
I feel the teacher must teach you what the temptations are along the way
so that when you get there, you're not blindsided.
You know, my antipathy to the United States of America is its stupidity
in allowing itself to get blindsided about every 15 minutes about everything.
What the hell are they doing?
They sound asleep up there or where are they, you know what I'm saying?
How can you be so sound asleep that you don't know that there's a half a million
communists across the border in North Korea?
You can't know there's a half a million?
I mean plain breathing.
Is it possible that someone at a calibration level down here has an intent for up here
or is it just an illusion?
No, people tend to evolve.
They want to evolve consciousness.
They want to evolve.
Yeah, that's why there's so many people involved in the spiritual work.
You know, religious and spiritual books outsell all others right now.
Probably in the
WGW, right?
Closures Weekly.
Yes.
So there's an enormous interest in it.
Yeah.
Those are called, those are called the tests along the way.
Right.
You know, I'm going to transcend seduction.
Well, it's like karma says, let's see.
Good looking.
Thanks.
So you're not, you're not really clear at all.
After 850, right?
You're always susceptible up to that point.
Well, you're susceptible the whole way.
At 850, you could fall for the power.
I know it grew as it did because very few through, very few go through that pass at 850.
It's so rare that you can see who was there and you see the decision they made.
And beyond 850?
You're in a different realm.
That temptation doesn't come up there.
Thanks.
Beyond 850 has to do with belief systems about the nature of divinity.
The nature of divinity itself.
I can't hear you.
Yes.
I was reading in your truth versus falsehood about that whole idea of alien abduction being false.
And I have a friend that is absolutely convinced that that's happened.
I didn't know if this was some kind of, you know, is that some kind of attack?
I'll explain alien abduction to you.
It has to do with, you know, in the New Testament.
What is the name of that chapter that covers the 70 revelations?
Yes, there are astral realms.
Now, you can go out of body.
Your spirit can go out of body and visit an astral realm and experience the reality there and come back.
And it did experience it only within a psychic level.
Let me see if I can explain it.
People go out of body, the spirit.
Visits an astral domain and has experiences and comes back.
There are some that are visited very often in the same report is reported over the centuries.
The apocalypse, you know, the forecast of John.
John calibrated at 70 and the book of Revelations calibrates at about 70.
That is a lower astral realm.
Hmm.
All right.
Due to maybe karmic propensity.
Sometimes alcoholism, very commonly temporal lobe epilepsy, various other conditions.
A person may experience the lower astral realm.
Now, it's not like a movie.
It's experiential, very convincing.
And I knew a teacher here and in Sedona at one time was in a high state and then went into that state and got a whole group to come out here for survival.
They're going to dig underground.
They're going to find homes and a lot of crap.
And he experienced it with such conviction that when he related to others, the conviction is what convinced them.
Likewise, the similar thing.
The conviction is because it was experiential.
You do experience it.
I see.
So he experienced a different reality.
Now, it's interesting because it's like there's only a couple movies that are popular or really accessible in the lower astral realm.
And they tend to replay over and over.
The end times is over.
And over again, California falls off in the ocean.
Earthquakes in the middle of New York City, ravaging hordes.
And anyway, the same apocalyptic forecast recur over and over again.
The one that John experienced this reported in the New Testament has been commonly experienced by people throughout the ages.
The end times, the end times are forecast, you know, every other week.
Somebody's got another forecast to the end times.
It was a guy.
And Sedona used to give lectures on the end times.
And he had a mustache that went up like this, like Salvatore Dali.
Anyway, at the time for the end times came and went, all he did is change the dates.
Is there any, I think, direction I can send this girl in to make her, you know, I'm concerned about her.
Why are you concerned about her?
Oh, you like her.
She's convinced what?
The end times are coming?
No, she's just convinced that this is going on.
And I don't.
I think that she needs to find some direction to work her way out of it.
Do I think she's going to recover?
Unlikely.
Yes.
It would take karmic research to see why she was prone to it.
Sometimes after brain injuries, after head injuries, under conditions of extremity, conditions of intoxication, post convulsive fugue, F-U-G-E episodes.
There is, there's a different, there's another name for it.
That's more accurate.
A fugue state is close to it, but there's a better word for it, which will come to me later.
I did write about it in one of the books too, about these particular paranormal states, paranormal states.
Also, if that astral, oh, I just got something else.
Yes.
If that astral future is your reality, then that's going to be your experience.
Your reality.
Because that's where you're at.
Oh, I just got it.