back David, don't hurry. We're in Excelsis, Dio. It is of course a great pleasure. I see you all again.
We always start with the end of the lecture first, so you don't have to bother listening in the
meantime. Witness that all things are happening spontaneously. Everything is happening in and of
its own nature as a consequence of that which it is, not as a consequence of that which it does,
which implies the duality of a doer and the action. Everything is within an infinite field
of power. The power is so immense that it escapes the capacity of human consciousness
to comprehend it because it's invisible, all present, just like people are not aware of gravity,
without which everybody in Australia would fall off the globe.
They do seem strange, too, because they're standing on their heads their whole lifetime.
All right. So I try to correlate the scientific modern mind, reason, and logic with spiritual
truth, and merge the two so that it's comprehensible from either direction.
Ordinarily, the world of science stops here, and the world of spirituality starts here,
and they really don't have an answer.
They don't have any dialogue. They have attempts at it, called science and religion,
science and consciousness. And if you listen carefully, you realize, what is the relationship
between science and religion? There isn't any.
What's the relationship between science and consciousness? There isn't any. Okay.
But we do try to merge the two because the modern spiritual truth is heard differently by the
modern mind than it was many centuries ago.
Where it was taken on an, ooh, faith kind of a basis, huh?
Now we have the modern mind to contend with, so it's both a help and a hindrance.
In a group like this, I advise skipping the mind altogether.
So if I just tell you what's happening, and all you have to do is notice it, you don't
have to think about it, although later we'll explain it.
The meaning of everything is what it is. That is its meaning. Its meaning is what
it is.
What's the meaning of a giraffe? The meaning of a giraffe is to be a giraffe. What did
you think it meant?
In this infinite field, which is beyond all dimensions and all description, of infinite
power.
Potentiality.
That is what is being manifested as actuality when conditions are appropriate.
So what you're witnessing is potentiality continuously emerging as creation.
Therefore, creation and evolution are one and the same thing because evolution is creation.
What did they think?
Creation was gonna be all done, goodbye.
God says, goodbye.
I'll see you on judgment day.
That's the way religion holds it, you know.
created the universe through the ball good luck folks you make it you'll see
me and if you don't make it you won't not too responsible right all right so
the potentiality becomes an actuality and all you're witnessing is the
emergence you're not even witnessing change that's another delusion there's
no time there's no change those are all mentalizations if I ask a rabbit what
time is it anyone know what I'm talking about
that's a mentalization that the ego projects on to experience huh you don't
even see change that's another illusion what you see is the emergence continuous
emergence of potentiality becoming an actuality the hand has a potentiality to
actualize in such a manner and try to accompany the speech if the hand is not
there it's not there it's not there it's not there it's not there it's not there
changing. It's just emerging into positionalities. So you see the actualization of the potentiality.
Everything is happening in and of its own as a consequence of that which it is. There's no doer
causing it. The difficulty in a group like this, which is erudite spiritually speaking,
is to jump from the paradigm of cause and effect. Why? Because the dualistic concept of cause and
effect, so long as you hold that as a reality, there will be a separate you. You understand?
There'll be going to be a separate self. Separate from the self with a capital S. Separate from the
oneness. There would have to be an explanation of a you who intended to make this thing happen.
I had nothing to do with it.
Don't blame me for what the body does and the voice says. I mean, I have nothing to do with it.
It emerges.
It emerges spontaneously as the consequence of the totality of the second. What is said as a
consequence of an audience of this style, of this group, would be different than what would be said
with a different audience. Because the collective energy and the individual consciousness that makes
it up would pull forth a different type of presentation and description. So what is being
said is a consequence of your being here. And the way it's being said is a consequence of the
totality. There's no person who decides it. No person decides it.
So the witnessing then that all phenomena are occurring spontaneously of their own is the
consequence of that which they are. And nothing is being caused by anything. Everything on the
other hand is dominated by the infinite field of power. So within an infinite field of power,
field of power that which you are automatic deterrence your alignment
within the field a giant electromagnetic field if you're a little filing where
are you going to be in that field depends on your charge negative or
positive that's how karma works every decision then influences your energy
your polarity and therefore your destiny is determined only by yourself
there's nobody paddling your canoe except you as a consequence of the
absolute judgment of the field itself we could we interject interject the idea
judgment see as a consequence of that which you are you are perfectly exactly
where you need to be in the universe not possible to be elsewhere if the field is
infinitely power powerful how could you be elsewhere than where you're supposed
to be in the field
consequently every choice and every decision then affects one spiritual
energy and one spiritual energy is karma karma which is well accepted in the
eastern world is not understood in the Western world which explains a lot of
things
the person who's aware of karma would really hesitate it sawing off somebody's
head you know I mean I would really give you the shakes you know
I mean I worry if I step on a bug don't you want to do it I step around the bug
I mean I don't want the current killing in innocent living thing and no right so
then karma serves an inner discipline why because it states a truth and the
truth is that everyone is completely accountable to the universe over and
over we verify that we have permission to ask that
Lord everyone is absolutely accountable to the universe at the level of the
absolute resist at the level of the absolute everyone is automatically
accountable to the universe this is true as a consequence of the power of the
field therefore it's the field that guarantees salvation yeah so our subject
today is intention intention very powerful it's the spiritual will that
that determines karma that determines calibrated level of consciousness the
calibrated level of consciousness is a mathematical way of sort of stating
where you are
armically what's been done what needs to be done yet yeah hmm they the
individual will is too weak to accomplish things I mean try and give up
Fritos before bed you know I mean forget it I'm into fried what are those potato
chips organic potato chips forget the individual will know something far more
powerful the intention that
Yes
to align oneself with divinity to be the servant of God to search and seek for
enlightenment to be a spiritual devotee is enormously powerful the divine will
when you invoke divine will calibrates at 850 so if you're a consciousness
level is at 302 and you try to accomplish a certain thing you become
discouraged you saying Almighty God I end up myself and I'm able to do this I'm able to do this.
And I ask for a miracle.
And then you forget it.
And then you walk through the door and it happens.
To get beyond cause and effect,
one sees that existence is continuously miraculous.
You witness the evolution unfolding.
You're witnessing the unfolding of evolution.
You're not witnessing cause and effect,
and you're not witnessing change.
And you're not witnessing time.
Those are all mentalizations that you project.
You know, Descartes was a great teacher.
And he pointed out the duality of res interna, res cogitans,
that is, that which is of the mind,
and res externa, otherwise known as res extensa,
which is the world the way it is,
and the difficulty then in spiritual evolution.
It's to presume that res interna is the same,
is representing res externa.
That how you see the world is the way it really is.
Thankfully, that's an error.
As you watch the commentators on the nightly news,
you say, thank God, mentalization is just,
it's only res interna.
Oh, boy.
So it means surrendering.
It's surrendering the illusion that you're the cause of anything.
Now, the ego, out of its evolution,
because of its evolution, presumes not only is it cause,
but it is the source of your life,
which is a confrontation that comes near the end of the pathway,
and which we've talked about.
Everybody, as a student, should know what's ahead.
Why?
Because ahead may become this moment within seconds.
You say, I won't have to look at that one for 20, 30 years.
Famous last words.
You get a cup of tea, and suddenly, the personal you disappears.
And there's only the totality of creation.
Stunning.
And then arises the last decision.
Yeah.
The last decision.
We tell that in the beginning.
See, we do everything backwards.
The world's been doing everything forwards,
and you see where it's at.
It took us centuries to move up one or two points in consciousness.
It's better to start from the ending, then.
If you don't project thinkingness onto the world
and become dumb like a bunny,
then you just see phenomena are happening of their own.
You don't have to invent a mystical you that's causing it,
some kind of causality out there, sociologic theory.
Everything is what it is, as a consequence of what it has become.
Along the pathway, and I'm finishing a book called Transcending the Levels of Consciousness.
And so it's taken me through all these levels.
Oh, the levels disappeared.
It's taken me through all those levels again, you know.
And in doing it, we presented the dualities that hold each level of consciousness where it is.
Every level.
Reflects an aversion and an attraction.
And the duality of the aversion and the attraction is a perceptual illusion.
And when you see through it and drop it,
you instantly move to a different level of consciousness.
So we did the dualities for the lower levels of consciousness from...
We finished some... Where's our thing that we always forget?
I've forgotten this all over the place.
Bob Henderson must have spent half an evening packaging it all up
and carefully mailing it to me after a slogan press cut.
Anyway, so what we did in the first part of the book is the duality.
So we started at the bottom and we moved up.
And I thought at each lecture, I'll present, you know, one slide.
So we have a slide of the dualities that characterize each level of consciousness.
So today we'll start at the bottom.
And then each lecture, we'll move on.
See?
So each one.
Now these levels aren't where we live.
Nobody in this audience don't live there.
But they are momentary.
They are transitory.
Your consciousness level can be, you know, here.
And suddenly you go into guilt, shame, grief, fear, desire.
So these are evanescent.
So one's consciousness level is that which is dominant.
It's dominant.
But it doesn't exclude these things coming up.
Why do they come up?
They come up from the unconscious.
They come up from the individual unconscious.
Some of them are things that were projected into the world.
And now that you're taking spiritual responsibility,
you suddenly feel guilt about them.
And so, but that's transitory.
That's not where you are.
However, we should know about them.
And so we're going to cover all the levels.
So how many people here are new today?
Okay, all right.
All right, so the contextualization of the lecture is
to cover the basics and add something new.
We cover the basics for those who are new.
We don't spend a long time on it, but we do cover them.
And then we add something new
for the people who have been here many times.
So we always have a review of the old
and an introduction of the new.
When there isn't any more new, the lecture is stopped.
That could be new.
There's nothing more to say other than that.
Well, folks, you're on your own.
All right, so what we're really doing
is presenting spiritual truth in a different context
than classically presented via religion
and various spiritual...
spiritual groups and organizations
which become formalized into a sort of ecclesiastic dogma,
complete with misunderstandings of the truth
that was originally spoken,
but some centuries later it's misinterpreted.
And those errors stand out glaringly, glaringly.
All right, so all phenomena are happening
of their own spontaneously.
Thinking that they're being caused by something
is an error of perception.
The mind tries to explain phenomena.
Now, frankly, the mind is too dumb to explain phenomena.
It doesn't even know why a rabbit is a rabbit.
It can explain genetics, it can give you a sign.
Those are all things about, but they have nothing to do
with what it is to be a rabbit.
Ask any rabbit.
I say, rabbit, what is it like to be a rabbit?
He says, I don't know, what does rabbit mean?
I say, you don't know what a rabbit is?
Rabbit is...no.
I get the encyclopedia.
He says, you get me the encyclopedia.
Rabbit. Sit down, rabbit.
OK. I read the rabbit the whole thing.
It takes me about 15 minutes to read all through rabbit.
I says, no. What do you think of that?
That's what you are.
He says, that's not what I am.
I said, well, what are you?
He says, I'm me.
LAUGHTER
So we're the same as the rabbit.
OK.
The rabbit, all he knows is that he's who he is, what he is.
That's all we really know.
All the rest is elaborate.
You don't need any of it.
When you're out at sea, you have a little boat and the wind is coming up,
what the encyclopedia says about humanity is pretty relevant.
You're very intensely just being who you are
and asking God's intervention in the matter.
So intention, then, is very powerful because the will is powerful.
It's the will that sets karmic destiny.
Very powerful.
So to surrender to God, to commit to the Lord, to God, to divinity, to enlightenment,
whatever you want to call it, now completely changes your future altogether.
Completely changes it.
Not by virtue of causality, but by virtue of intention which changes the field.
Everything comes about as a consequence of the field and not of the linear ego.
As the consequence, then, by commitment,
you've now become something different than what you were before you made the commitment.
It's like a change in the barometric pressure.
Now all of the weather.
It's going to change.
Not caused by anything, but as a consequence of the barometric pressure.
You see, the barometric pressure itself doesn't really cause anything.
It's the local condition.
So what you see, then, is potentiality becoming actuality
under the circumstances that prevail at the time.
The sea doesn't emerge until the sunlight, the warmth, and the water are appropriate.
But they don't cause the sea to.
They don't grow into a flower.
The other thing you'll notice, if you skip editing the world mentally,
is that things do not go from uncomplete to complete.
They do not go from imperfect to perfect.
They go from perfect to perfect.
All things, at all moments, are perfect.
Imperfection is a rejection of mentalization.
So, everything, by virtue of being what it is,
is already perfection.
Because all of creation is perfection.
Creation is the unmanifest becoming manifest
within the experiential domain as creation.
Creation unfolds spontaneously as the consequence
that the source is innate to that which has been created.
Instead of thinking of change and causality, then,
what you're witnessing is really emergence.
Emergence of potentiality becoming an actuality.
At each moment of emergence, it's perfect.
This is perfectly the fist.
This is perfectly the part of the open hand.
This is perfectly, perfectly, perfectly, perfectly.
So, as the flower unfolds, you see,
first it's a perfect bud.
Then it's a perfect half-open rose.
Then it's a perfect foliar.
Then it's a perfectly faded rose.
Then it becomes perfect fertilizer.
It's perfect at every moment.
So, things don't move from incomplete to complete
or from imperfection to perfection.
They move from complete to complete
and from perfect to perfect.
The half-open rose is completely a half-open rose.
It's complete.
It's perfect.
You witness that spontaneously,
perfection prevails.
All things are manifesting
their potentiality.
They're only being what they are.
And they can't be anything else.
To be perfectly stupid
is to be perfectly stupid.
That's where you're supposed to be right now.
Noodle-himers, we call them.
Why?
Because we were all once children.
And because the evolution of consciousness,
we have, by grace, divine grace,
by karmic merit,
earned the right to be
born a human.
Not only to have been born a human,
but to have heard of enlightenment.
Rarer still is it to have heard of enlightenment.
Rarer it is to be born a human.
A great karmic gift.
Rarer yet is it to have heard of enlightenment.
Rarest of all is it to have heard of enlightenment
and made the decision to seek it.
So, by the words of the Buddha,
this is indeed a gifted audience.
And I do bow to this audience.
All gifted here.
All here are gifted.
Gifted as a consequence of intention.
Somewhere in history,
this lifetime or sometime,
there was made that commitment
by a prayer, by a declaration,
by a devotion, by an inner decision.
That intention carries through forever.
Oh.
Ha, ha, ha.
Let me think it over again.
I meant I was going to be good for a while.
I didn't mean to be good all weekend.
Ha, ha, ha.
Is Saturday night included?
I'll give the id a break.
Saturday night off.
Id night.
Indulgence.
Be an animal.
Sunday morning you go to church.
That's the whole idea.
What I did last night.
Ha, ha, ha.
Ha, ha.
All right.
So that's all you really need to know.
We could leave now.
It's a letting things go
and seeing that everything is manifesting
as the consequence of a field.
So the universe is an infinite,
infinite fields of diminishing power
and as a consequence of that which things have become,
like an iron filing in a magnetic field,
each thing aligns itself where it needs to be.
It then emerges.
Its potentiality then emerges as an actuality
if conditions are appropriate.
There is no necessity to even conjure up
an intellectual axiom such as causality.
Causality is an explanation.
Calvary is at 450.
Spiritual truth, you know, really starts around 500.
Ha, ha, ha.
So therefore you have why science
and spirituality,
what's the relationship with them,
during me.
Ha, ha, ha.
All right.
So we're going to recapitulate.
We'll start with slide one.
And then we're going to move through rapidly.
Move through rapidly.
Move through rapidly, yes.
We're going to move through rapidly.
Well, we now have a total of 60 slides to select from.
And we thought eventually we'll put out a book
of slides and charts, you know.
Slides and charts.
A lot of people have asked for them.
Just slides and charts.
You don't have to read all that stuff.
Because you just get it in a hurry.
You know what I mean?
All right.
So this, of course, is very well known.
We've explained it many times.
These have to do with the evolution of consciousness.
It's a logarithmic number.
Therefore, as consciousness advances,
it advances more and more rapidly.
So in the beginning, it's slow.
But as you move along,
you can be surprised by a very sudden
jumps in consciousness.
Because of that,
I tell people what they need to know
way along the pathway early.
We didn't talk about the void today,
but that's another thing we have to tell you about.
And the temptations that come along the way
where people fall off the pedestal, you know.
Because each spiritual student, in a way,
is tested too, you know.
It's not like there's something evil out there testing you.
It's just that quality of the unconscious.
It's that quality of the ego which seeks to persist.
And when you say,
I'm going to be kind and benevolent to everybody,
instantly a dog bites your ankle.
The ego says,
I win.
Not going to get away from my clutches.
Whose clutches are you in?
I say the clutches of the primitive narcissistic ego.
The world would like to label it evil,
bad, the devil, Satan.
Give it all kinds of personifications
and then live in fear of their own personifications.
So, in science there's what is called
sufficient explanation.
So we will supply sufficient explanation.
You don't need anything magical
to superimpose on it or mythical.
We see the evolution of consciousness here.
And it demonstrates itself throughout humanity.
Each level is accompanied by a prevailing emotional state.
Heavenly, blissful, happy, less and less happy.
The process of consciousness.
This is the process of consciousness.
At the top we have illumination.
Down here we have inflation.
This is the...
You ever watch TV?
No matter what happens in the world,
somebody has to get on and give you their opinion of it.
What do I want to know his opinion for?
It's the American way.
Oh, okay.
And enslavement by addictions, you see,
and eventually suicide.
All right.
So we call these different levels,
we describe them in emotional terms
because that is the most commonly understood.
The view of the self is quite different.
These people hate themselves,
they project their hatred onto the world,
see evil out there.
And as you move up here,
the view of self becomes more and more positive.
More and more positive,
and finally you're comfortable with yourself.
The view of God then is a correlation
with your level of consciousness.
At the bottom you have the demonic depictions of God,
the anthropomorphic projections
in which God is punitive,
he's partial,
he's got favoritism,
and you've got to be afraid of him.
So this is the God of terror,
which is really satanic.
It's a satanic depiction of God.
These are satanic.
Those are the qualities of Satan,
not divinity.
Consequently, their introduction
in the New Testament,
in the Book of Revelations,
and in many chapters of the Old Testament,
are of the anthropomorphic God of primitivism.
Storms, you assuage the storms,
the gods were angry,
the gods were angry.
Even today, end times predictions
are always coming around.
And religious tracts that
describe everything.
Tsunamis and all.
There's predictions from the Bible, etc.
Of course, I always point out
that greater disasters
that have occurred in the history of mankind
occurred before mankind was here.
Earthquakes were here before man was here, folks.
Thugs were here before.
All those phenomena, in fact,
they're supposedly what wiped out the dinosaurs.
It was a natural disaster
that ostensibly knocked out the dinosaurs.
So unless God was angry at the dinosaurs,
I don't know how to explain it in Biblical terms.
Anyway, that kind of a God,
you eventually leave that kind of negative viewpoint,
sort of the Gothic downside of religion.
And that's why a lot of people become spiritual.
They know that somewhere within religion
there's spiritual truth.
But they find a lot of the teachings
confining and intuitively not in alignment
with that which is infinite truth.
That which is infinitely merciful.
That which is infinitely merciful is what?
It's infinitely merciful.
Oh.
So your view of God, then,
has nothing to do with God.
It has to do with your level of consciousness.
You see him as merciful, wisdom.
You see him as a source of love,
of oneness, of all-beingness.
And finally, divinity itself shines forth.
To transcend these levels of consciousness is,
you know, the book I just read,
I just got through finishing.
I said there's an upside and downside
that holds each of these levels.
This level is always looking for gain, etc.
It's based on feeling incomplete.
When you understand the universe,
you see everything is going from complete to complete.
Everything is complete and perfect right now.
Everybody here is just completely,
completely the perfect manifestation
of your total karmic evolution
up to this point in time.
There's nothing to be dissatisfied with about yourself,
except impatience.
Oh, I wish I was there instead of here.
Hmm?
So there's no problem other than impatience, correct?
Everyone here is destined to become enlightened.
We've checked this group out before.
We don't sell them a ticket, otherwise...
Everyone in this room is destined for enlightenment.
Resist.
We've checked that over and over.
Why?
Who else but a future golfer would be at a golf class?
I don't attend golf classes.
I'm not destined to be a golf star.
No, people here are here because of their intention,
which is the lecture today, intention.
The power of...
Somebody wrote a book called The Power of Intention recently.
Oh, yeah, right.
As I said, I read the last chapter
because it was free off the Internet.
No, but The Power of Intention.
So, all right, now let's see.
I want to go to the next slide, yes?
Intention, yes.
Yeah, all right.
The reason why intention is so powerful,
we'll get to the mechanics of it
for people who are still stuck
with being intelligent and rational and educated.
The reason intention is so powerful
has to do, of course, within this domain
with the Heisenberg principle.
So we will connect up science, quantum mechanics,
spiritual reality,
and connect up the Buddha and Einstein
and Heisenberg all at once, okay?
These are the higher states of consciousness.
Oh, yes, the last chart goes up to 600
because that covers about 99% of the population.
99.9%, actually.
So, but from 600 up then,
what are the more advanced levels
and what do we call them?
Enlightenment is typically 600 and over.
Classically, once you hit the state of bliss,
satchitananda, bliss.
At bliss, about half the people leave.
Something's today on.
Unless somebody comes and gets you,
you probably just dehydrate and fall over,
which is irrelevant.
But the world gets excited about that,
so the world comes along and the cops tell you
you can't sit on the rock anymore.
People tell you you haven't eaten since Tuesday,
so they force food on you.
All right, so 600 is the level of satchitananda,
infinite bliss.
It's complete.
It's complete and total within itself.
There is no need for anything.
There is no desire for anything.
Whether the physicality continues or not
is totally irrelevant.
And there's no inclination to do anything.
If you survive that, you get up into the 700s,
which is Ramana Maharshi, Nisargadatta Maharaj,
and one who did manage to survive
and reenter the world was Mother Teresa,
who also demonstrates 700.
These states get higher and higher,
and finally we reach states that are extremely unusual.
Extremely unusual.
When they occur, they usually have an historic impact
on the destiny of mankind for centuries.
So the impact of the Avatar has been
to totally design all of society down
through the centuries.
It's spiritual truth that gives ethics,
law, reason, all its integrity.
So in Europe what's happened now is
the spiritual truth which came out of
that particular religion and structured the society,
now it refutes the source of that,
and it becomes, it calls itself secular.
Now that we know,
we know how to do that on our own,
we don't need you folks anymore.
So they sort of said goodbye to the church.
But so out of those spiritual truths then,
all of society, the energy is so powerful
at a thousand or 850, 950 thousand,
it's so powerful that it contextualizes
all of society permanently, permanently you want to say.
Now you can refute its source,
but you still are what it created.
The Congress, whatever,
the law that you call forth
to back up your rights,
came out of religion.
So you can refute the religion,
but the truth of the structure that came out of it survives.
So that's the power of the Avatar.
On this planet,
it's very difficult to live beyond 600,
beyond 700, beyond 800.
It's very difficult.
850 is very difficult.
And it only happens very occasionally.
When it does,
it's by some divine intervention.
And the stress on the nervous system is extreme.
From 800 and up,
the stress on the nervous system is extreme.
All right.
And then so on this planet then,
eventually you leave and we ask,
you know, what is an archangel?
An archangel calibrates at 50,000 and up.
I once sent out a prayer that was answered by,
let's see,
I have permission to say this here.
That prayer was an archangel.
Yeah.
So anyway,
in the pits of hell,
which I've described elsewhere,
which are forever,
the pits of hell are beyond anyone's imagination.
And they are infinite.
They don't stop.
There is no time.
It's foreverness.
Out of that arose a voice.
It said,
if there is a God,
I ask him for help.
And then everything that one had been was eliminated.
And then shone forth the glory of divinity as all of creation.
The thought was picked up by,
I always call it a cruising archangel.
A cruising archangel just picked up the thought,
gave it a second's notice.
This life was totally,
totally changed.
So you don't want to mess with archangels.
Let's have the next one.
So it's like divinity is infinite.
And then like progressive levels,
the power,
what do you call those things,
the British power,
you know what I'm saying?
Yeah,
like diminishing transformers.
So the archangels are extremely high.
So what we consider the highest on this planet,
I always suspect is like kindergarten
and other dimensions.
Anyway,
don't mess with archangels.
Now the world's population is distribution,
which we'll understand when we see how the ego evolved.
Most of the planet,
approximately 80% of the planet,
is below the level of integrity.
80% of the people who walk this planet
are run by the animal ego
to get the best of you,
to see you as competition,
to hate you without feeling guilty about it.
It's a lifestyle,
then,
in 80% of the world.
So this is the distribution of levels of consciousness.
You see, therefore,
very few people are maintaining a balance.
And without them,
civilization would probably destruct.
Civilization would destruct.
Okay, let's see if that's true.
I have permission to ask this here.
Without the top 15%,
civilization would self-destruct.
Civilization would self-destruct
if it wasn't for those people of integrity.
How does that happen?
It happens because their consciousness is so powerful.
This never got colored in.
Their consciousness is so powerful
that they balance the other 80% of the world,
without which the 80% of the world would self-destruct.
We saw it come close, didn't we?
Remember when Russia had the mega-bomb
that would destroy all of life,
and in case Russia lost an atomic war,
ballistic war,
the final solution bomb would destroy all of life.
Hitler tried it with Germany.
Megalomania,
narcissistic megalomania,
the great rulers,
come close over and over.
You know, in my lifetime,
100 million people have died in war,
all as a result.
So what keeps then this
from totally destroying life
is that there is
the energy of people
keeping them afloat.
That's one of the jobs.
One of the jobs that you have
is by being what you are,
you counterbalance enormous negativity.
We once calculated
one person at 400
compensates for, I don't know,
1,000 people below 200.
At 500, you compensate for maybe 10,000.
By 600, you're holding up millions.
So this is the evolution of consciousness over time.
You see, at the time of the Buddha,
it was at 90.
At the time of Jesus Christ,
the consciousness level of mankind was 100.
It came up slowly.
It was 190 for centuries, centuries.
All of European history was at 190.
And now it went up to 205.
Now it's up to 207.
So people will say, well, what is the future?
Well, if this is the way consciousness is going,
it looks like the future is optimistic.
So forget about the end times, folks.
The future looks very good.
Okay, next.
I like this slide
because the difficulty,
the reason people leave religion
is often out of guilt and sin.
When I became an atheist,
it was a huge relief.
I was, I told you, I was very religious.
And I was an acolyte, a boy soloist.
I was religious to the point of scrupulosity.
They sent me to the, to the priests
to be counseled about scrupulosity.
I lived in dread and fear of sin.
Why?
Because sin was explained to me as a blot on your soul
and God can see it.
Oh, my God, if that doesn't throw you into paranoia,
you think the thought darn.
We weren't even supposed to say darn when I was a kid.
Darn.
Oh, God.
There goes the splat.
God sees you.
I tell you, life was tough, especially in adolescence.
Guys will know what that means.
All of it was no, no.
The whole subject was no, no.
The whole subject and all expressions thereof was sin.
That's tough to live with at 18, yeah?
All right, so the interpretation then of the animal instincts
became, I call it the Gothic viewpoint,
became sackcloth sin and penance
and fasting all during Lent and all kinds of miserable things.
Then one day walking through the woods,
I think I've related before,
not thinking of anything at all,
beautiful day in the woods,
out of the stillness and silence emerged
like a presentation,
a knowingness of the totality
of the suffering
of all of mankind throughout all of the ages.
The totality of the suffering of all of mankind.
A profound shock.
Profound shock.
Profound.
Right to the center of my being almost.
In that instant I became an atheist.
I said I cannot because in those days people thought
God created everything, see?
Like a personal act,
but decided so.
So I held God responsible
and of course the spiritual error was
I was seeing the consequences of the ego
and I held God responsible
for what the ego had created for man.
The current catastrophes in the world
are the consequence of the human ego.
At that time I would have blamed it on God.
I became a rabid atheist.
I was a ferocious atheist too.
I got straight A in theology,
straight A in the ethics,
straight A in Thomas Aquinas.
All the time I was an atheist.
The arguments for the existence of God
as first cause is idiotic.
It is idiotic.
You saw that this morning in our opening.
There is no first cause which would
make God linear with a beginning
and an ending and an elsewhere-ness.
Forever-ness is forever-ness.
It doesn't have any start.
So then I was free of the downside,
the interpretation of the animal instincts.
Their depiction is evil
and now you have to feel guilt and shame
and penance and all kinds of things.
And also you get addicted to that.
Curiously, when you depict it that way
it is now more difficult to get rid of.
Because you have given it importance
and strength and prominence
which it doesn't have in and of itself.
How did this arise then?
What the world calls sin and evil
is really the prevalence of the animal ego,
is it not?
Selfishness.
So when we look how life evolved
in the very beginning,
we see that life,
in order to survive on this planet,
had to have the capacity
to acquire energy.
That's the characteristic
of your ego right now.
The leading edge of the ego
is what I call the experiencer,
which we'll get to later.
It is constantly searching,
searching, searching, searching.
You look at Technicolor movies
from the bottom of the sea,
incredibly beautiful.
The incredible beauty
of all that exists down there,
every single thing there is incredible.
And you see that everything there
has exactly one function.
It's obsessed with getting, you know.
Even my cat's always at the dish.
I say, what the hell is this?
Are you some kind of an eating machine?
It's a fur-covered eating machine.
He's eaten four times today
and now he's at his bowl.
Meow, meow.
All right, so now here we have
the calibrated level of life.
You see it at its emergence.
So if we picked you up
and threw you onto Mars,
your survival is what you're about, right?
Your survival.
Where are you going to get oxygen?
Where are you going to get water?
Where are you going to get
what you need to survive?
So the ego has to do with get.
Get, get.
It sees itself as insufficient.
So the beginning.
Bacteria start at one.
Algae don't calibrate.
Calibrate at one.
Marine invertebrates at eight,
like a trilobite.
You get the early fish.
Scorpions.
Scorpions have been around
for 40, 400 million years.
They climbed out of the sea
and hang out causing trouble.
Some people like scorpions.
God bless them.
You sit on one,
we'll see how you change your mind.
They're at 17.
Then you get amphibians,
the great sharks,
the great white sharks,
the first reptiles,
the mirage of reptiles.
Dinosaurs.
Bony fishes.
The first birds.
Here we have birds.
And primitive mammals.
And now you see,
it took,
these are archeologic ages,
you know.
Like 1,300 billion years
or something,
which I can't even comprehend anyway.
So we'll go to the next slide.
You see how life evolved then.
These are not sinful.
They're not sinful.
The scorpion fish,
you know,
he just eats things.
All right.
So we have bacteria,
protozoa,
insects,
fish,
sharks.
Here we have the Komodo dragon at 40.
Reptiles.
You see these are all,
we picture them as predatory.
They're all predatory.
The birds of prey,
the rhinoceros.
And then you get higher and higher and higher.
And now at 200,
you suddenly see a shift of lifestyle.
You run into the giraffe,
the zebra,
the gazelle,
the deer.
And they do not live by predation.
They don't kill anybody.
So these animals here are higher than,
you're safer here
than you are with 80% of the people on the planet.
A giraffe will leave you alone
unless you just go around with them.
And then he'll give you a kick.
But he doesn't eat you.
The giraffe doesn't come over
and hit you over the head
and knock you unconscious
and begin to nibble on you.
He just says,
you're in my territory.
Whoop.
There he goes.
I don't know who thought up a giraffe.
They had a sense of humor,
I guess.
Some archangel,
some blade.
They have a design studio
somewhere up in heaven.
I already think of this one.
Okay, elephants,
you gotta be a little cautious with elephants.
They won't eat you either.
But they may sit on you.
And here we have kitty cats,
family cats.
You see how it evolves.
And then the chimpanzee
who has 99 point something,
the same DNA as we do.
And so you see
consciousness evolves
from severely predacious,
savage,
inconsiderate of the life of others,
then these people begin to form families.
You see the emergence of maternal care.
And now we get up to the highest levels.
And, of course,
we always like to mention
a dog's wagging tail is 500
and a cat's fur is 500.
A songbird's song is 500.
And a great parrot, Alex,
is exceptionally smarter than broccoli.
Well, he should.
He's got a PhD.
We spent years training him.
Broccoli had somebody like that,
year in and year out.
Let's see where broccoli is.
Broccoli's over 350.
355.
Broccoli's sort of stuck there,
around 350.
All right, the purpose of seeing all this.
What's the next slide?
I don't know what it is.
What's the next slide, you know?
All right.
What I'm trying to display then
is the evolution of consciousness.
All right, well, we'll save that one.
We'll flip that off for a second.
All right, so what we want to get out of all of this
is that the essence of life is to get.
So there's no point in feeling guilty about your ego,
selfishness.
You're supposed to be selfish
up to a point,
up to consciousness level 200.
It's supposed to run you.
Over 200, it's still,
is a tendency.
Sometimes it's strong.
Sometimes it's weak.
But it's not where you live.
It's not your,
the way you live.
You don't live in a predatory manner.
There are parts of the world that calibrate 200.
The whole contextualization of their society is predacious.
The minute you get off the plane,
they're selling you stuff.
They're fake,
fake antiques.
I said, how much is it to ride on a plane?
I said, how much is it to ride on this camel?
Five dollars.
Okay.
It's time to get off the camel.
Have you ever tried getting off a camel?
You have no idea how tall,
way up in the air a camel is.
You think of it like a big horse.
A camel is up where that ceiling is.
Now you want to get off.
How are you going to get off a camel without a ladder?
You can't.
So I say to the camel driver,
okay,
that's enough ride for you today.
I think I'll get down.
That'll be ten dollars, he says.
I contracted five dollars for the camel ride.
Now he wants ten to get off the camel.
You realize that's a matter of honor with him.
It's a matter of honor.
The naivete of international diplomacy just blows my mind.
We won't get into that today.
Do not know who you're dealing with.
It's a matter of pride.
Anybody in that culture
that pays an asking price
lives in shame henceforth.
Being nice to them
is considered weakness, idiocy,
and you deserve to die
because you're so stupid.
That's today's world.
All right.
So this animal then, instinct,
operates in the human brain.
Over the evolutionary time,
the prefrontal cortex,
when the hominid arose,
he got up on two hind feet.
And now he had two more limbs.
See?
He had that,
you got four limbs,
they're all busy just,
you know,
walking around.
What time did we quit?
Tell me.
1115?
Okay.
All right.
So the hominid then emerges.
Each thing emerges independent of the evolutionary tree.
Evolution,
when it comes to its linear designation,
occurs in the level of consciousness.
That's why you can't find
any missing links in the world
because there aren't any.
There aren't any missing links in the world.
Evolution of consciousness is within,
evolution is within consciousness.
And then it manifests out
and manifests
and it manifests in physicality.
So the evolution of the ego then
is that quality of life
since it began.
Since life began.
So you can see why spiritual work is difficult.
Because you're trying to overcome
patterns that have
consolidated over millennia,
over millennia.
Therefore,
the downside of human nature,
what we call the ego,
sin, guilt,
all the things that we
struggle to overcome and transcend,
judgmentalism,
vindictiveness,
et cetera,
are all qualities of our,
of our evolutionary,
the source of our evolution.
So what we do then,
instead of vilifying it,
feeling guilt,
blaming yourself,
see,
if you blame yourself,
then you got to project that onto the world.
So they're the ones that are causing it.
You know, they're the ones.
Then you have to attack and kill them.
What would the world be without that?
Nothing to do, I guess.
Kept mankind busy
and throughout the history of civilization,
you know,
peace has reigned 7% of the time.
7% of man's history
has been at peace.
93% of the time
we're at war.
93%.
Yeah.
So peace is in a natural condition.
Most people hate it.
Most people hate peace.
You know that.
I say, you know,
if you forgive this guy,
you'd be at peace.
Yeah, well, he don't deserve it.
He just refused peace, didn't he?
People refuse peace.
They really hate peace.
Why?
Because in the condition of peace,
they're nobody.
In a non-peaceful situation,
you get to be somebody.
You get to wear daggers.
You get to be the killer, bravado.
You get to be in charge.
Uh-huh.
You're somebody.
After the war is over,
who are you?
You're an ex-admiral.
Interesting, but...
All right, so I just want you
to get a benign view of the ego
before we get into the ego.
Look at it as benign.
It's animal.
It's just animal.
If your cat gets into the fish
you brought home from dinner
and eats it,
it isn't being evil.
It doesn't have to wear
sackcloth and ashes.
It doesn't have to go to confession.
It's just the kitty being a kitty.
So I want you to love your ego.
And I brought ego with me.
You always want something.
That's the way I'm brought up.
If I get mad at it, I chew it.
Oh, yeah, he bites it.
Uh-oh.
Aggression, that is innate.
So all the qualities that we work to overcome.
See, because when the prefrontal cortex evolved,
the hominids took it up.
Now he's got two limbs to do something with.
He got an opposing thumb.
Usually they have an opposing thumb.
I thought it was still there, for God's sake.
Anyway, with an opposing thumb,
now he can handle tools.
And the prefrontal cortex
became more and more complex.
But the prefrontal cortex
didn't replace the old animal brain.
It was just put there on top of it.
Now you can figure clever ways
to kill your enemies.
Clever, intelligent ways.
Atomic bombs.
So now what you have is an animal
that can think and is intelligent.
And that's really dangerous.
All right.
So we're going to take a break.
And we're going to resume.
Resume?
Resume.
We're going to resume at what time?
Huh?
We're going to resume in 15 minutes.
And again, we're going to give the best part of the lecture
in the beginning.
So if you're late, you'll miss it.
I have to wash my mouth.
I was soaked.
Where were we?
We were at...
We were ready for the great books
of the rest of the world, yeah?
All right.
We've gone over a number of these things
a lot of times.
And of course, repetition.
Repetition.
After you've heard a thing enough times,
you don't have to understand or think about it.
You just know it.
So I want to save you the problem of thinking.
I've repeated it often enough.
It's going to be handy when you try to clear guilt, see?
Because guilt has to do with demonizing the animal kingdom
within yourself.
All right.
So consciousness, you see how it evolved.
And then it came a long way.
And finally, in the 400s, you see the world of the intellect,
which is, of course, the blessings of the intellect
are civilization and science and pharmacology,
the electronic...
Well, I won't mention the electronic world, but anyway.
These are the great books of the Western world.
We calibrated every one.
You see they run in the mid-400s.
Occasionally, somebody gets to the high 400s.
Notable is Einstein, Freud, Sir Isaac Newton at 499.
That's genius as far as the intellect can go.
There's a paradigm jump at 499.
And this is difficult for people to comprehend.
All right.
The world from 500 up is of context and not content.
So the jump from the limitation of causality
means you have to jump the intellect.
Hegel...
Where is Hegel at 470?
I have a couple of favorites here.
Hegel, because one of Hegel's principles,
that was in Germany,
the high point of the intellect,
the great philosophers of Germany.
Hegel postulated the concept
of the principle of the absolute,
the absolute,
which is in diametric opposition
to today's modernistic, postmodernism,
trying to substitute relativism.
Relativism really says there is no God.
It really says that.
Many of them say it overtly.
Others do it just more sneakily.
That everything is only what you say it is
or think it is.
Which also negates the Cartesian principle.
So the modern world,
the social contention,
is based on relativism,
which calibrates quite low.
And of course,
the biggest proponent of relativism
was Karl Marx.
And Karl Marx, you see, stands out.
Everybody here is in the 400s,
even into 505, you know.
We have a great Schroesser, a Descartes.
All the great minds of history are here.
And because of history,
Marx was put in the great books of the rest of the world
at 130.
Stands out like a sore thumb.
And the devastation of society
is really Marxism in various disguises.
Which Marxism is so weak
because it sees dualistically,
it sees everything in terms of perpetrator and victim.
The minute you don't take responsibility,
you're now weak.
And that's why I'm sort of a champion of
the former comedian
who goes around
Bill Cosby, yeah.
Telling people, unless you accept responsibility,
the game is over, you know.
Responsibility.
That's all it is.
It's taking personal responsibility.
Well, Marx says there isn't any.
Nothing is your fault
because everything is the fault of something else.
So, that's the downside of relativism
which calibrates about 170 or 180.
And the philosophic schools that grew out of it.
So, it's an anomaly.
My favorite isn't even on here
and that's Socrates.
Socrates at about 570.
If you get just a couple of concepts,
everything else resolves.
You got the evolution of the ego,
that gets you off guilt.
Socrates will get you off the rest of the guilt.
Socrates never wrote any books.
He was short and ugly and bad to look at.
He had a mean wife, too.
Socrates' wife, Xanthippe,
had a sharp tongue
and she's famous throughout history.
I guess he went into thinking this
to get away from all that.
Anyway, from the dialogues of Plato and all that.
So, Socrates never wrote anything.
But Socrates at 570
got the whole principle,
without it you don't even need the Course of Miracles.
Socrates says that all men choose only the good.
The only problem is they don't know what is the good.
And they choose the illusory good for the real good.
They choose the temporary and temporal
for that which is eternal.
But you see the basic innocence then.
So, you see the basic innocence of man
by the evolution of consciousness
which you presented as it grew out of the animal kingdom.
The best way to evolve,
spiritually,
is to take like one stanza
of the 91st Psalm
and just be with it all week.
And the next week take the next stanza.
Then you have Socrates' month.
So we could designate June
as Socrates' month.
The way, you see,
the way of enlightenment is contemplative.
Meditation will take you into Samadhi.
But then when you get up and uncross your legs
and walk around the world,
the Samadhi disappears.
Contemplation takes you so that you become that.
It doesn't disappear when you get up and walk around.
Contemplation is a lifestyle.
By intention you dedicate your life to God
and your life thereby becomes a prayer.
As a manifestation of that prayer,
then you revere
the evolution of spiritual truth
as it came down over the centuries.
And then you move forward to the other side,
hang out with Socrates.
How's it going?
Well, you did pretty good with it there.
You gave him a whole week on it.
You could have given him two weeks.
The mind chooses only the good.
If that includes blowing up a busload of children,
don't you see, that's done for the good.
The mind chooses always what it deems to be the good.
If it's dominated by the animal,
then gain is always the good.
The intrinsic innocence.
From my own research,
say the mind is like,
the human mind is like a computer.
The brain is your hardware,
and then the software is superimposed.
Now the hardware has no say
about what it gets programmed with.
It'll play anything.
Whether that's true or false,
the hardware has no way of knowing that.
So people are programmed throughout life.
The mind is intrinsically innocent.
It cannot tell truth from falsehood,
because discernment doesn't occur
until the opening of the third eye of the Buddhic body.
At that point, you're extremely advanced.
And by that time,
you have spiritual vision instead of perception.
Spiritual vision,
you get the totality and the feeling,
the knowingness of the essential truth of a thing.
If you've done a lot of kinesiologic testing
and calibrating of things,
you finally get to be sort of that way yourself.
Somebody gives you a book,
you look at it,
and you get,
I get what it is.
It's about 280, yeah.
So you begin,
you become sensitive to the essence of things.
Therefore, the mind is innocent.
Everybody is innocent.
Because their hardware cannot control
the content of the software.
Of course, the miracle says that.
Jesus Christ says that.
The Buddha said that.
Man has only one sin,
in quotes,
and that is ignorance.
He does not know truth from falsehood.
At this point in evolutionary time,
emerging from the animal to the spiritual reality,
80% of mankind
is unable to discern truth from falsehood.
All right.
So the mind automatically then
chooses what it presumes to be the good.
That gives us a certain compassion
for all of life.
Yes?
This is the relationship
of the field of consciousness itself,
the context.
And this is content.
Content is linear.
Content is what differentiates a this from a that.
It's the limitation.
The limitation of the intellect.
The reason.
So the 400s represent the highest level
of sophistication and handling,
not the world but symbols of the world,
mathematics and concepts,
logic and reason.
The dialectic of reason
is what has fallen into disrepute
in academia.
So academia, which once calibrated
in the mid-400s
in many universities,
has dropped to like 180 or 190.
The greatest universities in the world
have come down, down, down, down.
And they now teach a philosophy
that calibrates at 190.
Yeah.
So education has come down over time.
So.
All right.
So anyway,
this is the field that spontaneously brings into
actuality potentiality.
So we'll move on.
So this is spirit and this is ego.
OK.
Spirit, this is spirit and this is ego.
Yes.
Well, today is on intention.
Today is Heisenberg Day.
Now all the great saints of history
didn't know anything about Heisenberg.
All right.
So you don't have to be irrational
to believe in prayer
or the power of intention
because now quantum mechanics
has demonstrated that.
And it's a very important connection
between the intellect, reason, rationality.
And it gets you off being ridiculed
by the secularist or the intellectual.
You say, why are you believing
in all that mystical, spiritual stuff?
And you tell them,
look, I'm just busy collapsing,
collapsing the potential.
I'm collapsing the wave function,
spiritual work.
I'm just putting into practice
the Heisenberg principle.
Oh, that's what you're doing.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Oh.
All right.
Intention is so powerful.
Now let's see the difference
between intellectual observation,
intellectual observation.
So the Heisenberg principle
was based on scientific experiments.
The minute you witness,
observe the experiment,
you've already changed the result.
OK.
Now, so the power of that intention
would be correlated
with the consciousness
level of the observer.
That is correct.
Resist.
OK.
So the power of the...
All right.
So the effect of the intention
of the observer
is going to depend
on the consciousness level.
I knew this years ago.
I run a big clinic, you know,
real big.
And I hired psychiatrists,
right and left therapists,
psychologists, et cetera.
And some doctors
just got everybody better.
And other doctors,
nobody seemed to get better.
According to the scientific design,
then,
which sees causality,
it believes in pharmacology.
I'll tell you,
I can get double the recovery rate
with Prozac
than somebody else can with Prozac.
Easily.
Double.
Yeah.
Let's see if that's true.
That's fact.
Triple.
Quadruple.
Ten times.
OK.
Ten times the recovery rate
would be the same.
Should we try for ten?
No.
The way we go over ten,
I know how it goes over ten.
What I'm holding in mind
is a fact, yeah.
OK.
Because I would pray for them.
That jumped you way beyond ten.
All right.
So the consciousness level of...
See, the physician
is not a mechanical pharmacologist.
He's a healer.
The modern paradigm,
which is secular,
doesn't see the physician
as a healer.
He sees them
as a provider of services.
A provider of services
is lucky to get a 20% improvement
with Prozac.
No.
The healer, then,
is the physician
whose caringness
about his patients
is so powerful
that anything will work
that he prescribes for them.
Well, we discovered that years ago.
So the effect
on the result
of the scientific experiment
reflects the level of consciousness
of the investigator
and not the mechanism being tested.
That revolutionizes all of research.
I can tell you,
in a research design,
the likelihood is success.
Now, if you tell me
who's going to do it,
I can guarantee to tell you.
All right.
So the power of the investigator
is more powerful
than the design,
the scientific design.
Some physicians,
everybody gets better.
Other physicians,
hardly anybody gets better.
Once in a while,
you get a hard nut.
I had one patient
that never got better.
When I finally quit practice,
I threw up my hands.
I don't know.
This guy just won't get better.
Frustration.
I tried everything.
I sent him to acupuncturists.
I did everything.
Chinese medicine,
herbal energy balancing.
I don't know.
Nothing ever made him feel better.
Even alcohol didn't feel better.
So I think that's true.
Don't you have a few drinks
or something?
I don't know.
I think he had a blood-brain barrier.
No matter what you put
in his bloodstream,
it somehow did not get
into his brain.
But that was the one guy.
Remember at the end
when I quit practicing?
I hung out with all my old patients
until they all teetered over
and died.
I didn't want to desert them.
But this one guy,
I had to refer him
to the Mayo Clinic.
I sent him to the Mayo Clinic.
God bless.
All right.
So the Heisenberg principle then
is that intention,
the field of consciousness,
you saw it from content and field.
The field is so powerful
that what you witness
as your consciousness advances
is that everything is fulfilling
its potentiality.
It's becoming the actuality.
The actuality happens
as a consequence of the field.
So your intention
is what empowers it to happen.
To devote yourself
to the search for enlightenment,
for Christ consciousness,
whatever you want,
self-realization,
to evolve spiritually
is so powerful
that it now aligns
everything in your life
because of the field.
All right.
So we know that
the Schrodinger equation
are both time-dependent
and time-independent.
That is the...
Then you introduce intention,
the Heisenberg principle.
Now the universe is different.
You've collapsed the wave function,
which is the quantum mechanics way
of saying what I've said
during lectures.
Potentiality becomes an actuality.
You've collapsed the wave function
by intention, by intention.
So the power of intention then
is even more powerful
if the intention
is instituted by a person
who is spiritually oriented.
Okay?
So below 200,
the fulfillment of an intention
is pretty much guided by
the animal level of consciousness.
The minute you get over 200 now,
you've pulled into the field
enormous power.
So a spiritual intention
is an act of the will,
is a very, very powerful event,
and it has enormous karmic consequences.
Uh-huh.
The von Neumann process
gives you the details.
Now we said Einstein was at 499.
Freud and Einstein both,
you know, refuted spiritual reality.
Einstein was religious,
but he said,
after the Soviet conference
in Denmark, I think it was,
that he preferred to believe
that there was an independent
existence out there,
an independent universe
that existed independently
of consciousness.
Independently of consciousness.
Yeah.
And so he's,
so at 499 is a paradigm jump,
paradigm jump,
out of causality,
out of,
and you move to subjectivity.
So at 500,
you move to the level of love.
That which is provable
is not spiritual reality.
Spirituality can be demonstrated,
confirmed,
experienced,
verified,
but it cannot be proven.
You cannot prove
that somebody loves somebody.
You cannot prove.
That which is provable
belongs to the 400s,
Newtonian paradigm
of cause and effect,
causality.
All right.
So Einstein drew back from it,
of course, as did Freud.
Freud, I agreed with,
as far as his,
that the images of divinity
are really projections
from the unconscious.
So what he's talking about
is the negative depictions,
the satanic depictions
of God of the Old Testament
as angry,
capricious,
paranoid,
jealous,
given to specialness,
favoritism,
et cetera.
Freud said,
that's on the unconscious
and projected on the divinity.
So because he disproved
the reality of
an actual truthful divinity,
he then falsely concluded,
therefore, there was no divinity.
The fact that the way you depicted it
is false,
and the limitation of that
would have been
the false depictions of God
are false
and arise out of
the collective unconscious.
Primitive man,
when the thunder rolled
and the volcano erupted,
he sacrificed more maidens.
The Mayan and Aztecs
calibrated about 90.
You know the priests
were so busy?
Busy.
How many hearts
they could rip out per hour?
Thousands were lined up
for centuries.
Those religions calibrated 90.
All right.
So Einstein then pulled back.
So there you have
what's called
the paradigm blindness.
So much of science,
journals on science
and religion,
science and consciousness,
is in the paradigm of blindness.
Religion, science,
and consciousness,
et cetera.
And conferences,
because I've spoken at them.
And they're stuck in that paradigm.
And you can't prove one paradigm
by the tools of another.
You can't find
ghosts with a Geiger counter.
So that's what science is doing,
is trying to find
ghosts with a Geiger counter,
because the intellect
is not the tool
to investigate
or verify spiritual realities.
There you have to deal with
the world of the mystics,
and people who have
subjectively experienced.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
We'll move on.
Yeah.
Now,
this is very important,
because what happens
at consciousness level,
you see,
without the avatars,
without the evolution
of spiritual awareness,
mankind,
the evolution of mankind
would have stopped at 200.
But man has intuited divinity.
Native American culture
intuited the Great Spirit,
mankind has intuited divinity.
All right.
So without the intuitive
knowingness of divinity,
consciousness,
mankind would have
destroyed himself.
Mankind would have
Why?
Because this animal over here,
the left brain,
would eventually,
once you gave him
atomic bombs
and machine guns and all,
would kill everyone.
Without spiritual awareness,
mankind would have
self-destructed,
resist.
Without spiritual energy,
without the Kundalini energy,
mankind would have
self-destructed,
self-destructed.
All right.
So the left brain then,
here's your animal brain.
Here's the animal brain.
We've done this before,
but it's good to know
that spirituality
is based on
a wholly different
brain function.
This is the animal brain,
you see,
which quickly bypasses
the cortex,
goes to another brain,
and then goes to
another brain,
the cortex,
goes to emotions,
and stores that in memory.
So below 200,
people have negative
memories of life.
And if they have
a good memory,
it's associated with
the pain of longing
or regretting.
So they never really
get to be happy.
Above 200 now,
you see the input
of the Kundalini energy,
and you see something
of great importance,
the emergence
of the etheric brain.
The animal does not
have an etheric brain.
People below 200,
I checked this over
and over and over
and I discovered that
people below 200
do not have
an etheric brain.
No.
They do not have
an etheric brain.
Not possible
to have spiritual awareness.
So what happens at 200 then,
by intention
and invocation,
what happens is
you now pull into yourself
spiritual energy,
the Kundalini energy,
and it shifts you
to the right side
of your brain,
the fast track
is through your
cerebral cortex,
the frontal cortex,
through your intelligence,
and especially
through your spiritual awareness,
it's very fast
to the emotional center.
Here you see
it was the animal response.
Here's the animal response.
Somebody cuts in
in front of you in traffic,
you son of a bitch,
I'm gonna get even with you.
And you go home
and you tell your wife,
boy, he was an SLB, you know.
Hopefully,
with the development
of the etheric brain,
this is no longer satisfactory
to you.
And you say,
what the hell,
give the guy a break.
You give the guy a break,
let him in.
So you're delayed
two seconds
getting to the grocery store.
You're not on your way
to a fire
or catching a plane.
All the indignation,
you think people
are going someplace important,
you know.
They're going to pick up
a Pepsi at the nearest
mini-mart.
And this tremendous
rush of energy
and energy
is tremendous rush.
You see him
like this
and then you pass him
and there he is,
he's getting a Coke.
Risking his life,
everybody's life,
risking his driver's license,
getting points,
running up his insurance bill.
Because he's run
with this here,
Harvey Wallbanger.
You remember the days
of the CBs?
It was fun.
I had my old truck,
you know,
and I drove all over the place
in my old truck.
And then you'd hear
there's a,
there's a Harvey Wallbanger
coming in east on 60.
Harvey Wallbanger
was a guy who was driving
like 85,
you know,
and going up on two wheels.
He always had a red car,
a red car.
That's why the insurance
rates are always higher
on red cars.
Did you know that?
They are,
they're higher on a red car,
yeah.
All right,
so because it tends
to pull up the left brain,
this brain will let
somebody in
and say,
give the guy a break.
All right,
so below 200
you got left brain dominance
and you're being run
by adrenaline.
You also tend to run out
the neurotransmitters
and you need Prozac
after a while.
Above 200,
the right brain dominates.
It's,
it enjoys peace,
positive emotion,
increased immunity,
a balanced acupuncture system.
All right,
so spiritual energy,
the Kundalini energy.
We'll move to the next slide.
So,
the so-called
Kundalini energy.
It sounds so Sanskrit,
you know,
it sounds so old Hindu
and Sanskrit-y
that it's really hard
for an American
to buy a Kundalini energy.
I'm going to invent
a new one.
I just call it
spiritual energy.
Spiritual energy
is unique.
It comes from the field.
It's transformative.
You now experience
yourself
and others
differently.
You know,
below 200,
humans
and animals
do not experience
that they exist
and that they exist
and that they exist.
They do not know
or experience
that they are.
Only over 200
do you become aware
that you are.
Only over 200
do you become aware
that you are.
Therefore,
there's no concern
for others below 200.
Over 200,
you experience
that you are.
So,
you presume
that the little beetle
on his back
is distressed.
You stop
and turn him over.
All right,
so you have
a different
way of relating
to the world
so intention
means you end up
relating
to the world
in a more benevolent fashion
towards all of life.
It also opens
your eyes
to beauty.
Once the right brain
is energized
by Kundalini energy,
if you stare
too much
at that,
you're going
to stop
the lecture.
As you move along,
eventually,
you discover
what you can't do
and still function
in the world.
All right,
so because
the stunning beauty
of everything
in the world
begins to shine
forth,
and it's
startling,
it's iridescent,
the absolute
perfection
and exquisite
beauty
of all
that exists
shines forth.
Everything
that exists
within form
is incredibly
and magnificently
beautiful
and that
begins
to dawn
on you.
You're walking
through the woods
and suddenly,
wow,
did somebody
turn on
the Technicolor
or what?
Everything begins
to radiate
and shimmer
with an innate
beauty,
not a conceptualized
beauty that
you project
onto it,
but its essence
shines forth.
It reveals
itself.
So spiritual
truth
is not
acquired.
It's revealing.
It's self-revealing.
And as it shines
forth,
the mind
goes silent
and nothing
to be said.
The perfection
of all things
stands forth.
Just as there's
no cause
for anything
out there,
neither is there
anything out there
that can make
you happy.
It can satisfy
your wantingness
momentarily.
All right.
We find that
the level
of consciousness,
how it presents
itself
in human life,
is directly
correlated
with rate
of employment,
rate of poverty.
You can have
suicide rate,
addiction rate,
happiness rate,
rate of criminality.
And you see
a major jump
here at 200.
Here at 200,
you see
the rate
of happiness
goes from
2%.
The number
of people
in prison
who are happy
is about
2%.
Calibrated level
of federal inmates
is about
50.
Calibrated level
of happiness
there is
about
2%.
The minute
you jump
over consciousness
level 200,
you instantly
have already
jumped
to 15%.
40%.
Okay.
Happiness.
So,
the causality
that there's
an out there-ness
causing you
to be the way
you are
or feel
the way
you are,
you feel
the way
you are
because of
what you are.
Because of
Eventually,
less becomes
more.
Yeah.
The less
you have,
the happier
you are.
Right now,
we were saying,
in terms of
activities,
we do.
Susan said
this week,
she says,
I spent
the whole week
with cars.
I spent
the whole week
with automobiles.
Yesterday,
I had to
go over
and get
the old truck.
That was
the last one.
The more
cars you have,
the more
encumbered
you become.
Anyway,
that's
present life.
We'll move
to the next one.
It pulls
forth
a very
powerful
energy
that transforms
the way
you experience
the world.
It shifts
you from
perception
to vision.
Oh,
we wanted
to,
how much
time
do we have
left?
Okay,
we're going
to finish
up here.
No,
I don't
need
you right
away.
What I'm holding
in mind,
what I'm holding
in mind
calibrates
over time.
That's
all I want
to know.
Let's see,
I want to
make sure
we get
through
because otherwise
we're not
going to be
happy
this afternoon.
Yeah,
we will.
Okay.