They've got all kinds of big people in the world now.
I don't know.
People were smaller when I first got here.
Now they're all bigger.
How are you doing, Dr. Robinson?
Good to see you.
Did we say hi to people here, over here?
There.
Hi, sweetheart.
Did we miss anybody?
The ladies wanted to say hi to you.
Yes, sweetheart, yeah, hi.
We'll come up to this side and go around.
I don't know.
Now we'll go do more things.
How are you?
Good to see you.
This is Sherry, my son's wife.
Hello.
Thank you.
Nice to see you again.
Ah, yes.
Hi, Doc.
How are you?
Good to see you.
Ah, I got you.
Thank you.
Here, we've got to do this side again now.
This is by Lindahl from Germany.
Oh, yes, I remember now, yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
So, say I love you.
Ah, here's all the people here.
Hi, hi.
Good to see you.
Hi.
It's an honor to be with you again soon.
Good morning, Doc.
I'm so happy to see you.
Good to see you.
Thank you.
Anybody we miss, we don't want to miss anybody, huh?
We want everybody to get to heaven.
We don't want to miss anybody, huh?
Absolutely.
Get there and say, where's George?
Oh, God.
If we don't say hello to everybody, we have to back up the bus.
Go back and pick up George.
He's got 20 more years to go.
Holy God.
We get everybody?
Then we get everyone.
We're better.
Right on time, Doc.
Right on time.
It's turned on, so I can hear what I'm saying.
Who's in the side control room today?
Gabe.
Oh, Gabe.
Let's see how he works.
Now, let's see you do that, eh?
Oh, the egos dream to be in control.
To rule everybody.
Make them do what you want them to do.
Make them think what you want them to think.
Behave the way you want them to behave.
And die for you, too.
Just a minor thing.
You should die for my beliefs.
That's today's rule internationally.
You all should die because of what I think.
Okay, so we start out the lecture with the ending.
That saves listening to the whole thing.
You can go to sleep.
We start from the beginning.
And we'll talk about leaving anything after that.
My final piece of advice is the way to the ultimate truth
is really to become the context instead of the content.
To make one's life a prayer.
To become that which people talk about.
To be kindly.
To be forgiving.
To see and witness the sacredness of all things.
And if you stay with the context continuously,
eventually what you witness
is that everything comes about spontaneously,
all on its own everything happens automatically is a consequence of the very nature of reality
itself there is no personal you doing anything all that's happening of its own all you have to
do is reject the vanity that there is an eye causing all that to happen the willingness to
let go seeing yourself as cause all happens spontaneously so with humility you say to the
mind you don't you see what's happening but you don't understand it you don't understand it all
you can provide is an explanation and an explanation is not the reality the explanation
is extraneous to the reality it has to be in order to be an explanation
hmm
so with sort of a deep humility you begin to witness that everything is happening spontaneously
of its own because there is potentiality potentiality then manifests as an actuality
and it does so by the power of the field not by the power of you minor little correction
makes the difference between heaven and hell
well
minor
I'd argue meant and all kinds of things all right so don't go with the ego and don't listen to
reason because that's its playground it plays with your head don't let it play with your head
say I don't want to go there it's a matter of witnessing we said there's two main spiritual
practices meditation and contemplation meditation serves its purposes at specific times in your life
where you have a mind you're not listening to the narrative right now there are two forms of the self
you can't live there
because you won't cross the first street
ha ha ha ha
together in laden
you can get taken out by the bus you know
ha
all right so meditation
we're just finishing a book nowhere finishing two books simultaneously as we knock off the tail of the last one three
books
um
in one of the books anyway
ha ha ha ha
It has to do with meditation and contemplation as a specific subject.
Meditation has its place.
It's very specific. It's very focused.
It always talks about one-pointedness of mind.
But it leads in, to me, meditation can also become a diversion.
Many are the meditators. Few are the enlightened.
And there's reasons for it, which we do cover in the lectures.
Because meditation is somewhat removed from life.
For 20 years or something, I did it for an hour in the morning and an hour in the evening.
But if your life gets busy, then you begin to skip it.
You take a class on meditation, you do a workshop, and boy, you're enthusiastic as all get-out.
You know, for maybe four or six months.
And then your aunt Tilly gets sick and visits, and well, well.
So you abandon it.
You abandon it.
Because it's not who you are.
It's something you're doing.
And it gets, it becomes held dualistically.
There's a me that's meditating.
A me here and now that's meditating then and there.
So it's not really you.
And very often, I think, there's deviations that are labeled meditation,
but they're really methods of achieving altered states of consciousness.
And when you stop whatever the thing is you're doing,
the altered state of consciousness disappears.
And the states that arise in sort of, to me, artificially-induced states are transitory.
They're called satori.
They come and they go.
And you can stand up and walk around and open your eyes to the spirit.
Transitory.
They are useful in another way because they give you a glimpse that there is another dimension,
another experiential dimension.
There is another experiential dimension there.
And, of course, the difficulty, as we pointed out in the lectures,
and we'll probably...
we'll cross over it again today,
is the idea that one can catch the space between two thoughts.
There isn't any space between two thoughts, folks.
And nobody's ever found it.
So we'll clarify that.
It's the space prior to the thoughts out of which all thoughts arise, a common field.
So contemplation then is a lifestyle, a way of being in the world.
And first, it's a disciplined practice.
Eventually, that's the reality of who you have become.
There is no this and that because you are that to begin with.
So that state, that condition that you contemplate,
the reason it works is because it is you.
Isn't that funny?
You imitate your real self artificially.
Oh, everything's beautiful.
Yes, yes, yes.
They're trying to say everything's beautiful.
But that's a steam engine.
Is that beautiful?
You know what I mean?
Well, I'm supposed to see its beauty.
So you stand back.
How about the horse apples on the street?
Are they beautiful?
My grandmother was Wisconsin, Milwaukee.
You know, when I grew up, horse and wagons were prevalent.
And electric cars, gimbals and all, had electric carts.
Looked like sort of UPS trucks today, but they're electric.
They're quiet.
And then there were the horses.
So the streets would get pretty thick.
We didn't go to the store.
The store came by.
It came in a wagon.
There was the fish man, the meat man, the bakery man, the utensils man, the hardware man.
Everything came down the alley.
So you didn't have to really go to the store.
But on a hot, hot day after a rain, it got pretty strong.
And my granddad, he said, you know what?
I'm going to go to the store.
And my grandmother, you know, would call up the sanitation department.
And she'd say, it's so strong, it's making the tears come to my eyes.
And then you'd see the guys down there, four breasts, you know.
Just a different way of life, huh?
Just a different way of life.
Yeah, when you're broke, that's a good job sweeping up that stuff.
I would have taken it.
I was too small.
You got to be stronger, they said.
.
Those big brims are very heavy.
You'd think they're light.
No, they're pretty heavy.
After three hours, they really get heavy.
All of that is apropos of nothing.
And why not?
Everything is apropos.
Something has gotten us into a hell of a pickle.
I think it's best to concentrate on things that are totally unimportant.
This morning, I was concentrating on something absolutely, totally unimportant.
Something I got.
Ah, incredible discovery.
See how it comes.
If I'd been thinking about something important, I would have never realized it.
I don't know whether to tell them or not.
Anyway.
Should we tell them what the realization was?
Yes?
Absolutely?
I didn't know it myself.
What was the purpose of this life, you see?
This life was very strange in many ways.
You know, starting at age three, I was thinking about life.
I was thinking about my family.
I was thinking about my friends.
And I was thinking about myself.
You know.
I was thinking about my family.
and then recurrently at age 12, and periodically, you know,
rather, you know, at least from a historical viewpoint,
rather unusual in the staggering states.
And the thought was, how come?
And then one time I was giving a lecture.
It was here someplace, you know, the other hotel, I think.
And I'm walking down the aisle, and I could leave.
I didn't know whether I was going to leave or not.
The permission to leave, which has been recurrent also.
But no, the body continued to walk on.
And I thought it looked sort of funny it falling down in the middle of a lecture,
but it's none of my business, so it walked on.
I said, oh, okay.
So it seems to be like some kind of a commitment.
So thinking about nothing at all this morning,
with manuscripts of various books around,
it seems that the purpose is to give witness and to testify
to the reality of divinity as the source of one's experience,
to testify and give witness to the subjective experience,
which is of such an incredible nature that it cannot adequately be described.
It emanates.
It emanates of its own energy.
To give witness to that reality, which is done periodically throughout history,
in various cultures.
And then it becomes mystified over time and given authoritative,
and develops into some kind of a religion.
And that brings me to the crashing halt.
And simultaneously, to develop a scientific objective means of discerning that truth.
First of all, then, the obligation is to witness the inner experience of the revelation of truth
as the source of reality.
And when you do that, you're going to be able to see the truth.
You're going to be able to see the truth.
You're going to be able to see one's existence.
Then to, like, go outside of yourself, the person of that state,
and develop a science of consciousness,
which we did as the calendar of consciousness.
And to first be that, witness it.
Because to speak of it with any energy of truth is to spread the energy forth.
Okay.
Then, because it happened to somebody who also, you know,
was a scientist, physician, psychiatrist, psychoanalyst,
the capacity to then go outside the state
and describe it in terminology comprehensible to the world
in the 400s, in the intellectual, logical.
Therefore, it's one thing to experience it.
It's quite another to describe it.
So this gave a yardstick,
an objective means of discerning truth.
So first to experience the truth,
witness its validity,
to testify to it as a reality,
and then to share with the world
the means of discerning truth from falsehood,
which the world has never had to this day.
This world has never had any means
of discerning truth from falsehood.
The best that has arisen is the inner state of the mystic,
but that's incomprehensible to probably 99.
99% of the world, you know.
Not too pragmatically valuable.
So then, you see, first to be it,
then to describe how it can be described
is verifiable by the world,
and thereby transcend Descartes' duality
of res interna and res externa.
Take that, Rene.
We got them by both, you know what.
Coming and going.
Res interna.
The mystic.
Our society doesn't understand mystic at all,
but I'm going to try to give it a few sentences
in the book I'm doing now.
The mystic, that's the inner experience
of the presence of the self.
Yeah.
Res interna.
One's inner subjective state.
Then there is res externa.
What's out there?
The world of nature.
It's creation.
So there's...
There's creation,
and what creation actually is.
Then there's what the mind thinks about it,
which is totally screwed up,
but useful, thankfully.
Otherwise, you wouldn't be able to get on an airplane
and one end and get off at the other, you know.
Pragmatically useful.
Anyway, having just discovered it,
I thought I'd share it.
Never did in a while I was here,
but I got it this morning.
Wow.
Zappo.
Look out now.
So let's see.
Where's the pointer?
We don't need the pointer.
Now, most of the people here have...
Okay, thank you, sir.
...have been here before.
How many new people do we have?
Oh, my gracious me.
Anybody here hasn't read Power vs. Force?
Get his number.
All right.
All right, so a rapid review then.
We try to go over that which we know,
have shared already,
because no matter how many times you go over it,
you get something new,
just like I did this morning.
And so we want to cover what we have presented before,
because from the academic viewpoint,
you know, as a professor, et cetera.
So from an academic viewpoint,
we do want to make sure that the material is covered.
A lot of the material in and of itself is transformative.
Just to have heard that and go,
oh, wow, you're somewhat different than you were before you,
I've heard it, you know.
So we want to share it for didactic responsibility to the intellect.
Because I respect the intellect,
it has certainly served mankind,
certainly in the form of science.
If it wasn't for the intellect,
most of us probably wouldn't be here.
We would have died early on of typhoid, diphtheria, syphilis,
tuberculosis, polio, all the things.
When I started out in medicine,
when I was the head of the infectious disease hospital,
people died right and left of all those things,
typhoid and diphtheria and whooping cough and scarlet fever
and meningitis.
And now, due to science and logic and reason,
we're all here.
Therefore, it's only a fool that belittles the intellect.
We'll get around to the difficulties of relativistic...
We'll get around to the distorted hermeneutics
of relativism later.
The beast.
The beast of relativism.
Trying to snatch the innocence of humans.
But I've declared war on it.
The way I declare war is I put a magnifying glass on it
and then the problem just shoots out at you and you say,
Oh.
All right, so we've got this map of consciousness
and it's...
It was because we discovered how to tell truth from falsehood.
That was the purpose of this life as well.
Mankind never had such a means.
And it was discovered via kinesiology
that kinesiology was not as presumed a cause and effect
local phenomena.
On the contrary, the response was due to comparing a stimulus
with the absolute.
And that the fuel...
The consciousness itself,
which is like a giant electrostatic field,
doesn't do anything.
And yet when a stimulus is provided,
it responds in an equal and opposite clarity,
much like an electrostatic,
what you would call the old electrostatic speaker system.
So what happens then?
In the presence of truth,
the energy goes out through the acupuncture system,
the body is strong.
The protoplasm recognizes that which is supportive of life,
that which is positive and that which is true.
When it's absent, it goes weak.
So the test is not true versus false.
The test is true versus not true.
That which has no reality.
If you're an electrostatic fuel,
then you only respond to the charge of that which is real.
If a fake truth is presented to you, you don't react,
because it doesn't have any reality to it.
There's no reality, no energy.
It doesn't really exist in the realm.
It's only a proposition.
It's a proposition, but it's not an actuality.
When you're presented with a loving mother
taking care of her children,
her energy as she makes noodle soup,
you've got a different phenomena.
It goes up to 500.
Karma yoga, the sacrifice,
one's convenience for the welfare,
the survival and happiness of others,
is the same thing.
It's karma yoga.
We then ended up with this.
Of course, I've been a psychiatrist
and through Columbia Psychoanalytic.
These are the so-called emergency emotions down here.
These are what we've classified as the welfare emotions.
They've been classically aligned this way
as the perennial philosophy for many centuries.
You could give us the author of this scale,
about 10 or 12,
different authors.
We found it's a very practical,
very practical,
with a little expertise.
Kinesiology only works if you're aligned with knowing the truth.
This is, in the name of the highest good,
you can ask a question,
in the name of the highest good,
because the ego is subtle
and it's always trying to proposition some gain,
some gain, some gain, some gain.
Personal questions are likely to be often
because of the motivation.
Therefore, you have to have the capacity
to be detached, detached,
scientifically, clinically detached.
One way to do it is to ask the question,
in the name of the highest good.
We'll get a book in the mail.
Susan, I'll do it, I'll see.
In the name of the highest good,
it's well for me to read this book.
.
We get a lot of no's.
We get a lot of yeses, yeah.
So I don't want to have a position about it.
I don't want to be impressed by the name of the author.
I don't want to be impressed by the color of the book.
I just want to know,
in the name of the highest truth,
what does this calibrate at.
So the dedication is through the truth.
So anybody can recapitulate the scale.
Anybody can choose their own numbers.
You don't have to use these numbers.
You know, clinically,
clinically a lot of people use one to ten you know on a level of one to ten
how bad is this headache okay we'll go on to the next so transcending these
levels of consciousness is a manuscript I just finished I just took each level
and tried to show how to escape because there's two traps on each level one is
the gain and the other is the fear of you let go of that gain so that's the
last slide of today if we're still awake we'll get to it we haven't disappeared
into the these are the enlightened states well the other yeah the other
scale goes up to 600 because it's extremely rare to go over 600 extremely
rare one in 10 million something like that and when it happens 50% of the time
the entity leaves the world
that'd be hard to explain except that is very tempting yeah they say the bliss is
complete and total unto itself and the condition of the body is irrelevant so
something or someone may come along and look after the body or may not or some
stimulus may come from someplace but it takes a lot to get it moving again so 50
percent of the time the people leave you remember from the story of Ruth
Ramana Maharshi, he went into that state as a teenager, I forget how old he was, from
just an ordinary religious person, he suddenly felt himself dying, so therefore it was an
actual state.
People talk about going into happy dream states, yeah right, when you feel yourself dying you
know you're about to get there, so he felt himself dying and didn't know if he had or
not, and he came anyway, he went into enlightened state and didn't speak for two years, he was
by himself and when he was discovered he was covered with mosquito, animal bites, insect
bites and he hadn't eaten, and by entreaty he resumed the physicality, but it was two
years before he spoke again, and the condition that was experienced in this lifetime was
never spoken about for 30 years.
It took 30 years to ever even refer to it, and even to refer to it now, it's the state
and you have to stop talking, so we won't talk about it, start talking about that, everybody
gets their money back, no, no, all right, so 600 is a state of satananda, a state of
bliss, it's self-fulfilling, whether physicality continues after that is frankly totally different
from what it used to be, it's totally irrelevant, it is absolutely irrelevant, so there must
be some reason for it, and if there is a reason for it, it gets up and walks around again
and eventually resumes life, my god, all those years I never knew until this morning, it
walked around for no reason, for reasons only, you know, you could hypothecate, it wasn't
really until this morning I suddenly realized why I kept walking around, why I didn't fall
over, right, and the luxury, I mean, I didn't know, I was down that end and I didn't know,
it seemed to walk right on again, I said, well, that's it, you know, all right, so
this is the state of enlightenment, the state of enlightenment is reached by women and men,
men and women, it is not a sexist proposition, god doesn't have genitals, and the denotation
he is, is only a semantic convenience.
Divinity is beyond gender, the non-linear is beyond gender, so, you know, you can't
politically sexualize religion, which sometimes comes up in the question and answer period
in various parts of the country, you know, I'm a sexist because God's called he, you
have to ask God about it, don't ask me about it, I don't know, it's a quality, it's a presence,
it's so far beyond gender that it's comical when they come up with a question, all right,
so beyond 600 years.
Beyond 600, there is no such thing as a linear reality, and gender, of course, is comical,
so here you realize you are, now this is an interesting thing, which we'll get to later,
also a recent discovery, also a recent discovery, below 200 entities, whether they're human
or animal, experience, experience, experience the phenomenon of life.
Right?
Below 200, there is the experience of experience, experiencing of life, but they don't realize
they are.
It's only at 200, you realize you are.
So I was writing about it this week and somebody got it.
So I use this analogy, you say to the kitty, what is it like to be a cat?
The cat says.
What does that mean, cat?
Oh, you're a dumb cat.
I don't even know what you are.
You are a cat.
I don't know what that means.
What does it mean?
I said, I'll get the encyclopedia.
I get the encyclopedia, and I get cat.
You know, we opened it to cat.
The cat sits there.
I said, listen carefully.
I put on my glasses, and I read the whole thing about cat.
I said, now do you understand what it is to be a cat?
I can't make any sense out of it.
Then I say, well, the cat, damn it, then who are you?
The cat says, I'm me.
The cat realizes that it exists.
Overconsciousness level 200 is the awareness of your own existence that you are, that you are.
The awareness of beingness existence is not present below 200.
That's why people below 200 don't care if they kill others,
because they don't experience existence,
so they don't see that they're destroying your capacity.
It's two different worlds.
We'll see it in the evolution of consciousness and its expression,
as the evolution of the animal kingdom.
You see that dramatic change at 200.
You see the dinosaur, the rapacious, the killer.
Below 200 is the killer.
Below 200 in the human domain is the killer.
The farther down you get, the more serious the killer.
Then at 200, which is the level of truth,
spiritual energy begins to flow, and you realize that you are.
Now, the value of human life shoots up.
People below 200 don't know what it means to exist that I am.
Therefore, they have no awareness
that they are.
They are killing that quality if they kill you.
Above 200, you have the beginning of morality, ethics,
and because the other, now the value of the other becomes important.
And you see that major transition in humankind,
in behavior, and in the animal kingdom.
At 200, the killer suddenly becomes the herbivore.
At 200, you see the emergence of the elk, the deer,
that which is benign.
Then the development of consciousness onward into the 200s.
And our pets are in the 200s, but the pets are unique,
and I've never finished the research on that.
It's a whole project in itself.
Why an animal in the 200s, as a species, is capable of experiencing
and responding to and recognizing love, which is in the 500s.
So the heart, the heart of the cat
and the dog is capable of responding to the 500s.
The dog's wagging tail is 500, and the cat's purr is 500.
The minute the cat experiences the presence of love,
it starts to purr, hmm?
Safety, security, and love, huh?
So how does this little animal, as a species, only about 250,
recognize that quality?
I don't know.
Yeah, so that's a whole research thing in itself.
All right, so we don't want to get stalled out here, but see,
these are the divine states that one can speak
of as the experiential subjective witness.
And the energy of that statement is forever.
Now, in the collective consciousness of all mankind,
to be it and then share it raises the level of the sea, huh?
So.
But people blow things up.
People blow things up.
Below 200, that's not a reality, is it?
Subjective reality is not knowable below 200.
So for 85% of the people on the planet, this is not a knowable reality, huh?
For a considerable percentage of the rest, it's an intellectual belief system.
They read that so-and-so said that, that, that, and that, that,
and therefore they respect it via the intellect, hmm?
So there's 85% of the world we see.
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't experience that they are.
Wow. So we realize the importance of within the ego, a structure called the experiencer.
And that experiencer is like a screen in which all these ego phenomena go on.
And it's one ten-thousandth of a second in advance of the experiencing of subjective reality.
So in meditation, classically, the misinterpretation
of the subject is the same.
It's the teaching of the Buddha, which I've spoken to him about, as I told you.
And he agreed, you know.
It's screwed up.
They figured it, fixed it.
Yeah. The infinite reality is not between two thoughts, it's prior.
It's the infinite ocean, silent out, non-linear, out of which the linear arises, huh?
Hmm. As a consequence of the desire to think and the pleasure of thinking this.
All right.
So there's the way the world is balanced.
That's okay.
And that's just another way of depicting it.
People say, well, isn't this negativity why we have tsunamis and floods and, eh?
No. That's so dumb.
I mean, it really is dumb.
No, the end times aren't here, folks.
These phenomena went on for millennia before mankind ever got here, folks.
And when lightning strikes, saint and sinner alike drown.
Saint and sinner go down.
Saint and sinner get out in the same ship at the same time.
And all those phenomena went on long before mankind was even thought of.
There was no homo sapien here at all.
The dinosaur kingdom was wiped out, you know.
Meteors hit the earth and blackened the sky.
And many life forms disappeared, huh?
The end of the dinosaur era, hmm.
No. So I don't believe in end times and prophecies and a lot, no.
Okay. Oh.
This is the end.
This is the evolution of consciousness.
How is life going now?
Well, it was pretty poor for a long time, wasn't it?
Life wasn't too cool at the time of the dinosaurs.
You had to have fast-running shoes to survive.
Then recently, recently, recently, 600,000 years ago is very recent.
And new evidence, the redating of the fossil, of the skull, is now projected.
The emergence.
The emergence of homo sapien, even earlier than was previously thought.
All right.
But that is only a few seconds ago.
Ah. And now, as you can see from the scale, the scale went like this.
And now the consciousness level of mankind is rising suddenly.
Okay, folks.
Here it is.
And that is not going to bring peace, is it?
The sword of truth.
The sword of truth is somewhat different than peace, is it not?
People kill each other over truth, you know.
Therefore, this rise of consciousness here is going to precipitate very severe conflict
just by confrontation.
That which is false is threatened by that which is true.
Does not look at it favorably.
Decides it better blow it up and kill it before truth gets loose on the planet
and brings their days to an end.
Therefore, didn't Jesus say that I bring you now the sword of peace or something?
What did he say?
Who knows that?
Anybody?
Any Christians here?
I put their hand up.
What did Christ say about the sword of truth?
Do you know it?
What did he say?
Aw.
Well, anyway.
The sword of truth.
Yes.
And I say, the sword of truth is not necessarily going to bring you hearts and flowers and
hymns and incense.
Heh.
But either you live by the sword of truth or you die by the sword of death.
Ha.
die by the sword of steel, which is what's happening in today's world. That's
the world conflict now, being threatened by the sword of steel. And what is your
response? Okay, we go on the next one. So anyway, there we have the evolution of
the animal kingdom and the emergence of life over great expanses of time. And it
took like forever for consciousness ever to even get up to 200. As you can see,
these are archeologic ages. We'll move on to the next slide. And here's the animal
kingdom. And here you see these all, these all lived by predation. Therefore, the
ego, as life interacted with material matter, it evolved, you know, as the energy
of consciousness rather, the light of God interacted with physicality. Out of it
arose the capacity for life.
Life to survive the way it was, the way it originated. Back here, all these people,
none of them have within themself a source of energy. They're all born without batteries.
They need a couple of double A's. You just open the box, there's double A batteries
in the box. But if the batteries run out, they don't have energy. They don't have
energy.
So how are you going to get energy? You got to get. To survive, you got to get. There
you got the solar plexus fix of the ego for eons of time, and it still operates as the
basis of the animal instincts in the human. All the calibrated levels below 200 are evidence
of the persistence of the instinctual drives of the animal, which were necessary for survival.
That's why we can't hate ego, because he has to eat. If he was green, we could sit
him in the sun, and his chlorophyll would re-energize his batteries. But he has no means
to re-energize his batteries. He has to eat. That means he has to eat something, or somebody.
Eat off your thumb, or God knows what it'll do.
All right.
So this is, you see the nature here. Then at 200, you see the major shift. And we then
have the animal kingdoms that we love. We love the gorillas. We love the gorillas. I
mean, all normal people love gorillas. They're adorable. And all these animals here, we learn
to love them all.
. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
Held the baby, then realized the mother would be afraid of her, laid the baby down.
You're the gateway for the mother.
I mean, it was, like, incredible.
Okay, next.
So that's over 200.
We mentioned today Descartes.
Where is he?
There he is, Descartes.
He was 470, wow.
So people who had a really big impact, intellectually at least, in my life,
were Descartes, Socrates, and Hegel.
Hegel, we'll move on to the next one.
Hegel defined, you know, he was a major philosopher in the first half of the 18th century in Germany.
One of his principles that calibrates extremely high is the principle of the absolute.
Well, calibrating levels of truth is calibrating like a thermometer.
What is?
What is the truth of this proposition, entity, or whatever, as compared to the absolute, as compared to the absolute.
So the recognition of the reality of the absolute as the primary yardstick of truth, then, was Hegel's contribution.
And so Hegel, at 470, had the intellectual capacity to recognize truth
and give it the respect that was due.
Now, then, as we've said before in previous lectures, Karl Marx's, unfortunately, unresolved edible complex
led him into a hatred of authority and edible problems.
So he disenfranchised the truth of Hegel and substituted a relativistic proposition,
the downside of which is the duality of perpetrator and victim.
So all relativism...
Relativism, which contaminates today's societies, is due to the duality of dividing things perceptually
into perpetrator and victim.
Perpetrator and victim depends on point of view, yeah?
And therefore, relativism is, truth is just what you think it is.
You can vote on truth, yeah, because it's only perception denies the reality.
Yeah.
And it is brought about all the contention in present society.
However, if you calibrate it, if you calibrate it, you find, you know, that it calibrates
extremely low.
And once you understand the ego dynamics of it, you see that the ego gain, you see the
ego loses, the ego loses when you get up to the mid-400s, because now you've got to go
along with the world of logic and verifiable reality.
The narcissistic ego loses dominion, and therefore wants to see itself as the arbitrator
of reality, does not want to surrender its presumptive divinity to something higher than
itself, not even the level of Hegel, doesn't want to surrender even to 470, much less divinity
or God, much less divinity or God.
So the core of the ego, then, is atheistic.
Atheistic.
Why?
Because it is God.
And even if it quotes God, it does so for its own reasons and kills you in the name
of God.
That way, it gets to still be God and yet pretend not to be pretentious, right?
Okay.
Very clever.
So that's happened over the centuries, you see.
The Protestant Catholics are busy killing each other off in 30-year wars.
And the history of the crown of England, of course, is extremely interesting.
Yeah.
We said to be able to know the truth.
The other problem is rhetoric and deviations from truth occur because people purposely
ignore stating the context.
A thing is true only within a certain context.
In another context, the same statement is false.
So one way of twisting people politically is to ignore the context.
Ignore the context.
Ignore.
you may get by with just a deck court. If it's a time of war and you pull the same
stunt, you'll get a major court-martial, major court-martial. To be intoxicated on
duty when the war is over, they'll get you a deck court. Try that when you're under
fire, find yourself in the brig badly. To be intoxicated and have your finger on
the gun, come over here sailor, put them in the brig. Not the same crime if you're
tied up at the wharf and the war is over and you're intoxicated, you get a
court-martial, 30 days and that's it. So therefore, context and of course the
ultimate context to which you're all answerable throughout all of time is the
infinite truth of the field of consciousness itself, in which all
things are recorded forever. The field of consciousness, which is a radiance of
energy, which emanates forth as the source of light, the light of God, records
all phenomena forever, beyond time or location. Therefore, the wonderment of
kinesiology, the kinesiologic test, calibrated levels of consciousness, is you're not
limited to the linear domain. You can ask anything about anything anywhere in
time or place.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
things that mystify the world, we haven't all saw before breakfast. We track Bin Laden
every day. Where's Bin Laden today? Well, we put him on the map, he's here, there he is.
You track anything and anybody that's going on in the world. And then of course, some of
those things we wrote about in the book, truth versus falsehood, and by the time
the book's published, it's already news, but we knew it long before it was news.
Yeah, long before it was news. It's useful in things, in the
practical world. You can calibrate the level of intention of a given society, and then
you can calibrate its capability in that area. Therefore, you don't have to walk around being
blindsided like our country and others have been throughout time. They're always surprised
by something that is so huge, it's like you're surprised to find an elephant in the living
room.
500,000 communists north of the Korean War.
500,000 Chinese communist troops.
And we were surprised by them.
We were surprised by Pearl Harbor.
We were surprised by 9-11.
We're always like, what are we, walking idiots, imbeciles?
I was surprised by the bus when it hit me.
Surprised.
So, okay, we'll move on.
Um, this is just a verbalization of the field.
We'll move on.
These are the virtues.
We say at 200, the world becomes different.
Experientially, the way you experience it,
you experience your own existence,
you experience that you are, you are.
And therefore, other things become more real, too.
So these are attitudes that begin to become real at 200.
Below 200, fairness is a stupid question.
You know how stupid fair and honest he is?
That's a joke.
Americans are blindsided because they're so naive.
They think, see the egotism?
Everybody out there must be like us.
They're not like you at all.
They don't think like you.
They don't believe like you.
They don't behave like you.
You've got nothing in common with them.
To screw the customer.
To screw the customer is a point of honor in certain cultures.
And if you don't, you hang your head in shame
and get beaten when you get home.
There's no, you're aware of that, yeah.
And people have been in those cultures.
Tell us, Dr. Kallenbach and all.
You know, honesty is not even a concept in their,
not even a concept.
What does it mean?
We have no concern about that.
You're supposed to get the best price
and the best deal you can get,
depending on the circumstance.
Everybody's been to those cultures.
He's gotten home with an ancient relic.
South America is good for it.
You know, a lot of cultures.
Genuine relic.
They take you secretly to a hidden place.
They got all, this isn't, they got a whole theater
that's worked out and they unveil these things wrapped
in velvet and take it out of a safe.
This, this is from his grandfather.
It was given to him by a brave who had an arrow in his chest.
He said, take this.
This is from my grandfather.
My grandfather's hand shook.
He put it away because he knew it was so priceless.
It's been kept in the family vault three generations.
But now, the family is poor.
The children are sick and need operations.
For $10,000, you can have the small one.
You see, there's more of them.
Greed comes up.
How about 200,000 for all of them?
Oh, no, no, no.
They can't, me with the family, you hear weeping in there, crying.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
So help me God.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
She gives up the family treasure of three generations.
Weeping, he comes and tells you, I know you will take good care of them.
And I'll go to the bank with you.
Everybody here is the chap of the world if that happened.
You find it's a plastic.
It was made in China.
They make them by the thousands.
And so would have dishonored him in the eyes of the family.
You understand?
It's like a reverse culture.
Now you understand why America doesn't do too good in international diplomacy?
OK, we'll do the next.
Move to the next.
This is what the mind does.
We don't want to talk about the mind now.
Go ahead.
This, I want to say I'm going to redo the slide, and I never do.
So we'll move on.
These are the functions of the mind.
You can see why it is sort of an endless trap, because once you get caught in it, it's pretty
hard to get out.
What are we doing on time?
I forgot what's going on in the world.
1115, we take a break?
Oh, good.
You know how long it takes to get enlightened?
Then it takes 50 years to recover from it.
I would say, if you're serious about spiritual work.
Realize that this is not a game, not an intellectual game.
Once you start pulling in the power of divinity by supplication, by declaration, I surrender
my life to thee, oh Lord.
I pray to be thy servant.
Wow.
You just did something.
Life ain't the same.
The consequences are different.
The sequence of options that comes up is different.
You just put a different program on your set.
When you do that, always be aware that you may have to make as a consequence some adjustment
later in life.
Yeah, you may.
Also, how do you want things handled?
People think, isn't that presumptuous?
No, it's not presumptuous, because it's more or less like taking down a glacier, see?
Spiritual work.
It's nice to people all the time.
That's like the sun coming down and melting the snow of the glacier.
A day, every day, a little of the glacier melts off and trickles down the side of the
mountain, and it keeps doing this.
Now what's holding up the glacier is getting weaker and weaker.
What's left of the glacier, the sheer weight of it now, wasn't a problem before, but you
can see it's a pending disaster in the eyes of the world.
Hmm.
I'm just saying it's my responsibility to teach people what I know, to also be prepared
in case spiritual reality moves much faster than what you would anticipate.
Yeah.
It can just suddenly leave you in a different state.
And who's going to pay the bills now and empty the wastebasket?
Nobody.
That's why.
You pack up your dust.
You pack up your duds in the back of your truck and drive away.
You throw your tools in the back of the truck, and you drive to the other side of the country.
And that's the end bite.
Now people will say you've gone crazy, totally mad, and of course you have.
So divine madness can't overtake anyone, and also there's a stage in spiritual evolution
where you get the fire in the belly, where you play with the spirituality, you do courses,
you do workshops, and then all of a sudden it becomes like a fever of drivenness, that
that is what now has priority over everything.
The person says to you, even me, yes, even you.
Those decisions come about.
So that's not too uncommon.
Let's say in 12 step groups.
That's not uncommon.
Those step groups, you know, hey, hey, the relationship worked so long as he was drinking.
She was in charge.
She ran the trick book.
She had the power.
Now the guy is sober, a different person.
Now he's living by different rules on top of it.
He's talking about one day at a time as he does it, huh?
And you can see how disruptions occur.
Okay, that's why they have Al-Anon.
So we'll move to the next one.
This is just for the person who's stuck in the tree.
You can't see the trees and still can't see the forest.
I want to give them a sneaky way out.
You can stick with logic, reason, the Newtonian paradigm of causality, and still be spiritual.
And your sneaky out is quantum mechanics, aha.
Quantum mechanics now introduces that something other than cause and effect and form is coming
to play, and that's intention, the Heisenberg principle, as we say, everything comes into
manifestation.
As a result of intentionality or potentiality, it becoming an actuality when the conditions
are correct.
So the Heisenberg principle now is an advancement beyond the Newtonian paradigm because it introduces
the enormous power of human consciousness and the will and volition, volition and will.
Therefore.
The way.
Well.
So the way is that the potential collapses into the particle, which is the actual.
And I see Henry Stapp has a new book out, which I haven't looked at or read yet, but
I'm looking forward to it.
Henry Stapp, of course, has a website in which he explains this quite neatly, and this is
sort of an adaptation of it.
So you can still be logical, scientific, rational and not risk being looked at as weird and
spiritual and yet see how phenomena that do not fit within the Newtonian paradigm.
paradigm can come into manifestation so we'll move to the next yes because now
you're looking at somewhat different paradigms of reality the Newtonian is
predictable the nonlinear is not predictable it's more propositions and
likelihoods so you see likelihoods rather than certainties so it's a
different dimension it's much more flexible the Newtonian paradigm is a box
very limited box the minute you open quantum mechanics now you open all kinds
of potentiality and variability so we'll move to the next one this is just to
demonstrate that the mind thinks dualistically and there's only one
quality now the calibrated levels of consciousness are just only a means of
tracking the one quality the presence of truth to what degree it's like light or
dark so there aren't two options
opposites of true versus false hood there's only relative degrees such as
heat heat and cold are just manners of speaking they're not separate realities
heat is present to a variable degree truth is present to a variable degree
move to the next the progressive fields of realization are interesting and I'm
writing about them lately because once you identify with the field instead of
the
of the field, you now put yourself at the likelihood of identifying with the witness
rather than the participant.
If you focus on the totality of experience from second to second, instead of the annoyances
of the particulars, then what you pick up is the energy of the field.
You don't worry about the particulars because the field is going to see to it.
It's either all going to happen if the field is favorable, and it's not going to happen
if the field is not favorable.
In contemplation, then, instead of focusing on the specifics of content, you become aware
of the, you might say, the intuitive inference of the totality of the overall field.
You become one with the field.
As you become one with the field, you move out of the movie.
You're not.
You're now the witness of the movie, the observer-witness.
So instead of seeing yourself as the victim, because to be in the movie, you're always
the victim of the movie, whether you have a good day or a bad day, depends on the vicissitudes
of the day.
You haven't got any choice.
When you move out of the movie, all is coming about of its own as the manifestation of that
which it is.
Then you've moved into the witness.
See?
And you're up above.
You're in the movie.
I am the movie.
And then, you see, you know that because it registers, and you recognize the phenomena
out there.
That's being a participant as you become the field now, awareness, the observer, the witness.
You become the witness of it, and therefore, you don't necessarily have to have any comment
about it.
Here.
So, just got blown up.
So, followed by a bomb and 30,000 people blown to bits.
You go, yeah?
So?
And then what?
I mean, so what?
It's been happening since the beginning of time.
The idea is to excite you into a positionality so that you cling eagerly to the ego and don't
realize that you're none of it.
If you aren't a movie, then you're not a movie.
movie, then of what interest is a movie? Once you realize that you are not a movie. If you think
you're a movie, then every other movie is fascinating. Once you realize, oh, I'm not a movie?
No. What are you? You're the witness of the movie. You're the theater in which the movie is happening.
So to move into the contemplative position then, by supplication to God, you say,
to thee, O Lord, do I surrender my existence, that I may be thy servant. It's a supplication
asking not to get, but to be shown. It's more of a yin position. Contemplation is more yin.
Meditation tends to be pretty yang, at least in its intention, it's very yang.
Very yang. Sit there cross-legged for six hours and don't scratch your nose.
I'll hit you with a stick if you get looked stupid.
And fall asleep. That's pretty yang. The inner phenomena, although ostensibly yin,
is better realized as a way of being that doesn't get isolated from daily life.
It's the way you are. You're the supportive watcher, experiencer, and eventually
the realization of reality as awareness itself. That even the watcher and the witness
are delineation.
Why do the watcher and the witness have any capacity or value? It's because of the presence
of awareness. Then you see, I'm not the subject of the movie. I'm not even the watcher or the
witness. So you stop trying to delineate it, and you see what you are is a quality,
the quality of awareness that is behind the observer-witness, which is the radiance of
divinity which shines forth.
Out of which arises all of creation.
Thank thee, we'll take a break. How long?
Fifteen minute break, yeah.
First thing to learn in spiritual work is discipline.
The lecture started five minutes ago, and all the crucial things have been said already.
It's a very special group of people. But don't think you're special just because you're special.
Thank you.
Yeah, what I'm holding in mind is true. What I'm holding in mind is true over 90%, 92%, about 90%.
Okay, so the question was, the only people that are attending a group like this are destined to become enlightened.
It says 90%.
You see, because the Newtonian paradigm, you think you're being driven by the past. In reality, you're being pulled by the future.
If you're destined to become enlightened, you're not. You're not. You're not. You're not. You're not. You're not. You're not. You're not. You're not. You're not. You're not. You're not.
Destiny wasn't to become enlightened, you wouldn't be here, nor would you be picking up the energy of the truth of it to carry forth into the world in subsequent generations, etc.
Therefore, I said to be prepared, because those of you who have already chosen it, consciously or unconsciously, to become enlightened, will then pull yourself into that direction.
And that could bring about changes in your life that can be surprising and quite a bit of a surprise.
rising, and quite maximum, quite maximum, maximum, yeah, then you know what maximum,
the word means, oh, that's what maximum means, yeah, like wiped out, outside we were just noticing,
the world of causality, the world of the intellect, the world of cause and effect,
the world of the ego, sees life as going from imperfection to perfection, it's imperfect,
so you fix it, it's imperfect, so you paint it, embellish it, you put fur on it, or what,
lipstick, sports shoes, when you become the field, you become aware that what you're witnessing
is perfection moving to perfection, to perfection, to perfection, that perfection is the prevailing
state at all times, this is not an imperfect rose,
becoming a perfect rose, it's a perfect half rose, it's still a perfect half rose,
it's a perfect developing rose, you understand, so what you witness is perfection, going to
perfection, to perfection, and what you're witnessing is creation and evolution are one
and the same thing, all you're witnessing, you're not witnessing causality or change,
you're witnessing the unfoldment of creation,
because creation and evolution are one and the same thing,
creation doesn't go from imperfection to perfection, it's idiotic,
that would be denying the divinity of God, all is perfect, all is perfect, all is perfect,
all is perfect, evolution goes from perfection to perfection, if you become part of the movie,
you think it goes from imperfection,
to imperfection, to imperfection, to imperfection, to imperfection, why, because you don't have
the whole picture, karmically, the best thing you can do right now is get wiped out, why,
oh, you've forgotten all the tens of thousands you slaughtered mercilessly, outside of this
bodiness, oh, yeah, right, you denied mercy to the innocent, and now you know, you're not
going to know what it's like, to feel blown up, the world is not in love, so, it is the world,
this world is the ultimate for our spiritual growth and development, the karmic opportunities
of a human lifetime are staggering, you can undo negative karma at one point, and be earning
positive karma at the other point, in fact, they can occur simultaneously, as you get blown up,
you say, thank you, God, for releasing me, thank you, God, for releasing me, thank you, God, for
releasing me, thank you, God, for releasing me, thank you, God, for releasing me, thank you, God,
you also have the option to curse God, and you end up in the lower astral domains, where
the choice no longer exists, so, you're witnessing the most perfect place for the evolution of
consciousness, for the achievement of enlightenment, the undoing of negative karma, all right,
to get to the positive side of the balance, karmic balance, requires the undoing of negative
side, which can be done in a variety of ways, some very, very specifically, almost a linear
rerun of the previous incident, only this time with a different intention, this time with a
different intention, so, there's no point of bemoaning, and crying, because the ego's a crybaby,
there's no point in crying about the state of the world,
a being from a different dimension has appeared, who's going to tell me the secrets of existence,
rebar, I am here from the future, yeah, well, I'm asphalt, I'm here from the past, buddy,
and I have secrets to reveal to you, what, that Jesus said to be kind to everyone,
oh, yeah, right, you can read in any book, folks, don't get glamorized by that which is none,
visible, if you keep fooling around those worlds, you'll bring them all in, the last second greeting
you got is why Mr. Asphalt is whispering to you the secrets, he's a reincarnation of the spirit
of the mystery schools, why are they a mystery, for Christ's sake, because you want to sell them,
what do you think, what is about truth that you want to mystify and keep secret, control,
right, control, all right, so in this lifetime, that comes back to you, and now you have a chance to say no to it,
all right, so to know that everything is evolving automatically is a consequence of evolution,
because evolution is how creation is expressed to the witness, it isn't what it is,
but it's what it seems to the witness, and then when you let go of the witness,
you are evolution, thanks, God, you are creation, man, what did you think it was,
you are the evolution of creation, you are the evolution of creation,
you are how creation evolved itself, on up from the animal kingdom, on up through the spiritual
dimensions, and then on into the non-linear, non-material presence, right, in that way,
this returns to its source, so we'll resume the slides, you can't give a lecture without a slide,
boy, give you a PhD, I say, where's your slides, you can't get a PhD without slides, nowadays it's
neat, you can give them all the slides in a little box like this, you know, used to be you had to have
your slide box, so that the committee could review your work, you see, all right, these are the spiritual practices,
so by intention, by alignment, by supplication, and by declaration, the job for declaration,
that's the time to make sure who's going to pay your bills, who's going to carry out the garbage,
because by declaration, when you declare that you are a servant of Almighty God to thee, O Lord,
you have just changed everything, and don't be naive and think that you haven't, you have changed
it dramatically.
The sequence of a life events that you summon forth will unfold of a totally different dimension
than people below 200, below 200, you go from imperfection to imperfection, to imperfection,
to imperfection, total dissatisfaction, resentment, pity, because you see whatever condition it is,
imperfection, you have desire and greed, desire and greed, I have to get it, so you go back to being a
protozoa,
that only lives by getting,
and you're refuting the divinity of your creation,
that that which you are, by virtue of what it is, summons forth that which it needs from the universe,
it's hard to be poor, try it, it's hard to starve to death, try it, you can't starve to death,
they call the police,
he hasn't eaten in a week, yeah,
you know,
I was the consultant to the Episcopal Zen Monastery,
the sisterhoods and residents, Catholic, Episcopal, all that, you know,
and they'd bring in some monk from the Zen Monastery,
is he catatonic or is he in Samadhi?
Yeah, it needs his Tuesday,
is it Samadhi or Catatonia?
The observer can't tell,
if you've been there, you know,
the way through,
but,
if you haven't been there,
you give him Thorazine and Shakti,
so in one of the books, anyway, I delineated how to differentiate,
and of course, with calibrated levels of consciousness,
you can get right away with, is this a schizophrenic break,
or is this a guy in Samadhi, you know,
because it doesn't happen with such frequency,
and Catatonia is quite impressive,
and I'll tell you a story about Catatonia,
I was,
in the state hospital, right into the psychiatric hospital,
and we had a catatonic,
catatonic, and he was a tall skinny thing,
and he wouldn't eat, so we tube fed him,
you know, once a day, you got a tube down there,
but he would, in Catatonia, the person has,
what do they call it, cataplexy or something like that, anyway,
if you put his arm like this, he will leave it there,
you can come back three days from now, it's still there,
immobile,
so we had a catatonic on the ward,
and I had the tube for these guys every morning,
make sure the tube went down the esophagus and not the bronchi,
so, yeah, so the doctor had to come around and place the tube,
and then the nurse could take it from there,
but, so you don't get the enriched milk in their lung,
and kill them,
I used to feel sorry for these creatures,
because they didn't want to eat, they couldn't eat,
and tears would come to their eyes,
but there wasn't anything I could do,
the law said you got to see to it they stay alive,
all right, so we had this catatonic,
and,
at the hospital, we had the doctor,
the doctor was a short little guy with a bald,
and,
I forgot his name now,
remember his name, yeah, anyway,
and anyway, we had a head nurse, just got off,
the boat from Ireland,
and this was in Ward's Island, underneath the Chiropractic Bridge,
the old Manhattan State Hospital,
and the personnel were mainly immigrants from Ireland, so,
yeah, Nellie Murphy, so Nellie Murphy was about 6'2",
and all brawn,
and doctor, whatever his name is, I forget, it was about this high,
well, the nurses weren't supposed to smoke or drink coffee in the nursing office,
and so this catatonic, you put them up against the wall,
and they tube feed them, and then you put them up against the wall,
and somebody just for something else to do,
would put his hand like this, you know,
well, you try and kid them out of it,
you go by, you put your hat on it,
you salute it,
pretend you're going to bite it,
no response,
he was this way for years.
One day, Nellie Murphy and Travis, that was it,
one day, Dr. Travis and Nellie,
come walking down, because they were separate buildings,
it looked like Wuthering Heights or something, you know,
late 1800s, all these,
brick buildings slightly tipped over the years,
and the floor is a little crooked,
and the smell of about 150 years of urine is coming up,
anyway, Nellie and Travis come walking down the walk, you know,
and this catatonic, it's sawed out the window,
he hadn't spoken in 20 years,
and all of a sudden he says,
Travis and Murphy,
and the nurses quickly put away their cigarettes and coffee,
and opened the windows,
and he never said anything again.
Okay, we'll resume.
So how do you tell that condition from Samadhi, you know,
and in the meditative states, you get into high states,
but then when you open your eyes,
the state disappears,
or if it still maintains with eyes open,
it disappears when you begin to stand up and walk around,
and you can't participate in the world,
so, because at a certain level,
the capacity, actually, as the state evolves,
and that's why I warned you about it,
you hit a point in which,
the capacity to function is zero.
There isn't capacity to function.
First of all, there isn't anybody to function,
nor is there anything to function about.
That's hard to explain,
but at 600, you become what's called a mystic,
and the world may have reasons for this body to go on walking around,
but the body itself has no such interest, you see.
Therefore, whatever happens is of karmic propensity,
a karmic propensity,
you know,
and if the karma is such,
then the continuation will continue,
and if the karma is already fulfilled,
and there is no obligation or commitment
before you have reentered this lifetime,
then you may just topple over.
So, to refunction again requires
the recreation of what you would call,
it's not recreated,
the activation of a potentiality,
it's not something called the personage.
It's a functionality,
it's not a thing or an entity.
So, the capacity to,
let's say, explain to an audience what goes on,
does so via a quality of the personage.
So, if the destiny is to continue on in the body,
let's say to teach for some reason,
teach or something,
then the capacity for personizing the knowingness,
emerges as vocabularization, et cetera,
of which one is not the participant.
They have no idea what's going to be said next at all.
That's why it's great.
Never heard it before.
So, there may or may not be
the emergence of a person,
a personalization.
It's like an aspect of the experiencer
that by karmic control,
by contract almost,
by agreement,
it continues on to fulfill a function.
You're not the function,
nor is there any person to do the function.
The function is its own self.
The function functions
without any person behind the function,
without any purpose or direction,
because it's part of evolution.
So, those that are destined to become enlightened, then,
express the potentiality
of creation and evolution
returning to its source,
and that's what the world calls enlightenment.
Yeah, enlightenment, at least from this realm.
From other realms, it's called kindergarten.
See, I'm a trainee for kindergarten.
All right.
These various spiritual practices.
All right, so once you've made the commitment,
the reason you made the commitment
was because you're merely stating what you've already,
what your future is,
to become enlightened.
Nobody else is here.
Only golfers are at a class on how to golf,
you know what I mean?
Why would you be in a class on golf?
So, only because one has already chosen that
is, that is your destiny.
Therefore, one is,
the appropriate way to be with that destiny
is one of respect.
Respect yourself.
Respect the information.
Respect the inspiration.
Because if that is your destiny,
that certainly deserves respect.
Respect yourself.
Respect truth.
Don't deviate it.
To not deviate out of guilt
is to just join the ego.
No, you don't deviate.
Respect truth out of your own integrity.
Therefore, what is due a teacher?
Respect.
That's it.
Not worship.
Not glorification.
Why would the absolute truth
and the infinite glory of God
need glorification
or amplification?
It's already so stunningly overwhelming what it is.
Any two cents you can add is actually a detraction.
All right.
One of the things that are done then
to reinforce the commitment,
and I think they're quite interesting,
just the sound, om,
which we're going to do this afternoon.
When do we do om?
After lunch?
It's morning now, right?
When do we do om?
The chant?
Yes.
This afternoon?
Oh, it's morning now.
Yes, okay.
All right.
So we do om,
which we're going to do collectively.
Then there's the various variations.
See?
Various variations of it.
You see that all these things
subserve spiritual intention.
This is over 200.
These are over 200.
This is already 540.
One way to reach an advanced state
is to drink yourself to death.
See if you can kill yourself with booze,
bad women and drugs,
all at the same time
while you gamble away your last few dollars.
And you either get to this way
or you leave.
Well,
through that lifetime,
a lot of people went out
five or six times
due to addiction
and it's only the sixth lifetime
that they finally got sober.
So it ain't all that easy
because that brings you right up at 540.
540 is 0.4% of the human population.
0.4% of the population
ever gets to 540.
So we don't have to feel bad.
Well,
we don't have to feel sorry
for these people anymore.
The thing is,
they're way ahead of us already.
Poor elkies.
Yeah, right.
At 540,
at 540,
they're in a state
that you wish you could experience.
All right.
So we,
the golden rule
doesn't make any point below 200,
as we said this morning.
To give a person an honest measure
is stupid in certain cultures.
Okay.
It's only over 200
that it gains any validity.
It is the various things we do,
the various prayers,
walking the maze.
When we were in Chartres Cathedral,
they were very clever there.
They won't allow you to walk the maze.
They cleverly do that
by putting chairs all over
so you can't walk the maze.
I guess they'd have
an endless parade of people
lined up outside
all walking the maze.
I don't see what's wrong with that.
If I were in the cathedral,
I'd have maze.
You go in there,
you do the maze.
In,
out.
Right?
Except in the middle,
you want to go to the bathroom,
you gotta,
I mean,
you know.
I wouldn't have done it that way,
but I don't know
their administrative problems.
They have a thing in the front for money.
They hit you with that right away.
Walking in Chartres Cathedral,
money.
The next thing you get
is everybody's on their cell phone.
Here's the most incredible.
It calibrates over 700.
I mean,
it's stupendous.
You can see that many workmen
gave an entire lifetime
surrendering it to God
as the perfection of their work,
the Karma Yoga of it.
People are on their cell phones.
It's unbelievable.
They're on their cell phones.
Oh, God.
Oh, well.
You either get it
or you don't get it,
you know.
It's like seeing God
and saying,
golly whiz, you know.
Things become,
you see how 540
is the result of intention.
By devotion and commitment to God
does the Ganges become holy.
Therefore,
many of these things
because they come
from different cultures,
instead of ridiculing them,
you see that
turning a prayer wheel
by intention
and
like genuflection,
kneeling to pray,
put one's hands together like this
is an act of respect.
For God,
for a teacher,
for truth,
for a divine place.
Prayerful handcrafts,
devotional acts,
turning the prayer wheel,
burning of incense,
the wailing wall,
bathing in the Ganges,
the prayer of St. Francis of Assisi.
Oh, that's a different level.
Hmm.
To be a channel of thy will,
oh Lord.
We'll go to the next.
All right.
So here is the left brain below 200.
This is the animal evolution
up to consciousness level 200.
So,
the animal evolution
up to consciousness level 200.
It's emotional primarily
and it has to do with survival.
It has to do with the core of the ego.
So,
the reason ego
is the way he is
is because he's programmed for survival.
If you want to take a piece of candy from him,
he will bite you
because he's supposed to.
Therefore,
we respect the ego
rather than vilify it.
Therefore,
my disagreement
with the textbook
of the Course in Miracles
is it seems to have a different energy
than the workbook
because it now gets into a dualistic positionality
about the ego.
The ego is innocent
by virtue of
the fact that it's being
what it was created to be.
For humans to be here,
evolution had to proceed up through the animal kingdom
to finally the development of a suitable
vehicle
for higher consciousness.
For higher consciousness,
which we call human.
So,
the only reason we're here
is because of our animal.
So,
therefore,
we're grateful for our animal
and I say,
ego baby,
if it wasn't for you,
I wouldn't be standing up
walking around
without the animal.
We wouldn't have a physicality
to walk around in.
Then this physicality reaches
a certain point of evolution,
but it has an even higher potentiality
than just the animal.
And at 200,
the energy of creation,
consciousness,
the light of God,
then,
manifests
and we begin to experience
the flow of the Kundalini energy
and now the brain switches
and processes information differently.
It experiences the world as more benign
and its intention is different.
And one of the main reasons
is because at consciousness level 200,
you develop an etheric brain.
The etheric brain.
Prior to 200,
people and animals
don't have a personal karma,
they have a group karma.
They're controlled by an attractor field.
The attractor field draws all
like unto like.
At 200,
you now have choice.
You experience and realize
that you are
and this are is now responsible
and capable of choice.
Culpability also increases at 200.
Unfortunately.
Also culpability.
Now that you know that you are
and others know that they are,
now the consequences karmically
become different.
The karmic consequences
of an animal eating a rabbit
is quite different
than you're taking a human life,
let's say.
All right.
So here karma changes.
The responsibility changes.
You have the inflow of Kundalini energy.
So we said below 200,
your left brain linear,
fight or flight,
alarm, resistance,
exhaustion,
stress and the thymus,
disruption of the acupuncture meridians,
more prone to illness.
Neurotransmitter depletion
is one of serotonin.
Okay.
Once you switch the spheres,
you get a different dominance.
It's nonlinear.
You're more interested in peace,
positive emotions.
Immunity increases.
Healing increases.
The acupuncture system is balanced.
And the track to the emotions
is slower than the prefrontal
and the etheric brain.
All this is crucial.
And most of the world
doesn't know about it.
So we'll go to the next.
We go to the next.
We said that
if it's not a world of cause and effect,
it's a world of
that which you are
draws like, draws to like.
That which you are by your own choice then.
So if we look at the level of consciousness
correlated with the various phenomena
about which sociologists are concerned,
you see, you don't see cause and effect.
You don't see cause and effect.
You see concordance.
I realized that,
I remember in World War II in the Navy.
After paydays,
the same guys were always broke every Friday.
Same guys.
Always broke.
And I learned how to make money shooting craps.
I'll tell you why you can't win at the casino.
If you look at the statistics,
if you look at shooting craps,
you'll see that winning and losing,
if you chart winning and losing in roulette,
or craps I think,
you see it spikes up,
then it spikes down.
These are your winnings,
these are your losses.
How far of a loss can you take
before you're out of the game?
I discovered that when I was 17.
You want to shoot craps? Yeah.
How much you got on you?
Three bucks.
I got ten.
I'll go for them.
Because I'm going to get his three.
If I got ten.
You got it?
All right.
So the house,
the house,
the house can go way, way down there.
And you're going to get wiped out.
The house can afford, you know,
being five million behind.
Can you?
No.
So we just go on probability,
sooner or later,
you're a big wheeler,
a big roller,
you got 40,000.
40,000 is to a big house.
I mean,
they eat that for lunch.
Can you go 100,000?
Can you go 200,000?
We don't have to send anybody even out
for extra money
unless you get well over a million.
Can you go a million?
No, you can't go.
So you can see,
obviously,
it's only a matter of time.
You're going to get wiped out
by the downside.
Okay.
Never shoot craps
unless you got a lot more money
than the other guy.
Now you know why your ten of the legs are right.
It's because these guys here
always lose.
They always lose.
Happiness is practically zero.
And criminality is an endemic way of life.
It's an endemic way of life, huh?
They receive it as criminal.
You practically never hear
of a child molestation,
murder, kidnapping
as a single isolated crime.
Just don't happen.
You know,
it's fine.
The suspect has a record
going back to childhood.
You got 30 or 40 incidences
of every kind.
It's a criminality is a way of life.
So this kind of an energy
will pull prison to it.
I guarantee you
they will be back in prison.
Guaranteed.
What?
By virtue of what they are.
I guarantee you this person
isn't going to be in prison,
you know,
as a quality of that which they are.
So you pull to you
that which is the concept.
Is the consequence
of that which you are.
That which you are
is destined for enlightenment.
So you pull to yourself
a lecture devoted to
how does that happen
and how do you do it and all.
Right?
In fact, you hear witnesses
that you're all destined
for such a destiny.
Okay.
All right.
So people that are up here
are going to pull to themself
that which is,
if you weren't destined
to climb Mount Everest,
you wouldn't be attending
a course on mountain climbing.
Okay.
We'll move on.
So you see,
this has nothing to do
with cause and effect.
These are movies.
We'll go on from there.
200 movies.
Well, these, we'll move on.
This is, we just,
we did represent this recently
at the World Children's Relief Fund
dinner in Phoenix
because people were devoted
to helping
the destitute.
And one of the places
I was interested in seeing
they were helping was Haiti.
And we know in the Western Hemisphere,
we'll move on.
We can move on.
Anyway, Haiti,
the only place in the Western Hemisphere
that's really very low
is Haiti.
And this group is very supportive
of building schools
and life supportive systems
and raising the level of people in Haiti.
Therefore, it's a pretty benevolent project.