Amen.
soul.
Okay.
Okay. Are
Okay. Are we
Okay. Are we prepared?
Okay. Are we prepared? Are
Okay. Are we prepared? Are we
Okay. Are we prepared? Are we set?
Okay. Are we prepared? Are we set? Okay.
>> I
>> I think
Okay. Are we prepared? Are we set? Okay.
>> I think we'll
>> I think we'll put
Okay. Are we prepared? Are we set? Okay.
>> I think we'll put the
>> I think we'll put the Kleenex
Okay. Are we prepared? Are we set? Okay.
>> I think we'll put the Kleenex out
>> I think we'll put the Kleenex out of the
way.
way. Yeah.
way. Yeah. In
way. Yeah. In the
way. Yeah. In the water.
All
All these
way. Yeah. In the water.
All these things
All these things are
way. Yeah. In the water.
All these things are in
All these things are in the
way. Yeah. In the water.
All these things are in the way.
All these things are in the way. All
this
this stuff
>> by
>> by water.
Yes.
>> Can
>> Can you
Yes.
>> Can you please
>> Can you please um
Yes.
>> Can you please um discuss
>> Can you please um discuss love
Yes.
>> Can you please um discuss love as
>> Can you please um discuss love as an
attachment
attachment in
attachment in a
attachment in a little
attachment in a little more
attachment in a little more detail?
>> Are
>> Are we
attachment in a little more detail?
>> Are we on?
>> I
>> I got
>> I got it
>> I got it now.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Say
>> I got it now.
>> Yeah. Say one
>> Yeah. Say one more
>> I got it now.
>> Yeah. Say one more time.
>> I'll
>> I'll repeat
>> I'll repeat the
>> I'll repeat the question.
>> Sorry.
>> It's
>> It's a
>> It's a excellent
>> It's a excellent question.
I
I don't
>> It's a excellent question.
I don't know
I don't know what
>> It's a excellent question.
I don't know what this
I don't know what this is.
>> It's
>> It's aligned
>> It's aligned with
>> It's aligned with what
>> It's aligned with what we
>> It's aligned with what we were
>> It's aligned with what we were speaking
about
about this
>> It's aligned with what we were speaking
about this morning.
about this morning. Love
>> It's aligned with what we were speaking
about this morning. Love is
about this morning. Love is an
attachment.
attachment. Okay.
attachment. Okay. The
attachment. Okay. The reason
attachment. Okay. The reason Ramach
Krishna
Krishna forbid
attachment. Okay. The reason Ramach
Krishna forbid his
Krishna forbid his followers
attachment. Okay. The reason Ramach
Krishna forbid his followers who
Krishna forbid his followers who were
young
young men
to
to have
young men
to have sex
to have sex or
young men
to have sex or to
to have sex or to touch
young men
to have sex or to touch money
to have sex or to touch money because
young men
to have sex or to touch money because he
felt
felt that
felt that the
felt that the attraction
felt that the attraction of
felt that the attraction of both
felt that the attraction of both were
felt that the attraction of both were so
strong
strong that
felt that the attraction of both were so
strong that especially
strong that especially a
felt that the attraction of both were so
strong that especially a young
strong that especially a young devote
would
would not
would not be
would not be able
would not be able to
would not be able to resist
would not be able to resist them.
One
One of
would not be able to resist them.
One of the
One of the reasons
would not be able to resist them.
One of the reasons people
One of the reasons people become
renunciate
renunciate and
renunciate and take
renunciate and take vows
renunciate and take vows of
renunciate and take vows of celibacy.
There's
There's too
renunciate and take vows of celibacy.
There's too much
There's too much noise
renunciate and take vows of celibacy.
There's too much noise in
There's too much noise in the
renunciate and take vows of celibacy.
There's too much noise in the back
There's too much noise in the back of
the
the room.
the room. You're
the room. You're going
the room. You're going to
the room. You're going to have
the room. You're going to have to
the room. You're going to have to stop
all
all the
the room. You're going to have to stop
all the conversation
all the conversation in
the room. You're going to have to stop
all the conversation in the
all the conversation in the back
otherwise
otherwise nobody
otherwise nobody can
otherwise nobody can hear
>> you're
>> you're starting
otherwise nobody can hear
>> you're starting about
>> you're starting about five
otherwise nobody can hear
>> you're starting about five minutes
early.
early. So
early. So that's
early. So that's what
early. So that's what I
early. So that's what I think.
>> The
>> The idea
early. So that's what I think.
>> The idea that
>> The idea that love
early. So that's what I think.
>> The idea that love is
>> The idea that love is an
early. So that's what I think.
>> The idea that love is an attachment
>> The idea that love is an attachment then
is
is what
is what we
is what we were
is what we were talking
is what we were talking about
is what we were talking about this
morning.
morning. The
is what we were talking about this
morning. The ego's
the
the ego's
the ego's conceptualization
the ego's conceptualization of
the ego's conceptualization of love
the ego's conceptualization of love as
an
an attachment
the ego's conceptualization of love as
an attachment and
an attachment and a
the ego's conceptualization of love as
an attachment and a possession
an attachment and a possession is
the ego's conceptualization of love as
an attachment and a possession is a
deterrent
deterrent to
deterrent to enlightenment.
But
But that's
deterrent to enlightenment.
But that's an
But that's an attachment.
deterrent to enlightenment.
But that's an attachment. Love
But that's an attachment. Love itself
calibrates
calibrates at
calibrates at 500
calibrates at 500 which
calibrates at 500 which is
calibrates at 500 which is nonlinear.
And
And if
calibrates at 500 which is nonlinear.
And if love
And if love is
calibrates at 500 which is nonlinear.
And if love is nonlinear,
And if love is nonlinear, attachment
calibrates at 500 which is nonlinear.
And if love is nonlinear, attachment is
not
not possible
not possible because
not possible because attachment
not possible because attachment is
always
always to
not possible because attachment is
always to linearity.
Now
Now love
Now love with
Now love with a
Now love with a capital
Now love with a capital L
Now love with a capital L is
Now love with a capital L is one
Now love with a capital L is one of
Now love with a capital L is one of the
qualities
qualities of
Now love with a capital L is one of the
qualities of the
qualities of the essence
Now love with a capital L is one of the
qualities of the essence of
qualities of the essence of divinity.
So
So to
So to surrender
So to surrender a
So to surrender a love
So to surrender a love because
So to surrender a love because you
misconceive
misconceive of
So to surrender a love because you
misconceive of it
misconceive of it as
So to surrender a love because you
misconceive of it as an
misconceive of it as an attachment
So to surrender a love because you
misconceive of it as an attachment is
misconceive of it as an attachment is a
major
major error.
major error. It
major error. It will
major error. It will take
major error. It will take you
major error. It will take you to
major error. It will take you to the
void.
void. By
major error. It will take you to the
void. By the
void. By the way,
it
it will
it will take
it will take you
it will take you to
it will take you to nothingness.
The
The same
it will take you to nothingness.
The same could
The same could be
it will take you to nothingness.
The same could be said
The same could be said of
it will take you to nothingness.
The same could be said of beauty.
The
The same
The same could
The same could be
The same could be said
The same could be said of
The same could be said of holiness.
The same could be said of holiness. The
same
same thing.
The same could be said of holiness. The
same thing. So
same thing. So attachment
The same could be said of holiness. The
same thing. So attachment then
is
is the
is the ego's
grasping
grasping onto
is the ego's
grasping onto something
grasping onto something and
is the ego's
grasping onto something and it
grasping onto something and it is
is the ego's
grasping onto something and it is a
limitation.
Therefore,
Therefore, love
limitation.
Therefore, love as
Therefore, love as an
limitation.
Therefore, love as an attachment
is
is best
is best to
is best to let
is best to let go
is best to let go of.
is best to let go of. Love
is best to let go of. Love is
is best to let go of. Love is however
is best to let go of. Love is however a
quality
quality of
is best to let go of. Love is however a
quality of divinity.
So
So to
So to release
So to release uh
So to release uh love
So to release uh love itself
So to release uh love itself is
So to release uh love itself is an
error.
Is
Is there
Is there a
Is there a specific
Is there a specific is
Is there a specific is there
Is there a specific is there a
Is there a specific is there a specific
technique
technique for
Is there a specific is there a specific
technique for let's
technique for let's say
Is there a specific is there a specific
technique for let's say just
technique for let's say just even
Is there a specific is there a specific
technique for let's say just even for
technique for let's say just even for a
love
love of
love of your
love of your pet
love of your pet if
love of your pet if you're
love of your pet if you're willing
love of your pet if you're willing to
sacrifice
sacrifice your
love of your pet if you're willing to
sacrifice your life
sacrifice your life for
love of your pet if you're willing to
sacrifice your life for your
sacrifice your life for your pet
love of your pet if you're willing to
sacrifice your life for your pet or
sacrifice your life for your pet or for
your
your dog.
your dog. Is
your dog. Is there
your dog. Is there a
your dog. Is there a specific
your dog. Is there a specific way
your dog. Is there a specific way to
your dog. Is there a specific way to uh
technique
technique for
your dog. Is there a specific way to uh
technique for surrendering
technique for surrendering that
your dog. Is there a specific way to uh
technique for surrendering that love
object?
>> It's
>> It's the
object?
>> It's the it's
>> It's the it's not
object?
>> It's the it's not the
>> It's the it's not the love
object?
>> It's the it's not the love object.
>> It's the it's not the love object. It's
the
the it's
the it's the
the it's the energy
the it's the energy of
the it's the energy of attachment
itself.
Could
Could you
Could you be
Could you be happy
Could you be happy without
Could you be happy without the
Could you be happy without the dog?
Could
Could you
Could you be happy without the dog?
Could you be
Could you be happy
Could you be happy without the dog?
Could you be happy without
Could you be happy without the
Could you be happy without the dog?
>> Well,
>> Well, my
>> Well, my quick
>> Well, my quick answer
>> Well, my quick answer would
>> Well, my quick answer would be
>> Well, my quick answer would be no,
>> Well, my quick answer would be no, but
I'm
I'm assuming
>> Well, my quick answer would be no, but
I'm assuming you're
I'm assuming you're saying
>> Well, my quick answer would be no, but
I'm assuming you're saying the
I'm assuming you're saying the answer
>> Well, my quick answer would be no, but
I'm assuming you're saying the answer is
yes.
>> Could
>> Could you
yes.
>> Could you be
>> Could you be happy
yes.
>> Could you be happy without
>> Could you be happy without the
yes.
>> Could you be happy without the dog
>> Could you be happy without the dog or
I'll
I'll blow
I'll blow your
I'll blow your brains
I'll blow your brains out.
>> All right.
So,
So, it's
So, it's not
So, it's not could,
So, it's not could, it's
So, it's not could, it's would.
So, it's not could, it's would. All
right.
right. So,
So, it's not could, it's would. All
right. So, if
right. So, if you
So, it's not could, it's would. All
right. So, if you lose
right. So, if you lose your
So, it's not could, it's would. All
right. So, if you lose your let
right. So, if you lose your let go
So, it's not could, it's would. All
right. So, if you lose your let go of
your
your attachment
your attachment to
your attachment to the
your attachment to the dog,
your attachment to the dog, you
your attachment to the dog, you won't
lose
lose the
your attachment to the dog, you won't
lose the dog.
lose the dog. You'll
your attachment to the dog, you won't
lose the dog. You'll only
lose the dog. You'll only lose
your attachment to the dog, you won't
lose the dog. You'll only lose your
attachment
attachment to
attachment to the
attachment to the dog.
attachment to the dog. The
attachment to the dog. The ego
attachment to the dog. The ego will
attachment to the dog. The ego will say,
"Well,
"Well, if
attachment to the dog. The ego will say,
"Well, if I
"Well, if I let
attachment to the dog. The ego will say,
"Well, if I let go
"Well, if I let go my
attachment to the dog. The ego will say,
"Well, if I let go my attachment,
"Well, if I let go my attachment, I'll
lose
lose it.
That
That which
lose it.
That which is
That which is yours,
lose it.
That which is yours, you
That which is yours, you can't
lose it.
That which is yours, you can't get
That which is yours, you can't get rid
of.
of. That
of. That which
of. That which isn't
of. That which isn't yours,
of. That which isn't yours, you
of. That which isn't yours, you can't
obtain.
>> Yeah.
>> Can
>> Can I
>> Yeah.
>> Can I have
>> Can I have the
>> Yeah.
>> Can I have the first
>> Can I have the first hug?
>> Question.
>> Question. No
>> Question. No hugs
>> Question. No hugs today
>> Question. No hugs today because
>> Question. No hugs today because my
>> Question. No hugs today because my bones
have
have turned
>> Question. No hugs today because my bones
have turned to
have turned to styrofoam.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> I
>> I didn't
>> Thank you.
>> I didn't want
>> I didn't want to
>> Thank you.
>> I didn't want to interrupt
>> I didn't want to interrupt you
>> Thank you.
>> I didn't want to interrupt you in
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. No,
>> Yeah. No, that
>> Yeah. No, that was
>> Yeah. No, that was perfect.
>> It
>> It was
>> Yeah. No, that was perfect.
>> It was a
>> It was a It
>> Yeah. No, that was perfect.
>> It was a It was
>> It was a It was a
Okay.
Okay. Um,
Okay. Um, you
Okay. Um, you need
Okay. Um, you need to
Okay. Um, you need to sit
Okay. Um, you need to sit right
Okay. Um, you need to sit right here
Okay. Um, you need to sit right here and
speak
speak right
Okay. Um, you need to sit right here and
speak right into
speak right into the
Okay. Um, you need to sit right here and
speak right into the mic.
>> Is
>> Is that
>> Is that hers?
>> No,
>> No, wait.
>> Is that hers?
>> No, wait. You're
>> No, wait. You're getting
>> Is that hers?
>> No, wait. You're getting me
>> No, wait. You're getting me confused.
Where'd
Where'd you
Where'd you get
Where'd you get this
Where'd you get this from?
>> I
>> I don't
Where'd you get this from?
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know. That
Where'd you get this from?
>> I don't know. That stack.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. No,
>> Okay. No, I
>> Okay. No, I need
>> Okay. No, I need this.
>> Okay. No, I need this. This
>> Okay. No, I need this. This is
>> Okay. No, I need this. This is the
>> Okay. No, I need this. This is the one
>> Okay. No, I need this. This is the one I
Here,
Here, I
>> Okay. No, I need this. This is the one I
Here, I got
Here, I got it.
>> Okay. No, I need this. This is the one I
Here, I got it. Don't
Here, I got it. Don't worry.
>> All right.
>> Those
>> Those two.
>> All right.
>> Those two. Okay.
>> Those two. Okay. Gigi,
I'm
I'm getting
I'm getting confused
I'm getting confused here.
I'm getting confused here. You're
I'm getting confused here. You're giving
me
me too
I'm getting confused here. You're giving
me too many
me too many at
I'm getting confused here. You're giving
me too many at once.
me too many at once. Okay.
>> Yes.
>> At
>> At what
>> Yes.
>> At what level
>> At what level do
>> Yes.
>> At what level do I
>> At what level do I calibrate?
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know.
I
I don't
>> I don't know.
I don't want
I don't want to
>> I don't know.
I don't want to know.
>> It's
>> It's not
>> It's not to
>> It's not to worry
>> It's not to worry about.
It's
It's not
>> It's not to worry about.
It's not to
It's not to worry
>> It's not to worry about.
It's not to worry about
because
because the
because the ego
because the ego instantly
because the ego instantly grabs
because the ego instantly grabs it
because the ego instantly grabs it for
better
better or
because the ego instantly grabs it for
better or for
better or for worse.
because the ego instantly grabs it for
better or for worse. Yeah.
better or for worse. Yeah. And
because the ego instantly grabs it for
better or for worse. Yeah. And therefore
it
it it
it it doesn't
it it doesn't really
it it doesn't really serve
it it doesn't really serve anything.
it it doesn't really serve anything. You
can
can tell
it it doesn't really serve anything. You
can tell where
can tell where where
it it doesn't really serve anything. You
can tell where where you
can tell where where you are
it it doesn't really serve anything. You
can tell where where you are on
can tell where where you are on the
calibrated
calibrated levels
calibrated levels of
calibrated levels of consciousness
calibrated levels of consciousness by
looking
looking at
calibrated levels of consciousness by
looking at the
looking at the prevailing
calibrated levels of consciousness by
looking at the prevailing emotionality
and
and world
and world view
and world view and
and world view and attitude
and world view and attitude and
and world view and attitude and that
will
will tell
and world view and attitude and that
will tell you
will tell you pretty
and world view and attitude and that
will tell you pretty much
will tell you pretty much where
and world view and attitude and that
will tell you pretty much where you're
at.
Mhm.
Also,
Also, you
Also, you know,
Also, you know, the
Also, you know, the degree
Also, you know, the degree to
Also, you know, the degree to which
you're
you're happy.
Also, you know, the degree to which
you're happy. You'll
you're happy. You'll see
Also, you know, the degree to which
you're happy. You'll see the
you're happy. You'll see the calibrated
levels
levels of
levels of consciousness
levels of consciousness are
levels of consciousness are also
correlated
correlated with
levels of consciousness are also
correlated with happiness.
correlated with happiness. You
levels of consciousness are also
correlated with happiness. You see
correlated with happiness. You see 500
and
and up
and up it's
and up it's approximately
and up it's approximately 100%.
and up it's approximately 100%. Below
200 it's
200 it's about
and up it's approximately 100%. Below
200 it's about 15%.
So
So the
So the higher
So the higher the
So the higher the level
So the higher the level of
So the higher the level of consciousness
the
the greater
So the higher the level of consciousness
the greater the
the greater the degree
So the higher the level of consciousness
the greater the degree of
the greater the degree of happiness.
So the higher the level of consciousness
the greater the degree of happiness. So
you
you I
you I would
you I would gauge
you I would gauge first
you I would gauge first your
you I would gauge first your degree
you I would gauge first your degree of
happiness
happiness and
you I would gauge first your degree of
happiness and joy
happiness and joy in
you I would gauge first your degree of
happiness and joy in your
happiness and joy in your own
you I would gauge first your degree of
happiness and joy in your own existence.
Yeah.
To
To experience
Yeah.
To experience the
To experience the joy
Yeah.
To experience the joy in
To experience the joy in your
Yeah.
To experience the joy in your own
existence.
>> Um
>> Um Dave,
existence.
>> Um Dave, did
>> Um Dave, did you
existence.
>> Um Dave, did you need
>> Um Dave, did you need a
existence.
>> Um Dave, did you need a pillow
>> Um Dave, did you need a pillow to
existence.
>> Um Dave, did you need a pillow to sit
>> Um Dave, did you need a pillow to sit on
to
to bring
to bring me
to bring me a
to bring me a little
to bring me a little higher?
>> Okay.
>> Okay. to
to bring me a little higher?
>> Okay. to say
>> Okay. to say you're
to bring me a little higher?
>> Okay. to say you're a
>> Okay. to say you're a little
to bring me a little higher?
>> Okay. to say you're a little higher.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. That
>> Okay. That way
>> Okay. That way I
>> Okay. That way I don't
>> Okay. That way I don't have
>> Okay. That way I don't have to
>> Okay. That way I don't have to hunch
over.
over. That's
>> Okay. That way I don't have to hunch
over. That's Thank
over. That's Thank you.
>> Okay. That way I don't have to hunch
over. That's Thank you. Sure.
over. That's Thank you. Sure. Yeah.
That's
That's fine.
>> I
>> I don't
That's fine.
>> I don't mind
>> I don't mind hunching,
That's fine.
>> I don't mind hunching, but
>> I don't mind hunching, but you
That's fine.
>> I don't mind hunching, but you look
hunchy.
>> I
>> I need
hunchy.
>> I need you
>> I need you right.
>> Go
>> Go ahead.
>> Just
>> Just right
>> Go ahead.
>> Just right there.
>> Which
>> Which mic
>> Which mic is
>> Which mic is yours?
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Which mic is yours?
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Take
>> Take that
>> Take that one.
>> I
>> I was
>> Take that one.
>> I was listening
>> I was listening to
>> Take that one.
>> I was listening to a
>> I was listening to a a
>> Take that one.
>> I was listening to a a lecture
>> I was listening to a a lecture you
>> Take that one.
>> I was listening to a a lecture you gave
a
a few
a few years
a few years ago
a few years ago and
a few years ago and the
a few years ago and the subject
a few years ago and the subject came
a few years ago and the subject came up
of
of disease.
>> Of
>> Of disease.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Yeah. And in
>> Yeah. And in that
>> Yeah. And in that context
>> Yeah. And in that context you
>> Yeah. And in that context you mentioned
that
that dread
>> Yeah. And in that context you mentioned
that dread and
that dread and fear
>> Yeah. And in that context you mentioned
that dread and fear of
that dread and fear of eternal
>> Yeah. And in that context you mentioned
that dread and fear of eternal damnation
is
is held
is held in
is held in the
is held in the superego
and
and you
>> Yes.
>> Yes. That's
>> Yes. That's one
>> Yes. That's one of
>> Yes. That's one of the
>> Yes. That's one of the u
>> Yes. That's one of the u propositions
>> Yes. That's one of the u propositions in
the
the super
>> Yes. That's one of the u propositions in
the super ego.
the super ego. Yeah.
>> And
>> And you
>> And you mentioned
>> And you mentioned that
>> And you mentioned that human
>> And you mentioned that human suffering
is
is self-imposed
>> And you mentioned that human suffering
is self-imposed and
is self-imposed and then
>> And you mentioned that human suffering
is self-imposed and then you
is self-imposed and then you said
>> And you mentioned that human suffering
is self-imposed and then you said that
there's
there's an
there's an archetype
there's an archetype that
there's an archetype that fuels
there's an archetype that fuels that
entire
entire belief
there's an archetype that fuels that
entire belief system
entire belief system and
there's an archetype that fuels that
entire belief system and I
entire belief system and I was
there's an archetype that fuels that
entire belief system and I was wondering
if
if you
if you could
if you could speak
if you could speak to
if you could speak to what
if you could speak to what that
archetype
archetype is
if you could speak to what that
archetype is and
archetype is and how
if you could speak to what that
archetype is and how it
archetype is and how it relates
if you could speak to what that
archetype is and how it relates to
archetype is and how it relates to it.
Well,
Well, uh
Well, uh if
Well, uh if you
Well, uh if you study
Well, uh if you study the
Well, uh if you study the Yian
archetypes,
archetypes, you'll
Well, uh if you study the Yian
archetypes, you'll see
archetypes, you'll see that
Well, uh if you study the Yian
archetypes, you'll see that they
archetypes, you'll see that they are
also
also the
also the spiritual
also the spiritual archetypes.
Uh
Uh the
uh
uh you
uh you might
uh you might say
uh you might say the
uh you might say the spleen
uh you might say the spleen of
uh you might say the spleen of the
spiritual
spiritual knight,
uh you might say the spleen of the
spiritual knight, the
spiritual knight, the black
uh you might say the spleen of the
spiritual knight, the black knight,
spiritual knight, the black knight, not
the
the white
the white knight,
the white knight, the
the white knight, the black
the white knight, the black knight
threatens
threatens you
the white knight, the black knight
threatens you that
threatens you that if
the white knight, the black knight
threatens you that if you
threatens you that if you um
the white knight, the black knight
threatens you that if you um violate
threatens you that if you um violate its
rules,
rules, you're
rules, you're going
rules, you're going to
rules, you're going to go
rules, you're going to go to
rules, you're going to go to eternal
damnation.
Well,
that's
that's obviously
Well,
that's obviously the
that's obviously the black
Well,
that's obviously the black knight
speaking.
speaking. The
speaking. The white
speaking. The white knight
speaking. The white knight thinks
speaking. The white knight thinks only
sees
sees only
speaking. The white knight thinks only
sees only salvation.
sees only salvation. The
speaking. The white knight thinks only
sees only salvation. The black
sees only salvation. The black knight
sees
sees damnation.
sees damnation. See,
sees damnation. See, the
sees damnation. See, the white
sees damnation. See, the white knight
sees
sees salvation
sees damnation. See, the white knight
sees salvation for
sees salvation for all
sees damnation. See, the white knight
sees salvation for all people
sees salvation for all people because
everyone
everyone operates
everyone operates out
everyone operates out of
everyone operates out of ignorance.
everyone operates out of ignorance. The
Buddha
Buddha said
everyone operates out of ignorance. The
Buddha said it.
Buddha said it. Jesus
everyone operates out of ignorance. The
Buddha said it. Jesus Christ
Buddha said it. Jesus Christ said
everyone operates out of ignorance. The
Buddha said it. Jesus Christ said it.
Socrates
Socrates said
Socrates said it.
Socrates said it. Uh
Socrates said it. Uh the
Socrates said it. Uh the only
Socrates said it. Uh the only error
Socrates said it. Uh the only error is
that
that man
Socrates said it. Uh the only error is
that man seeks
that man seeks the
Socrates said it. Uh the only error is
that man seeks the good.
that man seeks the good. The
Socrates said it. Uh the only error is
that man seeks the good. The only
problem
problem is
problem is he
problem is he doesn't
problem is he doesn't know
problem is he doesn't know what
problem is he doesn't know what is
problem is he doesn't know what is the
good.
good. So
problem is he doesn't know what is the
good. So he
good. So he seeks
problem is he doesn't know what is the
good. So he seeks the
good. So he seeks the illusion
problem is he doesn't know what is the
good. So he seeks the illusion of
good. So he seeks the illusion of good
rather
rather than
rather than the
rather than the reality
rather than the reality of
rather than the reality of good.
rather than the reality of good. Why?
Because
Because at
rather than the reality of good. Why?
Because at that
Because at that level
rather than the reality of good. Why?
Because at that level of
Because at that level of consciousness
doesn't
doesn't see
doesn't see essence.
doesn't see essence. It
doesn't see essence. It it
doesn't see essence. It it only
doesn't see essence. It it only the
doesn't see essence. It it only the ego
is
is in
doesn't see essence. It it only the ego
is in involved
is in involved in
doesn't see essence. It it only the ego
is in involved in perception.
is in involved in perception. And
the
the opening
the opening of
the opening of the
the opening of the third
the opening of the third eye
the opening of the third eye of
the opening of the third eye of the
Buddha
Buddha body
the opening of the third eye of the
Buddha body which
Buddha body which occurs
the opening of the third eye of the
Buddha body which occurs around
consciousness
consciousness level
I
I think
consciousness level
I think it
I think it opens
consciousness level
I think it opens up
I think it opens up around
consciousness level
I think it opens up around 540
is
is the
is the capacity
is the capacity for
is the capacity for discernment
is the capacity for discernment of
essence.
In
In that
In that case,
In that case, you're
In that case, you're less
In that case, you're less of
In that case, you're less of a
In that case, you're less of a sucker
for
for perception.
In that case, you're less of a sucker
for perception. You
for perception. You know,
In that case, you're less of a sucker
for perception. You know, easier
for perception. You know, easier to
fool.
fool. It
fool. It looks
fool. It looks attractive.
fool. It looks attractive. It
fool. It looks attractive. It sounds
lovely.
lovely. And
fool. It looks attractive. It sounds
lovely. And you
lovely. And you can
fool. It looks attractive. It sounds
lovely. And you can see
lovely. And you can see that
fool. It looks attractive. It sounds
lovely. And you can see that it's
lovely. And you can see that it's all
set
set up
set up for
set up for seduction.
Yeah.
Yeah. So,
set up for seduction.
Yeah. So, you
Yeah. So, you get
set up for seduction.
Yeah. So, you get the
Yeah. So, you get the essence
set up for seduction.
Yeah. So, you get the essence here.
Yeah. So, you get the essence here. Is
seduction.
seduction. So,
seduction. So, perception
seduction. So, perception doesn't
seduction. So, perception doesn't see
that.
that. Perception
seduction. So, perception doesn't see
that. Perception sees
that. Perception sees glamour.
seduction. So, perception doesn't see
that. Perception sees glamour. Uh
discernment
discernment sees
seduction.
>> All right.
It's
It's the
>> All right.
It's the opening
It's the opening of
>> All right.
It's the opening of the
It's the opening of the third
>> All right.
It's the opening of the third eye
It's the opening of the third eye of
>> All right.
It's the opening of the third eye of the
Buddha
Buddha body
Buddha body is
Buddha body is the
Buddha body is the way
Buddha body is the way it's
Buddha body is the way it's classically
called
called in
Buddha body is the way it's classically
called in the
called in the esoteric
Buddha body is the way it's classically
called in the esoteric literature.
called in the esoteric literature. The
etheric
etheric energy
etheric energy has
etheric energy has the
etheric energy has the higher
etheric energy has the higher spiritual
bodies
bodies you
etheric energy has the higher spiritual
bodies you know
>> it
>> it goes
>> it goes causal
>> it goes causal buddhic
>> it goes causal buddhic atmic
Christ
Christ body
>> it goes causal buddhic atmic
Christ body etc.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello.
>> Mhm.
>> I'm
>> I'm holding
>> Mhm.
>> I'm holding in
>> I'm holding in intention
>> Mhm.
>> I'm holding in intention that
>> I'm holding in intention that you
>> Mhm.
>> I'm holding in intention that you will
write
write a
write a book
write a book on
write a book on how
write a book on how to
write a book on how to use
write a book on how to use this
write a book on how to use this body
write a book on how to use this body of
information
information in
write a book on how to use this body of
information in doing
information in doing psychotherapy.
Well,
Well, it's
Well, it's for
Well, it's for the
Well, it's for the psychotherapist.
So,
So, the
Well, it's for the psychotherapist.
So, the psychotherapist's
So, the psychotherapist's consciousness
evolves
evolves and
evolves and then
evolves and then you
evolves and then you can
be
be of
evolves and then you can
be of assistance
be of assistance to
evolves and then you can
be of assistance to the
be of assistance to the patient
evolves and then you can
be of assistance to the patient from
be of assistance to the patient from a
higher
higher level
higher level of
higher level of consciousness.
higher level of consciousness. You
higher level of consciousness. You can
recontextualize.
recontextualize. So,
higher level of consciousness. You can
recontextualize. So, one
recontextualize. So, one of
higher level of consciousness. You can
recontextualize. So, one of the
recontextualize. So, one of the things
you
you learn
you learn from
you learn from spiritual
you learn from spiritual work
you learn from spiritual work is
you learn from spiritual work is to
you learn from spiritual work is to heal
via
via recontextualization.
So,
So, you
So, you can
So, you can recontextualize
So, you can recontextualize it
So, you can recontextualize it uh
So, you can recontextualize it uh so
that
that the
So, you can recontextualize it uh so
that the person
that the person sees
So, you can recontextualize it uh so
that the person sees it.
that the person sees it. Let's
So, you can recontextualize it uh so
that the person sees it. Let's say
that the person sees it. Let's say he's
riddled
riddled with
riddled with guilt.
riddled with guilt. You
riddled with guilt. You say,
riddled with guilt. You say, "Well,
riddled with guilt. You say, "Well, at
the
the time,
riddled with guilt. You say, "Well, at
the time, didn't
the time, didn't you
riddled with guilt. You say, "Well, at
the time, didn't you think
the time, didn't you think that
riddled with guilt. You say, "Well, at
the time, didn't you think that was
the time, didn't you think that was a
good
good thing?"
good thing?" Of
good thing?" Of course,
good thing?" Of course, otherwise,
good thing?" Of course, otherwise, you
wouldn't
wouldn't have
good thing?" Of course, otherwise, you
wouldn't have chosen
wouldn't have chosen it.
good thing?" Of course, otherwise, you
wouldn't have chosen it. So,
wouldn't have chosen it. So, you
good thing?" Of course, otherwise, you
wouldn't have chosen it. So, you can
quote
quote Socrates,
quote Socrates, that
quote Socrates, that man
quote Socrates, that man only
quote Socrates, that man only chooses
the
the good.
quote Socrates, that man only chooses
the good. The
the good. The only
quote Socrates, that man only chooses
the good. The only problem
the good. The only problem is
quote Socrates, that man only chooses
the good. The only problem is he
the good. The only problem is he doesn't
know
know the
know the losery
know the losery from
know the losery from the
know the losery from the real.
But
all
all the
all the great
all the great ones,
all the great ones, it
all the great ones, it said
all the great ones, it said man
all the great ones, it said man is
forgivable
forgivable by
all the great ones, it said man is
forgivable by virtue
forgivable by virtue of
all the great ones, it said man is
forgivable by virtue of his
forgivable by virtue of his innocence.
And
And there's
And there's only
And there's only one
And there's only one fault
And there's only one fault and
And there's only one fault and that
And there's only one fault and that is
ignorance.
ignorance. Huh?
>> How
>> How does
>> How does one
>> How does one do
>> How does one do that
>> How does one do that with
>> How does one do that with couples?
Marriage
Marriage counseling.
>> Well,
>> Well, we
>> Well, we spoke
>> Well, we spoke today
>> Well, we spoke today about
>> Well, we spoke today about alignment
>> Well, we spoke today about alignment and
differentiate
differentiate alignment
>> Well, we spoke today about alignment and
differentiate alignment with
involvement.
involvement. And
involvement. And once
involvement. And once they
involvement. And once they see
involvement. And once they see that,
involvement. And once they see that, if
they
they don't
involvement. And once they see that, if
they don't get
they don't get it,
involvement. And once they see that, if
they don't get it, send
they don't get it, send them
involvement. And once they see that, if
they don't get it, send them to
they don't get it, send them to a
different
different therapist.
>> I'll
>> I'll tell
different therapist.
>> I'll tell you
>> I'll tell you why.
different therapist.
>> I'll tell you why. Because
>> I'll tell you why. Because they
different therapist.
>> I'll tell you why. Because they don't
want
want happiness.
want happiness. They're
want happiness. They're looking
want happiness. They're looking for
want happiness. They're looking for you
uh
uh to
want happiness. They're looking for you
uh to to
uh to to trap
want happiness. They're looking for you
uh to to trap you
uh to to trap you in
want happiness. They're looking for you
uh to to trap you in their
uh to to trap you in their mutual
want happiness. They're looking for you
uh to to trap you in their mutual uh
manipulation.
>> Hi,
>> thank
>> thank you
>> thank you so
>> thank you so much
>> thank you so much for
>> thank you so much for all
>> thank you so much for all your
>> thank you so much for all your work,
>> thank you so much for all your work, Dr.
Hawkins.
Hawkins. You
>> thank you so much for all your work, Dr.
Hawkins. You and
Hawkins. You and Susan,
>> thank you so much for all your work, Dr.
Hawkins. You and Susan, it's
Hawkins. You and Susan, it's been
>> thank you so much for all your work, Dr.
Hawkins. You and Susan, it's been quite
wonderful.
wonderful. Um
wonderful. Um I
wonderful. Um I understand
wonderful. Um I understand that
wonderful. Um I understand that when
you're
you're below
wonderful. Um I understand that when
you're below the
you're below the 200
wonderful. Um I understand that when
you're below the 200 level
you're below the 200 level of
consciousness,
consciousness, you
consciousness, you don't
consciousness, you don't even
consciousness, you don't even think
consciousness, you don't even think as
people
people do
consciousness, you don't even think as
people do above
people do above 200
consciousness, you don't even think as
people do above 200 and
>> Oh,
>> Oh, they
>> Oh, they think
>> Oh, they think they
>> Oh, they think they think.
>> Oh, they think they think. Yes,
>> Oh, they think they think. Yes, they
think,
>> but
>> but they
>> but they wouldn't
>> but they wouldn't interpret
>> but they wouldn't interpret an
>> but they wouldn't interpret an event
>> but they wouldn't interpret an event the
same
same way
>> but they wouldn't interpret an event the
same way as
same way as someone
>> but they wouldn't interpret an event the
same way as someone above
same way as someone above it.
>> No,
>> No, because
>> No, because they
>> No, because they interpret
>> No, because they interpret it
differently.
differently. Mhm.
>> Well,
>> Well, my
>> Well, my question
>> Well, my question is,
>> Well, my question is, if
>> Well, my question is, if someone
>> Well, my question is, if someone below
200 suddenly
200 suddenly had
>> Well, my question is, if someone below
200 suddenly had a
200 suddenly had a rise
>> Well, my question is, if someone below
200 suddenly had a rise in
200 suddenly had a rise in consciousness
over
over 200,
over 200, would
over 200, would their
over 200, would their memories
over 200, would their memories of
over 200, would their memories of things
or
or concepts
over 200, would their memories of things
or concepts of
or concepts of of
over 200, would their memories of things
or concepts of of past
or concepts of of past events,
over 200, would their memories of things
or concepts of of past events, would
that
that change?
>> Uh,
>> Uh, no
that change?
>> Uh, no other
>> Uh, no other contextualization
that change?
>> Uh, no other contextualization of
>> Uh, no other contextualization of it
would.
>> Okay.
they
they would
they would see
they would see it
they would see it as
they would see it as error
they would see it as error or
they would see it as error or stupidity
or
or was
they would see it as error or stupidity
or was a
or was a byproduct
they would see it as error or stupidity
or was a byproduct of
or was a byproduct of their
they would see it as error or stupidity
or was a byproduct of their addiction.
>> So,
>> So, so
>> So, so they
>> So, so they could
>> So, so they could see
>> So, so they could see that
>> So, so they could see that they
>> So, so they could see that they that
that
that they
>> So, so they could see that they that
that they would
that they would admit
>> So, so they could see that they that
that they would admit that
that they would admit that some
>> So, so they could see that they that
that they would admit that some of
that they would admit that some of the
things
things that
things that they
things that they had
things that they had done.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Because
things that they had done.
>> Yeah. Because look
>> Yeah. Because look at
things that they had done.
>> Yeah. Because look at the
>> Yeah. Because look at the 12step
program.
program. Took
program. Took a
program. Took a fearless
program. Took a fearless moral
inventory.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. During
>> Yeah. During your
>> Yeah. During your drinking
>> Yeah. During your drinking days,
>> Yeah. During your drinking days, you
>> Yeah. During your drinking days, you did
this,
this, you
>> Yeah. During your drinking days, you did
this, you did
this, you did that,
>> Yeah. During your drinking days, you did
this, you did that, you
this, you did that, you stole
>> Yeah. During your drinking days, you did
this, you did that, you stole from
this, you did that, you stole from this
person
person and
person and you
person and you lied
person and you lied and
person and you lied and and
person and you lied and and you
person and you lied and and you asked
God
God for
person and you lied and and you asked
God for forgiveness
God for forgiveness and
person and you lied and and you asked
God for forgiveness and then
God for forgiveness and then you
person and you lied and and you asked
God for forgiveness and then you go
God for forgiveness and then you go on
from
from there.
from there. Other
from there. Other than
from there. Other than asking
from there. Other than asking for
forgiveness,
forgiveness, what
from there. Other than asking for
forgiveness, what can
forgiveness, what can you
from there. Other than asking for
forgiveness, what can you do
forgiveness, what can you do about
from there. Other than asking for
forgiveness, what can you do about it?
Right.
Right. Okay.
Right. Okay. Okay.
Right. Okay. Okay. Thank
Right. Okay. Okay. Thank you
Right. Okay. Okay. Thank you very
Right. Okay. Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Now
>> Now you
Right. Okay. Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Now you conceptualize
>> Now you conceptualize it
Right. Okay. Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Now you conceptualize it differently.
You
You contextualize
You contextualize it
You contextualize it differently.
>> You
>> You see,
You contextualize it differently.
>> You see, it
>> You see, it was
You contextualize it differently.
>> You see, it was the
>> You see, it was the result
You contextualize it differently.
>> You see, it was the result of
>> You see, it was the result of ignorance
and
and the
and the disease
and the disease or
and the disease or whatever
and the disease or whatever you
and the disease or whatever you were
suffering
suffering from.
>> We
>> We got
>> We got to
>> We got to find
>> We got to find where
>> We got to find where we
>> We got to find where we can
>> We got to find where we can write
>> We got to find where we can write on
this.
this. Here
>> We got to find where we can write on
this. Here it
this. Here it goes.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, no.
>> Oh, no. Cuz
>> Oh, no. Cuz that
>> Oh, no. Cuz that has
>> Oh, no. Cuz that has to
>> Oh, no. Cuz that has to be
>> Oh, no. Cuz that has to be taken
>> Oh, no. Cuz that has to be taken off.
You
You have
>> Oh, no. Cuz that has to be taken off.
You have to
You have to write
>> Oh, no. Cuz that has to be taken off.
You have to write on
You have to write on the
>> Oh, no. Cuz that has to be taken off.
You have to write on the cast.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know if
>> I don't know if it'll
>> I don't know if it'll print
>> I don't know if it'll print on
>> I don't know if it'll print on the
>> I don't know if it'll print on the cast.
Will
Will it?
>> Yeah.
>> I
>> I don't
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know
>> I don't know if
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know if I
>> I don't know if I get
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know if I get it
>> I don't know if I get it to
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know if I get it to write
>> I don't know if I get it to write on
there.
There
There you
there.
There you go.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Is
>> Is it
>> Thank you.
>> Is it okay
>> Is it okay for
>> Thank you.
>> Is it okay for me
>> Is it okay for me to
>> Thank you.
>> Is it okay for me to have
>> Is it okay for me to have a
>> Thank you.
>> Is it okay for me to have a picture
taken
taken with
taken with you
taken with you Susan
taken with you Susan before
taken with you Susan before I
taken with you Susan before I ask
taken with you Susan before I ask my
question?
>> I
>> I can't
>> I can't hear
>> I can't hear what
>> I can't hear what he's
>> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> We
>> We couldn't
>> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> We couldn't hear.
>> Is
>> Is it
>> Is it okay
>> Is it okay if
>> Is it okay if we
>> Is it okay if we have
>> Is it okay if we have Judy
>> Is it okay if we have Judy and
>> Is it okay if we have Judy and my
picture
picture taken
>> Is it okay if we have Judy and my
picture taken with
picture taken with you
>> Is it okay if we have Judy and my
picture taken with you before
picture taken with you before I
>> Is it okay if we have Judy and my
picture taken with you before I ask
picture taken with you before I ask my
question?
>> Sure.
>> What
>> What did
>> Sure.
>> What did he
>> What did he say?
>> He
>> He wants
>> He wants a
>> He wants a picture
>> He wants a picture taken
>> He wants a picture taken with
>> He wants a picture taken with you.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, a
>> He wants a picture taken with you.
>> Oh, a picture.
>> Oh, a picture. Yes.
>> He wants a picture taken with you.
>> Oh, a picture. Yes. Yeah.
>> Oh, a picture. Yes. Yeah. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. This
>> Okay. This is
>> Okay. This is picture
>> Okay. This is picture time.
>> A
>> A picture.
>> Yeah.
5,000
5,000 year old
>> Yeah.
5,000 year old man.
>> Hi.
>> Yes.
>> You're
>> You're answering
>> You're answering my
>> You're answering my basic
>> You're answering my basic question
>> You're answering my basic question I've
wanted
wanted to
>> You're answering my basic question I've
wanted to ask
wanted to ask you
>> You're answering my basic question I've
wanted to ask you for
wanted to ask you for months
>> You're answering my basic question I've
wanted to ask you for months just
wanted to ask you for months just a
>> You're answering my basic question I've
wanted to ask you for months just a few
minutes
minutes ago
minutes ago when
minutes ago when you
minutes ago when you were
minutes ago when you were talking.
Excuse
Excuse me.
minutes ago when you were talking.
Excuse me. But
Excuse me. But I
minutes ago when you were talking.
Excuse me. But I do
Excuse me. But I do want
minutes ago when you were talking.
Excuse me. But I do want to
Excuse me. But I do want to thank
minutes ago when you were talking.
Excuse me. But I do want to thank you
for
for what
for what you
for what you meant
for what you meant to
for what you meant to Judy
for what you meant to Judy and
for what you meant to Judy and me.
for what you meant to Judy and me. I
want
want to
for what you meant to Judy and me. I
want to thank
want to thank you
for what you meant to Judy and me. I
want to thank you for
want to thank you for what
for what you meant to Judy and me. I
want to thank you for what you
want to thank you for what you have
for what you meant to Judy and me. I
want to thank you for what you have done
for
for the
for the world.
for the world. At
for the world. At the
for the world. At the last
for the world. At the last lecture
for the world. At the last lecture we
attended
attended in
for the world. At the last lecture we
attended in October,
attended in October, there
for the world. At the last lecture we
attended in October, there was
attended in October, there was a
for the world. At the last lecture we
attended in October, there was a sunset
here
here in
here in Sedona
here in Sedona that
here in Sedona that was
here in Sedona that was so
here in Sedona that was so beautiful.
here in Sedona that was so beautiful. If
I
I talked
here in Sedona that was so beautiful. If
I talked to
I talked to her
here in Sedona that was so beautiful. If
I talked to her about
I talked to her about it,
here in Sedona that was so beautiful. If
I talked to her about it, I
I talked to her about it, I cry.
>> Oh
>> Oh yeah.
>> And
>> And I
>> Oh yeah.
>> And I did
>> And I did take
>> Oh yeah.
>> And I did take a
>> And I did take a photograph
>> Oh yeah.
>> And I did take a photograph of
>> And I did take a photograph of it.
>> Oh yeah.
>> And I did take a photograph of it. And
the
the feeling
the feeling of
the feeling of divinity
the feeling of divinity present
the feeling of divinity present was
the feeling of divinity present was so
strong
strong I
the feeling of divinity present was so
strong I wanted
strong I wanted to
the feeling of divinity present was so
strong I wanted to share
strong I wanted to share it
the feeling of divinity present was so
strong I wanted to share it with
strong I wanted to share it with you.
>> Aha.
That's
That's stunning.
Yes.
It's
It's because
Yes.
It's because you're
It's because you're aware
Yes.
It's because you're aware of
It's because you're aware of it.
Yes.
It's because you're aware of it. It's
not
not in
not in the
not in the picture.
not in the picture. It's
not in the picture. It's in
not in the picture. It's in you.
Is
Is this
not in the picture. It's in you.
Is this RC?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, that's
>> Yes.
>> Yeah, that's our
>> Yeah, that's our nice.
>> That's
>> That's beautiful.
>> It
>> It is
>> That's beautiful.
>> It is very
>> It is very beautiful.
Thank
Thank you
Thank you very
Thank you very much.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yes.
Um,
Um, hello.
Um, hello. I
Um, hello. I teach
students
students on
Um, hello. I teach
students on the
students on the Navajo
Um, hello. I teach
students on the Navajo reservation
students on the Navajo reservation and
several
several weeks
several weeks ago
several weeks ago in
several weeks ago in my
several weeks ago in my seventh
several weeks ago in my seventh grade
science
science class
several weeks ago in my seventh grade
science class I
science class I was
several weeks ago in my seventh grade
science class I was teaching
science class I was teaching them
chiology
>> and
>> and one
chiology
>> and one of
>> and one of my
chiology
>> and one of my students
>> and one of my students made
chiology
>> and one of my students made a
>> and one of my students made a report
that
that I
that I would
that I would like
that I would like to
that I would like to give
that I would like to give to
that I would like to give to you
that I would like to give to you what
>> report
>> this
>> this is
>> this is well
>> this is well I'm
>> this is well I'm a
>> this is well I'm a teacher
>> this is well I'm a teacher so
>> this is well I'm a teacher so she's
>> this is well I'm a teacher so she's got
to
to write
>> this is well I'm a teacher so she's got
to write so
to write so this
>> this is well I'm a teacher so she's got
to write so this is
to write so this is what
>> this is well I'm a teacher so she's got
to write so this is what she
to write so this is what she wrote
and
and my
and my question
and my question is
and my question is is
Um,
Um, have
and my question is is
Um, have you
Um, have you heard
and my question is is
Um, have you heard of
Um, have you heard of Bahala
and my question is is
Um, have you heard of Bahala and
Um, have you heard of Bahala and have
you
you calibrated
you calibrated his
you calibrated his revelation?
>> Who
bah?
>> I'm
>> I'm not
bah?
>> I'm not familiar
>> I'm not familiar with
bah?
>> I'm not familiar with the
>> I'm not familiar with the term.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, thank
>> Okay, thank you.
>> Is
>> Is that
>> Okay, thank you.
>> Is that an
>> Is that an Iranian
uh
>> uh
>> uh Bahala
uh
>> uh Bahala was
>> uh Bahala was born
uh
>> uh Bahala was born in
>> uh Bahala was born in Tran?
uh
>> uh Bahala was born in Tran? Yeah.
>> Huh?
>> Huh? Bahala
>> Huh? Bahala was
>> Huh? Bahala was born
>> Huh? Bahala was born in
>> Huh? Bahala was born in Thran.
>> Huh? Bahala was born in Thran. Yes.
>> Thrron.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. It's
>> Yes. It's uh
>> Yes. It's uh Bahigh.
>> Yes.
>> It's
>> It's Bahigh.
>> It's Bahigh. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. I've
>> It's Bahigh. Yes.
>> Yes. I've heard
>> Yes. I've heard of
>> It's Bahigh. Yes.
>> Yes. I've heard of the
>> Yes. I've heard of the founder
>> It's Bahigh. Yes.
>> Yes. I've heard of the founder of
Bahigh.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
Bahigh.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. Have
Bahigh.
>> Okay. Thank you. Have you
>> Okay. Thank you. Have you calibrated
his?
>> I
>> I think
his?
>> I think it
>> I think it Yes.
his?
>> I think it Yes. In
>> I think it Yes. In the
his?
>> I think it Yes. In the book
>> I think it Yes. In the book Truth
his?
>> I think it Yes. In the book Truth versus
Falsehood,
Falsehood, we
Falsehood, we did
Falsehood, we did calibrate
Falsehood, we did calibrate it.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
Falsehood, we did calibrate it.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. Thank
Falsehood, we did calibrate it.
>> Okay. Thank you. Thank you.
>> The
>> The Baja.
>> The Baja. Yes.
>> The Baja. Yes. Yeah.
>> The Baja.
>> The Baja. Yes. Yeah. I
>> The Baja. Yes. Yeah. I know
>> The Baja.
>> The Baja. Yes. Yeah. I know what
>> The Baja. Yes. Yeah. I know what he's
talking
talking about.
Yeah.
Yeah. And
talking about.
Yeah. And the
Yeah. And the founder
talking about.
Yeah. And the founder has
Yeah. And the founder has an
talking about.
Yeah. And the founder has an Arabic
Yeah. And the founder has an Arabic name
and
and I
and I can't
and I can't remember
and I can't remember because
and I can't remember because there's
and I can't remember because there's so
many
many apostrophes.
It's
It's L.
Hello
Hello Dr.
It's L.
Hello Dr. Hawkins.
Um
Um in
Um in Mahayana
Um in Mahayana Buddhism
Um in Mahayana Buddhism tradition
Um in Mahayana Buddhism tradition there
is
is an
Um in Mahayana Buddhism tradition there
is an emphasis
is an emphasis on
Um in Mahayana Buddhism tradition there
is an emphasis on the
is an emphasis on the bodhic
Um in Mahayana Buddhism tradition there
is an emphasis on the bodhic sava
is an emphasis on the bodhic sava path
um
um which
um which is
um which is to
um which is to remain
um which is to remain in
um which is to remain in this
um which is to remain in this world
after
after achieving
um which is to remain in this world
after achieving enlightenment.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Is
>> Yes. Is that
>> Yes. Is that what
>> Yes. Is that what it
>> Yes. Is that what it says?
>> Yes. Is that what it says? Yes.
>> Yes. Is that what it says? Yes. Mhm.
Using
Using using
>> Yes. Is that what it says? Yes. Mhm.
Using using the
Using using the map
>> Yes. Is that what it says? Yes. Mhm.
Using using the map of
Using using the map of consciousness
>> Yes. Is that what it says? Yes. Mhm.
Using using the map of consciousness did
Buddha
Buddha mean
Buddha mean that
Buddha mean that the
Buddha mean that the Buddha
Buddha mean that the Buddha ask
Buddha mean that the Buddha ask people
to
to remain
Buddha mean that the Buddha ask people
to remain in
to remain in this
Buddha mean that the Buddha ask people
to remain in this world
to remain in this world after
Buddha mean that the Buddha ask people
to remain in this world after achieving
>> above
>> above 600
>> above 600 it's
>> above 600 it's a
>> above 600 it's a meaningless
>> above 600 it's a meaningless uh
statement
statement because
statement because there's
statement because there's nobody
statement because there's nobody to
remain
remain in
statement because there's nobody to
remain in this
remain in this world
nor
nor would
nor would there
nor would there be
nor would there be any
nor would there be any intention
nor would there be any intention to
remain
remain in
nor would there be any intention to
remain in this
remain in this world.
nor would there be any intention to
remain in this world. What
remain in this world. What happens
nor would there be any intention to
remain in this world. What happens is
because
because of
because of one's
because of one's spiritual
because of one's spiritual alignment
because of one's spiritual alignment and
destiny
uh
uh a
uh a role
uh a role fulfills
uh a role fulfills itself
uh a role fulfills itself or
uh a role fulfills itself or does
uh a role fulfills itself or does not
beyond
beyond linearity.
There's
There's no
There's no conversation
There's no conversation but
There's no conversation but two
There's no conversation but two separate
entities.
entities. So
There's no conversation but two separate
entities. So there's
entities. So there's no
There's no conversation but two separate
entities. So there's no Buddha
entities. So there's no Buddha there
telling
telling you
telling you you
telling you you here
telling you you here to
telling you you here to do
telling you you here to do that.
telling you you here to do that. See
it
it would
telling you you here to do that. See
it would come
it would come to
telling you you here to do that. See
it would come to you
it would come to you as
telling you you here to do that. See
it would come to you as a
it would come to you as a given.
Right
Right now
Right now I
Right now I have
Right now I have the
Right now I have the feeling
Right now I have the feeling of
the
the to
Right now I have the feeling of
the to fulfill
the to fulfill the
Right now I have the feeling of
the to fulfill the books
the to fulfill the books that
Right now I have the feeling of
the to fulfill the books that I
the to fulfill the books that I have
outlined.
outlined. Complete
outlined. Complete the
outlined. Complete the presentation
outlined. Complete the presentation of
the
the entire
outlined. Complete the presentation of
the entire subject
the entire subject and
outlined. Complete the presentation of
the entire subject and then
the entire subject and then I
outlined. Complete the presentation of
the entire subject and then I feel
the entire subject and then I feel my
obligation
obligation is
obligation is fulfilled.
Obligation
Obligation to
obligation is fulfilled.
Obligation to who?
Obligation to who? To
obligation is fulfilled.
Obligation to who? To myself
to
to fulfill
to fulfill my
to fulfill my own
to fulfill my own potentiality.
with
with the
to fulfill my own potentiality.
with the same
with the same reason
to fulfill my own potentiality.
with the same reason that
with the same reason that Sir
to fulfill my own potentiality.
with the same reason that Sir Alexander
Fleming
Fleming shared
Fleming shared the
Fleming shared the discovery
Fleming shared the discovery of
Fleming shared the discovery of penis.
Then
Then he
Fleming shared the discovery of penis.
Then he felt
Then he felt complete
Fleming shared the discovery of penis.
Then he felt complete could
Then he felt complete could die
Fleming shared the discovery of penis.
Then he felt complete could die happy
as
as Wayne
as Wayne Dyrus
as Wayne Dyrus says.
>> Right.
>> Right. Right.
>> Not
>> Not to
>> Not to die
>> Not to die with
>> Not to die with your
>> Not to die with your song
>> Not to die with your song unsung.
>> Not to die with your song unsung. Yeah.
>> To
>> To feel
>> Not to die with your song unsung. Yeah.
>> To feel that
>> To feel that you
>> Not to die with your song unsung. Yeah.
>> To feel that you have
>> To feel that you have completed
>> Not to die with your song unsung. Yeah.
>> To feel that you have completed the
singing
singing of
singing of your
singing of your song.
singing of your song. Yeah.
>> Is
>> Is the
singing of your song. Yeah.
>> Is the fulfillment
>> Is the fulfillment of
singing of your song. Yeah.
>> Is the fulfillment of one's
>> Is the fulfillment of one's potential.
>> So
>> So it
>> So it had
>> So it had nothing
>> So it had nothing to
>> So it had nothing to do
>> So it had nothing to do with
>> So it had nothing to do with duality.
>> So it had nothing to do with duality. No
this
this and
>> So it had nothing to do with duality. No
this and a
this and a that.
>> So it had nothing to do with duality. No
this and a that. No
this and a that. No me
>> So it had nothing to do with duality. No
this and a that. No me and
this and a that. No me and a
>> So it had nothing to do with duality. No
this and a that. No me and a you.
this and a that. No me and a you. No
promise
promise is
promise is fulfilling
promise is fulfilling one's
potentiality.
>> So
>> So what
>> So what what
>> So what what is
>> So what what is the
>> So what what is the essence
>> So what what is the essence of
>> So what what is the essence of the
Mahayana
Mahayana Buddhism
>> So what what is the essence of the
Mahayana Buddhism teaching
Mahayana Buddhism teaching then?
>> So what what is the essence of the
Mahayana Buddhism teaching then? What
Mahayana Buddhism teaching then? What is
the
the essence
the essence of
>> what
>> what is
the essence of
>> what is the
>> what is the essence
the essence of
>> what is the essence of
>> essence?
>> essence? Then
>> you
>> you want
>> essence? Then
>> you want in
>> you want in one
>> essence? Then
>> you want in one sentence
>> you want in one sentence the
>> essence? Then
>> you want in one sentence the essence
>> you want in one sentence the essence of
Mahayana
Mahayana Buddhist
Mahayana Buddhist teaching.
>> It
>> It sounds
>> there's
>> there's nobody
>> there's nobody asking
>> there's nobody asking it.
>> there's nobody asking it. Thank
>> there's nobody asking it. Thank God.
Thank
Thank God
>> there's nobody asking it. Thank God.
Thank God there's
Thank God there's nobody
>> there's nobody asking it. Thank God.
Thank God there's nobody asking
Thank God there's nobody asking it.
>> there's nobody asking it. Thank God.
Thank God there's nobody asking it. So
I'm
I'm not
I'm not obliged
I'm not obliged to
I'm not obliged to answer.
>> So
>> So there's
I'm not obliged to answer.
>> So there's there's
>> So there's there's for
I'm not obliged to answer.
>> So there's there's for for
>> So there's there's for for true
I'm not obliged to answer.
>> So there's there's for for true like
non-duality
non-duality seeker,
non-duality seeker, one
non-duality seeker, one shouldn't
non-duality seeker, one shouldn't think
of
>> you're
>> you're asking
>> you're asking multiple
>> you're asking multiple questions.
>> you're asking multiple questions. Now
Mahayana
Mahayana Buddhism
>> you're asking multiple questions. Now
Mahayana Buddhism is
Mahayana Buddhism is the
>> you're asking multiple questions. Now
Mahayana Buddhism is the way
Mahayana Buddhism is the way of
>> you're asking multiple questions. Now
Mahayana Buddhism is the way of the
greater
greater vehicle.
>> It
>> It means
greater vehicle.
>> It means to
>> It means to be
greater vehicle.
>> It means to be concerned
>> It means to be concerned with
greater vehicle.
>> It means to be concerned with the
enlightenment
enlightenment of
enlightenment of all
enlightenment of all of
enlightenment of all of mankind.
enlightenment of all of mankind. Hinana
is
is personal
enlightenment of all of mankind. Hinana
is personal enlightenment
with
with the
with the implicit
with the implicit understanding
with the implicit understanding that
one's
one's personal
with the implicit understanding that
one's personal enlightenment
one's personal enlightenment benefits
all
all of
all of mankind
all of mankind whether
all of mankind whether by
all of mankind whether by intention
all of mankind whether by intention or
whether
whether just
all of mankind whether by intention or
whether just by
whether just by the
all of mankind whether by intention or
whether just by the quality
whether just by the quality of
all of mankind whether by intention or
whether just by the quality of that
state
state of
state of consciousness.
>> It's
>> It's a
state of consciousness.
>> It's a little
>> It's a little bit
state of consciousness.
>> It's a little bit of
>> It's a little bit of different
state of consciousness.
>> It's a little bit of different alignment
of
of conceptualization.
of conceptualization. In
of conceptualization. In reality,
of conceptualization. In reality, it's
all
all the
of conceptualization. In reality, it's
all the same.
>> I
>> I got
>> I got it.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
See,
See, the
>> Yeah.
See, the idea
See, the idea that
>> Yeah.
See, the idea that a
See, the idea that a person
>> Yeah.
See, the idea that a person can
See, the idea that a person can become
enlightened
enlightened is
enlightened is already
enlightened is already an
enlightened is already an illusion.
enlightened is already an illusion. So,
>> can
>> can you
enlightened is already an illusion. So,
>> can you sign
>> can you sign these?
>> Sure.
>> I
>> I don't
>> Sure.
>> I don't know
>> I don't know where
>> we'll
>> we'll sign
>> we'll sign anything,
>> right?
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know
>> I don't know where
>> I don't
>> I don't know where you're
>> I don't know where you're going
>> I don't
>> I don't know where you're going to
>> I don't know where you're going to sign
it.
>> I
>> I I'll
it.
>> I I'll worry
>> I I'll worry about
it.
>> I I'll worry about it.
>> It
>> It says
>> It says I
>> It says I owe
>> It says I owe you.
>> It says I owe you. Oh,
>> It says I owe you. Oh, I
>> It says I owe you. Oh, I owe
>> It says I owe you. Oh, I owe you.
>> I
>> I don't
>> It says I owe you. Oh, I owe you.
>> I don't know
>> I don't know where
>> It says I owe you. Oh, I owe you.
>> I don't know where to
>> I don't know where to sign
>> It says I owe you. Oh, I owe you.
>> I don't know where to sign it.
>> I don't know where to sign it. Let's
see.
>> That's
>> That's what
see.
>> That's what I
>> That's what I said.
>> Well,
>> Well, you
>> Well, you have
>> Well, you have me.
>> Well, you have me. You
>> Well, you have me. You have
>> Well, you have me. You have me
>> Well, you have me. You have me on
>> Well, you have me. You have me on a
predicament
predicament here.
>> Well, you have me. You have me on a
predicament here. Oh,
predicament here. Oh, yeah.
>> Well, you have me. You have me on a
predicament here. Oh, yeah. I
predicament here. Oh, yeah. I can
>> Well, you have me. You have me on a
predicament here. Oh, yeah. I can put
predicament here. Oh, yeah. I can put it
here.
I
I can
here.
I can put
I can put it
here.
I can put it here.
I can put it here. Can
here.
I can put it here. Can I
I can put it here. Can I in
here.
I can put it here. Can I in this
I can put it here. Can I in this disc?
>> No.
>> No. Any
>> No. Any any
>> No. Any any place
>> No. Any any place would
>> No. Any any place would be
>> No. Any any place would be fine.
>> Can
>> Can I
>> No. Any any place would be fine.
>> Can I put
>> Can I put it
>> No. Any any place would be fine.
>> Can I put it here?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. No,
>> Yeah. No, I
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. No, I think
>> Yeah. No, I think it'll
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. No, I think it'll it'll
>> Yeah. No, I think it'll it'll make
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. No, I think it'll it'll make it
funny
funny sound.
>> Sign
>> Sign it
funny sound.
>> Sign it right
>> Sign it right here.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you
>> Oh, you did.
>> Oh, you did. Please
>> Oh, you did. Please find
>> Oh, you did. Please find it.
>> A
>> A DVD
>> Oh, you did. Please find it.
>> A DVD is
>> A DVD is a
>> Oh, you did. Please find it.
>> A DVD is a digital
>> A DVD is a digital vict.
>> Oh, you did. Please find it.
>> A DVD is a digital vict. And
>> A DVD is a digital vict. And if
>> Oh, you did. Please find it.
>> A DVD is a digital vict. And if you
write
write on
write on it,
write on it, it
write on it, it goes
write on it, it goes rump
write on it, it goes rump rol.
When
When you
write on it, it goes rump rol.
When you play
When you play on
write on it, it goes rump rol.
When you play on the
When you play on the Victrola,
write on it, it goes rump rol.
When you play on the Victrola, it
When you play on the Victrola, it plays
back
back there.
>> Well,
>> Well, thank
back there.
>> Well, thank you
>> Well, thank you very
back there.
>> Well, thank you very much
>> Well, thank you very much for
back there.
>> Well, thank you very much for taking
questions.
questions. Uh
questions. Uh yeah,
>> I've
>> I've been
questions. Uh yeah,
>> I've been doing
>> I've been doing the
questions. Uh yeah,
>> I've been doing the course
>> I've been doing the course of
questions. Uh yeah,
>> I've been doing the course of miracles
and
and the
and the one
and the one lesson
and the one lesson that
and the one lesson that seems
and the one lesson that seems to
and the one lesson that seems to be
giving
giving me
and the one lesson that seems to be
giving me a
giving me a little
and the one lesson that seems to be
giving me a little trouble
comprehending,
comprehending, I
comprehending, I think
comprehending, I think it's
comprehending, I think it's a
comprehending, I think it's a big
comprehending, I think it's a big one,
is
is there's
comprehending, I think it's a big one,
is there's there's
is there's there's no
comprehending, I think it's a big one,
is there's there's no will
is there's there's no will but
comprehending, I think it's a big one,
is there's there's no will but God's.
And
And I'm
And I'm really
And I'm really trying
And I'm really trying to
And I'm really trying to wrap
And I'm really trying to wrap my
mind
mind around
And I'm really trying to wrap my
mind around it.
Maybe
Maybe that's
Maybe that's the
Maybe that's the wrong
Maybe that's the wrong thing
Maybe that's the wrong thing to
Maybe that's the wrong thing to do.
Well,
Well, you
Maybe that's the wrong thing to do.
Well, you could
Well, you could make
Maybe that's the wrong thing to do.
Well, you could make it
Well, you could make it easier
Maybe that's the wrong thing to do.
Well, you could make it easier to
comprehend.
comprehend. You
comprehend. You could
comprehend. You could say
comprehend. You could say there's
comprehend. You could say there's no
will
will worthy
comprehend. You could say there's no
will worthy of
will worthy of allegiance
comprehend. You could say there's no
will worthy of allegiance to
will worthy of allegiance to except
comprehend. You could say there's no
will worthy of allegiance to except the
will
will of
will of God.
will of God. You
will of God. You might
will of God. You might just
will of God. You might just say
will of God. You might just say that
will of God. You might just say that to
become
become the
will of God. You might just say that to
become the servant
become the servant of
will of God. You might just say that to
become the servant of God
become the servant of God is
will of God. You might just say that to
become the servant of God is to
become
become an
become an avenue
become an avenue of
become an avenue of God's
become an avenue of God's blessing
become an avenue of God's blessing to
become
become St.
become an avenue of God's blessing to
become St. Francis
become St. Francis of
become an avenue of God's blessing to
become St. Francis of Aises
become St. Francis of Aises uh
to
to be
to be an
to be an avenue
to
to serve
to be an avenue
to serve uh
to serve uh divinity.
to be an avenue
to serve uh divinity. Oh,
to serve uh divinity. Oh, that's
to be an avenue
to serve uh divinity. Oh, that's all
to serve uh divinity. Oh, that's all it
really
really means.
really means. Huh.
Uh
Uh the
really means. Huh.
Uh the personal
Uh the personal will
really means. Huh.
Uh the personal will of
Uh the personal will of course
really means. Huh.
Uh the personal will of course is
Uh the personal will of course is a
definition.
It's
It's really
definition.
It's really a
It's really a choice
definition.
It's really a choice or
It's really a choice or a
definition.
It's really a choice or a decision.
It's really a choice or a decision. So
you
you can
you can clarify
you can clarify it
you can clarify it by
you can clarify it by using
you can clarify it by using other
you can clarify it by using other terms.
You
You know
it's
it's intention.
What's
What's behind
it's intention.
What's behind the
What's behind the intention?
it's intention.
What's behind the intention? Desire.
What's behind the intention? Desire. Why
the
the desire?
the desire? To
the desire? To feed
the desire? To feed the
the desire? To feed the ego.
the desire? To feed the ego. Yeah.
the desire? To feed the ego. Yeah. So
it'd
it'd be
the desire? To feed the ego. Yeah. So
it'd be you
it'd be you can
the desire? To feed the ego. Yeah. So
it'd be you can you
it'd be you can you can
the desire? To feed the ego. Yeah. So
it'd be you can you can spiritual
it'd be you can you can spiritual work
is
is like
is like a
is like a sweater.
is like a sweater. You
is like a sweater. You can
is like a sweater. You can grab
is like a sweater. You can grab a
thread,
thread, a
is like a sweater. You can grab a
thread, a piece
thread, a piece of
is like a sweater. You can grab a
thread, a piece of the
thread, a piece of the yarn
is like a sweater. You can grab a
thread, a piece of the yarn anywhere
thread, a piece of the yarn anywhere and
unravel
unravel the
unravel the whole
unravel the whole sweater.
See?
>> Okay.
>> So,
>> So, when
>> Okay.
>> So, when I'm
>> So, when I'm expressing
>> Okay.
>> So, when I'm expressing my
>> So, when I'm expressing my will,
>> Okay.
>> So, when I'm expressing my will, that's
intentionality
intentionality and
intentionality and that's
>> well,
>> well, it's
intentionality and that's
>> well, it's implying
>> well, it's implying personal
intentionality and that's
>> well, it's implying personal personal.
>> That's
>> That's a
>> That's a personal
It's
It's implying
>> That's a personal
It's implying personalism.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
It's
It's also
>> Thank you.
It's also implying
It's also implying that
>> Thank you.
It's also implying that will
It's also implying that will is
>> Thank you.
It's also implying that will is the
capacity
capacity to
capacity to make
capacity to make the
capacity to make the potential
actual.
actual. The
capacity to make the potential
actual. The power
actual. The power of
capacity to make the potential
actual. The power of manifestation
actual. The power of manifestation is
only
only possible
only possible by
only possible by through
only possible by through the
only possible by through the power
only possible by through the power of
the
the will
only possible by through the power of
the will of
the will of God.
only possible by through the power of
the will of God. You
the will of God. You as
only possible by through the power of
the will of God. You as a
the will of God. You as a mortal
only possible by through the power of
the will of God. You as a mortal can
only
only choose
only choose one
only choose one option
only choose one option or
only choose one option or another.
only choose one option or another. But
your
your will
only choose one option or another. But
your will has
your will has no
only choose one option or another. But
your will has no power
your will has no power like
only choose one option or another. But
your will has no power like the
your will has no power like the will
only choose one option or another. But
your will has no power like the will of
God.
God. Yeah.
Yeah.
The
The unmanifest
The unmanifest comes
The unmanifest comes becomes
The unmanifest comes becomes manifest
because
because the
The unmanifest comes becomes manifest
because the presence
activates
activates potential
activates potential into
activates potential into actuality.
>> Okay.
>> And
>> And the
>> And the person
>> And the person personal
>> And the person personal person
>> And the person personal person takes
personal
personal credit.
>> And the person personal person takes
personal credit. It
personal credit. It says
>> And the person personal person takes
personal credit. It says I
personal credit. It says I did
>> And the person personal person takes
personal credit. It says I did that.
It's
It's like
It's like cutting
It's like cutting the
It's like cutting the apple
It's like cutting the apple from
It's like cutting the apple from the
tree
tree and
It's like cutting the apple from the
tree and saying
tree and saying I
It's like cutting the apple from the
tree and saying I made
tree and saying I made the
It's like cutting the apple from the
tree and saying I made the apple
tree and saying I made the apple fall
It's like cutting the apple from the
tree and saying I made the apple fall to
the
the ground.
the ground. You
the ground. You understand
the ground. You understand that
the ground. You understand that personal
will
will would
the ground. You understand that personal
will would be
will would be decision
the ground. You understand that personal
will would be decision that
will would be decision that I
the ground. You understand that personal
will would be decision that I made
will would be decision that I made the
apple
apple fall
apple fall to
apple fall to the
apple fall to the ground.
apple fall to the ground. It
apple fall to the ground. It falls
apple fall to the ground. It falls to
the
the ground
apple fall to the ground. It falls to
the ground by
the ground by virtue
apple fall to the ground. It falls to
the ground by virtue of
the ground by virtue of gravity
apple fall to the ground. It falls to
the ground by virtue of gravity which
would
would be
would be um
would be um parallel
would be um parallel to
would be um parallel to God
would be um parallel to God the
would be um parallel to God the will
would be um parallel to God the will of
God.
God. Yeah.
Yeah.
>> I'm
>> I'm a
Yeah.
>> I'm a student
>> I'm a student in
Yeah.
>> I'm a student in Flagstaff
>> I'm a student in Flagstaff and
Yeah.
>> I'm a student in Flagstaff and I'm
>> I'm a student in Flagstaff and I'm uh
taking
taking an
taking an introduction
taking an introduction to
taking an introduction to philosophy
class
class and
taking an introduction to philosophy
class and I
class and I have
taking an introduction to philosophy
class and I have to
class and I have to write
taking an introduction to philosophy
class and I have to write a
class and I have to write a paper
taking an introduction to philosophy
class and I have to write a paper on
class and I have to write a paper on the
meaning
meaning of
meaning of life.
>> The
>> The meaning
meaning of life.
>> The meaning of
>> The meaning of life.
meaning of life.
>> The meaning of life. Good
>> The meaning of life. Good luck.
meaning of life.
>> The meaning of life. Good luck. I'm
>> The meaning of life. Good luck. I'm glad
you
you I'm
you I'm glad
you I'm glad you
you I'm glad you started
you I'm glad you started young.
you I'm glad you started young. Yes.
>> I
>> I don't
you I'm glad you started young. Yes.
>> I don't um
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> That
>> That question
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> That question doesn't
>> That question doesn't seem
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> That question doesn't seem to
>> That question doesn't seem to have
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> That question doesn't seem to have a
point
point anymore.
>> Huh.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Meaning
>> Okay. Meaning is
>> Okay. Meaning is whatever
>> Okay. Meaning is whatever you
>> Okay. Meaning is whatever you choose
>> Okay. Meaning is whatever you choose it
to
to mean.
Meaning
Meaning is
Meaning is arbitrary.
Meaning is arbitrary. It
Meaning is arbitrary. It It
Meaning is arbitrary. It It deals
Meaning is arbitrary. It It deals with
the
the science
Meaning is arbitrary. It It deals with
the science of
the science of hermeneutics.
Yeah.
Yeah. And
Yeah. And the
Yeah. And the problem
Yeah. And the problem today
Yeah. And the problem today is
Yeah. And the problem today is the
paradox
paradox of
Yeah. And the problem today is the
paradox of distorted
paradox of distorted human
Yeah. And the problem today is the
paradox of distorted human hermeneutics
of
of relativism.
of relativism. See,
of relativism. See, that's
of relativism. See, that's why
of relativism. See, that's why you're
saying
saying now
of relativism. See, that's why you're
saying now you
saying now you don't
of relativism. See, that's why you're
saying now you don't know
saying now you don't know what
of relativism. See, that's why you're
saying now you don't know what it
saying now you don't know what it means
because
>> we're
>> we're having
because
>> we're having technical
>> we're having technical problems
because
>> we're having technical problems here.
>> The
>> The problem
sorry.
So
So meaning
So meaning then
So meaning then is
So meaning then is superimposed.
Anything
Anything means
So meaning then is superimposed.
Anything means anything
Anything means anything I
So meaning then is superimposed.
Anything means anything I decide
Anything means anything I decide for
So meaning then is superimposed.
Anything means anything I decide for it
to
to mean
to mean within
to mean within a
to mean within a certain
to mean within a certain context.
to mean within a certain context. That's
what
what Dorothy
to mean within a certain context. That's
what Dorothy was
what Dorothy was looking
to mean within a certain context. That's
what Dorothy was looking at
what Dorothy was looking at in
to mean within a certain context. That's
what Dorothy was looking at in the
Madhatter's
Madhatter's Tea
Madhatter's Tea Party.
Madhatter's Tea Party. It
Madhatter's Tea Party. It means
Madhatter's Tea Party. It means what
Madhatter's Tea Party. It means what I
mean
mean it
Madhatter's Tea Party. It means what I
mean it to
mean it to mean.
Madhatter's Tea Party. It means what I
mean it to mean. Yeah.
Higher
Higher levels
Higher levels of
Higher levels of consciousness,
Higher levels of consciousness, let's
say
say the
Higher levels of consciousness, let's
say the mid
say the mid 400s,
Higher levels of consciousness, let's
say the mid 400s, meaning
say the mid 400s, meaning is
Higher levels of consciousness, let's
say the mid 400s, meaning is pretty
say the mid 400s, meaning is pretty well
defined
defined in
defined in the
defined in the dictionary.
defined in the dictionary. It's
defined in the dictionary. It's not
defined in the dictionary. It's not just
what
what you
defined in the dictionary. It's not just
what you feel
what you feel like
defined in the dictionary. It's not just
what you feel like it
what you feel like it should
defined in the dictionary. It's not just
what you feel like it should mean.
Relativism
is
is the
Relativism
is the politicalization
is the politicalization of
Relativism
is the politicalization of that
uh
uh results
uh results in
uh results in sexism
uh results in sexism and
uh results in sexism and all
uh results in sexism and all the
uh results in sexism and all the various
isms
isms and
uh results in sexism and all the various
isms and um
results
results in
results in conflict
results in conflict and
results in conflict and ambiguity.
Now
Now a
results in conflict and ambiguity.
Now a thing
Now a thing means
results in conflict and ambiguity.
Now a thing means what
Now a thing means what it's
results in conflict and ambiguity.
Now a thing means what it's defined
Now a thing means what it's defined to
mean
mean by
mean by definition
mean by definition vocabulary.
mean by definition vocabulary. Yeah.
The
The course
mean by definition vocabulary. Yeah.
The course of
The course of miracles
mean by definition vocabulary. Yeah.
The course of miracles says
The course of miracles says nothing
mean by definition vocabulary. Yeah.
The course of miracles says nothing has
any
any meaning
any meaning except
any meaning except the
any meaning except the meaning
any meaning except the meaning I
any meaning except the meaning I give
any meaning except the meaning I give to
it.
it. Huh.
any meaning except the meaning I give to
it. Huh. including
it. Huh. including life.
>> Including
>> Including life.
>> Okay.
>> Meaning
>> Meaning is
>> Meaning is defined
>> Meaning is defined in
>> Meaning is defined in a
>> Meaning is defined in a linear
>> Meaning is defined in a linear fashion.
See,
See, and
>> Meaning is defined in a linear fashion.
See, and life
See, and life is
>> Meaning is defined in a linear fashion.
See, and life is nonlinear.
See, and life is nonlinear. So
>> Meaning is defined in a linear fashion.
See, and life is nonlinear. So to
See, and life is nonlinear. So to to
>> Meaning is defined in a linear fashion.
See, and life is nonlinear. So to to to
go
go to
go to a
go to a linear
go to a linear definition
go to a linear definition of
go to a linear definition of that
go to a linear definition of that which
is
is nonlinear
go to a linear definition of that which
is nonlinear is
is nonlinear is an
go to a linear definition of that which
is nonlinear is an is
is nonlinear is an is an
go to a linear definition of that which
is nonlinear is an is an epistemologic
impossibility.
I
I would
impossibility.
I would say
I would say it's
impossibility.
I would say it's an
I would say it's an epistemologic
impossibility.
impossibility. However,
I
I I
impossibility. However,
I I I
I I I would
impossibility. However,
I I I would guess
I I I would guess that
impossibility. However,
I I I would guess that this
I I I would guess that this is
impossibility. However,
I I I would guess that this is what
I I I would guess that this is what you
mean
mean by
mean by it.
mean by it. You
mean by it. You know,
you
you cannot
mean by it. You know,
you cannot define
you cannot define the
mean by it. You know,
you cannot define the nonlinear
you cannot define the nonlinear which
mean by it. You know,
you cannot define the nonlinear which is
life
life itself
life itself in
life itself in terms
life itself in terms of
life itself in terms of the
life itself in terms of the linear.
However,
to
to satisfy
to satisfy the
to satisfy the professor,
to satisfy the professor, you
to satisfy the professor, you you
to satisfy the professor, you you can
write
write jar,
to satisfy the professor, you you can
write jar, you
write jar, you know,
to satisfy the professor, you you can
write jar, you know, all
write jar, you know, all kinds
to satisfy the professor, you you can
write jar, you know, all kinds of
write jar, you know, all kinds of stuff.
It's
It's wonderful.
Write
Write a
It's wonderful.
Write a book
Write a book about
It's wonderful.
Write a book about the
Write a book about the meaning
It's wonderful.
Write a book about the meaning of
Write a book about the meaning of life.
Oh
Oh boy.
Just
Just think
Oh boy.
Just think what
Just think what fun
Oh boy.
Just think what fun you
Just think what fun you can
Oh boy.
Just think what fun you can have
Just think what fun you can have writing
a
a book
a book on
a book on the
a book on the meaning
a book on the meaning of
a book on the meaning of life.
a book on the meaning of life. Everybody
should
should do
a book on the meaning of life. Everybody
should do that,
should do that, right?
I
I think
I think it's
I think it's fun
I think it's fun though.
It's
It's an
I think it's fun though.
It's an intellectual
It's an intellectual exercise.
I think it's fun though.
It's an intellectual exercise. It's
It's an intellectual exercise. It's a
real
uh
uh professional
real
uh professional level.
uh professional level. It's
real
uh professional level. It's a
uh professional level. It's a real
that's
that's what
that's what academia
that's what academia is
that's what academia is really
that's what academia is really for
that's what academia is really for to
that's what academia is really for to my
mind
mind to
that's what academia is really for to my
mind to explore
mind to explore meaning
that's what academia is really for to my
mind to explore meaning and
mind to explore meaning and significance
and
and contextualization
and contextualization and
and contextualization and how
and contextualization and how it's
and contextualization and how it's been
handled
handled philosophically
and contextualization and how it's been
handled philosophically over
handled philosophically over the
and contextualization and how it's been
handled philosophically over the ages
you
you know
you know right
you know right through
you know right through the
you know right through the great
you know right through the great books
of
of the
you know right through the great books
of the western
of the western world
you know right through the great books
of the western world you
of the western world you know
you know right through the great books
of the western world you know how
of the western world you know how is
you know right through the great books
of the western world you know how is it
cited
cited by
cited by Socrates
cited by Socrates Plato
cited by Socrates Plato Aristotle
Deart
Deart Freud
>> Freud
>> it's
>> it's a
>> Freud
>> it's a fun
>> it's a fun thing
>> Freud
>> it's a fun thing so
>> it's a fun thing so you
>> Freud
>> it's a fun thing so you tell
>> it's a fun thing so you tell me
>> Freud
>> it's a fun thing so you tell me it
>> it's a fun thing so you tell me it would
take
take the
take the great
take the great books
take the great books of
take the great books of the
take the great books of the western
world
world to
take the great books of the western
world to answer
world to answer this.
>> However,
>> yeah,
>> yeah, I
>> However,
>> yeah, I know
>> yeah, I know it's
>> However,
>> yeah, I know it's interesting.
>> Well,
>> Well, we'll
>> Well, we'll see
>> Well, we'll see what
>> Well, we'll see what I
>> Well, we'll see what I come
>> Well, we'll see what I come up
>> Well, we'll see what I come up with.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Well, we'll see what I come up with.
>> Thank you. Shake
>> Thank you. Shake your
>> Well, we'll see what I come up with.
>> Thank you. Shake your hand.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, that's
>> Yes.
>> Yeah, that's a
>> Yeah, that's a fun
>> Yes.
>> Yeah, that's a fun question.
>> It's
>> It's about
>> It's about 10
>> It's about 10 to
>> It's about 10 to 4.
>> It's about 10 to 4. So,
>> we
>> we have
>> It's about 10 to 4. So,
>> we have a
>> we have a lot
>> It's about 10 to 4. So,
>> we have a lot of
>> we have a lot of people.
>> Yeah.
I
I knew
>> Yeah.
I knew the
I knew the secret
>> Yeah.
I knew the secret of
I knew the secret of the
>> Yeah.
I knew the secret of the meaning
I knew the secret of the meaning of
>> Yeah.
I knew the secret of the meaning of life
on
on the
on the way
on the way here,
on the way here, but
on the way here, but I
on the way here, but I forgot
on the way here, but I forgot it.
>> I
>> I wrote
on the way here, but I forgot it.
>> I wrote it
>> I wrote it somewhere.
on the way here, but I forgot it.
>> I wrote it somewhere. I
>> I wrote it somewhere. I don't
on the way here, but I forgot it.
>> I wrote it somewhere. I don't know
>> I wrote it somewhere. I don't know what
I
I did
I did with
I did with it.
>> I
>> I don't
I did with it.
>> I don't I
>> I don't I don't
I did with it.
>> I don't I don't have
>> I don't I don't have it.
Uh
Uh Dr.
Uh Dr. Hawkins,
Uh Dr. Hawkins, I
Uh Dr. Hawkins, I I
Uh Dr. Hawkins, I I think
Uh Dr. Hawkins, I I think I
Uh Dr. Hawkins, I I think I need
Uh Dr. Hawkins, I I think I need to
Uh Dr. Hawkins, I I think I need to have
my
my spiritual
Uh Dr. Hawkins, I I think I need to have
my spiritual compass
my spiritual compass recalibrated.
Uh Dr. Hawkins, I I think I need to have
my spiritual compass recalibrated. I
my spiritual compass recalibrated. I uh
my
my intention
my intention in
my intention in this
my intention in this lifetime
my intention in this lifetime is
uh
uh to
my intention in this lifetime is
uh to be
uh to be a
my intention in this lifetime is
uh to be a decent
uh to be a decent and
my intention in this lifetime is
uh to be a decent and harmless
uh to be a decent and harmless human
being.
>> Great.
>> Great. we
being.
>> Great. we need
>> Great. we need them.
>> And
>> And the
>> And the first
>> And the first year
>> And the first year I
>> And the first year I met
>> And the first year I met you,
>> And the first year I met you, I
>> And the first year I met you, I thought
I
I was
>> And the first year I met you, I thought
I was making
I was making great
>> And the first year I met you, I thought
I was making great progress.
I was making great progress. I
>> And the first year I met you, I thought
I was making great progress. I was
I was making great progress. I was um
>> And the first year I met you, I thought
I was making great progress. I was um I
I
I I
I I have
I I have the
I I have the joy
I I have the joy of
I I have the joy of existence
I I have the joy of existence and
I I have the joy of existence and and
I I have the joy of existence and and I
could
could see
I I have the joy of existence and and I
could see the
could see the goodness
I I have the joy of existence and and I
could see the goodness my
could see the goodness my friends
I I have the joy of existence and and I
could see the goodness my friends and
people
people around
people around me.
people around me. And
people around me. And this
people around me. And this year
people around me. And this year it's
people around me. And this year it's not
so
so good.
Well,
>> you're
>> you're getting
Well,
>> you're getting somewhere,
>> you're getting somewhere, huh?
Now
Now you're
Now you're coming
Now you're coming up
Now you're coming up with
Now you're coming up with positionality.
See,
See, because
Now you're coming up with positionality.
See, because you
See, because you rise
Now you're coming up with positionality.
See, because you rise above
See, because you rise above your
Now you're coming up with positionality.
See, because you rise above your karma
and
and then
and then your
and then your negative
and then your negative karma
and then your negative karma comes
and then your negative karma comes up
with
with catches
and then your negative karma comes up
with catches up
with catches up to
and then your negative karma comes up
with catches up to you
>> with
>> with a
>> with a vengeance.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So
>> with a vengeance.
>> Yeah. So now
>> Yeah. So now what
>> with a vengeance.
>> Yeah. So now what you're
>> Yeah. So now what you're checking
>> with a vengeance.
>> Yeah. So now what you're checking out
are
are the
are the residual
are the residual positionalities
that
that you
are the residual positionalities
that you weren't
that you weren't aware
are the residual positionalities
that you weren't aware are
that you weren't aware are playing
are the residual positionalities
that you weren't aware are playing a
part
part in
part in how
part in how you
part in how you see
part in how you see and
part in how you see and experience
part in how you see and experience the
world.
world. You
part in how you see and experience the
world. You know,
>> I
>> I mean,
>> I mean, a
>> I mean, a kindergartener
>> I mean, a kindergartener can
>> I mean, a kindergartener can be
>> I mean, a kindergartener can be happy
with
with the
>> I mean, a kindergartener can be happy
with the world.
with the world. It
>> I mean, a kindergartener can be happy
with the world. It doesn't
with the world. It doesn't mean
>> I mean, a kindergartener can be happy
with the world. It doesn't mean they're
enlightened,
enlightened, you
enlightened, you know.
>> I
>> Yeah.
seemed
seemed like
>> Yeah.
seemed like I
seemed like I was
>> Yeah.
seemed like I was headed
seemed like I was headed the
>> Yeah.
seemed like I was headed the right
direction,
direction, but
direction, but is
direction, but is it
direction, but is it is
direction, but is it is it
direction, but is it is it possible
direction, but is it is it possible to
to
to make
direction, but is it is it possible to
to make a
to make a U-turn?
direction, but is it is it possible to
to make a U-turn? Is
to make a U-turn? Is it
direction, but is it is it possible to
to make a U-turn? Is it possible
to make a U-turn? Is it possible to
direction, but is it is it possible to
to make a U-turn? Is it possible to make
a
a wrong
a wrong turn
a wrong turn if
a wrong turn if you
a wrong turn if you have
a wrong turn if you have your
a wrong turn if you have your intention
in
in mind?
>> Uh,
>> Uh, no.
>> Uh, no. It
>> Uh, no. It would
>> Uh, no. It would be
>> Uh, no. It would be a
>> Uh, no. It would be a change
>> Uh, no. It would be a change of
intention.
>> So,
>> So, no,
>> So, no, you're
>> So, no, you're flo
>> So, no, you're flo you
>> So, no, you're flo you were
>> So, no, you're flo you were floating
above
above your
>> So, no, you're flo you were floating
above your karma
above your karma and
>> So, no, you're flo you were floating
above your karma and you're
above your karma and you're feeling
happy
happy and
happy and carefree
happy and carefree and
happy and carefree and gay
happy and carefree and gay and
happy and carefree and gay and now
happy and carefree and gay and now all
of a
of a sudden
happy and carefree and gay and now all
of a sudden stuff
of a sudden stuff comes
happy and carefree and gay and now all
of a sudden stuff comes up,
>> right?
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So,
>> right?
>> Okay. So, you've
>> Okay. So, you've gotten
>> right?
>> Okay. So, you've gotten far
>> Okay. So, you've gotten far enough
>> right?
>> Okay. So, you've gotten far enough about
above
above it
above it that
above it that you
above it that you can
above it that you can now
above it that you can now handle
above it that you can now handle it.
>> Mhm.
doesn't
doesn't feel
doesn't feel like
doesn't feel like handling
doesn't feel like handling it.
doesn't feel like handling it. I
doesn't feel like handling it. I almost
almost
almost had
doesn't feel like handling it. I almost
almost had a
almost had a fight
doesn't feel like handling it. I almost
almost had a fight with
almost had a fight with a
doesn't feel like handling it. I almost
almost had a fight with a man
almost had a fight with a man over
doesn't feel like handling it. I almost
almost had a fight with a man over the
seat
seat here
seat here in
seat here in the
>> I
>> I want
seat here in the
>> I want what
>> I want what I
seat here in the
>> I want what I want
>> I want what I want when
seat here in the
>> I want what I want when I
>> I want what I want when I want
seat here in the
>> I want what I want when I want it
>> I want what I want when I want it and
seat here in the
>> I want what I want when I want it and if
I
I don't
>> especially
>> especially when
I don't
>> especially when it
>> especially when it comes
I don't
>> especially when it comes to
spirituality.
>> All
>> All right.
spirituality.
>> All right. tell
>> All right. tell you.
>> So,
>> So, it
>> So, it was
>> So, it was a
>> So, it was a lecture
>> So, it was a lecture we
>> So, it was a lecture we were
>> So, it was a lecture we were talking
about
about that
>> So, it was a lecture we were talking
about that I
about that I we
>> So, it was a lecture we were talking
about that I we can
about that I we can see
>> So, it was a lecture we were talking
about that I we can see how
about that I we can see how it
>> So, it was a lecture we were talking
about that I we can see how it it
about that I we can see how it it wants
to
to have
to have its
to have its way,
>> right?
>> And
>> And it
>> And it takes
>> And it takes it
>> And it takes it so
>> And it takes it so seriously.
>> And it takes it so seriously. God,
>> And it takes it so seriously. God, it
takes
takes it
>> And it takes it so seriously. God, it
takes it so
takes it so seriously.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Yeah. And it's
>> Yeah. And it's and
>> Yeah. And it's and it's
>> Yeah. And it's and it's ugly
>> Yeah. And it's and it's ugly and
frightening.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, it
>> Oh, it isn't
>> Oh, it isn't ugly
>> Oh, it isn't ugly and
>> Oh, it isn't ugly and frightening.
>> Oh, it isn't ugly and frightening. It's
just
just the
>> Oh, it isn't ugly and frightening. It's
just the animal.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
>> So, I'm
>> Yeah.
>> So, I'm still
>> So, I'm still okay.
>> You're
>> You're all right.
Yeah.
Yeah. The
>> You're all right.
Yeah. The dark
Yeah. The dark night
>> You're all right.
Yeah. The dark night of
Yeah. The dark night of the
>> You're all right.
Yeah. The dark night of the soul,
Yeah. The dark night of the soul, huh?
Happens
Happens to
Happens to the
Happens to the greatest
Happens to the greatest saints.
Happens to the greatest saints. Oh,
Happens to the greatest saints. Oh, my
beloved,
beloved, why
Happens to the greatest saints. Oh, my
beloved, why hast
beloved, why hast thou
Happens to the greatest saints. Oh, my
beloved, why hast thou forsaken
beloved, why hast thou forsaken me?
I
I am
I am so
I am so grateful
I am so grateful to
I am so grateful to be
I am so grateful to be in
I am so grateful to be in your
I am so grateful to be in your presence
and
and I
I am so grateful to be in your presence
and I have
and I have a
I am so grateful to be in your presence
and I have a continuation
and I have a continuation of
I am so grateful to be in your presence
and I have a continuation of his
question.
question. I
question. I have
question. I have a
question. I have a feeling.
question. I have a feeling. Um
I
I know
question. I have a feeling. Um
I know you've
I know you've been
question. I have a feeling. Um
I know you've been answering
I know you've been answering this
question
question all
question all day,
question all day, so
question all day, so forgive
question all day, so forgive me
question all day, so forgive me if
question all day, so forgive me if I
have
have to
question all day, so forgive me if I
have to ask
have to ask it
question all day, so forgive me if I
have to ask it one
have to ask it one more
question all day, so forgive me if I
have to ask it one more time.
At
At your
At your last
At your last lecture,
At your last lecture, you
At your last lecture, you talked
At your last lecture, you talked a
At your last lecture, you talked a lot
about
about the
At your last lecture, you talked a lot
about the need
about the need for
At your last lecture, you talked a lot
about the need for spiritual
about the need for spiritual courage.
And
And I
And I think
And I think it
And I think it triggered
And I think it triggered in
And I think it triggered in me
And I think it triggered in me a
spiritual
spiritual crisis
And I think it triggered in me a
spiritual crisis that's
spiritual crisis that's manifested
And I think it triggered in me a
spiritual crisis that's manifested by
having
having absolutely
having absolutely no
having absolutely no ability
having absolutely no ability to
having absolutely no ability to sleep
having absolutely no ability to sleep in
the
the last
having absolutely no ability to sleep in
the last seven
the last seven weeks
having absolutely no ability to sleep in
the last seven weeks without
the last seven weeks without sleep
having absolutely no ability to sleep in
the last seven weeks without sleep aids.
There's
There's this
There's this vibrational
There's this vibrational energy
There's this vibrational energy that
There's this vibrational energy that is
enormous.
And
And I
And I have
And I have not
And I have not resisted.
And I have not resisted. I
And I have not resisted. I have
And I have not resisted. I have looked
at
at this
And I have not resisted. I have looked
at this as
at this as a
And I have not resisted. I have looked
at this as a teacher
at this as a teacher and
And I have not resisted. I have looked
at this as a teacher and as
at this as a teacher and as um
>> good
>> good yeah
>> a
>> a learning
>> good yeah
>> a learning experience
>> a learning experience and
>> good yeah
>> a learning experience and have
>> a learning experience and have had
>> good yeah
>> a learning experience and have had a
>> a learning experience and have had a lot
of
of insights
of insights from
of insights from it
of insights from it and
of insights from it and a
of insights from it and a few
of insights from it and a few freakouts
but
but mostly
of insights from it and a few freakouts
but mostly insights
>> and
>> and I
>> and I see
>> and I see a
>> and I see a pattern
that
that I
>> and I see a pattern
that I believe
that I believe has
>> and I see a pattern
that I believe has spanned
that I believe has spanned multiple
lifetimes
lifetimes in
lifetimes in this
lifetimes in this inability
lifetimes in this inability to
lifetimes in this inability to surrender
in
in a
lifetimes in this inability to surrender
in a spiritual
in a spiritual sense.
lifetimes in this inability to surrender
in a spiritual sense. I
in a spiritual sense. I can't
lifetimes in this inability to surrender
in a spiritual sense. I can't even
surrender
surrender to
surrender to sleep
surrender to sleep right
surrender to sleep right now.
I
I look
surrender to sleep right now.
I look in
I look in my
surrender to sleep right now.
I look in my life
I look in my life for
surrender to sleep right now.
I look in my life for where
I look in my life for where this
surrender to sleep right now.
I look in my life for where this could
have
have occurred
and
and this
have occurred
and this may
and this may be
have occurred
and this may be baloney
and this may be baloney but
have occurred
and this may be baloney but my
and this may be baloney but my sense
have occurred
and this may be baloney but my sense is
this
this is
this is a
this is a real
this is a real old
this is a real old one
this is a real old one where
this is a real old one where out
this is a real old one where out of
spiritual
spiritual arrogance
this is a real old one where out of
spiritual arrogance I
spiritual arrogance I jumped
this is a real old one where out of
spiritual arrogance I jumped too
spiritual arrogance I jumped too quickly
and
and couldn't
and couldn't get
and couldn't get back
and couldn't get back to
and couldn't get back to myself.
So
So my
and couldn't get back to myself.
So my question
So my question is
and couldn't get back to myself.
So my question is how
So my question is how how
and couldn't get back to myself.
So my question is how how does
So my question is how how does one
and couldn't get back to myself.
So my question is how how does one heal
a
a spiritual
a spiritual misperception
a spiritual misperception if
a spiritual misperception if that's
a spiritual misperception if that's what
it
it is?
>> Oh
>> Oh it's
>> Oh it's a
>> Oh it's a contextualization.
Um
Um you've
>> Oh it's a contextualization.
Um you've called
Um you've called it
>> Oh it's a contextualization.
Um you've called it what
Um you've called it what you
>> Oh it's a contextualization.
Um you've called it what you described
it
it as.
What
What if
it as.
What if you
What if you don't
it as.
What if you don't call
What if you don't call it
it as.
What if you don't call it anything?
What if you don't call it anything? Then
what
what is
what is it?
>> Lots
>> Lots of
what is it?
>> Lots of energy.
>> Lots of energy. Mhm.
>> Lots
>> Lots of
>> Lots of energy.
>> Yeah.
So,
So, what
So, what do
So, what do you
So, what do you do
So, what do you do with
So, what do you do with all
So, what do you do with all that
So, what do you do with all that energy?
You
You clean
So, what do you do with all that energy?
You clean the
You clean the house
So, what do you do with all that energy?
You clean the house at
You clean the house at midnight.
>> That's
>> That's a
>> That's a good
>> That's a good idea.
>> That's a good idea. That's
>> That's a good idea. That's a
>> That's a good idea. That's a good
>> That's a good idea. That's a good idea.
No,
No, you
>> That's a good idea. That's a good idea.
No, you uncor
No, you uncor uh
you
you unccor
you unccor areas
you unccor areas of
you unccor areas of uh
you unccor areas of uh enormous
you unccor areas of uh enormous energy
and
and they
you unccor areas of uh enormous energy
and they become
and they become liberated.
you unccor areas of uh enormous energy
and they become liberated. Yes.
and they become liberated. Yes. I
wouldn't
wouldn't worry
wouldn't worry about
wouldn't worry about it.
wouldn't worry about it. It
wouldn't worry about it. It fluctuates.
You
You know,
wouldn't worry about it. It fluctuates.
You know, it's
You know, it's that
wouldn't worry about it. It fluctuates.
You know, it's that period
You know, it's that period where
wouldn't worry about it. It fluctuates.
You know, it's that period where you're
exhausted
exhausted for
exhausted for six
exhausted for six months
exhausted for six months and
exhausted for six months and can't
hardly
hardly get
exhausted for six months and can't
hardly get out
hardly get out of
exhausted for six months and can't
hardly get out of bed.
hardly get out of bed. But
>> so
>> so what
>> you
>> you can
>> so what
>> you can look
>> you can look in
>> so what
>> you can look in the
>> you can look in the encyclopedia
botanical
botanical mystics
interesting
what
what their
what their experiences
what their experiences were.
Encyclopedia
Encyclopedia Bratannica
what their experiences were.
Encyclopedia Bratannica mystics
mysticism.
>> I
>> I will
mysticism.
>> I will thank
>> I will thank you.
mysticism.
>> I will thank you. The
>> I will thank you. The experience
mysticism.
>> I will thank you. The experience of
>> I will thank you. The experience of all
the
the great
the great famous
the great famous mystics
the great famous mystics throughout
time.
Take
Take to
Take to your
Take to your bed
Take to your bed six
Take to your bed six months
Take to your bed six months out
Take to your bed six months out of
Take to your bed six months out of the
year
year says
be
be prepared
be prepared for
be prepared for aches
be prepared for aches and
be prepared for aches and pains.
Be
Be prepared
be prepared for aches and pains.
Be prepared for
Be prepared for strange
be prepared for aches and pains.
Be prepared for strange phenomena.
>> Yeah.
>> Microphone
>> Microphone is
>> Yeah.
>> Microphone is out
>> Microphone is out of
>> Yeah.
>> Microphone is out of the
>> Microphone is out of the way
>> Yeah.
>> Microphone is out of the way there.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Go
>> Yes. Go ahead.
>> First,
>> First, I
>> Yes. Go ahead.
>> First, I wanted
>> First, I wanted to
>> Yes. Go ahead.
>> First, I wanted to thank
>> First, I wanted to thank you
>> Yes. Go ahead.
>> First, I wanted to thank you both
>> First, I wanted to thank you both for
your
your lives
your lives and
your lives and for
your lives and for your
your lives and for your work.
Yes.
>> Um,
>> Um, this
>> Um, this question
>> Um, this question is
>> Um, this question is about
>> Um, this question is about kundalini
energy.
>> Yes.
>> I
>> I know
>> Yes.
>> I know that
>> I know that one
>> Yes.
>> I know that one is
>> I know that one is never
>> Yes.
>> I know that one is never supposed
>> I know that one is never supposed to
force
force it.
force it. Um,
force it. Um, but
force it. Um, but is
force it. Um, but is there
force it. Um, but is there ever
force it. Um, but is there ever a
force it. Um, but is there ever a reason
to
to direct
force it. Um, but is there ever a reason
to direct or
to direct or redirect
force it. Um, but is there ever a reason
to direct or redirect kundalini
to direct or redirect kundalini energy
or
or can
or can one
or can one allow
or can one allow it
or can one allow it to
or can one allow it to do
or can one allow it to do its
or can one allow it to do its thing
or can one allow it to do its thing on
its
its own?
>> I
>> I believe
>> I believe to
>> I believe to allow
>> I believe to allow it
>> I believe to allow it to
>> I believe to allow it to flow
>> I believe to allow it to flow on
>> I believe to allow it to flow on its
own.
own. There
>> I believe to allow it to flow on its
own. There are
own. There are simple
>> I believe to allow it to flow on its
own. There are simple breathing
exercises
exercises where
exercises where you
exercises where you picture
exercises where you picture the
condolini
condolini energy
exercises where you picture the
condolini energy moving
condolini energy moving up
exercises where you picture the
condolini energy moving up the
the
the sit
the sit the
the sit the two
the sit the two channels
the sit the two channels along
the sit the two channels along the
the sit the two channels along the spine
into
into the
the sit the two channels along the spine
into the various
into the various chakras
the sit the two channels along the spine
into the various chakras and
into the various chakras and breathing
it
it up
it up to
it up to the
it up to the crown
it up to the crown chakra.
it up to the crown chakra. That's
it up to the crown chakra. That's about
as
as far
it up to the crown chakra. That's about
as far as
as far as I'd
it up to the crown chakra. That's about
as far as I'd go
as far as I'd go with
it up to the crown chakra. That's about
as far as I'd go with it.
>> But
>> But does
>> But does one
>> But does one have
>> But does one have to
>> But does one have to do
>> But does one have to do even
>> But does one have to do even that?
>> But does one have to do even that? I
mean
>> uh
>> uh one
>> uh one doesn't
>> uh one doesn't have
>> uh one doesn't have to.
>> uh one doesn't have to. No.
However,
However, that's
>> uh one doesn't have to. No.
However, that's a
However, that's a classic
>> uh one doesn't have to. No.
However, that's a classic yoga
However, that's a classic yoga practice
to
to picture
to picture this
to picture this energy
to picture this energy flowing
to picture this energy flowing up
to picture this energy flowing up like
white
white light
to picture this energy flowing up like
white light up
white light up your
to picture this energy flowing up like
white light up your spine
white light up your spine and
to picture this energy flowing up like
white light up your spine and up
white light up your spine and up to
to picture this energy flowing up like
white light up your spine and up to the
crown
crown chakra.
crown chakra. Huh?
crown chakra. Huh? You
crown chakra. Huh? You ever
crown chakra. Huh? You ever read
crown chakra. Huh? You ever read Guppy
Krishna?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Part
>> Yes. Part of
>> Yeah.
>> kind
>> kind of
>> kind of scary.
>> So,
>> So, you
>> kind of scary.
>> So, you can
>> So, you can see
>> kind of scary.
>> So, you can see just
>> So, you can see just doing
>> kind of scary.
>> So, you can see just doing it
willy-nilly.
willy-nilly. You
willy-nilly. You know what
willy-nilly. You know what I
willy-nilly. You know what I mean?
willy-nilly. You know what I mean? Went
up
up what
willy-nilly. You know what I mean? Went
up what one
up what one side
willy-nilly. You know what I mean? Went
up what one side of
up what one side of his
willy-nilly. You know what I mean? Went
up what one side of his brain
up what one side of his brain but
willy-nilly. You know what I mean? Went
up what one side of his brain but not
the
the other,
the other, right?
>> He
>> He walked
the other, right?
>> He walked lopsided
>> He walked lopsided for
the other, right?
>> He walked lopsided for 20
>> He walked lopsided for 20 years
the other, right?
>> He walked lopsided for 20 years or
whatever
whatever it
whatever it was.
That
That was
whatever it was.
That was unusual.
That was unusual. That
whatever it was.
That was unusual. That was
That was unusual. That was unusual.
I've
I've been
I've been the
I've been the reason
I've been the reason that
I've been the reason that I
I've been the reason that I ask
I've been the reason that I ask is
I've been the reason that I ask is I've
been
been told
I've been the reason that I ask is I've
been told um
been told um to
I've been the reason that I ask is I've
been told um to do
been told um to do that
I've been the reason that I ask is I've
been told um to do that and
been told um to do that and to
I've been the reason that I ask is I've
been told um to do that and to the
been told um to do that and to the heart
chakra
chakra otherwise
chakra otherwise one
chakra otherwise one could
chakra otherwise one could end
chakra otherwise one could end up
chakra otherwise one could end up in
Gopi
Gopi Krishna's
chakra otherwise one could end up in
Gopi Krishna's position
>> Gopi
>> Gopi Krishna
>> Gopi Krishna is
>> Gopi Krishna is extremely
>> Gopi Krishna is extremely rare
>> Gopi Krishna is extremely rare case
>> Gopi Krishna is extremely rare case and
probably
probably had
>> Gopi Krishna is extremely rare case and
probably had karmic
uh
uh karmic
uh karmic components
uh karmic components which
uh karmic components which were
uh karmic components which were unusual
you
you know
>> okay
>> okay thank
>> okay thank you
>> yeah
>> yeah I
>> okay thank you
>> yeah I wouldn't
>> yeah I wouldn't worry
>> okay thank you
>> yeah I wouldn't worry about
>> yeah I wouldn't worry about it
>> okay
>> you
>> you see
>> okay
>> you see to
>> you see to be
>> okay
>> you see to be as
>> you see to be as loving
>> okay
>> you see to be as loving as
>> you see to be as loving as you
>> okay
>> you see to be as loving as you can
towards
towards all
towards all of
towards all of life.
towards all of life. People
towards all of life. People say,
towards all of life. People say, "If
towards all of life. People say, "If I
was
was going
towards all of life. People say, "If I
was going to
was going to do
towards all of life. People say, "If I
was going to do just
was going to do just one
towards all of life. People say, "If I
was going to do just one spiritual
practice,
practice, what
practice, what would
practice, what would I
practice, what would I do?"
practice, what would I do?" I
practice, what would I do?" I would
practice, what would I do?" I would try
to
to be
practice, what would I do?" I would try
to be kind
to be kind and
practice, what would I do?" I would try
to be kind and loving
to be kind and loving and
practice, what would I do?" I would try
to be kind and loving and considerate
and
and thoughtful
and thoughtful of
and thoughtful of all
and thoughtful of all of
and thoughtful of all of life,
and thoughtful of all of life, no
and thoughtful of all of life, no matter
what.
what. Period.
and thoughtful of all of life, no matter
what. Period. You
what. Period. You see
and thoughtful of all of life, no matter
what. Period. You see the
what. Period. You see the incredible
beauty
beauty of
beauty of this.
beauty of this. I
beauty of this. I mean,
beauty of this. I mean, you
beauty of this. I mean, you see
beauty of this. I mean, you see the
incredible
incredible beauty
beauty of this. I mean, you see the
incredible beauty of
incredible beauty of everything
beauty of this. I mean, you see the
incredible beauty of everything that
exists.
exists. Yeah.
And
And that's
exists. Yeah.
And that's loving
And that's loving it.
exists. Yeah.
And that's loving it. To
And that's loving it. To love
exists. Yeah.
And that's loving it. To love a
And that's loving it. To love a thing
exists. Yeah.
And that's loving it. To love a thing is
to
to see
to see its
to see its beauty.
to see its beauty. Yeah.
And
And you
to see its beauty. Yeah.
And you look
And you look at
to see its beauty. Yeah.
And you look at the
And you look at the trees
to see its beauty. Yeah.
And you look at the trees that
And you look at the trees that they
to see its beauty. Yeah.
And you look at the trees that they want
to
to chop
to chop down.
to chop down. It
to chop down. It outrages
to chop down. It outrages me
to chop down. It outrages me all
to chop down. It outrages me all the
time.
time. You'll
to chop down. It outrages me all the
time. You'll see
time. You'll see there's
to chop down. It outrages me all the
time. You'll see there's a
time. You'll see there's a dead
to chop down. It outrages me all the
time. You'll see there's a dead tree.
time. You'll see there's a dead tree. We
better
better cut
better cut it
better cut it down.
better cut it down. Why
better cut it down. Why should
better cut it down. Why should we
better cut it down. Why should we cut
better cut it down. Why should we cut it
down?
down? Because
better cut it down. Why should we cut it
down? Because it's
down? Because it's dead.
Here's
Here's this
Here's this incredible
Here's this incredible piece
Here's this incredible piece of
sculpture.
Incredibly,
Incredibly, magnificently
Incredibly, magnificently beautiful.
Incredibly, magnificently beautiful. And
they
they want
Incredibly, magnificently beautiful. And
they want to
they want to chop
Incredibly, magnificently beautiful. And
they want to chop it
they want to chop it down.
Well,
thank
thank you.
>> Yeah.
I
I hope
>> Yeah.
I hope the
I hope the sound
>> Yeah.
I hope the sound is
I hope the sound is coming
>> Yeah.
I hope the sound is coming through
correctly
correctly now.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, they
correctly now.
>> Yes, they had
>> Yes, they had a
correctly now.
>> Yes, they had a buzz.
>> Yes, they had a buzz. The
correctly now.
>> Yes, they had a buzz. The wire
>> Well,
>> Well, there
>> Well, there was
>> Well, there was a
>> Well, there was a shirt
>> Well, there was a shirt buzz.
>> Well, there was a shirt buzz. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. I
>> Well, there was a shirt buzz. Yes.
>> Yes. I met
>> Yes. I met you
>> Well, there was a shirt buzz. Yes.
>> Yes. I met you last
>> Yes. I met you last year
>> Well, there was a shirt buzz. Yes.
>> Yes. I met you last year in
>> Yes. I met you last year in Seattle
>> Well, there was a shirt buzz. Yes.
>> Yes. I met you last year in Seattle and
for
for some
for some reason
for some reason I
for some reason I I
for some reason I I was
for some reason I I was compelled
for some reason I I was compelled to
come
come see
for some reason I I was compelled to
come see you.
come see you. I
for some reason I I was compelled to
come see you. I don't
come see you. I don't know
for some reason I I was compelled to
come see you. I don't know why.
>> I
>> I I
>> I I don't
>> I I don't understand
>> I I don't understand why.
He
He was
>> I I don't understand why.
He was compelled
He was compelled to
>> I I don't understand why.
He was compelled to come
He was compelled to come and
>> I I don't understand why.
He was compelled to come and see
He was compelled to come and see you
>> I I don't understand why.
He was compelled to come and see you and
he
he was
>> God
>> God loves
he was
>> God loves you.
>> God loves you. That's
he was
>> God loves you. That's why
>> God loves you. That's why I
he was
>> God loves you. That's why I guess
yeah
see
see you
yeah
see you find
see you find what
yeah
see you find what you
see you find what you seek.
It's
It's because
It's because you're
It's because you're seeking
It's because you're seeking for
It's because you're seeking for it.
It's because you're seeking for it. You
found
found it.
It's because you're seeking for it. You
found it. You
found it. You find
It's because you're seeking for it. You
found it. You find it.
found it. You find it. You
It's because you're seeking for it. You
found it. You find it. You know,
well,
well, you
well, you only
well, you only see
well, you only see in
well, you only see in my
well, you only see in my eyes
well, you only see in my eyes what
well, you only see in my eyes what is
actually
actually you.
Doesn't
Doesn't come
Doesn't come from
Doesn't come from me.
Doesn't come from me. It
Doesn't come from me. It comes
Doesn't come from me. It comes from
Doesn't come from me. It comes from you.
You
You see
Doesn't come from me. It comes from you.
You see yourself
reflected
reflected back.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
Yes.
>> My
>> My question
Yes.
>> My question is
>> My question is uh
Yes.
>> My question is uh if
>> My question is uh if the
Yes.
>> My question is uh if the mind
>> My question is uh if the mind can't
differentiate
differentiate between
differentiate between truth
differentiate between truth and
falsehood,
falsehood, then
differentiate between truth and
falsehood, then how
falsehood, then how do
differentiate between truth and
falsehood, then how do you
falsehood, then how do you know
differentiate between truth and
falsehood, then how do you know you're
progressing?
>> Well,
>> Well, the
progressing?
>> Well, the how
>> Well, the how you're
progressing?
>> Well, the how you're progressing
>> Well, the how you're progressing is
progressing?
>> Well, the how you're progressing is not
a
a consequence
a consequence of
a consequence of mentalization
a consequence of mentalization or
thinkingness.
Uh
Uh it's
Uh it's a
Uh it's a matter
Uh it's a matter of
Uh it's a matter of knowingness
which
which is
Uh it's a matter of knowingness
which is nonlinear.
You
You can
You can tell
You can tell when
You can tell when you're
You can tell when you're making
spiritual
spiritual progress
You can tell when you're making
spiritual progress and
spiritual progress and when
You can tell when you're making
spiritual progress and when you're
stuck.
stuck. You
stuck. You don't
stuck. You don't have
stuck. You don't have to
stuck. You don't have to think
stuck. You don't have to think about
stuck. You don't have to think about it.
>> The
>> The reason
stuck. You don't have to think about it.
>> The reason I
>> The reason I ask
>> it's
>> it's just
>> it's just sort
>> it's just sort of
>> it's just sort of intuitive
>> it's just sort of intuitive knowing
this.
this. You
>> it's just sort of intuitive knowing
this. You know
>> the
>> the reason
>> the reason I
>> the reason I ask
>> the reason I ask is
>> the reason I ask is because
>> the reason I ask is because sometimes
>> the reason I ask is because sometimes I
feel
feel like
>> the reason I ask is because sometimes I
feel like I'm
feel like I'm really
>> the reason I ask is because sometimes I
feel like I'm really progressing
feel like I'm really progressing and
then
then other
then other times
then other times I
then other times I feel
then other times I feel like
then other times I feel like I'm
then other times I feel like I'm going
backwards.
>> No
>> No backward.
>> No backward. The
>> No backward. The only
>> No backward. The only way
>> No backward. The only way to
>> No backward. The only way to go
backwards
backwards would
>> No backward. The only way to go
backwards would be
backwards would be to
>> No backward. The only way to go
backwards would be to refute
backwards would be to refute one's
intention
intention and
intention and deni
intention and deni deny
intention and deni deny the
intention and deni deny the reality
intention and deni deny the reality of
divinity.
No,
No, because
No, because once
No, because once you
No, because once you set
No, because once you set your
No, because once you set your compass,
the
the spiritual
No, because once you set your compass,
the spiritual will
the spiritual will sets
No, because once you set your compass,
the spiritual will sets the
the spiritual will sets the compass.
No, because once you set your compass,
the spiritual will sets the compass. Now
you're
you're at
you're at sea.
you're at sea. You've
you're at sea. You've already
you're at sea. You've already set
you're at sea. You've already set your
destination.
destination. Now
you're at sea. You've already set your
destination. Now the
destination. Now the waves
you're at sea. You've already set your
destination. Now the waves and
destination. Now the waves and the
you're at sea. You've already set your
destination. Now the waves and the wind
will
will come.
will come. You
will come. You see?
will come. You see? And
will come. You see? And so
will come. You see? And so every
will come. You see? And so every little
fluctuation
fluctuation in
will come. You see? And so every little
fluctuation in mood
fluctuation in mood and
will come. You see? And so every little
fluctuation in mood and emotion
fluctuation in mood and emotion and
will come. You see? And so every little
fluctuation in mood and emotion and all
doesn't
doesn't mean
doesn't mean you've
doesn't mean you've changed
doesn't mean you've changed the
doesn't mean you've changed the compass.
If
If you
doesn't mean you've changed the compass.
If you change
If you change the
doesn't mean you've changed the compass.
If you change the compass,
If you change the compass, you'll
doesn't mean you've changed the compass.
If you change the compass, you'll know
that
that you've
that you've made
that you've made a
that you've made a major
that you've made a major spiritual
decision.
decision. There
that you've made a major spiritual
decision. There won't
decision. There won't be
that you've made a major spiritual
decision. There won't be any
decision. There won't be any question
about
about it.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Mhm.
I
I think
>> Mhm.
I think you've
I think you've really
>> Mhm.
I think you've really already
I think you've really already answered
this
this question,
this question, but
this question, but I
this question, but I want
this question, but I want to
this question, but I want to ask
this question, but I want to ask it
anyway.
anyway. When
this question, but I want to ask it
anyway. When one
anyway. When one understands
um
um to
um to surrender
um to surrender to
uh
uh one's
um to surrender to
uh one's experiencer
um
um is
um is there
um is there a
um is there a way
um is there a way to
um is there a way to differentiate
whether
whether that
um is there a way to differentiate
whether that understanding
whether that understanding comes
um is there a way to differentiate
whether that understanding comes from
desire
desire of
desire of the
desire of the ego
desire of the ego or
desire of the ego or true
desire of the ego or true intuition?
>> Intuition
>> Intuition is
desire of the ego or true intuition?
>> Intuition is like
>> Intuition is like um
desire of the ego or true intuition?
>> Intuition is like um yin
>> Intuition is like um yin experience.
desire of the ego or true intuition?
>> Intuition is like um yin experience. it
comes
comes to
comes to you.
Um,
experiencing
experiencing is
experiencing is of
experiencing is of a
experiencing is of a this
experiencing is of a this of
experiencing is of a this of a
experiencing is of a this of a that.
Spiritual
Spiritual reality
experiencing is of a this of a that.
Spiritual reality has
Spiritual reality has neither
experiencing is of a this of a that.
Spiritual reality has neither subject
nor
nor object.
nor object. It's
nor object. It's just
nor object. It's just what
nor object. It's just what one
nor object. It's just what one is.
>> And
>> And if
nor object. It's just what one is.
>> And if what
>> And if what is
is
>> desire
>> desire of
is
>> desire of surrendering
>> desire of surrendering rather
I'm
I'm confused
I'm confused there.
>> Well,
>> Well, what
I'm confused there.
>> Well, what one
>> Well, what one is
I'm confused there.
>> Well, what one is is
>> Well, what one is is a
I'm confused there.
>> Well, what one is is a person
>> Well, what one is is a person who
I'm confused there.
>> Well, what one is is a person who is
spiritually
spiritually oriented
and
and then
spiritually oriented
and then thinkingness
and then thinkingness would
spiritually oriented
and then thinkingness would try
and then thinkingness would try to
decide
decide where
decide where you
decide where you are
decide where you are with
decide where you are with that
decide where you are with that progress.
The
The only
decide where you are with that progress.
The only uh
The only uh consideration
decide where you are with that progress.
The only uh consideration the
The only uh consideration the only
decide where you are with that progress.
The only uh consideration the only thing
you
you have
you have to
you have to to
you have to to decide
you have to to decide is
you have to to decide is the
you have to to decide is the setting
you have to to decide is the setting of
the
the compass.
you have to to decide is the setting of
the compass. That's
the compass. That's all
you have to to decide is the setting of
the compass. That's all you
the compass. That's all you got
you have to to decide is the setting of
the compass. That's all you got to
decide.
decide. Then
decide. Then the
decide. Then the boat
decide. Then the boat goes
decide. Then the boat goes this
decide. Then the boat goes this way,
decide. Then the boat goes this way, you
turn
turn the
decide. Then the boat goes this way, you
turn the wheel
turn the wheel a
decide. Then the boat goes this way, you
turn the wheel a little
turn the wheel a little bit
decide. Then the boat goes this way, you
turn the wheel a little bit this
turn the wheel a little bit this way.
And
And then
And then it
And then it comes
And then it comes this
And then it comes this way.
And then it comes this way. You
And then it comes this way. You turn
And then it comes this way. You turn the
wheel
wheel a
And then it comes this way. You turn the
wheel a little
wheel a little bit
And then it comes this way. You turn the
wheel a little bit this
wheel a little bit this way.
And then it comes this way. You turn the
wheel a little bit this way. I
wheel a little bit this way. I once
sailed
sailed the
sailed the ship
sailed the ship through
sailed the ship through a
sailed the ship through a three-day
typhoon
and
and it
and it would
and it would hit
you
you just
and it would hit
you just quartered
you just quartered into
and it would hit
you just quartered into the
you just quartered into the wave.
and it would hit
you just quartered into the wave. Too
much
much this
much this way,
much this way, you
much this way, you begin
much this way, you begin to
much this way, you begin to roll
much this way, you begin to roll over.
Too
Too much
much this way, you begin to roll over.
Too much into
Too much into the
much this way, you begin to roll over.
Too much into the wind,
Too much into the wind, you
much this way, you begin to roll over.
Too much into the wind, you blew
sideways.
So
So the
sideways.
So the spiritual
So the spiritual work
sideways.
So the spiritual work is
So the spiritual work is just
sideways.
So the spiritual work is just constantly
uh
uh correcting
uh correcting the
uh correcting the wheel.
uh correcting the wheel. Just
uh correcting the wheel. Just like
uh correcting the wheel. Just like when
you're
you're driving
uh correcting the wheel. Just like when
you're driving a
you're driving a car,
uh correcting the wheel. Just like when
you're driving a car, you
you're driving a car, you know,
uh correcting the wheel. Just like when
you're driving a car, you know, you're
constantly
constantly making
constantly making little
constantly making little corrections
constantly making little corrections in
the
the car,
constantly making little corrections in
the car, but
the car, but you
constantly making little corrections in
the car, but you haven't
the car, but you haven't changed
constantly making little corrections in
the car, but you haven't changed your
destination,
>> right?
>> right? Thanks.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Um,
>> Um, please
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Um, please stick
>> Um, please stick to
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Um, please stick to one
>> Um, please stick to one question,
please.
please. One
please. One question.
>> Hi.
>> Time
>> Time to
>> Time to sign
>> Time to sign your
>> Time to sign your books
>> Time to sign your books at
>> Time to sign your books at home.
>> Sign
>> Sign that.
>> Time to sign your books at home.
>> Sign that. Okay.
>> You
>> You bet.
>> You bet. This
>> You bet. This is
>> You bet. This is a
>> You bet. This is a big
>> You bet. This is a big opportunity
because
because I
>> You bet. This is a big opportunity
because I come
because I come from
>> You bet. This is a big opportunity
because I come from the
because I come from the Toronto
>> You bet. This is a big opportunity
because I come from the Toronto area
because I come from the Toronto area and
I've
I've read
I've read your
I've read your books
I've read your books and
>> Oh,
>> Oh, Toronto.
I've read your books and
>> Oh, Toronto. Yes.
>> Today
>> Today was
>> Today was really
>> Today was really on
>> Today was really on target
>> Today was really on target for
>> Today was really on target for what
>> Today was really on target for what I
was
was needing
>> Today was really on target for what I
was needing to
was needing to hear.
>> Today was really on target for what I
was needing to hear. My
was needing to hear. My one
>> Today was really on target for what I
was needing to hear. My one question
was needing to hear. My one question is
uh
how
how does
uh
how does one
how does one connect
uh
how does one connect more
how does one connect more not
uh
how does one connect more not with
how does one connect more not with ego
because
because it
because it can
because it can do
because it can do nothing
because it can do nothing with
because it can do nothing with spiritual
will
will and
because it can do nothing with spiritual
will and grace
will and grace to
because it can do nothing with spiritual
will and grace to pull
will and grace to pull us
because it can do nothing with spiritual
will and grace to pull us further
will and grace to pull us further uh
because it can do nothing with spiritual
will and grace to pull us further uh to
spend
spend more
spend more yin
spend more yin time
spend more yin time in
spend more yin time in the
spend more yin time in the presence
spend more yin time in the presence and
to
to be
spend more yin time in the presence and
to be drawn
to be drawn further
spend more yin time in the presence and
to be drawn further since
to be drawn further since the
spend more yin time in the presence and
to be drawn further since the ego
to be drawn further since the ego can
spend more yin time in the presence and
to be drawn further since the ego can do
nothing.
nothing. How
nothing. How do
nothing. How do we
>> well
>> well just
nothing. How do we
>> well just pray
>> I
>> I guess
>> I guess it's
>> I guess it's intentionality
>> I guess it's intentionality and
>> intentionality
>> intentionality prayer
>> I guess it's intentionality and
>> intentionality prayer prayer
>> intentionality prayer prayer of
>> I guess it's intentionality and
>> intentionality prayer prayer of St.
Francis
>> uh
>> uh to
Francis
>> uh to be
>> uh to be a
Francis
>> uh to be a servant
to
to ask
to ask guidance
for
for as
to ask guidance
for as to
for as to divine
to ask guidance
for as to divine help
for as to divine help and
to ask guidance
for as to divine help and dedicate
whatever
whatever you're
whatever you're doing
whatever you're doing to
whatever you're doing to god
whatever you're doing to god karma
whatever you're doing to god karma yoga
looking
looking for
whatever you're doing to god karma yoga
looking for no
looking for no payoff
>> and
>> and that
>> and that potentiates
>> and that potentiates the
>> and that potentiates the whole
>> and that potentiates the whole progress
>> you
>> you don't
>> and that potentiates the whole progress
>> you don't have
>> you don't have to
>> and that potentiates the whole progress
>> you don't have to worry
>> you don't have to worry about
>> and that potentiates the whole progress
>> you don't have to worry about that
>> you don't have to worry about that it's
not
not your
not your problem
>> sense
>> sense of
not your problem
>> sense of responsibility
>> sense of responsibility I
not your problem
>> sense of responsibility I guess
>> yeah
>> yeah you're
>> yeah you're asking
>> yeah you're asking me
>> yeah you're asking me how
>> yeah you're asking me how to
>> yeah you're asking me how to make
>> yeah you're asking me how to make it
happen
happen don't
>> yeah you're asking me how to make it
happen don't worry
happen don't worry about
>> yeah you're asking me how to make it
happen don't worry about having
happen don't worry about having to
>> yeah you're asking me how to make it
happen don't worry about having to make
it
it happen
>> but
>> but more
it happen
>> but more yin
>> but more yin time
it happen
>> but more yin time is
>> but more yin time is is
it happen
>> but more yin time is is something
>> but more yin time is is something we
have
have control
have control over
have control over more
have control over more more
contemplative
contemplative time
have control over more more
contemplative time which
contemplative time which the
have control over more more
contemplative time which the ego
contemplative time which the ego can't
help
help happen.
help happen. It's
intention
intention and
help happen. It's
intention and spiritual
intention and spiritual will.
>> It's
>> It's just
>> It's just a
>> It's just a decision.
>> It's just a decision. Decision
>> to
>> to float
>> It's just a decision. Decision
>> to float with
>> to float with the
>> It's just a decision. Decision
>> to float with the wind,
>> to
>> to float
>> to float with
>> to float with the
>> to float with the stream
>> to float with the stream instead
>> to float with the stream instead of
paddling.
>> Right?
>> See,
>> See, everybody
>> Right?
>> See, everybody thinks
>> See, everybody thinks I
>> Right?
>> See, everybody thinks I won't
>> See, everybody thinks I won't float
downream
downream to
downream to the
downream to the ultimate
downream to the ultimate spiritual
downream to the ultimate spiritual goal
unless
unless I
downream to the ultimate spiritual goal
unless I paddle
unless I paddle like
downream to the ultimate spiritual goal
unless I paddle like crazy.
Uh
wow
wow way.
Uh
wow way. The
wow way. The way
Uh
wow way. The way of
uh
uh the
uh the towel,
uh the towel, the
uh the towel, the dowel
is
is to
uh the towel, the dowel
is to not
is to not resist.
uh the towel, the dowel
is to not resist. Once
is to not resist. Once you've
uh the towel, the dowel
is to not resist. Once you've set
is to not resist. Once you've set your
intention,
intention, then
intention, then you
intention, then you don't
intention, then you don't resist
intention, then you don't resist because
the
the intention
intention, then you don't resist because
the intention will
the intention will carry
intention, then you don't resist because
the intention will carry the
the intention will carry the rest
intention, then you don't resist because
the intention will carry the rest of
the intention will carry the rest of the
way.
>> And
>> And when
way.
>> And when you
>> And when you ask
way.
>> And when you ask God
>> And when you ask God for
way.
>> And when you ask God for help
>> And when you ask God for help in
way.
>> And when you ask God for help in that,
then
then you
then you don't
then you don't have
then you don't have to
then you don't have to worry
then you don't have to worry about
then you don't have to worry about it.
>> So
>> So that
then you don't have to worry about it.
>> So that overcomes
>> So that overcomes any
then you don't have to worry about it.
>> So that overcomes any resistance
>> So that overcomes any resistance to
increasing
>> contemplative
>> contemplative end
increasing
>> contemplative end time.
>> contemplative end time. the
increasing
>> contemplative end time. the the
>> contemplative end time. the the wi
increasing
>> contemplative end time. the the wi the
the
the willing
the willing the
the willing the willingness
the willing the willingness will
the willing the willingness will come
the willing the willingness will come up
again
again you
the willing the willingness will come up
again you know
>> and
>> and then
>> and then you
>> and then you constantly
>> and then you constantly surrender
>> and then you constantly surrender it
>> okay
>> it
>> it isn't
>> it isn't something
>> it isn't something you
>> it isn't something you make
>> it isn't something you make happen
>> it isn't something you make happen it's
something
something you
>> it isn't something you make happen it's
something you allow
something you allow to
>> it isn't something you make happen it's
something you allow to happen
>> right
>> because
>> because destiny
>> right
>> because destiny has
>> because destiny has already
>> right
>> because destiny has already got
>> because destiny has already got control
of
of it
>> if
>> if you
of it
>> if you weren't
>> if you weren't destined
of it
>> if you weren't destined to
>> if you weren't destined to be
enlightened
enlightened you
enlightened you wouldn't
enlightened you wouldn't be
enlightened you wouldn't be able
enlightened you wouldn't be able to
lecture
lecture like
enlightened you wouldn't be able to
lecture like this
>> okay
>> okay thank
>> okay thank you
>> we
>> we have
>> okay thank you
>> we have a
>> we have a long
>> okay thank you
>> we have a long I
>> we have a long I got
>> okay thank you
>> we have a long I got it.
>> we have a long I got it. I'm
>> okay thank you
>> we have a long I got it. I'm worried.
>> I
>> I know,
>> I know, but
>> I know, but uh
>> I know, but uh look
>> I know, but uh look how
>> I know, but uh look how many
>> I know, but uh look how many people
>> I know, but uh look how many people have
>> Don't
>> Don't worry
>> I know, but uh look how many people have
>> Don't worry about
>> Don't worry about it.
>> I know, but uh look how many people have
>> Don't worry about it. Always
>> Don't worry about it. Always ends
>> I know, but uh look how many people have
>> Don't worry about it. Always ends up
right.
I
I have
right.
I have a
I have a um
right.
I have a um um
I have a um um basically
right.
I have a um um basically a
I have a um um basically a simple
question
question but
question but and
question but and sometimes
question but and sometimes I
question but and sometimes I think
question but and sometimes I think that
I
I ask
question but and sometimes I think that
I ask it
I ask it out
question but and sometimes I think that
I ask it out of
I ask it out of fear
question but and sometimes I think that
I ask it out of fear but
I ask it out of fear but nevertheless
question but and sometimes I think that
I ask it out of fear but nevertheless um
if
if there
if there is
if there is the
if there is the archangels
if there is the archangels at
if there is the archangels at 50,000
if there is the archangels at 50,000 and
and
and divinity
if there is the archangels at 50,000 and
and divinity at
and divinity at infinity
if there is the archangels at 50,000 and
and divinity at infinity at
and divinity at infinity at one
if there is the archangels at 50,000 and
and divinity at infinity at one end
and divinity at infinity at one end of
the
the spectrum
the spectrum at
the spectrum at the
the spectrum at the other
the spectrum at the other end
the spectrum at the other end of
the spectrum at the other end of the
spectrum
spectrum do
the spectrum at the other end of the
spectrum do you
spectrum do you have
the spectrum at the other end of the
spectrum do you have total
spectrum do you have total um
the spectrum at the other end of the
spectrum do you have total um denial
spectrum do you have total um denial of
divinity
divinity at
divinity at the
divinity at the other
divinity at the other end
divinity at the other end into
divinity at the other end into infinity
as
as well
divinity at the other end into infinity
as well or
as well or is
divinity at the other end into infinity
as well or is there
as well or is there a
divinity at the other end into infinity
as well or is there a point
as well or is there a point where
divinity at the other end into infinity
as well or is there a point where it
as well or is there a point where it Is
it
it is
it is it
it is it down
it is it down there
it is it down there too
it is it down there too or
>> that
>> that is
it is it down there too or
>> that is a
>> that is a hypothetical
question.
question. Yes,
question. Yes, I
question. Yes, I would
question. Yes, I would just
question. Yes, I would just forget
question. Yes, I would just forget it.
Yeah,
>> good
>> good idea.
>> When
>> When she's
>> good idea.
>> When she's asking,
>> When she's asking, are
>> good idea.
>> When she's asking, are there
>> When she's asking, are there various
levels
levels of
levels of hell?
levels of hell? Yes,
levels of hell? Yes, indeed
levels of hell? Yes, indeed there
levels of hell? Yes, indeed there are.
>> We
>> We don't
levels of hell? Yes, indeed there are.
>> We don't want
>> We don't want to
levels of hell? Yes, indeed there are.
>> We don't want to go
>> We don't want to go there.
>> We
>> We don't
>> We don't want
>> We don't want to
>> We don't want to go
>> We don't want to go to
>> We don't want to go to hell.
>> We don't want to go to hell. Don't
>> We don't want to go to hell. Don't want
to
to go
>> We don't want to go to hell. Don't want
to go to
to go to hell.
>> No,
>> No, no,
>> No, no, you
>> No, no, you don't
>> No, no, you don't want
>> No, no, you don't want to
>> No, no, you don't want to go
>> No, no, you don't want to go there.
>> No, no, you don't want to go there. Uh,
I
I just
>> No, no, you don't want to go there. Uh,
I just watched
I just watched your
>> No, no, you don't want to go there. Uh,
I just watched your uh,
I just watched your uh, video
>> No, no, you don't want to go there. Uh,
I just watched your uh, video from
February,
February, the
February, the lecture,
February, the lecture, and
February, the lecture, and I
February, the lecture, and I found
February, the lecture, and I found it
very
very interesting
February, the lecture, and I found it
very interesting when
very interesting when you
February, the lecture, and I found it
very interesting when you said
very interesting when you said you
finally
finally figured
finally figured out
finally figured out your
finally figured out your purpose
finally figured out your purpose in
finally figured out your purpose in this
life.
>> Did
>> Did I?
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, you
>> Did I?
>> Yeah, you did.
>> I
>> I was
>> I was lying.
>> I
>> I was
>> I was lying.
>> My
>> My question
>> My question is
>> My question is uh,
>> My question is uh, do
>> My question is uh, do we
>> My question is uh, do we have
>> My question is uh, do we have a
>> My question is uh, do we have a purpose
every
every lifetime?
>> My question is uh, do we have a purpose
every lifetime? Is
every lifetime? Is there
>> My question is uh, do we have a purpose
every lifetime? Is there a
every lifetime? Is there a special
purpose
purpose for
purpose for each
purpose for each lifetime
purpose for each lifetime or
purpose for each lifetime or is
purpose for each lifetime or is it
purpose for each lifetime or is it just
on
on occasion
purpose for each lifetime or is it just
on occasion or
on occasion or what?
>> It's
>> It's really
>> It's really a
>> It's really a consequence
>> It's really a consequence of
>> It's really a consequence of karmic
inheritance.
>> Uh
>> Uh you
>> Uh you wouldn't
>> Uh you wouldn't be
>> Uh you wouldn't be reborn
>> Uh you wouldn't be reborn as
>> Uh you wouldn't be reborn as a
>> Uh you wouldn't be reborn as a human
unless
unless you
>> Uh you wouldn't be reborn as a human
unless you were
unless you were destined
>> Uh you wouldn't be reborn as a human
unless you were destined to
unless you were destined to undo
negative
negative karma
negative karma and
negative karma and have
negative karma and have the
negative karma and have the opportunity
to
to gain
negative karma and have the opportunity
to gain positive
to gain positive karma.
negative karma and have the opportunity
to gain positive karma. You
to gain positive karma. You couldn't
negative karma and have the opportunity
to gain positive karma. You couldn't get
reborn
reborn as
reborn as a
reborn as a human.
reborn as a human. That's
reborn as a human. That's what
reborn as a human. That's what the
Buddha
Buddha meant.
reborn as a human. That's what the
Buddha meant. Fortunate
Buddha meant. Fortunate indeed
reborn as a human. That's what the
Buddha meant. Fortunate indeed to
Buddha meant. Fortunate indeed to be
born
born within
born within this
born within this do domain
because
because of
born within this do domain
because of its
because of its enormous
born within this do domain
because of its enormous opportunities.
Hey,
Hey, what
Hey, what was
Hey, what was the
Hey, what was the question?
Do
Do we
Hey, what was the question?
Do we have
Do we have a
Hey, what was the question?
Do we have a special
Do we have a special purpose
Hey, what was the question?
Do we have a special purpose in
Do we have a special purpose in each
life?
>> I
>> I don't
life?
>> I don't know what
>> I don't know what you
life?
>> I don't know what you mean
>> I don't know what you mean by
life?
>> I don't know what you mean by special.
>> A
>> A specific
>> A specific reason
>> A specific reason or
>> specific?
>> Yeah.
>> Your
>> Your specific
>> Yeah.
>> Your specific was
>> Your specific was to
>> Yeah.
>> Your specific was to bring
>> Your specific was to bring in
>> Well,
>> Well, like
>> Well, like specific
meaning
meaning by
>> Well, like specific
meaning by intention.
>> Yes.
>> Do
>> Do we
>> Yes.
>> Do we have
>> Do we have an
>> Yes.
>> Do we have an intention?
>> Do we have an intention? Well,
>> Yes.
>> Do we have an intention? Well, we're
we're
we're only
we're only born
we're only born in
we're only born in the
we're only born in the human
we're only born in the human domain
we're only born in the human domain by
virtue
virtue of
we're only born in the human domain by
virtue of saying
virtue of saying yes
we're only born in the human domain by
virtue of saying yes to
virtue of saying yes to it.
we're only born in the human domain by
virtue of saying yes to it. Everyone
virtue of saying yes to it. Everyone is
here
here by
here by their
here by their own
here by their own ascent.
>> Consequently,
>> Consequently, that
here by their own ascent.
>> Consequently, that would
>> Consequently, that would sort
here by their own ascent.
>> Consequently, that would sort of
>> Consequently, that would sort of tend
here by their own ascent.
>> Consequently, that would sort of tend to
answer
answer the
answer the question.
Okay.
>> You
>> You get
>> You get the
>> You get the karmic
>> You get the karmic opportunity
>> You get the karmic opportunity to
>> You get the karmic opportunity to go
>> You get the karmic opportunity to go a
play
play go
>> You get the karmic opportunity to go a
play go you
play go you got
>> You get the karmic opportunity to go a
play go you got to
play go you got to get
>> You get the karmic opportunity to go a
play go you got to get get
play go you got to get get to
>> You get the karmic opportunity to go a
play go you got to get get to go
play go you got to get get to go to
>> You get the karmic opportunity to go a
play go you got to get get to go to the
best
best school
best school uh
best school uh in
best school uh in this
best school uh in this galaxy.
This
This is
best school uh in this galaxy.
This is the
This is the one
best school uh in this galaxy.
This is the one and
This is the one and only
best school uh in this galaxy.
This is the one and only not
This is the one and only not only
best school uh in this galaxy.
This is the one and only not only the
best
best but
best but the
best but the one
best but the one and
best but the one and only
best but the one and only such
best but the one and only such a
best but the one and only such a school
in
in this
best but the one and only such a school
in this galaxy
in this galaxy exist.
We've
We've already
We've already checked
We've already checked that
We've already checked that out.
We've already checked that out. There
We've already checked that out. There is
another
another no
We've already checked that out. There is
another no other
another no other human
We've already checked that out. There is
another no other human domain
another no other human domain in
We've already checked that out. There is
another no other human domain in the
Milky
Milky Way
Milky Way that
Milky Way that we
Milky Way that we know
Milky Way that we know of.
>> Yeah.
Also,
Also, I
Also, I noticed
Also, I noticed that
Also, I noticed that you
Also, I noticed that you had
Also, I noticed that you had a
a
a a
Also, I noticed that you had a
a a special
a a special um
Also, I noticed that you had a
a a special um you
a a special um you like
Also, I noticed that you had a
a a special um you like this
a a special um you like this critter.
And
And uh
And uh I
And uh I I
And uh I I was
And uh I I was walking
And uh I I was walking around
And uh I I was walking around Sedona
yesterday
yesterday and
And uh I I was walking around Sedona
yesterday and I
yesterday and I saw
And uh I I was walking around Sedona
yesterday and I saw this
yesterday and I saw this thing.
>> I'm
>> I'm going
>> I'm going critter.
>> I'm going critter. Another
>> I'm going critter. Another critter.
>> A
>> A critter.
>> I'm going critter. Another critter.
>> A critter. Yes.
>> A critter. Yes. And
>> I'm going critter. Another critter.
>> A critter. Yes. And I
>> A critter. Yes. And I couldn't
>> I'm going critter. Another critter.
>> A critter. Yes. And I couldn't believe
that
that I
that I found
that I found this
that I found this in
that I found this in Sedona.
that I found this in Sedona. So
that I found this in Sedona. So I
>> Oh
>> Oh my
that I found this in Sedona. So I
>> Oh my goodness.
>> Oh my goodness. A
that I found this in Sedona. So I
>> Oh my goodness. A grand
>> Oh my goodness. A grand surprise.
>> Yes.
>> Oh
>> Oh my
>> Yes.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> Oh my gosh. A
>> Yes.
>> Oh my gosh. A grando
>> Oh my gosh. A grando surpriso.
>> Yes.
>> Oh my gosh. A grando surpriso. Oh
>> Oh my gosh. A grando surpriso. Oh my
gracious
gracious me.
Uhhuh.
It's
It's an
It's an octopus.
>> Isn't
>> Isn't that
It's an octopus.
>> Isn't that cute?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, do
>> Oh, do you?
>> You
>> You know,
>> and
>> and they
>> and they won't
>> and they won't let
>> and they won't let me
>> and they won't let me do
>> and they won't let me do the
>> and they won't let me do the octopus
anymore.
>> Hey,
>> Hey, can
>> Hey, can I
>> Hey, can I get
>> Hey, can I get you
>> Hey, can I get you can
>> Hey, can I get you can I
>> Hey, can I get you can I get
>> Hey, can I get you can I get you
>> Hey, can I get you can I get you to
>> I
>> I I
>> Hey, can I get you can I get you to
>> I I already
>> I I already have
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you
>> Oh, you did?
>> Oh, you did? Okay.
>> I
>> I did
>> Oh, you did? Okay.
>> I did get
>> I did get away
>> Oh, you did? Okay.
>> I did get away with
>> I did get away with it
>> Oh, you did? Okay.
>> I did get away with it once
>> I did get away with it once and
>> Oh, you did? Okay.
>> I did get away with it once and I
>> I did get away with it once and I was
reprimanded
reprimanded strongly
reprimanded strongly afterwards.
reprimanded strongly afterwards. So,
>> I
>> I saw
reprimanded strongly afterwards. So,
>> I saw that.
>> I saw that. I
reprimanded strongly afterwards. So,
>> I saw that. I couldn't
>> I saw that. I couldn't I
reprimanded strongly afterwards. So,
>> I saw that. I couldn't I couldn't
>> I saw that. I couldn't I couldn't I
couldn't
couldn't resist
couldn't resist it.
>> Enjoy
>> Enjoy the
couldn't resist it.
>> Enjoy the glass
>> Enjoy the glass octopus.
>> You
>> You see
>> You see how
>> You see how the
>> You see how the octopus
>> You see how the octopus is
>> You see how the octopus is experienc
>> You see how the octopus is experienc how
alert
alert it
>> You see how the octopus is experienc how
alert it is.
alert it is. You
>> You see how the octopus is experienc how
alert it is. You know,
alert it is. You know, it
>> You see how the octopus is experienc how
alert it is. You know, it has
alert it is. You know, it has to
>> You see how the octopus is experienc how
alert it is. You know, it has to sense
the
the color
the color of
the color of the
the color of the sand.
the color of the sand. It
the color of the sand. It has
the color of the sand. It has to
the color of the sand. It has to sense
everything.
everything. It's
the color of the sand. It has to sense
everything. It's got
everything. It's got an
the color of the sand. It has to sense
everything. It's got an incredible
experience
experience there
experience there that
experience there that has
experience there that has to
experience there that has to experience
the
the whole
experience there that has to experience
the whole seabed
the whole seabed to
experience there that has to experience
the whole seabed to become
the whole seabed to become one
experience there that has to experience
the whole seabed to become one with
the whole seabed to become one with that
seabed.
seabed. I
seabed. I mean,
seabed. I mean, isn't
seabed. I mean, isn't that
seabed. I mean, isn't that amazing?
>> All
>> All the
seabed. I mean, isn't that amazing?
>> All the chroma
>> All the chroma chrom
seabed. I mean, isn't that amazing?
>> All the chroma chrom chromataphors
>> All the chroma chrom chromataphors and
all
all that
all that kind
all that kind of
all that kind of thing.
all that kind of thing. I
all that kind of thing. I think
all that kind of thing. I think it's
just
just an
all that kind of thing. I think it's
just an incredible
just an incredible little
all that kind of thing. I think it's
just an incredible little animal.
>> Dr.
>> Dr. Hawkins,
>> Dr. Hawkins, you
>> Dr. Hawkins, you have
>> Dr. Hawkins, you have written
>> Dr. Hawkins, you have written of
>> Dr. Hawkins, you have written of the
>> Dr. Hawkins, you have written of the new
race
race homospiritus.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Have
>> Yes. Have any
>> Yes. Have any of
>> Yes. Have any of that
>> Yes. Have any of that race
>> Yes. Have any of that race incarnated
whose
whose nervous
>> Yes. Have any of that race incarnated
whose nervous systems
whose nervous systems would
>> Yes. Have any of that race incarnated
whose nervous systems would not
whose nervous systems would not be
subject
subject to
subject to a
subject to a 10,00
subject to a 10,00 limitation?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, at
subject to a 10,00 limitation?
>> Oh, at this
>> Oh, at this point
subject to a 10,00 limitation?
>> Oh, at this point is
>> Oh, at this point is still
subject to a 10,00 limitation?
>> Oh, at this point is still subject.
>> Oh, at this point is still subject. In
other
other words,
other words, it
other words, it means
life
life evolved
other words, it means
life evolved on
life evolved on up
other words, it means
life evolved on up to
life evolved on up to the
other words, it means
life evolved on up to the animal
kingdom.
kingdom. Spirituality
kingdom. Spirituality appeared
kingdom. Spirituality appeared in
kingdom. Spirituality appeared in on
kingdom. Spirituality appeared in on you
know
know once
kingdom. Spirituality appeared in on you
know once consciousness
know once consciousness level
kingdom. Spirituality appeared in on you
know once consciousness level reached
200.
Once
Once consciousness
200.
Once consciousness level
Once consciousness level reached
200.
Once consciousness level reached 200
that
that was
that was the
that was the emergence
that was the emergence of
that was the emergence of spiritual
energy
energy uh
that was the emergence of spiritual
energy uh in
energy uh in this
that was the emergence of spiritual
energy uh in this on
energy uh in this on this
that was the emergence of spiritual
energy uh in this on this planet.
>> Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Mhm.
>> Uhhuh.
When
When you
When you need
When you need to
When you need to be
When you need to be in
When you need to be in the
When you need to be in the world,
When you need to be in the world, but
you're
you're feeling
When you need to be in the world, but
you're feeling really
you're feeling really tender
When you need to be in the world, but
you're feeling really tender and
you're feeling really tender and raw,
how
how do
how do you
how do you do
how do you do it?
>> Painfully,
you
you got
you got to
you got to get
you got to get thicker
you got to get thicker skin,
you got to get thicker skin, right?
>> Surrender
>> Surrender the
you got to get thicker skin, right?
>> Surrender the juice
>> Surrender the juice you
you got to get thicker skin, right?
>> Surrender the juice you get
>> Surrender the juice you get out
you got to get thicker skin, right?
>> Surrender the juice you get out of
suffering
suffering pain.
If
If everything's
suffering pain.
If everything's painful
If everything's painful in
suffering pain.
If everything's painful in this
If everything's painful in this world,
it's
it's because
it's because your
it's because your ego
it's because your ego is
it's because your ego is getting
it's because your ego is getting that
this
this world
it's because your ego is getting that
this world is
this world is painful.
it's because your ego is getting that
this world is painful. You
this world is painful. You have
it's because your ego is getting that
this world is painful. You have to
surrender
surrender the
surrender the belief
surrender the belief system.
surrender the belief system. This
surrender the belief system. This is
surrender the belief system. This is not
a
a painful
surrender the belief system. This is not
a painful world.
a painful world. It's
surrender the belief system. This is not
a painful world. It's neither
a painful world. It's neither painful
nor
nor pleasurable.
nor pleasurable. This
nor pleasurable. This world
nor pleasurable. This world is
nor pleasurable. This world is neither
painful
painful nor
nor pleasurable. This world is neither
painful nor pleasurable.
Pain
Pain and
Pain and pleasure
Pain and pleasure is
Pain and pleasure is purely
Pain and pleasure is purely a
subjective.
subjective. If
Pain and pleasure is purely a
subjective. If I
subjective. If I want
Pain and pleasure is purely a
subjective. If I want this
subjective. If I want this here,
Pain and pleasure is purely a
subjective. If I want this here, it's
pleasurable.
pleasurable. If
pleasurable. If I
pleasurable. If I don't
pleasurable. If I don't want
pleasurable. If I don't want it
pleasurable. If I don't want it here,
it's
it's painful.
pleasurable. If I don't want it here,
it's painful. It's
it's painful. It's all
pleasurable. If I don't want it here,
it's painful. It's all up
it's painful. It's all up to
pleasurable. If I don't want it here,
it's painful. It's all up to my
it's painful. It's all up to my own
inner
inner decision.
inner decision. So
inner decision. So reionown
inner decision. So reionown that
inner decision. So reionown that you
have
have the
inner decision. So reionown that you
have the power
have the power to
inner decision. So reionown that you
have the power to make
have the power to make that
inner decision. So reionown that you
have the power to make that decision
that
that life
that life can
that life can be
that life can be pleasant
and
and that
that life can be pleasant
and that pain
and that pain is
that life can be pleasant
and that pain is not
and that pain is not a
that life can be pleasant
and that pain is not a requirement.
You
You may
You may have
You may have some
You may have some unconscious
You may have some unconscious guilt
thing
thing that
You may have some unconscious guilt
thing that you
thing that you got
You may have some unconscious guilt
thing that you got to
thing that you got to suffer
You may have some unconscious guilt
thing that you got to suffer through
life
life or
life or life
life or life is
life or life is suffering.
life or life is suffering. You
life or life is suffering. You got
life or life is suffering. You got some
program
program running.
So
So I'd
So I'd ask
So I'd ask for
So I'd ask for divine
So I'd ask for divine help
So I'd ask for divine help to
So I'd ask for divine help to transcend
that.
that. Ask
So I'd ask for divine help to transcend
that. Ask the
that. Ask the Holy
So I'd ask for divine help to transcend
that. Ask the Holy Spirit
that. Ask the Holy Spirit for
So I'd ask for divine help to transcend
that. Ask the Holy Spirit for a
that. Ask the Holy Spirit for a miracle
to
to transform
to transform that
to transform that belief
to transform that belief system
to transform that belief system into
to transform that belief system into a
reality.
Life
Life is
Life is only
Life is only what
Life is only what you
Life is only what you make
Life is only what you make it.
Life is only what you make it. It's
neither
neither pleasant
Life is only what you make it. It's
neither pleasant or
neither pleasant or unpleasant.
Breathing
Breathing air
Breathing air you
Breathing air you think
Breathing air you think is
Breathing air you think is pleasant.
Well,
Well, fish
Breathing air you think is pleasant.
Well, fish doesn't
Well, fish doesn't think
Breathing air you think is pleasant.
Well, fish doesn't think so.
Get
Get me
Get me out
Get me out of
Get me out of this
Get me out of this air,
Get me out of this air, man.
Get me out of this air, man. I
Get me out of this air, man. I die.
Get me out of this air, man. I die. Kill
me.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> That's
>> That's true.
>> When
>> When you're
>> That's true.
>> When you're a
>> When you're a bad
>> That's true.
>> When you're a bad fish,
>> When you're a bad fish, they
>> That's true.
>> When you're a bad fish, they condemn
>> When you're a bad fish, they condemn you
to
to the
to the air.
Hello
Hello Dr.
to the air.
Hello Dr. Vivian
Hello Dr. Vivian and
to the air.
Hello Dr. Vivian and thank
Hello Dr. Vivian and thank you
to the air.
Hello Dr. Vivian and thank you for
Hello Dr. Vivian and thank you for your
work
work and
work and your
work and your teachings.
>> I
>> I surrendered
work and your teachings.
>> I surrendered my
>> I surrendered my ego
work and your teachings.
>> I surrendered my ego to
>> I surrendered my ego to come
work and your teachings.
>> I surrendered my ego to come up
>> I surrendered my ego to come up this
work and your teachings.
>> I surrendered my ego to come up this far
in
in business
in business if
in business if is
in business if is it
in business if is it possible
in business if is it possible to
in business if is it possible to help
people
people get
in business if is it possible to help
people get beyond
people get beyond the
in business if is it possible to help
people get beyond the 200
people get beyond the 200 level
in business if is it possible to help
people get beyond the 200 level and
people get beyond the 200 level and is
there
there a
there a way
there a way that
there a way that I
there a way that I can
there a way that I can attract
there a way that I can attract clients
above
above the
there a way that I can attract clients
above the 200
above the 200 level?
If
If you
If you have
If you have an
If you have an integrous
If you have an integrous company
If you have an integrous company with
stated
stated integrous
If you have an integrous company with
stated integrous purposes
and
and integrous
and integrous administration,
and integrous administration, it'll
automatically
automatically be
and integrous administration, it'll
automatically be integrous.
>> If
>> If you
>> If you have
>> If you have zero
>> If you have zero tolerance
>> If you have zero tolerance for
>> If you have zero tolerance for anything
else,
>> that
>> that sells
>> that sells it.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. Will
>> that sells it.
>> Mhm. Will I
>> Mhm. Will I be
>> that sells it.
>> Mhm. Will I be able
>> Mhm. Will I be able to
>> that sells it.
>> Mhm. Will I be able to help
>> Mhm. Will I be able to help those
>> that sells it.
>> Mhm. Will I be able to help those people
under
under 200?
>> You
>> You don't
under 200?
>> You don't let
>> You don't let God
under 200?
>> You don't let God worry
>> You don't let God worry about
under 200?
>> You don't let God worry about the
>> You don't let God worry about the people
under
under 200.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Salvation
>> Okay. Salvation is
>> Okay. Salvation is the
>> Okay. Salvation is the purpose
>> Okay. Salvation is the purpose of
>> Okay. Salvation is the purpose of Jesus
Christ.
>> Not
>> Not me.
>> That's
>> That's a
>> Not me.
>> That's a shake
>> That's a shake your
>> Not me.
>> That's a shake your hand.
>> We
>> We can
>> We can encourage
>> We can encourage people.
>> We can encourage people. I
>> We can encourage people. I think
>> We can encourage people. I think being
>> We can encourage people. I think being a
a
a fellow
>> We can encourage people. I think being a
a fellow spiritual
a fellow spiritual companion
>> We can encourage people. I think being a
a fellow spiritual companion to
a fellow spiritual companion to others
along
along the
along the way
along the way is
along the way is serving
along the way is serving God.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
along the way is serving God.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. May
along the way is serving God.
>> Okay. Thank you. May she?
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yes.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
Yes.
>> When
>> When we
>> When we talk
>> When we talk about
>> When we talk about reincarnation,
we
we think
>> When we talk about reincarnation,
we think that
we think that our
>> When we talk about reincarnation,
we think that our perception
we think that our perception is
>> When we talk about reincarnation,
we think that our perception is that
it's
it's sequential
it's sequential that
it's sequential that we
it's sequential that we we
it's sequential that we we live,
it's sequential that we we live, we
it's sequential that we we live, we die,
we're
we're reborn.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. We
>> Yeah. We give
>> Yeah. We give it
>> Yeah. We give it a
>> Yeah. We give it a linearity.
>> My
>> My question
>> Yeah. We give it a linearity.
>> My question is,
>> My question is, are
>> Yeah. We give it a linearity.
>> My question is, are these
>> My question is, are these lifetimes
linear
linear or
linear or are
linear or are they
linear or are they happening
linear or are they happening all
linear or are they happening all at
once?
>> Could
>> Could be
>> Could be both.
You're
You're going
>> Could be both.
You're going to
You're going to send
>> Could be both.
You're going to send me
You're going to send me away
>> Could be both.
You're going to send me away thinking
about
about that.
I'll
I'll go
about that.
I'll go I'll
I'll go I'll go
about that.
I'll go I'll go I
I'll go I'll go I will
about that.
I'll go I'll go I will go.
Well,
Well, either
Well, either orness
Well, either orness is
Well, either orness is an
Well, either orness is an ego
Well, either orness is an ego position
positionality
positionality you
Well, either orness is an ego position
positionality you know
positionality you know and
Well, either orness is an ego position
positionality you know and very
positionality you know and very linear.
Yeah.
Yeah. Is
Yeah. Is it
Yeah. Is it sequential
Yeah. Is it sequential within
Yeah. Is it sequential within a
Yeah. Is it sequential within a temporal
dimension?
dimension? Well,
Yeah. Is it sequential within a temporal
dimension? Well, reality
dimension? Well, reality is
Yeah. Is it sequential within a temporal
dimension? Well, reality is not
temporal.
temporal. There's
temporal. There's no
temporal. There's no then
temporal. There's no then uh
temporal. There's no then uh there's
temporal. There's no then uh there's no
past,
past, present
temporal. There's no then uh there's no
past, present or
past, present or future
temporal. There's no then uh there's no
past, present or future in
past, present or future in the
temporal. There's no then uh there's no
past, present or future in the infinite
reality.
reality. So
reality. So from
reality. So from a
reality. So from a ego
reality. So from a ego position
reality. So from a ego position it
reality. So from a ego position it could
be
be simultaneously
reality. So from a ego position it could
be simultaneously both
multiple
multiple dimensions
multiple dimensions simultaneously.
Yeah.
Yeah. The
multiple dimensions simultaneously.
Yeah. The decision
Yeah. The decision made
multiple dimensions simultaneously.
Yeah. The decision made at
Yeah. The decision made at one
multiple dimensions simultaneously.
Yeah. The decision made at one level
Yeah. The decision made at one level is
affecting
affecting the
affecting the existence
affecting the existence at
affecting the existence at another
level.
In
In reality
In reality there
In reality there is
In reality there is no
In reality there is no sequence.
In reality there is no sequence. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. But
In reality there is no sequence. Yes.
>> Okay. But that's
>> Okay. But that's a
In reality there is no sequence. Yes.
>> Okay. But that's a very
>> Okay. But that's a very advanced
question.
>> Yeah.
Thank
Thank you.
>> Is
>> Is your
Thank you.
>> Is your reality
>> Is your reality outside
Thank you.
>> Is your reality outside of
>> Is your reality outside of time?
Thank you.
>> Is your reality outside of time? Yeah,
it
it is.
>> Doc.
>> Yep.
>> I'm
>> I'm in
>> Yep.
>> I'm in for
>> I'm in for it.
>> They
>> They come
>> They come on
>> They come on friendly
>> They come on friendly like,
>> They come on friendly like, "Hi,
>> They come on friendly like, "Hi, D.
Yeah.
Yeah. Go
>> They come on friendly like, "Hi, D.
Yeah. Go ahead.
>> Well,
>> yeah.
>> Um,
>> Um, I
>> Um, I wanted
>> Um, I wanted to
>> Um, I wanted to thank
>> Um, I wanted to thank you
>> Um, I wanted to thank you for
>> Um, I wanted to thank you for sticking
around
around and
>> Um, I wanted to thank you for sticking
around and giving
around and giving us
>> Um, I wanted to thank you for sticking
around and giving us the
around and giving us the work
>> Um, I wanted to thank you for sticking
around and giving us the work that
around and giving us the work that you
have.
>> Yeah.
>> It
>> It has
>> It has totally
>> It has totally destroyed
>> It has totally destroyed what
>> It has totally destroyed what I
>> It has totally destroyed what I used
>> It has totally destroyed what I used to
call
call my
>> It has totally destroyed what I used to
call my life
call my life over
>> It has totally destroyed what I used to
call my life over the
call my life over the last
>> It has totally destroyed what I used to
call my life over the last year
and
and probably
and probably saved
and probably saved me
and probably saved me four
and probably saved me four or
and probably saved me four or five00
lifetimes
in
in the
in the future.
in the future. And
in the future. And I
in the future. And I do
in the future. And I do have
in the future. And I do have a
in the future. And I do have a question.
I
I wanted
in the future. And I do have a question.
I wanted to
>> make
>> make that
>> make that statement.
>> Yeah.
>> In
>> In February,
>> In February, you
>> In February, you talked
>> In February, you talked about
>> In February, you talked about karmic
blockages,
>> but
>> but you
>> but you didn't
>> but you didn't go
>> but you didn't go into
that
that in
>> but you didn't go into
that in detail,
that in detail, and
>> but you didn't go into
that in detail, and that
that in detail, and that has
>> but you didn't go into
that in detail, and that has stuck
that in detail, and that has stuck in
>> but you didn't go into
that in detail, and that has stuck in me
uh
uh since
uh since that
uh since that time.
uh since that time. I
uh since that time. I I
uh since that time. I I would
uh since that time. I I would like
uh since that time. I I would like you
to
to maybe
uh since that time. I I would like you
to maybe expound
to maybe expound on
uh since that time. I I would like you
to maybe expound on that
to maybe expound on that if
uh since that time. I I would like you
to maybe expound on that if you
to maybe expound on that if you can.
>> Well,
>> Well, is
>> Well, is there
>> Well, is there a
>> Well, is there a way
>> Well, is there a way to
>> Well, is there a way to get
>> Well, is there a way to get around
>> Well, is there a way to get around it?
There
There could
>> Well, is there a way to get around it?
There could be
There could be a
>> Well, is there a way to get around it?
There could be a reputation
There could be a reputation that
>> Well, is there a way to get around it?
There could be a reputation that one
There could be a reputation that one has
made
made and
made and you
made and you could
made and you could begin
made and you could begin to
made and you could begin to intuit
made and you could begin to intuit it
that
that s
made and you could begin to intuit it
that s you
that s you know
made and you could begin to intuit it
that s you know such
that s you know such a
made and you could begin to intuit it
that s you know such a reputation
that s you know such a reputation must
have
have been
have been made
have been made by
have been made by you
have been made by you at
have been made by you at some
have been made by you at some time
have been made by you at some time and
what
what you
have been made by you at some time and
what you do
what you do is
have been made by you at some time and
what you do is presume
what you do is presume that
have been made by you at some time and
what you do is presume that it's
what you do is presume that it's a
reality
reality and
reality and pray
reality and pray about
reality and pray about it
reality and pray about it ask
reality and pray about it ask for
forgiveness
forgiveness that
reality and pray about it ask for
forgiveness that you
forgiveness that you refuse
reality and pray about it ask for
forgiveness that you refuse the
forgiveness that you refuse the reality
when
when was
when was offered
when was offered to
when was offered to you
when was offered to you and
when was offered to you and uh
when was offered to you and uh it's
when was offered to you and uh it's a
see
see guessing
when was offered to you and uh it's a
see guessing karma
see guessing karma is
when was offered to you and uh it's a
see guessing karma is like
see guessing karma is like a
when was offered to you and uh it's a
see guessing karma is like a presumptive
thing.
thing. It
thing. It isn't
thing. It isn't necessary
thing. It isn't necessary to
thing. It isn't necessary to do
thing. It isn't necessary to do it,
thing. It isn't necessary to do it, but
it
it facilitates
thing. It isn't necessary to do it, but
it facilitates the
it facilitates the work
thing. It isn't necessary to do it, but
it facilitates the work sometimes
it facilitates the work sometimes when
you're
you're up
you're up against
you're up against a
you're up against a a
you're up against a a brick
you're up against a a brick wall,
you're up against a a brick wall, you
know.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
A
A number
>> Thank you.
A number of
A number of people
>> Thank you.
A number of people um
A number of people um in
>> Thank you.
A number of people um in the
A number of people um in the audience
are
are former
are former students
are former students of
are former students of a
are former students of a spiritual
teacher
teacher that
are former students of a spiritual
teacher that taught
teacher that taught in
are former students of a spiritual
teacher that taught in Boulder
teacher that taught in Boulder City
are former students of a spiritual
teacher that taught in Boulder City for
a
a number
a number of
a number of years
a number of years by
a number of years by the
a number of years by the name
a number of years by the name of
a number of years by the name of Vernon
Howard.
Howard. He
a number of years by the name of Vernon
Howard. He taught
Howard. He taught the
a number of years by the name of Vernon
Howard. He taught the man's
Howard. He taught the man's biggest
problem
problem was
problem was that
problem was that he
problem was that he was
problem was that he was asleep,
problem was that he was asleep, a
problem was that he was asleep, a kind
of
of psychic
>> unconscious.
>> unconscious. Yeah.
>> unconscious. Yeah. Yeah.
>> unconscious. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> unconscious. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Mhm.
>> So
>> So um
>> unconscious. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Mhm.
>> So um and
>> So um and that
>> unconscious. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Mhm.
>> So um and that what
>> So um and that what he
>> unconscious. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Mhm.
>> So um and that what he needed
>> So um and that what he needed to
>> unconscious. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Mhm.
>> So um and that what he needed to do
>> So um and that what he needed to do was
wake
wake up.
>> Yep.
>> So
>> So my
>> So my question
>> So my question is
>> So my question is is
>> So my question is is that
>> So my question is is that true?
>> So my question is is that true? And
>> So my question is is that true? And if
it
it is
>> So my question is is that true? And if
it is true,
it is true, is
>> So my question is is that true? And if
it is true, is the
it is true, is the map
>> So my question is is that true? And if
it is true, is the map of
it is true, is the map of consciousness
kind
kind of
kind of a
kind of a scale
kind of a scale of
kind of a scale of awakening?
>> It
>> It is.
kind of a scale of awakening?
>> It is. And
>> It is. And I
kind of a scale of awakening?
>> It is. And I agree
>> It is. And I agree with
kind of a scale of awakening?
>> It is. And I agree with Vernon
>> It is. And I agree with Vernon Howard
that,
that, you
that, you know,
that, you know, and
that, you know, and it's
that, you know, and it's been
that, you know, and it's been said
that, you know, and it's been said by
every
every spiritual
that, you know, and it's been said by
every spiritual master
every spiritual master one
that, you know, and it's been said by
every spiritual master one way
every spiritual master one way or
that, you know, and it's been said by
every spiritual master one way or the
other.
other. Man
other. Man is
other. Man is unconscious.
other. Man is unconscious. Uh
other. Man is unconscious. Uh man
other. Man is unconscious. Uh man is
ignorant.
ignorant. Man
other. Man is unconscious. Uh man is
ignorant. Man is
ignorant. Man is spiritually
other. Man is unconscious. Uh man is
ignorant. Man is spiritually asleep.
He's
He's unaware.
Uh
Uh he
He's unaware.
Uh he chooses
Uh he chooses what
He's unaware.
Uh he chooses what he
Uh he chooses what he thinks
He's unaware.
Uh he chooses what he thinks is
Uh he chooses what he thinks is the
good,
good, but
good, but he
good, but he doesn't
good, but he doesn't know
good, but he doesn't know the
good, but he doesn't know the good
good, but he doesn't know the good from
the
the real
good, but he doesn't know the good from
the real from
the real from the
good, but he doesn't know the good from
the real from the illusory.
So
So that's
So that's why
So that's why man
So that's why man is
So that's why man is intrinsically
innocent
innocent because
So that's why man is intrinsically
innocent because of
innocent because of the
So that's why man is intrinsically
innocent because of the limitation
innocent because of the limitation of
his
his evolution.
Man
Man has
his evolution.
Man has only
Man has only evolved
his evolution.
Man has only evolved to
Man has only evolved to hear.
his evolution.
Man has only evolved to hear. So
Man has only evolved to hear. So how
his evolution.
Man has only evolved to hear. So how can
he
he be,
he be, you
he be, you know,
he be, you know, responsible
he be, you know, responsible for
he be, you know, responsible for knowing
what
what you
he be, you know, responsible for knowing
what you don't
what you don't know
he be, you know, responsible for knowing
what you don't know till
what you don't know till you
he be, you know, responsible for knowing
what you don't know till you get
what you don't know till you get here?
Yeah.
Yeah. He
Yeah. He makes
Yeah. He makes a
Yeah. He makes a decision
Yeah. He makes a decision based
Yeah. He makes a decision based on
Yeah. He makes a decision based on what
it
it seems
Yeah. He makes a decision based on what
it seems like
it seems like the
Yeah. He makes a decision based on what
it seems like the best
it seems like the best decision
Yeah. He makes a decision based on what
it seems like the best decision at
it seems like the best decision at the
time.
Even
Even if
time.
Even if it's
Even if it's an
time.
Even if it's an error,
Even if it's an error, his
time.
Even if it's an error, his intention
Even if it's an error, his intention was
at
at least
at least to
at least to choose
at least to choose the
at least to choose the good.
at least to choose the good. Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Socrates
>> Yeah. Socrates has
>> Yeah. Socrates has the
>> Yeah. Socrates has the answer.
He
He was
>> Yeah. Socrates has the answer.
He was my
He was my hero
>> Yeah. Socrates has the answer.
He was my hero as
He was my hero as a
>> Yeah. Socrates has the answer.
He was my hero as a kid.
He was my hero as a kid. Socrates,
>> he
>> he went
>> he went to
>> he went to death
>> he went to death rather
>> he went to death rather than
>> he went to death rather than deny
>> he went to death rather than deny God,
you
you know.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you for
>> Thank you for your
>> Thank you for your teachings.
>> Um,
>> Um, for
>> Thank you for your teachings.
>> Um, for the
>> Um, for the past
>> Thank you for your teachings.
>> Um, for the past few
>> Um, for the past few years,
>> Thank you for your teachings.
>> Um, for the past few years, I've
>> Um, for the past few years, I've been
doing
doing research
doing research because
doing research because I'm
doing research because I'm really
doing research because I'm really clear
that
that I'm
doing research because I'm really clear
that I'm to
that I'm to write
doing research because I'm really clear
that I'm to write a
that I'm to write a book
doing research because I'm really clear
that I'm to write a book in
that I'm to write a book in regards
doing research because I'm really clear
that I'm to write a book in regards to
mother.
>> In
>> In regards
mother.
>> In regards to
>> In regards to what?
>> Mother.
>> M
>> M O
>> M O T
>> M O T H
>> M O T H E
>> M O T H E R.
>> Yes.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yes.
um
um in
>> Oh, yes.
um in looking
um in looking at
>> Oh, yes.
um in looking at history
um in looking at history which
>> Oh, yes.
um in looking at history which is
um in looking at history which is a
great
great teacher
great teacher as
great teacher as the
great teacher as the women
great teacher as the women have
great teacher as the women have exodus
the
the home
great teacher as the women have exodus
the home in
the home in the
great teacher as the women have exodus
the home in the 50s
the home in the 50s and
great teacher as the women have exodus
the home in the 50s and the
the home in the 50s and the children
have
have been
have been left
have been left um
have been left um I
have been left um I see
have been left um I see a
have been left um I see a great
have been left um I see a great call
have been left um I see a great call for
love
love and
have been left um I see a great call for
love and nurturing
love and nurturing that
have been left um I see a great call for
love and nurturing that isn't
love and nurturing that isn't being
have been left um I see a great call for
love and nurturing that isn't being met
so
so what
so what I
so what I would
so what I would like
so what I would like to
so what I would like to do
so what I would like to do is
so what I would like to do is present
material
material to
so what I would like to do is present
material to show
material to show the
so what I would like to do is present
material to show the profound
material to show the profound effect
that
that that
that that nurturing
that that nurturing and
that that nurturing and that
that that nurturing and that being
that that nurturing and that being with
that
that child
that that nurturing and that being with
that child how
that child how important
that that nurturing and that being with
that child how important that
that child how important that is
>> do
>> do you
>> do you need
>> do you need to
>> do you need to write
>> do you need to write a
>> do you need to write a book
>> do you need to write a book on
>> do you need to write a book on that
>> isn't
>> isn't that
>> do you need to write a book on that
>> isn't that a
>> isn't that a presumption
>> do you need to write a book on that
>> isn't that a presumption of
>> isn't that a presumption of all
>> do you need to write a book on that
>> isn't that a presumption of all of
>> isn't that a presumption of all of human
society
>> it
>> it doesn't
society
>> it doesn't look
>> it doesn't look like
the
the women
the women aren't
the women aren't there.
>> I
>> I just
the women aren't there.
>> I just want
>> I just want to
the women aren't there.
>> I just want to raise
>> I just want to raise the
the women aren't there.
>> I just want to raise the consciousness
of
of that
of that nurturing
of that nurturing and
of that nurturing and the
of that nurturing and the importance
of that nurturing and the importance of
that.
that. But
of that nurturing and the importance of
that. But I
that. But I don't
of that nurturing and the importance of
that. But I don't want
that. But I don't want to
of that nurturing and the importance of
that. But I don't want to produce
that. But I don't want to produce I
guess
guess my
guess my question
guess my question is
guess my question is how
guess my question is how can
guess my question is how can I
guess my question is how can I do
guess my question is how can I do that
without
without producing
guess my question is how can I do that
without producing shame
without producing shame or
guess my question is how can I do that
without producing shame or guilt
without producing shame or guilt or
>> well
>> well don't
>> well don't beat
>> well don't beat up
>> well don't beat up the
>> well don't beat up the downside
>> well don't beat up the downside just
extol
extol the
>> well don't beat up the downside just
extol the virtues
extol the virtues of
>> well don't beat up the downside just
extol the virtues of the
extol the virtues of the upside.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Just
>> I
>> I mean
>> Okay. Just
>> I mean nothing
>> I mean nothing that
>> Okay. Just
>> I mean nothing that can
>> I mean nothing that can really
substitute
substitute during
substitute during the
substitute during the formative
substitute during the formative years
from
from nurturings.
substitute during the formative years
from nurturings. Yeah.
from nurturings. Yeah. adequate
nurturing
nurturing and
nurturing and its
nurturing and its absence
nurturing and its absence cripples
nurturing and its absence cripples the
person
person and
nurturing and its absence cripples the
person and has
person and has bio
nurturing and its absence cripples the
person and has bio creates
person and has bio creates actually
biochemical
biochemical damage
biochemical damage to
biochemical damage to the
neurotransmitters
neurotransmitters in
biochemical damage to the
neurotransmitters in the
neurotransmitters in the brain
biochemical damage to the
neurotransmitters in the brain and
neurotransmitters in the brain and so
deprived
deprived of
deprived of nurturance
deprived of nurturance at
deprived of nurturance at a
deprived of nurturance at a crucial
deprived of nurturance at a crucial time
uh
uh leads
deprived of nurturance at a crucial time
uh leads to
uh leads to you
deprived of nurturance at a crucial time
uh leads to you know
uh leads to you know warping
deprived of nurturance at a crucial time
uh leads to you know warping of
uh leads to you know warping of the
personality
personality it's
personality it's the
personality it's the worst
personality it's the worst thing
personality it's the worst thing that
can
can happen
personality it's the worst thing that
can happen to
can happen to you
>> so
>> so just
>> so just produ
>> so just produ presenting
>> so just produ presenting the
>> so just produ presenting the truth
>> just
>> just present
>> so just produ presenting the truth
>> just present the
>> just present the truth
>> so just produ presenting the truth
>> just present the truth and
>> just present the truth and of
>> so just produ presenting the truth
>> just present the truth and of course
there's
there's a
there's a lot
there's a lot of
there's a lot of research
there's a lot of research in
there's a lot of research in the
psychological
psychological and
there's a lot of research in the
psychological and psychiatric
psychological and psychiatric literature
that
that told
that told that
that told that you
that told that you know
>> Ashley
>> Ashley Monagu
that told that you know
>> Ashley Monagu is
>> Ashley Monagu is the
that told that you know
>> Ashley Monagu is the person
>> Ashley Monagu is the person exactly
Okay,
Okay, thank
Okay, thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Well,
>> Well, something
>> Well, something you
>> Well, something you said
>> Well, something you said today
>> Well, something you said today kind
>> Well, something you said today kind of
threw
threw me
>> Well, something you said today kind of
threw me a
threw me a little
>> Well, something you said today kind of
threw me a little offkilter.
threw me a little offkilter. Well,
>> Well, something you said today kind of
threw me a little offkilter. Well, more
ego
ego has
ego has been
ego has been battering
ego has been battering me
ego has been battering me around
ego has been battering me around a
ego has been battering me around a lot
and
and I'm
ego has been battering me around a lot
and I'm lose
and I'm lose track
ego has been battering me around a lot
and I'm lose track of
and I'm lose track of my
ego has been battering me around a lot
and I'm lose track of my spiritual
intentions,
intentions, it
intentions, it seems,
you
you know,
intentions, it seems,
you know, in
you know, in working
intentions, it seems,
you know, in working or
you know, in working or just
intentions, it seems,
you know, in working or just my
you know, in working or just my daily
life.
life. And
life. And I've
life. And I've been
life. And I've been thinking
life. And I've been thinking real
seriously
seriously that
life. And I've been thinking real
seriously that a
seriously that a really
life. And I've been thinking real
seriously that a really good
seriously that a really good thing
life. And I've been thinking real
seriously that a really good thing for
me
me would
me would be
me would be to
me would be to retire
me would be to retire a
me would be to retire a little
me would be to retire a little bit
me would be to retire a little bit for
me would be to retire a little bit for a
while
while into
me would be to retire a little bit for a
while into a
while into a more
me would be to retire a little bit for a
while into a more of
while into a more of a
me would be to retire a little bit for a
while into a more of a spiritual
encouraging
encouraging environment.
encouraging environment. But
encouraging environment. But you
encouraging environment. But you you
were
were saying
encouraging environment. But you you
were saying that
were saying that you
encouraging environment. But you you
were saying that you were
were saying that you were a
encouraging environment. But you you
were saying that you were a realist
were saying that you were a realist and
you
you you
you you know
you you know believed
you you know believed that
>> yeah
>> yeah you
you you know believed that
>> yeah you belong
>> yeah you belong to
you you know believed that
>> yeah you belong to any
>> yeah you belong to any spiritual
you you know believed that
>> yeah you belong to any spiritual groups
>> not
>> not really
>> not really in
>> not really in a
>> not really in a very
>> that's
>> that's the
>> not really in a very
>> that's the problem.
>> that's the problem. You
>> not really in a very
>> that's the problem. You don't
>> that's the problem. You don't have
>> not really in a very
>> that's the problem. You don't have to
retire
retire from
retire from society.
retire from society. You
retire from society. You go
retire from society. You go to
retire from society. You go to the
meeting
meeting on
retire from society. You go to the
meeting on Monday
meeting on Monday night
retire from society. You go to the
meeting on Monday night of
meeting on Monday night of course
retire from society. You go to the
meeting on Monday night of course of
miracles.
miracles. Tuesday
miracles. Tuesday night
miracles. Tuesday night some
miracles. Tuesday night some 12step
group.
group. Thursday
miracles. Tuesday night some 12step
group. Thursday night
group. Thursday night a
miracles. Tuesday night some 12step
group. Thursday night a Vernon
group. Thursday night a Vernon Howard
class.
class. Friday
class. Friday night
class. Friday night church
class. Friday night church religious
science
science go
class. Friday night church religious
science go to
science go to unidan.
class. Friday night church religious
science go to unidan. Sunday
science go to unidan. Sunday morning
class. Friday night church religious
science go to unidan. Sunday morning you
see
see how
see how busy
see how busy you
see how busy you are.
see how busy you are. You
see how busy you are. You don't
see how busy you are. You don't have
see how busy you are. You don't have to
leave
leave the
see how busy you are. You don't have to
leave the world
leave the world or
see how busy you are. You don't have to
leave the world or leave
leave the world or leave your
see how busy you are. You don't have to
leave the world or leave your job.
leave the world or leave your job. You
know
you
you can
know
you can be
you can be totally
know
you can be totally immersed
you can be totally immersed in
know
you can be totally immersed in the
spiritual
spiritual community
spiritual community without
spiritual community without leaving
spiritual community without leaving you
work
work or
>> or
>> or well
>> or well maybe
>> or well maybe I
>> or well maybe I might
>> or well maybe I might want
>> or well maybe I might want to
>> or well maybe I might want to move
>> or well maybe I might want to move to
>> or well maybe I might want to move to a
place
place where
>> or well maybe I might want to move to a
place where that's
place where that's more
>> or well maybe I might want to move to a
place where that's more available.
>> It's
>> It's available
>> It's available everywhere.
>> Internet.
>> No
>> No no
>> No no not
>> No no not internet.
You
You need
>> No no not internet.
You need a
You need a human
>> No no not internet.
You need a human being.
>> Well,
>> Well, you
>> Well, you can.
>> Well, you can. Yes,
>> Well, you can. Yes, you
>> Well, you can. Yes, you can.
>> It's
>> It's like
>> Well, you can. Yes, you can.
>> It's like people.
>> It's
>> It's available
>> It's available everywhere.
>> Where
>> Where do
>> It's available everywhere.
>> Where do you
>> Where do you live?
>> It's available everywhere.
>> Where do you live? The
>> Where do you live? The North
>> It's available everywhere.
>> Where do you live? The North Pole
>> Where do you live? The North Pole or
what?
Well,
Well, I
what?
Well, I was
Well, I was think
what?
Well, I was think I
Well, I was think I have
what?
Well, I was think I have been
Well, I was think I have been kind
what?
Well, I was think I have been kind of
Well, I was think I have been kind of in
a
a inner
a inner kind
a inner kind of
a inner kind of a
a inner kind of a limbo
a inner kind of a limbo now
a inner kind of a limbo now of
a inner kind of a limbo now of halfway
moving
moving here
a inner kind of a limbo now of halfway
moving here because
moving here because there's
a inner kind of a limbo now of halfway
moving here because there's a
moving here because there's a lot,
a inner kind of a limbo now of halfway
moving here because there's a lot, you
know,
know, of
know, of course
know, of course of
know, of course of miracles
know, of course of miracles and
>> there's
>> there's a
know, of course of miracles and
>> there's a lot
>> spiritual
>> spiritual groups
>> spiritual groups of
>> spiritual groups of all
>> spiritual groups of all kinds
everywhere.
everywhere. There's
>> spiritual groups of all kinds
everywhere. There's not
everywhere. There's not one
>> spiritual groups of all kinds
everywhere. There's not one town
everywhere. There's not one town in
America
America that
America that doesn't
America that doesn't have
America that doesn't have an
America that doesn't have an AA
America that doesn't have an AA group
that
that I
America that doesn't have an AA group
that I know,
that I know, dualep
America that doesn't have an AA group
that I know, dualep group,
>> miracles
>> miracles groups,
Bible
Bible study
>> miracles groups,
Bible study groups,
healing
healing groups,
St.
St. Luke
healing groups,
St. Luke groups,
they're
they're everywhere.
they're everywhere. However,
they're everywhere. However, if
they're everywhere. However, if you
they're everywhere. However, if you want
to
to move
they're everywhere. However, if you want
to move here,
to move here, that's
they're everywhere. However, if you want
to move here, that's great.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Thank you
>> Okay. Thank you very
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
I
I have
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
I have to
I have to tell
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
I have to tell the
I have to tell the chamber
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
I have to tell the chamber of
I have to tell the chamber of commerce
about
about this.
>> Interest
>> Interest in
about this.
>> Interest in spirituality,
>> Interest in spirituality, come
about this.
>> Interest in spirituality, come to
Sedona.
32 different
32 different spiritual
Sedona.
32 different spiritual groups
32 different spiritual groups every
night
night of
night of the
night of the week.
>> Hello,
>> Hello, Dr.
night of the week.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. And
night of the week.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. And I
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. And I want
night of the week.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. And I want to
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. And I want to thank
you
you so
you so much.
you so much. Mhm.
>> Uh,
>> Uh, a
you so much. Mhm.
>> Uh, a question
>> Uh, a question I
you so much. Mhm.
>> Uh, a question I have
>> Uh, a question I have is
you so much. Mhm.
>> Uh, a question I have is when
>> Uh, a question I have is when you
you so much. Mhm.
>> Uh, a question I have is when you showed
that
that chart
that chart with
that chart with infatuation
that chart with infatuation and
that chart with infatuation and love.
>> Mhm.
>> Um,
>> Um, what
>> Um, what came
>> Um, what came to
>> Um, what came to me
>> Um, what came to me was
>> Um, what came to me was when
>> Um, what came to me was when you
>> Um, what came to me was when you first
met
met your
>> Um, what came to me was when you first
met your beautiful
met your beautiful wife,
>> Um, what came to me was when you first
met your beautiful wife, Susan,
was
was it
was it love
was it love at
was it love at first
was it love at first sight?
>> Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> I
>> I was
>> Thank you very much.
>> I was just
>> I was just wondering
>> Thank you very much.
>> I was just wondering about
>> I was just wondering about the
circumstances.
>> It
>> It was
circumstances.
>> It was an
>> It was an energy.
circumstances.
>> It was an energy. It
>> It was an energy. It was
circumstances.
>> It was an energy. It was just
>> It was an energy. It was just a
circumstances.
>> It was an energy. It was just a energy.
>> And
>> And you
>> And you knew.
>> You
>> You knew.
>> And you knew.
>> You knew. you
>> You knew. you knew.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> It
>> It went
>> Thank you very much.
>> It went both
>> It went both ways.
>> It
>> It didn't
>> It didn't require
>> It didn't require any
>> It didn't require any thought.
>> Just
>> Just like
>> First
>> First of
>> First of all,
>> First of all, I
>> First of all, I want
>> First of all, I want to
>> First of all, I want to say
>> First of all, I want to say thank
>> First of all, I want to say thank you.
>> First of all, I want to say thank you. a
couple
couple of
>> First of all, I want to say thank you. a
couple of months
couple of months ago
>> First of all, I want to say thank you. a
couple of months ago or
couple of months ago or a
>> First of all, I want to say thank you. a
couple of months ago or a couple
sessions
sessions ago,
sessions ago, you
sessions ago, you recommended
sessions ago, you recommended I
sessions ago, you recommended I join
like
like an
sessions ago, you recommended I join
like an Allenon
like an Allenon 12step
sessions ago, you recommended I join
like an Allenon 12step group
like an Allenon 12step group and
sessions ago, you recommended I join
like an Allenon 12step group and I
like an Allenon 12step group and I have
joined
joined it
joined it and
joined it and I'm
joined it and I'm working
joined it and I'm working through
joined it and I'm working through it
joined it and I'm working through it and
thank
thank you
joined it and I'm working through it and
thank you very
thank you very much
joined it and I'm working through it and
thank you very much for
thank you very much for that.
joined it and I'm working through it and
thank you very much for that. Been
thank you very much for that. Been a
great
great source
great source of
great source of help.
great source of help. You
great source of help. You talked
great source of help. You talked about
relationships
relationships and
great source of help. You talked about
relationships and my
relationships and my question
great source of help. You talked about
relationships and my question is
relationships and my question is in
finding
finding a
finding a companionship
in
in that
finding a companionship
in that relationship
in that relationship so
finding a companionship
in that relationship so that
in that relationship so that you
finding a companionship
in that relationship so that you don't
make
make mistakes.
make mistakes. Mhm.
>> And
>> And uh
make mistakes. Mhm.
>> And uh what
>> And uh what I've
make mistakes. Mhm.
>> And uh what I've used
>> And uh what I've used is
make mistakes. Mhm.
>> And uh what I've used is like
>> And uh what I've used is like a
make mistakes. Mhm.
>> And uh what I've used is like a like
>> And uh what I've used is like a like an
initial
initial filter
initial filter where
initial filter where you
initial filter where you uh
initial filter where you uh you
initial filter where you uh you know
initial filter where you uh you know ask
if
if the
initial filter where you uh you know ask
if the person
if the person positively
initial filter where you uh you know ask
if the person positively fulfills
if the person positively fulfills what
you
you value
you value as
you value as as
you value as as one
you value as as one filter.
you value as as one filter. Is
you value as as one filter. Is that
person
person at
you value as as one filter. Is that
person at a
person at a level
you value as as one filter. Is that
person at a level of
person at a level of integrity
you value as as one filter. Is that
person at a level of integrity or
person at a level of integrity or above?
>> Uh
>> Uh and
>> Uh and is
>> Uh and is there
>> Uh and is there intentions
>> Uh and is there intentions towards
>> Uh and is there intentions towards you
>> um
>> um of
>> Uh and is there intentions towards you
>> um of the
>> um of the highest
>> Uh and is there intentions towards you
>> um of the highest good
>> um of the highest good and
>> Uh and is there intentions towards you
>> um of the highest good and highest
purpose?
purpose? Okay.
purpose? Okay. But
purpose? Okay. But what
purpose? Okay. But what happens
purpose? Okay. But what happens when
purpose? Okay. But what happens when you
get
get to
purpose? Okay. But what happens when you
get to you
get to you know
purpose? Okay. But what happens when you
get to you know you
get to you know you got
purpose? Okay. But what happens when you
get to you know you got a
get to you know you got a group
purpose? Okay. But what happens when you
get to you know you got a group that
fits
fits into
fits into that
fits into that category?
fits into that category? Is
fits into that category? Is there
fits into that category? Is there like
fits into that category? Is there like a
critical
critical point
fits into that category? Is there like a
critical point analysis
critical point analysis that
fits into that category? Is there like a
critical point analysis that you
critical point analysis that you can
fits into that category? Is there like a
critical point analysis that you can uh
apply?
>> How
>> How about
apply?
>> How about for
>> How about for you?
apply?
>> How about for you? It
>> How about for you? It went
apply?
>> How about for you? It went pop,
>> How about for you? It went pop, you
know.
>> How
>> How about
know.
>> How about polygamy?
>> How about polygamy? You
know.
>> How about polygamy? You could
>> How about polygamy? You could just
know.
>> How about polygamy? You could just marry
them
them all.
>> Might
>> Might be
them all.
>> Might be a
>> Might be a biggamist
them all.
>> Might be a biggamist then.
>> Well,
>> Well, the
>> Well, the lucky
>> Well, the lucky the
>> Well, the lucky the lucky
>> Well, the lucky the lucky winner
>> Well, the lucky the lucky winner will
get
get you
lucky
lucky winner.
>> Is
>> Is there
lucky winner.
>> Is there a
>> Is there a do
lucky winner.
>> Is there a do you
>> Is there a do you have
lucky winner.
>> Is there a do you have like
>> Is there a do you have like a
lucky winner.
>> Is there a do you have like a some
>> Is there a do you have like a some type
of
of thought
of thought towards?
>> No,
>> No, because
of thought towards?
>> No, because there's
>> No, because there's so
of thought towards?
>> No, because there's so many
>> No, because there's so many karmic
influences
influences too.
influences too. You
influences too. You see?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. And
influences too. You see?
>> Yes. And you
>> Yes. And you choose
influences too. You see?
>> Yes. And you choose that
>> Yes. And you choose that which
influences too. You see?
>> Yes. And you choose that which you
consider
consider to
consider to be
consider to be aligned
consider to be aligned with
consider to be aligned with your
intentions
intentions and
consider to be aligned with your
intentions and purposes.
And
And then
And then the
And then the rest
And then the rest is
And then the rest is pretty
And then the rest is pretty much
And then the rest is pretty much up
And then the rest is pretty much up to
karma.
karma. I
And then the rest is pretty much up to
karma. I think
karma. I think you
And then the rest is pretty much up to
karma. I think you know
karma. I think you know and
all
all you
all you can
all you can set
all you can set is
all you can set is your
all you can set is your intention.
>> Okay.
>> And
>> And that
>> And that intention
>> And that intention should
>> And that intention should pull
>> And that intention should pull to
>> And that intention should pull to you
that
that which
>> And that intention should pull to you
that which is
that which is uh
harmonious
harmonious harmonious
harmonious harmonious with
harmonious harmonious with your
intention.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
Yeah.
>> Hi,
>> Hi, David.
>> Hi, David. My
>> Hi, David. My name
>> Hi, David. My name is
>> Hi, David. My name is Jeff.
>> Yes.
>> When
>> When you
>> When you experience
>> When you experience the
>> When you experience the pits
>> When you experience the pits of
>> When you experience the pits of hell
>> When you experience the pits of hell in
this
this incarnation,
>> When you experience the pits of hell in
this incarnation, did
this incarnation, did your
>> When you experience the pits of hell in
this incarnation, did your calibration
level
level go
level go down?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, God.
level go down?
>> Oh, God. I
>> Oh, God. I wouldn't
level go down?
>> Oh, God. I wouldn't know.
>> Oh, God. I wouldn't know. It
level go down?
>> Oh, God. I wouldn't know. It was
>> Oh, God. I wouldn't know. It was off
level go down?
>> Oh, God. I wouldn't know. It was off the
chart.
Was
Was off
chart.
Was off the
Was off the chart.
You
>> Okay.
>> Okay. And
You
>> Okay. And also,
>> Okay. And also, I
You
>> Okay. And also, I was
>> Okay. And also, I was going
You
>> Okay. And also, I was going to
>> Okay. And also, I was going to ask
You
>> Okay. And also, I was going to ask you
>> Okay. And also, I was going to ask you a
hypothetical
hypothetical question.
hypothetical question. I
hypothetical question. I recognized
hypothetical question. I recognized it
as
as hypothetical
hypothetical question. I recognized it
as hypothetical as
as hypothetical as soon
hypothetical question. I recognized it
as hypothetical as soon as
as hypothetical as soon as I
hypothetical question. I recognized it
as hypothetical as soon as I started,
as hypothetical as soon as I started, so
I
I won't
I won't ask
I won't ask it.
I won't ask it. But
I won't ask it. But I
I won't ask it. But I brought
I won't ask it. But I brought you
something
something today.
I won't ask it. But I brought you
something today. Yeah.
>> This
>> This is
>> This is from
>> This is from uh
>> This is from uh Katie,
>> This is from uh Katie, the
>> This is from uh Katie, the marupial
lady.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yes.
>> She
>> She likes
>> Oh, yes.
>> She likes little
>> She likes little animals.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And you
>> Yes.
>> And you often
>> And you often speak
>> Yes.
>> And you often speak about
>> And you often speak about Shreddinger's
equation.
>> So,
>> So, she
equation.
>> So, she picked
>> So, she picked you
equation.
>> So, she picked you out.
>> So, she picked you out. Shreddinger's
cat.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
cat.
>> Oh, yeah. Shredder's
>> Oh, yeah. Shredder's cat.
cat.
>> Oh, yeah. Shredder's cat. That's
>> Oh, yeah. Shredder's cat. That's a
cat.
>> Oh, yeah. Shredder's cat. That's a very
famous
famous cat.
famous cat. Those
famous cat. Those of
famous cat. Those of you
famous cat. Those of you who
famous cat. Those of you who are
familiar
familiar with
famous cat. Those of you who are
familiar with quantum
familiar with quantum mechanics,
Shreddinger's
Shreddinger's cat
Shreddinger's cat is
Shreddinger's cat is a
Shreddinger's cat is a is
Shreddinger's cat is a is a
Shreddinger's cat is a is a great
teaching
teaching example.
Shreddinger's cat is a is a great
teaching example. Shreddinger
teaching example. Shreddinger set
Shreddinger's cat is a is a great
teaching example. Shreddinger set the
the
the equations
the equations you
the equations you know
the
the the
the equations you know
the the condition
the the condition of
the equations you know
the the condition of the
the the condition of the universe
the equations you know
the the condition of the universe as
the the condition of the universe as it
is
is calculated
is calculated by
is calculated by shreddinger's
is calculated by shreddinger's equations
which
which are
is calculated by shreddinger's equations
which are both
which are both time
is calculated by shreddinger's equations
which are both time independent
which are both time independent and
is calculated by shreddinger's equations
which are both time independent and time
dependent.
dependent. Then
dependent. Then by
dependent. Then by choice
dependent. Then by choice you
dependent. Then by choice you collapse
the
the wave
dependent. Then by choice you collapse
the wave function
the wave function potentiality
dependent. Then by choice you collapse
the wave function potentiality into
actuality
and
and you
actuality
and you can
and you can recalculate
actuality
and you can recalculate you
and you can recalculate you know
actuality
and you can recalculate you know the
potential
potential energy.
potential energy. Now
potential energy. Now using
potential energy. Now using a
potential energy. Now using a different
set
set of
potential energy. Now using a different
set of uh
formulas
derog
derog equations.
>> Mhm.
>> And
>> And according
>> Mhm.
>> And according to
>> And according to the
>> Mhm.
>> And according to the little
>> And according to the little tag
>> Mhm.
>> And according to the little tag on
>> And according to the little tag on the
cat,
cat, the
cat, the significance
cat, the significance of
cat, the significance of the
cat, the significance of the cat
cat, the significance of the cat is
cat, the significance of the cat is that
he's
he's in
cat, the significance of the cat is that
he's in a
he's in a box
cat, the significance of the cat is that
he's in a box and
he's in a box and he
cat, the significance of the cat is that
he's in a box and he might
he's in a box and he might be
cat, the significance of the cat is that
he's in a box and he might be dead
he's in a box and he might be dead or
cat, the significance of the cat is that
he's in a box and he might be dead or he
might
might be
might be alive
might be alive and
might be alive and therefore
might be alive and therefore he's
might be alive and therefore he's both
dead
dead and
might be alive and therefore he's both
dead and alive
dead and alive at
might be alive and therefore he's both
dead and alive at the
dead and alive at the same
might be alive and therefore he's both
dead and alive at the same time.
>> That's
>> That's true.
>> That's true. That's
>> That's true. That's that's
>> That's true. That's that's the
>> That's true. That's that's the box.
>> That's true. That's that's the box. And
it
it has
>> That's true. That's that's the box. And
it has a
it has a little
>> That's true. That's that's the box. And
it has a little note
it has a little note to
>> That's true. That's that's the box. And
it has a little note to PETA
it has a little note to PETA members
>> That's true. That's that's the box. And
it has a little note to PETA members on
there
there that
there that no
there that no cat
there that no cat was
there that no cat was harmed
there that no cat was harmed in
there that no cat was harmed in the
making
making of
there that no cat was harmed in the
making of this
making of this equation.
>> That's
>> That's good.
>> That's good. No
>> That's good. No cat
>> That's good. No cat was
>> That's good. No cat was harmed.
>> He's
>> He's a
>> That's good. No cat was harmed.
>> He's a really
>> He's a really cute
>> That's good. No cat was harmed.
>> He's a really cute cat.
>> He's a really cute cat. And
>> That's good. No cat was harmed.
>> He's a really cute cat. And he
>> He's a really cute cat. And he looks
confused,
confused, too.
confused, too. His
confused, too. His two
confused, too. His two eyeballs
confused, too. His two eyeballs are
confused, too. His two eyeballs are like
this.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. The
>> Yeah. The Heisenberg
>> Yeah. The Heisenberg principle
>> Yeah. The Heisenberg principle has
>> Yeah. The Heisenberg principle has made
a
a big
>> Yeah. The Heisenberg principle has made
a big difference.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Most
>> Yeah. Most of the
>> Yeah. Most of the science
>> Yeah. Most of the science hasn't
>> Yeah. Most of the science hasn't gotten
it
it yet,
>> Yeah. Most of the science hasn't gotten
it yet, but
Thank
Thank you
Thank you for
Thank you for all
Thank you for all your
Thank you for all your work.
Thank you for all your work. I
Thank you for all your work. I wanted
Thank you for all your work. I wanted to
ask
ask for
Thank you for all your work. I wanted to
ask for help
ask for help with
Thank you for all your work. I wanted to
ask for help with discernment
ask for help with discernment in
Thank you for all your work. I wanted to
ask for help with discernment in in
wanting
wanting to
to
to have
wanting to
to have a
to have a life
wanting to
to have a life of
to have a life of service
wanting to
to have a life of service and
to have a life of service and place
wanting to
to have a life of service and place like
my
my resources
my resources and
my resources and my
my resources and my time
my resources and my time at
my resources and my time at the
my resources and my time at the service
of
of people.
my resources and my time at the service
of people. I
of people. I I
my resources and my time at the service
of people. I I feel
of people. I I feel it
my resources and my time at the service
of people. I I feel it seems
of people. I I feel it seems as
my resources and my time at the service
of people. I I feel it seems as though
I'm
I'm a
I'm a sucker.
I'm a sucker. I
I'm a sucker. I feel
I'm a sucker. I feel like
I'm a sucker. I feel like um
I'm a sucker. I feel like um I
I'm a sucker. I feel like um I live
I'm a sucker. I feel like um I live in
northern
northern Arizona
I'm a sucker. I feel like um I live in
northern Arizona on
northern Arizona on the
I'm a sucker. I feel like um I live in
northern Arizona on the Navajo
reservation
and
I
I would
I would like
I would like to
offer
being
being a
being a person
being a person of
being a person of serenity
being a person of serenity and
being a person of serenity and peace
being a person of serenity and peace and
stability
stability maybe
being a person of serenity and peace and
stability maybe and
people
people that
people that I've
people that I've met
people that I've met from
people that I've met from you
people that I've met from you know
12step
12step or
people that I've met from you know
12step or jail
12step or jail or
people that I've met from you know
12step or jail or different
12step or jail or different places
Um,
I
I feel
Um,
I feel like
I feel like I'm
Um,
I feel like I'm being
I feel like I'm being taken
Um,
I feel like I'm being taken advantage
I feel like I'm being taken advantage of
or
or I'm
or I'm not
or I'm not making
or I'm not making wise
or I'm not making wise choices
or I'm not making wise choices with
or I'm not making wise choices with what
to
to do
or I'm not making wise choices with what
to do with
to do with my
or I'm not making wise choices with what
to do with my time.
>> You
>> You have
>> You have a
>> You have a job
>> You have a job there.
>> You have a job there. What
>> You have a job there. What do
>> You have a job there. What do you
>> You have a job there. What do you do
there?
>> I
>> I used
>> I used to
>> I used to work
>> I used to work as
>> I used to work as a
>> I used to work as a a
>> I used to work as a a physician
>> I used to work as a a physician and
>> I used to work as a a physician and my
husband
husband still
>> I used to work as a a physician and my
husband still works
husband still works there.
>> Yeah.
>> I
>> I stopped
>> Yeah.
>> I stopped working
>> I stopped working there
>> Yeah.
>> I stopped working there about
>> I stopped working there about nine
>> Yeah.
>> I stopped working there about nine years
ago.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And
>> And we
>> And we still
>> And we still live
>> And we still live there
>> And we still live there and
>> And we still live there and there's
>> And we still live there and there's a
lot
lot of
>> And we still live there and there's a
lot of there
lot of there is
>> And we still live there and there's a
lot of there is a
lot of there is a lot
>> And we still live there and there's a
lot of there is a lot of
lot of there is a lot of beauty
>> And we still live there and there's a
lot of there is a lot of beauty and
lot of there is a lot of beauty and I
have
>> a
>> a lot
have
>> a lot of
>> a lot of what?
>> Beautiful
>> Beautiful beauty.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> And
>> what's
>> what's the
>> And
>> what's the question?
helping
helping me
helping me discern
helping me discern when
helping me discern when a
helping me discern when a person
helping me discern when a person comes
to
to me
helping me discern when a person comes
to me asking
to me asking for
helping me discern when a person comes
to me asking for help
to me asking for help of
helping me discern when a person comes
to me asking for help of time
to me asking for help of time or
helping me discern when a person comes
to me asking for help of time or money
or
or resources
discerning
discerning whether
or resources
discerning whether it's
discerning whether it's coming
or resources
discerning whether it's coming from
discerning whether it's coming from a
place
place of
or
or whether
place of
or whether you're
or whether you're being
place of
or whether you're being worth
>> right
>> oh
>> oh you
>> right
>> oh you can
>> oh you can only
>> right
>> oh you can only do
>> oh you can only do it
>> right
>> oh you can only do it by
>> oh you can only do it by I
>> right
>> oh you can only do it by I guess
kinesiology
we
we often
kinesiology
we often ask
we often ask you
kinesiology
we often ask you know
we often ask you know we
kinesiology
we often ask you know we get
we often ask you know we get all
kinesiology
we often ask you know we get all kinds
of
of propositions
>> this
>> this proposition
of propositions
>> this proposition caliates
>> this proposition caliates over
of propositions
>> this proposition caliates over 200
>> this proposition caliates over 200 yes
no
>> all
>> all right
no
>> all right to
>> all right to to
no
>> all right to to do
>> all right to to do such
no
>> all right to to do such and
>> all right to to do such and such
no
>> all right to to do such and such would
serve
serve the
serve the highest
serve the highest good.
>> I
>> I would
serve the highest good.
>> I would use
>> I would use kinesiology
>> and
>> and I
>> and I I
>> and I I don't
>> and I I don't I
>> and I I don't I don't
>> and I I don't I don't trust
>> and I I don't I don't trust my
>> and I I don't I don't trust my ability
to
to do
>> and I I don't I don't trust my ability
to do that.
>> Well,
>> Well, practice
>> Well, practice it
>> Well, practice it like
>> Well, practice it like riding
>> Well, practice it like riding a
>> Well, practice it like riding a bicycle
this
this way.
>> Well,
>> Well, she's
>> Well, she's got
>> Well, she's got a
>> Well, she's got a husband.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Okay. So I
>> Okay. So I I
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Okay. So I I was
>> Okay. So I I was wondering
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Okay. So I I was wondering is
>> Okay. So I I was wondering is like
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Okay. So I I was wondering is like the
gut
gut sense
gut sense that
gut sense that gh
gut sense that gh I
gut sense that gh I feel
gut sense that gh I feel like
gut sense that gh I feel like I
gut sense that gh I feel like I just
>> Well,
>> Well, you
gut sense that gh I feel like I just
>> Well, you could
>> Well, you could use
gut sense that gh I feel like I just
>> Well, you could use your
>> Well, you could use your gut
gut sense that gh I feel like I just
>> Well, you could use your gut sense
>> Well, you could use your gut sense too
>> when
>> when you
>> when you feel
>> when you feel like
>> when you feel like you're
>> when you feel like you're being
>> when you feel like you're being had
whether
whether it's
>> when you feel like you're being had
whether it's a
whether it's a real
>> when you feel like you're being had
whether it's a real need
whether it's a real need or
>> when you feel like you're being had
whether it's a real need or whether
whether it's a real need or whether it's
a
artificially
artificially created
a
artificially created need
artificially created need to
a
artificially created need to work
artificially created need to work you
for
for something
>> and
>> and then
for something
>> and then I
>> other
>> other than
>> other than a
>> other than a kinesiologic
>> other than a kinesiologic diagnosis
there's
there's no
>> other than a kinesiologic diagnosis
there's no objective
there's no objective way
>> other than a kinesiologic diagnosis
there's no objective way I
there's no objective way I could
>> other than a kinesiologic diagnosis
there's no objective way I could think
of
of to
of to discern
>> and
>> and be
of to discern
>> and be willing
>> and be willing to
of to discern
>> and be willing to forgive
>> and be willing to forgive myself
of to discern
>> and be willing to forgive myself if
>> and be willing to forgive myself if I
feel
feel like
feel like I
>> so
>> so what
feel like I
>> so what if
>> so what if you
Well,
Well, then
Well, then I
Well, then I feel
Well, then I feel like,
Well, then I feel like, oh,
Well, then I feel like, oh, I'm
Well, then I feel like, oh, I'm an
enabler
enabler and
Well, then I feel like, oh, I'm an
enabler and I
enabler and I messed
Well, then I feel like, oh, I'm an
enabler and I messed up
enabler and I messed up and
>> Oh,
>> Oh, that's
>> Oh, that's your
>> Oh, that's your problem.
>> So,
>> So, you
>> Oh, that's your problem.
>> So, you just
>> So, you just go
>> Oh, that's your problem.
>> So, you just go on.
>> Okay.
>> You
>> You make
>> Okay.
>> You make mistakes
>> You make mistakes and
>> Okay.
>> You make mistakes and you
>> You make mistakes and you go
>> Okay.
>> You make mistakes and you go on.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So,
>> Yeah. So, maybe
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, maybe you
>> Yeah. So, maybe you were
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, maybe you were an
>> Yeah. So, maybe you were an enabler
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, maybe you were an enabler and
now
now he's
now he's dead.
now he's dead. So,
now he's dead. So, he's
now he's dead. So, he's dead.
>> I
>> I didn't
now he's dead. So, he's dead.
>> I didn't ask
>> I didn't ask him
now he's dead. So, he's dead.
>> I didn't ask him to
>> I didn't ask him to die,
now he's dead. So, he's dead.
>> I didn't ask him to die, did
>> I didn't ask him to die, did I?
now he's dead. So, he's dead.
>> I didn't ask him to die, did I? Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> He's
>> He's got
>> Thank you.
>> He's got his
>> He's got his own
>> Thank you.
>> He's got his own karma.
>> He's got his own karma. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So,
>> Yeah. So, your
>> Yeah. So, your intention,
>> Yeah. So, your intention, you're
responsible
responsible for
>> Yeah. So, your intention, you're
responsible for your
responsible for your intention,
>> not
>> not the
>> not the outcome,
>> not
>> not the
>> not the outcome,
>> not the outcome.
>> not the outcome. You're
>> not the outcome,
>> not the outcome. You're you're
responsible
responsible for
responsible for your
responsible for your intention,
responsible for your intention, not
responsible for your intention, not the
result.
result. Okay.
>> All
>> All right.
And
And if
>> All right.
And if you
And if you get
>> All right.
And if you get taken
And if you get taken in,
>> All right.
And if you get taken in, so
And if you get taken in, so you
>> All right.
And if you get taken in, so you got
And if you get taken in, so you got to
take
take it
take it in.
take it in. Big
take it in. Big deal.
>> Yeah.
>> Just
>> Just move
>> Just move it
>> Just move it down
>> Just move it down just
>> Just move it down just a
>> Just move it down just a little.
>> Just move it down just a little. Yeah.
>> Get
>> Get you
>> Just move it down just a little. Yeah.
>> Get you all
>> Get you all fixed
>> Just move it down just a little. Yeah.
>> Get you all fixed up
>> Get you all fixed up there,
>> Just move it down just a little. Yeah.
>> Get you all fixed up there, huh?
>> There
>> There you
>> There you go.
>> I'm
>> I'm a
>> There you go.
>> I'm a walking
>> I'm a walking microphone.
>> I
>> I know.
>> I know. Uh
>> I know. Uh my
>> I know. Uh my question
>> I know. Uh my question is
>> I know. Uh my question is about
>> I know. Uh my question is about uh
>> reincarnation
>> reincarnation the
>> I know. Uh my question is about uh
>> reincarnation the blueprint
>> reincarnation the blueprint or
>> I know. Uh my question is about uh
>> reincarnation the blueprint or the
intention.
intention. Now
intention. Now uh
intention. Now uh when
intention. Now uh when um
uh
uh we
intention. Now uh when um
uh we go
uh we go from
intention. Now uh when um
uh we go from lifetime
uh we go from lifetime to
intention. Now uh when um
uh we go from lifetime to lifetime.
Okay.
Okay. Our
Okay. Our energy
Okay. Our energy level
Okay. Our energy level or
>> that's
>> that's one
Okay. Our energy level or
>> that's one option.
>> that's one option. That's
Okay. Our energy level or
>> that's one option. That's one
>> that's one option. That's one option.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Uh
>> Okay. Uh does
>> Okay. Uh does it
>> Okay. Uh does it increase
>> Okay. Uh does it increase every
>> Okay. Uh does it increase every lifetime
onward
onward and
>> Okay. Uh does it increase every lifetime
onward and upward
onward and upward or
>> Okay. Uh does it increase every lifetime
onward and upward or does
onward and upward or does it
>> Okay. Uh does it increase every lifetime
onward and upward or does it fluctuate
like
like the
like the stock
like the stock market?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, a
like the stock market?
>> Oh, a lot
>> Oh, a lot of
like the stock market?
>> Oh, a lot of people
>> Oh, a lot of people make
like the stock market?
>> Oh, a lot of people make big
>> Oh, a lot of people make big mistakes.
So
So you
So you see,
So you see, you've
So you see, you've got
So you see, you've got the
So you see, you've got the option.
That's
That's why
So you see, you've got the option.
That's why you
That's why you earn
So you see, you've got the option.
That's why you earn karmic
That's why you earn karmic merit.
>> You
>> You don't
>> You don't earn
>> You don't earn karm
>> You don't earn karm karmic
>> You don't earn karm karmic merit
>> You don't earn karm karmic merit if
>> You don't earn karm karmic merit if the
only
only option
>> You don't earn karm karmic merit if the
only option you
only option you have
>> You don't earn karm karmic merit if the
only option you have is
only option you have is goodness.
It's
It's because
It's because you've
It's because you've got
It's because you've got to
It's because you've got to choose
between
between the
It's because you've got to choose
between the alternatives
between the alternatives that
It's because you've got to choose
between the alternatives that you
between the alternatives that you earn
karmic
karmic merit.
>> Okay?
>> Okay? If
karmic merit.
>> Okay? If you
>> Okay? If you have
karmic merit.
>> Okay? If you have a
>> Okay? If you have a a
karmic merit.
>> Okay? If you have a a certain
>> Okay? If you have a a certain if
karmic merit.
>> Okay? If you have a a certain if you
decide
decide your
decide your intention
decide your intention is
decide your intention is certain
decide your intention is certain uh
intent
intent and
decide your intention is certain uh
intent and you
intent and you require
decide your intention is certain uh
intent and you require a
intent and you require a lesser
decide your intention is certain uh
intent and you require a lesser uh
calibration.
calibration. I
calibration. I always
calibration. I always say
calibration. I always say you're
calibration. I always say you're 195
instead
instead of
calibration. I always say you're 195
instead of 300.
instead of 300. Does
calibration. I always say you're 195
instead of 300. Does it
instead of 300. Does it work
calibration. I always say you're 195
instead of 300. Does it work that
instead of 300. Does it work that way
calibration. I always say you're 195
instead of 300. Does it work that way or
does
does it
does it always
does it always continue
does it always continue to
does it always continue to go
does it always continue to go higher?
>> No,
>> No, you
does it always continue to go higher?
>> No, you can
>> No, you can make
does it always continue to go higher?
>> No, you can make bad
>> No, you can make bad choices.
>> Lots
>> Lots of
>> Lots of people
>> Lots of people have
>> Lots of people have crashed
>> Lots of people have crashed badly.
>> Lots of people have crashed badly. I
mean
mean big
>> Lots of people have crashed badly. I
mean big time
>> during
>> during the
>> during the lifetime.
>> during the lifetime. But
>> during the lifetime. But when
>> during the lifetime. But when you're
>> during
>> during this
>> during the lifetime. But when you're
>> during this lifetime.
>> during this lifetime. Yes.
>> during the lifetime. But when you're
>> during this lifetime. Yes. Well,
>> during this lifetime. Yes. Well, when
you
you come
you come into
you come into the
you come into the lifetime,
>> uh,
>> uh, you
you come into the lifetime,
>> uh, you you
>> uh, you you don't
you come into the lifetime,
>> uh, you you don't have
>> uh, you you don't have that
you come into the lifetime,
>> uh, you you don't have that intention,
though.
>> No.
>> Napoleon
>> Napoleon was
>> Napoleon was 440,
>> Napoleon was 440, I
>> Napoleon was 440, I think.
>> Then
>> Then he
>> Napoleon was 440, I think.
>> Then he crowned
>> Then he crowned himself
>> Napoleon was 440, I think.
>> Then he crowned himself em
>> Then he crowned himself em emperor,
denied
denied the
denied the divinity
denied the divinity and
denied the divinity and the
denied the divinity and the power
denied the divinity and the power of
denied the divinity and the power of God
and
and says,
denied the divinity and the power of God
and says, I
and says, I of
denied the divinity and the power of God
and says, I of myself
and says, I of myself can
denied the divinity and the power of God
and says, I of myself can proclaim
and says, I of myself can proclaim my
own
own sovereignty.
He
He went
own sovereignty.
He went from
He went from 440
own sovereignty.
He went from 440 to
He went from 440 to 175.
>> Wow.
>> And
>> And the
>> Wow.
>> And the Duke
>> And the Duke of
>> Wow.
>> And the Duke of Wellington
>> And the Duke of Wellington knocked
>> Wow.
>> And the Duke of Wellington knocked him
on
on his
on his tail.
>> Stalin
>> Stalin did
on his tail.
>> Stalin did the
>> Stalin did the same
on his tail.
>> Stalin did the same thing.
>> Stalin did the same thing. and
on his tail.
>> Stalin did the same thing. and Hitler
did
did the
did the same
did the same thing.
did the same thing. Castro
did the same thing. Castro did
did the same thing. Castro did the
did the same thing. Castro did the same
thing.
>> Okay.
>> So,
>> So, there's
>> Okay.
>> So, there's plenty
>> So, there's plenty of
>> Okay.
>> So, there's plenty of opportunity
to
to go
to go down.
>> Go
>> Go down.
>> Okay.
Thank
Thank you
>> Okay.
Thank you very
Thank you very much.
>> Yeah.
It's
It's your
>> Yeah.
It's your mind
It's your mind to
>> Yeah.
It's your mind to get
It's your mind to get to
>> Yeah.
It's your mind to get to be
It's your mind to get to be emperor.
Call
Call me.
Call me. Call
Call me. Call me.
Call me. Call me. I'll
Call me. Call me. I'll tell
Call me. Call me. I'll tell you.
>> Hi,
>> Hi, Dr.
Call me. Call me. I'll tell you.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Yeah.
Call me. Call me. I'll tell you.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Yeah. Um,
uh,
uh, probably
uh, probably about
uh, probably about 3
uh, probably about 3 or
uh, probably about 3 or 4
uh, probably about 3 or 4 weeks
uh, probably about 3 or 4 weeks ago,
uh, probably about 3 or 4 weeks ago, my
my
my girlfriend
uh, probably about 3 or 4 weeks ago, my
my girlfriend and
my girlfriend and I
uh, probably about 3 or 4 weeks ago, my
my girlfriend and I found
my girlfriend and I found out
uh, probably about 3 or 4 weeks ago, my
my girlfriend and I found out we
my girlfriend and I found out we were
pregnant.
pregnant. And,
pregnant. And, um,
>> found
>> found out
pregnant. And, um,
>> found out what?
>> We
>> We were
>> We were pregnant.
>> We
>> We were
>> We were pregnant.
>> We were pregnant. I'm
>> We were pregnant. I'm trying
>> We were pregnant. I'm trying to
>> We were pregnant. I'm trying to be
politically
politically correct
>> We were pregnant. I'm trying to be
politically correct and
politically correct and inclusive.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, is
>> Oh, is that
>> Oh, is that politically
>> Oh, is that politically correct?
>> I
>> I don't
>> Oh, is that politically correct?
>> I don't know.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. Go
>> Oh, yeah. Go ahead.
>> Um,
>> Um, and
>> Oh, yeah. Go ahead.
>> Um, and um,
>> yeah.
>> And
>> And uh,
>> yeah.
>> So,
>> So, that
>> yeah.
>> So, that was
>> So, that was shocking
>> yeah.
>> So, that was shocking to
>> So, that was shocking to the
>> yeah.
>> So, that was shocking to the ego,
>> So, that was shocking to the ego, of
course.
course. and
course. and um
course. and um and
course. and um and by
course. and um and by the
course. and um and by the grace
course. and um and by the grace of
course. and um and by the grace of the
divine
divine and
course. and um and by the grace of the
divine and and
divine and and thanks
course. and um and by the grace of the
divine and and thanks to
divine and and thanks to your
course. and um and by the grace of the
divine and and thanks to your teachings,
I
I mean,
I mean, a
I mean, a real
I mean, a real u
I mean, a real u surrender
I mean, a real u surrender and
I mean, a real u surrender and a
I mean, a real u surrender and a joy
I mean, a real u surrender and a joy and
a
a peace
I mean, a real u surrender and a joy and
a peace rose
a peace rose and
I mean, a real u surrender and a joy and
a peace rose and we're
a peace rose and we're welcoming
I mean, a real u surrender and a joy and
a peace rose and we're welcoming this
baby
baby into
baby into the
baby into the world.
>> So,
>> So, that's
baby into the world.
>> So, that's great.
>> So, that's great. And
baby into the world.
>> So, that's great. And now
>> So, that's great. And now I
baby into the world.
>> So, that's great. And now I I'd
>> So, that's great. And now I I'd just
like
like some
like some words
like some words of
like some words of wisdom
like some words of wisdom on
like some words of wisdom on fatherhood
and
avoid
avoid it
avoid it at
avoid it at all
avoid it at all cost.
avoid it at all cost. You
avoid it at all cost. You know,
>> he
>> he said
avoid it at all cost. You know,
>> he said avoid
>> he said avoid it
avoid it at all cost. You know,
>> he said avoid it at
>> he said avoid it at all
avoid it at all cost. You know,
>> he said avoid it at all cost.
Word
Word of
Word of advice
Word of advice about
Word of advice about fatherhood.
Uh
Uh it's
Word of advice about fatherhood.
Uh it's very
Uh it's very enjoyable,
Word of advice about fatherhood.
Uh it's very enjoyable, you
Uh it's very enjoyable, you know,
Word of advice about fatherhood.
Uh it's very enjoyable, you know, to
Uh it's very enjoyable, you know, to see
your
your little
your little progyny
your little progyny running
your little progyny running around
your little progyny running around and
uh
uh you
your little progyny running around and
uh you got
uh you got a
your little progyny running around and
uh you got a dog
uh you got a dog and
your little progyny running around and
uh you got a dog and a
uh you got a dog and a cat
your little progyny running around and
uh you got a dog and a cat and
uh you got a dog and a cat and a
your little progyny running around and
uh you got a dog and a cat and a kid,
you
you know,
you know, I
you know, I mean,
you know, I mean, you're
you know, I mean, you're all
you know, I mean, you're all set
now
now to
you know, I mean, you're all set
now to enjoy,
now to enjoy, you
you know, I mean, you're all set
now to enjoy, you know,
now to enjoy, you know, being
you know, I mean, you're all set
now to enjoy, you know, being to
now to enjoy, you know, being to be
you know, I mean, you're all set
now to enjoy, you know, being to be when
you
you see
you see what
you see what happens
you see what happens to
you see what happens to children
you see what happens to children who
don't
don't have
you see what happens to children who
don't have parenting.
>> It's
>> It's so
>> It's so severe.
>> It's so severe. It
>> It's so severe. It actually
>> It's so severe. It actually causes
neurological
neurological damage
>> to
>> to the
>> to the brain
>> to the brain lit
>> to the brain lit literally.
>> to the brain lit literally. So
>> to the brain lit literally. So you
>> to the brain lit literally. So you see
that
that your
>> to the brain lit literally. So you see
that your presence
that your presence your
>> to the brain lit literally. So you see
that your presence your intention
that your presence your intention and
your
your presence
your presence you
your presence you know
your presence you know radiates
your presence you know radiates a
certain
certain health
your presence you know radiates a
certain health and
certain health and uh
your presence you know radiates a
certain health and uh and
certain health and uh and especially
during
during the
during the early
during the early years
during the early years you
during the early years you know
during the early years you know it's
important
and
and then
and then to
and then to be
and then to be able
and then to be able to
and then to be able to support
and then to be able to support the
and then to be able to support the the
mother
mother you
and then to be able to support the the
mother you know
mother you know so
and then to be able to support the the
mother you know so not
mother you know so not only
and then to be able to support the the
mother you know so not only do
mother you know so not only do you
and then to be able to support the the
mother you know so not only do you serve
the
the child
the child but
the child but you
the child but you serve
the child but you serve the
the child but you serve the mother
the child but you serve the mother help
her
her to
the child but you serve the mother help
her to be
her to be the
the child but you serve the mother help
her to be the best
her to be the best mother
the child but you serve the mother help
her to be the best mother she
her to be the best mother she can
the child but you serve the mother help
her to be the best mother she can be
her to be the best mother she can be so
fulfilling
fulfilling then
fulfilling then the
fulfilling then the destiny
fulfilling then the destiny of
fulfilling then the destiny of humanness
>> born
>> born human
fulfilling then the destiny of humanness
>> born human So
>> born human So that
fulfilling then the destiny of humanness
>> born human So that brings
>> born human So that brings certain
obligations
obligations and
obligations and opportunities.
>> Mhm.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> You'll
>> You'll be
>> Thank you.
>> You'll be a
>> You'll be a good
>> Thank you.
>> You'll be a good dad.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You
>> Yeah. You mean
no
no and
>> Yeah. You mean
no and you're
no and you're responsible
>> Yeah. You mean
no and you're responsible person
wouldn't
wouldn't worry
wouldn't worry about
wouldn't worry about it.
>> Hello.
>> Yes.
>> Hi.
Well,
Well, in
Well, in February,
Well, in February, I
Well, in February, I was
Well, in February, I was here
Well, in February, I was here for
Well, in February, I was here for the
first
first lecture
Well, in February, I was here for the
first lecture and
first lecture and Susan
Well, in February, I was here for the
first lecture and Susan said,
first lecture and Susan said, "Why
didn't
didn't you
didn't you come
didn't you come up
didn't you come up and
didn't you come up and tell
didn't you come up and tell everybody
who
who you
didn't you come up and tell everybody
who you are?"
who you are?" So,
didn't you come up and tell everybody
who you are?" So, I'm
who you are?" So, I'm Sandra
didn't you come up and tell everybody
who you are?" So, I'm Sandra Sole
who you are?" So, I'm Sandra Sole and
I'm
I'm the
I'm the new
I'm the new unity
I'm the new unity minister
I'm the new unity minister here
I'm the new unity minister here in
I'm the new unity minister here in town.
>> And
>> And I
I'm the new unity minister here in town.
>> And I have
>> And I have a
I'm the new unity minister here in town.
>> And I have a question.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. We
>> Yes. We spoke
>> Yes. We spoke at
>> Yes. We spoke at Unity
>> Yes. We spoke at Unity about
>> Yes. We spoke at Unity about a
>> Yes. We spoke at Unity about a month
ago,
ago, right?
>> Yes. We spoke at Unity about a month
ago, right? We
ago, right? We did.
>> Yes. We spoke at Unity about a month
ago, right? We did. We
ago, right? We did. We did
>> Yes. We spoke at Unity about a month
ago, right? We did. We did a
ago, right? We did. We did a couple
>> Yes. We spoke at Unity about a month
ago, right? We did. We did a couple of
sermons.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> you
>> you weren't
>> you weren't there,
>> you weren't there, so
>> you weren't there, so we
>> you weren't there, so we took
>> you weren't there, so we took advantage
of
of it.
>> Yeah.
>> I
>> I ran
>> Yeah.
>> I ran up
>> I ran up and
>> Yeah.
>> I ran up and gave
>> I ran up and gave the
>> Yeah.
>> I ran up and gave the sermon.
>> I ran up and gave the sermon. She
>> Yeah.
>> I ran up and gave the sermon. She was
out
out of
out of town.
>> And
>> And he
out of town.
>> And he did
>> And he did a
out of town.
>> And he did a great
>> And he did a great job.
out of town.
>> And he did a great job. They're
>> And he did a great job. They're still
talking
talking about
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> It's
>> It's a
>> It's a spiritual
>> It's a spiritual community
>> It's a spiritual community that
>> It's a spiritual community that has
>> It's a spiritual community that has set
the
the intention
>> It's a spiritual community that has set
the intention with
the intention with their
>> It's a spiritual community that has set
the intention with their vision
the intention with their vision for
>> It's a spiritual community that has set
the intention with their vision for the
whole
whole community
whole community to
whole community to be
whole community to be spiritually
enlightened.
enlightened. Mhm.
>> And
as
as I
>> And
as I have
as I have come
>> And
as I have come into
as I have come into it,
>> And
as I have come into it, it's
as I have come into it, it's like
everybody's
everybody's been
everybody's been waiting
everybody's been waiting for
everybody's been waiting for me
everybody's been waiting for me to
arrive.
arrive. It
everybody's been waiting for me to
arrive. It seems
arrive. It seems like
everybody's been waiting for me to
arrive. It seems like there's
arrive. It seems like there's been
everybody's been waiting for me to
arrive. It seems like there's been this
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you're
>> Oh, you're the
>> Oh, you're the catalyst,
>> Oh, you're the catalyst, huh?
>> I
>> I got
>> Oh, you're the catalyst, huh?
>> I got here
>> I got here at
>> Oh, you're the catalyst, huh?
>> I got here at the
>> I got here at the right
>> Oh, you're the catalyst, huh?
>> I got here at the right time,
>> I got here at the right time, I
>> Oh, you're the catalyst, huh?
>> I got here at the right time, I guess.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, you're
>> Yeah, you're the
>> Yeah, you're the catalyst.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. and
>> Yeah, you're the catalyst.
>> Yeah. and and
>> Yeah. and and the
>> Yeah, you're the catalyst.
>> Yeah. and and the best
>> Yeah. and and the best that
>> Yeah, you're the catalyst.
>> Yeah. and and the best that I
>> Yeah. and and the best that I can
>> Yeah, you're the catalyst.
>> Yeah. and and the best that I can sense
and
and I
and I I
and I I just
and I I just maybe
and I I just maybe I'm
and I I just maybe I'm wanting
and I I just maybe I'm wanting you
and I I just maybe I'm wanting you to
give
give me
and I I just maybe I'm wanting you to
give me some
give me some guidance
and I I just maybe I'm wanting you to
give me some guidance about
give me some guidance about it
and I I just maybe I'm wanting you to
give me some guidance about it is
holding
holding that
holding that intention
holding that intention of
holding that intention of unconditional
love
love for
holding that intention of unconditional
love for the
love for the community
holding that intention of unconditional
love for the community and
love for the community and at
holding that intention of unconditional
love for the community and at the
love for the community and at the same
time
uh
and
and you
and you kind
and you kind of
and you kind of said
and you kind of said it
and you kind of said it again
and you kind of said it again over
and you kind of said it again over there
with
with somebody
and you kind of said it again over there
with somebody else
with somebody else is
and you kind of said it again over there
with somebody else is that
with somebody else is that that
and you kind of said it again over there
with somebody else is that that business
of
of of
of of really
of of really holding
of of really holding to
of of really holding to the
of of really holding to the integrity
that
that that's
of of really holding to the integrity
that that's kind
that that's kind of
of of really holding to the integrity
that that's kind of like
that that's kind of like my
of of really holding to the integrity
that that's kind of like my place
that that's kind of like my place of
holding
holding to
holding to the
holding to the integrity.
>> Um,
>> you're
>> you're the
>> you're the fulcrum.
>> you're the fulcrum. You're
>> you're the fulcrum. You're the
>> you're the fulcrum. You're the central
energy
energy that
>> you're the fulcrum. You're the central
energy that is
energy that is missing
>> you're the fulcrum. You're the central
energy that is missing and
energy that is missing and now
>> you're the fulcrum. You're the central
energy that is missing and now it
energy that is missing and now it just
happens
happens by
happens by virtue
happens by virtue of
happens by virtue of your
happens by virtue of your beingness.
happens by virtue of your beingness. You
don't
don't necessarily
happens by virtue of your beingness. You
don't necessarily have
don't necessarily have to
happens by virtue of your beingness. You
don't necessarily have to do
don't necessarily have to do much
happens by virtue of your beingness. You
don't necessarily have to do much about
it
it because
it because this
it because this just
it because this just automatically
it because this just automatically going
to
to become
it because this just automatically going
to become transformed
to become transformed by
it because this just automatically going
to become transformed by the
to become transformed by the fact
it because this just automatically going
to become transformed by the fact that
you're
you're here
you're here now.
You
You know,
you're here now.
You know, we
You know, we haven't
you're here now.
You know, we haven't got
You know, we haven't got no
you're here now.
You know, we haven't got no unity
minister
minister here.
minister here. God,
minister here. God, you
minister here. God, you know,
minister here. God, you know, so
minister here. God, you know, so finally
we
we got
minister here. God, you know, so finally
we got one.
we got one. Now
minister here. God, you know, so finally
we got one. Now we're
we got one. Now we're happy.
Everything's
Everything's fine
Everything's fine because
Everything's fine because we
Everything's fine because we got
Everything's fine because we got one.
>> Ah,
>> Ah, okay.
Everything's fine because we got one.
>> Ah, okay. Okay.
>> Ah, okay. Okay. Okay.
Everything's fine because we got one.
>> Ah, okay. Okay. Okay. So,
>> Ah, okay. Okay. Okay. So, Jess,
>> the
>> the biggest
>> the biggest gift
>> the biggest gift you're
>> the biggest gift you're giving
>> the biggest gift you're giving us
>> the biggest gift you're giving us is
>> the biggest gift you're giving us is to
be
be here.
>> All right.
>> To
>> To fulfill
>> All right.
>> To fulfill that
>> To fulfill that function,
>> All right.
>> To fulfill that function, to
>> To fulfill that function, to be
>> All right.
>> To fulfill that function, to be the
fulcrum,
>> to
>> to be
fulcrum,
>> to be the
>> to be the focus.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. And of
>> Yeah. And of course,
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. And of course, the
>> Yeah. And of course, the people
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. And of course, the people will
>> Yeah. And of course, the people will all
do
do the
do the work
do the work for
do the work for you,
do the work for you, you
do the work for you, you know,
do the work for you, you know, and
you're
you're the
do the work for you, you know, and
you're the orchestrate
you're the orchestrate it
do the work for you, you know, and
you're the orchestrate it and
>> be
>> be the
>> be the centrum
>> be the centrum around
>> be the centrum around which
>> be the centrum around which it
>> be the centrum around which it kind,
>> be the centrum around which it kind, you
know,
know, so
>> be the centrum around which it kind, you
know, so everybody's
know, so everybody's got
>> be the centrum around which it kind, you
know, so everybody's got to
know, so everybody's got to check
>> be the centrum around which it kind, you
know, so everybody's got to check with
somebody.
somebody. So,
somebody. So, you're
somebody. So, you're the
somebody. So, you're the somebody
somebody. So, you're the somebody they
check
check with.
somebody. So, you're the somebody they
check with. You
check with. You know what
somebody. So, you're the somebody they
check with. You know what I'm
check with. You know what I'm saying?
you
you know.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
you know.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Otherwise,
>> Otherwise, they're
>> Otherwise, they're like
>> Otherwise, they're like children
>> Otherwise, they're like children without
a
a teacher
>> Otherwise, they're like children without
a teacher in
a teacher in the
>> Otherwise, they're like children without
a teacher in the classroom.
a teacher in the classroom. You
what
what I'm
what I'm saying?
>> We're
>> We're certainly
what I'm saying?
>> We're certainly glad
>> We're certainly glad she's
what I'm saying?
>> We're certainly glad she's here.
>> We're
>> We're certainly
>> We're certainly glad
>> We're certainly glad we
>> We're certainly glad we she's
>> We're certainly glad we she's here.
>> Put
>> Put it
>> We're certainly glad we she's here.
>> Put it together
>> Put it together or
>> We're certainly glad we she's here.
>> Put it together or not.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh
>> Uh this
>> Yeah.
>> Uh this ego
>> Uh this ego has
>> Yeah.
>> Uh this ego has gotten
>> Uh this ego has gotten into
>> Yeah.
>> Uh this ego has gotten into a
positionality
positionality that's
positionality that's caused
positionality that's caused the
positionality that's caused the duality.
And
And the
positionality that's caused the duality.
And the duality
And the duality is
positionality that's caused the duality.
And the duality is this.
And the duality is this. How
positionality that's caused the duality.
And the duality is this. How does
And the duality is this. How does one
hold
hold unconditional
hold unconditional love
hold unconditional love towards
hold unconditional love towards all
hold unconditional love towards all and
avoid
avoid that
hold unconditional love towards all and
avoid that which
avoid that which is
hold unconditional love towards all and
avoid that which is negative?
>> You
>> You hold
>> You hold or
>> You hold or it's
>> You hold or it's a
>> You hold or it's a way
>> You hold or it's a way of
>> You hold or it's a way of being.
>> You hold or it's a way of being. Say
you're
you're mentalizing
>> You hold or it's a way of being. Say
you're mentalizing it
you're mentalizing it as
>> You hold or it's a way of being. Say
you're mentalizing it as either
you're mentalizing it as either or
decision.
You
You just
decision.
You just are
You just are that.
decision.
You just are that. And
You just are that. And that
decision.
You just are that. And that which
You just are that. And that which is
decision.
You just are that. And that which is not
like
like you
like you will
like you will be
like you will be repelled
like you will be repelled by
like you will be repelled by you.
Frankly,
you
so
so it's
you
so it's a
so it's a way
you
so it's a way of
so it's a way of being.
It's
It's an
It's an intention.
It's an intention. Yeah.
And
And uh
It's an intention. Yeah.
And uh that's
And uh that's all
It's an intention. Yeah.
And uh that's all you
And uh that's all you have
It's an intention. Yeah.
And uh that's all you have to
And uh that's all you have to do
It's an intention. Yeah.
And uh that's all you have to do about
it.
>> Be
>> Be that.
it.
>> Be that. Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> See,
>> See, it's
>> Thank you.
>> See, it's your
>> See, it's your intention
that
that brings
that brings that
that brings that about.
One
One helpful
that brings that about.
One helpful way
One helpful way is
that brings that about.
One helpful way is to
One helpful way is to see
that brings that about.
One helpful way is to see the
One helpful way is to see the beauty
that brings that about.
One helpful way is to see the beauty of
all
all that
all that exists.
all that exists. Just
all that exists. Just see
all that exists. Just see the
all that exists. Just see the the
all that exists. Just see the the beauty
of
of it.
>> Here's
>> Here's a
>> Here's a big
>> Here's a big tall
>> Here's a big tall handsome
>> Here's a big tall handsome guy.
>> Here's a big tall handsome guy. Looks
like
like Yep.
>> Here's a big tall handsome guy. Looks
like Yep. Y
>> Thanks.
>> Thanks. Um,
>> Thanks. Um, I
>> Thanks. Um, I was
>> Thanks. Um, I was just
>> Thanks. Um, I was just recently
>> Thanks. Um, I was just recently exposed
to
to your
>> Thanks. Um, I was just recently exposed
to your teachings
to your teachings and
>> Thanks. Um, I was just recently exposed
to your teachings and they've
to your teachings and they've really
resonated
resonated with
resonated with me
resonated with me and
resonated with me and I
resonated with me and I feel
resonated with me and I feel like
resonated with me and I feel like I
resonated with me and I feel like I have
a
a tremendous
resonated with me and I feel like I have
a tremendous amount
a tremendous amount of
resonated with me and I feel like I have
a tremendous amount of momentum
a tremendous amount of momentum built
up,
up, but
up, but I'm
up, but I'm really
up, but I'm really concerned
up, but I'm really concerned that
up, but I'm really concerned that I'm
going
going to
up, but I'm really concerned that I'm
going to lose
going to lose that
up, but I'm really concerned that I'm
going to lose that momentum
going to lose that momentum and
up, but I'm really concerned that I'm
going to lose that momentum and I'm
wondering
wondering if
wondering if you
wondering if you recommend
wondering if you recommend anything
specifically
specifically to
wondering if you recommend anything
specifically to kind
specifically to kind of
wondering if you recommend anything
specifically to kind of help
specifically to kind of help reinforce
your
your teachings
your teachings and
your teachings and just
your teachings and just kind
your teachings and just kind of
your teachings and just kind of build
into
into my
your teachings and just kind of build
into my daily
into my daily life
your teachings and just kind of build
into my daily life uh
into my daily life uh so
your teachings and just kind of build
into my daily life uh so I
into my daily life uh so I continue
your teachings and just kind of build
into my daily life uh so I continue to
move
move forward
move forward and
move forward and in
move forward and in the
move forward and in the right
move forward and in the right direction.
>> Well,
>> Well, you
move forward and in the right direction.
>> Well, you you
>> Well, you you try
move forward and in the right direction.
>> Well, you you try to
>> Well, you you try to find
move forward and in the right direction.
>> Well, you you try to find something
simple
simple something
simple something simple
simple something simple that
simple something simple that you
simple something simple that you can
recall.
recall. Let's
simple something simple that you can
recall. Let's say
recall. Let's say if
simple something simple that you can
recall. Let's say if your
recall. Let's say if your problem
simple something simple that you can
recall. Let's say if your problem is
you're
you're always
you're always angry
you're always angry and
you're always angry and indignant
you're always angry and indignant about
the
the state
you're always angry and indignant about
the state of
the state of the
you're always angry and indignant about
the state of the world
the state of the world and
you're always angry and indignant about
the state of the world and all
the state of the world and all the
sinners
sinners in
sinners in it
sinners in it and
sinners in it and god
sinners in it and god knows
sinners in it and god knows what.
sinners in it and god knows what. Uh
sinners in it and god knows what. Uh you
could
could just
sinners in it and god knows what. Uh you
could just pick
could just pick Socrates
sinners in it and god knows what. Uh you
could just pick Socrates see
and
and Socrates
and Socrates quote
and Socrates quote and
and Socrates quote and just
and Socrates quote and just frequently
remind
remind mind mind
and Socrates quote and just frequently
remind mind mind yourself
remind mind mind yourself of
and Socrates quote and just frequently
remind mind mind yourself of it
remind mind mind yourself of it and
eventually
eventually you'll
eventually you'll see
eventually you'll see that
eventually you'll see that everyone
eventually you'll see that everyone is
innocently
innocently just
eventually you'll see that everyone is
innocently just following
innocently just following their
eventually you'll see that everyone is
innocently just following their own.
They're
They're just
They're just being
They're just being who
They're just being who they
They're just being who they are.
They're just being who they are. Run
They're just being who they are. Run by
the
the belief
They're just being who they are. Run by
the belief systems
the belief systems that
They're just being who they are. Run by
the belief systems that are
the belief systems that are running
their
their heads,
you
you know,
their heads,
you know, like
you know, like in
their heads,
you know, like in a
you know, like in a sleep.
In
In a
In a sleep.
In a sleep. Yeah.
In a sleep. Yeah. That
In a sleep. Yeah. That people
In a sleep. Yeah. That people can't
In a sleep. Yeah. That people can't help
themselves
themselves from
In a sleep. Yeah. That people can't help
themselves from being
themselves from being what
In a sleep. Yeah. That people can't help
themselves from being what they
themselves from being what they are
because
because that's
because that's as
because that's as far
because that's as far as
because that's as far as they've
because that's as far as they've gotten
in
in evolution.
So,
some
some kind
So,
some kind of
some kind of just
So,
some kind of just um
anchor
anchor that
anchor that will
anchor that will take
anchor that will take you
anchor that will take you back
anchor that will take you back to
something,
something, the
anchor that will take you back to
something, the 91st
something, the 91st Psalm,
anchor that will take you back to
something, the 91st Psalm, for
something, the 91st Psalm, for instance.
The
The 91st
The 91st Psalm,
The 91st Psalm, pick
The 91st Psalm, pick something
The 91st Psalm, pick something that's
The 91st Psalm, pick something that's a
favorite
favorite that's
The 91st Psalm, pick something that's a
favorite that's very
favorite that's very meaningful
The 91st Psalm, pick something that's a
favorite that's very meaningful to
favorite that's very meaningful to you
and
and then
and then just
and then just refer
and then just refer to
and then just refer to it
and then just refer to it often
throughout
throughout the
and then just refer to it often
throughout the day.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
Mhm.
>> I'm
>> I'm Elder
>> I'm Elder Parson.
>> Hi.
>> I
>> I have
>> I have one
>> I have one question
>> I have one question first.
>> I have one question first. If
>> I have one question first. If I
>> I have one question first. If I get
>> I have one question first. If I get one,
can
can I
>> I have one question first. If I get one,
can I have
can I have the
>> I have one question first. If I get one,
can I have the first
can I have the first question
>> I have one question first. If I get one,
can I have the first question is
can I have the first question is may
>> I have one question first. If I get one,
can I have the first question is may I
shake
shake your
shake your hand?
>> Yes.
>> Do
>> Do I
>> Do I get
>> Do I get another
>> Do I get another one?
>> No,
>> No, that's
>> Do I get another one?
>> No, that's it.
One
One one
One one shake
One one shake is
One one shake is all
One one shake is all I
One one shake is all I get.
>> You
>> You want
One one shake is all I get.
>> You want me
>> You want me to
One one shake is all I get.
>> You want me to sign
>> You want me to sign that?
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, cuz
>> Yeah, cuz I
>> Yeah, cuz I don't
>> Yeah, cuz I don't know
>> Yeah, cuz I don't know where
>> Yeah, cuz I don't know where else
>> Yeah, cuz I don't know where else to
sign.
>> That'd
>> That'd be
>> That'd be nice.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, that's
>> That'd be nice.
>> Oh, that's a
>> Oh, that's a clever
>> That'd be nice.
>> Oh, that's a clever place
>> Oh, that's a clever place to
>> That'd be nice.
>> Oh, that's a clever place to put
>> Oh, that's a clever place to put it.
>> That'd be nice.
>> Oh, that's a clever place to put it. I
don't
don't know
don't know where
don't know where to
don't know where to sign
don't know where to sign it.
>> Just
>> Just right
don't know where to sign it.
>> Just right there.
>> Right
>> Right there.
>> Yeah.
>> Fine.
>> I
>> I just
>> Fine.
>> I just signed
>> I just signed the
>> Fine.
>> I just signed the back
>> I just signed the back of
>> Fine.
>> I just signed the back of my
>> I just signed the back of my left
>> Fine.
>> I just signed the back of my left hand
>> in
>> in your
>> in your in
>> in your in your
>> in your in your book
>> in your in your book power
>> in your in your book power versus
>> in your in your book power versus the
only
only one
>> in your in your book power versus the
only one I've
only one I've read
>> in your in your book power versus the
only one I've read so
only one I've read so far.
>> in your in your book power versus the
only one I've read so far. Yes.
only one I've read so far. Yes. But
>> in your in your book power versus the
only one I've read so far. Yes. But I'm
gonna
gonna read
gonna read that
gonna read that and
gonna read that and see
gonna read that and see that.
gonna read that and see that. Um
gonna read that and see that. Um my
pedantic
pedantic question
gonna read that and see that. Um my
pedantic question is
pedantic question is in
gonna read that and see that. Um my
pedantic question is in the
pedantic question is in the all
gonna read that and see that. Um my
pedantic question is in the all the
bibliography
bibliography you
bibliography you have
bibliography you have which
bibliography you have which is
bibliography you have which is just
blows
blows my
bibliography you have which is just
blows my mind
blows my mind is
bibliography you have which is just
blows my mind is uh
blows my mind is uh the
bibliography you have which is just
blows my mind is uh the a
blows my mind is uh the a lot
bibliography you have which is just
blows my mind is uh the a lot of
references
references to
references to the
references to the chaos
references to the chaos theory
references to the chaos theory and
references to the chaos theory and I
wonder
wonder the
references to the chaos theory and I
wonder the chaos
wonder the chaos theory
>> chaos
>> and
>> and I
>> chaos
>> and I wonder
>> and I wonder what
>> chaos
>> and I wonder what the
>> and I wonder what the references
>> chaos
>> and I wonder what the references Yeah.
And
>> you
>> you think
And
>> you think those
>> you think those are
And
>> you think those are impressive
references?
>> Oh
>> Oh yes.
>> Where
>> Where do
>> Where do you
>> Where do you see
>> Where do you see truth
>> Where do you see truth versus
>> Where do you see truth versus falsehood?
>> Yeah.
Anybody
Anybody argues
Anybody argues with
Anybody argues with me
Anybody argues with me is
Anybody argues with me is going
Anybody argues with me is going to
Anybody argues with me is going to be
Anybody argues with me is going to be up
against
against it.
Anybody argues with me is going to be up
against it. I
against it. I got
Anybody argues with me is going to be up
against it. I got enough
against it. I got enough references
Anybody argues with me is going to be up
against it. I got enough references to
blast
blast them
blast them right
blast them right off
blast them right off the
blast them right off the planet.
blast them right off the planet. Go
ahead.
ahead. We
blast them right off the planet. Go
ahead. We got
>> you
>> you know
>> you know which
>> you know which one
>> you know which one could
>> you know which one could I
>> you know which one could I read
>> you know which one could I read that?
>> What
>> What about
>> you know which one could I read that?
>> What about it
>> What about it now?
>> Which
>> Which one
>> Which one of
>> Which one of your
>> Which one of your references
>> Which one of your references on
>> Which one of your references on chaos
theory
theory do
>> Which one of your references on chaos
theory do you
theory do you think
>> Which one of your references on chaos
theory do you think I
theory do you think I could
>> Which one of your references on chaos
theory do you think I could get
theory do you think I could get the
>> Which one of your references on chaos
theory do you think I could get the most
out
out of?
>> Which
>> Which one
out of?
>> Which one of
>> Which one of the
out of?
>> Which one of the references
>> on
>> on chaos
>> on chaos theory?
>> Of
>> Of chaos
>> on chaos theory?
>> Of chaos theory.
Oh.
Oh. Uh,
Oh. Uh, there's
Oh. Uh, there's one
Oh. Uh, there's one that
Oh. Uh, there's one that where
Oh. Uh, there's one that where it
Oh. Uh, there's one that where it was
popularized.
popularized. Um,
Oh. Uh, there's one that where it was
popularized. Um, I
popularized. Um, I can't
Oh. Uh, there's one that where it was
popularized. Um, I can't think
popularized. Um, I can't think of
Oh. Uh, there's one that where it was
popularized. Um, I can't think of the
name
name now.
name now. There
name now. There was
name now. There was one
>> James
>> James Glick.
>> Huh?
>> James
>> James Glick
>> Huh?
>> James Glick in
>> James Glick in the
>> Huh?
>> James Glick in the book.
>> There
>> There you
>> There you go.
>> There you go. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. There's
>> There you go. Yeah.
>> Yeah. There's a
>> Yeah. There's a book
>> There you go. Yeah.
>> Yeah. There's a book that
>> Yeah. There's a book that popularizes
>> There you go. Yeah.
>> Yeah. There's a book that popularizes it
and
and makes
and makes it
and makes it comprehensible
and makes it comprehensible to
and makes it comprehensible to the
layman.
>> Glick.
>> Glick. What's
>> Glick. What's the
>> Glick. What's the name
>> Glick. What's the name of
>> Glick. What's the name of the
>> Glick. What's the name of the book
again?
>> Chaos.
>> Chaos. It's
>> Chaos. It's James
>> Chaos.
>> Chaos. It's James Glick.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, right.
>> Oh, right. Right.
>> Oh, right. Right. Yeah.
>> Oh, right. Right. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Oh, right. Right. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> There's
>> There's also
>> Oh, right. Right. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> There's also Menelbrook.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. middle
>> Yeah. middle of
>> Yeah. middle of seen
>> Yeah. middle of seen his
>> Yeah. middle of seen his fractile.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Chaos
>> Yeah. middle of seen his fractile.
>> Yeah. Chaos theory.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, those
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah, those two
>> Yeah, those two are
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah, those two are very
>> Yeah, those two are very good.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Excuse
>> Excuse me.
>> I
>> I think
>> what's
>> what's predictable
>> I think
>> what's predictable about
unpredictability.
unpredictability. That's
unpredictability. That's what
unpredictability. That's what it
unpredictability. That's what it wants
to
to know.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You
>> Yeah. You know,
>> it's
>> it's predictable
>> Yeah. You know,
>> it's predictable is
>> it's predictable is it's
>> Yeah. You know,
>> it's predictable is it's going
>> it's predictable is it's going to
>> Yeah. You know,
>> it's predictable is it's going to be
unpredictable,
unpredictable, which
unpredictable, which means
unpredictable, which means it
unpredictable, which means it could
unpredictable, which means it could stay
the
the same.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Nobody
>> Nobody ever
>> Thank you.
>> Nobody ever thinks
>> Nobody ever thinks of
>> Thank you.
>> Nobody ever thinks of that.
Uh
Uh follow
Uh follow that.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh
>> Uh my
>> Uh my question
>> Uh my question refers
>> Uh my question refers to
>> Uh my question refers to the
>> Uh my question refers to the chart
>> Uh my question refers to the chart you
showed
showed us
>> Uh my question refers to the chart you
showed us this
showed us this afternoon
>> Uh my question refers to the chart you
showed us this afternoon about
showed us this afternoon about the
relationships
relationships between
relationships between a
relationships between a infatuated
relationships between a infatuated sort
of
of relationship
relationships between a infatuated sort
of relationship and
of relationship and and
relationships between a infatuated sort
of relationship and and a
of relationship and and a relationship
of
of true
of true love.
of true love. uh
of true love. uh course
of true love. uh course of
of true love. uh course of miracles
speaks
speaks of
of true love. uh course of miracles
speaks of uh
speaks of uh unholy
of true love. uh course of miracles
speaks of uh unholy relationships
speaks of uh unholy relationships and
holy
holy relationships
holy relationships and
holy relationships and how
holy relationships and how uh
holy relationships and how uh through
prayer
prayer to
holy relationships and how uh through
prayer to the
prayer to the Holy
holy relationships and how uh through
prayer to the Holy Spirit
prayer to the Holy Spirit one
holy relationships and how uh through
prayer to the Holy Spirit one might
prayer to the Holy Spirit one might be
able
able to
>> um
>> um heal
able to
>> um heal the
>> um heal the relationship
able to
>> um heal the relationship through
powerful
powerful intention
powerful intention to
powerful intention to make
powerful intention to make it
>> I
>> I would
powerful intention to make it
>> I would guess
>> I would guess go
powerful intention to make it
>> I would guess go from
>> I would guess go from one
powerful intention to make it
>> I would guess go from one to
>> I would guess go from one to the
powerful intention to make it
>> I would guess go from one to the other
if
if their
if their intention
if their intention is
if their intention is strong
if their intention is strong enough
if their intention is strong enough is
it
>> in
>> in a
>> in a difficult
>> in a difficult relationship
>> in a difficult relationship which
>> in a difficult relationship which has
been
been let's
>> in a difficult relationship which has
been let's say
been let's say has
>> in a difficult relationship which has
been let's say has elements
been let's say has elements of
>> in a difficult relationship which has
been let's say has elements of maybe
both
both or
both or appears
both or appears to
both or appears to at
both or appears to at times
both or appears to at times if
both or appears to at times if that's
possible
>> is
>> is it
>> is it possible
>> is it possible to
work
work with
>> is it possible to
work with oneself
work with oneself and
>> is it possible to
work with oneself and with
work with oneself and with prayer
>> is it possible to
work with oneself and with prayer to
heal
heal that
heal that relationship
heal that relationship or
heal that relationship or is
heal that relationship or is one
heal that relationship or is one better
off
off cutting
heal that relationship or is one better
off cutting and
off cutting and running
heal that relationship or is one better
off cutting and running if
off cutting and running if it's
heal that relationship or is one better
off cutting and running if it's just
off cutting and running if it's just not
going
going to
going to work.
>> You've
>> You've done
going to work.
>> You've done the
>> You've done the whole
going to work.
>> You've done the whole course.
>> Uh
>> Uh many
>> Uh many years.
>> Oh,
all
all right.
all right. So,
all right. So, it's
all right. So, it's a
all right. So, it's a special
relationship.
relationship. So
>> when
>> when asking
>> when asking for
>> when asking for the
>> when asking for the miracle,
>> when asking for the miracle, you're
asking
asking to
>> when asking for the miracle, you're
asking to have
asking to have it
>> when asking for the miracle, you're
asking to have it reconextualized
asking to have it reconextualized so
that
that the
that the specialness
that the specialness is
that the specialness is removed
that the specialness is removed and
that the specialness is removed and you
see
see the
that the specialness is removed and you
see the essence
because
because any
because any two
because any two human
because any two human beings
because any two human beings who
because any two human beings who have
because any two human beings who have a
halfway
halfway reasonable
because any two human beings who have a
halfway reasonable intention
halfway reasonable intention toward
because any two human beings who have a
halfway reasonable intention toward each
other
other can
other can transcend
other can transcend specialness
other can transcend specialness because
specialness
specialness is
other can transcend specialness because
specialness is trying
specialness is trying to
other can transcend specialness because
specialness is trying to deduce
specialness is trying to deduce it
other can transcend specialness because
specialness is trying to deduce it for
something.
Uh
Uh so
something.
Uh so you'd
Uh so you'd have
something.
Uh so you'd have to
Uh so you'd have to find
something.
Uh so you'd have to find out
Uh so you'd have to find out what
remnants
remnants there
remnants there are
remnants there are of
remnants there are of specialness.
remnants there are of specialness. Is
remnants there are of specialness. Is it
control
control or
remnants there are of specialness. Is it
control or ownership
control or ownership or
remnants there are of specialness. Is it
control or ownership or what
control or ownership or what is
remnants there are of specialness. Is it
control or ownership or what is it
control or ownership or what is it and
whether
whether you're
whether you're willing
whether you're willing to
whether you're willing to relinquish
that?
>> Mhm.
>> Right.
So
So if
So if let's
So if let's say
So if let's say if
So if let's say if one
So if let's say if one feels
So if let's say if one feels they're
making
making a
So if let's say if one feels they're
making a sincere
making a sincere effort
So if let's say if one feels they're
making a sincere effort to
making a sincere effort to do
So if let's say if one feels they're
making a sincere effort to do that
making a sincere effort to do that but
the
the other
the other one
the other one wants
the other one wants to
the other one wants to drag
the other one wants to drag it
the other one wants to drag it back
the other one wants to drag it back down
to
to that
the other one wants to drag it back down
to that level
to that level is
the other one wants to drag it back down
to that level is one
to that level is one better
the other one wants to drag it back down
to that level is one better off
to that level is one better off just
trying
trying it
trying it may
trying it may not
trying it may not work.
trying it may not work. I
trying it may not work. I have
trying it may not work. I have an
investment
investment one
trying it may not work. I have an
investment one way
investment one way or
trying it may not work. I have an
investment one way or the
investment one way or the other.
trying it may not work. I have an
investment one way or the other. What
>> may
>> may not
>> may not work.
>> may not work. Yeah.
>> Just
>> Just uh
>> All right.
>> All right. Thank
>> All right. Thank you
>> All right. Thank you very
>> All right. Thank you very If
>> All right. Thank you very If one's
>> All right. Thank you very If one's very
spiritually
spiritually aligned
>> All right. Thank you very If one's very
spiritually aligned and
spiritually aligned and the
>> All right. Thank you very If one's very
spiritually aligned and the other
spiritually aligned and the other is
not,
not, it
not, it very
not, it very frequently
not, it very frequently does
not, it very frequently does not
not, it very frequently does not work.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> And
>> And that's
>> And that's a
>> And that's a miracle
>> And that's a miracle because
>> And that's a miracle because you
>> And that's a miracle because you get
free
free of
>> And that's a miracle because you get
free of it.
I
I mean,
I mean, one's
I mean, one's going
I mean, one's going to
I mean, one's going to keep
I mean, one's going to keep robbing
banks
banks and
I mean, one's going to keep robbing
banks and the
banks and the other's
I mean, one's going to keep robbing
banks and the other's going
banks and the other's going to
I mean, one's going to keep robbing
banks and the other's going to start
going
going to
going to church.
going to church. I
going to church. I mean,
going to church. I mean, you're
going to church. I mean, you're going
going to church. I mean, you're going to
get
get along,
going to church. I mean, you're going to
get along, you
get along, you know.
>> Hello.
>> My
>> My question
>> Hello.
>> My question um
>> My question um concerns
>> Hello.
>> My question um concerns the
>> My question um concerns the role
>> Hello.
>> My question um concerns the role of
suffering
suffering on
suffering on this
suffering on this path.
suffering on this path. It
suffering on this path. It seems
suffering on this path. It seems to
suffering on this path. It seems to me
in
in my
suffering on this path. It seems to me
in my limited
in my limited understanding
suffering on this path. It seems to me
in my limited understanding of
in my limited understanding of this
suffering on this path. It seems to me
in my limited understanding of this that
often
um
um enlightenment
often
um enlightenment or
um enlightenment or growth
often
um enlightenment or growth comes
um enlightenment or growth comes after
often
um enlightenment or growth comes after a
period
period of
>> maybe
>> suffering
>> suffering or
>> suffering or deep,
>> suffering or deep, you
>> suffering or deep, you know,
>> suffering or deep, you know, turmoil.
>> suffering or deep, you know, turmoil. Is
that
that necessary?
>> suffering or deep, you know, turmoil. Is
that necessary? And
that necessary? And if
>> suffering or deep, you know, turmoil. Is
that necessary? And if so,
that necessary? And if so, what's
>> suffering or deep, you know, turmoil. Is
that necessary? And if so, what's the
best
best way?
>> It's
>> It's how
best way?
>> It's how you
>> It's how you contextualize
best way?
>> It's how you contextualize it.
>> Okay.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Not
>> Not necessary.
>> Not necessary. Then
>> what's
>> what's the
>> Not necessary. Then
>> what's the question
>> what's the question again?
>> Is
>> Is that
>> Is that a
>> Is that a necessary?
>> Is that a necessary? No,
>> no,
>> no.
>> Okay,
>> good
>> good to
>> good to hear.
>> good to hear. Thank
>> good to hear. Thank you.
>> You
>> You can
>> good to hear. Thank you.
>> You can get
>> You can get to
>> good to hear. Thank you.
>> You can get to God
>> You can get to God via
>> good to hear. Thank you.
>> You can get to God via joy.
>> God's
>> God's at
>> God's at the
>> God's at the top
>> God's at the top part
>> God's at the top part of
>> God's at the top part of the
>> God's at the top part of the chart,
suffering's
suffering's at
>> God's at the top part of the chart,
suffering's at the
suffering's at the bottom,
>> God's at the top part of the chart,
suffering's at the bottom, you
suffering's at the bottom, you know.
>> Good
>> Good afternoon,
>> Good afternoon, doctor.
>> Um,
>> Um, I
>> Good afternoon, doctor.
>> Um, I guess
>> Um, I guess my
>> Good afternoon, doctor.
>> Um, I guess my question
>> Um, I guess my question is
>> Good afternoon, doctor.
>> Um, I guess my question is I
>> Um, I guess my question is I think
>> Good afternoon, doctor.
>> Um, I guess my question is I think you
mentioned
mentioned something
mentioned something about
mentioned something about this
mentioned something about this about
contracts
contracts before
mentioned something about this about
contracts before we
contracts before we come.
mentioned something about this about
contracts before we come. My
contracts before we come. My question
mentioned something about this about
contracts before we come. My question is
>> that's
>> that's a
>> that's a hypothesis.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So,
>> that's a hypothesis.
>> Okay. So, Carolyn
>> Okay. So, Carolyn Mace
>> that's a hypothesis.
>> Okay. So, Carolyn Mace talks
>> Okay. So, Carolyn Mace talks about
>> that's a hypothesis.
>> Okay. So, Carolyn Mace talks about this
is
is like
is like that
is like that we
is like that we actually
It's
It's just
is like that we actually
It's just a
It's just a theory.
is like that we actually
It's just a theory. You're
It's just a theory. You're saying
is like that we actually
It's just a theory. You're saying we
>> It's
>> It's a
>> It's a hypothesis.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So,
>> It's a hypothesis.
>> Okay. So, it's
>> Okay. So, it's not
>> It's a hypothesis.
>> Okay. So, it's not reality
>> Okay. So, it's not reality that
>> It's a hypothesis.
>> Okay. So, it's not reality that we
>> Okay. So, it's not reality that we make
a
a contract
a contract before.
>> Well,
>> Well, you
a contract before.
>> Well, you you
>> Well, you you would
a contract before.
>> Well, you you would have
>> Well, you you would have to
a contract before.
>> Well, you you would have to check
>> Well, you you would have to check at
a contract before.
>> Well, you you would have to check at al
kinesiology
kinesiology whether
kinesiology whether in
kinesiology whether in your
kinesiology whether in your case
kinesiology whether in your case there
was
was such
kinesiology whether in your case there
was such a
was such a contract
kinesiology whether in your case there
was such a contract if
was such a contract if things
kinesiology whether in your case there
was such a contract if things are
happening
happening that
happening that cannot
happening that cannot explain
happening that cannot explain be
explained
explained any
happening that cannot explain be
explained any other
explained any other way.
Sometimes
Sometimes it's
Sometimes it's the
Sometimes it's the only
Sometimes it's the only answer
Sometimes it's the only answer for
Sometimes it's the only answer for weird
karma.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> Okay. Okay. Appreciate
>> Okay. Okay. Appreciate that.
You
You have
>> Okay. Okay. Appreciate that.
You have to
You have to ask
>> Okay. Okay. Appreciate that.
You have to ask if
You have to ask if you
>> Okay. Okay. Appreciate that.
You have to ask if you have
You have to ask if you have permission
to
to ask
to ask on
to ask on can
to ask on can I
to ask on can I notice
to ask on can I notice that
to ask on can I notice that karma
to ask on can I notice that karma you
say
say I
to ask on can I notice that karma you
say I have
say I have permission
to ask on can I notice that karma you
say I have permission to
say I have permission to ask
to ask on can I notice that karma you
say I have permission to ask this
question
question you
question you may
question you may get
question you may get a
question you may get a no
question you may get a no sometimes
>> Dr.
>> Dr. I
question you may get a no sometimes
>> Dr. I just
>> Dr. I just like
question you may get a no sometimes
>> Dr. I just like a
>> Dr. I just like a a
question you may get a no sometimes
>> Dr. I just like a a photo,
>> Dr. I just like a a photo, please.
>> I
>> I just
>> I just like
>> I just like a
>> I just like a picture
>> I just like a picture with
>> I just like a picture with you,
>> I just like a picture with you, please.
>> Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Sorry.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, move
>> Sorry.
>> Oh, move up
>> Oh, move up a
>> Sorry.
>> Oh, move up a little
>> Oh, move up a little closer.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Right
>> Okay. Right there.
>> Okay. Right there. Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Now,
>> Okay. Right there. Okay.
>> Okay. Now, take
>> Okay. Now, take his
>> Okay. Right there. Okay.
>> Okay. Now, take his picture.
Thank
Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you,
>> Okay. Thank you, doctor.
>> My
>> My joy.
>> My joy. My
>> My joy. My pleasure.
>> One
>> One more
>> My joy. My pleasure.
>> One more question.
>> That's
>> That's it.
Have
Have a
>> That's it.
Have a question
Have a question about
>> That's it.
Have a question about kinesiology.
Have a question about kinesiology. How
could
could I
could I use
could I use kinesiology
could I use kinesiology to
could I use kinesiology to answer
could I use kinesiology to answer a
question
question like
could I use kinesiology to answer a
question like how
question like how I
could I use kinesiology to answer a
question like how I can
question like how I can get
could I use kinesiology to answer a
question like how I can get rid
question like how I can get rid of
cancer?
cancer? Should
cancer? Should be
cancer? Should be different
cancer? Should be different than
cancer? Should be different than what
cancer? Should be different than what is
my
my calibration
cancer? Should be different than what is
my calibration where
my calibration where I
cancer? Should be different than what is
my calibration where I don't
my calibration where I don't know
cancer? Should be different than what is
my calibration where I don't know the
answer.
answer. It
answer. It wouldn't
answer. It wouldn't be
answer. It wouldn't be a
answer. It wouldn't be a yes
answer. It wouldn't be a yes or
answer. It wouldn't be a yes or a
answer. It wouldn't be a yes or a no.
>> That's
>> That's an
answer. It wouldn't be a yes or a no.
>> That's an information
>> That's an information question.
answer. It wouldn't be a yes or a no.
>> That's an information question. You
would
would have
would have to
would have to ask
uh
uh would
would have to ask
uh would such
uh would such and
would have to ask
uh would such and such
uh would such and such a
would have to ask
uh would such and such a treatment
uh would such and such a treatment be
effective?
effective? You
effective? You mean
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I
effective? You mean
>> Okay. I see
>> Okay. I see you're
effective? You mean
>> Okay. I see you're Were
>> Okay. I see you're Were you
effective? You mean
>> Okay. I see you're Were you getting
>> Okay. I see you're Were you getting Yes.
>> You
>> You have
>> You have to
>> You have to get
>> You have to get specifics.
>> You have to get specifics. Yes.
>> So,
>> So, you
>> You have to get specifics. Yes.
>> So, you could
>> So, you could think
>> You have to get specifics. Yes.
>> So, you could think of
>> So, you could think of some
>> You have to get specifics. Yes.
>> So, you could think of some things
>> So, you could think of some things and
try
try them.
try them. That's
try them. That's what
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
try them. That's what
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Good.
>> Okay. Good. Thank
>> Okay. Good. Thank you.
>> You
>> You think
>> Okay. Good. Thank you.
>> You think it'd
>> You think it'd be
>> Okay. Good. Thank you.
>> You think it'd be helpful
>> You think it'd be helpful or
>> Okay. Good. Thank you.
>> You think it'd be helpful or not
helpful?
>> Always
>> Always ask
helpful?
>> Always ask permission
>> Always ask permission before
helpful?
>> Always ask permission before you
>> Always ask permission before you ask.
>> Yeah.
So
So no
>> Yeah.
So no matter
So no matter what
>> Yeah.
So no matter what you're
So no matter what you're asking,
>> Yeah.
So no matter what you're asking, always
ask
ask permission.
ask permission. Yeah.
>> Permission
>> Permission to
ask permission. Yeah.
>> Permission to ask
>> Permission to ask this
ask permission. Yeah.
>> Permission to ask this question.
>> Always
>> Always ask
>> Always ask that.
>> That's
>> That's absolutely
>> permission
>> permission of
>> permission of God.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> permission of God.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> And
>> And now
>> And now I'm
>> And now I'm being
>> And now I'm being prompted.
And
And I
>> And now I'm being prompted.
And I want
And I want all
>> And now I'm being prompted.
And I want all of
And I want all of us
>> And now I'm being prompted.
And I want all of us to
And I want all of us to thank
>> And now I'm being prompted.
And I want all of us to thank our
prompter
prompter without
prompter without whom
prompter without whom we
prompter without whom we would
prompter without whom we would not
prompter without whom we would not be
able
able to
prompter without whom we would not be
able to have
able to have the
prompter without whom we would not be
able to have the lectures.
Thank
Thank you.
Show
Show them
Thank you.
Show them what
Show them what I'm
Thank you.
Show them what I'm doing.
So,
so,
so, so
So,
so, so for
so, so for truth,
So,
so, so for truth, so,
so, so for truth, so, so
So,
so, so for truth, so, so for
so, so for truth, so, so for truth
versus
versus falsehood,
versus falsehood, she
versus falsehood, she did
versus falsehood, she did 7,000
calibrations.
calibrations. Show
versus falsehood, she did 7,000
calibrations. Show them
calibrations. Show them your
versus falsehood, she did 7,000
calibrations. Show them your arm
calibrations. Show them your arm now,
honey.
>> That's
>> That's it.
Well,
Well, we
Well, we thank
Well, we thank you
Well, we thank you very
Well, we thank you very much.
Well, we thank you very much. It
Well, we thank you very much. It was
Well, we thank you very much. It was a
joyous
joyous day.
Well, we thank you very much. It was a
joyous day. As
joyous day. As I've
Well, we thank you very much. It was a
joyous day. As I've said
joyous day. As I've said before,
Well, we thank you very much. It was a
joyous day. As I've said before, we've
all
all been
all been together
all been together before.
all been together before. We're
all been together before. We're all
destined
destined the
all been together before. We're all
destined the same
destined the same destiny.
all been together before. We're all
destined the same destiny. We're
destined the same destiny. We're united
by
by the
by the alignment,
by the alignment, the
by the alignment, the truth,
by the alignment, the truth, and
by the alignment, the truth, and the
destination
destination towards
by the alignment, the truth, and the
destination towards alignment.
Otherwise,
Otherwise, there'd
Otherwise, there'd be
Otherwise, there'd be no
Otherwise, there'd be no reason
Otherwise, there'd be no reason to
Otherwise, there'd be no reason to be
here
here anymore.
Otherwise, there'd be no reason to be
here anymore. That
here anymore. That people
Otherwise, there'd be no reason to be
here anymore. That people who
here anymore. That people who are
Otherwise, there'd be no reason to be
here anymore. That people who are not
intended
intended to
intended to be
intended to be golfers
intended to be golfers would
intended to be golfers would be
intended to be golfers would be a
intended to be golfers would be a class
on
on golfing.
I
I see
I see is
I see is like
I see is like f
I see is like f flock
I see is like f flock karmically.
I see is like f flock karmically. We
come
come in
I see is like f flock karmically. We
come in as
come in as a
I see is like f flock karmically. We
come in as a group.
come in as a group. We
I see is like f flock karmically. We
come in as a group. We swoop
come in as a group. We swoop into
I see is like f flock karmically. We
come in as a group. We swoop into the
planet.
planet. We
planet. We fulfill
planet. We fulfill a
planet. We fulfill a certain
fulfillment.
fulfillment. Then
planet. We fulfill a certain
fulfillment. Then we
fulfillment. Then we swoop
planet. We fulfill a certain
fulfillment. Then we swoop back
fulfillment. Then we swoop back out
planet. We fulfill a certain
fulfillment. Then we swoop back out to
the
the inner
the inner plains
the inner plains and
the inner plains and then
the inner plains and then we
the inner plains and then we swoop
the inner plains and then we swoop back
here
here again.
the inner plains and then we swoop back
here again. And
here again. And then
the inner plains and then we swoop back
here again. And then we
here again. And then we keep
the inner plains and then we swoop back
here again. And then we keep swooping
back
back and
back and forth.
back and forth. So
back and forth. So we're
back and forth. So we're like
back and forth. So we're like a
back and forth. So we're like a group
back and forth. So we're like a group of
swans
swans that
back and forth. So we're like a group of
swans that keep
swans that keep I
back and forth. So we're like a group of
swans that keep I was
swans that keep I was like
back and forth. So we're like a group of
swans that keep I was like those
swans that keep I was like those swans
that
that follow
that follow those
that follow those lighter
that follow those lighter than
that follow those lighter than air
aircraft.
aircraft. That's
that follow those lighter than air
aircraft. That's magical.
And
And here's
And here's these
And here's these swans
And here's these swans going
And here's these swans going along.
And here's these swans going along. So
Al's
Al's picture
And here's these swans going along. So
Al's picture is
Al's picture is sort
And here's these swans going along. So
Al's picture is sort of
Al's picture is sort of like
And here's these swans going along. So
Al's picture is sort of like swooping
Al's picture is sort of like swooping in
together
together and
together and because
together and because we're
together and because we're all
together and because we're all aligned
by
by the
together and because we're all aligned
by the intention.
by the intention. That's
together and because we're all aligned
by the intention. That's what
by the intention. That's what aligns
together and because we're all aligned
by the intention. That's what aligns you
is
is intention.
is intention. All
is intention. All of
is intention. All of us
is intention. All of us here
is intention. All of us here are
is intention. All of us here are aligned
with
with enlightenment
is intention. All of us here are aligned
with enlightenment or
with enlightenment or you
is intention. All of us here are aligned
with enlightenment or you wouldn't
with enlightenment or you wouldn't be
here.
We
We are
here.
We are the
We are the enlightened
here.
We are the enlightened beings
We are the enlightened beings of
here.
We are the enlightened beings of the
future.
Yeah.
So
So I
So I thank
So I thank you
So I thank you for
So I thank you for being
So I thank you for being here
So I thank you for being here and
So I thank you for being here and I
really
really enjoyed
So I thank you for being here and I
really enjoyed this
really enjoyed this today.
So I thank you for being here and I
really enjoyed this today. It
really enjoyed this today. It was
exquisitly
exquisitly joyful.
exquisitly joyful. AMEN.
GOOD
GOOD JOB.
HALLELU.
HALLELUJAH.
HALLELUJAH.ALLELUALLELU.
HALLELU.
HALLELUJAH.