we're talking about serenity. Serenity that arises then is an automatic consequence of
understanding and comprehension. It's affirmative, simplistic, non-operative, and people, it's
invitational, invitational, no promotion, no promotion. It's non-predictive because
reality is non-linear and you cannot tell what the secret is now. Why would that be?
Why is it you can't tell the future? There'd be no point to existence, human existence.
Why? Because the future then is created by every choice and every option you make, is
it not? Every choice and option determines where you are within the overall infinite
field. Because the future hasn't happened yet, it has no reality, and you can't calibrate
the level of any of that.
Anything that is not a reality, you know, is a fiction. So there's fictional propositions
about the future, but the future obviously is not a possibility or there would be no
point to creation, no point to divinity or existence, much less human life, yeah? Uh-huh.
You understand what I'm saying? It's only because you have an option, you could choose
this or that.
Yeah.
Well, if this, the outcome was determined.
There'd be no point to human life, would there? We'd all be in some other realm where
you're done already. And if you blew it, you blew it forever. If you blew it, boy, you
blew it, okay. It's not sentimental. We said, you know, the value of being empathic, I know
what it is to walk in my brother's moccasins. That's empathy. That's coming from the heart
of humanity within you. Your heart understands where their heart is. So I understand that.
Yeah.
I understand how they feel. Sympathy is joining them, which is something else. As a psychiatrist,
you're empathic, but you won't last long if you're sympathetic. Sympathetic. Yeah.
Uh-huh.
So, the amateur offers sympathy, which is a way of seduction. Sympathy is a form of
seduction and exploitation. Empathy allows you both to maintain your own integrity. I
understand how you feel.
Non-sentimental, non-authoritarian, no rules. Teachers are respected but don't
walk around with special titles. Educational, provides information so it's
primarily educative and inspiration. It's self-supporting, it's freestanding,
devoid of induced or altered states of consciousness, which is something else I
just got through writing about. Repetitious things, exercises, physical
and otherwise, can induce an altered state of consciousness. Biofeedback,
alpha-wave training, various things, can provide an altered state of
consciousness, but that is not a spiritual condition. The altered state of
consciousness then disappears when you remove the basis. Certain spiritual
disciplines,
through repetitive practices, bring about states of satori, but then when the
exercise is over and you get up and you walk around, the state disappears. The state
disappears. A prevailing level of consciousness is not dependent on
externals, much less physical physicality or physical manipulations. We said that
brain function is the automatic consequence of that which
you have become. The so-called cities, supernormal phenomena, are the automatic
consequence of that which you have become. So to take classes on learning how
to fly or bi-locate or anything like that, you can see, are actually injurious. Why?
Because the spiritual ego is what seeks them out. Why do you want to learn to
travel and fly?
Obviously the spiritual ego gives some kind of status to that. Some kind of
status. See? People who seriously do the, you know, spiritual work eventually reach
a state where these phenomena appear of their own. You hold it in mind and of
course it shows up. You drive into the Lincoln Center in New York City and you
hold in mind a parking space right near Lincoln Center. By God, the closest one is
there. You pull up, the other car pulls apart.
One of the first, those begin to happen, you call them miraculous. After a while you
just see it's normal. It's just normal. What you're holding in mind is
manifesting when conditions are favorable. To seek the cities or so-called
mystical powers for their own is off the rail to begin with. The very reason it
can't work because the reason you want it in the first place is already
non-integrous.
You want it from the viewpoint of spiritual pride. Why do you want to learn
to fly? Tell me that, please. If you were meant to fly, you'd have wings, you know.
No, you're meant to walk, pedestrian. As a pedestrian, you keep humility. If you gave
men wings, his ego's bad enough as it is, I mean, he'd really go nuts.
Alright, we'll move past that one.
Alright, we want to get to the dualities of attraction and aversion.
Because these apply to all the levels of consciousness.
All the levels of consciousness are held in place by what I call, the ego
juice of the payoff. You're getting a payoff, and you look at
letting go of it in a negative way, so you develop an aversion. Every
positionality that your mind gets caught in is attracted there by an attraction,
and it's held there also by an aversion.
to be forgiven. How often
have we heard that? I forgive
him, but he doesn't deserve it.
I forgive
I heard
all the veterans of World War II long ago
forgiving their
former enemies,
but I heard there was one guy, a holdout
on television not long ago.
Even though it's been over 60
years or whatever, this guy was
holding on.
Holding on,
They don't deserve to be
forgiven. Who's the
beneficiary of
forgiveness? Not the person
you forgive, but the forgivor.
He's denying himself
the benefit of forgiveness. He's not
denying the other guy
that forgiveness.
The warrior of both
sides, in my view, were equally
integrous. They both did what they thought
was required by their
role in society.
By their obligation
to God, government,
womanhood, their mother,
and God knows what all.
Everybody did what they felt they needed
to do to fulfill that role
at that time.
Therefore, I always saw
everyone equally
integrous, no matter which side they're on.
Doctors Without Borders
sees it the same way. They don't care
which side they're on. If they come
in injured, you
repair his leg. It doesn't matter which
side he was on. Because
each side is doing what they consider to be
the highest good. So
the attraction, then, and
the aversion. These
are general. When we get to
the levels, we'll be more specific.
But generally, to see
what holds things in mind gives you
tools by which to undo
them. First of all, we
like that which is familiar.
We'd rather be wrong
all the time because it's comfy.
And to find a new
way home. Did you ever try a new way home from
work? It's annoying. I've tried
it. I don't know.
I thought, this is boring. I'm going to try a different way home.
Pretty soon, I'm going back the same
old way.
We like the familiar.
Habitual. So we
don't like really
change and fear the newer
unless we choose it. And then we choose it
for novelty.
So this way, the attraction is
it's easier
to just hate the SOB
than it is to go through the effort
of processing it and
forgiving. The attraction
of pride then,
so we have pride in all of our positionalities
and the aversion
is humility.
People confuse humility with
humiliation. The truly
humble person cannot be
humiliated. The person
who owns his downside
cannot be hurt.
Is not sensitive about slights.
Doesn't feel
that their rights have been violated
because somebody disagrees with you.
Why? Because they've accepted their downside.
The way to get over being
sensitive, that's the problem.
If your feelings get hurt easily, sit down
and make a list of all the downsides
of your self you can think of.
And then picture the great comedians
of all time discussing
your problem.
They're the
great therapists of Jack Benny.
Those are the great Red Skelton. Those are the
great therapists. And the black
guy who did more to
get rid of
prejudice against blacks. The guy who blew himself
up with something. Richard Friar.
Richard Friar, yeah. By the time he knocked
out all those stereotypes, there wasn't anything
left you could say about them.
And if you do the same thing with yourself,
then
nobody can hurt you there.
You accept all the things that you're
embarrassed about which hadn't happened
and accept that that's part
of your karmic inheritance
to have lived through those things.
And now nobody can
hurt you there.
So pride
keeps us away from humility.
And the humble
person whose feelings cannot be hurt.
Feelings cannot be hurt.
If you call yourself,
I love nicknames amongst, this is understood
amongst men,
that they have nicknames for each other
which emphasize their surety.
That was called surety in the Navy.
Well nowadays a sensitive person
would be, their rights are violated,
they've been,
not supposed to be discrimination
based on height, you know.
Surety. So anyway, you own
and amongst the work
crew we always used ethnic
names for each other.
Back in Wisconsin there were Bohonks
and Germans, you know, we all had
names for each other.
And there was Jigaboos and Bohonks
and
we all owned that
about ourself.
And therefore it was a fun thing.
One thing.
Kiss me I'm Polish, you know.
It was the guy
who used to go over to the girl's ranch every
month and he had his license plate.
Kiss me I'm Polish. Instantly you love all the
Polish people and you really always feel like
kissing them, you know, because
it takes you out of the stereotype
and into the reality.
Humility.
Confusion of anger with strength
and passivity as weak.
I don't want to give up anger
because people swell up with anger
get an artificial feeling of strength.
Anger gives you an
artificial charge like you are
stronger than you really are.
You feel stronger
but actually you're not because the angry
person of course is much weaker.
And in, you know, karate
and various martial arts
and various
other things I've done
you try to provoke the guy to get mad
because once he gets mad you got him.
You got him.
You got him. The minute you got him mad
he freezes into an angry
space.
Instantly you got him. In a flash
the angry person is skewered
on the thing.
The attraction of course is always
to win and never to lose
but winning and losing are
how you contextualize it.
The ego's loss is
usually the spirit's gain and vice versa.
The attraction
is always importance and
fear of being a nobody.
The ego is always seeking a gain
wants money
wants excitement
and serenity is the last thing it wants.
Teenagers see
serenity as boredom, right?
There's nothing happening around here.
I mean what's happening here in this town?
I mean everybody just goes to work and goes to church
on Sunday. I mean what's happening?
Why would I want to meditate
and think about nothing, you know what I'm saying?
So the ego
loves excitement and
hates serenity.
It hates boredom.
It's addicted to desiring, wanting
it loves status
hates the idea of being a nobody
and it wants to be noticed
and of course the Hollywood
madness is the
desire to be noticed at
all costs, no matter what.
It likes to be
opinionated, doesn't want to be seen as
ordinary. It's just awful
to be ordinary.
When you see the safety of being ordinary
you can't wait to be ordinary.
You know anybody ordinary who was
assassinated lately? I don't know.
You want to blow off the bus or what?
To have an opinion
you then, so
this is why we need freedom from speech
because
we have an inversion of
spiritual values in our society
in which freedom of speech
has become worshipped as the
ideal pinnacle of
mankind. The pinnacle
of this country and all we stand
for is called free speech.
Free speech
calibrates about
I forget two-fifths or something like that
higher than
spiritual truth, higher
than reason, higher than logic
higher than compassion
higher than sanity.
Free speech is
God. It feeds the
media. The media is in a
feeding frenzy
over free speech.
Narcissism to the max is what
it amounts to.
Narcissism to the max.
Free speech is more important
than God. Free
speech. Calibrates
it's one of the
attributes of
political freedom but it is not
the highest good of all mankind.
Why? Because it gives equal
voice to fallacy.
Does it not? Equal voice
to fallacy. When it's time
to operate and do brain surgery
I don't pull the people
around for their opinion.
That guy should
you think I should
clamp the left
cerebral artery?
All in favor? Now they want
a family in the operating room.
I would refuse to operate on anybody
with a family in the operating room.
They want to document it so you can be
sued later if you make a wrong move.
I mean the intention is so
non-integers to begin with.
You can't vote
on truth, you see.
You can't vote on truth.
And the downside of our society
you know, which if not corrected
will be its destruction
much as Socrates predicted
in 350 BC or 450
please don't write me it was 458
not 350.
Around that time
he said if you give every man an equal vote
and equal power he will destroy society.
So free
speech then. So
I'll say now for history.
For historical reasons.
That the downside
of this society occurred
when action was
legislated
from the bench as
symbolic speech.
If action is symbolic speech
in a free country you can
say anything you want
there is no constraint at all
on anything by anyone.
I can do anything I want
so if I want to publicly
burn the flag
is that speech? I don't
even open my mouth.
That's symbolic speech.
Therefore the Ku Klux Klan
is okay. Therefore
Sodomy is fine.
Peter Philly is great.
These are all symbolic speech are they not?
All action now
is free of all restraints.
There is no
answerability, no responsibility.
The complete and total destruction
of morality and ethics without which
society soon becomes
chaotic.
It will become the Chomsky ideal.
Atheistic
chaos.
The downside then is
The people who believe in no government
what do you call them?
Anarchists.
Whatever you call them. Anarchists.
The anarchists.
So the atheistic anarchist
ideal
will come about through relativism
by which
anything I do is my
right to do
because it's my right
because it's symbolic speech.
Die.
That's just symbolic speech folks.
With a little sword.
Therefore with no right or wrong
then war is just as
okay as peace.
Criminality is just as okay as
law abiding.
There's no point to truth because
fallacy is of equal
merit.
So historically
we say it for the record
the downside of this
civilization came about
when action was
legally defined
as symbolic speech
and therefore
without restraints, responsibility
or answerability.
If that don't take down a society
I don't know
what would.
So how can you have
a serenity
with such a prospect perhaps
So I've said the worst thing I can
about the world, I've already said
that is the worst thing I can say about the world
because through acceptance then you
accept that is the karmic
potentiality of humankind
and we're not here to question
God's purpose in creating human life
in this world.
Anybody wants to change the world
remember Ramana Maharshi said
there's several ways
to reach the truth
you can ask who am I constantly
for you know
20 years constantly
you spend a whole lifetime
asking who am I
and spend a whole lifetime
or you can surrender the world to God
and you got it in a second
So I want everybody to surrender
the world to God at lunch
and we'll resume at what time
we will resume at 2 o'clock
and we're going to spend more time
on questions than answers
I was spoiled by being in Korea
went there twice
important missions
society is this way
when they meet each other
all the people wait on you in the hotel
it's really incredible
you know and you get spoiled by it
the politeness, the reverence
for something higher than your personal ego
it's a charming
charming society
Oh Lord
Amen
Okay
I wanted to further clarify
the kinesiology
like everything else
is evolving
it was first discovered
this particular usage
actually my own observations
back in the 70s
I saw a lecture by
John Diamond
and then I was going to give
I used to give demonstrations of it
and
I needed a subject
so
I grabbed some
we had the second attitudinal healing center
Jerry Jempolski
came to New York
stayed with us this weekend
with his staff
and we started an attitudinal healing center
so we had an active Course in Miracles group
that met in the clinic
for intractable
incurable conditions
so anyway
I grabbed a couple of people
to be
to work with me
to demonstrate
and certain things make everybody go weak
fluorescent lights
sweet and low held over the solar plexus
pesticides
held over the solar plexus
made everybody go weak
so I said
I had a couple of volunteers
I said I'll go with you tonight
so I said well try it out
I did the fluorescent light and he didn't go weak
I did the sweet and low he didn't go weak
I did the pesticides he didn't go weak
I said what the world is this
everybody goes weak from these things
but these people didn't
wow
so then we did an investigation
we had some people just starting the Course in Miracles
and we tested them
and they went weak
with the same things
then we tested them a couple of months later
and it no longer made them go weak
we found that after
about less than 75
around in there
if a person stayed with the Course in Miracles
by the time they got that far
they were only subject to what you hold in mind
is less than 70 I think
you're only subject to what you hold in mind
if you believe you got a fever
you got it
just the fact that you
believe and think that
gives it the power over you
so anyway
that was the beginning of calibrating levels
and
so it
kinesiology is also
in its infancy
we're just discovering
we discovered something
discrepancies which came up at London
lunch today
that we didn't know before
so I just want you to demonstrate
how it's evolving
we discovered that
the application
you see when we calibrate things
the Heisenberg principle is operative
we have just observed something
asked a question that's never been asked before
in all of history
and by doing that
we discovered we already
are changing the calibrated levels of things
people over 200 when you witness and observe
something from lovingness
are already raising its calibrated
level of consciousness
measurably
so we found things that we considered
adorable
and the fact that you consider it adorable
it would have been a 204
and now it will jump to 310 or something
independently
and that same
manifestation will be
diagnosable by everyone
around the world
that is a fact to resist
wow
so don't you see what this means
your lovingness by witnessing
see when I say
you don't need to go to fancy things
just witness the sacredness
of all of existence
approach all of love with reverence
and good will
and by doing so
you're changing the world
by virtue of the Heisenberg principle
so if we say
Kitty's Purr is adorable and loving
I don't know if Kitty's Purr was at 500
before we said it
probably not
but it is now
so
therefore
the sheer observation
the higher the level of consciousness of the observer
the greater the impact on the observed
that we have literally been changing
the calibrated levels of consciousness
and much of society by the sheer observation
of the work that we're doing
collectively
isn't that something
so everything we look at lovingly
huh
hmm
let's see how the Komodo dragon is making out
well
look at the Komodo dragon
he's just being what he is
God bless him
being a good Komodo dragon
of course you eat everything up
Komodo dragon did calibrate at 40
the adorable Komodo dragon
calibrates over 45
seeing the lovability of the Komodo dragon
is an expression of divinity's
unfoldment of creation
so as we witness the unfoldment of creation
and acknowledge that his source
is divinity
we're already raising the level of
all that is within this world
wow
so this world is becoming
that which we hold in mind
just wow hmm
look at all the power
he walked around and didn't know it
okay
so everything that we look at
forgive it for being what it is
witness the sacredness
that it is an expression of
evolution
at some level of evolution
and it serves some ultimate purpose
so we stop hating it
and see its intrinsic beauty
I mean the Komodo dragon
is an impressive animal
impressive you know
I don't know where this came from
last night we were watching alligators
we love the nature channel
if you want to learn a lot about spirituality
you just watch the nature channel
because
you see in nature
where you don't have any prejudices
the witnessing of phenomena
that you won't see in humanity
because you got too many
upsides and downsides
but it was marvelous
here's the hippopotamus and the alligators
and the alligators
are on the beach
and the hippopotamus is also on the beach
but the hippopotamus
has sort of a maternal motherly instinct
towards alligators
I mean who could love an alligator but a hippopotamus
now that
everybody is afraid of alligators
except hippopotamus
hippopotamus comes over and nudges the alligator
and often even licks him
and makes sure that the alligator is comfortable
the alligator is twitching
and the hippo will push the alligator over
until the alligator is happy
so here's the alligators all happy
the hippopotamus is like tending to them
they're all like mothers
overlooking the babies here
and nudging them
imagine licking an alligator
now there's
love and acceptance
so the hippos
love the alligators and nurture them
and lick them and protect them
and see to their comfort
isn't that marvelous
it's certainly marvelous
but you don't see that on the nature channel
you see you won't read that in the New York Times
so we should be more like the hippopotamus
then
and be sort of
nurturing towards
all that the world really looks down at
as
homo horribilis
we'll start fretting
whether Ben Loudon is getting a sunburn
getting sand in his eyes
from the wind out there
I'm sure
that he does what he feels
it is his destiny
to do
and therefore
from the viewpoint of Socrates
he does what he feels obligated
to do
and therefore
like a hippopotamus
we should make sure he feels comfy
in his pillows
and stuff
but isn't that amazing
and therefore
some of the discrepancies
because this work covers some years
and truth versus false
so those calibrations were done
all from 2003
right up to the beginning of 2005
and some of them changed
as merely the consequence
of our having calibrated them
without our realizing that
okay so we just got today at lunch
what was about
that's what I'm saying
it's evolving
man's desire to know the truth
tends to pull the truth to him
because this was just a realization
there wasn't any thinking about it
it was just suddenly you realize
wow
the Heisenberg principle
depends on who's doing the observing
so the more loving the person
witnessing a thing
in a certain way
has a powerful tendency
to have potentiality
so that's one of the mechanisms
by which
evolution unfolds
as creation
so creation is continuous
it happened today at lunch
there was creation right there
I caught it
there's creation
gotcha
alright so thank you Susie
without Susie I wouldn't know these things
I'd just puzzle over them
I'd have to find a hippopotamus
to work with
a friendly hippo
probably because
a hippo if you hold something in mind
in a certain way
he probably reacts one way
if you hold something else in mind
he reacts a different way
that's yes and that's no
their mouths are just amazing
even alligators are scared of hippos
even alligators
and they kill more people
than any other animal on the planet
and yet they're the most
benign creature when you see it around
how could a hippo have a maternal
instinct towards an alligator
anyway they apparently made friends
over the millennia
ok so where were we with the slides
as we said
we're going to do more
spontaneous interaction
with the audience
I was just talking to Robert about it
who's our mastermind genius
behind all the productions
and we'll work out a way
to sort of wander through the audience
and we've done that in the past
and everybody's sort of liked that
you can talk to the person
and they come up with what's real to them
at the moment
and then share it with the audience
the true nature of divinity
yes well this had to do with
consciousness level 850
which has never been explained
in the world's literature
that I know of
I'm not going to say that
because somebody will email me
and there's confusion of nothingness
with buddhahood
so because there's nobody around to explain it
we'll have to explain this
the pathway of negation
huangpo
did we explain this last time
huangpo is yes
ok well we'll just cover it again
the pathway of negation then
which is really meaning
negating the linear
as a reality
and not being attached to it
the pathway of negation
will take you to the void
which is consciousness level 850
now we found some interesting things
also never really
noticed before
these are characteristics of god
but they calibrate different than
god
experientially as divinity
divinity is often
defined as
omniscience, omnipresence
and omnipotence
now you think you've defined divinity
you haven't, you've only
defined it up to consciousness level 850
because these are
qualities of divinity
but the qualities
do not define the essence
because the essence
of divinity is
infinite love
because divinity
calibrates at infinity
so these are qualities
but they are not the totality
the buddha
because he calibrated at 1000
obviously didn't
stop at 850
so buddhahood does not mean
voidness or nothingness
now buddha obviously
experienced divinity
as the infinite source of creation
and infinite love
as I mentioned
because of an experience
at age 14 or something
of experiencing
the presence
as exquisite love
that happens spontaneously
in which time
is stopped
and the infinite presence
wiped out any personal self
there was only the foreverness
and
the presence was
infinite love
and the quality of the love
was beyond all time
beyond all definition
beyond all limitation
exquisite
exquisitely gentle
and yet infinitely powerful
simultaneously
infinite power
and infinite gentleness
not
not resistible
in any quality forever
that beyond which
beyond your own existence
that which you are before
and will be after all universes
we've already calibrated the truth of that
that which you are
exists before all universes
and will continue on forever
after all universes have disappeared
because it's beyond the limits
of the universe
and we mentioned also
that Duane Poe discovered the air himself
but never wrote anything more
that happened with several other famous
teachers of history
whose names escape me at the moment
at the time of their writing
they calibrated it at a certain level
and then they went into a more advanced
enlightened state and never wrote anything more
which I can understand
laughter
they didn't have
computers and secretaries
alright
so divinity
you know the presence of divinity
these qualities are unmistakable
the complete oneness of all of existence
and in that state
everything
happens of its own
spontaneously as a consequence
of that which it is
it is completely
there is no this causing of that
everything is presenting itself
as the fulfillment
of its own potentiality
manifesting as an actuality
and the profoundness of the presence
silence the mind
which in all
stops talking
happily
okay there we are
we wanted to do that one
for what reason I don't know
but there must be a purpose
alright because it came up next
ah yes
so you see
the Arhat calibrates at 800
see
the Alak links
Derlisla
the penance
Maisa
the
bres
this
uh
what
is
a
spirit
life
lovingly you've already changed its level of consciousness. We did some of
these in the recent lectures. We started at the bottom of the levels of
consciousness and these are all discussed in a forthcoming book. The
downside, the attraction of apathy. What's the use? I can't, I'm the victim, they're
they're the cause, indifferent, defeatist, all kinds of excuses, I'm helpless, I'm
hopeless, I'm not worth anything, and I'm too weak, and all right. Why is it
calibrated negatively? Why is sloth one of the cardinal sins? Because it negates
the gift, divine gift of life itself. To say your life is worthless
is to say you're worthless.
It is a denial of the gift of life from divinity, a lack of respect. You are the
steward, you are responsible for that which is a gift from divinity, which is
your own life. Therefore, you owe it to God and out of self-respect to do the
best you can with what you have, yes? To do the best as you can. It's nice
to see yourself as unworthy and not worth the effort. The future looks bleak.
I'm incapable and passive rather than active, reject help and accept help. People
reject help all the time. People go over the edge with people offering their hand
because they don't want to take it, because they're getting too much payoff from the
self-pity and being a loser and succumbing. This is sort of masochistically satisfying
to let yourself become degenerate, hopeless.
Filthy, dirty, homeless, abject, poverty-stricken. You're like an affront to divinity, see? You
lay there in the doorway, yeah. An aversion then to getting over it and moving on and
therefore it is really a subtle form of resistance, subtle form of resistance. Okay, move on.
Grief is the next higher. We cling to, we cling to it because we can juice it, you know?
You can live in the past and bargain with God, see it as a loss, have anger, resentment,
feel empty, and the aversion is to get over it and accept it. Select the imperfection
of personal human life with the overall perfection of human life itself. The unwillingness to
work it through, accept your limitation, and see happiness as internal and personal. You
have to accept it as internal rather than external. So the value of the pathway of
negation is that you let go your attachment and seeing some external limited source as
the source or the cause of your happiness and then the realization that the source of
happiness is within. So grief then saw the source of happiness. You are my happiness
is going to put you in a bad place later.
You contribute and support my happiness, that's a good place, but you are the source, you
are it, then if I lose you, I've lost it all and go into grief and so go back in time.
The attraction of this also is the emotionality of it. See the source of happiness is in here
instead of out there, you know? Okay, so we'll move on.
Life is full of solutions. As we said, life moves actually from perfection to perfection.
It doesn't move from imperfection to perfection or from incomplete to complete. It moves from
complete to complete. At every moment, it's perfect. Perfectly despondent. You're perfectly
despondent. The unfolding flower is not an imperfect flower. It's a perfect half unfolded
flower. Now it's a perfect unfolded flower. Now it's a perfect half unfolded flower. Now
it's a perfect drooping flower. Now it's a perfect withered flower. Now it's a perfect
seed for next year. So, it goes, everything is perfectly the fulfillment of its own potentiality
as it actualizes. Everything is perfect and then perfect and then perfect. So, if you
want to improve the world, you're going to have to go from perfect to more perfect.
Because it is.
There's a downside in the tragedies of the world that tend to energize the ambition to
transcend it. To transcend it, yeah. Fear, of course, everybody knows this one. The excitement
of the danger, dramatizing it, the emotionalism. And, of course, fear has to do with being
on the front of the crest of the wave. And just like grief is clinging to the past, fear
is anticipating.
Equanimity and peace is to be right on the peak of the wave without resisting this or
without clinging to that. With neither clinging nor resisting. Neither attraction nor aversion.
People have an aversion unless they're trained to stay cool. Now, men learned that in the
military. You stay cool. The bigger the danger, the more you stay cool. Nobody wants you to
emotionalize.
.
People have an aversion to staying calm in the middle of disaster. You hear people screaming
all over. Why you'd want to scream when your house is being carried away by a tornado is
beyond me. I think it's the last ten moment I would think about screaming. You know what
I mean? I'm trying to hang on to the dog and hang on to the cat and you're going up through
the air.
.
We'll leave the screaming till later, you know.
And the other thing interesting about the Weather Channel, you know, they've got quite
a few... .
I'll go to the map and press the minute.. .
So they're server uses the standoff, all right?
Let there be one at the middle.
And then there's never a leve d demonstration, no.
.
One of the interesting stuff that's just heard, the må бывает
to be a teams game.
.
We've dog fighter teams, you see.
When you wann' go up and want to carry you
know.
When you get on board the boat, everyone wants to wave.
When you want to let me do the follow-up,
is like that.
.
That's part of what's good about Sierra. You know what's not right. You do! .
they prayed. That was interesting. The other thing that was interesting is an occasional
one will tell you, maybe about once a year, a survivor of a tornado will tell you how
they were lifted up 50, 100 feet in the air, and they went into a state of sublime peace.
A number of them did that. I was whirled up into the air 100 feet over, and then suddenly
a great profound sense of peace came upon me. If all else fails, get sucked up in a
tornado. It's a poor time to emotionalize, right? You're 100 feet whirling in the air.
Another time you can blubber later, but right now. All right, so we'll let go of fear.
So we'll let go of fear, then, and perhaps see it as the indulgence of the child within
us.
Because when...
When is fear appropriate? I don't know when it's fear. Caution is a different thing. Caution
is not the same thing. Caution is thinking, anticipating, but it's not emotionalizing.
Fear is going into hysteria and coming apart, see? And you can't come apart if the situation
is one of real danger, where you need to stay cool. You have to learn to handle it calmly.
All right, in the end, you can surrender.
You can
surrender.
There we go.
So, that's the end.
Thank you.
Thank you, Dr. H complimenting a lot today, and thank you to Dr. David.
Thank you, Dr. David.
And I appreciate it.
So big deal, you know what I mean?
So even facing death, you see, fearful emotionalization is not even necessary
because with acceptance, you transcend into serenity.
And he got it from me, and I got it from him.
I guess I got it from the near-death experience where I realized that fear was not,
it wasn't really a near-death experience, but what people think is that death is not a possibility.
Now, on a certain level, everybody sort of knows that
because when we calibrated a near-death experience,
it shows a major jump in consciousness before and after the experience,
whereas out-of-body experience, you don't see any change at all.
A person who calibrates at 340 goes out of body for the first time,
comes back in body, later they still calibrate at 340.
A person near death calibrates at 340, they come back,
they can maybe calibrate, you know, 560 or 570 or something.
And we asked, why is that?
And we got because out-of-body is really experiencing that you're a spirit and not a body,
and you know that already.
You've already spent eons as a spirit,
and therefore, you haven't learned anything.
You knew that all along.
So when you get out of the body, you're back where it's more familiar than being in the body.
Being in the body is really actually strange.
Being out of the body is more familiar.
So it's not a surprise you didn't learn anything new when you went out of body
because you knew that's who you were.
You knew that you were a spirit all along, you know.
That you are in space wherever you think you are in space,
wherever you think you are, you're there.
So, that's interesting.
So we let go of fear then of death by total acceptance.
That death is not a possibility.
And we surrender our life to God, trust God.
And if it's time to blow up, so you blow up.
Okay, next.
More fear, oh dear.
Well, the attraction is fears tend to proliferate.
And of course, you let go of fear.
We like to harbor our fears and justify them.
We like to reject the cause as being out there, out there.
The cause of the fear is out there.
The cause of the fear is the Komodo dragon.
It's the commander, he's the one that's causing my fear.
Therefore, projecting the source as external.
And of course, fear sees life as strictly physical, focuses on the body.
And the bottom fear of the ego is really death.
And surrendering a stack of fears, if you use the technique of it, then what?
So, you take a fear.
I'm going to lose my car.
Well, then what?
Well, then I won't have transportation.
Then what?
Then I'll lose my job.
Then you'll have to walk to work.
Yeah.
But there aren't any jobs like that.
Well, then you won't have any money.
Yeah.
Then what?
Then I'll be poor.
Okay, so you're poor.
Then what?
Then I'll starve to death.
Okay.
So, at the bottom of every stack of fears is death.
Physical death.
And when you say, so what to physical death, nothing scares you anymore.
Nothing really frightens you.
Because the basic fear, once you surrender completely to the physical death, the whole
stack is brought down.
Remember in Estes they used to talk about stacks, you know?
So, fear is a big stack.
And at the bottom of that stack is the fear of physical death.
So, once you've accepted physical death, then most of the fears that we have, which are
focused on the body and loss of possessions and things, disappear.
So, we'll move on.
You do that by acceptance.
This is the one that really bothers most people most of the time.
You know, fears come along and grief comes along, et cetera.
People are apathetic about certain things in their life.
But the desire and wantingness is the one that really bothers the most people most of the time.
Because of the attraction of winning.
Money, gain, control, getting, winning the election, approval, success, fame, acquisitions,
conquest, of course, being right.
Being right, people are willing to die right and left for being right.
They would rather die and be right than not be right.
The ego doesn't mind dumping your body at all.
Rather than admit defeat, the ego will walk you.
Over the cliff.
People die for illusions all the time.
In my lifetime, 100 million people, probably twice that, have died chasing some illusion rather than admit it.
I mean, Chairman Mayo's economic agricultural plan resulted in the starvation of 30 million people.
Mayo's Little Red Book.
The faith in Chairman Mayo, God bless him.
Resulted in the death of 30 million people by starvation.
The greatest famine in all of history.
After that, would you think Marxism maybe is wrong?
No.
We will spread it further into the world.
The inability to learn, the pride of the ego then.
So, the desire to be right, to control, approval, all these things we are very familiar with.
Because it's part of everyday life.
We all fear appearing passive, weak, a failure, poverty, losing.
And many people want to be noticed at all times.
You see the extremes to which people go to be noticed.
Say anything, no matter how outrageous, as long as you're on camera.
Or get on the camera.
So, we'll go next.
The dualities of anger is closer a little bit to the animal world.
Because you feel expanded and stirred up, bigger than life with anger.
It gives you a feeling to dramatize and emotionalize and to be right.
So, the animal in you growls and shows its teeth and tries to win by intimidation.
The last thing it wants is to be calm, be at peace.
Afraid it will appear weak.
Doesn't want to give in, you know.
And, of course, not wanting to see a bad guy go free.
Let go.
The Buddha said you don't have to worry about getting even with your enemies.
Because they will bring themselves down by their own hand.
They will bring themselves down by their own hand.
And with consciousness calibration, of course, we affirm the truth of that over and over.
So, let's move to the next one.
Yes.
Is this the next one?
Oh, it is the next one.
No wonder I can't find the next one.
Okay, pride.
We're talking about spiritual pride.
We're not talking about self-esteem.
Self-esteem is earned.
Therefore, it's not ego-inflating.
Pride is something, a projection that we impose.
And it gives you status.
And it gets you noticed.
And you get to be superior.
You get to be an insider.
You get to be elite.
What is it?
Politically elite or politically correct.
You get to be above the common people.
Which is, of course, the paradox of egalitarianism.
Which is that all people are of equal value.
But some people are more valuable than others.
Meaning us mainly.
The reason is because we're more egalitarian than anybody else.
And that makes us superior to the rest of the people.
So the downside of which is humility.
The fear you may look down on.
You may just be ignored because you're common and ordinary.
The worst of all things, of course, is to be wrong.
And people would rather die than be wrong.
They do it all the time.
We'll see a whole other generation of people dying rather than admitting that they were following a false teacher.
An error.
Yeah?
Next.
Uh-huh.
If what we're witnessing is creation unfolding, you know, evolution is creation unfolding,
then what we view as mistakes really represent a success because they demonstrate the outcome of a fallacy.
If 30 million people starve to death according to a certain belief system,
this is the automatic demonstration of falsity.
So we see that falsity then, instead of trying to prevent its occurrence in the world,
we try to counter it, but it serves its own purpose.
So completely surrendering the world to gods sees it as not wanting to change the world,
but instead to become aware of its ultimate purpose.
This is the ultimate opportunity for karmic,
for karmic evolution,
to undo negative karma and gain positive karma.
If this were a heavenly realm and everybody calibrated at 600,
there would be no purpose to be here.
That's why you can't predict the future,
your future.
The future is, is not possibly set,
can't possibly be set,
because it hasn't been created yet,
because we all contribute to the evolution
of the expression of consciousness.
Because we haven't done so yet,
you can't possibly predict the future,
because it as yet has no reality,
it's only a potentiality,
has no reality,
so you can't predict the future,
because it has no reality.
If you could predict the future,
that would confirm predestination,
that everything that is bound to happen
is already predestined.
If predestination were the rule,
our lives would be of no value.
We'd be like omatons,
just fulfilling a role
like something in a movie, see?
Reciting a script.
We'd all be following a script.
There would be no karmic gain.
So the anticipated pleasures here,
of course, we're very familiar with control
and familiarity,
the excuses of not wanting to
or can't kind of try,
the fears of surrendering,
moving to the unknown,
the truth of...
So we already said,
with a gun at your head,
the I can't reveals itself
as a truth that I won't.
I won't.
With a gun at your head, you can.
So I can't is not the truth.
I want is the truth.
So anytime you think you can't do something,
remind yourself you mean you won't.
Usually it's too much effort,
and bother.
Really, that's why you can't
clean up the garage.
It isn't that you can't,
it's that you don't want to,
because it lacks sufficient pleasure.
All right, so we'll move on.
Yeah.
Oh, right. Oh, great.
Oh, boy, I'm relieved.
So we did the whole thing.
I don't have to spend the rest of the afternoon
feeling guilty.
Slide 32.
Get back to the other side.
Slide 32, boy.
Sorry, Socrates.
Yeah.
All right.
So we have a different way now
of understanding kinesiology,
that it is clinical,
not academic.
Academic means set in stone.
Clinical means variable.
What's considered a healthy
physical measurement
is a sign at one point
in the evolution of medicine,
a decade later is not.
So it's constantly evolving
and learning.
And today, just a matter of an hour ago,
we learned the demonstration
of the Heisenberg principle
that all of us looking at
favorably in a loving way
all that exists
are already uplifting all of mankind.
Uplifting all of mankind.
Yes.
All of us doing that,
doing that,
affect the level of consciousness
of all mankind.
This group here,
sizeably,
affects the overall consciousness
level of mankind.
Resist.
By virtue of the awareness
of levels of consciousness
is indicative of truth.
This is a very powerful group.
So you have like respect for
that which has been given
you have respect for it.
And therefore,
the respect takes the form
out of thankfulness and gratitude
to use it
for the good of all mankind.
What can you do to raise
the level of consciousness
of all of mankind?
We just stumbled upon it, didn't we?
Because loving
to see the worth and the value
and the sacredness
of all that exists
is the process of sanctification.
Oh, I see what's going on.
All right.
So thereby,
the self sanctifies creation.
Thereby,
does creation become sanctified
by our experience
and witnessing of it.
So therefore,
there is a value to all of us
collectively as well as individually
that somehow we serve
the evolution of consciousness.
This is a very rare group.
Statistically,
the chances are like
one in ten zillion.
But a group like this
we just confirmed
is profoundly important
to the evolution
of humanity
and the evolution
of the level of consciousness.
The evolution of consciousness
is already on the upswing
and a group like this
that kick starts it
through the momentum.
We're careful.
All right, so what happens
when you find something like that
is you revere the gift,
you revere it,
and you see it as a gift.
You say, thank you, O Lord.
And out of gratitude
I'm dumbfounded
with the revelation
of the responsibility
and the power and the gift
to bring a greater lovingness
to this experiential world.
Today, O Lord,
we do collectively
give thanks for ourselves
and for our lives
and for our inspiration.
All of those who agree,
say amen.
Amen.
Wow, isn't that neat?
That was some lunch.
I have to go to that restaurant again.
That was on a fish sandwich.
Wow.
But those awarenesses
come out of nothingness,
you see.
Not out of thinkingness.
Nobody's thinking about it.
Let's say you discuss a subject,
you forget all about it.
Two or three hours later, wow.
Suddenly the inference of that
settles upon you.
Just as I told you
early in life,
I was a religionist,
very devout.
One day walking through the woods,
the totality of the suffering
of all of mankind
in all of history
unfolded itself
through conscious awareness.
Wasn't thinking about it,
nothing. Walking through the woods
in a beautiful day
and out of nowhere
the totality of the suffering
of all of mankind
throughout all of time.
It was staggering.
And in that moment
I became an atheist.
With the same dedication
and devotion I was
a devout atheist.
I wasn't a half-you-know-what
atheist, I was a devoted one.
Then I went from atheist to agnostic,
which is much better.
Atheism is also egotism.
It's saying you know
that there is no God,
which is idiotic.
The agnostic is an honest.
The agnostic says,
I of my own self
am unable to prove
nor disprove the existence of God.
That is honesty.
On a calibrated level
agnostic
does not calibrate negative
because you're being honest.
That is a fact.
In and of your own limited ego
you really cannot say that God
either exists or does not exist.
It's a different paradigm
and a different dimension.
There's no way for the human mind
which stops at 499
to be able to affirm the reality
and the existence of that
so that's an honest statement.
If you're doubtful,
forget being an atheist
and cling to being agnostic
because that is devotion to the truth.
The devotion to the truth
persisted.
First it was
vested in
religion, religiosity.
Then it was invested in
for a moment
atheism
but then quickly shifted
to agnosticism.
But at all times
the dedication was to the truth
and throughout psychoanalysis
all the years every day on the couch
Freudian and then Jungian
and various others
the dedication was to search for
and reach the absolute
core of truth itself
and the mind
just refused
all possible answers
and saw that they were belief systems
but the core of that which I am
that which I am
drilled right through
and had to reach the very
essence and the source of truth itself
the source of truth in life and existence
and that took me
as I've related before
to the depths of hell
the depths of hell are far worse than
no one can imagine
and
it's beyond conceptualizing of the human mind
because it's non-linear
depictions of hell are all linear
the experience is non-linear
timeless
and eternal
eternal darkness forever
with no hope ever of salvation
goes on for eons
eons
eons of abandon all hope
ye who enter here
and out of the silence of that
non-linear
hopelessness beyond all hope
a voice arose within
and said
if there is a god I ask him for help
and then oblivion
and then
suddenly the lights turned on again
all of existence shone forth
as the glory of god as
all of creation
and now you see a validation
of your own worth no matter who or what you are
what you do
by your sheer presence
you see that your mere witnessing
the lovability and the sacredness
of all of creation is already changing
creation
this group here is changing
in which creation is unfolding
wow
you see that doesn't appeal to the ego at all
that's sort of scary in a way
because you get wow
we have been somehow given this
possibility
the pen is
mightier than the sword
you see to know to really know this
is already transforming potentiality
the fact that a group
knows that it has somewhat of
some kind of an input
destiny
and destiny of mankind
alright let's see if that's so
we have permission to ask that
in front of this group
that this group does play a part in the ultimate
destiny of the evolution
of man on this planet
part of creation
a critical part of creation
a critical part of evolution
ok so in as much as you play a
critical part in evolution
creation has
unfolding of evolution
via consciousness itself
which is it's field
a group such as this
is changing the destiny
of mankind
let's see if that's so
resist
so mealy mouthing won't help you
anymore
what can I do just poor me
I'm just a clerk at the grocery store
alright
so you own
I'm trying to move you closer to
the realization of the self
for the capital S is the source of your own existence
because if you accept this
about yourself you move closer
to the truth of the source of your own existence
you diminish this
the voice of the
ego you diminish the voice of the
self and you've opened
the door for the expression of the
self for the capital S
and out of this meditation today
some people here are going to be
realizing the full
presence of the self
so help me
alright so we'll take a break
and then we're going to do questions and answers
we're going to spend more time with that
more in the future it's more informal
it's not didactic
we've supplied all the didactic
material you need
and we've armed
you with the defense if you're accused of being
spiritual that you're
applying the Heisenberg principle to all
of life's expressions
we'll meet you after the break which is
what three
what
no I wanted to
stop earlier because I wanted to give more time for
questions and answers
we'll take maybe 20 minutes
I want to leave more time for
interchange
and more of the traditional
teacher role
with the group where we
exchange with each other back and forth and
discuss and express
in a non didactic non formal
way sometimes I feel
like I'm being too much like a college prof
and you know presenting sort of a
linear didactic kind of a
understanding but that's part of
understanding to transcend the mind
you first satisfy it with
the information it wants to know
and now that it's got that information
it can transcend that information
and evolve into its own
potentiality as a knowingness
rather than a knowing about
the knowingness
occurs as a consequence
of becoming that
so first you have to know what it is you want to
become then what's
preventing you you drop that
and then your life becomes
the expression of
prayer so
our hope is that through the lectures
your life becomes the
expression of your own potentiality
that your life is your prayer
your life is the prayer
of who you are and the expression of who
you are which as we can see
benefits all mankind
amen so we'll see you after a break
take these with me