bacteria at one then you see the protozoa the crustaceans the insects you
see the what's that god you know like too much those things you what is that
guy he comes up with his tail like that scorpion 400 million years ago the
scorpion crawled out of the sea I wish he'd stayed there should have stayed
there anyway so we have the arachnids the amphibians the fish the octopus it
was a friend of mine I love octopuses they are so clever and smart and
beautiful I just could just sit and watch octopus they're just they
slithered and they change the color and nothing you put an octopus on a
checkerboard and he gets checkerboards all over him I mean it's just magical
you know you take an octopus and put him on a checkerboard he develops checkers
out I mean it's just yeah we should put him on an oriental rug see what he does
and he's a great guy
so here's our buddy the comodo dragon we use him because there are very
prominent people you know influencing all the world who calibrate less than a
komodo dragon we do not worship life we worship death what is that calibrated
I mean what's that calibrate right right 20 let's say that quote we have
permission through that quote here we worship death not life calibery it's over
20. Calibrates less than a Komodo dragon.
Mm-hmm. Komodo dragon.
Calibrates less than a Komodo dragon. Oh, wow. The implication
of that is just profound. Less than a reptile. All right.
So we see then, where is the dinosaurs?
Here they are. Less than a dinosaur. Less than a dinosaur.
There are people on the planet more dangerous than Tyrannosaurus Rex.
Think we should check their passports as they come in? I don't know.
I would like to, but anyway.
There are people that go into the cage with the Komodo dragon. There was a movie star's
spouse or friend or something. Went in the cage with the Komodo dragon without shoes on.
It lived tail to tail. All right. So most of us have a sufficient intelligence
that we try to avoid that which is reptilian and predatory. Here you have
the snakes and the alligators, the dinosaurs. Here's the dinosaurs.
And then, oh, God, I don't want to mention this. The whales and the dolphins.
Everybody who's a whale person, raise your hand. Whales.
OK. Dolphin people. Dolphins. That's it.
That's about even. 50-50. They're playing in Pittsburgh next month, the whales versus the dolphins.
These are the migratory birds.
They can't seem to get settled in one place or another. They keep wandering up to there and then back again.
And birds of prey you'd think would calibrate
lower, but no. 105. Rodents, rhinoceros.
Songbirds at only 125. That's a little disappointing, isn't it? I thought, gee, songbirds should be way up higher.
And the same with doves. So you see what we project upon them, what we value
about them. Grizzly bears, water buffaloes. Then we get to
wolves at 190, which people want to put back in the park system.
Hippopotamuses that you can't trust. I would advise you never
trust a hippopotamus. They kill more
people, surprisingly, than any other animal. Isn't that funny? A hippopotamus.
So then we suddenly see, as we do in mankind,
at level 200, a shift of intention. At 200,
that which is rapacious becomes benign.
You go from the carnivore, that which has to kill
in order to survive, to the herbivore, the
grazers, the zebra, the gazelle, the giraffe, the deer, the elk.
And the dairy cows, the sheep. And now you see the emergence
into the mid-200s of the pets and the gorilla.
You see the gorillas that actually saved the little baby's life. That was really,
that was touching, wasn't it? That wasn't Coco, but
let's get what that gorilla was. I got that gorilla in mind. You remember she
picked them up, picked up the child and put the child over where,
she knew people were coming. We have permission to do that gorilla.
That gorilla's consciousness is over 400, 410, 415,
420, 415. Alright, so that gorilla was at about 415
because of her interaction with humans. And it's more trustable
than 80% of the people on the planet.
I'd rather be with a mountain gorilla.
If you pay attention to your own business, the gorilla pays attention to you and eyes you
and after a while you get used to each other. And as long as you don't eat his bamboo shoot,
he's leaving you a bee. And of course, here's the animals that we love
and are very unique. And here's, we said the songbird is less there, but the songbird's
song is 500, just like the cat's purr and the dog's wagging tail.
Alright, so we'll go on to the next.
The great books of the Western world, I just, we've seen this many times.
What time do we have to stop? 12, I got 10 minutes to finish up the rest of the time.
The great books of the Western world are very interesting because they are the intellectual structure
of democracy and our society, the Western world. You can calibrate
the great names of history and you can see their veneration was
appropriate. The mid 400s is the stability, the backbone
of society, the backbone of government, democracies and
we pointed out before, it calibrates I think overall at 455
or 460, I forget where it is.
Calibrates I think at 450 or 455 overall. And then if you
remove Marx, Karl Marx jumps to about 460 and
if you remove Engels, Engels is at 200, he's not below 200, but he doesn't help the average.
Overall, if you take out Marx and Engels, the calibrated level, the wisdom of mankind
calibrates around 460. That's very impressive
erudition. Mathematics, science, quantum theory, all
cover around 460. So 460 you might say is scientific intellectual
certitude, philosophic discipline,
you're following the dialectic, you're respecting the Kantian categories, you're not jumping
from one category to another, which is characteristic of rhetoric.
So to be with logic you have to follow the rules of logic.
So this is the intellectual discipline, the structure, the strength of morality,
society, government, accountability,
responsibility, and of course the great philosophers looked at man's
upside and looked at man's downside because out of them also came metaphysics.
And theology, and therefore this is the wisdom of the ages.
This is where I spent my youth, misspent youth.
Kids are out there playing sockball or whatever they were doing there, hitting on each other
in vulgarities. I huddled in a chair with this.
So one thing about being small and fragile is the coach wouldn't allow me to play anything.
That wasn't allowed on the field.
And so he said, your bones are going to get crunched out there, Shorty.
So I lifted heavy books instead.
These are all heavy books.
And therefore, so the thing that you see, life compensates itself.
I wasn't a strong physical mesomorph.
And so all that energy went elsewhere.
And so these were all the friends of childhood, frankly, the friends of childhood.
And here we see the great names of all times.
Copernicus, Darwin, Descartes, Engels.
We see Faraday, all the foundation of science.
Sigmund Freud at 499.
I myself had years and years of psychoanalysis every day of the week, an hour on the analyst's couch.
And it's not politically correct to favor Freud anymore.
But I'll tell you, if you don't believe in the unconscious, all you have to do is lay on the analyst's couch an hour a day.
Every week and see what comes up.
And you will rediscover the Oedipal complex, I think.
You cannot believe it until you lay down on the couch.
I was just thinking of a patient that I saw one time.
And I noticed, he was a new patient.
I noticed that he drove in the exit of the parking lot.
He drove in the exit.
And then when he left, he drove out the entrance.
And said, help me.
When he came into the office, you know, we had discussed the psychoanalytic procedures.
He laid down on the couch backwards.
Instead of his head being here and his feet there, he lay around this way.
Yeah.
So 50 years of listening to the inner, speaks to the human mind, you know, year after year after year.
Having gone through it yourself gives you a certain insight.
So when critics come around, I say, yeah, right.
Uh-huh.
You just lay down there and see what comes up with you.
So these are my friends, Plato and Aristotle.
And, of course, my favorite friend is Socrates.
Because if you put together what we said this morning about the intrinsic innocence of mankind, you know, Socrates said that all men can choose only the good.
And that really reinforces, you know, you may not be able to go along with Jesus Christ and forgive your persecutors.
But Socrates certainly makes sense.
Because once you understand what Socrates says, then you can apply what Jesus recommended, you know.
And the Buddha recommended forgiveness because they don't know what they do.
Compassion out of man's ignorance.
So the Buddha said the only limitation in man is ignorance.
Which Jesus Christ said.
But it was Socrates that explained it and made it operational.
So it also satisfies your intellect.
That man's motivation, he can only choose what he perceives to be the good.
So if the good is killing off Americans, he's doing the good.
The more Americans he kills and blows up, the better.
The more Americans he blows up, the better.
The better.
Does he believe in forgiveness?
No, he believes in death.
So how can we forgive somebody who's pledged to the death of all of us?
There isn't one person in this room he would save.
Not one.
None of you.
Nobody.
All of you should die.
Huh?
Can we forgive him?
He believes that's the ultimate good.
So he's doing the ultimate good with the god of his imagination or his belief system.
So in his naivete, then.
His naivete.
However, that which is extremely naive is extremely dangerous.
A ten-year-old behind the wheel of a car, you know.
No sense of responsibility.
Nobody for the lives or the welfare of others.
So we can forgive them.
It doesn't mean to turn your back on them when they're holding a loaded gun, you know.
To turn your back.
Instead, it means to stand up for what you believe to be the truth.
To stand up for what you believe to be the truth.
Uh-huh.
All right.
So let's move on.
I forget what time we got to stop.
Oh, 35 minutes.
Well, I'm trying to finish up a couple thousand years.
I knew it.
And we'll make it.
This is the content.
And this is the context.
This is the situation.
We say that potentiality becomes an actuality when conditions are appropriate.
What you hold in mind tends to manifest.
Because this infinite field is what gives your thoughts power.
Therefore,
what you hold in mind tends to manifest.
In Scotland, in the middle of the tattoos, I'm thinking,
I'd love to have my group experiences.
That's the last I thought of it.
Next thing I know, a couple weeks ago,
I said, hey, let's get Piper's so we get the experiential instead of just the mental, intellectual, theoretical.
So the thought, a couple years ago in Scotland, bang,
happened this morning. See?
Uh-huh.
That is causality.
It's just because you love that thought.
You give it energy.
And now the thought, one day, you're sitting down and I'll say,
geez, why don't we get the bangpipers that we're going to get for St. Andrews
and have them come here?
Because not everybody's going to be going to St. Andrews.
And we get to experience the experiential, what 525 or what 530 feels like.
What 530 feels like.
Yeah.
That oneness of mankind.
Our oneness with our fellow man through the heart.
Yeah?
So we have trouble forgiving somebody.
We hold Socrates that each person is choosing what in their perception is the good.
Then within our heart, we hold a compassion for that person's ignorance.
It's not just seeing their ignorance but having compassion for it.
I know that that person probably completely believes what he's saying,
which brings forth even more compassion because I realize the helplessness
and the hopelessness
of the brainwash of that kind of a person
who's now unable to think independently or for himself.
Uh-huh.
So this is the linear.
This is the nonlinear.
And this is the situation we say that things manifest
as a consequence of local conditions.
So if there weren't any bangpipers around in Arizona,
we wouldn't have had them this morning.
Right?
Yeah.
So the motivation.
So intention then is very powerful.
Because of intention, what is held in mind is the Empire State Building appears.
The bangpipers show up.
All of us are here together.
The charts get done.
The books get written.
It's all because of collective intention.
And therefore, I want to thank everyone here for energizing our collective intention,
which I enjoyed very much this morning.
And we'll see you again after lunch.
Amen.
Tell us a story about the Mitchell Gym.
Now what?
You've got to fight your way up.
I am a tough guy.
I went to Richie Mitchell's gym when I was a kid.
He was the former medium heavyweight champion.
I was always getting beaten up, you know.
And I was brought up not to hit people lower than I am.
Other people weren't brought up that way.
So I was hittable.
Especially during corner practice.
I belong to the church choir.
Wednesday night.
Saturday and Sunday we practiced.
I was a boy solo.
Boy soloist, you know.
Soprano.
And I sang the Obligato de Panis Angelicus.
Ooh.
A full cathedral.
A full orchestra.
Stained glass windows.
The sun coming back and lighting up the incense.
And this incredible voice floated out of nowhere.
Physicality was here, I guess.
Yeah.
So, but anyway, I used to get beaten up.
So.
I've tried being nice to people.
Anyway.
So anyway, I went to Richie Mitchell's gym and I learned the Marquis of Queensbury rules.
You know, so we boxed with Marquis of Queensbury rules.
And I wasn't a heavy hitter, but I was fast.
So I found that if you give a guy a bloody nose, that's usually the end of the fight.
So I would give him a bloody nose and the guy would go like this and the fight was over.
So they started leaving me alone.
Wow.
Then I visited my grandmother.
She lived in a different neighborhood.
Went out in the alley.
And I was challenged to a fight.
Well, I never turned down a challenge to a fight.
I was fought.
Even though I was gonna lose.
I figured, what the hell.
So I went out and scrapped it.
So this guy challenges me to a fight.
And I said, okay.
And he kicked me in the butt.
You know, where.
And I was down on the ground.
So I learned to never use Marquis of Queensbury rules in other areas of the world.
But I was a tough guy.
I was a tough guy.
You know, you know, you're the boy.
You know.
But I was a tough guy.
down the ground. So I learned never use Marquis of Queensbury rules in other
areas of the world, which is what our country is learning. Yeah, Marquis of
Queensbury rules are okay. Anyway, then I, when I was in the Navy, I went aboard a
minesweeper, and the boatswain's mate there, who stayed a friend of mine until
he left this world not too long ago, he said, Shorty, do you box? I said, well I
took boxing lessons. So he said, we'll go up in the gun tub. Okay. So we went up in the gun tub to go around.
He hit me once and I was out cold. Then I find out later he was the champion of
the third fleet. Jimmy Sanders, God bless him. We stayed in touch. 18 guys on that ship.
It happened the last
one, the Survivor. Christmas, you don't get any more Christmas cards. So all the
non-smokers are dead. That's true. All my buddies who were, they always ate out of
the brown paper bag, and they died jogging, actually. That's a fact, yeah.
Well, we'll get back to reality here now. We were talking about traps, traps. The
reason we're always looking for something outside of ourself is because
we feel insufficient. If you go from incomplete to complete, that's the way
you picture the world, then at any moment you're incomplete. Because you project
yourself ahead in time, and you're going to be incomplete. You may not be incomplete
now, but five minutes from now you can be incomplete. So how do you stay
incomplete? Well, at this exact moment, everybody here is complete. Agree? Anybody
lacking anything? I don't know. Okay.
So if you go from, instead from incomplete to complete, at every moment
you are complete. The way to get away from all anxiety is to live in
this exact split second of now, this mode.
Let's say you're going to be beheaded, okay? Right now,
do I have a problem? No. Now do I have a problem? No. Now do I have a problem? No!
Let's just put your head on the block,
do I have a problem now? no.
Do I have a problem now? No.
Look at your head. Do you have a problem now? No.
At any one moment of time, you do not have a problem
because you're not projecting into the hypothetical.
You're living in the real, the experiential.
And in the real, the experiential, you're always complete.
Everything is perfect this moment.
You might have to go to the bathroom five minutes from now,
but now you don't.
Well, let's see.
We were going to talk about something important today,
but I can't remember what it was now.
Oh, yes, okay.
Yes, there you go.
The other trap is the reason people don't get out of the ego
is because of the payoff.
What holds the ego in place is that we get, we juice it, we juice it.
All right.
Why don't people give up hate?
Because they get so much out of hate.
They juice it.
They love it.
They love hate.
There was a recent semi-celebrity, all of the media,
and as she got arrested, she was just radiating with joy.
Blissful glee as she's being arrested, right?
All right.
So what happens is, you see, because of the spiritual energy,
it hasn't arrived.
The spiritual energy doesn't arise until consciousness level 200,
and we'll show the brain physiology shift at that level.
You got a brain physiology shift at that level?
Yeah?
Anyway, so the ego lives on animal energy.
I need that brain physiology.
You got the next?
Is that the next one?
Anyway, the animal is left brain.
It always has to be ready to get what's out there.
It lives off adrenaline, danger, and et cetera.
Its source is animal energy, the thrill of hate, the thrill of anger,
the thrill of fear.
All those things pump out adrenaline and energy
and neurotransmitters.
Was this the one we wanted?
Let me just see.
I wanted quantum mechanics.
We'll go back to quantum mechanics.
We can live without quantum mechanics.
The brain function.
Oh, here we got quantum mechanics.
No, I don't want quantum mechanics now.
If I couldn't have it when I didn't want it,
I don't want it now.
All right, we get hooked.
We get hooked on this pathway here.
I saw you do that.
You thought it was subliminal, but I was faster than you.
I'm faster than 110,000th of a second.
All right.
So here's the animal.
We call it in the human left brain.
It's an instinctual animal energy.
And people who live below 200,
that is the only source of psychic energy they have.
Therefore,
they have to have it and thrive on it.
You can't take hatred and self-pity and all that away from them.
Anybody here who's a therapist
knows that people that are hooked on self-pity,
there's no way.
When they're hooked on being victim,
there's no way you can cure them.
The payoff of being victim,
self-pity, anger, resentment, being right,
I mean, you know, it's overwhelming.
It's like intoxicating.
So this is, I'm right, you're wrong.
Okay.
What happens at level 200 now
is you have the inflow of kundalini energy,
spiritual energy.
I wish it had a different name.
Kundalini sounds so Sanskrit like it came from Uhu land.
But anyway,
for lack of a better word,
spiritual energy,
a different new energy now begins to pour in.
That's why we see the difference at level 200
in both the human and the animal kingdom.
You see the beginning of spiritual awareness.
Below 200,
there is no awareness
of your existence.
You experience,
but you're unaware of your is-ness and beingness,
of existence as such.
Therefore, you do not value the life of others.
Few below 200 do not value the life of others.
The life of others is meaningless.
Hitler says they lost the war,
kill all the Germans,
burn down, you know, burn down Paris,
slaughter the family.
We're going to be seeing that
in the international trial coming up.
Slaughter the family,
slaughter,
or as in-laws, slaughter his own children, slaughter his people, slaughter his own troops.
How can that be?
Level 200 or under, others don't have any worth or humanist value to their existence,
other than being utilizable.
No conscious awareness of the worth or the value of others.
Therefore, to expect that being a decent person, they will respect you,
you're projecting that value onto them and presuming they have it.
They do not have it.
What calls for mercy is an idiot's call to them, and they'll chuck your head right off.
As you cry for mercy, huh?
Why? Because it has no reality below 200.
It's only when you get to 200 that the value of others, others even, comes into the consideration.
Okay, what happens then?
As you see, the shift in the brain function is now right brain.
See, this is a fast brain to the emotional reaction that reacts.
Kill the bastard.
Yeah.
You remember him as the son of a bitch who deserved to die.
That's the left brain view of him.
Once you get the right brain, the fast track is to the prefrontal cortex,
but what you see here is the birth of the etheric energy body.
It's only at 200 that you develop an energy field body.
It's called the etheric body and the etheric brain.
Now information fast tracks the etheric brain, and you get the essence of the thing,
and that makes you hold back from pulling the trigger.
You don't pull the trigger unless you've got to pull the trigger.
Whereas in the left brain, you're happy to pull the trigger.
In fact, you're eager for an opportunity.
All right, so we have completely two different populations.
You see, here we have left brain dominance, which is linear, based on stress, fight or flight,
alarm reaction, thymic stress, disrupts the acupuncture system, and proneness of the disease.
Above 200, you see right brain dominance.
What you're picking up right brain is the overall dimension, the nonlinear.
You release endorphins, positive emotions that supports the thymus gland,
which pours out more killer cells, decreases immunity, increases healing,
and you attract.
The emotions is slower.
Here's the difference in therapeutic results between the healer and the, let's say,
academically limited treater, you know, the provider of services.
Now they call it provider of services, and you're a consumer of services.
And the provider-consumer, which is the business model, has a certain level of recovery.
So what I discovered from the clinic back east where I had, you know, 50 employees,
and I had a dozen therapists, and psychiatrists, psychologists, social workers,
is some got terrific results all the time, and some got lousy results all the time.
And what was the difference?
Because they were all academically well-trained.
Why was two different doctors having different results?
It was because of the calibration level of the physician.
So the double-blind experiment, therefore, is fallacious.
First of all, it's usually set up fallaciously, with skepticism, etc.
And it discounts the subjective.
It discounts the subjective.
No, it's who the treater is, who the healer is.
That makes all the difference in the world, you know?
In fact, they get in my mind, this SLB is going to recover.
By God, he's going to recover.
And, you know, I stayed in practice long after I closed my practice.
I had a part-time just Thursday morning as they saw some guys,
because they'd been with me so many years, you know,
the positive transference was keeping them going.
And I knew if I quit on them, they'd croak.
So I thought, I've got to wait until they all die before I can quit, which I did.
Including the guy who used to walk in and ask me for a light when he had his oxygen thing on.
He'd smoke a cigarette with his oxygen thing on.
I said, can you do that? Won't we blow up?
He said, no, he won't.
I said, okay.
He must know, or he would have blown himself away already.
All right, so the dedication to this guy, you know, there's a dedication to him.
So it was that love for your patient, your love for who they are, you know.
They couldn't help but recover.
And it was only one patient I treated that didn't recover, one.
I don't know why to this day, and I knocked my brains out,
I did everything holistic, everything you could do.
And he just would not get well.
Hey, I'll have to kill this guy, let's get rid of him.
.
You know, and he told me he had one day of happiness in his life.
At age 26, he never forgot that day.
And he lived in the hope that that day would recur somehow.
It was really sad.
I couldn't help him.
I sent him to the Mayo Clinic, et cetera.
So when local conditions are right, one local affecting condition is karma.
So there are sort of heavy karmic situations.
In which the permission, you haven't achieved the right or the permission yet, okay?
All right, so let's just go back.
What we were going to do was before.
Let's go back to the, I wanted to just bring in the Heisenberg principle, yeah.
This is the quantum mechanics and the kinesiologic response.
And of course, you're all familiar with the Schrodinger equations and the Dirac equations,
and the von Neumann process.
This is by which the Heisenberg principle operates.
The power of intention.
Wayne Dyer's book, Power of Intention.
One of the local conditions is intention.
So your intention about that person, the way you hold them in mind,
is already very powerfully influencing the consequence.
So the physics experiments where the result is altered
by the mere observation of the experimenter,
does not take into account the consciousness level of the experimenter.
So let's say the average experimenter is around 420 or 430, around there.
And he looks at the experiment with a certain expectation.
The consequence has already changed.
He's collapsed the wave function and brought about a potentiality into an actuality.
What would be the effect of somebody who calibrated 500 meters?
He calibrated 500 looking at that experiment with a specific intention in mind.
That's the value of the teacher, the healer, the therapist, the coach, the confidant.
Because what you're holding in mind for those people now has quite a powerful effect.
And the likelihood of their fulfilling your expectation for them is quite high.
So the von Neumann, I mean the Heisenberg process then,
is the explanation in quantum mechanics of the power of intention.
The field in which you're operating.
So let's leave that, it's the same sort of academic.
But I just want to show that you can move from the intellectual, scientific,
and move through the higher mathematics, move into quantum theory,
and merge into the next paradigm.
Because at level 500, you leave the world of academic Newtonian,
you can leave via the door of quantum mechanics,
and still stay a respectable scientific person.
And if they say, are you spiritual?
You say, no, I'm just practicing the Heisenberg principle.
Just practicing that, applying the Heisenberg principle to experiments.
We don't want to see this, it's too academic.
And, alright, so we're again talking about causality.
There is no causality.
There is no cause outside of yourself.
It's only what you hold in mind that has any power.
You're only subject to what you hold in mind.
Okay?
What you hold in mind.
So, people think that, well, the source of happiness is out there.
In that case, if the source of happiness is out there,
then now you're a victim.
You're a victim.
And you're subject to fear and anxiety.
Because the out there-ness can disappear at any moment.
Besides, whatever you achieve in the world,
as you will see,
is not related to out there-ness at all.
In fact, statistically, it has nothing to do with out there-ness.
Statistically, the rate of happiness is directly a result of level of consciousness.
And here you see the level of consciousness.
The rate of happiness is practically zero.
All the way down here, the rate of happiness is,
we're still less than ten percent.
And anger, which people love to be angry.
Why?
Because the animal in you loves to puff up and intimidate people.
And you get a false sense of strength.
False sense of strength.
Pride, which is as far as you can go, below 200,
certainly feels better than these things below it.
So, I don't knock pride.
It's a way to go.
But it's very, very vulnerable.
The minute you cross over the line at 200,
you see the rate of happiness jumps 22 to 55,
and then it escalates rapidly.
So, happiness is related to the level of consciousness directly.
Directly related to the level of consciousness.
So, if you plan to live in the moment and stop anticipating the future,
and leave the future up to God,
you can feel fine as it cuts your head off.
Just do a good job of it, right?
It helps the tip of my phone.
I've got a few ducats for you, my boy.
Okay, don't tell anybody.
I always tip the has-been.
Those of you who remember some previous lives will remember it.
It's always well to pay the has-been, you know.
Okay, let's move to the next one, eh?
Ah, yes.
Do we know what's the next one?
Oh, yes. Is that what we were going to go to?
Yep.
You remember that?
Mm-hmm.
We did brain function, rate of happiness?
No.
Okay, all right.
All right.
So, anyway, today we're talking about the traps.
We're talking about the seductions, the payoffs of the ego.
So, you never have to give up the negatives.
You never have to give up greed and all those things
that you think you can possibly never give up.
All you have to give up is one thing over and over.
No matter what it is, the negative feeling,
the out-there-ness, there's only one thing you've got to be willing to surrender,
and that's the payoff of that.
Therefore, the fun of cutting off somebody's head
is the same as the fun of getting a new car.
It's always just the payoff.
Could I surrender the pleasure I get out of that?
You don't have to give up hating people.
You can say, can I give up the feeling of satisfaction I get out of there?
Yeah, I could.
Now the question is, well, would you?
Would you be willing to give up the payoff of it?
Don't give up hate.
Don't give up regret.
Don't give up remorse.
Don't give up being better than other people.
Don't give up greed.
Forget about all that.
Look at what you want to get rid of and just see that there's a payoff.
So there's only one thing.
It's like Johnny One Note.
It's only the payoff of it, not the thing itself.
What you're addicted to is the payoff.
Whether it's getting even.
Take that.
That's so mean.
Or being right.
Stupid.
You are so stupid.
The pleasure of being arrogant.
It's just that I am better than other people.
Most people give it a secret.
My view of the world is right and yours is wrong.
Whatever.
All right.
All those positionalities, there's only one thing holding them all in place.
They have exactly the same single payoff.
And that's the ego juice you get out of it.
Over and over again, all you've got to do is be willing to give up the ego juice.
That person says, well, I can't give up the ego juice out of that.
And so I hold a gun to their head and I say, if you don't, I'm going to blow your freaking brains out.
Now could you?
Yes, I could.
So it isn't that you could.
It's that you won't.
Of course you could.
Revolver to your brains.
Could you give up the juice of being right all the time?
No.
That was, I had it on an empty cylinder.
But he gave it up right then and there.
So you could.
So consequently, it's a matter of willingness.
Well, will is a whole different thing than being addicted.
Will.
Because the human will is only as strong as one's level of consciousness.
You'll hear people say, I tried willpower.
I tried willpower.
It didn't work.
Somebody at consciousness level 150, that's the power of their will.
So when they use willpower, it only, it calibrates at 150.
That isn't strong enough.
A lifetime of doing this, it's going to take more than 150, you know.
We know all the good intentions that went by the board January 1st things, you know.
We're going to do this this year and it doesn't happen.
No.
It's only by surrender.
When you see that I of myself am unable to do this, you ask for God's help.
Now, the spiritual will calibrates at 850.
Aha.
Divine will is a 50.
The divine will, then recovery from a lifetime addiction, can happen in an instant.
People who are members of 12-step groups were helplessly, hopelessly addicted.
And I treated so many over the years.
And the instant they completely surrendered to God, they recovered.
In that instant, they recovered.
It comes as a flash.
The willingness to surrender.
So the way out of anything, any stuckness, then, is to see that it isn't you couldn't, but you wouldn't.
You wouldn't because in your experience, willpower hasn't worked.
Therefore, surrender at great depth brings recovery from anything.
Surrender at great depth, yeah, is the secret, huh?
All right.
We were talking about traps and we mentioned sort of far out kinds of religious and spiritual fantasy worlds.
Fiction, fiction.
And people get hooked in that fiction because the child in them, you know, likes the idea of magic.
Likes the idea of magic.
And Potter books are honest because she tells you that it's fiction and that it's magic, you know.
She doesn't pretend that this is a spiritual truth.
She doesn't pretend it's a spiritual truth.
Her books calibrate, I forget, to 10 or 20 or something.
I remember when they came out, a lot of people, evangelicals especially, were worried about it.
But it does calibrate over 200 because she makes clear that which is fiction and that which is fact
and that which is deleterious mixes the two.
So you're reading fiction.
But it's expressed as though it's fact, you know.
So research uncovered these secrets hidden in the hairs of the camel, the nose of the camel.
And God really revealed his secrets there, you see.
You count the stones of the Sphinx and divide it by the sacred cubit and all the rest.
So to avoid that, to avoid the traps of that, all you need is to compare it to that which is highly integrative.
That which calibrates at the very highest.
What are the earmarks then of spiritual truth and teachers and spiritual groups?
One thing about spiritual truth is it's always the same.
The presence within.
When the ego drops, when the ego dissolves, which it did when you turn over your...
The last thing left was life.
And that was the last thing.
The ego turning over one's life.
Because what you think is your life is the...
You think it's the core of the ego.
The core of the ego has you convinced that it is the source of your life.
Therefore, when you're faced with the last thing left to go through the last door is to turn over your life to God,
then it takes all what you've got.
And if you've heard the truth before, the vibrations and the frequency of your aura.
And from Zen I got,
All fear is illusion.
So you walk through the final door of fear and it is terror.
You are dying.
You actually feel yourself die.
And then shines forth the splendor of all eternity.
Beyond all of time.
So, the truth is true at all times and in all places.
The realization of that state and that condition has been the same throughout time.
Whether it's the Buddha, whether it's...
All the mystics throughout history.
The realization of the Self with a capital S as God immanent.
See, religion is preoccupied with God transcendent.
That means elsewhere in time and place.
But the mystic is concerned with the realization of God as immanent.
That which is divine is obviously everywhere.
It can't be just transcendent.
If that was so, God would come up and stop right around here, you see.
And that which is you would be outside of God.
Obviously, if God is universal, then God is within you as well, yeah?
If God is the source of all life, then the source of your life also.
The radiance of divinity within, then.
What it does is it silences the mind.
It silences the mind.
The mind.
The mind never talks again.
Happily.
Conversing this is an aspect of the persona
which is an attribute that you learn later.
Just like with the whereabouts of the body and all.
And people are talking to the body.
You can't figure out who the hell they're talking about.
Because that which is you, there is no such thing as that in that bodiness.
But you see that they presume the body must be where you are.
So you learn how to correspond.
And after a great deal of time, then there's the relearning of how to be in the world.
And if one is karmically destined,
then that is what happens.
You do come back in the world.
What the world calls back in the world.
Anyway, the truth is the truth at all times and all places.
So described 5000 B.C. in the Gita in the great Aryan.
It was first described about 5000 B.C. out of the Aryan culture of ancient Hindu.
Ancient India.
And has remained the same ever since.
Truth is the truth.
Truth is not exclusive.
It's non-sectarian.
In other words, it's free and available to everyone.
Available, open to all.
Not exclusive.
You don't have to sign up.
There are no secrets.
Nothing is hidden.
There's nothing sold.
Nothing peddled.
No magical formulas or mysteries.
How can there be a mystery to that which is universally true?
Ancient hidden mysteries.
Come on, give me a break.
How much?
That's right.
For 5000 B.C. you could be a master.
What the hell?
Make me a master, right?
With kinesiology you can tell the truth of anything.
There are no hidden secrets in this universe.
Nowhere.
Even without kinesiology.
Learn to leave the body, you know.
Which I learned to do.
It happens spontaneously.
Then I learned how to do it.
It will.
You want to know the secret?
What's in that box?
Just project yourself into the box.
It says, hello.
Greetings.
You come back out of the box and tell people it says, hello, greetings.
Say hello to everyone who says, hello, greetings.
There are no hidden secrets.
All right.
It's not exclusive.
It's available to everybody.
You try to make it available in all kinds of ways.
Integrity of purpose.
There's nothing to gain or lose.
It's nonsectarian.
Truth is not the exposition of a limitation.
See how people own God.
God favors this genetic group.
God favors this part of the world.
God has favoritism.
You see what kind of an anthropomorphic God that is.
The truth is available to all.
See?
Nothing is hidden.
Nothing is sold.
The truth has nothing to gain or lose.
Whether you go with it or don't go with it is immaterial.
You know what I mean?
Guy says, I don't believe him.
I said, well, don't read the freaking book.
You know what I'm saying?
Tell me a favorite.
Don't read it.
I mean, what gain is there?
What gain is there?
It's devoid of positionalities and it's independent of opinion.
Truth is nonlinear.
There you got it.
So the things that we're talking about that are misleading, the fabrications about spirituality,
all have to do with linearity.
Every one of them.
Time, place, people with names.
I don't know.
Master Dinggong, from the year 6032, and planet number 67.
That's all linear.
The presence within is like infinite space.
It's nonlinear.
Hmm.
Consciousness is like an infinite field of energy.
An infinite field of energy is non-linear.
It doesn't have any thingness, dates, positions, form, figures.
Huh?
It's continuous.
It can brush its teeth.
It can make it thats.
There's no thingness to it, okay.
Devoid of positionality, truth is not anti-anything.
Falsehood and ignorance are not its enemies,
but merely represents the absence.
Therefore, the dictum, there is no opposite to truth,
there is only its absence.
Truth has no opposite.
It only has an absence.
And it's comparable to electricity being in a wire.
The electricity is either there or not there.
When it's not there, you can't say,
well, now what's running down the wire is offness,
and offness is the opposite of electricity.
You understand?
Truth is either present or not present.
So, it doesn't have an enemy, you see,
because it's either there or not.
There are no requirements or demands,
no required memberships, you don't have to sign up,
you don't have any dues, no oaths, no pledges,
no regulations, no rules.
No conditions.
Because those are methods of control.
Now, why would somebody who's enlightened want to control you?
Well, he'd get out of controlling you.
Yeah, your sex life, what you eat, where you sleep,
whether you should work, take this job, not that job.
So, you'll see those things which are really sort of cults.
They worship this guy, usually with some fancy name,
and he tells them all about their sex life, what to wear, how to dress,
what they can do.
All for a price.
All right, no regulations, no oaths.
You don't have to sign anything.
And there's no consequences if you leave.
You're free to leave.
You can leave any time you want.
No consequences.
Nobody's going to put a rattlesnake in your mailbox.
Non-controlling.
Spiritual purity has no interest in the personal lives of others.
Now, why would an enlightened being be interested in what you wear,
your dress, your style, your sex life, your economics,
your family patterns, your dietary habits,
or whether you wear a hat or not?
Whether you wear a hat or a beard,
various other anatomical details, what you eat.
All right.
So, spiritual truth is free of force or intimidation.
No brainwashing, no adulation of leaders,
no training rituals, no indoctrinations,
and truth.
A young man came on TV, I think it was last night or the night before.
He follows a sort of highly visible leader.
And as he began to talk,
he was just like the perfect exposition of brainwashing.
The languaging, the style, the context in which he held it.
Just perfect brainwash.
Once you've heard brainwash,
you know what it looks like and what it sounds like.
And you can spot brainwash.
It's a mile away.
This is a kid who'd been indoctrinated.
All his, the style of the languaging,
from his background, ethnic, educational,
that isn't his style of languaging.
That was an indoctrinated style of languaging.
The style of languaging is foreign to the person's cultural background
and educational level, et cetera.
All right.
Next thing we go is non-binding.
There are no regulations, laws, edicts, contracts, or pledges.
You see, those are all attempts to control.
Why would that which is infinite and present in all that exists,
you know, be willing to control you?
Willing to control you.
You see, that's coming from a linearity and a causality.
You understand, as we've explained before,
the infinite field of consciousness itself
is like a giant electromagnetic field of infinite power.
And your spirit, by virtue of your freedom of your will,
by ascent and decline,
you have decided what kind of a charge to put on the little iron filing.
So your little iron filing, this is your spirit.
It's got its karmic propensities.
When you're born, you can already calibrate a child.
The minute they're born, they have a calibrated level of energy,
calibrated level of consciousness.
At the moment of birth,
in a universe in which nothing is accidental,
then, the karmic propensity manifest in this lifetime
starts out at that level.
Then, by your own will,
by your own will,
you, like, comfortably change the charge
and the polarity on this little iron filing.
Now, where you go in this giant electromagnetic field
is not up to an arbitrary god, is it?
It's all...
Divine justice is that what you have become
automatically aligns you in the field
by virtue of that which you are.
And that which you are came about only by your own decision.
Each one paddles his own canoe.
So there doesn't need to be an arbitrary god
who gets jealous, angry, punitive,
because that which you are
automatically aligns you in the field.
When the lightning bolt hits, it's not by accident.
You just happen to be there and get fried,
because that's where you were in the electromagnetic spectrum.
Okay, non-binding.
Freedom.
Participants are free to come and go.
No proselytizing, no intimidating,
no brainwashing.
There's no hierarchy.
People who work in this field
do so voluntarily.
Commonality.
Recognition is a consequence of what one has become,
rather than as a result of ascribed titles, adjectives, or trappings.
That gets you out of guruism.
Guruism, you know, calibrates now below 200, yes?
Because of its exploitation.
In India.
India has a tradition of exploitation, yeah?
Because the exploitation of the title, you see,
it now calibrates below 200, that title,
which once was a very high title.
Truth avoids glamorization
and trying to impress people
with wealth and great buildings
and great trappings and drapings.
You know, that's glamorization.
So you see in some, in a lot of cults,
you see the glamorization of spiritual truth,
the glamorization of it,
because of the seductive lure of the glamorization.
Every week we get some slick magazine.
It's alleged to be spiritual.
On the front, it's always slick.
There's usually somebody in a meditating yoga position.
Failing that, there's a slick, seductive-looking,
pretty blonde or brunette, you know?
And the whole thing is done in a certain artistic style,
sort of like the 20s, you know?
So there's a glamorization and a seduction,
the adding of like a lure to it, a lure,
a seductive lure, yeah?
There's a big fair someplace next week,
and all these gurus and shamans
and all this stuff.
It's going to be there.
And magic, magic is going to be very big.
Okay.
So this is a, you know, everyday kind of catalog.
You get it.
The catalog I'm holding in mind,
I have permission to cover it, right?
It's over 200 resist.
Yeah, all right.
So you're going to spend the whole day
in amusements.
These are okay.
So if you say I'm going to the New Age Festival Carnival,
that's fine.
The thing is not to get seduced
and trapped into it, you see,
because there's no teachers on the other side
who don't know what a teacher on this side knows.
I haven't heard of a teacher on the other side
that couldn't tell you anything
your grandmother couldn't tell you.
You can't, your mother-in-law, eat well,
you know, eat your spinach, watch your nutrition.
All right, are there adepts on the other side?
Yes, because they reach their highest level
in Mesopotamia.
What we see is the New Age Festival
is old hat in Mesopotamia.
The same entities are still practicing.
The same entities, they're on the other side
in the astral domains.
Same entity that read your fortune
in 450 BC is reading your fortune
in Sedona next week.
Same entity, same entity.
All right, so with a little kinesiology,
you can check it out for yourself.
If these people were spiritually erudite,
they would have transcended
and be in heavenly realms by now.
Since Mesopotamia, you've had a lot of time, folks.
To get off Energy 240,
you should be up to 500, 600 by now.
You should be in a celestial realm.
After a couple thousand years
if this entity on the other side had it together,
they would have been in a celestial realm long ago.
So you just find out with kinesiology
the next time you get a reading.
How long that entity has been doing this.
You'll see what I'm talking about.
After that much time, they are extremely adept.
They are extremely adept, and they're intuitive,
and they're very psychic.
And, of course, you go through that yourself
when the kundalini energy comes in.
You know exactly what a person is thinking.
You can even see their past lives.
You can tell by their aura, the whole thing.
The whole thing is an instant readout
without even trying it, see?
So these people are very adept.
The slightest hesitation, they know they got you hooked.
People will say,
I don't believe that anymore, and I'm still going.
True.
Okay.
Freedom to come and go.
Recognition of anybody with anybody
is because of who they are.
And it's inspirational.
No glamorization.
No seduction.
Non-materialistic.
Neediness.
You don't need to pump people for wealth,
prestige, their connections,
their buildings, whatever.
Truth is already total and complete
and has no need
to proselytize
or sign up people.
There's no point to sign up people.
I don't want anybody
signing up anybody to come here.
In fact, if you've been signed up, I'm throwing out.
It's so much ahead.
Give you ten bucks for everybody
to get there to sign up for.
All right.
So that's, you see, the commercialization of spirituality.
You see commercialization of it all over the place.
Detached.
There's no involvement,
non-involvement in worldly affairs.
I'm not in any parades at all.
These parades are too dangerous
with the dogs
and the fire hoses
and all the crap.
Detached.
There's non-involvement in worldly affairs.
Why?
Because you see the evolution of consciousness.
You see the evolution of mankind.
And you see the convolutions
which evolution goes through.
It's benign.
Truth is identifiable
along a progressive gradient.
It has no opposite.
That's what we mean
by calibrated levels of consciousness.
Therefore it has no enemies
to castigate or oppose.
Spiritual truth would not be involved
in a religious war.
Spiritual truth has nothing to gain
by converts.
Nothing to gain.
So those who see converts
are looking for worldly power.
Worldly power.
That which is linear.
That which is transitory.
That which is a projected value
of the ego.
Non-intentional.
Truth does not intervene
or have any agenda or propose
on others.
We don't try to sell truth.
We don't try to impose it on others.
We don't try to glamorize it.
We don't commercialize it.
There's something within each person
that hears the truth.
When you're ready for it
you get it right away.
I remember somebody said
when I was at some place
he just mentioned
nobody had ever heard of the Course in Miracles
he said when you get home
look up the Course in Miracles.
Something like that.
When I got home I looked up the Course in Miracles
I met the publisher
got to know Bill and Helen
and all of them.
As a consequence.
Yeah.
So when you're ready to hear it
you get it the first instant you hear it.
Non-intentional.
Does not intervene, have an agenda to propose
doesn't try to promulgate
doesn't try to enlist people.
Non-dualistic.
Everything occurs as a consequence
of that which it is.
Not as a consequence
of something outside of itself.
Potentiality manifests as actuality
rather than
as a result of causation.
You see the minute you look for cause
you're now involved in a
dualistic positionality with the world
and you're going to favor this cause
and defavor that cause.
This cause is going to become your enemy, etc.
Tranquility and peace.
There are no issues or partialities.
No desire to change others
or impose.
The effect of higher energies
is inside and not dependent
on propagation or effort.
God doesn't need help anymore
than gravity needs
the help of an apple falling from the tree.
Does worship please God
or does it just fulfill your own potentiality?
Can't you see God
with his ego all puffed up
look at all the people worshiping him.
Oh God.
Equality.
Equality is the reverence for all of life
and all of its expression.
And it really avoids that which is deleterious
rather than opposing it.
That's also in accord with Christ's teaching.
Not to oppose evil
but to avoid it.
That which you perceive as evil
do not become interlocked with it
because now you will become
at the effect of evil.
So therefore hating evil and fighting evil
is a losing cause
because by doing so
you're merely propagated.
Equality.
Reverence for all of life
and all of its expressions.
The willingness to merely be benign
to have good will towards all of life.
People say
what spiritual thing can I do?
I say just have good will towards all of life
no matter what it may be
and without exception.
This eventually leads to being conscious
and aware of the beauty of all that exists.
This eventually
results in a reverence for all of life
and
this world and all of its expressions.
It means that
you walk around the beetle
instead of stepping on it.
You don't have to go to great lengths
and go to
scrupulosity but
you see people at a certain level
I watched a guy actually
go out of his way and
risk turning his car over
in order to try and hit a cat that was
crossing the road.
He turned on his wheels, went up on two wheels
he was trying to hit this cat.
Which is different than stepping over the beetle.
We've used the beetle many times.
The beetle lays there
and his little legs are going like this
and above consciousness level 200
you grab a twig and you put it down
and he grabs it
and he walks away. He's happy.
Yeah, that may not
do him any good but it's good for your karma
isn't it?
What the hell did you turn me over
on my feet for? I was having a good time
laying on my back wiggling my feet
this idiot comes over and grabs me
for all of life
because eventually you see
the sacredness of all that exists.
So if evolution
and creation are one
and the same thing
then what you eventually begin to witness
is the sacredness of all that exists
and you have a reverence
for all that exists.
Therefore, you care
for everything equally.
I'm not going to
care for the beautiful flower
because it's nicer than this
nor am I
going to waste this.
You know everything
you see what a wonderful
how we're surrounded by
nothing but wonderful things.
The sacredness of all of life
life is realized to be eternal
and physicality is temporary
life is not subject to death
and that brings us to the law
of
conservation of matter
conservation of energy
the law of conservation of life
life cannot be destroyed
it can only be
forced to change form
when you spot the moth
slap the moth
he goes right on flying
in his etheric body
and doesn't even notice it
you think he died
how could he die
death is not a possibility
the moth goes right on flying
in his etheric body
and doesn't even notice
resist
because his energy body
is what he experiences
of physicality
so he's only experiencing
his own experience to begin with
the non-linear
the non-linear domain
is not provable
that which is provable
is linear
and within the Newtonian paradigm
instead it's mystical
it arises as
as a knowingness
ineffable
not capable of definition
devoid of temporality
is that the end 26?
I think we have 31
38 oh my god you've been sneaking some more in
affirmative
non-operative
truth does not do anything
it just is
it influences everything around it
by virtue of that which it is
not by virtue of that
which it does
which is looking at it from causality
the Newtonian paradigm
thinks that it's because of what
the person does
no, it's because of what the person is
their presence transforms
the energy in the room
non-predictive
therefore it doesn't predict
the events in the future
whether the world is going to end in 1692
or whatever it's going to be
non-sentimental
devoid of emotionality
so sometimes I sound cryptic
because emotionality
emotionalism
is a self-indulgence
it's a self-indulgence
I heard he died
right, right
I got it
is anything more necessary?
no, nothing more is necessary
I got the message
and I've gone through the death of many people
close friends
I got he's gone
period
that's the end of it
I got the hurricane killed 3000 people
I got it
save the emotionality
why?
because you're bleeding out energy all over the place
nobody is helped by your emotionality
somebody needs a fracture fixed
you're crying and blubbering
how much?
you need the cast put on
you need something to eat
non-emotionally
so it doesn't get sentimental
and waste energy on emotionalism
non-authoritarian
there are no rules or dictates to be followed
non-egoistic
teachers respected only for
what they are
what they have become
educational provides information in every kind of format
you can think of
books, audio tapes, video tapes, lectures
self-supporting
neither mercenary nor materialistic
doesn't solicit
freestanding
complete without dependence on external
authorities
what I say
depends completely
on nobody
it's not so
because so and so said it
in the year 720
it's so because it's so
right now
because truth is always true
like right now
so instead of quoting authorities
so and so
you shine forth the truth of that which you are
period
so you are your own authority
the self within is the authority
it's not so
because I'm the sixth descendant
of the sixteenth patriarch
et cetera
which is putting
the source of truth outside of yourself
no
the mystic knows it's a knowingness
because of the radiance, the effulgence of the self
within
because the truth is just obvious
you don't have to quote from somebody
it's just plain obvious
it's stunningly obvious
you'd have to be a noodle-heimer not to see it
freestanding
complete without dependence on external
authorities
you might have induced
yeah, natural, and I think that's the last one
devoid of altered states of consciousness
now
my understanding and my experience
not to try to force the kundalini
energy up
why? because the kundalini energy will rise
through the chakra system as a consequence
of that which you have become
when you become forgiving towards others
when you see the sacredness
and beauty of all of life
the kundalini energy
flows in accordance with it
so artificial means
of trying to raise the energy
through various systems
I think is unwise
it's premature
if you could handle the energy at that level
it would be at that level
so people get into weird and strange
spiritual crises
from trying to force
the energy systems
with breathing systems
and various yoga systems
all of which have their place
if they're in accord
with that which you have
really become
so
the best known example of
misplaced
practices such as that
such as that
it was Gopi Krishna
Gopi Krishna wrote a book about it
one of Gopi Krishna's
friends has been in many of our lectures
and
Gopi Krishna's kundalini energy
went up one side of the brain
and he was lopsided and had a terrible time
for some years
as the kundalini energy
begins to rise
you feel it
it's like an exquisite pleasure
flowing up your back
and then you feel it flowing into your brain
if you close your eyes
you go into a bliss state all the time
everybody complains
why you've always got your eyes closed
because that bliss state is there
the energy comes up
and with it it occasions
all kinds of the so called
SIDDHIS
which again should not be
pursued for their own sake
so the last spiritual trap
we'll mention
is the pursuit of the so called
cities for their own sake
taking classes on
things that are
occurring natural phenomena
once that kundalini
rises all those so called
super normal phenomena
arise and happen of their own
and to try to acquire
them
if you're going to take a class on levitation
good luck
yeah
you can see that the attraction
to take a course in one of these cities
is already an ego vanity
otherwise you wouldn't be wanting to take it
you understand
unless it's something you've already experienced
and you just want to
learn and discipline it
alright so what happens now
is we're going to have Niko chat
so this morning
we shared the
heart of man
and now Niko is going to
do the
chant
Lotus Sutra in Sanskrit
which again is experiential
after the chant then
we'll reassemble for questions and answers
yes
I'll take this out
do the chairs support you
any issues
no