A non-integrist person wouldn't be worried about it.
It's because of integrity that you worry about it.
Because of spiritual responsibility, you worry about it.
A person of low integrity wouldn't even be concerned
about the question.
But, like yourself, I tended to be scrupulous.
I tended to scrupulosity and perfectionism, you know?
Agonized everything, whether it was, you know,
in today's language, you're above or below 200, you know?
Yeah?
My question is also about karma.
My understanding is that you have said that
animals and people calibrating below 200
do not have individual karma.
No, I didn't say individual karma.
They don't have an awareness of existence.
They experience.
But they don't realize that that experience
is coming out of existence.
So they cannot extrapolate that to other human beings.
See, over 500, I mean, you know, over 200,
you say, yeah, but how is that gonna affect others
if I do that?
Below 200, you don't care how that affects others.
That's their problem.
But over 200, no, you take on spiritual responsibility.
Oh, I know what you got that from,
when I said that you don't develop an etheric body,
etheric brain, until over 200.
Yeah, it's true, you don't have an etheric.
Okay, the karma of people below 200 is group karma.
It's group karma.
Now, from 200 up, you got individual responsibility.
Up to that time,
you're like one of the mob.
So by agreement, let's say a mob in front of the guillotine,
they're all getting there with their netting,
get there early.
They love to watch the heads get chopped off, see?
They have formed a group karmic energy field, see?
So they're subject to the karma of that animal level.
The cat is subject to the consequence
of the karmic energy field of cat-ness, see?
With the exception of the cat's purr
and the dog's wagging tail.
And you know when we've asked about that,
we said we weren't allowed to ask about it.
Something unique about it.
But so, up to 200, you inherit the group karma,
the karma of that group, yeah.
And then from 200 on, it gets individual,
let's ask that again.
This is a fact, the Lord resist.
It was surprising when we came across it to tell you the truth.
I'll pick it up faster.
Thank you.
You see the consequences.
consequences of group karma in massive planetary things. How come just they
were underneath the volcano as it erupted? Everybody knows this thing
erupts periodically, and yet they're living there. Why is that? Then they all
get killed by the volcano. I mean, so obviously a group karmic participation,
is it not? Yeah. See, there's also the upside to the group karma, see? Not just
the downside, but because they experience love of each other in that
village and attachment to home and the valuation of love and it's various
expressions. So, there's not just downside, you know, but also upside. Must be something to
love your village so much that you just hang out there even though it's going to
get buried under a volcano, you know? Just can't leave home, I don't know. I understand them.
I've got a question about choice, and I'm
very curious about the relationship between the two. You know, it's a lot of
About choice, I'm not really sure.
After listening to some of the things you said,
you said that lots of times you'll have thoughts will come up
and your ego will take credit for them.
So how do I know when I'm choosing and when my egos,
you said that lots of times thoughts come out of nothingness as well,
but we have free will and choice.
So how do I tell the difference between the two?
Well, what's coming up are options.
They're coming out of a nothingness into a manifestation as thinking this.
And they tend to create options continuously.
I mean, should I have a sip of coffee now or not?
Or should I stop and do this?
Should I let the coffee wait to that?
Will he feel offended if I stop and have coffee?
You know what I'm saying?
So like multiple options are existing simultaneously.
The propensity is going to depend on your level of consciousness.
Which of the choices are going to seem to be the most attractive, you know?
And certain options are going to be zeroed out,
not even an option because of who you've become, you know?
But there's a variety of options and I can choose a multiple number of those options at any time?
Or does the field determine what I'm going to choose?
The field is where it's presented, you might say.
And then you perceive within that field what looked to you to be the,
you know, the various options.
Now you don't have a choice about whether you're going to make a choice.
You don't have a choice about making a choice.
You've got to make a choice.
You know what I'm saying?
When your foot's in the air, you've got to put it down somewhere.
You can't stand for 20 years with this foot trying to decide.
So, the mind works so quickly, see?
So the propensity, so what you're seeing is the consciousness level
brings up propensities and options that would not come at a different level.
Okay, so then I would be, then I do influence things.
So, it's not the same as cause, but it's influenced because it's a part of the...
Yeah, who you are is the field now.
It's influencing the options that have seemed to you, see?
Because you could say, I could let him die or not let him die.
Now, at a certain level, you can't let him die.
At another level, you've got to let him die.
So, what's correct depends on the contextualization of that level.
Consciousness, right?
At a certain level, it's wrong to let him die.
Another level, it's wrong to let him live.
See what I'm saying?
It all depends on context.
I understand that.
I've quoted to this group the guilt I had for a great deal of time
that after goring a guy right in the groin with a spear,
I did not administer the coup de grace.
That was a mistake to let him live.
There, I should have.
One warrior's obligation to the other brought his suffering to an end,
like you leave one bullet in a revolver, see?
So, then it would depend on context.
So, I had to go through it in this lifetime,
and I recall the exact failure.
It was a moral failure.
My obligation is one warrior to another.
You give him an easy way out of this pain and suffering.
Yeah.
So, it depends on where you're at at the time.
That's what I was learning then, see?
So, is that the influence of that situation,
that's not the same as causing it then?
It's not causal, no.
But what's unresolved gets brought back to choose again.
A Course in Miracles presents that nicely.
I think it's even called choose again.
You're represented, now choose again, see?
If that happened with that warrior again,
I would, of course, administer the coup de grace.
I'd say to him, okay, and he'd say okay.
So, see how it differs then depending on the context.
Thank you for asking me.
It's ten to four.
All right.
I'll make the answer shorter.
I thought we started earlier so I could go on and on.
Oh, I can't go on and on.
I have to be brief and short to the point.
I've been bad again.
Okay.
Yes.
First, thank you.
I flew here with my friend from London yesterday
to come and be here.
And 20 years ago when I started on my kind of conscious path
of development through being sentenced through the course
to Alcoholics Anonymous and then that kind of started
this whole thing.
And about every five years in my personal obsession
with my enlightenment, my whole life seems to fall apart
and then I'm not who I think I am.
And about a year and a half ago I started reading your material
and listening to your tapes and then it really fell apart.
And, you know, my business went, my wife went,
the house went, the car went, the children's private schools went,
you know, everything went.
And now I'm living in a tiny little rented flat in London.
Cool.
Just outside of London.
And I've never had less in terms of, you know, having a lot of things.
Yeah.
My question is when I force myself to make my career work,
I can make it work.
When I surrender myself more and more, I usually end up with less and less.
And, you know, like I want to provide for my children
and my business is gone.
I want to be able to provide for my ex-wife and I've got no work.
But I know if I go out there and just, you know, give it some stick
and forget about surrendering everything, I can make things happen.
But I don't want to work like that.
I do want to be able to continue to surrender myself to God,
to the God of my understanding and be able to provide for my children.
So I'm...
What you're saying is that they're alternate whereas actually they do work together.
You can continuously be a provider and also constantly surrender.
It's just that you're going to be presented with different things to surrender
than you would have been if you had not participated back in the workaday world.
Hmm.
You see, if you live your life in a contemplative style,
you don't have to leave the world.
You can still participate in the world, at least up to a certain level.
So I would try that.
Try participating in the world to fulfill that other obligation
and continue the spiritual work as a continuous contemplation.
Yes.
Can I ask you one more thing?
I mean, I can drive a cab and also be contemplative.
I've done it.
Yes.
Can I ask you one more thing?
Yeah.
The more I try and solve my money problems,
the worse it tends to get.
And...
Do you know what I mean?
Everything I do is to be able to make more money.
I surrender to make more money.
I go out and knock on doors to get business to make more money.
And I'm in this kind of paradox of wanting to give all that up,
but I want to give it all up so I'll have more of it.
So I can provide.
And I just don't know if I'm missing the point.
Yeah, you must be.
Get a job, eh?
I don't mind working.
Yeah.
I would just get a job.
Forget the business.
Sorry?
Just get a job.
Forget the business, business.
Forget the what?
Business.
Oh, I see.
Just get a job.
Deal with it.
Okay.
Thank you.
Good.
Simple.
That's what the Buddha said in my ear, you know.
Yeah.
Oh.
Hi, Dr. David.
My question has to do, I know you came in this incarnation with a very honed intellect.
And my question is, you seem to be sharing with us some divine wisdom and knowledge.
And I'm just curious how that comes to you.
That's my question.
It doesn't come.
Okay.
It is.
Let me explain.
What was becomes replaced by a different state.
This state is complete and total within itself.
This state is unmoving, non-responsive, has no volition, couldn't care less whether you
learn anything, whether I'm a teacher or not, you know?
Okay.
All right.
Then, that presence within responds.
It uses the intellect as a tool, you know?
But actually, there's nobody there.
The energy activates.
It activates the apparatus appropriately, depending on who's approaching about what,
see?
And that precipitates back an answer.
There's no knowingness what's going to be said until I've just heard it.
There's no, like, think of an answer and then say the answer.
See, that's coming from causality.
It just is of its own.
Well, it's hard to explain.
Because the mind thinks in cause and effect.
Thinks there must be a causal agent, see?
That does this.
There isn't a this that does that.
It is, it radiates out of that which it is, spontaneously.
So, basically...
It's called the Purusha in Sanskrit.
I know you're dying to know the term, you know?
So, your job was to...
To...
Okay.
Cute.
You came in as a teacher and then you reached that level where you...
You're open to the teachings being channeled through you?
I don't get any channeling.
Okay, okay.
Channeling is dualistic.
There's a that channeling a this to a this, you know?
It's a consequence of that which you are.
You see the radiance of beauty?
The flower is not doing that.
The flower is that.
Got it?
Yes.
Didn't come into this world to be beautiful.
Right.
You're projecting an intentuality which is a dualistic conceptualization.
Okay.
It radiates what it smells like because of that which it is.
That's easy, eh?
And so, you are expressing your teacher-ness.
That's what the world would call it, yes.
Okay.
And so, each of us has something we came to express.
Everyone is also a teacher to those who are behind you because we're all on an evolutionary
scale of consciousness.
Okay.
So, compared to this one, you're a student, but compared to this one, you're a teacher.
Right.
You know, probably the preponderance of humankind calibrates lower than you do, see?
So, to them, you radiated an energy which uplifts and sustains them.
So, each one is a student of that which is ahead and a teacher to that which is behind.
So, we are all either a teacher or a student depending on the relationship.
If I'm with somebody and he's a better carpenter than I am, then I'm the student and he's the
teacher, see?
So, yeah?
Thank you.
Yes.
Okay.
Go ahead.
I got you.
I would like to know if it's in my highest good to leave my marriage.
I don't know.
That's a complicated one.
And you'd have to pray for guidance and handle it the best you can.
I can't do that for you because I'd be robbing you of the karmic consequence.
Well, that's a decision.
What I get is that it's a decision.
And it's an important decision because what you're going to do is going to depend on your
values and how you prioritize those values, you know?
You see what I'm saying?
I'd be robbing you of the karmic benefit.
I'd be making a judgment call.
Yes?
That's a tough one for everybody.
Okay.
Thank you for being you.
My desire is to surrender to God everything but peace and love, which I've learned from
you.
And I would like to know how best I am to do that.
It's by your overall alignment and commitment.
Also, you do it by prayer and by service and asking God's will in all things.
Every day in the 12-step groups, you take a moral inventory.
And you ask for God's guidance and his will for you.
How can I best be of service to thee, O Lord?
And then that invocation, you put out with great devotional intensity.
And then your life becomes somewhat...
What you've just done by virtue of the Heisenberg principle is you've just changed the options
that are going to be coming up for you.
See, this was going to be coming up for you.
With that invocation, this comes up for you.
See?
Because you've just changed the field.
See, the spiritual intention is already working in people's lives, and they don't recognize
it, so they think that they're failing.
They're not failing.
What's in front of you right now is the consequence of what you've been asking.
Not being able to see, not having any money, all those things are the consequence.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Yes, ma'am.
You're right.
Thank you.
That's right.
So, for years I led a prayer group, and then I hit a point where I was not sure if I should
for some reason.
Should pray?
Not...
Well, as a group.
To lead a group.
To lead a group in a healing ministry kind of thing.
Oh, oh.
Lead a prayer group.
Oh, yeah.
Mm-hmm.
So I guess that sort of is my question.
Is there a value in praying together as a group for people that request it?
I think so.
Because, as I said here, the intention of the student, the intention of the teacher,
and the intention of the group, the three together form a very powerful field.
So when people group together in prayer, a prayer group is a very positive.
You know, silent unity, for instance.
Mm-hmm.
Miracles happen all the time out of silent unity.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Yes.
Good idea.
Dr. Hawkins, could you talk about some of the differences between a student and a prayer
group?
Yeah.
A state that might be psychologically destabilizing and one that might be spiritually
growthful?
You may not be able to tell the difference, because sometimes spiritual growth seems to
manifest as a psychological disorder temporarily, see?
Because all your values and your paradigm of reality may shift, see?
So there's...
In fact, I just wrote about it in one chapter, that there's periods in the spiritual evolution,
of confusion and disorientation, and am I doing the right thing, and should I be living
this way?
There's periods of doubt and uncertainty, periods of upset.
Because evolution, as we said today, is in a way revolution.
Evolution upsets the routine order of things.
If you're staying still and not moving spiritually, you won't have any disruption, see?
Yeah.
And then you begin to shift values.
Let's say when a person first takes their moral inventory, their view of themself may
change quite a bit, just as a consequence of that, and may have some psychological disruption
period, temporarily at least.
Yeah.
Is there any place where we should show caution?
That's too general in a way to ask, yes.
There are boundaries.
In fact, in the books I'm finishing, I'm making clear the boundaries.
There's certain places I advise people not to go.
The supernormal, investigating the paranormal, the supernormal, the lower astral realms,
invisible entities.
You don't know how to play in there.
You don't know how to play there.
I wouldn't play there.
You're not equipped.
You can't handle this world.
What the hell?
You're looking at another dimension, and you have the slightest understanding of what's
going on there, you know?
So you're a bee, you're a witless babe to these entities.
They've been at it for eons.
Yeah.
Maybe the channels that exist today were exactly the same in Mesopotamia.
All right.
So if they were that spiritually evolved, they would have moved up to celestial realms
quite a few centuries ago.
So therefore, I don't approve of seeking anything outside of what you can see, you know?
Anyway, momentary transitional periods of confusion and upset are pretty normal.
You know, when you confront yourself about something.
You know, something will come up, and you're disturbed for a couple of days about this.
Why?
Because you're looking at what it means and all the stuff it brings up, you know?
Right.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
It's pretty normal for a cavern.
If you don't figure out how to get upset, you're probably not working on yourself too
much, you know?
You don't think about suicide at least once a week.
You ain't moving on from it.
I'm excited.
Yeah.
I've traveled here from Estonia to see you.
You're from where?
Estonia.
Where is that?
South of Cincinnati?
It's one of the Baltics.
Correct.
That's correct.
That was correct.
Do I win a prize?
Well, there is an Estonia, Illinois, I think.
You know, I just wanted to make sure.
What I'm seeking is clarity on an issue.
I hope you can help me ask the question as well, even, because I'm quite confused about
it.
Okay.
Thank you.
I'm really, really, really, really confused.
The topic is on the will of God.
You mention very often surrendering to the will of God.
I guess it's a very general question, it is what is the will of God?
I ask that because in several deep spiritual experiences, it's almost like playing a tennis
game when I ask that question because it gets batted back to me as, what is your choice?
What…
It almost seems like.
. . .
has been presented to me that the will of god is this this life with infinite choice
and then i'm choosing well what is your will and it's just back back to me again okay so don't
turn it into a dualistic me asking a you god a question say what you do by invocation is you
create a field of powerful truthful integrity and within that field your options are going to be
modified by the power of the field which you did not ask god's help those options would not appear
to you nor would you be conceptualizing them the same way so you're probably getting answers to
your prayers but you're not recognizing it as such i think it's because you've contextualized
it as a dualistic you asking a that god you see what i'm saying when you're saying you bounce it
about an answer so you got a dualistic conceptualization of this there's a you
bouncing against the will of god
see how you're holding it i do and at the height of the asking of the question was in the first
place yes a consequence of your asking for god's help otherwise you wouldn't have thought of the
question so how does one believe that they are in fact the divinity they are god that's a belief
system i don't believe in okay believing it is a belief system right how does one realize that
by spiritual evolution takes quite a long time
the realization that the source of your own existence awareness consciousness is the self within capital s
divinity imminent comes about as a it's not a question answer not conceptualized as non-verbal
it's a knowingness that is so profound there's no question about whether you've been answered see
otherwise you're talking about bouncing a concept against the concept you got sort of a this me and
you god kind of way of thinking about it and you're not conceptualizing it as a non-verbal
contextualizing your thing okay i would wait more for intuition to sort of bring forth
the knowingness to you that which it becomes obvious the fuel reveals to you
not by conversation but by revelation the unfolding of the understanding you're lying
in bed you just wake up and you just sort of get that this is the way you know the answer comes of
its own those moments have come and then and then they go
yeah because you're doing conversational play play games with it and then the desire is for that
longing is for god only god to see everywhere to know how does one avoid the inherent suffering of
that desire when one has to wait as you've said a long time evolutionary time scale how does one
why suffering because you're desiring desiring something you're projecting a time on it you're
seeing yourself as a person you're seeing yourself as a person you're seeing yourself as a person
is incomplete. You see, you don't go from incomplete to complete, or imperfect to perfect.
You go from perfect to perfect to perfect. You go from complete to complete to complete.
Right now you're completely this, then you move to completely that, then you move to perfectly
completely this. You see how you're projecting a dualistic conceptualization on it. The way you
are right now is absolutely perfect. The next move will take you to the next moment of perfection.
You understand? You're projecting a concept of imperfect, and perfection is in the future,
and now you feel, yeah, yeah. Don't project imperfect, and then...
What is driving that, then? Huh?
What is driving that to want to go to...
Your spiritual...
Yeah, it's where you will, see? Your spiritual intention. But don't forget, people think in
terms of causality. You think there's a person on you that's driving the...
spiritual volition. What you don't see is that you're being drawn by the future. The future is
already set up by your own decision. You're being attracted by the future, and not driven by the
past. So it's not possible to be a failure anywhere along the line. You haven't failed
enlightenment, you see? Otherwise you're going to feel constantly guilty that you failed
enlightenment, you see? You haven't failed enlightenment.
Yes, that arises.
Well, the requirement of enlightenment is to go through what you're going through. What do you
think it's easy to get there but it'd be enlightening I know what you mean it's
it's the presumption of imperfection in not being into that projected future but
I want you to just see through the illusory nature of it and not answer you
on a yes or no understand you know meditate on what I say kind of like that
okay mm-hmm the question is on self healing the
body's had tremors very as far as back far back as I can remember any tremors
pardon me what'd you say tremors yeah Oh tremors oh yeah okay it's had them
ever since I can remember yeah what would be the best approach for self
healing or is this something that I just handle or is it something periodic or
permanent or permanent constant pretty much yeah well everything's physical
mental and spiritual
so what is it medically they say it's a familiar tremor oh he's got oh I know
what you got yeah yes well it's benign so it's called benign familiar you know
it's benign so just deal with it huh so just deal with it I I would give up the
self-consciousness and I'm just tell people I have benign what the hell's the
name of it I forget Kalmbach you know benign something
rather tumor yeah it's a kitchen it's got a form
benign or familiar tremor
there at lesson but I'm familiar chairman yeah if you have a knife
familiarity also what beta blockers tend to help it someone data blockers other
than beta blockers I would just live with it you know okay
I wasn't sure if it was something that maybe I was supposed to heal or I don't
know I could see your question I would pray about it saying Lord God is there
anything I can do and then with that intent and then you live with it the
best you can or does some karmic
you can I could have some karmic tien master evil sleep lots I might just come out
component. Is there a way you could test for that?
I don't know. Huh? Is there a way you could test for that?
A karmic component?
Yeah.
You know how to do kinesiology?
Is there any way you could test for that?
We have permission to do this
for this gentleman here and now.
No. Okay.
I would presume there's a karmic propensity
if you've got a chronic condition.
I don't know what it is.
There's probably some inherent lesson.
Maybe about pride or God knows what.
Okay.
Can I get a picture with you guys?
You can have a picture.
Yeah.
Other than beta blockers,
I don't know.
Some physical conditions you've got to
just live with.
I was born myopic and nearsighted
and couldn't see well besides.
You know what I mean?
Okay. Pretend like you like me.
What else can you do about it?
Yeah.
Pretend like you like me.
Yeah. Yeah.
Thanks, guys.
Thank you.
Dr. Hawkins?
Yeah.
I hope this question is appropriate
because I know you've been talking a lot
about the illusory nature of the ego.
It's not illusory, but it leads to illusion, yeah.
The ego is very much there, yeah.
As a former mental health practitioner,
could you say something about the,
the limits or potential of hypnosis
and self-hypnosis about changing
a person's subconscious negative beliefs
about himself?
Oh, if used within the correct context,
I think it's a useful tool, yes.
Depends on what your intention is.
If you're looking for a magical cure
or something, I don't think that's
the proper use, but you could use
hypnosis to get to the roots of it
so that you see what the roots
of the problem are.
Maybe go on a path, you could do a past lifetime, too,
to see maybe its historical origin.
I would use it for clarification rather than
trying to sort of magically cure something
and accomplish something.
I would use it for deeper inner insight.
And I think it's a useful tool.
Well, with that, then what would you say would be
the best tool for someone to fix self-esteem?
To fix self-esteem?
Well, self-esteem isn't just a thing, you know,
it's a component.
You can't just pause it.
It's like the overall level of the ocean, you know.
You can't just change the level of the ocean, you know.
Self-esteem, first of all, is a judgment, you see.
But no, in every case, it's rather complex.
I think it's valuable to you because it drives you
within to understand yourself.
And you'll arrive at the answer yourself.
You'll arrive at the answer yourself.
It could be some self-condemnation
you have.
You've forgotten.
It could be somebody programmed you.
You've got to cancel that program.
See, one's esteem should not be a matter of
come see, come saw.
It's a gone conclusion.
It's a done.
It's not a matter to be questioned.
Your value or your worth is not a matter of question.
Your existence already answers whether you're worth anything.
God created you.
Well, what more do you want?
You came from Wal-Mart, so I mean, you know.
Very good.
Thank you.
Life via God, body by Wal-Mart, yeah?
General Motors.
Body by General Motors.
What did you say?
Life by God, body by Wal-Mart?
Yeah.
Well, self-worth, you're denying the divinity of your own essence,
your creation, you know, which is created of God.
You can hardly ask, what is this worth, you know?
Hi.
My question to you is, what is this worth?
To you is surrendering everything to God.
And when I say, and this too, Lord, I often go, well, maybe I'll do it.
You winced, you winced, huh?
And all my money too, God.
Well, I surrendered my youth and good luck, and you see what happens.
And with children as well.
Yeah.
You know that they're, like, I know that they're in the hands of the Lord,
but then just to let them go, you know, as they get older.
Yeah.
Yes, I understand that, but just to do it without guilt of being, you know,
I don't know, just...
All right, so it brings up stuff a lot with a kid, you know.
There's attachment, there's control.
Not only to relinquish them to live their own life,
but to fulfill their own karma, see, you know?
Correct.
So that's being a good parent, of course, is sooner or later you've got to let them go.
As far as a linear control...
Relationship.
But not as far as the contextualization of love,
which is beyond distance and presence and physicality.
So the love you have for them, they've already incorporated.
They better...
You see, the love that you give to the child in and of itself is worthless
unless the child incorporates it in their own self-concept.
The child who's been deprived of love in early childhood
hasn't incorporated it.
The good, loving parent can't really experience themself
as loving or lovable or worthwhile.
It could be they've already picked up that energy from you
and they don't need it anymore in a direct fashion, one-to-one fashion,
because they've already adopted that principle, you know?
But for me to let that go, like, I know my children know how to love
and that I have been a loving parent,
but then as they go...
through their life, and not to worry...
What do you mean, not to worry?
Well, you know, something might happen.
The only way you can not worry is to be dead, you know?
The infant's worried the minute it's born.
It begins crying and bawling and mewling.
The mother's worried the minute it's born.
The nurses are worried. The doctor's worried.
The neighbors are worried.
You want to not worry? Yeah, God bless you.
You don't worry hard enough. That's your problem.
God bless you, Dr. Hawkins.
And I bring all the love and blessings of every member
of the Dr. Hawkins Study Group in Albuquerque
and in Santa Fe.
We love you.
Okay.
I'm a religious science practitioner,
and since studying with you,
I've come into a great deal of conflict
about the method of prayer that is used in religious science.
I have a lot of people come to me
and ask me to pray for them, you know, for specific things.
And the whole idea behind a prayer in religious science is
that you have what's called the realization stage,
where you affirm or claim that this good
is coming to this person's life.
That good is coming to this person's life?
Yeah, the particular good that they mention.
Oh, their particular good, yeah.
Yeah, and it brings me into a lot of conflict
because I've heard you say, and, you know,
it's the absolute truth, you know,
you don't want to interfere in someone's karma.
Well, you can't anyway.
Yeah, and so, right, and, you know,
you don't want to try because then, you know,
I remember you answered a question
about a lady whose sister was alcoholic,
and you said, you know, you're just,
every time you rescue her, you're pushing her further away.
And so all of this has come to play
in my attempts to pray for people
who come and ask me to pray for some particular good,
and I'm thinking...
Yeah, but you're seeing yourself as a doer.
Yeah.
You're not a doer, my dear.
You're only a presence.
So the presence plus your intention
is all that you can do as a prayer,
as the prayer person.
And the acceptance of that, the fulfillment of that,
depends on their personal karma.
You're not going to override it.
So it's not like you're overriding a person's personal karma.
Okay.
So you pray, dear Lord, for a healing
to the degree that it can be done
by that divine grace and mercy, you see,
and now it's up to divinity.
Okay, that's a little bit different from
what we are told, from how we're told to pray.
Well, say it again, how you do it.
We just affirm that this particular good
is coming to this person's life,
like if they want a really good job or something like that.
Oh yeah, it's okay, it's optimism.
Okay.
So we affirm that this person here present,
about whom we are praying,
will be coming into the needed job
to support his family.
Huh? Right? Is that it?
Something, yeah, something like that, yeah.
Oh.
You're not going to violate their karma,
because if...
it's not going to happen.
The very fact that they've asked you to pray for them
has already changed their karma, hasn't it?
Yeah.
Yes.
All right.
The very fact that they've asked God's help,
and you're just an avenue with that.
I'm a vehicle, yeah.
Yeah, okay.
So you're just an avenue.
It's still up to divinity
and propensity of proclivity
of manifesting an actuality out of a potentiality,
which you're just one of the agents in the field.
Yeah.
And we do think of ourselves as vehicles,
and yet I want to pray accordingly,
you know, according to God's grace and so forth.
But it's just,
it's not something that you say in a religious science prayer,
you know.
Or is it verboten?
I mean, do they excommunicate you or something?
Is it in accordance with God's will?
I mean, I never got that out of religious science,
that it's that restrictive.
No, I don't think it would be verboten.
No.
I think I'm having trouble finding the correct wording.
Yeah, I think that's all it is.
Yeah.
You're uncertain how to contextualize it.
Yes.
You can just add,
in accordance with thy will, O Lord.
And in accordance with the highest good, perhaps.
Yeah, I see.
I see a Mercury coming into your future,
a Ford,
all in accordance with God's will.
A new SUV.
Yeah.
Okay, sweetheart.
Thank you so much.
Yeah, it is just the way you were contextualizing it
you were worried about.
Thank you so much.
Yeah, we did a sermon at a workshop at religious science
about a month ago.
Brother, we've always asked for a Mercedes Benz.
Huh?
We've always asked for a Mercedes Benz.
Oh, yeah.
And a Mercedes Benz, huh?
Yeah, Mercedes Benz.
Doctor, it's my understanding that it's more spiritually advantageous
to see the ego as a friend rather than an adversary.
So I've become quite concerned lately
about the behavior of my friend, the ego.
The friend who?
His friend, ego.
He's become concerned about the behavior of his friend, ego.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So when you were in the depths of the pits of hell with the ego
and finally he let go,
was the ego capable of learning anything from that experience?
It disappeared.
Disappeared.
Got frightened.
Okay.
Frightened.
No, flames are the upper part of hell, that's just the frosting on the cake.
Hi, Dr. Hawking?
Yes.
Okay, you got to get it over here and into the mic.
Sure.
How does one cultivate love so it's not objectified?
Oh, it's a capacity, a way of being, in the appreciation
that all of creation is the unfolding of divinity.
Evolution is the unfolding of divinity, of the unmanifest becoming manifest and discernible via linearity.
So your consciousness is like a probe from the non-linear into the linear.
Thank you.
The incredible beauty of the flowers, you see, is God.
He's saying you're done.
I'm done.
Is this microphone correct?
Yeah.
Okay.
See, as you evolve, the incredible beauty of everything begins to shine forth.
In the beginning, you only see it in that which is blatantly aesthetically pleasing.
As it goes on, you begin to see it in everything.
You see that everything is perfect and everything is incredibly beautiful.
If we had enough time, I'd tell you about it, but anyway.
I just wanted to ask you if you would ohm.
She wants you to do an ohm.
Nico did an ohm.
She wants you to do it.
Why do you want me to do an ohm?
Because you do a good ohm.
You ohmed in my son's face, and he said his knees buckled, and so I thought, well, I want that too.
I did an ohm.
Yeah, it was another time.
Yeah, when he met you previously.
Oh.
Thank you.
You better get crazy soon.
You keep telling me that.
You're going to just.
No, you're going to flip out.
I didn't expect to get ohm today, by golly.
That was a different lifetime where I did ohm.
Man, we all did ohm together.
Caught amongst through eternity.
Wow.
Yeah.
My question is about karma.
Can you give us some more understanding?
Of how to release accumulated negative karma?
How do you want it?
How to release an accumulated negative karma?
Oh, the undoing of it?
The undoing of it.
Well, that's the purpose of this lifetime, undo it.
So you're presented with the same thing you didn't forgive before, and now this time you've got the option to forgive it.
So it's like a representation of opportunity.
So by striving, you gain good karma, you might say.
And you are presented with limitation.
So the constant letting go of the limitation, negative feelings and perceptions.
It's a continuous process.
I can describe it as a contemplative way of being in the world.
Your life becomes the prayer.
You are the supplication to divinity by the quality of your presentation to God.
You are the mood.
All you have to do is you be this.
Now you don't have to do anything, verbalize anything.
You are the prayer by virtue of the alignment and contextualization of your existence.
Thank you.
Your life becomes a supplication and an invocation.
Your life becomes the prayer of invocation by which your existence is constantly reflecting.
The divinity and will of God as it's comprehensible to this level of consciousness now.
You don't have to worry about it because you are it already.
Can you describe the relationship between mind and consciousness?
Well, mind generally means mentation, mentalization, intellectualization, visualization, ideas, memories, you know, consciousness.
Did you ask me about that?
Yes.
Consciousness is the underlying field which itself is non-linear.
It's the light by which you see the linearity of the thinkingness, right?
How do you know that you're thinking?
How do you know you're thinking?
By being aware.
Huh?
By becoming aware.
How come you're aware?
Where does awareness come from?
Is that consciousness?
You woke up with it.
You came into this life with consciousness.
Right.
The consciousness is not you.
It's a quality you have.
Right.
It's protoplasmic.
You didn't create protoplasm.
You are, you know, you came into this life with protoplasm.
The capacity to be aware.
So I say, you know, as a contemplative lifestyle or a meditative style, you would draw from
identification with the movie and the linearity.
You move into the awareness of self as the witness observer.
The witness observer witnesses all the time, watches.
But it doesn't get involved or participate.
It doesn't judge.
It doesn't think about that.
It witnesses it.
See?
It's like a spectator.
So as you move out of participating in the movie to the witness of the movie, then you're
the watcher of the witness.
Then you say, the watcher of the witness, where do they come from?
They come from awareness.
Awareness comes from consciousness.
Consciousness comes from divinity.
It's nonlinear.
Yeah?
Yeah.
As you move your identification out of the out there.
Out there-ness, you'll see that what is innate is an impersonal quality that's independent
of you.
And that's getting closer and closer to the self as consciousness.
So how could consciousness by error choose oneness or singleness?
I mean, how can consciousness error?
Because you said it in chapter 18 of this book.
How can consciousness error?
Yeah.
You said.
Consciousness can.
By error, no.
You said by error can.
Have I got the word right?
Yeah.
Well, maybe I'm saying it wrong.
The error occurs within consciousness itself before there is even any person involved.
Consciousness can experience itself either as singularity or as oneness.
How?
That is mine to me.
I mean, I'm confused.
I don't quite understand your question.
It's the chapter 18.
Yeah.
How?
How do spiritual errors come about?
That's a pretty general question.
It would have taken an hour to answer that.
How do spiritual errors come about?
You're really asking the nature of consciousness itself.
Is the a priori quality out of which awareness arises?
Yeah.
It's the background feeling.
It's the background field out of which awareness then becomes progressive.
It expresses to the witness, the observer, and then the witnesser, the observer of the linear what, you know?
But independent of what, what, is the innate nonlinear quality of consciousness itself, which prevails all the time, you know?
You all see?
And I say, look past the content.
Underneath the mind is an infinite field of stillness.
You can focus on that any time.
You don't have to go into a meditative state.
Be aware that it's like the ocean, and the thoughts are like the fish flying out.
Yeah.
Focus on that which, what is the condition just before the thinkingness arises?
Not linear sequentially, but the substrate of all thinkingness, out of which all thinkingness arises, is an infinite field always available.
That's what you are, the infinite field of consciousness, which is, which is vacant of content.
It's like space.
Space exists independent of whether there's anything.
Anything in it or not is going to drive me crazy.
He's 22.
Thank you.
Okay.
We'll move along faster.
We got a good one coming up.
I know.
Yeah.
Hello, all.
I'd like to thank you all for being supportive, and in this group, I have gained a lot of strength and courage facing my situation right now.
And my question is, I'd like to seek advice on how to deal with my heart.
My heart hurts.
My heart has been beating very nervously, very fast, in the past year and a half.
And it gets intensified when I'm exposed to spiritual teachings, spiritual teachers, and spiritual groups like this.
Like when I read the book, I, in the evening.
Is it better or worse?
It gets worse.
Worse?
Very exciting.
Oh, oh, oh.
It's almost like overwhelming.
Oh, yeah.
So, yeah, I like to, like, I try different things.
Like I try to argue.
Like, puncture.
Didn't work.
Oh.
I went to a doctor.
He said, my heart is no problem.
Paroxysmal tachycardia?
What did he call it?
Did he suggest a beta blocker?
A beta blocker.
Something that cuts down overreaction to adrenaline?
I never know.
He didn't suggest a beta blocker.
Ordinarily, a beta blocker would be.
So, everything that's physical, mental, and spiritual.
So, you want to block off the symptom itself, but at the same time, you also want to see the origin of it, huh?
Mm-hmm.
It's just emotional excitement as you get closer and closer to spiritual truth, yeah.
So, what would.
Tachycardia.
He needs a beta blocker, yeah?
Yeah.
I would try a simple beta blocker.
They're very cheap.
Generic.
Beta blocker.
They call.
Can you write it down here?
What's in there?
Midoprolol.
I don't want to prescribe as a physician now, but you should ask your doctor.
Yeah.
Did you.
But when I go to him, then he listen to my heart, and then he beats normal.
Huh?
Yeah.
When I visit the doctor.
When he sees the doctor, it's beating normally.
Oh, yeah.
Well, yeah.
See, he doesn't have to see the tachycardia.
You just tell him, you know, I have periodic periods of tachycardia, you know?
You don't need a tranquilizer for that.
You don't need the tranquilizer.
A beta blocker decreases sensitivity to adrenaline.
You may react to excitement over adrenaline.
That's all.
Uh-huh.
So, is it going to be a transition thing?
I can just take it for a while, and then I.
Yes.
Oh, yes.
No.
It's just symptomatic.
You know.
Yeah.
I think I'm going to take it for a while.
You can take it very low dose.
Uh-huh.
It sounds good.
Anyway, that's.
See, everything's physical, mental, and spiritual.
Uh-huh.
So, that's the physical, see?
And then the mental, I don't know, the excitement.
And the emotional, I'm not sure about that.
You know, that would take some period of investigation.
We couldn't have probably reached it just in a question and answer period.
Uh-huh.
A related question is, when I go to, like, crowded places, like to subway in big cities.
Yes.
Then I feel I share the emotions of the people.
Yeah.
And they kind of worsen my organs.
Uh-huh.
Like, my heart sometimes feel beating very fast, my stomach tight, or I feel agony, loneliness,
emptiness.
Yeah.
No, that.
Now, you need to just continue working on a spiritual level, and you'll transcend all
that.
In the meantime, beta blockers are very cheap.
You know, I shouldn't ask you that.
There's the temporary.
The physical, the mental, and the spiritual.
See?
Uh-huh.
Even the Course in Miracles says the physical, the mental, and the spiritual.
Because the physical is only the expression of the intention of the spiritual.
Uh-huh.
People think, you know, if I pray for a job, it's going to come out of the sky.
I remember a guy said, I prayed and prayed for a job, and nothing happened.
And if it hadn't been for my brother-in-law calling me up, I'd still be unemployed.
That's a fact.
God didn't answer his prayer for a job, and his brother-in-law saved him.
He didn't see the consequences.
Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
Beta blockers are cheap.
They're pretty safe.
You know, I'm talking about temporary relief, you know.
Long-term, you'll transcend this whole level of anxiety.
Well, this is a medical question.
If the calibration level of a physician can influence the outcome of a treatment, does
the calibration level of the patient also influence?
Yeah.
Sure.
You've got an interaction of two energy fields.
But that's a problem.
I mean, being a physician, a lot of times I can't control the calibration level of
the patient.
That's correct.
But the calibration level is reflecting their karma.
So they may be karmically entitled to a recovery, or they may not.
And your field may or not, you know, you can't impose your will on it.
So you do your intention, you do your physical.
I suggest you're on the physical, mental, and spiritual.
So I tell them, physically this is what I do, mentally this is what I do, and spiritually
this is what I advise.
Then it's up to them, see?
I think all things are physical, mental, and spiritual.
Thank you.
Take a beta blocker and also go to the Course of Miracles.
Also go to the Course of Miracles and see a good psychotherapist.
Now you're doing it at an all-terrain level.
Is this authentic here?
Isn't that funny?
Do you know anything else?
Oh, God.
Do you want me to sign this?
Yeah, sure.
Is that authentic, that dedication?
Isn't that cute?
I mean, that's really adorable.
Oh, it probably is.
It's the longest part.
Yeah, that's the reason.
Thank you very much, Dr. Hawkins.
Thank you.
Thank you, Susan.
As you probably remember, I'm a medical doctor.
And, I've surrendered to God and try to make my life an instrument of divine will.
And within this year, I've left two positions.
You know, one I kind of used the fact that it was interrupting my coming here as an excuse,
and the other one, more recently, seemed to be a test.
Yeah.
and I was wondering if you could affirm this or not I went to this position that
there was such a macabre bunch of people of the lower realms it seemed like they
were they were symbolic of vampires and it became so so obvious to me that I was
and that I was going to be you know tarnished by by fraud or bad stuff you know I mean I even
described it from my mother and she said what are you still doing there you know there's nothing I
can actually prove but it would you know but I left that and I was wondering you know because
I've read and you probably said too that the as you advance along the path these things come at
you more and more you know as tests there you just decline the opportunity
yeah yeah could you do you see if that was a test yeah it's just you decline the option
yeah doesn't mean you can't briefly you know participate well I did before I found out
because I didn't want to yeah but then as the as the essence begins to reveal itself you withdraw
yeah yeah you were true that was good that's good I get the sense that's great do you know
dr. Miriam Yost is this because I mean I just got this from
I don't know from Amazon and it's hard it's hard to remember so many years over the years thank you
very much I once had a member of the Mafia when I was in trouble treating back I remember the
Mafia and his mother had a severe depression severe bad no response to antidepressants and
I said well probably a color shock she should come out of it and so we laid the money says
I'll put you in events that's rolling out the bills
she better do alright you know what I mean
she better do it right you know what I mean
well thankfully thankfully after about three treatments she snapped right out of it
um having heard the uh Lotus Sutra recited before we
left or you gotta talk closer to the microphone what was the question
um
Having heard the Lotus Sutra recited today before we left for lunch, I just wanted to
ask what the connection between Nam-myoho-renge-kyo and your teachings is.
I don't understand what she said.
She wants to know what Nikko's chant has to do with your teachings.
Nikko's chant is just a way of doing the Aum because the Kabir is over 700.
The music we play is also over 700.
So it's to create a context in which the busyness of the world tends to recede and you tend
to go in a higher field, you more quickly get spiritual information.
Thank you.
It's hard to get spiritual information in a casino, you're just in the wrong context.
Although one time we did one, you had to walk through the casino to give the lecture, didn't
we?
Sure.
Dr. Hawkins, when you look at the scale of consciousness, you immediately see how
mathematically perfect it is that all the significant points occur in very round numbers.
That's because I rounded them off.
Okay.
Is that true?
It's not really 200 or 400 or 500?
No, no, it isn't literal.
Also, the calibrations are usually round out to the nearest five.
Okay.
If you're going to do meticulous research on some very specific subject, then it would
make a difference if you move one or two points.
Right.
But generally, you get a letter from somebody and somebody will ship me something and I'll,
without opening it, say, you know, what this calibrates are.
If it's under 200, then I put it over in that pile.
You open it.
But, for example, 600 is not the exact number.
It's not the exact number.
600 is not exactly that.
It's a rounded number.
500 is a rounded number.
Yeah.
I mean, whether you're at 598, 602, you know, I mean, you're in a field.
And the field of bliss begins to manifest.
So the field that you could say, if you could meticulously calibrate every incident, it's
at 595, 599, 600, 601, 602.
Okay.
So you could do micro-research.
Very seldom do we need micro-research, you know, because you're just trying to, you know,
what general energy field is this representing, you know what I'm saying?
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Yes.
It's an honor to be here next to you, Dr. Hawkins.
My name is Doris Ann, and I am a practicing, new practice, holistic...
Practicing what?
What's your name?
Practice?
New.
A new practice, practitioner of holistic kinesiology in Sedona.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
And my question to you is that I have found that sometimes, whenever I'm working
with somebody, that they could benefit by me clearing out what is in their DNA blueprint.
You're going to clear in them?
I use...
What are you going to ask me now?
I use certain extracts, herbs, and various other things that are for emotional or spiritual
clearing.
And this is...
Is there a homeopathic, you mean?
Can be, sometimes.
Yeah.
Yes.
Okay.
All right.
And I find that sometimes they could benefit from some clearing...
Yeah.
...with what's in their DNA blueprint that's come down from their parents.
But sometimes, it can be from a past life.
Yes.
And I would like your advice and recommendations if I should go there.
Go where?
In their past life?
Yes.
And...
You'd have to be a trained hypnotherapist to begin with.
Uh-huh.
You'd have to be pretty advanced spiritually.
I don't...
If you...
My only intuition is I wouldn't get involved in it.
Okay.
Do you have any recommendations of where I should go?
Yeah.
Do you have any recommendations of where I should go with my practice?
What would you...
No, because that would take really a consultation where you go into your motivations, your background,
your qualities.
So, what you do is you bring products into the person's life that will have a therapeutic
benefit.
Is that what you're saying?
What I do is I have...
I don't like the word clearing.
Okay.
No, I don't like it at all.
I have some testers that...
Huh?
I have a whole series of testers.
And a muscle test.
Yes.
With what is a health remedy using the emotional points which are on the hand.
Oh, I see what you're doing.
Yeah.
Right.
And then what tests strong is what the body is saying that it could benefit from.
Yeah.
Okay.
I see what you're doing.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm .
So, I really don't even have to know what the product is.
The body knows.
Mm-hmm .
And so, you know, a lot of people will choose to get on the remedy and they do get better.
Of course, sometimes, you know, I need to refer them.
I need to refer them out to somebody like you or to a hypnotherapist or to da-da-da-da,
you know.
So, anyway, that's why I wanted to...
Mm-hmm .
Do you still do consultations?
Mm-mm .
You don't?
Okay.
No.
Remember the Bach flower remedies?
Do you use them?
Yes.
I do.
Yeah.
Okay.
They're expensive.
Mm-hmm .
They work.
I don't use them anymore, but they're too expensive to throw away, aren't they?
Okay.
So, that's using nature's vibrations and...
Yes.
...healing power of nature, you see.
I use a lot of the flower essences.
Yeah.
I also use a lot of the essential oils.
Okay.
So, you use the Bach flower remedies.
Mm-hmm .
Okay.
I think you're doing what you can do, you see.
Mm-hmm .
Yeah.
Okay.
Cool.
Is my book set?
Yay.
Hi.
I've been placed in an unlikely position to be a teacher for some people, and I would
like to get your opinion on the...
The calibration of the TM movement, Maharishi Mahesh Yogi, and also the Maharishi effect.
So, what is it you're asking now?
You're asking multiple questions here.
You want to become a teacher of TM?
No.
No?
I was saying I've been placed in an unlikely position to hold some folks accountable within
that movement, and I was curious to know your opinion about the TM movement.
Maharishi Mahesh Yogi, and the Maharishi effect.
Well, you want to withdraw from this?
My son was murdered last year at the Maharishi University of Management.
Uh-huh .
And I'm involved in some moral decisions and some issues, and legal issues.
And I'm curious to know your opinion of the TM movement, as well as Maharishi Mahesh Yogi,
and the Maharishi effect.
TM calibrates, I think, about...
Yeah.
I got Mêmeh, though, at a wrong time, right here in Atlanta.
There's only about 290, I think.
I personally felt that it was commercialized.
I felt it got commercialized.
I'll tell you why.
Because spiritual truth stands on its own, right?
And you can't really peddle it and bring in proselytite followers and use it to manipulate
things.
So I felt that, although it had promise, it wasn't comprehended in an overall, pristine
way you know how it played into the consequences in your life I really can't
say you know so you believe it was essentially commercialized and perhaps
well my my feeling is there a number of very helpful techniques out there but
then what happens is they get peddled see and then you and this followers you
get sort of multi-level marketing and the whole thing the intention now
becomes gain so you're not coming from the heart you come from the solar plexus
to gain money to gain followers you know to gain dominance or seeking rank you
know the head leader and I think it becomes contaminated by worldliness up
to a certain level even if it's contaminated by worldliness you know it
probably serves a certain certain function it's like selling training and
how to do the cities you know I'm saying
it's five thousand dollars uh-huh I understand your agony and indecision you
know just by prayer you try to do what you think is the best thing you can do
you know thanks it's a difficult place you're in well ethically spiritually
morally he's got he's got a pickle yes I'm watching it you know okay we're
gonna zip through the end my question is about the void is it a necessary part of
one's spiritual life or is it a necessary part of one's spiritual life
experience or can you meditate on the illness and love of God and avoid the
void it's not necessary I'm just warning people if you follow the pathway and
negate negation it's gonna take you there and then you won't know what to do
about it and so I'm explained to them in case it should happen it came about
because you negated the reality of love thinking that it's an attachment once
you realize that mistake you've been back out of the void thank you that's
good news the ultimate state is character
sunrise by a radiance of love of unspeakable quality it's unmistakable
and if whatever level you're at that's not there that ain't it thank you yeah
okay well my question is about remembering I guess so my first time
here I think I understand that we're supposed to try and grow along the
spiritual path and I think it takes effort to do that and I'll put forward
the effort and then I'll look back and three days
have gone by and I've been a weenie for three days.
So I need to
I need some practical advice about
how to recover.
Well, the constancy.
The Course in Miracles calls it faithfulness.
Constancy. The 12-step groups
say you live it one day at a time.
Don't worry about whether you didn't do it for three days.
You're only supposed to be worrying about today.
So your intention
to follow that
practice or spiritual practice, whatever
you're doing today, is
all you don't have to worry about yesterday or the day
before. That's not a reality.
The only reality is your decision in the now.
Yeah. Faithfulness,
intuitiveness, persistence.
Yeah.
It corrects itself.
Hi.
My question has to do with, I understand that the ego
is like our animal nature.
And my question is
if the ego is like the animal,
did God create the ego?
You can't really ask the question.
Okay.
Because of the way you're
defining the ego and God in your head.
Life evolves
spontaneously.
And then it continues
to evolve because consciousness
tends to return to its source.
One of its potentialities,
because its potentialities
are unlimited,
is to evolve as the animal
kingdom. Then from the animal kingdom
it would obviously begin to evolve
beyond the animal kingdom because it's seeking to
return to its source.
Yeah.
So what you want to do is avoid any
judgmentalism about
how creation
appears to you.
Because let's say
by calibrating, there's an inference
that one thing is better than another.
It's not really better.
Each thing can become the perfection
of its own level.
The perfect amoeba is the perfect amoeba
that's already fulfilled
perfection within its own domain.
Okay. Yeah. Thank you.
My name is
Boone Gordon from Silverthorne, Colorado
and a World War II fighter pilot.
I came back from the war
and I noticed
that there was a sense of community
that we had in our fighter squadron.
And I also noticed there wasn't
this purpose we had in the war.
And I also noticed that
there wasn't much spirituality.
When we were fighter pilots, we seemed to
tap into the source.
Anyway, so about 1950
I started meditating
with Raja Yoga.
And I started getting these messages
on how to design a town of the future.
And so
now these ideas are mine.
So they're on this book here for you.
Oh, isn't that nice?
And the question is
I think that most of the
ideas are above 500 consciousness.
I call it LQ.
In other words, light quotient.
And now my question is,
how can I get this word out?
And how can I find the people
for this town of the future?
Any suggestions?
Oh, God, I don't know.
You're going to put out a call.
I mean, this is putting out a call right here
for people to join you in this quest.
And the quest is what?
To establish sort of a heavenly state
here on Earth or in other dimensions?
Well, we want to build an actual city
because then people will look and see
that this higher consciousness
Oh, a city of light.
A city of light.
On the physical realm?
It's a physical realm.
I think you're too old for that.
I understand that 1,200 of us
are dying each day in World War II.
But I think I have a couple years left.
I think a city of light
would take, you know,
something more than a few years.
All right.
I think if you hold it in mind,
then that tends to manifest.
And you can certainly join with artists
to hold it in mind.
But the practicality of how to manifest it
in the linear domain,
I don't know.
Thank you.
You got a lot of money?
Don't have any money.
I don't need money.
You can have it all figured out.
Okay.
Okay, the vision would...
Oh, yes, I think I know what you're saying.
Yes, I already got what you said.
I just got the whole design
that you have in your mind.
Yeah.
I'm not saying it's not doable.
But what you're questioning
is really how to present it
and create an attraction to the idea.
Yes, correct.
See?
How to promulgate it.
Right.
Because...
Other than writing a book,
about it,
or talking on the radio,
or I don't know how else.
Thank you.
Yeah, that's adorable.
Yes?
Yes, my name is Vishali Shaheen.
I'm from Oakland, California.
Yeah.
And my question is,
about two years ago,
I liquidated all my assets
in order to pay off my debt
and save some money
and moved in with friends
and living very quietly.
And after a few years of that,
and of course,
I'm on a spiritual path,
I just kind of went,
wow, it would be nice
to have more in my life.
A relationship, a home,
things like that.
As I'm getting older.
And the question is,
you know,
in wanting a better life,
I don't want to create more karma.
And...
Well, you're always going to create karma.
Well, maybe good karma.
What's wrong with just living a normal life?
Well, that would be.
Right now, we don't see
how I'm living a normal life.
Right now, I'm living with friends.
Yeah, yeah.
But a normal life to me
would be a home,
a relationship.
Okay, so how do you bring that
into manifestation?
Is that what you're asking?
No, I'm going to,
I would like to bring that
into manifestation.
I guess my intention
is to make sure that I
do that in a way
that doesn't create more karma
because I would like
to continue evolving
on this path
without being distracted
by worldly stuff.
But having it,
opening up to God's abundance
and allowing that to be
and not creating more karma.
Well, can you accomplish
some worldly goal
without creating more karma?
You can't.
Okay.
And it's,
okay,
it's good enough.
You see,
you hold in mind
that which you value.
And then what you hold in mind
automatically manifests,
not as a doingness,
not as a this and a that
which creates karma.
You hold in mind
a vision for yourself
because that which you hold in mind
tends to manifest.
Now it's up to divinity
to fulfill it.
The divinity of the karma.
Thanks.
Mayor?
Yeah.
Thank you.
What you hold in mind
tends to manifest.
We calibrated that
and that's true.
Just hold it in mind
without volition,
without trying to make it happen
or force it
or cause it or something.
Hello.
Yes.
My question is about yoga
and qigong.
And I was seeing
in your new book,
which of course
I haven't read,
but I was looking
at somebody else's book.
And hatha yoga
and qigong,
I forget exactly,
but,
they both calibrate
240, 260.
Yeah, positive.
Yeah.
Well, but I wanted to know
what's wrong with them.
I didn't say
there's nothing wrong with them.
I see you're over 200.
So what do you mean
what's wrong with them?
Well.
The Buddha didn't say
to do that to get enlightened.
So I mean,
do you expect it to be 800 or what?
No, no.
Okay.
Well, the reason I asked
is that I love,
I teach those things.
Yes.
And I love teaching them.
And I wanted to make sure
that I wasn't teaching
something false.
Oh, no.
They're very integrous.
Okay.
Well, but I mean,
if you compare that
to like modern medical science,
which is at 400,
I thought,
well, why shouldn't I just tell
all my yoga students
just go to the doctor?
That doesn't make sense to me.
You don't go to a doctor
for spiritual advancement,
do you?
No, it didn't make sense.
So you're trying to apply
apples and peaches.
They're two different realms,
you know.
No, what she's doing
is she's saying that
240 is lower than 400.
Oh, yeah.
But you're comparing
of apples and pears
and they're two different things.
Yeah, so.
Yeah, well, going to the Louvre,
you know, there's pictures
in the Louvre that are 700.
So you shouldn't be doing
what you're doing.
You should be sending
all these people to the Louvre.
Send everybody to the Louvre
and give up whatever you're doing.
Yeah.
So, so, but.
The only thing that's important
is what you're doing
is over 200.
That's all.
That's it?
Does it matter
that I love what I'm doing?
Of course not.
It doesn't matter?
No.
Besides, you're only asking
about a mechanical technique.
You're not asking about
the intention of the practitioner,
which is probably
far more powerful
than the technique.
Okay.
Because of your intention
and your love for your patients,
you know, they're going to do fine.
Okay.
You know, somebody who calibrates
to 180 and is doing these things
just for the money,
you know, maybe their people
don't get better, you see.
Okay.
So.
So the most important thing
is my intention as a practitioner.
There you go.
And then the technique.
Yeah, the technique
is just the mechanism,
the means, you know.
Right.
Okay.
So.
So it's,
is there anything wrong
with yoga or qigong?
I just want to make sure.
It's okay.
Let's see.
They're okay.
They're integrous.
They're above 200.
They're in line with truth.
Okay, good.
And so, all right.
Thank you.
They're healing techniques.
Okay.
Yeah, look at it.
She's integrous.
That's why she asked.
She wants to just verify
the integrity.
She did it because
there's so many bogus things
out there, you know.
And she just wants to make sure.
Yeah.
I've seen many times
you perform kinesiological testing
with Susan.
And I know in power versus force,
you describe a technique
that you can perform
on your own.
Could you go to that again?
Yeah.
I can't find it.
I've looked at the book all over.
She should demonstrate.
Could you demonstrate
the self?
She wants to know
kinesiology testing
like the self.
Oh, the ring finger.
Yeah.
Some people can do it themselves.
I say kinesiology
is like riding a bicycle.
Some people are gifted
to get it right away.
Other people struggle
and keep falling off the bicycle.
You hold Abraham Lincoln.
You hold these two fingers
like this.
Now, use this like a hook.
Okay.
I'm holding Abraham Lincoln
in mind.
And I,
well, that's saying it.
I'm not saying anything
about Abraham Lincoln.
I'm just holding Abraham Lincoln
in my mind, you see?
You see what I'm doing?
Thumb and third finger.
Okay.
Now, I use this.
I make a hook out of this.
Okay.
All right.
Now, I hold these together
strongly.
Okay.
I'm holding Abraham Lincoln
in mind
and I try to break the ring.
Okay.
Do that.
No way.
What?
Okay.
No way.
All right.
Stop that.
Okay.
Now, hold.
Hold.
Stop laughing.
Hold Ben Loudman in mind.
Picture Ben Loudman.
His staff and all that.
Okay.
Now, pull your fingers apart again.
You see any difference in the strength?
Actually, not the tip of your finger,
but actually higher up, I noticed.
What you're saying?
I don't know.
What are you saying?
You're trying to make something
very simple and complicated.
You just go like this
and you go like this.
Okay.
You got it.
You don't have to go to college for that.
You don't have to do that.
It doesn't have to be right.
The best thing to do
is it isn't a test of strength.
Right.
Yeah.
It's a test of relative strength.
What it is is you see,
when you feel,
you get the feel of it.
So,
you put it in
and you say,
okay, Ben Loudman.
Okay.
There's another way of doing it.
You take something
that weighs a couple pounds
like a brick.
Okay?
Okay.
Hold this up in front of you
about the chest height.
This is a new way
I'm showing everybody.
Okay.
Now, hold Abraham Lincoln in mind
and now lift this.
Okay.
Now,
hold Ben Loudman in mind
and try and lift it.
It weighs a great deal more
when I hold Ben Loudman
and I have much more difficulty
lifting it.
That's something
I just came across recently.
I haven't really tested it out
so I'm not recommending it.
You know,
you heard it here.
But I was trying to do it.
How can I do it all by myself?
See,
other than this technique
and I think somebody said it there
or something.
But you know,
you lift a certain weight
holding one thing in mind
and then lift the same weight
holding something else in mind.
And just compare the amount
of strength it takes.
And I found I could do kinesiology
on my own
even when she's doing something else
out in the garden.
Practice makes perfect.
It's just a comparison
of the relative ease.
You can tell.
It takes a lot of effort
to lift these bricks
when I hold him in mind
and when I hold him in line
it seems to go easier.
See?
Okay, that's it.
What do you think
about pendulum work?
Oh,
it's useful.
I would not use it
in the negatives.
I wouldn't check out
the universe
of the lower astral
with a pendulum.
You're inviting like lightning
to hit your rod.
What?
We were going to do
a healing prayer.
There's a lot of people here
for healings
and could we do
a healing prayer?
I don't know what that is.
All right.
No.
Okay.
Out of body again.
What was the healing prayer?
What are you talking about?
Anyway,
it's my joy
to be with you
as usual
and we look forward
to the next time.
As I say,
we're evolving
into a very,
very powerful group.
Very powerful group.
Group intention
of a people this advanced
impacts the universe.
It lifts the overall field
of consciousness
of all of mankind.
It benefits everyone
not on a causal,
of this causing of that.
As a consequence
of that which we have become
to align yourself,
surrender yourself
to divinity,
fulfill your karmic
potentiality to the fullest,
what more can you do?
You know?
I want you to live
in such a way
that your life is a prayer.
I want you to live
your life in such a way
that you have no
anxiety at all
about meeting God.
Are you willing
to be answerable
for who you are
and what you've done
with what you are?
What more can you ask?
That I live in such a way
that frankly,
I'm not scared
of talking to God.
I've done the damnedest I can
in every direction here.
I've pushed myself
to the limit
to be the fulfillment
of my potential.
That relieves me
of all guilt
because now I can make
a mistake.
Yes, I make a mistake.
But in the overall context,
you see,
I've sanctified
that mistake.
By your overall intention.
So, by intention,
then,
our life becomes
the devotion.
We become the prayer.
By virtue of that,
we invoke divinity.
And then through the heart,
through the heart,
through the devotion,
through the alignment
with divinity,
we empower all of mankind.
Yeah?
So,
we say,
Gloria in excelsis,
Deo.
Glory
to God
in the highest.
And what more
could be said?
So,
how far in the room?
Oh, I don't know.
Now, if you like it,
we'll spend more and more time
with individual questions
and answers
and I'll leave it up
to the group.
You know,
I'll leave it up to the group.
Let's do it now.
Would people favor
more time
with personal questions
and answers
and spontaneous interviews?
Okay.
Vis-a-vis didactic teaching.
Let's see the answer for that.
So, we've got a lot of scholars here, too.
All right.
So, well, you know,
we make it half and half
because we're always discovering new things
and therefore,
we want to present it on every level
from the heart
and from the intellect,
from the mind, you know.
And we,
the reason doesn't,
isn't just stuck in 400
because you see reason
in and of itself
calibrates in the 400s.
But when you use reason
as a means
of
pursuing,
pursuing God,
pursuing spiritual intention,
then you've sanctified the intellect.
Okay?
You're not just using it
for its own egoistic.
Therefore,
you can sanctify
your intellect
and you say,
for the old Lord,
Lord,
do I try to understand
and incorporate these teachings
that they may bring me closer
to the old Lord.
So, you can sanctify
the mind
essentially.
See?
Which is different than a secular mind
which is only looking for
to squeeze
the gain out of information.
Yeah?
So,
let's,
how's that?
We'll sanctify the mind collectively.
Oh Lord,
we do surrender our collective minds
to thy service
that we may
be
the fulfillment
of thy potential
in this demand,
in this dimension.
Amen.
It's okay to be an intellectual.
It's okay.
Oh, golly.