We are scheduled for today.
It's happening.
First, the first break will be at 2 to 11.30.
Now, in the universal room, which is the last room to the left over here,
there is refreshments for you on both breaks.
Then the lunch hour will be from 12 to 2 o'clock
so that you can leave if you want to have lunch.
We'll resume.
And then after the second break is at 3.15,
and that's when we have our question and answer.
So if you have any questions that you would like to ask Dr. at that time,
we'll form two lines and we'll sign books at that time also
and you can come up and ask any questions.
And the good news is that we have a new website that's ready to be up.
We've been working on it.
Robert's been working on it diligently for us.
And if you'd like to take a peek at it, it's Dr. Paul Kempf.
Dr. Hawkins.info.
If you'd like to take a quick peek at it.
We're going to have little clips of some of the seminars in it.
Dr. Hawkins.info.
If you'd like to take a peek, we're going to have some little cuts out of seminars.
Does that mean I'm, does that qualify me as a blogger?
I hope not.
Does that make me a blogger?
You are. You are one.
Get ready to be blogged, baby.
You ain't seen no blogging until you see my blogging.
That's humility for you.
What a divine blessing to be here.
I don't know what we're talking about today.
So I made a diagram.
Oh yes, I remember.
Well, we all start off.
The same way that we start off in the end of the lecture.
And to save all that time of having to listen through all that.
You live your life in a contemplative style.
In a contemplative style, you're not commenting on everything all the time.
You're not taking a positionality about it all the time.
You're just witnessing it.
The witness is already detached from the participant.
You know, the leading edge of the ego.
The exception.
The experiencer.
He's not content with just witnessing it.
He wants to get involved.
And give you its opinion, etc.
What's the world going to do without?
Anyway.
A contemplative lifestyle, if you do it habitually,
it will come out of nowhere.
The witnessing that all phenomena are occurring spontaneously.
As a consequence of that which they are.
And for no other reason.
You see that things are emerging, evolving, and appearing as they appear spontaneously.
By contemplation and witnessing then, you've shut off the mind.
And without the mind, you don't see any cause and effect.
That's a mentalization you project.
So, if through humility, you say,
Dear God, I don't know what anything means anyway.
I would like to be the witness of creation.
Then, you witness creation.
And you witness creation, doing whatever creation is, how it's evolving at this unfoldingness over what the world calls time.
Sequentially.
You realize that all phenomena are being what they are.
Expressing their essence by which what the world calls evolution occurs.
And therefore, it throws it on you.
It comes out of nowhere, not out of thinkingness.
That creation and evolution are the one and the same thing.
That what you're seeing is evolution, which is creation in 3D.
The linear expression of evolution then.
The linear which you can witness in the physical domain.
This is very simple.
Is that correct?
Anybody have a problem with evolution and creation are one and the same thing?
Therefore, there's no conflict.
No conflict.
So, non-duality means you withdraw from the participant experience.
Experience or edge of the ego.
And instead, you withdraw to the witness.
You withdraw from thinkingness.
Thinkingness comes to your aid when you want it to.
You're not supposed to be at the effect of thinkingness.
That it allows you peace when it wants to.
It's supposed to be the other way.
You think when you decide to think.
When there's some purpose or benefit.
Something that you have to go into the world.
And left brain it.
Sequentially.
Which is wearisome, frankly.
Why anybody prizes the body and the mind is beyond me.
But they do so.
Both are wearisome.
Okay.
However, without a body you can't walk around here.
So, you can see it does serve a useful purpose.
We're talking about overcoming obstacles.
Today.
That's the name of the.
I seldom pay attention to the title of the lecture.
But I did notice it was overcoming obstacles.
Overcoming obstacles.
And the human condition is certainly full of them.
And the Buddha said transcend the identification of the linear.
Because this is a world of considerable discomfort.
Yes.
Which we witness in today's news.
The tragic events which sweep across the earth.
In one place or another almost continuously throughout all of history.
Earthquake.
Flood.
Lightning.
Tsunamis.
Hurricanes.
And they're frightening.
Same time they're exciting.
And at the same time they allow us the full expression of our own karmic potential.
We always watch the weather news at night.
The storm stories.
Storm stories.
And we notice that the survivors of catastrophes in relating it subsequently almost all.
Almost every single one of them remarked about how they prayed.
So, one of the quickest ways to God is to face sudden death.
.
Atheism goes just like that.
And it's possible through surrender to face anything with great equanimity.
Walk right into the hail of bullets and either you die or you don't die.
Which is surrender to the will of God.
Which is different than nihilism.
It's different than denial.
It's different than skepticism let's say.
Okay.
So, I thought today also the obstacles are the limitations of the mind.
And skepticism has sort of showed up on the radar.
So, I thought we have a similar goal in mind with skepticism.
Skepticism arose in ancient Greece.
The philosophy of ancient Greece.
The followers of Pyro.
P-R-R-Y-H-O I think is the spelling.
Skeptikos.
The Greek word is skeptikos.
And the philosophy of the skeptic was that truth is not knowable.
Truth is not knowable.
Which is exactly what we say.
The mind in and of itself is unable to discern truth from falsehood.
Therefore, you would think skepticism would be a great fan of ours.
However, it seems to be antagonized by us.
Mainly because, you know, consciousness research verifies the validity of divinity.
You know, which is antagonistic to the skeptic.
So, of course, the problem with the skeptic is if truth is unknowable,
it means that there is no value to their speech.
Because their speech is also there expressing ignorance, is it not?
So, the skeptic is hung in his own petard.
.
If knowledge is not knowable, then what are they blabbering about?
Anyway, we did write a little essay on skepticism.
Because that sort of has come up in the world of bloggers.
I am now a fellow blogger.
Now they better watch out.
Suffer from bloggerism.
Yeah.
Much of bloggerism, you know, is services.
It's a great purpose.
It provides information, you know.
And then there's what I call the vanity sites, you know.
My turn.
Bill's corn.
Bill tells you what he thinks about everything.
Anyway, skepticism calibrates about 160.
Now, why is that?
It's a low.
In as much as ostensibly, it supposedly is seeking the truth.
It's because it is very close to nihilism.
Nihilism calibrates at 120.
It is also very close to anarchy because it denies the authenticity of all authority.
And therefore skepticism is by its nature atheistic.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
So it doesn't carry it too far.
The good side of skepticism is that it has revealed outrageous frauds.
Outrageous frauds.
And therefore I'm an enthusiast to skepticism.
.
Uh, with a sharp eye on its downside.
However, when you study skepticism, you end up skeptical of scepticism.
I do not think that skepticism is going to lead us to God or to truth or the salvation of mankind, you know.
And of course, every new development in mankind's history brings the skeptics out of the woodwork.
I was a little worried that they weren't coming around after I published truth versus nihilism.
I thought, good God.
Not even worth the skeptics attack.
But now my ego is reinflated.
I am happy to be under attack by the skeptics.
So now I'm somebody.
.
I'm somebody.
So I have my sympathy is with what I think is their ostensible purpose.
However, it is not.
It is not.
I'm an somebody, I'm not somebody, I have a purpose.
However, the methodology, etc., it doesn't work.
If you don't like the message, you attack the messengers.
So also in blogger land we've had ad hominem attacks on yours truly.
And I thank thee, Lord, that I do not have an unpaid parking ticket.
Clean as the whistle.
No parking tickets.
Oh.
All right.
confrontational. There's a caveat in the front of the book, Truth vs. Fault. The caveat tells you that it's confrontational.
If you're not prepared for it, don't read any further.
Some people ignored the caveat, obviously. I thought we would do some, a couple of things, you know,
the other thing they question, of course, is kinesiology. So I said before I wrote this,
you'll get politically motivated attacks, which they all are.
You know, you'll get people that are very anti-God, they all are, and then you get the critics of kinesiology, because
not a single
critic has addressed the main premises or the main conclusions or anything important in the book, so they didn't comprehend that at all.
So nobody has addressed that at all. They only go for the peripheral issues.
So the skeptic,
you know, questions kinesiology.
Well, I taught kinesiology,
you know, kinesiology was new on the radar 30 years ago. It's old hat now. Everybody's
done all the tricks to try and prove it and disprove it, and
there's many very excellent
DVDs out there by professionals in kinesiology
who know a great deal about it. I know practically nothing about it. I just know yes or no, that's all I know.
But there's many tricks you can do. You can go like this, and they go weak, and then you go like this, and they go hot,
and then you go like this, and they go strong, and you go this, and they go weak, so
it makes me dizzy, and
Pat Flanagan used to be an expert showing on that, and so if you're really interested in it.
Yeah, I'm only interested in it that it serves a
pedagogical function
because it allows us how to
move from the Newtonian paradigm of science
into the nonlinear domain. It gives us the only trail I know of from the linear to the nonlinear.
Therefore, I thought it served a pedagogical technique, you see.
But if your findings come up to support what people don't want to hear about, then they suddenly hate kinesiology,
which is the only other possible attack they can have on it, you see.
So I used to give lectures all over the country, all the world in fact, and
you know, the results were consistent in every single country.
The mistake I made in meoculpa
the error, the omission, was in power versus force. You know, I'll tell you how it developed.
I saw kinesiology with John Diamond and did a workshop with him, and then I
started giving lectures on it because I had a huge clinic, you see, and we used holistic
practices. We thought kinesiology would lead us maybe to
unsuspected causes of mental disorders.
So I added that to, you know, we did all kinds of things.
They were non-traditional and had tremendous recoveries in hopeless cases. The clinic specialized in hopeless cases.
We had the largest practice in the country.
People came from all over the world because we've got recoveries where nobody else could, and it's because we weren't just limited to the Newtonian
traditional science.
So
medicine has always been town versus gown. The town
are the doctors that are out there, and the gown
is the academics, who live in a much more restrained
world of provability.
The experienced clinician can get recoveries where the academics can't, so our usual patient
had been to all the universities, seen all the specialists, and were given up as hopeless,
and so we specialized in the hopeless.
So we looked for everything that could be helpful on kinesiology was one of the things we researched.
So I began teaching it. So
when we started teaching it,
I was going to give a class.
So in the clinic back there,
we had A Course in Miracles students
and all kinds of things.
And so I grabbed a couple of people
and I said,
there's one traditional test.
If you take an ordinary person
and they look at fluorescent lights,
they go weak.
If you hold sweet and low
where there's solar plexus,
they go weak.
So I grabbed a couple of people
and I said, okay,
well, let's try this out.
So we did the fluorescent thing
and they didn't go weak.
Well, we tried the sweet and low,
they didn't go weak.
I thought, God,
they're going to make
lousy test subjects, I tell you.
But the curiosity was,
how come they didn't?
Then we discovered
it had something to do
with A Course in Miracles.
So we got some new students
who were just starting
A Course in Miracles
and I tested them.
They went weak
with fluorescent lights
and sweet and low.
And we tested them serially.
And about the time
they got to less than 75,
80 around in there,
suddenly fluorescent lights
did not make them go weak,
nor did sweet and low
nor any other local stimulus
make them go weak.
Aha.
So, anyway,
when I wrote Power Versus Force
and we did a video on it,
I think the video is still,
isn't there one,
a demonstration of Power Versus Force
on kinesiology?
Okay.
Well, all the people I knew
and hung out with
all calibrated over,
200, you know what I'm saying?
So we thought that kinesiology
would be useful for everyone.
Then we later discovered
that you can't use it
below 200
and that the integrity
of the question
also has to be 200.
So I didn't put that
in Power Versus Force
and I must have created
the illusion that anybody,
anywhere can do it
under any circumstance,
which is not so.
That's later corrected
in subsequent books.
But so I take responsibility
that we did not know it
at the time.
And when we did the video
on Power Versus Force
demonstrating the kinesiologic test,
we grabbed everybody
that came along
and they were all
integrous people.
So of course it worked
for 100% of those people.
It's like it probably worked
for 100% of the people
in this crowd, you know,
because you wouldn't be here
if you were under 200,
I don't suppose.
So the error was
I thought everybody could do it
and I misled the public
by, you know,
omission.
I just didn't know it.
So therefore,
kinesiology,
consciousness research,
et cetera,
are evolving,
you see,
and they're evolving.
They're evolving.
So I thought we'd do
a brief demonstration
this morning
for those of you
who never heard
one of my wonderful lectures
on kinesiology.
I can do the whole thing
in about two minutes.
And we'll take two minutes.
You want to participate?
Yeah?
Under threat, yes.
Come over here.
You're a calcitrant lady.
All right.
Stand here.
Now,
all right,
I don't know if the crowd
can see this or not,
but I,
you know,
all you have to do
is read the book
Behavioral Kinesiology
by John Diamond
and it tells you
all you need to know,
you see?
Okay.
All right,
I just want you to do this.
I want you to look
at the top diagram.
Resist.
Okay.
I want you to look.
Just at the lower diagram.
Resist.
So you can see
there's no psychological suggestion.
I'm not selling her any program.
We're not to prove anything.
You understand that?
It's just a physiologic response
to a stimulus.
All right.
Okay,
I'm going to hold something in mind.
Okay.
Now resist.
Okay,
I'm going to hold something else in mind.
Resist.
Lincoln at first
and Bin Laden second.
Okay.
I mean,
it's,
kinesiology is so simple.
I don't see anything to argue about,
you know what I mean?
It's all like,
a retard can do it,
you know?
Let's see.
I don't know what's in here,
but it says do not swallow.
So anyway.
Okay.
Just look at this.
Just please,
just look at the bottle.
Focus and concentrate on the bottle.
Now resist.
Thank you.
Okay.
Now just,
just focus on the bottle.
Just look at the bottle.
Now resist.
Focus on this bottle.
No, no, no, no,
the bottle.
Not on the bottle.
I'm sorry.
Not the bottle.
Focus on the content of the bottle.
Resist.
All right.
Let's do it again.
Focus on this bottle.
The bottles are okay.
All right.
So the bottles are okay.
What's in them?
One is Miracle Girl,
which miracles strong and the other is a poison that kills bugs and ants and stuff.
So she doesn't know what it's in it because I was sprung this as a surprise there this morning.
So if you all want to do it at once,
we can do it.
You want to take out five minutes?
I'll show you how we used to do it in the big city.
The person next to you,
you decide who's going to be a one and who's going to be a two.
That's what I got to do.
One, two, one, two.
Just choose who's one, who's two.
Okay.
Well, all right.
Stand up, stand up.
Ones and twos face each other.
I don't, I don't want to mix them up.
Okay.
Ones and twos.
Now we have to have silence.
We have to silence.
Uh, okay.
The, the, the, what we're trying to do.
Is, uh, um, for the sake of the highest good, discover truth.
So that has to be the intention.
Okay.
Number one is the doctor.
Number two is the test subject who puts their arm out.
Who put out numbers two, put out your test subject.
Everybody.
Number two is put out your arm.
Number one's, uh, okay.
Number twos.
I also, I want you to all look at what's in this bottle,
which is in my hand.
This green powder.
Okay.
Number twos, look at the powder.
Doctors number one, press down on their arm and say, resist.
Do they resist?
Everybody goes strong.
All right.
Now, occasionally a person will give you a paradoxical answer.
No, they'll give you a paradoxical answer.
Now, did anybody go weak on that?
Because we can fix that right away.
Okay.
If you went weak, I want you to do the following thing.
Uh, I got a microphone on.
I don't know how I can do this.
You pound down the upper breastbone.
You go, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
All right.
Now you do, you think of somebody you love when you do that.
Okay.
And any time you say, I surrender my life to God.
You don't have to do that.
All right.
Okay.
Now, those that went weak before, let's retest them.
Teams, retest.
Um, okay.
Those that went weak before, test subjects, focus on the content of this bottle.
Just look at the bottle.
Don't think anything.
Just look at it.
Okay.
Doctors say resist and press down on their arm with two fingers.
How do we do this thing?
All right.
Anybody that didn't get fixed by the thymus thump, uh, has to stay after class and we'll work with you.
We'll work with you.
No, it's because, um, anybody who's done acupuncture and all knows.
Anybody who's been listening to certain kind of music within the last half hour, uh, and various things like that will make you go weak for a period of time.
Also various physical conditions or medications you're taking.
So, uh, but the majority of people, most of the time it's going to work.
All right.
Um, now what's the other one?
Okay.
Let's do it again.
This time we want number twos to look at the contents of this bottle.
Look, just look at the contents of this, uh, focus on it.
Okay.
Doctors, uh, tell them to resist.
Press down with two fingers, two fingers, resist, resist, resist.
Okay.
I don't think you can see this diagram from the floor.
Uh, you could do it again with a curved smile on top and a curved smile on the bottom.
I like the curve smile because there's no content to it.
You know what I'm saying?
Now, if you want it, we can switch ones and twos switch number two, you're going to be the patient.
Number one, you're going to be the doc.
No, no, sorry.
Number two, you're going to be the doctor.
Uh, you can tell them that they should close their eyes during this, because otherwise anything could have, the one who's being tested should be the doctor.
Okay.
Uh, Susan, who's an expert at, probably the world's expert, says also close your eyes.
Uh, she can't, they can't look at this and close their eyes.
All right, just look at this to close your eyes, get the energy of it.
Okay, doctors, press down with two fingers and say resist.
Quickly, briefly, resist.
Ha, ha, ha.
All right, that, that's just the experience of it.
We can all sit down.
Now, what I just want you to notice, it's very simple.
It's very simple.
All right, so out there in blogger land, uh, out there in blogger land, of course, there's people that demean kinesiology, etc.
And, uh, every single one of them calibrates at 160.
The skeptics dictionary calibrates at 160.
The author of the skeptics website calibrates at 160.
And the references that, uh.
And demean, kinesiology, all, all calibrate at 160.
So 160 is the level of skepticism, skepticism.
And the skeptic is, uh, why it's so low, as I said, it has to do with nihilism, really
has to do with the negation of truth.
Of course, the real problem is the narcissistic ego.
Hmm.
The narcissistic ego, uh, feels extremely threatened that there is such a thing as absolute
truth, uh, and divinity.
Because the narcissistic ego, uh, to itself is divinity, and therefore God would be the
ultimate hated rival.
And you see, therefore, the criticisms are, uh, pretty polemic, pretty polemic, okay.
Because it threatens the, it threatens the narcissistic ego, uh, so, see if a person's
really interested in inquiry, they ask a question.
Uh-huh.
They ask a question.
How come this or that?
Of course, most, a lot of the questions are, you know, have to do with the irrelevant.
How come a hippopotamus calibrates more than a toad or something?
Having nothing to do with getting to God, but, uh, you know, the design of the books
has the intention of enlightenment, so it's only to, to provide some kind of a, uh, teaching,
uh, technique, method that just confirms God.
Uh-huh.
That just confirms, gives an additional confirm...confirmation, because of the modern mind.
The, uh, in ancient times, uh, science did not dominate, nor did Newtonian paradigm of,
uh, provability and causability, so in the old days faith was all that was, uh, sufficient.
Uh-huh.
The modern mind, uh, takes faith, but with a grain of salt, so the idea of kinesiology
as a pedagogical technique...
is it adds an affirmation to truth that is comprehensible and meaningful
to the modern intellectual scientific mind, understand?
So it's just a pedagogical technique.
And as I pointed out in my response to that blogger, give him a blog, baby.
These are not textbooks on kinesiology.
Yeah, pick up John Diamond or somebody else.
So anyway, I just thought I'd mention that.
The reason I mentioned it was because somebody sent me a book on bloggers,
and it said the first negative blog that comes up about you, you better answer it,
otherwise it's going to be copied all over the Internet.
So ordinarily I would have just ignored it and let it go away by itself.
And so I decided it's better to do what we've got to do.
There's a certain...
misunderstanding of spirituality that thinks it has to do with passivity.
Passivity.
A lot of people think you should be of a certain political persuasion
and also a pacifist.
Passivity.
As we pointed out, truth versus falsehood.
Passivity actually calibrates below 200.
No, spiritual truth means to stand for the truth.
To stand for the truth.
Passivity.
Passivity, then, is encouraging fallacy, is it not?
To not speak back to falsehood.
To not stand up for truth.
We noticed that standing up for truth cost Socrates his life.
It cost Jesus Christ his life.
It cost all the apostles.
All the apostles ended up in disasters.
Any one of them could have survived by merely refuting
the truth.
Refuting the truth.
No.
You have to stand for the truth and I think the best way to do it is to explain.
To explain.
Therefore I wrote an essay on skepticism and I wrote an essay on kinesiology,
which will be out there in bloggerland maybe.
And it's just that because you want to recontextualize it so that it's more comprehensible and then
what they do about it is their own karmic problem.
All right, so is there any more questions about that?
There was also a misquote.
They don't mind misquoting you all over the place.
That I lost my thumb in an accident.
I did not lose my thumb in an accident,
nor did I state that I,
I never stated that I lost my thumb in an accident.
I said in the universe, no accident is possible
because everything is in divine order.
The universe is infinite, infinite.
So how can anything occur outside of the universe?
Everything is in divine order.
Not long ago, four of us met,
I think in the northwest someplace at a convention,
four of us of this group,
all four of us are missing a thumb.
In fact, there's another missing thumb.
Four of us missing thumbs.
You think that's by accident?
Why have four of us that show up at the same place
all missing the same thumb?
You notice in my writings I say,
swear no.
Swear no oaths.
Or let the words be my fate.
I say, it came out of the Bible,
swearing oaths.
I didn't know where it came from.
I just knew it.
Swear no oaths because you don't know
in what lifetime you're going to pay it off.
So all four of us paid it off.
We were members 300 years ago in the same brotherhood
and we all swore and did the blood thumb deal.
And if we,
if we break this vow,
may so and so happen to us,
and it did.
So it was not by accident at all.
It was,
and when all four of us came together,
you know,
we did some past life research.
We all belonged to the same organization
and the same group.
And we all left it
and may the reverse be our fate
was the price we paid.
So losing the thumb,
was not accidental.
That's confusing it with intentional.
If you think it's not intentional,
that doesn't mean it's accidental.
It just means it's not intentional.
So losing the thumb was not intentional consciously,
but fate just had its moment.
Boom, like that, you know.
Quicker than a wink.
Well, you only need this one to hitchhike,
so it's all right.
I spent many years,
I hitchhiked to school every day for years,
out in the cold and snow.
Wisconsin.
And of course then I was also maligned
that there was one commentary,
and then I'll finish with the Bloggerland.
It said,
of course,
he grew up in the Midwest
and was in World War II.
So that explained.
Well, he can't help it.
He grew up in the Midwest
and was in World War II.
And went to church as a kid.
So, you know, I mean,
what can you expect from a guy like that?
I just thought I'd share those little biographical things.
Well, we live in a current world
in which Bloggerland is a reality,
and therefore it's just something
we have learned to live with, you know.
I don't know how to work a computer,
and I don't want to.
I once came across the computer.
I was covering a clinic
in Cottonwood
where the doctor was sick,
and they gave me this office.
This was many years ago,
and here sat this thing I'd heard about
called the computer.
And I examined it all over,
and I looked at it,
and I couldn't find an on or off switch.
I looked at the plug.
I examined it.
There was no on or off switch on that.
The next week I came back,
same office.
I examined it all over again.
There was no on or off switch.
That was the end of my interest in computers.
That was the end of my romance with computers.
All right.
So let's,
how many people here are new, huh?
Okay.
All right.
We do this again,
because for the sake of the new,
we're going to cover the basics.
The basics are in the written material.
And therefore,
we don't spend a lot of time.
But we do cover the basics enough
for somebody who hasn't been here before
or is a guest
to give them some comprehension
and overall contextualization, Betty.
Betty.
Boop.
Way ahead of me.
All right.
The map of consciousness.
Now, the other thing is,
people accuse you of positionality.
It's because they're so positionalized,
they can't imagine that somebody
could not come from a non-positionality
looking for some kind of gain, you know?
They project onto you what they do themselves.
You'll notice that you don't have any stake
in what the answer's going to be.
So to get a correct answer,
you can't have any stake in it.
Therefore, I'll say,
first of all,
ask for the arm.
I have permission to ask this.
Number one, get permission.
All right.
You remember,
in some of the lectures,
we got nos, didn't we?
We got nos.
And sometimes,
because of people that were in the group,
we got the no at that time.
But anyway,
you can get a no.
Then you have to position
what you want to address
as a statement,
not a question.
A statement.
Old Rover is still
something or other.
And then you quickly press down,
and it's a very quick response.
You can ask for the,
in the name of the highest good.
So the right way to do it is,
I have permission to ask this.
Okay.
In the name of the highest good,
I have permission to calibrate this.
Yes.
And so and so calibrates over 200, 300, 400,
whatever, until the arm goes weak.
Now, you have no vested interest
in that answer,
having turned it over
to the highest good,
and avoiding, you know,
trying to beg the question.
So people who are integrous
and who follow the right technique,
then again,
it's a matter of experience.
Now, kinesiology is not the only way
to discern truth from falsehood,
physiologically.
There's a whole raft of them,
the whole raft of them.
Pupillary response,
blood pressure,
breathing,
vasomotor response,
idiomotor response,
acupuncture balance,
brain physiology.
There's a million ways.
Some people are very good at it.
They just stand up,
and truth makes them fall forward,
and falsehood makes them fall backward.
You can use your whole body like a pendulum.
Of course, dowsers do it.
I remember going across the border
into Northern Ireland
many years ago
when there was conflict,
and when you crossed the border
into Northern Ireland,
the police there patted you down,
and they looked you in the eye,
closely at your pupil,
and they said,
are you carrying a gun?
They watched your pupil response.
And, of course, being a doctor,
I said, that's interesting.
You're watching the pupil?
He says, yeah.
You watch for a flare of the pupil
when the guy lies.
So, of course,
the lie detector is set up
to do all these things.
Body language,
facial expression,
voice analysis is common.
A guy gives a lecture,
and the voice analyst says
he was lying on this sentence,
lying on this sentence.
There's many ways to verify it, too.
Kinesiology is so quick.
I just say,
what do you think about,
I think so-and-so has a good idea,
resist.
That takes less than about 30 seconds.
So, I can't set up
a whole brainwave machine
and do all that crazy stuff
for a voice analysis machine.
So, kinesiology is not,
you know,
it's just one of many,
but it's practical.
It's practical.
So, I thought I'd mention that.
All right.
So, we'll go back
to the map of consciousness,
which is pretty much known worldwide.
It's in just about every language
in the world.
You know,
we use kinesiology
to stop a war, you know.
It was,
a near ballistic missile war,
the verge of it.
And,
you know,
Susan and I got
tracked halfway across the globe.
And,
with all the top officials
of the government
in front of all the officials,
who are very wise men,
thank God,
we analyzed every single move
on this side
and every single response
on that side.
And we came up
with a resolution
to support the person's
political power,
in which case
he will drop military power.
Within 72 hours,
the headlines
were a piece.
So,
it's pragmatic value.
It allows you
to access information
that's not available
by any ordinary means.
A great deal
of the stuff
that we appear,
that appears
in Truth Versus Falsehood,
we held back
for several years.
You know,
we held back
the publication.
Most of,
you know,
the recent news,
we knew years ago.
We knew years ago
food for oil
and all that kind of stuff.
We knew that years ago.
So,
it allows you
access to information.
And,
not all the information
can you share
with the world.
You can't.
So,
there's a great deal
we did not share
with the world.
And,
it's bad enough
in blogger land
with what we did,
you know.
You can't
say,
tell everything,
you know.
So,
all right.
the,
if the intention
is integrous then,
this serves
a very useful
pragmatic function.
This is
the perennial philosophy.
Although,
it's actually,
I mean,
the,
this is
the perennial
philosophy
throughout all of time.
It's most recent,
it was a psychologist
named,
something,
who published
an article
on it
back in the 50s.
Columbia
Psychoanalytic
Institute
where I,
my analyst was.
Those were
our training
analysts there.
These are called
the
Psychoanalytic
Institute.
These are called
the
Emergency Emotions.
These are called
the Welfare Emotions.
And,
they taught
a tech,
a variation
of Freudian
psychoanalysis
called
Adaptational.
Adaptational Analysis.
How do any
of these
serve
adaptation?
We can see
that the lower ones
do not serve
adaptation
very well.
All right.
So,
we'll move on.
These are
all logarithmic
numbers.
The distribution
of consciousness
of mankind.
Approximately
80%
of mankind
is below
200.
Okay.
We'll move on
to the next.
This is
the evolution
of consciousness
against time.
And,
we'll move on.
So,
you see
mankind's
level of
consciousness
is rising
rapidly.
So,
therefore,
it's rational
to be
optimistic.
The other thing
is that
everything,
everything
and anything,
you end up
with a
self-verifying
concordance.
If this is
so,
then this
should be
so,
too.
So,
even if
kinesiology
isn't right,
it's probably
the most useful
fraud in
history.
If it works,
they'll knock
it,
you know
what I
mean?
Because we can
make a
huge
investment
such as
the epics
of the
earth
over great
time,
three and a
half billion
years ago.
Three and a
half billion
years ago.
So,
we can track
the evolution
of life
over
the epics
of billions
of years
and calibrate
what was the
energy of
life
when it
first
appeared.
That's
very interesting.
Going into
the evolution
of this
planet
over great
periods of
time,
three and a
half billion
years or
something like
that.
Okay,
so,
and then how
oxygen arose,
chlorophyll,
etc.
There wasn't
any oxygen
here until
the chlorophyll
critters got
here,
the vegetation,
which of
course takes
the carbon for
the forest,
the Amazon forest
puts out.
I forget what
percent of
the earth's
oxygen.
Okay, so,
we'll move on
to the next
slide.
So,
Ecclesiology,
we can track
the evolution
of life,
it's a
consciousness
level from
the very
beginning of
time.
Then we can track
it through
the animal
kingdom.
We can track
it through
the animal
kingdom because
birds are in
there about
someplace,
birds.
Birds,
yeah,
are less than
200.
So,
with the exception
of birds,
below 200
is primarily
from a
human view
predatory.
Of course,
from the animal's
view,
he's not
predatory,
he's just
having lunch.
And you can't
have lunch
unless you
bite it hard
and then it
gets delicious,
huh?
The same
energy field
in a human
is usually
accompanied
by,
or due
to other
things.
Also,
please do not
ask me
why,
send me
an email
why dolphins
calibrate
less,
more than
whales.
Please do
not.
I don't
know why
the hell
they do
that.
It's just
the way
it is.
All right,
so we go
through the
animal kingdom.
Now,
you see,
the usefulness
of the
fraudulent
technique
in the
kinesiology,
it lays
out a
whole
evolutionary
map of
the entire
animal kingdom.
Not only of
life from
when it
first appeared
on earth,
but through
the whole
animal kingdom.
Now,
we're
going to
look at
the evolution
of the
ego.
I think
medieval
Christianity
had a
downside
that tends
to
result in
aversion.
It's
looking at
lower levels
of consciousness
as sin,
sackcloth,
ashes,
penance.
It gets
sort of a
dismal
downness
to it
in the
ego.
And here
it is.
Here's the
ego,
how it
evolved
through the
animal kingdom
over periods
of time.
So that we
re-contextualize
the ego,
not as
sin and
evil
requiring
penance,
guilt,
self-hatred,
and even
self-destruction
out of guilt.
On the
contrary,
it's
our
ego.
Now,
when you
think about
the
locus
of
evil,
you can't
call all
these people
evil here,
can you?
You can't
call all
these people
evil,
just because
they calibrate
below 200.
In fact,
the
hippopotamuses
can be
quite kindly.
There was
a wonderful
one on
the History
is nursing the alligators.
So, let's put in a good word for the hippopotamus.
It's a bad-looking thing.
They need somebody to speak for them.
Okay, we'll move on.
Now, we can take the kinesiologic test
and go through the entire intellectual history of mankind.
We can go all the way back.
Of course, the greatest time was the Golden Era in Greece,
and life has really gone downhill since then.
Life was at its peak in Athens, in Greece,
in about 350, 400, 500 B.C.,
the time of Socrates, Plato, Aristotle, etc.
All right, so we can go through the great books of the Western world
and calibrate what is the intellectual background
of understanding of the Western world.
This is the basis of all of the Western world,
and we calibrate all the great names in history.
All the great names in history,
and...
And this in itself serves as quite an interesting thing.
They say it would take 10 years to study the great books of the Western world.
Take 10 years.
Takes 10 years, okay.
Very interesting.
We notice the limitation of the intellect.
We notice that Freud, Einstein,
calibrated 499.
499.
So, the 400s...
This is the world of the intellect.
This is the world of science.
Kant, Kepler, the great astronomers.
The great names in history here are all in the mid-400s.
Hippocrates at 485,
the discovery of the human...
Galen...
Sir Isaac Newton, 499.
499 is about as high as you can get with the intellect.
And at 499, you have to leave the world of cause and effect,
the Newtonian paradigm of reality,
because 500 is the emergence of the non-linear.
Below 500 is the world of the linear,
which is provable, documentable, and provable.
From 500 and up, suddenly reality jumps to the subjective,
experiential, not provable, not logical,
cannot be documented, but transformative.
So, from 500 and up, our spiritual energies,
therefore, people ask me,
what is the relationship between science and spirituality,
or science and theology?
And I tell them, there isn't any.
There isn't any.
Two different realms altogether.
The 400s can talk about it,
can talk about it,
but that's all they can do.
So, that's intellectualization.
You can't prove the existence of God through the intellect.
You know, I was once a rabid atheist,
and I remember St. Thomas Aquinas.
I had straight A in theology and everything and such,
even though I was an atheist.
But, Thomas Aquinas says,
arguments, which he derived from Aristotle,
arguments for the proof of the existence of God
are considered nonsense,
especially the argument for first cause.
That which is infinite has no beginning or ending,
so how could it have a cause?
The argument for first cause.
Anyway, Friday afternoon,
we go to the bar and, of course, argue about this.
So, it was fun being an atheist.
I was a rabid atheist for some years.
I've already told you how I arrived there.
Sir Isaac Newton then is 499, Plato 485.
See the great names throughout history,
Shakespeare, Spinoza.
And we always point out that, unfortunately,
Marx got in, inadvertently put in here,
because of his historical importance.
But at 130, he brings this whole scale,
all of them collectively,
with Marx, comes to 450.
Without Marx, it comes to 465.
Therefore, falsehood has a serious,
deleterious effect on society,
and history of Marxism merely demonstrates that fallacy.
And the fallacy there was a projecting
duality of perpetrator-victim into the world
and politicizing it.
Okay, so move to the next.
We'll move to the next.
This is the world, the linear, provable world,
which is content, content.
But the content occurs in an approximate field,
and that even in a greater context,
the nonlinear context, the infinite context,
which is the absolute by which we calibrate
the truth of anything here is in contrast to this.
The approximate field is local conditions.
Things appear when local conditions,
when potentiality becomes an actuality,
when local conditions are favorable.
So the local conditions don't cause it.
They allow the potentiality to actualize.
The seed, when it gets sun and warmth and water,
its potential becomes an actual.
But the sun and the water does not cause it to do that.
So in appropriate circumstances,
this is called in logic, in ethics itself,
situational ethics,
which some religions don't like
because they think it can be used as a cop-out excuse.
But the law recognizes that the degree of guilt, etc.,
depends on the conditions at the time.
And insanity, defense, all these things take that into account.
Now, from our own research,
we come to the discovery
that even without culpability,
you are still responsible and accountable.
The act, you are still accountable and responsible karmically,
even though you may have very little culpability
due to other factors.
So you have to differentiate between culpability
and accountability and responsibility.
That's enough of that.
All right.
That which attracts, this is called lower mind,
is less evolved.
It's less evolved.
That mind, for instance, cannot really comprehend kinesiology.
Consciousness 160 is unable to comprehend it.
Why?
Because it projects its own limitation onto what's out there
and thinks it sees it as out there.
So therefore, it doesn't work unless the people involved
reach consciousness level 200.
200.
Why?
Because otherwise it's dominated by lower mind,
which hangs out around 155,
which is the level of skepticism and all that, about 160.
It's unable to comprehend.
You have to move over 200 towards higher mind.
Higher mind.
You have to have the capacity for faith,
the integrity with which a thing is spoken,
and the integrity.
You have to sense it.
You can sense the integrity.
You can't prove it.
All right.
Meaning it's a person that has no particular personal gain.
It doesn't make any difference whether it goes this way or that way.
That level of consciousness is called neutral.
With neutral, if you get this job,
if you don't get this job, you'll get another.
What's the big deal?
You're not going to commit suicide.
Easygoing.
These people are very positionalized and emotionalized, everything.
Emotionalized.
Yesterday's paper, the Arizona Republic,
said in an article that people voted for a certain proposition
primarily with their emotions.
It's scary, isn't it?
Not because they reason what's best for the country,
what's fair, what's equitable,
just from emotion.
Just emotion.
All right.
So 155 is emotionalism without thought.
It doesn't mean sensitivity, et cetera, or balance.
So move to the next.
This is just to show, again,
we're trying to show a bridge between the Newtonian linear limitation
and the nonlinear, which is the spiritual domain.
Quantum mechanics is, again, only a pedagogical technique.
It doesn't prove anything that we're talking about.
But it does provide a means of comprehending
why prayer is a thing.
It's effective.
This has to do with wave and particle and potentiality.
We said that potentiality becomes an actuality
under the appropriate conditions.
What's one of the conditions?
Intention.
Intention is the Heisenberg process is intention.
So a man sits with his feet on the desk,
imagines building the biggest, tallest building in the world.
Then it gathers energy.
Then he gets his banker friends behind it.
He talks to architects.
And in exactly one year, one year,
the Empire State Building went up on, what is it,
32nd Street or 32nd Street?
One year. One year.
Due to this, Native American steel workers,
who were absolutely fearless of height,
60 stories up walking on a beam.
Anyway, they were fearless.
But you see, it took the intention to make it happen.
And that's Wayne Dyer's very popular book,
The Power of Intention.
Intention is what drives also all spiritual evolution.
Your intention.
All right.
So this is explained extremely well.
So this is, let's say it's an analogy.
It is not an explanation, not an explanation.
It's an analogy that by intention,
potentiality becomes an actuality.
That is, the intention is part of the outer field,
is part of the field of context.
Okay, so we'll move on.
This is just, you get two different paradigms.
The proof, this is the world of provability.
This is confirmable but not provable.
You can't prove you love somebody.
You can't prove that you care about your dog.
No way to prove that.
Therefore, this is limited and this is unlimited.
When you, in context,
in contemplation and meditation,
you try to move from this paradigm to this one.
You try to move from the specific linear restricted focused
to the nonlinear overall context,
the overall context.
Okay, so we'll move over to the next slide.
Linear gradations.
Yes, we said the mind thinks dualistically,
good and bad,
black and white,
high and low,
hot and cold.
And these are positionalities.
Because people say,
what do you mean a positionality?
Positionality is an optional point of view.
It doesn't exist in the world.
See?
So I say,
now, imagine three points here,
a point here,
a point here.
All right, now connect the dots.
You just made a triangle.
Where does the triangle exist?
Up there.
Constellations of astrology are from the viewpoint of the witness.
If you take a spaceship and go up there,
there ain't no Sagittarius up there.
It only looks like Sagittarius from here.
From here, it looks like a dog.
Therefore, they have no independent existence
except as a mentalization which you project into the world.
There is no constellation there.
In the universe.
You understand what I'm saying?
Anybody don't get it?
You can take any bunch of dots,
and as a kid,
you can make it into a horse or a dog.
But that's a projection.
See?
And the crux of what we teach has to do,
of course,
with the differentiation between res interna,
res cogitans,
and res externa,
the world the way it is.
A very important distinction.
Very important distinction.
Of Descartes.
The ordinary mind thinks that
how it sees it is how it is.
That, of course, is the comment by Socrates.
That all men choose only what they perceive to be the good.
It's just that they don't know the real good from the false good.
But that does reinforce your understanding of the innocence of mankind.
That mankind can only know what's within
without some kind of a higher teaching.
So, we use temperature.
We say this is very hot.
And I always say this is very cold.
That would...
There's only one variable,
the presence of heat or the absence of heat.
There aren't two variables, heat and cold.
There's only one.
Heat is either present or not present.
If it's present, we say it's hot.
If it's not present, we say it's cold.
One variable, heat.
We do the same thing with the calibrated scale of consciousness.
One variable, called truth.
It's either present or not present, and to what degree.
Very simple, you know.
Calibrating the laws of consciousness is very, very simple.
The same with goodness.
Light.
He said there's two opposites, light and darkness.
There's either light or there's not light.
There's not two opposites.
And the best example of all is on and off.
Offness is not the opposite of onness.
You can't send offness down an electric wire.
Electricity is either present or not present.
Or it's not present.
You don't send offness.
The opposite doesn't exist.
It's a meditation, you understand.
You only send electricity there or not.
Electricity is either there or it ain't there.
Heat is either there, light is either there.
And truth is either there or not.
So to what degree is truth there is the very purpose of calibrating levels of consciousness.
It can be extremely there, very little there, hardly there at all.
When you correlate that with all of human history and calibrate all the important figures, countries, books, movies, everything on the planet,
you come out with a configuration that even without kinesiology would make complete and total sense to anybody who's sane.
Move over.
Okay.
Spiritual practices, yes.
Therefore, for the first time really,
you can calibrate the relative truth.
Therefore, the reality, the real authenticity of various things that are completely nonlinear and not provable.
You can't prove that the Lord's Prayer, you know, does any good in the world at all.
Can you prove it?
You can't prove it.
No.
All right.
But you can certainly pick up the likelihood by calibrating it, calibrating it.
The Lord's Prayer is 650.
You see, om, pronounced correctly as oh, calibrates different than ah-oh-um.
Huh?
Ah-oh-um.
I say that because there's a translation by Satchitananda in which he does say A-U-M,
and I think it's incorrect.
Quite a bit of difference versus a three-syllable version of it, yeah?
Interesting to notice.
Om Namah Shivaya.
These are all the great chants.
Ammanipadmiham.
Let's do an om for fun.
Oh.
Let's hold the people in the disaster, in the gopherry in mind and do om.
Hold them in mind and go om.
Oh.
Okay.
The intention is to bring them spiritual energy to uplift them, uplift them,
to pray to God.
through periods of great stress
because
having been through periods of great stress myself
it's only by surrendering to God
that you survive them
as they take off your leg or your thumb
or whatever they do to you
surgery, no anesthesia, whatever
in the middle of war you're about to blow up
all you can do is surrender
continuously in a prayerful
attitude
and surrender to God
and once karmic proclivities will then
emerge of their own nature
and
we know also from kinesiologic research
that there's population
karma, population karma
whole populations
we here in this room
are part of a population wave
population waves
each population seems to
be subject to various things
World War I, World War II
Crimean War, War of 1812
starvation, drought
okay let's ask about that
that's just intuitive
we have permission to ask this
in the name of the highest good
there is such a thing as population karma
okay
intuition
so a lot of things you intuit it
and it seems rather certain
and actually you know it
actually you know it
because you've existed over a great period of time
and you know it
because you lived through it
um
so there is whole population
karmic consequences
not consequences
but opportunities
because it's really
only when you're faced with the sword
that you make that decision
I surrender my life to thee oh lord
unreservedly
if you physically die
you die
so
so if you die you die
big deal
I remember I told you the incident
here's this mind sitting here
with this horn sticking out of it
it's about this far from the ship you know
and this guy looks at me
I said
you go you go
so
but you see how when you communicate that
surrender
how it reinforces the other person
because the fear left his eyes
he looked at me and he got that
and he just
went that way too
as tough as it is
other than surrendering each step of the way
there isn't any other way
and you look at me and you say
you learned what you can from it
and as I said
there is interestingly the survivors that we see
in storm stories almost all mention how they prayed to God
and the one that's most interesting
a couple of people who got picked up
in a tornado
and lifted
like a block up in the air
there they are suspended a block up in the air
hundreds of feet up in the air
in a state of profound peace over Canaan
several of them in a row I said
it was like an infinite
I was held in infinite peace
I was always sad
when it was over
and I had to come
crashing back to earth
so
that option to transcend the identification with the physicality
and realize the truth that you're a spirit
a great opportunity
man's catastrophe is
God's opportunity is the favorite saying about that isn't it
so
by contemplation
and meditation is a different thing
but by contemplation
instead of identifying with form
with content
emotionalizing it
getting positionalized about it
and reactive to it
you become non-attached
you become the observer witness
a contemplative lifestyle
yeah you know what's going on
I got the gist of it all
how many videos do I have to see of disaster
I mean I got it
I got it
total disaster in all of its expression
all of its expressions
you get it
without getting caught in it
oh it's so sad
oh it's so bad
you don't have to emotionalize about it
because emotionalizing doesn't help anybody
see
in the middle of a crisis
you don't need people that are blubbering and crying
you need a cool head
when you're on the verge of death
you need to be cool
you're about to blow up
you're second from disaster
second from disaster
you just become very calm
alright
super calm
and then
emotionalize about it later
on TV or on a blog site
yeah
okay
so you
a contemplative lifestyle then
is an awareness
in which you open yourself to be
aware of the field
rather than the content of the field
the field tells you whether it's safe or not safe
the field tells you what the overall intention is
it's closer to intention
and non-verbal non-linear knowingness
like a knowingness comes forth
yes there is such a thing as population karma
then you can go and verify it
you see
it just seemed like an awareness
but it doesn't come out of thinkingness
it just comes out of being with
the overall situation
being with the overall situation
we all send help in whatever linear form we can
we all send checks and do what we can
in the linear domain
but to the person who's laying there in the foxhole
linear domain is
not all that interesting at the moment
because what's up
what you're up against is spirit
you're up against whether
you're going to
feel
safe no matter what
bodies come and bodies go
your attitude is going to be the result of the context
so when we pray for people as we did
we're trying to send spiritual energy to the context
so that somebody who is about ready to give up
and hopeless
suddenly feels
no I'll keep going
where did they get the oh I'll keep going
they got it from being the upliftment
because as we hold them in mind
and do om or pray
we uplift the field
and thereby everybody's upliftment
is uplifted in the field
mankind evolves by the upliftment of the field
upliftment of the field
alright so we withdraw then to the watcher
the witness
the observer the witness
and once
you get in the habit of being the witness of the phenomena
then over time
even the witness disappears
for a time there is identifying with the witness
but pretty soon you realize the witness
disappears
and that comes about because witnessing is happening of its own
there is no you that is doing the witnessing
there is no this or that
the witnessing is happening of its own
there isn't any you doing a witnessing
so that gets you out of the duality of a separate me
and of that
the witnessing is happening of its own
it always is
the other way the last lecture was supposed to be on
equanimity or something wasn't it
yes
we forgot to mention it anyway
so equanimity then comes from non-attachment
detachment
you become the witness
and being the witness you have no positionality about
what is going on
you have no positionality
so you are detached
and pretty soon the observer witness goes away
and what is
the only thing left is consciousness itself
consciousness itself
without a subject and an object
a non-dualistic way of being
therefore contemplative lifestyle
eventuates
into a non-linear non-dualistic way of being
way of being
and your way of being then
is in a greater accord with reality than it is with content
if you're the witness you get the total same
you don't have to hear somebody blubbering
we need help here
right
ten thousand people in disaster
it's like saying isn't that a beautiful sunset
you know the way to kill a sunset is
everybody is getting off on a sunset
and somebody says isn't that a beautiful sunset
unnecessary protrusion
or isn't that beautiful music
it was so you spoke yes
the contemplative person gets it
when we were in Europe you know
and calibrating the Greek cathedrals
it was really astonishing
we'd walk into this incredible cathedral
incredible sculpture
you can see even one cornice
it took a man's entire lifetime to dedicate
because all the workmen are dedicating their efforts to God
here's this incredible
I've been there a thousand years
in England the one I first spoke at in 71
I can't think of the name of it at the moment
oh yeah right yes
yeah anyway
so here you are in these incredible cathedrals
and people are running around with their cell phones
talking to their mother
ordering merchandise
I mean it's like studying you see
I can't believe it
I was sort of annoyed
that happened also in France
in Chartres I think it was yeah
and I thought you know
where are the people running this cathedral you know
I mean I would be telling them
shush or get out
you know what I mean
yeah but I guess this is the era of self-expression
yeah
self-expression
talking on your cell phone
and
unbelievable right
it's like missing the entire context
so caught up in this personal
self-interest content
that they don't even get
you know what it's about
same thing happened in the Lincoln Memorial in Washington DC
I mean it always makes you speechless
the experience
it's not like a picture of it
the experience of it is just stunning overwhelming
integrity you're just confronted with
integrity do or die kind of integrity
is there
grandeur the grandeur of integrity
yeah
and there again people were you know
on their cell phones
so we're gonna take a break
did you enjoy the little brief thing with kinesiology
I don't know I thought it's
we've never done it you know
because we're not teaching kinesiology
and I'm not trying to convince anybody
and I have no vested interest
in owning any kinesiology
things you know
and if you want to ignore it
the truth is exactly the same
without the calibrations
and all the calibration does
is give you a verification from the linear domain
so that you can remain a modern human
thinking
who's used to logic and proof and all that kind of thing
and move with comfort and ease into the non
linear non-provable
subjective experiential
thank you
so we'll meet again after
11.30
okay
we were talking about serenity
equanimity
in the last lecture
I
there was
one important thing I
forgot although I've spoken of it many times
in the contemplative state also it facilitates
being with the silent space
out of which thinkingness arises
now
this can be discovered
in meditation
it also occurs of its own
via contemplation
the Newtonian paradigm
presumes that thoughts are linear
you know
it's being caused by this that or the other thing
and it goes off into
never never land
once the mind starts thinking
it's unstoppable
therefore to try and look
you can't find
a peace between two thoughts
and we've said this before
the mistranslations of the Buddha
has to do with that
the infinite space is not between two thoughts
the infinite space is prior to thought
okay let's see if that's correct
the statement
if we have permission
is correct oh lord
yes
you know
as far as we can see
experientially you'll notice
if you watch thoughts
they start out as sort of a vague urge
like dogginess arises
and then it becomes dog
then it becomes rover
and then it goes into how rover was run over
and then how we all cried
you know it's a whole long story
in meditation with one pointedness of mind
you witness the emergence of thoughts
and you surrender them
at their point of origination
now in the beginning
you decide that you can let go
the sad story of how rover got run over
and how the children cried
and all that crap
you can let all that emotion out of you
we know it was tragic
okay
you've already thought that sad tragic thought
probably four or five hundred times
it's not exactly news
okay
you'll notice
that one is enamored of thinkingness
that the experience or edge of the ego
survives on thinkingness
it gets desperate
when there's nothing going on
and it resorts to thinkingness to stay alive
because the ego has no source of energy
other than animal energy
it doesn't have spiritual energy
spiritual energy doesn't arrive
till consciousness level 200
so it seeks
some kind of gain
the experience or edge of the ego
is always out there
milking everything
for what kind of juice it can get out of
tragedy
oh poor old rover
oh
oh the worst of the story
before the ego thrives
oh my god
it was the ultimate tragedy
and the steers start
that's how the ego feeds itself
it juices it
it doesn't want to let it go
that's the obstacle
is the
ego is getting such juice
out of negativity
that it clings to it
the egotistic display
you gotta get on the blog site
and tell the world what you think about it
the world's been waiting for it
all these centuries
it's funny
anyway
alright
so you're willing to give up the self indulgence
of thinking this
and the juice that you're getting out of all the drama
the fear
you're getting juice out of the fear of the future
you're getting juice out of clinging and grief out of the past
those are the obstacles
the primary obstacle
is the juice that you're getting out of the experience or edge
alright
the way you walk away from it
is you have to surrender
you have to first see
that all the ego's positionalities
are devices to
juice energy out of them
out of being right
getting even
being richer
more famous
more
being right
getting even
holding a grudge
people will hold a grudge an entire lifetime
entire lifetime
the diet aids
whatever
the same grudge they've had all these years
oh god
yeah
yeah I remember that
after the world war two
you know after the war was over
almost instantly both sides forgave each other
almost instantly
freaking war is over
yeah
so you salute the kamikaze pilots
I mean they did what they could for their country
with their white thing going
and their bravery
and their courage
and both sides respect each other
everything is fine
they even celebrate together
some members of the opposite sides became lifetime friends
wrote books about it
and some people hung on to it
I saw a veteran on TV not long ago
yeah
50 years ago
and he's still hanging on to it
he still hates them
50 years ago
we were all forgiving each other
everybody was doing what they had to do at the time
for god
for country
for the Fuhrer
whatever you thought you were supposed to do
you know
Japan and the Hirohito was
the sun god
descendant of the sun god
so you did it for god
so each one does what he sees as the good
now the experiencer
is the advancing edge of the ego
and it is the processor
the experiencer processes everything
it processes it
one ten thousandths of a second
after the event
therefore
you never experience anything
you experience the ego itself
there's a readout of it
if you have permission to ask this oh lord
what I just spoke was the absolute truth
absolute truth oh lord
amen
resist
the absolute truth as far as we can verify
so you see what I did with kinesiology
I just want to verify it
because it's a new thought
never even heard of it expressed before
I've never heard it expressed before
anyway
this experiencer is out there
to juice things
and it
so what's coming out of this
is then the readout
so what you think is experiencing out there-ness
is not out there-ness
it's the ego's readout of out there-ness
it is so fast
one ten thousandths of a second
that you cannot catch it
the reason you can't
glimpse an infinite space between two thoughts
is that which the perceiver
is moving at the same rate as the thoughts
you see
you would have to move faster than one ten thousandths of a second to catch it
well the mind can't move faster
move that fast
so to use the mind to try and find an empty space
between two thoughts
doesn't work
I don't know of anybody who became enlightened
by noting the space between two thoughts
by certain meditative techniques
you can hit a momentary saturity
but it doesn't last
and when you get up and open your eyes
the experiencer takes hold again
in the enlightened state then
at a certain level of consciousness
what happens is the experiencer dissolves
and then
the brilliance and radiance
of divinity as all of existence shines forth
and stuns the mind silent
it's possible then to let go of the
desire to think earlier and earlier in the game
you feel the dogginess coming up
and you surrender it as it arises
you follow the emergence of the thought
eventually you come to the realization
that there's an energy of thinkingness
there's an energy that's creating this endless stream of thoughts
and beneath that
if you surrender that
is infinite silence
ninety-nine percent of the mind is silent
the way to find the silence space
is not between thoughts
but a priori
so it's like the sea
and I've given the analogy of the flying fish coming out of the sea
there's a still sea
out of which the thoughts are arising individually
it's not very difficult
in fact you can even do it while I'm talking
and I'm going to do the same thing
beneath the field of thinkingness
there is infinite silence
out of the infinite silence
I hear the doc talking about what he's talking about
I have no relationship to him
I'm not interested in him
frankly I don't even care what he's talking about
the infinite silence space is
is the next step from contemplation
see with contemplation you're not wanting to do anything
to what's happening out there
you don't have to rescue this person
you don't have to challenge him
you don't have to challenge this person
you don't have to thump this person's chest
everything is just being what it is
being what it is
what does the thing mean?
I'll tell you exactly what everything means
what it means is what it is
identity is its meaning
that saves you all kinds of cerebration
what does it mean?
it means what it is
I told you the analogy of the cat
you ask the cat
you're telling a cat about being a cat
and the cat says what does cat mean?
you get down to the encyclopedia and the dictionary
and you read them all what it says about cat
and the cat says that's got nothing to do with me
that's your head talking
what's that got to do with me?
and I say to the cat
well then who are you?
the cat says I'm me
I'm me that's what the cat is
and the reality is subjectivity
the cat doesn't know anything about catness
that's all
mentalization
so the only reality is that of existence
of being that
therefore the enlightened state is merely to surrender
everything that is not the self with a capital S
and one automatically is left with what one is
so enlightenment is not the attainment of something new
it's the relinquishment of everything that stands in the way
the surrender of everything
so to understand the mechanisms of the ego and how it works
puts you at a tremendous advantage
you don't have to undo every negative thing you could ever think about
or every experience you've ever had etc
you have to merely witness
so from the contemplative style
you become the witness
you become the witness of how the experience is
you experience your edge
is out there trying to juice things
and a true renunciate
then renounces that payoff of the ego
denies it reality
you don't have to wear sackcloth and ashes
you don't have to live on figs and nuts
and other disgusting diets
you don't have to wear sandals
you don't have to shave your head
and retreat to a cave
not necessary
you do it by intention now
just let go of the whole audience
I couldn't care less what the audience thinks, feels
whether they learned anything
I'm completely and totally indifferent to it
I couldn't care less
that took one instant
see, I didn't have to undress, wear sandals
go someplace
and eat weird things for 30 years
that's an inner decision
to let go of the payoff
the satisfaction, oh the audience is pleased
or the fear the audience is not pleased
or gee I might be boring them
or oh oh I might be repeating myself
or you know what I'm saying
that would screw up your head totally
what are you even talking about
it's got my head screwed up
golly I wonder if they are happy
with what I'm talking about
oh poor old rover
I remember how he got run over
poor old rover
I guess I gotta quit juicing fear
okay
could you let go and please everybody
yep
how long would it take you?
done
alright so the easiest way into it
is a contemplative lifestyle
in which you are only being that which you are
nothing is required
there's no this or that
everything happens spontaneously
and as you retreat from the juice
of thinking this then
you let go wanting to think
could you surrender wanting to think
would you be willing to surrender
your thinkingness to God?
I surrender this thinkingness
to thee oh Lord
uh huh
and you step back into the silence
and you live in the silence
the noise goes on
the world goes on
the bombs go off
the buses collide
and it's all out there
so that's what Ramana Maharshi means
the world you think you see
doesn't even exist yet
that's true if you're at consciousness level
at 720
if you're not I wouldn't walk across the street
with your eyes closed
one thing about spiritual truth is
you have to be
integrous
to the level that you're at
it sounds good
you know that the world you see is
but that's at 720 or so
see
that's true
that's true if you're at 720
it's not true if the sheriff is
at your door
alright so the way to serenity then
is to
witness
by witnessing
you get that the experiencer is out there
juicing everything
now we saw how the ego arose
over great periods of time
we saw that
four and a half billion years ago
or whatever the great bang
please don't send me an email
it wasn't four and a half billion years ago
a long long time ago
my understanding which I
I won't give credit to history channel
where did all my
that's all my education of history
because
as a child I slept through history
it was so boring
because you just had to memorize dates
and now history is so vital and interesting
I have to stay up late and watch the history channel
all the stuff I miss
is the grade school
it's very exciting and dramatic
and I love it
anyway so
the evolution of our planet Earth
and our planetary system then
this spinning lava
spun through space
and
slowly cooled off
a crust formed
and then
the interface of
the light of divinity
consciousness as the light of divinity
interacting with matter
when local conditions permit
emerges as life
so all life is of divine origin
the physical mechanical world
is of a different order of existence
this order cannot create
this order
those of you that understand abstract intellectual
dialectic
you cannot jump level
this level cannot cause this level
it takes
the energy of divinity
interacting with matter
so matter interacting with matter
is incapable of creating life
that's a true statement of the Lord
resist
matter interacting with matter
is incapable of producing life
because life is of a completely different order
high level of
abstraction
a completely different paradigm
with different qualities
the energy required
to create life is infinite
which is great
that's much greater than all the universes
put together
clanking together
is still not infinite
no it takes the energy
an infinite omnipotence
out of which arises life
and its interaction with matter
when divinity looks at matter
matters lit up
emerges as a new paradigm
okay
so life then emerges as creation
that's good to know
because if life is an aspect of divinity
then it can't be extinguished
cannot be extinguished
so we have another addition to man's knowledge
we have the survival of matter
and energy
and now we have
the indestructibility of life itself
thus we're reaffirmed just again
we're not using kinesiology
except to just affirm the reality of what is obvious
what's obvious
okay
what's obvious is that life is indistinguishable
and that death is not a possibility
resist
yes
for death to be a possibility
God would have to be subject to mortality
you understand that?
yeah
okay
so you see electricity
is independent of this toaster
and this cooking machine
and this egg beater
and this washing machine
now each
the washing machine thinks it's the source of life
electricity
so does the toaster
the washing machine says
I'm the source of electricity
now you're the locus
you see
so the source of life is like the electricity
and you're plugged into it
but you cannot extinguish electricity
so life is not linear
therefore it cannot go on and off
on-ness and off-ness
is only a consequence of linearity
that which is non-linear
has no beginning and no ending
therefore no origination
and therefore no finality
therefore death is not a possibility
law of the conservation of life
I don't know why man never discovered that
he's got
law of conservation of energy
of matter
and then you say
and
and life idiot
can't see the most obvious
yeah it's because it's right before you
you can't see the most obvious
so then
a contemplative lifestyle
is progressively non-linear
the witness
the witnesser
you will quickly
gather
is doing it on its own
it's not a you witnessing
it's just witnessing witnessing
it's autonomous
witnessing is autonomous
it's an aspect of consciousness
it doesn't need a personal you
it only needs a personal you to report it
as a person
subjective experience to report it
the witnessing then becomes more abstract
and moves into consciousness itself
and then the realization that consciousness is also beyond volition
the consciousness is autonomous happening of its own
it is what it is
complete and total
so the realization then eventually comes
and it opens up into realization
of the presence of the self as
the inner author of one's own existence
which is the source of one's joy
so
pleasure and joy does not come from out there
accomplishment
possessions
vanity
things like that
it comes from the subjective exquisite completeness
that in and of myself
I am complete and total and need nothing
in and of myself oh lord
that's a statement of the absolute truth
resist
yes
so the more evolved you become
the less you need
you don't really need anything
they're conveniences
you can do without money
you can do without anything
I did it
walked away from everything
sold truckloads of manure
great
ten bucks to fill it up
sold it for forty
what more do you need
I had a cot from the dime store
I lived in that for years
a couple of blankets I got from the goodwill
and a box next to the bed
what more do you need
well you need a six pack at night
pepsi idiot
all right
so
no
all right
so
neediness then disappears
so what do you want to do is
transcend identification with the experiencer
that's one of the great
that's the great obstacle
you are not the
the experiences of that which
you're experiencing
experiencing is happening on its own
all right
so you got to tell the truth
humility means to tell the truth
there's thinking that's happening.
Then you want to take credit for it or blame for it.
No, it's happening spontaneously.
And you can step away from it.
You can step away from it even when you're giving a lecture.
I don't know what he's talking about.