I'll get you around.
Nice to meet you.
Hi, sweetheart.
What's your name, honey?
Elizabeth.
Elizabeth Cheatham.
Oh, God bless you.
Thank you so much, sweetheart.
No problem.
I didn't know it was you all the time.
It's totally my honor.
Thank you so much.
I've really enjoyed reading your book.
Thanks.
Good.
Thank you for coming here.
Yeah, it was a pleasure.
Hi.
Did we have everybody?
Did we go down that side?
Well, we didn't go down that side, did we?
Morning.
You're running the camera?
Yes.
I don't like these people walking in front of the camera.
Why are they walking in front of the camera?
I bulked up just for that reason.
Hi.
I'll talk to you later.
Good morning.
Hello.
Yes.
Good morning, doctor.
Hi.
How are you?
Nice meeting you.
Hi.
Good to meet you.
Have a good day.
My bag is not so good.
Good to see you, brother.
Good to see you, sir.
Hello.
Hi.
That's my favorite kind of shirt.
God bless you.
Okay, we did it.
All right.
Okay.
Yeah.
Are you?
Yep.
I didn't shake your hand.
You don't know it.
Yeah, it was like you didn't shake my hand.
Are you doing a good job?
I'm not shaking my hand.
I'm good.
I see.
It's good.
Are you married?
Yeah.
I'm going to do those two things.
We can do that.
All right.
I'll see you later.
Bye.
Bye-bye.
All right.
Bye.
are familiar with the work to some great degree.
How many people are new, just so I know?
Oh dear, oh dear, so we cannot skip the basics, all right.
So what we do to accommodate the audience, the mixed audience,
is we try to review the basics, at least briefly,
for those who haven't been here before,
and then we go on to something new.
And as soon as I get rewired,
the modern world is really,
it was better a couple centuries ago here, I'll tell you folks.
I lived in a cave, you had needles and nuts,
and beetles and nuts, and...
Try that.
Try and live in a cave and walk around half naked,
they put you away nowadays, so.
Today I'm dressed Hollywood style.
I have a new jacket, gift to me, stunning, right?
Yeah, she looks pretty ritzy today, so.
So along the sandals and robes and nuts and beetles,
and along here.
Because what we try to do is represent spiritual truth
in an entirely new context for the modern world.
You see, because the historic context of religion
was set in a different culture,
different side of the planet, different language,
it was presented in a different context.
And since then, man goes back and tries to recreate,
and he has to take it on faith.
He takes it on faith, he takes it on hearsay,
he takes it from the scriptures.
And of course, the scriptures, as you'll see from the book,
Truth Versus Falsehood, you can say me you knew me when,
Truth Versus Falsehood, you know what happens
to people who tell the truth in this world?
Well, anyway.
We're reviewing what's happened to the people
who tell the truth over history, and I said,
geezie, you sure you wanna go today, Susie?
Socrates.
And all my old friends.
So anyway, we discovered a means by which to create
an entirely different context to validate spiritual truth
and the evolution of consciousness,
designed really for modern man who lives in a world
of the intellect and science and reason and logic
and provability and computers, et cetera,
of what relevance is what happened a couple thousand years
ago in a different culture.
What are the original ideas?
What's it got to do with us today?
What's it got to do with you?
And you see the credibility of religion has deteriorated.
You see that the scriptures themselves calibrated lower,
sometimes considerably lower, than the original avatar
who spoke them due to misunderstanding by the followers.
Then it wasn't written down for a couple of centuries.
You ever play that parlor game where you whisper something,
and then?
See what comes out at the other end?
On top of that, the scribes did a little editing of their own.
Then when you got this plausible representation of truth,
there were so many different...
If you look at the history of the New Testament,
the History Channel always has a representation of it periodically.
Then there were various translations.
So then everybody had to get together at the Council of Nicaea
and vote on what was legitimate and what wasn't legitimate.
That isn't really the way you arrive at truth.
You can't really go out in space on those kind of speculations.
It won't get you out there in a rocket.
If you're going to base your life on some truth,
it's better to be better than hearsay and misunderstandings
and written down by word of mouth for hundreds of years
and then lost.
In a cave, and oh God, the whole story.
So you're asking a lot of credibility for a modern man
that places his faith in all that.
However, if we create a different context then,
from the viewpoint of a different context,
clinical science of truth itself,
through consciousness research then,
creates a context that is comprehensible to modern man
by which to go back through history, religious history,
spiritual history,
and validate and revalidate truth from a completely different context
in which it's irrelevant whether it was true at that time or not.
It doesn't make any difference.
I don't care whether what the Buddha said was true or not then.
Do you?
650 BC, were you there?
No.
So what's it to you, you know what I mean?
Do you speak Sanskrit?
No, you don't.
So it's historical,
which appeals to certain people
who are authoritative,
authoritatively oriented.
But our modern society is not authoritatively oriented at all.
In fact, it's anti-authoritative.
You see that stupid sticker on people's bumpers,
question authority.
Who is this jerk to question authority,
you know what I mean?
What is your authority to question authority?
What they really mean is authoritarianism,
but they don't know the difference between authority and authoritarianism.
So, I mean, it's a rather,
rudimentary kind of attitude.
But it pervades all of our society and academia
and, of course, relativism as a philosophic political position,
you know, has really eroded the fabric and caliber of society,
to tell you the truth,
in which things don't have to be truthful anymore
because you have a freedom of speech
and the right to say it.
So you can lie around the clock.
It's your very great right to do so.
So we needed a new context.
With which to define what is truth,
how can it be discovered,
what out of history proves to be valid
by a modern means of examining truth.
And so the calibrated level of truth, then,
gives us a way to recontextualize all of life
because the energy field of consciousness itself is non-linear.
It exists outside of time and place
and outside of causality.
It's not subject to error.
The infinite field of consciousness,
it's not subject to error.
Wow.
So if you use that, then, as the yardstick,
the absolute Hegel,
the German philosopher of the 18th century,
one of his principles was the absolute.
And we sort of rediscovered,
what is that absolute?
And that is consciousness itself.
Infinitely power, omniscient, omnipresent.
And the unique thing about consciousness,
the field of consciousness,
is it includes all that exists, now or ever.
It's non-linear, everywhere present.
And the quality of it that makes it very beneficial
is that, curiously, it records every event
throughout all of time, on every level,
thought, feeling, word, deed, et cetera.
All that happens, every hair on your head
is not only counted, but numbered.
Numbered, now we've got them numbered.
Anyway.
Yeah.
Therefore, any truth or any event anywhere in history
can be obtained right now.
Because outside the linear domain,
there is only right now.
And there's only right here.
Because all exists completely everywhere, all the time.
That was sort of mind-boggling to discover that.
Then we discovered the clinical science of kinesiology.
And inadvertently,
I witnessed the phenomena and merely comprehended it
from a different viewpoint.
I did not see it as local, but as non-local.
That was because of my own spiritual experiences
early in life.
I saw things from the viewpoint of context,
from the allness.
And I just was stunned with what I saw.
I saw the field of consciousness
had been presented with a stimulus,
like an electrostatic field.
An electrostatic field does nothing.
It just stands there.
But when you present a stimulus,
it reacts to an equal and opposite.
This many electrons on this side,
you get that many positrons to equal and opposite.
The field itself does nothing.
It just, but it has a capacitor.
So that's what we're used to seeing in the old speakers
a couple of decades ago, the electrostatic speaker.
So we had a new way in which to reinvestigate
the truth throughout history.
And the book, Truth Versus Falsehood,
which came at 5 o'clock last night.
What a cliffhanger.
We had threats, you either have the book or else.
I was like, God, honey, I don't know if it's safe to go.
So 5 o'clock, they showed up.
And the publisher, really, was up against the line
to get it done.
So anyway, we got the first copies in the world.
First copies in the world, right here.
Wow, wow, wow.
So anyway, we got the first copies in the world.
First copies in the world, right here.
So this is a select group.
All right.
So it's an historic event, because within myself,
I'm a student and a scholar, always have been.
And looking at it as a student and a scholar, I say,
man, oh, this is unreal.
I mean, this book is like .
If I lived through it, it'd be, anyway.
They say to tell the truth quickly, leave town,
so I don't know.
But I tried to recontextualize.
So I tried to recontextualize.
How it arose, I tried to create a context so that calibrations that would be outside people's expectations,
if you recontextualize it, they'd say, oh, I see why it came out that way.
Oh, I see why it came out that way.
Of course, during the research, we were surprised to ourselves many times.
And I'd say, it scratched my head, and we'd repeat it over and over again,
and we'd get the same number, and then that would bring up what I needed to know to recontextualize it.
Oh, no, when you complete the whole picture.
So truth is only true, then, within a context.
And much of fallacy is because you look at content and ignore the context.
What's okay during war is not okay during peace.
And it makes a difference to mention, oh, we happen to be at war at the time.
Oh, that does make a bit of a difference.
So you can say things when you're in the Army.
When you're not in the Army, you can't say,
when you're in the Army, because the context changes.
Your responsibility changes.
Your responsibility changes as a physician.
You know, we were talking about that this morning,
whether my allegiance was to the approval of my colleagues or to the patient,
because I was doing innovative work, holistic work at that time,
and, you know, not completely approved by academia.
So I said, is my allegiance to academia or to the healing of this patient?
Well, I took an oath to heal my patient to the best of my ability,
and I'm answerable to God for that.
So I'm going to have to do what I think is going to help this patient to the best of my ability,
and whether my colleagues like it or not is going to be their problem.
You know what I'm saying?
So anything you do is controversial.
You know, traditional medicine is controversial.
Lots of people hate it.
Psychopharmacology is controversial.
But holistic medicine is also controversial.
Acupuncture is controversial.
Everything's controversial.
Just kidding.
Being here is controversial, you know what I think?
You know.
So controversy then just means that it's upsetting somebody's apple cart.
So evolution is also revolution.
Evolution is revolution.
That's what Jesus Christ said.
He said, I came to bring the sword of truth.
Don't expect domestic.
Don't translate that into the world.
I came to bring you spiritual truth.
Well.
That does tend to bring some discussion up.
See?
So that's natural.
If you find everybody in the world is agreeing with you, you better look out.
Yes, if there had been no reaction to the book, I would have felt myself a failure.
I've been disappointed that there's been hardly any rep about it all.
Do you?
All right.
So that's the introduction of the new book.
And how it arose.
It brings us to an experiential state now.
So if you realize that there is some kind of a guideline to truth,
and if you follow it because God expresses it as divinity,
as infinite love, wholeness, allness, oneness, and also as truth.
So then truth is one of the aspects or qualities of divinity.
And devotion is of the heart.
So when you put together the mind and the heart in devotion to God,
then you know what your alignment is.
And then the rest is automatic.
Once you align that way and devote your life to God,
to be a servant of God and a servant of truth,
and to be loving towards all of life to the best of your capacity,
there isn't much more that can be asked in this worldly life.
So, also, we're always discovering something new.
Always something new.
Interestingly, I was writing about, I'm finishing two other books.
Transcending Levels of Consciousness, that's almost done.
And Doshanam Duality.
So there was a little thing in there about out-of-body experience.
And I thought, you know, the near-death experience is transformative.
If you calibrate somebody before, level of consciousness before,
and then after, it makes a huge jump.
In my life, it made a huge difference, you know.
It wasn't really a near-death, but it was equivalent.
As a teenager, recontextualize what the ultimate truth is like, see?
Because the radiance of that love is like, poof, outside of time.
Transformative.
In contrast, out-of-body experience,
the person's calibrated level is the same after as before.
Right?
Right.
I always wondered about that.
I thought, I mean, it's really amazing, you know.
It happened to me spontaneously several times.
And it was rather amazing.
I mean, here's the you, definitely the me, who can see and hear and everything,
up here, and there's the body down there.
It's pretty clear that you are not the body.
You think, boy, that would be a huge jump in consciousness.
In fact, the body is really boring and totally uninteresting.
You look at the body.
You look at the body there and you have absolutely no, no attraction to it at all.
Whether it survives or not is irrelevant, you know.
It's really strange out-of-body, and anybody out-of-body has experienced that.
So the self, the consciousness, then, exists independently of the body, because you're
up here.
Now, the other peculiarity is, how can you hear and see if the ears and the eyeballs
are in the body down there?
Well, there's tests, you know, where you put the ears in the eyeballs, you know, and you
put objects around the room, and, you know, especially during surgery, people go out
of body, and they saw the fan on the top of the cabinet and come back in, so how do you
see and hear and be and realize the complete and total oneness of the self, and the body's
there?
You'd think, wow, after an experience like that, especially if it happens more than once,
but there's no advance in consciousness after such an amazing, revealing experience.
So we checked it out.
I said, ah.
And the answer was, because we didn't discover something new, we knew it all the time.
And when you incarnate, you get amnesia for it.
I bet you incarnate going to amnesia for the other state, otherwise you wouldn't be able
to tolerate the state, you know what I'm saying?
It agonizes me all the time, you know?
I want to go from here to there, and I've got to truck this body with me.
And I think, good God, what a nuisance, you know, I'm supposed to out of body, I think,
and there I am.
I'll just think I'm there, and I'm there instantly.
You don't have to drag this thing along with you, you know what I'm saying?
Subject to arthritis and busted bones and everything else.
So isn't that an interesting discovery?
So we make those kind of discoveries all the time.
You know it, you knew it all the time.
That's why it's not a, you know, this is your familiar condition, and this is an arbitrary,
temporary thing.
That's what it is.
And so therefore it's not a surprise to you, isn't that amazing?
We run across things like that all the time.
So where were we?
Oh yes, we were back here talking about the calibrated level of consciousness.
There was therefore a new way to approach religious spiritual reality, reconfirm it,
reexamine it, to see what is the level of truth.
So the calibrated scale is not better than, but different way, different levels of expression.
You can express things on the intellectual level, the emotional level, et cetera, the
perceptual level, the linear level, the non-linear level.
So we could go back and reexamine anything and everything everywhere in history, which
is what the book does.
We did like 7,000 calibrations to arrive at all those things.
So that's what it is.
That's what it is.
Some of them don't change.
Some of the calibrations don't change over the time because they have to do with historical
events.
Others do because of the change of current events.
So some of the things that were written in 2003, they probably changed a little bit now.
But we delayed publication until hysteria died down.
Okay.
So we have a new means of recalibrating and reverifying truth.
One thing I like about the consciousness research technique is that it's not just about the
truth.
It reaffirms itself, re-corroborates itself, because if this is true, then so-and-so must
be true.
And it is.
So it's constantly reconfirmatory.
It creates a context that is overall comprehensive.
Therefore, it's very pragmatic, very pragmatic.
It's limited, however, to people 200 and over, calibrate 200 and over, meaning that
integrous people who ask an integrous question with an integrity question.
It's limited, however, to people 200 and over, calibrate 200 and over, meaning that integrous
people who ask an integrous question with an integrity question.
It's limited, however, to people 200 and over, calibrate 200 and over, meaning that
integrous people who ask an integrous question with an integrous intention.
So people who are not integrous and have a non-integrous intention and calibrate below
200 will think kinesiology doesn't work.
Well, that's what we said, that it won't work if you're below 200.
So that reaffirms the truth of kinesiology, that people below 200 can't get the truth
out of it.
All right.
We said that in the beginning.
So let's just put up the scale of consciousness one more time.
Okay.
All right.
Eventually, devoting yourself to truth and letting go of the barriers ... So today, we're
talking about letting go of the barriers, letting go of the resistances to the evolution
of consciousness.
As consciousness evolves, then, truth appears differently to each level of consciousness.
Below 500, love is irrelevant.
I mean, it's nice, but it's irrelevant.
Over 500, love becomes predominantly important.
so you have a whole change of context
of meaning, value, worth
and how much you want to devote yourself to it
so let's say the approval of your colleagues
or critics is a nicety
but you're not about to devote your life to that
or abandon your devotion, your commitment
to the welfare of your patient
if your consciousness is on the level of pridefulness
then approval of academia is
a priority in your life
and the patient will just have to stay sick
well I had a very severe ulcer
it developed in medical school
I think the freshman year
in medical school
I mean if you don't get an ulcer in medical school
there's something wrong with you
you're not listening
anyway
it was a terrible
it was really a very bad ulcer
and it caused a lot of agony
I had it for 20 years
did everything possible
I lived on antispasmodics, antacids
a diet
just the thought of espresso coffee
would give you a perforation
and then periodically
I would get it re-X-rayed
and it would appear in one part of the duodenum
then it would reappear a year later
in another ulcer, a different one
finally there was one
that caused severe pain
in my heart
in my back excruciating
I really had to call a doctor
and get a shot of morphine
it was unbelievable
it was perforating into the pancreas
so the doc says
you're going to get pancreatitis
and the pain is pretty awful
and when he releases narcotics
the pancreatitis patients
end up addicted to narcotics
and gave me a grim prognosis
I said oh my god
well then I heard
the first acupuncture clinic
in the United States
was established in Washington D.C.
it was experimental
and when you went there
there was an old acupuncturist
from China
and he didn't speak any English
but there was a translator
but because it was being examined
for its credibility
any patient accepted there
had to go through
a diagnostic workup first
and then after you had
the acupuncture treatments
you had to go back
and repeat the diagnostic workup
so before
I went for it
I repeated the upper GI series
and sure enough
there was a
you know
very active ulcer
and
so I went to this acupuncturist
I said he didn't speak English
and the translator
I heard acupuncture was painless
that's the big lie
no
anyway
I lay down at the table
and these acupuncture needles
he put it right through here
I think it went right through
this is the acupuncture
this point right here
and I screamed
I go God man
I could hardly stay on the table
and he goes ho ho ho
bad ulcer huh
this must be your ulcer point folks
anybody got one
it's right here
that's where he did it
I can feel it now
God
then they did moxie combustion
he had needles all over
and you know
and he puts a little fuzzy stuff
and lights it
so you're like a little birthday cake there
he's a little crazy
you know
these herbs are going up in the air
the local police
it's not like a pot party in there
you know
all these herbs going
all right
so I went back
I flew down from New York to Washington DC
got the acupuncture and flew back
and I did that I forget once a week
or something
whatever it was
twice a week
and after the third treatment
the ulcer disappeared
and it has been gone ever since
forever
chronic
intractable
progressive
I don't know
progressive ulcerating
sooner or later it's gonna perforate
sooner or later it's gonna perforate in the pancreas
hopeless and incurable
3 acupuncture treatments
and you can see all the espresso coffee I drink
so am I gonna believe clinical science
or am I gonna believe academic science
academic science had it's shot
if I stayed with that
academic science
I wouldn't be here
I would have perforated
and gotten peritonitis
and gone years ago
and tat curly hair
tat curly hair
that's how it shows
that's how it looks
Les效
As you read this I realize exactly what it difer크
All right, so there's two levels of truth, isn't there?
There's the experiential.
In the meantime, there's all kinds of critical stuff about acupuncture.
I suppose it's still out there.
It's probably, I hate acupuncture websites, you know?
Poo-pooing the whole thing.
However, it was my ulcer, and I'll tell you, I eat anything and everything.
All right, so what I'm trying to do is redefine what is reality, then.
Reality is more than a hypothesis.
It's more than a dictum.
It's more than a belief system.
It's subjectively experiential.
Subjectively experiential.
So the things we write about, then, in our lectures and all,
has to do with verifiably experiential, subjectively experiential.
You know, as Descartes said, res interna versus res externa.
Res interna has to do with res cogitans, cognitans.
It has to do with what you think, opinion and all that.
Then there's res externa, which is the world the way it is.
And the disparity.
Man can't tell the difference between his thoughts and views and opinions
and the world the way it is.
You can see the academic intellect says acupuncture is unscientific and doesn't work.
That's res interna, which tends to be considerably progressively more and more
just egotistical.
Okay, because a critic of acupuncture, I should say to him,
you know, have you ever tried it?
No.
Well.
So the experiential, then.
So we've created a clinical science, experiential, subjectively verifiable.
And as consciousness evolves, then,
it represents itself as different levels of consciousness as it evolves.
By doing so, we've evolved.
We've evolved a different way of conceptualizing spiritual and religious truth,
which I think is less pejorative, which is less traumatic,
which is less, for which there's less aversion.
The old, I would call it the Gothic downside of Christianity,
you know, was sackcloth ashes and it was built on sin and guilt and penance.
Protestantism, the downside of Protestantism got it to be into the hatred of sin
and all such stuff.
The whole deal got pretty.
Grim, you know what I'm saying?
Most people really don't like religion that much.
They go because they ought to, you know, but it's because of the way in which from 200 down was contextualized.
It was contextualized as sin and evil.
Well, it's a spiritual truth.
You should avoid that which makes you go weak with kinesiology.
That's what Jesus taught.
He said, avoid anything that makes you go weak with kinesiology.
He also said,
oppose it, avoid it.
Do not go there.
Just do not go there.
Okay?
You don't have to challenge the coyote dragon to a duel, you know.
Just don't go in his pen.
All right.
So we had a new way to contextualize what is integrous.
And then we went back and reexamined religions and religions and spirituality
and came to a different understanding.
If you recontextualize the human being,
the human condition, then, you can avoid the guilty self-vilification and self-hatred
and inner fear that arises from a demonized ego.
You don't have to demonize the ego.
You don't have to demonize it.
So when we recapitulate the evolution of consciousness from its first appearance on this earth,
and then it comes up through the animal kingdom, I don't have to call him evil anymore.
I don't have to go into a sin fit.
I don't have to do sackcloth and ashes.
I don't have to do penance, see?
Because all of us arose from him.
There isn't anybody here that don't have an animal body.
So why in the world would you want to go into sin and guilt over your animal nature?
Now, your job is to transcend your identification with that.
Oh, our job here is to evolve.
So this world offers the maximum karmic opportunity.
To undo negative karma and gain positive karma.
You can only do that in an environment where you have the alternate options.
You can't purify yourself in a pure atmosphere.
You understand that?
Otherwise, we'd still be on the other side.
But you can't move there.
Because you don't have any option.
Everybody's loving.
Everybody's swell.
Everybody's nice.
Great old.
That's where you stay.
Because you don't have any option.
No.
Here.
You've got all the options now to undo that which you would like to undo from the past
and grow and gain positive karma, positive merit, whatever you want to call it.
On the other hand, it's egoistic, spiritual ego to seek spiritual, I mean, karmic merit for its own sake.
Sometimes you say, well, you do this, you get karmic merit.
But that's sort of spiritual greediness, isn't it?
That's a spiritual greediness.
Spiritual ego said, give me karma, I mean, give me merit, okay?
You don't like your bank account, so you switch it from money to your karmic bank account.
No, you do it because that's what you've become.
Oh, right.
So with consciousness calibration, then, we're able to remove the mass of deception.
Is something what it says it is or not?
All right.
So here's the scale.
And this evolved, as you remember, historically, when I saw Dr. Diamond demonstrate kinesiology.
And I just got that it wasn't a local cause and effect, the tomato on your solar plexus making your arm go weak.
What I saw was the presentation of a stimulus to which the energy field innate to all of life either reacts positively,
you know, it records that it's positive, or it withdraws from it.
So like an amoeba, in the presence of this, goes forth and opens up.
In the presence of this, he pulls back.
So consciousness must have learned, for the sake of survival on this planet, how to differentiate truth from falsehood.
So you can look at it as almost a protoplasmic wisdom.
It's like protoplasm knows what's inimical to its survival.
And it also...
And to it's that which is not.
Therefore, life had to be able to gain and integrate information.
And that's how intelligence arose.
Intelligence arose in the nonlinear field of consciousness.
It doesn't arise in the world.
It expresses itself as genes and chromosomes.
But that's only the expression of that which is on a different realm.
Because this is not the realm of causality.
Yeah.
So, with a basic understanding, you then become stunningly aware
that evolution and creation are one and the same thing.
You see how the dualistic mind would like to set them as creationism, you know, creation versus evolution,
and then take an egoistic stand on which one is the truth and attack the other.
So, you see how duality, you know, leads to conflict.
Evolution and creation are one and the same thing.
So, evolution is nothing but the unfolding of creation, you know.
That gives you a different context in which to perceive all of experience.
So, instead of seeing it as cause and effect of this causing of that,
what you see is the unfolding of an emergence of a potentiality into an actuality
when local conditions are favorable.
You're not even seeing change.
You're not seeing change.
Dispassion.
This pupa in the chrysalis is not changing into a butterfly.
It isn't a pupa anymore.
Yeah.
So, the potentiality becomes an actuality when the conditions are appropriate.
You see?
Nothing is changing.
It's emerging as its potential.
So, at a certain level of consciousness, you don't see anything changing.
Everything is just automatically evolving as the consequence of that which it is.
Everything positions itself within the infinite field of consciousness as a consequence of that which it is.
So, the karmic propensities then tend to define that which you are.
And that which you are will determine how you respond in the overall, you might call it, electromagnetic field.
So, I use the analogy that we're like little iron filings.
It's not the best analogy, but in a giant electromagnetic field,
you can see where that little thing positions itself depends not only on the power of the field,
but on how its charge is.
He's got a lot of positive at this end of his little iron filing and a lot of negative at the other end.
So, he's going to position himself depending on what he's become.
So, the more you align yourself with truth, you're going to obviously move as a consequence,
not of causality, not of an arbitrary capricious God,
but as a consequence of what?
Who you've become, you automatically align, become aligned by the power of the field.
The power of the field is infinite.
Therefore, God's justice is absolute.
God's justice is absolute.
Nothing can happen to you by anything outside of yourself, but only because of what you are.
Only by your own ascent and your own free will.
Isn't that divine justice?
That's divine justice beyond any description I've ever heard.
Frankly.
But that's so clearly obvious, it's just stunning.
It's just stunning.
All comes about then as a consequence of that which it is.
What is the meaning of everything?
What it is, is its meaning.
That's what it means.
That's what this means.
Anybody can see it, right?
What it is is what it means, you see?
All right.
That avoids the...
That avoids the dualistic split between res interna mentation and res externa, the world as it is.
So what we do is we transcend that dualistic split and approach it from the viewpoint of non-duality, which is not subject to such error.
All right.
So we then calibrated, we ended up with a scale of consciousness in which it goes from one to a thousand.
One is the beginning.
One is the beginning of life.
And 1,000 is the maximum level of consciousness possible in this domain.
It was a logarithmic scale because the numbers go up mathematically very rapidly and they get so big you can't handle them.
So then it dawned on me, wow, use logarithms.
Okay.
With logarithms, it came out really great.
From one to a thousand, I'm a market gas.
So we asked, what has ever existed on this planet?
The highest calibration of consciousness.
And this was 1,000 and it was the great avatars, Christ and Buddha and Zoroaster and Krishna, the great beings who have set the paradigm of reality for mankind down through the centuries, huh?
One to a thousand.
Then we found with presenting a stimulus with kinesiology, and as I repeat, you can't have any vested interest in the answer, the two people have to be integrous people, and their intention has to be,
and the best way to achieve that is to ask questions in the name of the highest good.
You want to work for ABZ company.
Working, so you check ABZ company, I have permission to ask about, yes.
Is it an integrous company?
Yes.
ABC company calibrates over 200.
That's all I want to know.
Yes.
Okay.
Am I accepting this job would serve the highest good?
Yes.
Oh, no.
Hmm.
Maybe not.
Why not?
You can either ask or not ask.
Then you find out.
Then you can start asking.
Then you find out, after you've asked a dozen questions, it isn't the money, it isn't the
sun, then you ask, would I fit in with the crowd there?
No.
That's why.
You just wouldn't fit in with those people.
See, you don't know that as a person, but the infinite field knows that, because it's
not limited in time and space.
So you say, in the name of the highest good, this would be a great job.
This would be a great job for me.
And you get no.
And you got yeses on everything else.
What's the explanation?
You can either just accept it and say, look, God said no, so the heck with it.
Or you can check it out as to why the no.
So it's, see, when you ask in the name of the highest good, you forget the highest good
includes you.
People say, well, I'm interested in, you know, whether I'm going to succeed on it.
Yeah.
Well, the highest good is you're included in the highest good.
Your misery is not going to serve the highest good.
So you've got to know, because it's not the highest good.
All right.
So that saves you going there, appearing to be a bumpkin, getting thrown out, because
you don't fit in with the crowd.
You know what I mean?
I used to run into that periodically as a door-to-door salesman selling vacuum cleaners
and stuff, you know.
You know, I just wasn't glib and without any scruples.
However, I was a great canvasser.
I could get into anybody's house, because I was benign and innocuous, you know.
And they'd let me in, you know, but I couldn't close the deal.
So to close the deal, you had to call in a closer.
And the closer would nail him up against the wall.
I mean, I'd say, she's going to get a divorce if her husband don't pay for this vacuum cleaner.
But I was not a closer, you know, not a closer.
Oh, God.
So.
Whether you're designed for the job or not, see, is something I wouldn't know experientially.
So, if I'd used that before selling vacuum cleaners house-to-house, I would have said,
you know, I thought, what was I selling?
What was Kirby vacuum cleaners?
I'd say, Kirby vacuum cleaners is Integra's.
Yeah, they're a great vacuum cleaner.
And this, it would serve that as good for me to take this job.
I would have gotten a no.
Save myself all that misery.
All right.
So, it has a very pragmatic use.
So, let's just go back to the scale.
Now, this scale we readdressed a number of times because it's a common point of reference.
It's relatively simple and straightforward.
And it covers different ways of looking at it.
These are different levels of the evolution of consciousness.
This is not the evolution of good and bad.
Doesn't mean this down here is bad.
Experientially, it's bad.
But it's not bad-bad.
It doesn't mean this is good and this is bad.
What it means is this is how life evolves from the most primitive to the most advanced.
And how it evolved over great periods of time.
It's extremely useful from a pragmatic viewpoint.
And the book Truth vs. Falsehood is an examination of the pragmatic utility of having a means of discerning truth from falsehood.
And none of that but the calibrated level.
What do all these things in our world, throughout history and our current world, what do they reflect and what can be learned out of that that is helpful to the world?
One of my biggest intentions out of this book would be that it would create for the first time a science of diplomacy.
A science of diplomacy whereby peace could prevail.
The history of mankind.
Mankind has been at war 93% of the history of civilization.
It's only been at peace 7%.
If you do the calibrated scale of consciousness then on an international diplomacy level,
you make discoveries that are really aha.
You instantly see what the problem is.
It's so simple.
A kindergartner could practically see it.
And here's all these erudite people and all this money and pomp and all this.
And it's falling on its butt.
You know what I'm saying?
And the answer is really simple.
And it's so simple that it's sort of pathetic to arrive at what the answer is.
We've actually done it for some countries that were really on the edge of ballistic war, frankly.
And, you know, within an hour you got an answer to the whole thing.
Within three days the whole deal is over.
Everybody's hugging everybody.
It's all in the papers and harmony prevails.
That was a pragmatic application of it.
But it was a unique example because we had a bunch of congressmen.
They were not just politicians.
They were statesmen.
And they sat there in great wisdom.
And I remember we had a whole bunch of members of the Congress and other important people.
And Susan and I were trying to answer all these questions.
And I look at them and they all look like Buddhas.
You don't see any vociferous arm waving.
You don't see veins standing on their neck.
You don't get right and wrong and all this crap.
It's just time to say they're going hmm.
Eight or ten people all going hmm.
And then we calibrated the response to different moves on the part of this country.
What would be the response to them?
And we came up with a simplistic, simplistic solution.
Simplistic solution.
Let's see if I got permission to reveal the solution.
I have permission to reveal the solution to this audience who resist.
Anyway, it was a rather obvious solution.
I was just using it as a pragmatic, pragmatic.
But it did work and history attests to that fact.
Okay, so we'll move on.
So it is very practically useful.
In the world, of course the original design was not about the world.
The original design had to do with pursuing spiritual truth.
And as a psychiatrist I was interested in emotionality, the levels of human consciousness.
I've been psychoanalyzed in Columbia Psychoanalytic.
And these were called the emergency emotions.
And these were called the welfare emotions.
And these are calibrated in accordance with the perennial wisdom.
Repetitiously throughout all of history.
It appears in many forms in all cultures.
So there's corroboration by collective human experience over great eons of time.
As well as psychoanalytic principles.
Psychology and psychiatry.
And these levels are reaffirmed when we start calibrating the levels of truth in society.
And all of its expressions.
We get that the serial killer calibrates around 30.
Yeah, he does.
He does, serial killer 30.
About 30.
We get that Mother Teresa calibrates over 700.
I forget what.
750 or something.
Mother Teresa calibrates at 700.
So that's rather obvious, isn't it?
The serial killer is not up here and Mother Teresa is not down here.
So it sort of reaffirms.
And when you do this thousands of times, you recontextualize the totality of the human experience.
All right.
So let's move on to the next slide.
I want to just, because for the new people we want to.
I have to know what time we have the break time.
Yeah, I got a better hustle.
All right.
And we're going to do a little different.
Nico is going to chant before lunch instead of before the question and answer period.
Because he has to leave early.
Because he's doing a spiritual thing workshop elsewhere.
Okay.
So we recalibrate then.
We reaffirm the reality of divinity itself.
There's a lot of skeptics, atheists.
Various people don't believe in God.
All right.
So are they correct?
No.
The level is about 160.
The skeptic, the atheist, et cetera, is not really a high level.
The agnostic is a much higher level of truth.
See, agnosticism, you say, frankly, of myself, I don't know the reality whether God exists or not.
That's truthful.
So that's integrity.
To say that God doesn't exist is pretty grandiose.
Nobody knows that God doesn't exist.
That's a fallacious statement to begin with.
All right.
So humility then, even though you don't know, you're still being honest.
So we can recalibrate and verify all the great states of consciousness reported throughout history.
We'll go to the next slide.
The enlightened condition, the advanced mystical states, illuminated conditions, have been reported from,
everywhere on the globe, all different cultures since at least 5000 BC.
And these various cultures are separated from each other.
And yet each inner experience, each mystic reports exactly the same inner revelation.
So it's revalidated outside of cultures, outside of belief systems, outside of ethnic identifications, outside of religions.
We'll move on to the next one.
This is how the levels of consciousness are distributed in the world.
If you see the world as a land of great opportunity, then you can live with this fact.
78% of the world's population calibrates below the level of 200, below the level of integrity.
That's why it is a difficult world to live in.
This is not a celestial realm.
There's naive romantic people who think that we should convert this to a celestial realm.
God bless you.
Anyway.
If this is supposed to be a celestial realm, it would be, wouldn't it?
And if it was a celestial realm, why would you be here?
You know, Ramana Maharishi said,
there's no point in trying to save the world, because the world you see doesn't even exist.
It's how you conceptualize it.
So the average human mind laments this condition,
that this much of the population calibrates below 200.
But that's why this is a world of maximum karmic opportunity.
Because you have here all choices from the lowest.
You can kill them.
You can forgive them.
You can try and save them.
You know what I'm saying?
You can bless them.
You can curse them.
Every one of those is going to move your little magnetic filing somewhere in the electrostatic field.
I hate you, you son of a bitch.
I'm going to kill you.
You just went down.
On the other hand, Socrates said,
man chooses only the good.
Therefore, this man is doing what he thinks is the best thing to do.
Your little iron filing just moved up.
You see?
Forgiveness, the course of miracles, 12 steps, how they work.
All right.
So here you see, the reason man has not exterminated himself
is because the power of the people at the top of the pyramid,
their power overbalances.
The downside is 78% below 200.
So above 200, you have levels of power,
and below 200, you have levels of force.
Therefore, only a few people on the planet,
only half a dozen on the planet,
who calibrate extremely high,
counterbalance the total negativity of all of mankind.
All of mankind.
And we've asked with kinesiology,
if it weren't for those people near the top,
mankind would have self-destructed eons ago,
and we got yes.
He would have self-destructed eons ago.
But because there is that paradigm,
that power of truth prevailing,
this is the evolution of consciousness sent to us by a student.
And it just shows, people ask this often,
what about the future and all the prophecies of the future,
which all calibrate below 200, by the way?
The world's going to end in 682.
Yeah, right.
Okay.
And the UFO religions all calibrate low.
I'm over 20.
All right.
So, this is how consciousness is evolving over time.
And you see, this is where it is now.
Therefore, the future of mankind is not cataclysmic,
apocalyptic, whatever they predict all the time.
On the contrary, you see that the level of consciousness of mankind
is now advancing more and more and more rapidly.
Uh-huh.
But don't forget that evolution leads to revolution.
You say, well, if man's evolving,
shouldn't we have peace all the time everywhere
and no poverty and all that?
Yeah, right.
Hey, too much Kool-Aid, folks.
They have that Kool-Aid.
Jesus Christ said the same thing, you know.
As evolution advances, we saw the change in the corporate America.
When the calibrated level of consciousness went over,
it was at 190.
It was at 190 for eons.
Then it went up to 205.
Now it's 207.
Shortly after the level of consciousness went from 190 to 205 and then 207,
you saw the great fraudulent corporations hit the decks.
The biggest names in corporate business, giant accounting firms.
I mean, they were like, you know, a Wall Street bank collapsed.
So, non-integrity.
So, you see evolution then brought forth integrity
as the new principle of success.
And so, on the level of integrity, this was not success anymore.
In fact, that was collapse.
Therefore, evolution tends to bring revolution.
You certainly saw legal revolution on Wall Street.
Giant firms, Rural Comm and Enron.
I don't remember the name of them all because I don't follow the business news.
But they fell one after another.
Catastrophic.
But you could get away with it.
190, you cannot get away with it.
207, you cannot get away with it.
Consciousness level 207.
You can get away with it temporarily.
But the field is now so high, it's going to surface you.
Sooner or later, the field is going to surface you.
You won't be able to hide in the shadows because you might say the light has gone up.
Because the light of truth has gone up,
darkness can no longer survive with equal facility.
I'd like to recapitulate the evolution of life on this planet since the beginning of time.
These are archeologic ages that run into billions of eons, etc.
But you see the level of consciousness of life over the eons.
Back here, so far prehistoric that I can't even conceptualize it.
Approximately rock creation in millions of years.
And you run into billions of years.
So anyway, the evolution of life that you see begins way back in time.
It calibrated as one, and then two, and then on up.
And it exhibits itself in the evolution of consciousness.
So life started very primitive.
Let's go to the next one.
Because I want to get to the core of the point we're making this morning before the break.
In the animal kingdom, you can track the evolution of consciousness.
See, this has got nothing to do with sin and guilt, folks.
Right?
This is how life evolved, see?
All right.
It starts out here, one, bacteria, protozoa.
On up through the octopus, sharks, Komodo dragon, reptiles, snakes, alligators, dinosaurs, whales, dolphins.
On up through the birds of prey, rhinoceros.
They're not too friendly sometimes.
Water buffaloes.
Very dangerous water buffaloes.
Watch out for water buffaloes.
They look like they're not paying attention to you.
They're fooling you.
The minute you try to walk behind them, and they're fast.
All right, I'm just worried about water buffaloes and you folks.
Wolves, hippopotamus, they kill a lot of people.
Hippopotamus kills a lot of people.
And then suddenly, all of a sudden, level 200, you see you go from the carnivore to the herbivore.
These are all herbivores.
200 and up.
So the same thing happens in the animal kingdom as in the human kingdom.
At 200 and up, you have a totally different way.
You have the herbivore, who doesn't have to kill anything, doesn't live by predation.
It just eats grass and fertilizes the grass back, and so it's mutually beneficial, huh?
Then you come on up through the evolution of the animal kingdom, up through chimpanzees,
and then you have these unique expressions as the dog's wagging tail and the cat's purr,
which are peculiarly at 500.
You're safer with a dog than 78% of the people on the population.
That's a cruel fact, but it is a fact.
And I'd rather be in a cage with a gorilla than 78% of the people on the planet.
A mountain gorilla just eats his stuff.
I mean, if you don't go and hassle him or try and steal his baby, you're just another being, right?
Anyway, all right.
So you see the expression of the evolution of consciousness, then.
And that brings us to the essential point I want to make before we take a break.
What time do we take a break?
11.15?
Okay, we've got to save some minutes to save your soul.
Okay.
We want to reconstruct spiritual truth.
Take it outside of the Gothic paradigm of sin and guilt, see?
Because what you saw in the evolution of consciousness there had nothing to do with sin and guilt, did it?
It had to do with how far you evolved.
All right.
It goes from predacious to non-predacious.
Life in the beginning.
So in the beginning, out of the unmanifest arose the manifest.
The light of divinity.
Then interacted with matter.
And the interaction of the light of divinity, the radiance of divinity, and the interaction of matter arises the potentiality for life.
So life is, the essence of life is of divine origin.
That's why life cannot be killed.
You cannot kill life.
You can force it to move into different expressions.
But you cannot kill it.
Why?
Because you'd be killing God.
You don't even kill life.
You just kill God.
God and life, that is the source.
The radiance of divinity is life.
So then this life, in order to succeed on this planet, has to know survival.
So it has to get.
So the point I'm trying to make this morning is that the ego is your gettingness that comes out of the evolution of consciousness and its expression in the animal kingdom.
And if you didn't know how to get, you wouldn't be here today to feel guilty about getting.
For life to survive, then, these primitive things have to know, be able to probe, probe their environment.
They have to be able to process whether it's good or bad, biochemically, is it biologically beneficial, etc.
So life comes about, then, as a consequence of getting.
That's where we're, when we're stuck on our solar plexus.
All right.
Then it evolves to the animal kingdom in which your survival depends on getting.
So the ego is the basis of your animal, then.
To survive, you have to get.
And you'll notice everything about your ego has to do with get, whether it's pride, whether it's grief.
You just look, grief is you just lost.
Whether it's competition, rivalry, you see, because as animal life evolves, you go into tribal, your survival depends on the tribe, the wolf pack, etc.
So these are still expressions.
Some other wolf pack poaches on your territory.
Now you're at war.
So war is the automatic evolution, then, of the animal kingdom.
Animal kingdom.
We're just the same as the warring factions of primitive man, primitive men, being dominated by the survival mechanisms of the animal brain, which, of course, is on one side of the brain.
And then when you get above level 200, you get the inpouring of Kundalini spiritual energy, which changes your brain physiology.
And you see and experience the world differently.
The predominance of this evolutionary history within the human psyche is what religion calls sin.
If it predominates, you're sinful.
If you learn to transcend it, then you're not sinful.
But what has sackcloth and ashes got to do with it?
Not really anything, huh?
Well, it's thought to be a learning tool.
So, yes, it's thought to be.
And at a certain level, it is a learning tool.
And it's very pragmatic for sort of primitive evolution.
But it's only at level 200 that other people's existence becomes significant to you.
Below 200, other people are only to be used for your own personal gain, for your popularity, your winning an election, making more money, sexual satisfaction.
So the animal is always predacious.
And that is what religion calls sin.
If you see it now as the persistence of animal survival behavior when it's no longer appropriate, then you have a different way to contextualize it.
People don't want to look at their downside because it brings up guilt.
You see what I'm saying?
And that guilt is endemic to traditional religion.
In psychoanalysis, the first premise is to undo the patient's punitive superego.
Before you start pulling up what's in the unconscious, the superego, which is the conscience, tends to be sadistic.
You've got to ameliorate and become a reasonable conscience that accepts the fact you're human.
Yes, you do make mistakes.
So what?
You learn and go on.
In other words, you don't have to savage yourself about every little character defect that you discover within yourself.
So what brings that about is the alliance between the patient and the analyst.
So when you say, you know, you don't say anything for about 10 minutes, and they go, okay, all right, now come on.
So you tell them, well, and then you recall something from childhood in which you're very embarrassed and in chagrin and shame.
And then the analyst says, well, of course you did that.
Oh, of course you did that, right.
All children are that way, right?
All children get into sex play.
So you, you know, so you play doctor and nurse with the eight-year-old next door.
Well, try telling that to your analyst, you know, when you're a mature adult about how you play doctor and nurse with the eight-year-old next door.
Sounds good when you're sitting up all by yourself.
You try laying it down, and then what are you thinking about, Doc, Dave, you know?
Thinking about the eight-year-old girl.
Yeah.
The eight-year-old down the block.
We're playing doctor and nurse.
And you feel chagrin, shame, embarrassment, guilt, all about your animal, huh?
Ex-sexual curiosity, which is part of the animal, of course.
So when your analyst says, well, of course that's natural and evolutionary, and every kid's curious about what the hell it's all about.
Don't you think they ought to be?
Well, all of a sudden your sadistic superego becomes more rational now, and you can look at yourself without savaging yourself.
So I like to recontextualize all this, and I'm doing it again today.
This contextualization makes the inner honesty that's required for spiritual evolution a more benign experience, you see.
You have to have a benign view of your little animal.
And as I keep repeating, without your animal, you wouldn't be here to, you know, to feel guilty about your animal.
Now you've got a shift.
Period.
You've got a shift paradigm from this being real to this being of a higher value.
Just like, you know, whether I'm supposed to treat this patient, cure this patient, or please my colleagues, you know?
So there's the two paradigms you've got to choose, you know?
Do I want approval by my colleagues?
Or when I face God, do I want to be accountable that I, you know, refuse to do what I know would help this guy, you know?
He was committing suicide every time.
Every time he got on a hypoglycemic episode, in and out of the hospital, suicide.
There are some people with blood sugars, so if they eat a lot of sugar, you know, their blood sugar goes out like this.
Then it'll shoot down like this, whammo, in a matter of hours.
And they're shaking, and they will go into a rage.
They'll go into a rage.
Irrational rage.
Or they'll get drunk.
Or they'll hit somebody.
Or they'll commit suicide.
Or they'll get depressed.
At that time, everybody had poo-pooed.
You know.
Functional hypoglycemia.
I can remember a friend of mine who put me up for an exclusive club.
He had the worst case of functional hypoglycemia I ever saw.
He weighed over 450 pounds.
And was periodically drunk.
And I counseled him.
He stood off sugar and sweets.
Got sober.
Was doing fine.
Began to enlarge his business.
Then he saw a lady doctor in New York City who poo-pooed hypoglycemia.
Of course, that's what he was looking for.
I ain't hoping.
And he went back.
And you could tell he had hypoglycemia.
Because anything sweet on a table, he was, like, riveted to it.
He was, like, riveted to it.
I mean, he had a voracious craving for sugar, you know.
And he died some months later.
He went back to sugar and died.
All right.
So, academically, hypoglycemia probably still isn't acceptable.
Except that it can cost you your life to not know the difference.
It can cost you your life, yeah.
People with functional hypoglycemia can become, I've seen them get catatonic.
And I told you the story about this patient having the glucose tolerance test in the laboratory.
And the guy that ran the lab was a big, tall, skinny guy with a long, white lab coat, you know.
And her blood sugar shoots down to, like, I don't know, 86 or 92 or 80, 40 or something.
And then they were in the fifth hour.
Shot down like this.
At one point, she tore off all her clothes, ran naked down the street in Northern Boulevard
in Manhattan, New York.
It's a busy boulevard.
Stark naked.
She pulls this off.
She's totally irrational.
Running naked down the street.
Cars all banging against each other.
And here's the lab director, like Ichabod Crane, 6'6", and all skinny, this white coat
flying behind him.
Come back, Ms. Cormack.
His coat's on.
She's running wildly.
He's running after her.
All right.
So you better believe clinical science.
Academic science is good for an orientation, but you can't live with it.
You can't live with it.
You can't perforate your ulcer because people don't believe in acupuncture.
You can't go into a psychotic state and get hospitalized and commit suicide and murder.
Criminals, they'll do that.
They're going to have to go into a rage, punch somebody out, and the guy dies.
He's still in prison.
All he had to do was get off sugar and sweets.
He'd be a free man.
All right.
So we're trying to give you a realistic viewpoint of what can you really trust in this world,
because you'll see the focus of the news is always on what's the truth.
What's the truth in Aruba?
What's the truth in Iraq?
What's the truth in Porsche?
What's the truth?
So now, we have a means of discerning truth from falsehood, and to me, it's a gift.
It's a gift from consciousness itself.
It's a gift.
It's like, karmically, we've evolved to the point where we've earned the gift for those
who are at least integrous to have the means of discerning truth from falsehood.
First time in all of our life.
Ninety-three percent of the time, man's been at war.
He can't tell truth from falsehood.
He doesn't know whether this is a great leader or a case of malignant, messianic narcissism
that calibrates at 40.
They can't tell.
A great leader.
Napoleon, in the beginning, was like at 440 or something like that.
Then he crashed, and that was Waterloo.
So, you can't tell the difference between a great leader, an Eisenhower, or a Bin Laden.
Without a calendar, you can't tell what day it is.
Without a compass, you don't know which direction you're going.
So, we've got a compass for the first time in human history, for which I am grateful
and thankful.
And I give thanks for mankind to God.
Thank you, God.
Amen.
Now we're going to take a break, and we're going to reconvene in 15 minutes.
Is that correct?
Boy, you've got to move fast in 15 minutes.
All right.
We're ready to resume.
Because there's always new people, we tried to recapitulate the evolution of consciousness,
how it expresses itself in life.
We tried to recontextualize the nature of the ego itself,
because it is so central to all society.
It is so central to all spiritual work.
And reinterpret it in the light of history, to avoid the Gothic downside of religion,
which causes a certain aversion to religion.
You see, a lot of people avoid it, because they just don't want to look at guilt and
sin.
And in the 12-step groups, the fourth step is, first step, you admit you're powerless
without God's help.
And then, in the fourth step, you take a fearless inner inventory.
A lot of people get that.
A lot of people get sober and stay sober up to step three, and never do step four.
Took an honest and thorough spiritual inventory, yeah.
And why do people avoid that?
They avoid that because of the way the ego's been contextualized.
So, with a different contextualization, you can see what all you're saying is, the primitive
drives within the human brain, because they're genetically there, imprinted, you know, in
time and chromosomes and all, and genes, tend to dominate, unless there's some reason
to go beyond them, or go beyond them.
And, of course, the big jump is honesty and owning responsibility for one's own actions.
To take responsibility for one's own actions.
To be innocent reduces culpability, but that does not eliminate responsibility.
That's a fine point.
The fact you didn't know reduces culpability, but the fact that you've got to undo that,
you've still got to undo it.
Even though you owe the money not through any fault of your own, you still owe the money
to the bank.
See what I'm saying?
So, on the other hand, your punishability is down to zero, but you're still your responsibility,
to take responsibility for your own decisions.
It's true.
The human is driven by fallacy, because of the distortion of the animal brain, but he
still is responsible for his actions and to evolve beyond them.
This is possible to do it without your superego, which is your Freudian conscience, attacking
you with guilt.
So, if you're relatively...
If you're relatively unafraid of your own conscience, then you can do an honest and
integrous inner spiritual inventory.
But if it looks like it's a dangerous animal waiting to bite you the minute you admit something,
you're going to avoid it.
So, to avoid that denial and aversion to inner honesty, I think recontextualizing the ego
is useful.
Useful.
Yeah.
One thing I tried to do was also integrate spiritual reality, consciousness reality,
consciousness research with prevailing physics and the intellectual paradigm.
And of great interest to us in spiritual work is the Heisenberg principle.
The Heisenberg principle.
The Heisenberg principle is very critical.
So, the state of the universe, the state of the universe, any condition, you can calculate
with the Schrodinger equations, which are both time dependent and time independent.
Which has a significance also.
Then, by introducing consciousness, you change and you collapse the wave function from potentiality
into actuality.
So, the concordance of quantum theory and Heisenberg principle and spiritual reality.
Because, you know, at a certain level, all you see is everything actualizing its potentiality
when local conditions are correct.
Well, one local condition is intention.
So, the Heisenberg principle is the mathematical abstract about sub-particle physics explaining
how the universe works at a much deeper level than the strictly measurable linear.
And it's of extreme importance because intention, intention, alignment with integrity and truth
then makes possible, makes possible.
So, your spiritual intention then realigns and changes the way you see options and choices.
Spiritual commitment then collapses the wave function so that the potential becomes actual.
And that's how you become enlightened.
Just do the Heisenberg principle over and over again.
That's what prayer does.
That's the supplication.
Turning the prayer wheel.
In the book, you'll see most of those things, which Westerners laugh at, calibrate quite
high.
Why?
Because of the power of the intention of the heart.
The intention of turning the prayer wheel is appealing to God, see?
So, it's got nothing to do with the mechanics of turning the prayer wheel.
It has to do with the intention which empowers it.
So, the Heisenberg principle then is a correlation between the scientific paradigm and spiritual
work.
The intention facilitates transformation.
Your intention to be devoted to truth and to serve God through all the various yogas
or whatever means is what accounts for it.
So, some people reach very advanced states even though they're following sort of fallacious
teachings and practices because of the purity of their intention, the purity of their intention.
Yeah, purity of their intention.
The Heisenberg principle then introduces.
And, of course, that's where Einstein rebelled.
And so, you see, Einstein calibrates at 499, genius and brilliance, and himself religious.
But, you remember, as I've said before, he rebelled at the Heisenberg principle because
he preferred to think that there was a universe out there independent of human consciousness
or consciousness itself.
Which, of course, was just a preference.
But, what that means is he bucked, he bucked.
You see, because the 400s is a paradigm.
And then from 500 and up is a different paradigm.
It runs by different rules.
It comes from, it evolves from a wholly different source.
In science today, many, you know, science and theology, news and all those things, you'll
see they calibrate in the 400s.
What they're trying to do is define the reality.
The reality, spiritual reality and religious truth in terms that are appropriate to the
400s.
You can't define the 500s in the terminology and conceptualization that's appropriate for
science.
If you ask me what is the relationship between science and religion, I'll tell you flat out.
There ain't any.
They're two different, totally different paradigms of what is truth, how do you arrive at truth.
Science and theology, right, yeah.
Science and consciousness.
Most of those things, when you, those conferences, calibrate in the 400s.
So, I'll say it's like looking for ghosts with a Geiger counter.
It's just the wrong tool, you know.
Just the wrong tool.
The intellect and science, logic, causality, the Newtonian paradigm is not how you arrive
at spiritual truth.
In fact, it's got nothing to do with it, frankly.
So, what's the relationship between the two?
There ain't any.
Okay.
So, the problem is a paradigm, paradigm.
So, a certain level of consciousness, you begin to see that certain things are more
important than facts.
Love is more important than whether it's logical, you know.
You know, logic says this, but love says that.
So, you recontextualize life from a new paradigm.
Now, the value of everything is different.
You see, in the 400s, you look at pragmatic value.
In the 500s, you keep it because you love it.
Why don't you throw that old thing away?
Yeah, but because you love it.
Oh.
Right now, on my desk, I have a cutesy little box some carpenter made.
It must have taken him weeks.
It's so incredible.
I'm just enchanted with it, you know.
Everybody comes in my office, I say, look at this, how it opens like this.
You know, it's not its worth.
It's not its intellectual value at all.
But you can see what he put into that.
I mean, what a piece of work.
I'll bring the box next time, you know.
Susan bought it, came with an antique sewing machine,
which she's attached to, too.
Of course, those modern computer models are much better,
but it isn't her little old antique sewing machine.
And so you see how the heart now begins to predominate.
She loves her little antique sewing machine and sews on it all the time.
And the computer model sits in the box, you know.
Because it's got directions.
They're sick, you know, in four languages.
It starts with Spanish, goes into Chinese, and so on.
In the meantime, she's got it all done with this little machine.
So this adorable box.
So, adorability.
You see, I said adorable box.
It's a collector's item.
Why?
Because it appeals to some innate characteristic of humankind, humanity.
Quaintness, uniqueness, you know.
It appeals to the heart.
That's why I never liked Frank Lloyd Wright.
There isn't a heart in it at all.
Big slabs of coal, concrete, you know.
There's a local bank we go.
Everything is sleek and, you know, glass and plastic, you know.
I'm sure it's highly efficient, you know.
And I'm sure computers are happy there.
I mean, there's no life around, you know.
It's completely non-life.
It would not nurture life, you know, so.
And I remember the original, the same bank, National Bank has an office in Prescott.
It's cute, you know.
It looks like 1892.
You know, the spittoons, but there's big leather chairs and brass, you know.
You remember like a bank looked in around 1910 or something.
I mean, it looks like a place you'd put your money, you know.
It looks like solid citizens sitting there.
Cigars, spittoons, et cetera.
Anyway, so they opened a branch here and I went to this branch here and I thought,
I'm going to see a recapitulation, you know.
I expected to walk into a sort of Victorian atmosphere and I was disappointed it was all cold modern.
Oh, well.
So stripped of heart, stripped of heart.
Okay, so then we'll move on then.
So quaintness, cuteness, lovability is a whole different paradigm.
And this happens when your brain goes over 200.
When consciousness level goes over 200, you shift from, this is your animal brain, below 200.
You see how the relay is very fast through your emotions.
Already you hate somebody and you haven't even had a chance to think about it because going through the cortex is slow.
Well, it should be because this part is easy.
This part is eons old and the cortex is an add-on.
So here you have the animal.
Now this animal evolves to the point you put on the prefrontal cortex.
The only problem with the prefrontal cortex is it was plastered on the front of the old animal brain.
So now you're a better animal than you were before, smarter animal.
So what you see in the world, the conflict in the world is because the prefrontal cortex was plastered on the brains
of people who calibrate below 200.
And therefore they are just an intelligent animal.
Out to get you, out to kill you.
And they can rationalize killing you.
They can do it for God.
God, I'm going to blow you all up because you're all infidels.
Boom, bye.
I'm going to heaven where there's all these, what do you call them, who's waiting for all these guys there?
70 virgins, yes.
And as I always tell the tale, what they don't tell you is when you get over there,
the 70 virgins are 90 years old, toothless, and they hate men.
He's picturing a go-go girl.
I've been waiting for you a long time, baby.
Waiting for you to come to me.
You got your 70 virgins all right, baby.
They're going to take terms eating you alive, you know.
Slowly, slowly, they eat the back of your neck so your head falls off, but slowly.
Those are the 70 virgins waiting for you.
All right.
Over 200 then, you see the brain physiology changes amazingly.
You go right brain.
Now, you celebrate quickly and then to the emotions and then it's stored in memory.
But the main thing here is at 200, you now develop an etheric brain.
This sounded difficult to grasp when I first discovered it.
Below 200, people do not have an etheric body or etheric brain.
They don't have an etheric brain.
All right.
At 200 now, you develop an energy system, a spiritual energy system, and the etheric brain.
So the etheric brain now in spiritual people sees and processes differently.
The physical brain does also.
But here, the fast track is through the etheric brain very fast.
And you get what the whole thing is about.
It goes through the cerebral cortex fast.
So in the right brain person, instead of responding and killing the guy and then deciding it probably wouldn't be a good idea later,
you're looking for a spiritual solution to this guy.
See?
You've already forgiven the guy before he even pulls the trigger.
Because you see what's coming up.
Jesus comes to you.
Forgive them.
I mean, Jesus' words come to you.
The minute your life is threatened.
Your life is threatened by an assassin.
It's really amazing.
Forgive them.
You're already forgiving them for they don't know what they do.
You can see they're run by something.
He needs drugs.
He needs money.
I don't know what his problem is.
But that's God's problem.
So you see your etheric brain.
Then you're already heightened to a spiritual awareness.
Below 200, therefore, we say it's linear.
You're releasing adrenaline all the time.
This is the fight or flight reaction.
It's stressful.
It's a struggle to the acupuncture system.
You get a negative kinesiologic response.
So a calibration level below 200 triggers this.
And that triggers the arm goes weak.
So with kinesiology, it's not between true versus false.
Because there is no such thing as falsity.
There's only the absence of truth.
Truth is either present or not present.
It's like light.
Darkness is not the opposite of light.
It's the absence of life.
Absence of life.
So in nonduality, then, you bypass that positionality.
And you see that good, goodness, et cetera, like light.
And truth is present to a variable degree.
When it reaches a low degree, we call that darkness.
And when consciousness reaches a low degree, we call that evil.
But they're not opposites.
It's just that darkness is the absence of light.
Why?
Because you cannot have such a thing as non-light.
You see?
If it was equal, then you could have something called non-light.
You'd say, hey, show some non-light into this closet.
Truth is comparable, then, to electricity running down a wire.
It's either on or it's not on.
There is no opposite of on-ness called off-ness.
You cannot send off-ness down electric wire.
It doesn't exist.
That's one way you bypass duality, is to see that truth is a matter of gradations.
It's not opposites.
Because you get caught in the polarity of the opposites, which we'll get to later,
because we haven't even gotten to the title of today's lecture yet.
But we don't want to be rigid, anyway.
All right, this is triggered by the release of kundalini energy.
Alignment with truth and divinity, devotion, all these things, and positive karma.
And you evolve to a certain point, and then there's the release of spiritual energy.
So the animal, from 200 down, people are run by, this is animal energy.
The left brain animal energy, and this is the physiology of left brain animal energy.
Not different than that of the tiger, the whale, or anybody there.
This is the brain's physiology.
What you had to do with spiritual energy, spiritual energy has a totally different quality.
Spiritual energy now, recontextualized, you have right brain dominance, it's non-linear.
What you're interested in is peace, you get the release of endorphins, positive emotions,
increased immunity, better healing, you balance the acupuncture system,
and you get a positive kinesiologic response.
Positive kinesiologic response.
So like on-ness and off-ness.
The kinesiologic response is the response, truth is either present, in which case the arm goes strong,
or it's not present.
So the answer is yes or not yes.
It's not yes versus no.
Otherwise there would be such a thing in the world as no-ness.
There is no no-ness anywhere.
You can't find non-ness or non-existence.
Where would you find the existence of non-existence, right?
All right, we'll go to the next one.
All right, that's enough of the didactic, academic.
Levels of happiness.
This is important to know, because the level of happiness does not depend on acquisition.
The level of happiness, people's reported levels of happiness,
are correlated almost exactly with their calibrated level of consciousness.
A very evolved person needs practically nothing at all to be happy in this world.
You've got a cot, you've got a box, you've got an apple,
you've got a candle there,
and you've got a six-pack of Pepsi in the fridge.
And a pound of yak cheese.
I gave up yak cheese in that lifetime.
I don't have to eat yak cheese anymore, thank you God.
And sour camel milk.
I'll tell you, I'm very happy to be American.
In the modern world, you know.
Okay.
All right, so happiness.
So you see, the interesting thing here is the minute you jump over 200,
the rate of happiness more than doubles.
You see, you jump down here, these people think they're happy,
but that's because they're delusional.
They don't know any better.
Breathing in and out makes them happy.
But you see, instantly, the minute you're over 200,
the likelihood of being happy increases and eventually reaches,
which is 100%.
Because you have no needs from the world.
There's nothing you have to prove about yourself.
There's nothing you have to gain.
Everything is complete and total within itself.
It doesn't mean that you can't envision, you know,
being a help to society or a better world,
or having cutesy sewing boxes.
But those are additions, those are elaborations.
I wouldn't be depressed this morning because we didn't get a cutesy little,
wooden box to put the sewing parts in, see?
I wouldn't be depressed about that.
So, all right, so what you need from the world is very minimal.
What you need from the world is very minimal.
And there's a value to asceticism.
Asceticism to become aware of your avarice for the pleasures of the world
and then discover that without any of them, practically,
you can be happy as a clam.
You can live without money.
You can live without anything.
I walked out the door with nothing.
Nothing at all, not even food.
And sure enough, around noontime, somebody said,
hey, you going for lunch?
I said, no, I haven't got any money.
He said, I'll take you for lunch.
Lunch appeared itself.
Dinner appeared itself.
The next morning, somebody came over with rolls or something.
He bought too many.
I mean, even food just appeared out of nowhere.
Oh, God.
OK, correlation of that with greater happiness.
So we'll move on.
We'll move on.
We think we'll move on.
We have hopes to move on.
Our intention is to move on and collapse the wave function.
We'll collapse the wave function just in time.
Thank God for our intention.
Thank you, Betty, and your intention.
Anyway, we collapsed the wave function.