song.
be
Good to see you.
>> Hi, sweetheart.
>> Dr. Anon. Thank you.
Hi. Good to see you again.
>> I love sweethearts. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi.
Sweet. There you go. There you go.
So sweet.
>> Am I standing up straight? I guess I am.
>> Beautiful.
Whoa. Wow.
I always like I
>> Nice to see you again, sir.
>> Hi. Hi.
Thank you for all your help.
>> I'll be around here.
>> Good to see you.
>> We're going to move faster. Yeah.
>> We're going to go around this way.
>> We'll go around this way. Say hello to
everybody.
I can see I want to be the one in the
game.
>> Knock them over and if they come up,
knock them over again.
>> Knock them down. If they bob up, knock
them down again. That's what I say.
>> I'm gay. Mom,
>> I know you.
Where did you go for dinner?
>> Uh, we went to I don't know.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> And I found out that touching
>> transmits the vibration and energy more
than just being with them. Now I have to
touch everybody.
>> I'm sorry I asked the question.
>> Oh yeah, I remember.
>> Hello. Hello.
Oh, we so everybody get
who's this big tall guy.
>> He's one of the big ones there. You see
him?
>> Yeah.
>> We sign him up for some kind of a team.
I don't know what team.
>> Oh, here we are. Oh, hi. Hi.
I've known him 25 years at least. At
least
>> congratulations on your new book.
>> Thank you.
>> We waited a long time for that.
>> Oh god.
>> Hey, Nico. How you doing? Good to see
you. Thank you. Thank you. Much better.
Hi.
What's the temperature at home?
>> What's the temperature at home where you
are?
>> 115.
>> 100 is cool, huh?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, it is.
>> I Yeah.
>> All right.
each other.
Yeah,
>> we got it now.
>> Here we are. H how to explain that?
Start there.
>> I forgot what the lecture is about
today. So,
uh that's what it's about. Nothing at
all.
This is about what it's about. We're
going to cover that subject today.
uh because it's rare to cover that
subject and also because I'm finishing
two books
uh at the same time and I'm at the end
of both books and both of them bring up
the problem of crossing the void
consciousness level 850
and um people write me that they've
gotten to that state and don't know how
to get beyond it. So we're going to
cover that today. We're also going to
cover more relativism. There's a
handout. Did everybody get a handout as
you came in?
>> No.
Oh jeez,
Vicki.
Anyway, we printed up 300 handouts uh
because it's a very precise description
of moral relativism
uh which is important to understand in
today's society.
The pope says that it's the biggest
threat to uh integrity, spiritual
reality, etc.
and uh the well-being of the world. And
I agree with them. Don't I don't always
agree with the pope, but
on this issue.
Yeah, I've brought in 300 copies.
All right. So, moral relativism, it's
covered uh extensively in the book truth
versus falsehood. I put a lot of time in
on it.
It's really the subject of the
problematic hermeneutics of relativistic
epistemology.
The problematic hermeneutics of
relativistic epistemology, baby. It was
what's wrong with this world.
You heard it here.
That's what the pope meant. So, I
thought I'd spell it out for him.
Uh, it's a reprint from the Philadelphia
trumpet also, which I don't always agree
with, but
Philadelphia Trumpet has some excellent
articles in it.
They get too much into um biblical
prophecies of disasters and all that,
which I don't believe in. So,
all right, in one short page, it sort of
uh puts it precisely. In the book, I
spent a lot of time viewing it from an
academic level. The French intellectuals
from which it originated, uh they're all
atheists, agnostic and uh I mean they're
all atheists and um also anarchists. So
atheistic anarchist is really the source
of it. and Herbert Marcus have
popularized the United States and that's
why the fact the academic level of the
universities have gone down considerably
because it is a sort of a cache sort of
cutesy to be into the latest French
intellectual
BS. So,
you know, like Hollywood elite, you
know, even though it's it's uh idiotic,
it's sort of cute and very in to be into
it. So,
uh all right. So, I made it uh
comprehensible in the book. Also, truth
versus falsehood. We uh didn't
anticipate it. I usually do like five or
10 thousand copies and then pick up the
mistakes and correct them before the
next reprint. Uh, however, truth versus
falsehood, I didn't get a chance to do
that because they're all sold out the
minute they got printed. So,
so truth versus falsehood does have some
errors in it for those of you who are
preoccupied with the trees and not the
forest.
Quite a few of you out there. In fact,
there's some people don't get what the
trees are about. Forget the forest.
There are some errors and we will put
them up on the website. They are really
errors of the manuscript. This man
manuscript, the truth versus false, it
took well over three years. This is
probably the 15th revision and uh Sonia
and I wore out our fax machines back and
forth with all of them and I got lost in
the book a couple times and uh couldn't
remember what part went where.
being in uh linear domain is not my
forte anymore
and um so there are some mismatches you
know one place in the book it says it
calibrates at this and another place it
says it calibrates at that there's
various reasons for it as I explain in
the book uh if you're going to do
political parties or current events they
change
so al-Qaeda might you know calibrate it
one thing
in 2003 3 when we first did it and then
by the end of 2004 and so you see
because we're all like iron filings in a
giant electromagnetic field and by the
option of our decisions we constantly
move up and down
uh the Palestinian leader is probably
one of the best recent examples what was
his name or something what's his name
>> yeah 440 in the beginning and I don't
know about 65 at the end see so you ask
you know what's Arafat caliber It
depends when you know right before he
blew up a b a a busload of children he
was here and then after he blew it up he
was there you know.
So
anyway
we won't get those corrections in the
first the next printing but in the one
after that. So we've got a number of
them and something will be in two
columns at the same time and we forgot
to move it over. So there's problems in
the manuscript but the it's the thrust
of the tree. It's the forest and not the
trees. The trees are just to demonstrate
demonstrate. Little variations in
calibration levels are interesting only
if you're doing research in that area.
Research in that area. Uh that gen, you
know, if I had to redo the books, I
probably would have just said, you know,
middle uh low, middle, and high 300s,
low, middle, and high 400s. I mean,
because what you want to get is the
range. See? And um then there were other
things we found about calibrating too
because we learn as we go also you know
we uh learn also
sometimes I'll take a book and and and
uh I'll get one calibration and then I
take the author and I get another
calibration I say my presumption was the
author and the book are the same you
know so uh anyway worth correcting those
and if you can forgive human error um
I'll admit they're Uh,
which proves how humble I am.
I got the humble award for the year.
Yeah. The spiritual ego is the Achilles
heel.
uh and has to be watched all the time
because as you advance you know the
spiritual ego wants to take credit for
that you understand so you have to
constantly watch it so today we'll talk
you know I always want to mention some
precautions along the spiritual pathway
because we see disasters the way the
roadside is littered with uh uh
spiritual disasters and uh I feel it's
the responsibility of the teacher to
share what the disasters are in each
level, what not to fall into, what may
you may be confronted
because each person as they evolve, it's
their first time through it, too. So,
how do they know? You know, in the high
500s, everybody's going to throw
themselves at you. They're mentally in
love with you.
So, as you get into the high 500s, which
is the likelihood in a group like this,
that's for sure. Uh because the energy
of spiritual love, the condolini energy
is so strong, people will look at you
and fall in love with you. They really
will. And uh you can walk in the door
and they'll tell you all the way back
and then ask you to would you like to go
to bed, you know,
haven't even met you yet. I'd like to
meet you first. But anyway,
you can see why many gurus and there's a
lot of them that you'll see calibrated,
you know, 550 and around 560, 570.
And then they fell for the seduction,
the glamour.
So there's a lot of things we have to
watch for as we go.
the 400s which is intellectual the
spiritual ego comes up and says I know
that what you mean is you read a book on
it you don't know that you read a book
you heard about it I like the Buddha's
use of the term have heard about the
Buddhist term I have heard of that
to know it is something else uh so the
ego you know says well I've I've heard
all that
so then you look at him and you say
Well,
then now what if you've heard about it?
Why not make it be? Yeah.
All right. So, those things we are,
you'll notice that we do caution as you
go along the line. Today, we're going to
talk also about the void which happens
at consciousness level 850 and which can
happen as a consequence of following the
pathway of negation.
How many here have followed the pathway
of negation?
Yeah, right. Okay.
Well, we don't exist, so we don't have
to answer the question, do we?
How many here are new for the first
time?
Oh, dear. Oh, dear. Okay.
All right. Gloria and excelsia deal.
Each lecture we try to cover the main
basics for those who haven't been here
before and then we go on as we keep
evolving. What we're working on is
transcending the levels of
consciousness. So each level of
consciousness has its upside and its
downside. It has its attractions and its
aversions. So we what we've been doing
in in these lectures and we'll finish
them by the end of the year is we're
taking each level of consciousness and
showing what are the attractions and
what are the aversions because if you
can nail them down it really helps you
spiritually a lot instead of you know
meditating for 6 months to find out what
you're hung up on and there it is on
page 32. you just glance and said, "Oh,
it's just a matter of bringing it to
your awareness because the ego is not of
its own going to seek it out and I'd be
happy to tell you about that.
You like the pride of humility, you
know, that we just talked about. You
know, ego isn't going to let you know
about that." So, all right. Each level
then has its attractions and its
aversions.
Uh we're not going to spend much time on
the slides and next year I don't think
we'll do any slides. Uh we'll pretty
much have finished with the dedactic
material because it's unique in its
conceptualization and contextualization.
I thought it's a thing that I had to
share with the world because it's never
been presented in that way that's
comprehensible
and so many people you know are
attracted to spiritual work through
reading and the literature and all that.
And I thought for the modern mind, for
the old, you know, for the for centuries
past, u ecclesiastic authority was
sufficient. In today's world,
ecclesiastic authority plus a quarter
will get you on the subway, you know.
Because that's not sufficient to the
modern mind.
So we've tried to reconceptualize
spiritual reality
that's in accord with the modern mind
and how it thinks rational logical
mathematical
starting really from the Newtonian
paradigm and moving on past the
Newtonian via quantum mechanics and
subparticle physics and Heisenberg
principle etc. so that you can still
remain a a logical uh modern
scientifically educated human being and
become spiritual without having to be
apologetic for it. You know anyway he
says you believe in prayer you say don't
you know anything about the Heisenberg
principal idiot
were you still in your Newtonian bag of
cause and effect give me a break will
you
cause and effect that was hundreds of
years ago I mean where have you been you
know
Okay. So, um we'll start then we'll go
through the slides and maybe say them a
little differently than in the past.
Uh consciousness calibration came about
spontaneously. Uh I was watching a
lecture by John Diamond, an excellent
teacher. his body his books behavioral
kinesiology and your body don't doesn't
lie calibrated extremely high and he
himself is very integrous and very
wonderful speaker in watching the
demonstration of kinesiology I did not
see it as a local phenomena of cause and
effect
because of spiritual experiences that
were quite profound that had recurred
throughout my early life childhood and
adolescence etc uh I just saw but
comprehended it comprehended the
phenomena
uh from beyond the Newtonian paradigm. I
saw that the field of consciousness
itself
was being presented with a stimulus. The
field of consciousness itself
would be the most secularized uh way to
describe the presence of God. We don't
like to use the name God in public much
anymore. So we stay with cons the field
of infinite field of consciousness
so that nobody gets offended. You see?
All right. But then we discovered that
we could calibrate
that the absolute presence of the field
of consciousness itself is really the
infinite power of divinity unmanifest.
and and it has the potentiality then to
become manifest.
The infinite field itself
with no beginning and no ending
doesn't do anything. It just is.
It is that out of which all of creation
continuously evolves. Okay? Because
evolution and creation are one and the
same thing. It which is obvious. Anybody
disagree?
All right. Nobody disagrees.
Either I'm a success or a total failure.
You know what I mean?
All right. So anyway, we notice that
this phenomena
depended on the energy of the stimulus.
So you have an electrostatic field like
the oldfashioned electrostatic speaker
uh back in the days of stereo.
When presented with a stimulus, it
responds with an equal and opposite
direction. This many electrons on this
side, this many posetrons to balance it.
So the electrostatic field is the space
in which that happens. But the field
itself does nothing. Does nothing. It
just is.
Yeah.
So that this kinesiologic response then
was
um like a revelation. It's it's like it
just I saw what it could do and we then
spent years investigating it.
It has it has a limitation and in the
back of all the books I have a section
on kinesiology describing the technique
then the uh limitations
uh for the for it to work both people
have to be over if it's done two people
together uh both people have to
calibrate over 200 the intention of the
question or the proposition has to also
be over 200. Therefore, it's rare that
people can use kinesiology adequately in
our population.
First of all, they both have to be
integrous. The intention has to be
integrous. The question has to be
integrous. All right? So,
you can't do it in order to prove
something you already believe, which is
there's critics of kinesiology out there
and they all calibrate about 160.
And some guy wrote me, you know, that it
was all a fraud. And I sort of his
calibration was 160 and all the all the
references he gave me were 160. And of
course, that's what I said in the book.
Under 200 don't work.
So he just proved that what I said is
true.
It's because of karmic uh propensity,
because of karmic reasons. probably
having uh reviled the truth or
desecrated the truth, people are now
allowed to have access to it apparently
something like that. Anyway, at 200
consciousness level 200 there's a
dramatic change which we'll hit when we
we'll cover briefly. At 200 there's an
evolution of consciousness
uh in which the condolini energy now
begins to pour in through the atheric
body. Prior to consciousness level 200
PE there there is no atheric body which
was stunning to me when I discovered it
and we reaffirmed it over and over
again. Didn't seem fair.
No, that's true. So below 200 is sort of
animal karma. In other words,
the the karma is that of the field.
Karma is that of the field. At 200,
there's an individualization
and karmic responsibility now shifts to
a different dimension. The emergence of
the atheric brain
and the flow of condundalini energy up
through the nervous system which is
transformative. And when we get to that
slide, you're all familiar with that
slide. Uh there's a major shift in the
way the brain processes information and
the way you contextualize your
relationship to life and to other human
beings and what your responsibility is
to it. Uh
so below 200 you can do anything you
want. You can just chop up people, kill
them, blow them up, feel good about it.
Over 200 that's sort of tacky.
over 200. You say, "I really don't know
if we should bump this whole busload of
kids." You know,
300 kids at once. You know, maybe just a
couple of kids. How's that? You know,
we won't bomb people by the thousands.
We'll just knock off a few in the
subway, you know.
So at 200 then there's uh responsibility
towards life and one's attitude towards
life. They're really two different
populations.
200 and up is actually a different
population than under 200. You don't
know how different it is. In the book
Truth Versus Falsehood, I describe
Messianic malignant narcissism
and I spend a couple of pages because
it's so obvious and yet people look it
right in the face and don't even get it.
You think this is a nice kitty? It's not
a nice kitty. Didn't you notice the
stripes on the nice kitty's face?
That's the difference.
The difference is instant death. So,
it's good to know the difference between
a kitty and a tiger. Kitty and a tiger.
So, I spent pages describing that tigers
have stripes on their faces.
Kitty's purr. Tigers have face on their
faces. So, you can tell the difference.
Despite thousands of years of evolution,
mankind is still pathetically limited in
its capacity to recognize even the
obvious. the obvious obvious okay all
right so
we'll start then with cal with the we'll
go through the slides
um so I wanted to tell you the
limitation of the kinesiologic test uh
the reasons why people don't get it some
of there's only one of them that's
really well known and he calibrates at
190 he that doesn't get it the rest of
them are sort of wackos but um
because what why why do why does why do
what they write calibrate 160 60 cuz
their intention from the beginning is to
disprove it. You know, you like if our
intention was to disprove the existence
of God, well, that would already
define what you're going to be writing.
You can't define what you dis want to
research before you do it. See? So, all
right. So, what happened to the
calibrated levels of consciousness? I
don't know. They just disappeared. Uh,
did we do them?
>> Oh, yeah. All right. So this is of
course is extremely well known and uh
it's in every language in the world now.
It's all over the world and uh
kinesiology to diagnose things is
already in use by a couple of
governments several governments. You
know I saw its value in international
diplomacy
and uh in and its use in international
diplomacy uh to diminish the chances of
war.
So um of course our government hasn't
heard about it yet but other governments
have
other governments have and they're
already using it. Several governments
are already using uh calibrating uh
energy fields of diplomats and tension
and all. So uh in the book we did that
for various things and of course the
calibrations there will change you know
we did Iran uh what's its nuclear
capacity and what's its nuclear
intention.
uh I don't know when we did that
probably 2004 somewhere so it could be
the numbers could be different now see
but if you know what the capa capacity
is and you know what the intention is
you know what you're dealing with
because the rest is happy talk all these
politicians
um they don't know how to do anything
else except be deceptive that's their
obligation is to be deceptive and evade
the truth you see so Um all right so the
calibrated lows of consciousness then
are of great use in spiritual research
evolution of personal consciousness
and it's it recontextualizes
all of human life actually because you
see how all human life evolves and how
it's displayed out in the cultures of
the world past and present. Okay. So
we'll go on to the next. So we when we
do kinesiology uh we're we intend to do
a teaching tape on it. We did one many
years ago. We think we're going to do
another one. We thought we did it last
November, but we didn't do it, did we?
In fact, in this book, it said in the
back of the book, it says the it gives
the publication of it, and we didn't do
it yet. Well,
as soon as the lecture is over, we're
going to run home and do it.
But I'll just tell the group here. I
hold I don't have to tell her what's
going on to to overcome the objection
that you know it's a suggestion to the
other person. I hold in mind what I want
what I'm I'm asking about. And then I'll
say what I'm holding in mind calibrates
over so and so and so and so until she
goes weak. You know, let's do one. Um
there's a book on my desk. What is the
book?
Oh yeah. Okay. The book I'm holding on
my desk. Uh the teaching calibrates over
840 850
850 850. Okay. Zen teachings of Wayne
Pole.
See Wayne Pole if you follow him as a
pathway in negation will take you 850
and then he ups and dies and leaves you
there.
No. Oh no, that isn't true. I'm sorry,
Wang Po. Forgive me. Uh,
that's not true.
We'll get to it later. But Hang Po, the
10 teachings of Wang Po are revered
about the 7th century or so, 9th
century, takes you to the void. And um,
but Huang Po himself did not stop there.
Huang Po although his writings are at
850, he takes you to the void.
um the pathway of negation will take you
to nothingness.
But he himself then evolved later to
960. Hanging Po did not stop at 850. He
left you folks there.
He left you in the middle of
nothingness.
All right. So we're going to cover that
today because it hasn't been covered
probably for a thousand years
correctly. I don't know of anybody uh
that can describe what the downside the
upside is. How to get in it and how to
get out of it and and what the problem
is with it. Okay. So the distribution of
levels of mankind everybody's familiar
with this and it's why um you know unity
unity is having a prayer day. I had some
kind of things I was supposed to talk
about
extensive notes as you can see.
Uh,
it's just how I said it. Unity World Day
of Prayer is September 8th. September
8th, you can make a note on your
calendar to pray for. Doesn't say unity
world day prayer. It doesn't say pray
for what? Uhhuh. Guess it's up to you.
Anyway, we know that u when large
numbers of people who are, you know,
relatively spiritually evolved pray
together, it has quite a profound
effect. We saw that when the
consciousness level of mankind went from
190 to 205 in the late 80s. That was
concordant harmonic concordance. We saw
it again in 2003 when we were in San
Francisco again. The harmonic
concordance it went up from 205 to 207.
Those were both days of world prayer.
And I think unity is researching uh the
effect of large masses of people's
effect when they all pray together.
All right. So, world days of prayer then
are not just dooderism. I used to be
skeptical. I said, "Yeah, right.
World Day of Prayer as well."
But I but now you see research shows
that it is a powerful impact when huge
numbers of people on the same day let's
say pray for world peace harmony
whatever it does have an effect on
mankind you know it does have an effect
on the collective consciousness of
mankind and of course the colle
consciousness collective consciousness
of mankind is like the level of the sea
and as you raise the level of the sea It
raises everyone uh floating on the sea.
Mhm. All right. So, this is the
uh these are the people that are
responsible
uh responsible to each other and to the
world to do what they do the best they
can because you can see what you're
balancing. So, let's move on. I mean,
the history of the world, we'll move
past that one, too. History of the world
is gruesome enough as it is.
Um the the other thing I've tried to do
in these lectures is recontextualize the
understanding of the ego. Uh I don't
think it's extreme I don't think it's
very well understood.
There's the Freudian ego that which is
quite correct. It's quite correct.
That's a psychological ego.
The evolution of the ego from a
religious spiritual viewpoint to me has
been somewhat mis misleading.
The ancient scriptures
everything below 200 is described as
evil and sin and guilt and sackcloth and
ashes and penance. And because it's so
awful, you have to deny it. Uh I'm not
greedy. Uh etc.
uh because it because it's so loaded
with guilt, you can't own it. If you
can't own it, you project it. Either
repress it or you project it.
Consequently, the world has not made
great strides. From a very advanced
view, spiritual viewpoint, the world has
not really made great great strides.
Small small areas. Yes. Bunch of
Buddhist monks meditating in a monastery
someplace. They're doing swell. But what
about the folks out there?
They're getting wiped out by one war
after another. The same as usual. Same
as usual.
It's just where the war is.
As you know, war has prevailed 93% of
the time of uh human history. 93% of the
time is therefore peace is a very
abnormal condition. Abnormal 7% of the
time. And at any one time, there's
usually at least several dozen wars
going on on the planet. Somebody
recently said that there's 35 of them
going on currently.
Yeah.
If we if we say forget about the sin and
guilt business, forget about sin and
guilt.
Um let's say we came from another u uh
galaxy. We want to examine the human
condition.
uh we would say how do these people get
to be the way they are?
We'd have to start at the beginning of
life and see how did it evolve. You see
that out of the unmanifest arises
through the field of consciousness
itself.
The light of creation
uh out of that arises manifest physical
world
and time and space.
And when this the energy field interacts
with matter as matter finally evolved uh
it has the capacity to be for the
beginning of life. So life originates
from divinity only. Let's see if that's
correct. Divinity.
The source of life is solely the
consequence of divinity.
Resist. solely the consequence of
divinity.
Uhhuh.
It's not possible for a bunch of
chemicals to just happily accidentally
interact with each other and create life
because they don't have the intrinsic
power. They don't have the power.
As life begins and it begins at the most
primitive level and the reason I repeat
this in all the lectures is because
guilt about the e downside of the ego is
so pounded into the human psyche that it
really takes a great deal of work to
undo it. All right. So animal life in
order to survive and you might say I
wouldn't call it hostile environment
certainly not friendly. It'd be like
trying to start life on Mars. I mean
there's nothing there to support it. So
the energy of life itself then
intrinsic to it it lacked animal life
lacked within itself a source of energy.
When you're in the linear domain then
you have to have structure and the
structure requires energy.
So you have to have the capacity to
acquire.
The acquisition of energy then was the
emergence of the ego. It's consequent to
the beginning of life itself.
Bacteria you see calibrated one. The
bacteria doesn't have a little power
pack or you know his sandwich packed by
his mom and his sack.
Consequently the there's the emergence
of
the leading edge of the ego which I call
the experiencer.
This is like an information probe.
You watch your ego, you'll see it's
constantly probing.
It's constantly seeking. It's sampling
everything. It's constantly foraging the
environment. You watch a person when
they walk into the room, they're
foraging the the flowers and see this
thing here. And what's in here? Can I
have some of that? And what's he talking
about? Is it interesting or not
interesting? And how this itches here.
Anyway, did I wear the right thing
today? I mean, you see it just go. It's
just a constant buzzsaw.
The buzzsaw, the experiencer
is like a greedy searcher out there.
Okay, that's what you identify with as
you.
Not just the ego, not the whole ego,
although the whole bolox comes later,
but it's really the leading edge of the
experiencer,
which is, I would say, best defined as
the information probe from the nonlinear
into the linear domain.
It's like the nonlinear domain
then
manifests
through consciousness an information
processing probe unit.
This unit is diversified throughout all
of the animal kingdom. But you'll see
the leading edge of the experiencer is
to constantly search, forage, probe,
sample, gather information, process that
information. Therefore, intelligent
design is an adequate description if the
word God makes you nervous. See,
because as it does this, it then
acquires information. It then begins to
progressively process the information.
The core of then which religiously is
called ignorance. Ignorance.
Ignorance.
Anyway, the core of the ego then is this
information probe which doesn't have a
conscience doesn't have a conscience.
The problem of life in its earliest
formation is to continue as life. So you
see then uh she's saving electric. Oh
okay.
All right. So you see uh how life
evolves and throughout time and and
these are huge periods of time uh uh
millions and millions of rock ages and
all and infinite billions of years.
Slowly life evolves to more evolved uh
to more evolved expressions
and therefore you see the energy of life
when it first appears on the planet as
we said uh we calibrated that at one
bacteria first signs of life discernible
life I'm sure somebody will have an
argument that there something else
existed so that's okay with me but
anyway bacteria one so let's start there
and then you see lifey evolves and you
see the level of consciousness
uh progressively uh over these uh rock
epics. Let's go to the next slide.
Ah all right. So then life evolved in
the animal kingdom and when you look at
your body we left we left him home
today. He was very bad so we didn't
bring him
but I brought this instead.
This is my little animal.
I take him wherever I go.
I got it with me. So, I don't need my
teddy bear anymore.
You are my teddy bear, cutie paw.
Okay? So, I don't need to have guilt
about this physicality
because we were born with it, right?
As we watch the evolution of
consciousness over time, then you see
that it grows through the animal
kingdom. It's innate to a
three-dimensional linear
animal existence.
Without your animal, without the ego,
you wouldn't be here to feel guilty
about having an ego. Yeah.
>> You wouldn't have to worry about sin
because you wouldn't even be.
All right. So why label the animal
nature uh sin? Huh?
And thereby have to repress it and
project it onto others and then you have
to bomb the others because they're evil.
Evil America, evil England, evil Spain.
I mean, you know, it's going to be
endless, right?
That's repressed guilt projected out as
hatred on of others. You know, if you
own that your own animal within
yourself, you'll see in you as the
alligator that likes to chop up people,
the killer that likes to I mean, when
somebody cuts in in front of you in
traffic, you want to strangle the son of
a don't you? He deserves to die,
doesn't he? Blow his brains out.
That's what you'd like to do. Isn't that
effect?
Should you repress that and feel guilty
about it? No. You're supposed to do
that. Boy, how long would you be around
here if you didn't do that? You know,
you wouldn't have survived World War II
and all
waterfront dives all over the orient.
You know, you wouldn't be here.
So, we congratulate oursel that we have
evolved to the point where we can now
transcend just the limitation. So now
into this evolved animal
uh consciousness kept evolving and
birthed uh a locust for spiritual
evolution and we crossed over to
consciousness level 200. At 200 then
this condundolini energy begins to
transform us. Now we see life
differently. From 200 and up, the animal
part of us is no longer as
uh welcome. Well, from 200 and up now,
anger, rage, murderous thoughts are no
longer comfortable because it we become
recontextualized.
There's a major recontextualization at
level 200 and then the next major
recontextualization is at 500.
So as we merge over 200 now the the
animal nature is no longer as welcome
greed and all that. So we give it a bad
label. We give it a bad label. You know
all those labels should probably be
everything should be relabeled.
Instead agreed we just call it what?
Nibbleness.
Got to have this. Got to have got to
have got to have in order to stay alive
you got to have don't you? So all right
so we see then the evolution of
consciousness through the animal kingdom
and therefore you get an idea how the
ego grew spontaneously as a consequence
of evolution.
You see it the ego is a consequence of
the evolution of consciousness
doesn't come out of wickedness sin guilt
and evil. It comes just from the
hippopotamus, the whales, the dolphins,
you know, it grew out of of the
evolution of consciousness, the little
deer that are outside the window. And
see, then we see the every life becomes
relatively more benign, more benign, and
then it starts to get more and more
intelligent, more and more intelligent.
It can even conceptualize.
You get up to Alex. Alex can actually
think. Oops. And so can Coco. Uh, these
people can think. And these two people
here, kitties and dogs, uh, can love
without thinking. They don't need to
think.
The kitty purr at 500 and the dog's
wagging tail at 500.
And Coco uh, Coco the uh, trained
gorilla 405. So you see animaless then
and this of course is an animal. This is
protoplasm. This is protoplasm. The
thing here and it's living in and you
poke it, it bleeds.
It's protoplasm. Now protoplasm knows
that which is favorable to it and and it
knows through this enormous evolutionary
time that which is not favorable to
life.
Therefore, the kinesiologic test is
really almost like a protoplasmic
response. It's impersonal.
It goes weak in that which is enimicable
to life and goes strong in that which is
supportive of life. The higher the level
of consciousness, the more power
powerfully supportive of life it is.
So, let's go next. So, we discovered we
could calibrate everything that ever
existed. Uh, the evolution of
consciousness. We're going to finish all
the dactic stuff by the break. So, we're
going to talk faster.
The intellect, the prefrontal cortex now
emerges. See, the homminid arises
uh I don't care how many years ago it
was. Wasn't too recent. A long time ago.
Anyway, rises up. The hommininator rises
up on two feet on two two limbs instead
of four. Now when you what happens when
you stand up is you got two limbs you
don't need for locomotion. Wow. Now they
can be used for other things. Exploring
and information gathering and climbing.
And then you have the emergence of the
thumb. And now with the with the thumb
that can approximate, you have the
beginning of tools. The use of tools.
The use of tools then greatly supports
the evolution of the prefrontal cortex
as the homminid emerged. You see uh
ancient men calibrated around 80
Neanderthal men peaking men all these
folk all these folks
all these folks calibrated around 80 85.
In fact, at the time of the birth of
Buddha around 635 BC, uh mankind was at
90 at the time of Christ. It reached 100
uh 100 at the time of the birth of
Christ. Yes. And then slowly evolved
over the centuries to 190 where it
stayed for many centuries and then
jumped suddenly recently to 205.
The second coming of Christ to me
there's happened then in uh when the
consciousness level of mankind went from
190 to 205.
The consciousness of the Christ to me is
the presence of divinity as truth. So
when the consciousness level of mankind
went from 190 to 205,
the Christ consciousness now dominated
the earth and and no longer was it
dominated by the animal consciousness at
190.
190 by the way is the rel is the level
of moral relativism. Yeah.
So all right. So consciousness then
evolved and it became very I think the
most advanced time in human history was
uh uh in Greece ancient Greece about 350
BC and man it's really going down since
that time if you ask me
it was doing fine 350 BC and it's then
you know
gotten worse progressively all right so
the great uh minds then carried on the
tradition the intellectual tradition of
ancient Greece u their emphasis on truth
on the intellect on reason balance on
justice and of course all of you have
read the the great books of the western
world and here we see how consciousness
then evolved through the 400s
through the 400s I forget what
percentage of mankind is in the 400s but
it's not impressive in the United States
however this is very common very coming
uh because of the high educational
level,
high education. People talk about
poverty and peace and what to do about
all that. And uh I said the best thing
to do is educate people. And that was
corroborated by the recent history of uh
the Celtic Tiger,
you know, the the Irish economy.
>> Just the last few years that surged from
centuries of poverty, centuries. Susie
was just reading a book. What's the name
of that book? Uh
>> um
>> huh.
>> Anyway,
>> Angelina Ashes,
>> I think it's Angelina.
>> Angelina's Ashes. Yeah. Wow. What
poverty was really like, you know, uh
grinding poverty? Really? And uh and now
the Celtic Tiger is surging. Is now the
most successful economy in all of
Europe. Wow. after centuries of poverty,
how does it become the leading uh the
leading uh economy in Europe? Yeah.
Ireland has now jumped to the very top
of the European nations from poverty of
centuries and centuries of poverty. And
how did they do it? They did it by
restructuring.
And the restructuring was based on
education,
free college and free high school
education for everybody. Instantly they
went from poverty to the leading uh
economy in Europe. Wow. So the cure to
poverty then is to uh use our taxpayer
money and donations
and give everyone free education because
education automatically reduces the
birth rate because the cause of poverty
is overpopulation. Is it not?
There isn't any other cause other than
overpopulation.
Relativistic theories aside,
the too many people, if you can't afford
two kids and you got six, you got
poverty. Period. That's all. So anyway,
the more educated you are, the less more
responsibility and you tend to have only
as many children as you can actually
afford. Okay?
But I think that it's it's such a
dramatic recent example of what
education does. So this is the field of
education and we see that it is
enormously important the mid 400s and in
there of course is my favorite uh
philosophers of all time and uh when I
go back on the other side I'm looking
forward to hanging out with number of
them again
Socrates and all my friends
all my all my pals over there
will commiserate about the state of the
world. Huh? How about it?
Commiserate about the state of the
world. Yeah. So the theory of the you
know the principle of the absolute was
also a philosophic theory of Hegel
famous German philosopher of the fier
part of the 1800s.
The absolute
the absolute is what the moral
relativist hates. If you want to know
what the far left hates, it's the
absolute.
The absolute.
It would like to pre pretend there is no
such thing as truth. The truth is only
whatever you say it is and therefore is
purely subjective and has no reality.
Huh?
That takes you to calibration 190. It
doesn't take you quite as far as marks
because Markx perfected it. And of
course on all the calibrated levels of
the western world the only one that
stands out uh oddly is Karl Marx. And we
know that his propensity to divide
everything into perpetrator and victim
of course is the whole what happened as
the great cold war Mayo's China
um out of Marxism
uh brought about the death of probably
half a billion half a billion humans
you know consequently you see how
important knowing what a calibrated
level of consciousness is
this this level of consciousness This
destroyed 300 300 million Chinese
destroy destroyed people
by the multi-millions and continues to
do so. It's not called Marxism anymore.
They got a new label, but it's the same
same era of consciousness.
130.
All right. So we'll move on the
understanding of spiritual reality then
has what I really teach is called you
know devotional non-duality that's
title of the last book all the other
books are leading up to the final one
devotional non-duality
because the ultimate reality is spirit
the presence of the spirit the self with
a capital S the experiential
source to one's own existence is
nonlinear, cannot be defined, cannot be
proven, cannot be measured etc.
To define spiritual reality then
the way the mind thinks is in terms of
content and context and the content is
the event itself and this is the
situation.
This this is why we have situational
ethics.
Traditional religions, some of them
don't like situational ethics because
they think it can be abused as a copout.
Um it's correct in a certain way. If the
situation is such you're responsible
uh uh you're responsible but not
culpable. So
the situation doesn't really change that
you're responsible, but the degree to
which you're culpable.
If you run over somebody by accident,
that has a different culpability than if
you del deliberately uh shoot somebody
out of hatred and rage. Yeah. So the
context then uh spiritual reality
becomes more and more nonlinear.
nonlinear and finally it becomes the
field itself and the infinite field is
the infinite field of consciousness
itself.
All right. So we'll move on. So truth
cannot be defined.
An interviewer
from a leading uh
periodical in the world visit me a week
week ago. Yeah. and um represents sort
of an organization devoted to peace,
etc., etc., etc. And uh as as we got
through talking, you know, I I kept
saying to him, there's only one thing I
want you to get that peace is a is a
nonsensical concept,
idiotic word. It's a delusion. Everybody
walking around with flowers and praying
for peace. God, God help. Because peace
is not possible unless you can discern
truth from falsehood.
If you can't tell truth from falsehood,
if you don't know a messianic
narcissistic megalomaniac
from a antigous leader, your chances for
peace are zero. Forget the peace parades
and panning out handing out the things
for peace without knowing truth from
falsehood. But now mankind never had any
capacity to tell truth from falsehood.
Therefore, he's never had any peace
either. Consequently,
without the capacity to discern truth
from falsehood, peace is just a fancy
idea.
And most of these peace organizations,
you know, global peace and all they
calary at around 250 and all. Okay. So,
you know, that's sort of high, you know,
sort of teenage idealism. We should all
be at peace, right?
Now what?
Now what? So I'm more interested in the
practical. Uh for me, a peace
congregation would be served best by
having a having a lecture on the rising
economy of Ireland.
>> Hey.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. If you want to have peace, then
you got to get rid of poverty. And how
do you get rid of poverty? Through
education. And you know, you got to get
rid of overpopulation, which is again
education. Uh
So it's the how to as an ideal everybody
everybody votes for peace. I mean you
know doesn't mean anything
doesn't mean anything. All right.
The transition from the world of the
intellect which we are going to be
leaving by the break.
Uh here the reason it's important for
spiritual people is because of the
principle of uh uh when you go out of
the Newtonian paradigm. You see the cho
at 500 you jump to a different paradigm.
The 400s are uh explicable in Newtonian
terms of cause and effect, measurable,
calibratable, predictable.
But then you start getting into
nonlinear dynamics, the unpredictable,
and you go to subparticle physics and
the theory, you know, equals MC². You
end up then finally in quantum quantum
theory. The interesting thing about
quantum theory is the principle of
intention because the Heisenberg
principle you see uh so you go from the
existing state of the universe
um
explicable as the wave function by the
direct shreddinger equations and then by
intention you collapse the wave function
so that the potentiality becomes an
actuality which is exactly what I always
lecture about and the Heisenberg
principle then is the in is the
consequence of consciousness.
Now they talk about
once an experiment is looked at even
looked at it now it changes the outcome
and so far nobody has calibrated what is
the effect of the uh consciousness of
the observer
uh of the Heisenberg principle what is
the effect of that person's level of
consciousness
>> for some idiots to look at the
experiment it gives you a worse result
you
You write that
disprove kinesiology, right? Yeah.
>> So anyway,
what is the effect if the consciousness
level is high? Therefore, group prayer,
world prayer does have a powerful effect
because the potential is there and now
you need uh the intention of the
observer. Okay. So the attention of the
observer collapses the wave function uh
from and you can now recalibrate the
world and and different mathematical
terms and those are the durac equations.
So our transition from being reasonable
and logical then is through quantum
mechanics which says that intention
begins to change outcome. Intention
changes outcome
and therefore spiritual intention does
transform your life because it
transforms outcome.
The subjective experience of life of
people over 200 is completely different
than the people under 200. People don't
realize how different they are.
People have difficulty even
understanding what is the opposite of
spiritual integrity and truth.
What is the exact opposite?
All right. So this transforms at 200 the
condundalini energy comes in. We won't
spend any time on this uh today but this
demonstrates that brain function itself
changes that um the nonspiritually
oriented person the animal uh their
brain processes information in in an
animal way releasing adrenaline alarm
reaction
because it sees the thing and reacts
with an emotion.
All right,
over 200. Now the whole thing is slowed
down. The fast track is through your
etheric brain and through the prefrontal
cortex uh to the emotion. So the emotion
is more delayed more delayed. You have
to think about it for a second or you
have to take a second look at it. Uh you
have to process it. So the information
now is processed via the right brain. So
you have different physiologic
processes. you have different health
characteristics.
Below 200, you have certain problems and
over 200 you have different ones.
The the intention then is quite
powerful. And when I ran a big clinic,
we noticed certain doctors always got
good results and other doctors always
got lousy ones. Why was this?
Academically, they were the same. But
some doctors just had what whatever it
was, a caringness, a consideration, a
way of being with your patient. And so
people
uh physicians have a higher
consciousness calibration and have
different consequences. So that's the
trouble with the double blind
experiment. Double blind by done by who?
you know, you can't compare results
because some people have bad responses
and other people have good responses,
you know, and of course over the years I
had a lot of patients that stayed well
so long as I was breathing and seeing
them. So, I didn't want to quit practice
until they left the planet. So, I did.
The old guy I've talked about used to
come in with the oxygen tank, you know,
and ask me for a light for a cigarette,
you know, I'd say, "Aren't we gonna blow
up?" He said, "No, I do it all the
time." I said, "Okay." So,
he finally left
a couple of guys. So, I hung in until
they all left, you know, because it was
their relationship, you know, with that
kept them going, you know, kept them
going, the positive transference. So uh
science you see is eliminates humanism
and science doesn't realize and when
it's misapplied in in clinical in the
clinical realm because in the clinical
realm uh the amount of humanness and how
it's expressed profoundly alters uh
consequences and results okay uh because
you're shifting people over to this when
I listen to the side of the the
advertisements on TV there was one last
night I couldn't even believe it on
premarin and it tells you. Why these
drug companies put advertisements on the
public TV is beyond me, you know.
Anyway, they're talking about primit.
says it can cause heart disease, death,
stroke, blindness,
mental deterioration and total insanity
and convulsions
plus bleeding and vaginal this and that
and breast and cancer
and total blindness and uh and stro and
a strokes you know and I thought ask and
then he says and then ask your doctor
about it.
I'd rather die whatever I got than take
whatever does all that.
I don't know why they do that. I mean
>> I mean the doctor knows that and with
the individual patient you contextualize
it in terms of the risk benefit ratio
and whether in your case and what the
options are the way you just put it on
like that information I can't believe
any patient you know taking permanent I
wouldn't let my wife take permanence and
she came over to the doctor the thing
for permanent I'd tear it up and
take that I'll kill you kill that
I don't know. The world gets dumber all
the time when I listen to the evening
news. I I don't believe it. Okay. So
that's um
the atheric brain. Now you process
things differently. Your basic
physiology is different. So the capacity
to get well and heal and respond and to
help others is profoundly transformed
due to this energy. We'll move to the
next one. the uh and the rate of
happiness
as the condolini energy rises uh you can
see the rate of happiness uh is
conccommatant.
So as far as uh moral relativism that
handout sociological theories which
weaken people are always trying to put
the blame on out there out there instead
of taking responsibility yourself. The
greater you take self- responsibility,
the lower the rate of unemployment, the
lower the rate of poverty, the greater
the rate of happiness and criminality
goes down. You see that those are not
sociologic phenomena,
you know, at all.
The relationship is completely almost
100% with calibrated level of
consciousness itself.
Therefore, one reason moral relativism
is weak is because it it falls into the
dualism of causality.
There's an evil something out there
causing an unwanted consequence here.
It's thinking in terms of causing and
effect victim and perpetrator. So long
as you think that, you'll be weak. So
uh
you see the level of consciousness this
is criminality. This is criminality.
Uh this is also al-Qaeda and various
things that are below 50. Uh Wahabism.
Wahhabism.
Wahhabism came out of a guy who
calibrated. We did it over and over
again. I said I can't believe the guy
was that low. It's not possible. Uh but
he was
um I think I'm 20 or something. Amazing.
>> 30.
>> 30. Yeah. Jesus Christ. So here you have
a thief of
uh religious truth runs off with a
offshoot
and he calibrates at 30. Good God. So
all right. So here you see uh a
consequence.
We know that coming out of prison uh
that the most effective ways the only
ways out of prison that have shown any
kind of benefit are through 12step
faith-based programs
uh which are of course illegal
and that's supposed to have religion and
public property or something right the
thing that helps them is not going to be
illegal right however one thing is legal
dogs so you see the criminals who
uh devote themselves to training. Seeing
eye dogs have a very high recovery rate.
Some will even stand stay in prison
after their sentence is over to finish
working with this dog. So you see what a
prof profound influence you the dog's
heart at 500. The dog's wagging tail.
The dedication to something other than
yourself, the well-being of an other
then is transformative. Now these are
hardened criminals. the worst. You can
take the worst criminals and have them
train seen eye dogs and something like
35% will recover. I mean, that's like
35% of people with advanced fatal cancer
recovering. I mean, that's just a
miracle in itself. And the fact they're
willing to stay in prison, you after
their sentence is over to finish working
with this dog. What a profound
transformation that is. What a profound
transformation.
All right, we'll go to the next one.
Huh?
>> Yeah. Three minutes. She says
I trying to get
this is too complicated. We won't go
into that.
>> I'm watching.
>> All right. All right. So, all right. So,
um,
yes. Well, we'll we'll come back to
this. We'll come back to this. We'll
come back to this because we're going to
have a break in a few minutes. So, I
just want everybody to get that little
handout on moral relativism. It's the
weakness of our society. If you
understand it, you'll understand um
political contentiousness, what it's all
about. You'll you'll grasp the
intellectual ideational basis of it. And
once you see what that is, it at least
makes it clear. It's based on the
presumption that there is no absolute.
Therefore, there is no answerability.
Therefore, anything is just what I want
it to be or think it is. It means
there's no morality, no ethics, no basis
for intellectual integrity
or even for the law. And of course, this
has it inroads
especially in the ninth circuit court of
appeals where you know truth is whatever
you want it to be however you define it.
Yeah. So the uh constitution you know
says free speech. All right. So what is
speech?
Is that speech?
This is speech.
Is this speech?
No, that's not speech. Speech comes out
of here. Huh? All right. So if I
interpret free speech to mean free
expression,
free expression.
That's the downside. You see, free
expression now is anything I want it to
be. Baby,
>> we can have sex in the park. I'm free.
Pedophilia is okay. Anything
goes
because there is no morality, there is
no ethics and there is no truth.
Consequently, whoever can shout the
loudest wins the game. Yeah. The end of
society. It's really the end of society.
And of course is exactly what happened
in Rome. The fall of Roman Empire uh
collapsed from within. Therefore,
uh, al-Qaeda's job is really done for
them already by college professors
everywhere who profess
mar.
It's done more cruy and slowly and
painfully
uh through moral relativism because your
life becomes progressively degenerate
and with degeneracy goes the
consequences of the lower calibrated
levels of consciousness. So, it's really
more cruel. Be more kind to just blow
them up and get it over with in a
second, you know.
All right. So, we won't forget
September. What was the date of uh we're
all going to pray? Unity.
>> Tom Zinder. I told Tom Zinder, the
president CEO of Unity that I would tell
the group and about it. And they're
doing a research project there at Unity
on the efficacy of prayer. And of
course, noetic science is also joined
them. So, we'll join them. And u So, you
marked your calendar, September 9th. So,
we're going to take a break and I don't
want anybody to think about anything at
all until we get back.
>> September 8th.
>> 20 minutes.
>> What?
>> September 8th.
>> Huh?
>> September 8th. Sorry.
September 8th is the day we'll all join
with unity worldwide. Yeah,
>> as we go along, we're going to finish
the dedactic material and cover the
levels of consciousness. We're going to
talk more about meditation and things
and as we progress, I want to leave more
time for discussion with the audience.
Um, we did one for unity not long ago in
which I just wandered through the
audience and we had a um,
whatchamacallit that we gave the people
and that worked extremely well. Sort of
wandering around kind of a thing. Can we
do that, Robert?
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. Can we do it today?
>> We're not ready for it, but we'll try.
>> Yeah. It's just a different experiment.
All right. So, spiritual work, it has to
do with purification.
People say, "How come I feel worse since
I got involved in spiritual work?"
It's because the overall context now is
different. Uh the overall context is to
transcend limitation.
So once you commit to reaching the state
of enlightenment or advanced levels of
consciousness or unconditional love
whatever works
you started the process of purification
and the process of purification brings
up all which needs to be purified
right
the dark night of the soul. So when you
decide you're going to be loving towards
everybody,
your hatred for your great uncle Louie
comes up.
How he screwed you out of a pair of
tires and never gave him back.
So it doesn't mean you are worse. It
means that you are going through the
process of purification.
I wanted to say a little bit before I
get carried away with whatever subject I
get carried away with. Uh
I want to discover uh discuss meditation
styles and you know I contrasted
meditation and contemplation.
Contemplation is a way of being in the
world and um it serves you all the time.
Meditation is rather specific. It tends
to become limited in time and place.
It often starts out with great
enthusiasm
and then diminishes because the baby's
diaper needs changing. The phone is
ringing and uh there goes your mitt and
there so sitting cross-legged and go and
doing and stuff and and shaving your
head and all and wearing sandals and
shorts, you know, will only carry you so
far. And then you got to become that in
the world, which is a whole different
ballgame. So, you know, pick a phrase
for the day and live with it. 91st
Psalm, any any great teaching, uh, and
live with it. You know, I used to
contemplate one, uh, sentence a month,
uh, the 91st Psalm. Um, because you you
you live with that and as you live with
that, it re it becomes self-revealing.
It's not one of discovery, it's one of
revelation.
Instead of being yang, you become very
yin. So the commitment to spiritual
endeavor is a very yang kind of a
commitment.
You know in my own case it was including
death itself. Whatever it took to get
there which took me to the depths of
hell.
But the drive was yang unstoppable.
Nothing physical death. The terrors of
hell nothing stood back. It was very
yang. But then the process as it
unfolded was very very yin.
And as Dr. Colinbach said to me the
other day, uh he says it's ultra yin.
Yes.
Okay. So the commitment is ultra yang,
but the process is ultra lin yin. to
step back and surrender and the along
this now that you've stated what your
goal is
the process you've triggered the process
then the process of purification
you surrender everything to God as as it
arises
condemning yourself for past faults
wallowing in guilt self-punitive blame
is cured by will being willing to
surrender that judgment to God because
at the time you did the best that you
could do knowing what you knew at the
time being what you were at the time and
of course now you would choose
differently
but then isn't now and you aren't you
weren't then what you are now so it's
difficult to get by self judgment unless
you're willing to surrender it to God
Yeah. So that's how you bypass some of
the difficult things that come up. And
when we get to the dualities, we'll
speak of them more specifically.
Sometimes people act about ask about
meditative styles. You know, I was a
consultant to every kind of a religious
organization back east including the Zen
monastery. I myself was a member of the
first Zen monastery in New York, first
Zen Institute in New York and did Zen
meditation etc.
I'm very familiar with all kinds of
meditation meditations.
Uh
there's really three simple styles.
There's all kinds of books. There's
whole libraries of meditation. There's
whole spiritual disciplines that go back
for centuries.
Uh but there they fall into really three
categories. And I believe in
demystifying them. Demystifying them.
the simplest meditative style.
Uh and I meditated an hour twice a day
for 20 years and then came out west and
meditated uh like all day every day for
some years.
There's a simple meditative style you
can do anytime anywhere.
Uh it if you are able to close your
eyes, don't do this one while you're
driving.
I put this label on the bottom of this.
Do not do while driving.
Close eyes. And uh if you if you merely
close your eyes, which I'm doing right
now, uh you'll notice that you don't
have total darkness. There's little tiny
uh specks of light. If you just close
your eyes, you'll notice there's little
tiny specks of light.
uh those are called um spheronmes uh
little light impulses in the nerves uh
itself. If you close your eyes and just
look straight ahead, you'll see a black
dark field and in it are a million
little speckles of light sort of varying
in different color and
uh etc. Is that so? Anybody don't see
that?
Okay, they're there.
Just got to notice that maybe you got a
mental thing that when you close your
eyes, everything turns black. It does
not turn black. It does not turn black.
No, those little spherronomes or spheros
something or others
look like little tiny little bitty
things. All right. So if you do nothing
but breathe quietly and uh look at them
and do nothing but look at them.
Do nothing but look at them.
As you look at them
you uh you're not interested in what the
mind is saying. It's sort of irrelevant.
You you become eventually emerge with
the little light spec spectacles and you
transcend thought and thinkingness.
You enter a silent
underneath thinkingness is a profound
field of silence.
99% of the mind is silent. Only 1% is
talking.
As you so you merge with the field, you
become one with the little speckles
which are nonverbal, non-intellectual,
and you're already out of the
thinkingness. You're already beyond 400.
You're into phenomena. So you become one
with the phenomena. You're witnessing a
phenomena.
So even as I'm talking now, you close
your eyes and don't pay attention to the
speaker.
You just look at the little tiny specks
and do nothing but become
merge with the specs.
As you do that, eventually the total
context
uh how should we say the whole context
of your beingness will begin to expand
will begin to expand. There's no longer
a me looking at a them.
The lookingness, the experiencing
is a total oneness.
You can very quickly bypass duality,
thinkingness, and thinking mind. Very
simple. You can do it on the bus, on the
subway.
You can do it in the doctor's waiting
room. You can do it any place.
You can do it just when you got nothing
else to do. Uh it's the simplest med and
the fastest meditation style I know. If
you're going to be conscious of anything
else other than the little specules of
light inside your eyelids, the only
other thing would be the be be one with
the breathing. So you can be one with
the breathing and then the spicules of
light and then forget the breathing and
you become one with the light. uh
instantly not instantly but relatively
rapidly your whole state of
consciousness will expand and you may go
through certain phases which you come to
recognize every time you do it I used to
call uh shortly after you start it you
hit a thing in which the whole field
turns an intense blue I would say that's
the stage of the blue then beyond the
blue is another and you will it will be
as though you're going through various
dimensions
more and more expanded dimensions
of the
of of the field of consciousness itself.
See, because you're starting from the
witness observer and then you go past
the phenomenology of the witness
observer uh to the infinite field of
consciousness itself which is totally
nonlinear and has no confines.
It's a very rapid way to go beyond
anything.
doesn't take
uh much to do it. You can do it anytime,
any place. And you go into sort of a
bliss state.
And uh people get annoyed that you're
always closing your eyes when you're
talking to me. Stop closing your eyes
when you talk to me.
It's because you go into a bliss state.
So you find yourself blissing out in
this state all the time. You know, it's
very fast and easy.
Then there's the way through the mind.
The way through the mind
is more classic meditation
is uh witnessing the phenomena of the
mind. You see thoughts arising and
falling away. And we've talked about
that in prior lectures
that the thinkingness what you think is
thinking isn't thinking anyway. It's
mentalizing.
Mentalizing is not thinking. People say
I was thinking all day. They weren't
thinking about anything. I say to you,
"Well, what brilliant new think did you
come up with?" They haven't got any.
They were foraging through the past,
anticipating the future, images of all
kinds of things. They M&M's off
television, wagging dogs tails,
horrible pictures they just got on the
day news. It's
not thinking, that's imaging. So this
computer
TV screen. So what you then then do in
classic meditation sit down cross-legged
do the whole deal and um stop eating
meat too. See and become a vegetarian
and live on brown rice. That helps the
whole deal.
Take off clothes. Live on brown rice.
Sit cross-legged. Get your head shaved.
All right. So then you you're witnessing
the phenomena of the mind. You're not
witnessing thinkingness.
And the purpose of it is to withdraw
into the witness observer. You become
the witness of the phenomena instead of
the subject. And as you do that, as you
move into witness observer,
you it suddenly dawns on you there is no
me doing the thinking. Not am I not only
am I not the mind and the thinking there
really isn't any thinking going on
there's mentalization and I am not even
the mentalization the sense of is
withdrawn
from the content of the mind as it plays
across the television screen
that's the way through the mind there's
a third way which I can't Remember
what did I say? Don't forget to mention
uh
three meditative styles. I don't
remember what they were now, but they
must have. You can't become enlightened
without them.
The mantra
>> yeah contemplation uh a mantra you know
has
we calibrate them they can be quite high
the difficulty with the mantra is that
you sometimes you're only with it when
you're doing the mantra and the downside
of mantra is self-hypnosis you go into
an autohypnotic you go into an altered
state of consciousness rather than an
advanced state of consciousness.
Yeah.
As you can any kind of repetitive
movement and spiritual religion
historically is full of it. Ringing of
bells, cranking of prayer wheels,
anything that's repetitious and
repetitious and repetitious and
repetitious and repetitious
may take you into an altered state of
consciousness. It's an altered state of
consciousness is not a spiritual state.
You can go into an alpha state with a
you know alpha wave training and various
techniques. Um
the consequence of the mantra then is
based on your intention of what you
expect it to do for you etc. Also the
calibrated level of that particular
mantra. The one we do here uh from the
Sanskrit
lotus sutra calibrates around 700.
So what you preserve out of that is the
state of consciousness that prevails and
not the mantra itself. So that you can
discontin the mantra and the condition
prevails. You know condition prevails.
The contemplative lifestyle is
um
a way of being in the world where you
become
uh you are that which you're holding in
mind. You see, you surrender
that it already is a reality and you
become that. So the contemplative
lifestyle is not focused.
Don't try it when you're don't when you
first started, don't try it driving.
That's a label I'm putting on the
bottom. Tell your lawyer said he said do
not do this while driving.
Do not put electric cord in your mouth.
You know
the meditative lifestyle is one of
floating awareness, not focused. It's a
floating awareness
uh without intention. It's not focused.
What it does is put you in the witness
observer. See the witness observer.
In the beginning, you are part of the
movie. You're you're the subject. It's
you're the hero or the heroine of the
subject of the drama going on. You are
the the star. And you move out of being
the star and being part of the movie.
You become the witness observer.
And then eventually you you notice that
the witness observer is impersonal. If
you lead a contemplative lifestyle, you
realize that mentation, awareness and
all these things are phenomena that are
happening of their own. There isn't any
you doing that at all.
The witnessing the phenomena
as you become
the context
the witnessing awareness passing
phenomena is happening autonomously
you don't decide when you get up in the
morning I think I'll be aware what's
going on today I mean right awarenessing
witnessing
is not a personal eye so as you move
from identification with the movie my
dog Rover and my ex-mother-in-law and
what they did to me and all this
melodrama.
As you pull back, you become the witness
observer that the mind thinks that way.
You stop calling it my mind or me. It's
the mind just like this is the body.
See, this is the body assigned to me for
this trip. I haven't got much to say
about it, do I? Except be friendly with
it. I try to be very friendly with the
body. It doesn't cooperate at all times.
But
that's my assignment. While you're here,
Dave, took take care of this. Okay.
Thank you, sir. I'll do my best.
And you're responsible for it while
you're here. Oh.
Contemplative then is
you with withdraw into the witness
observer of phenomena and it becomes
more and more impersonal until finally
the duality recedes and the totality of
the oneness uh shines forth of its own
radiance.
Uh there's no me witnessing that. No me
observing that. Witnessing observing
doesn't have a personal pronoun. It's
only a phenomena. It's a quality of
consciousness. So you withdraw from
identifying a mei as the body or the
mind or the feelings and withdraw. So by
meditation and contemplation then you
withdraw from identification with the
body and the mind. You become the
witness and finally you are the that
which is aware of the witness. You
become awareness itself.
And the phenomena of awareness itself
then is unlimited. And therefore that's
a way to transcend
identification of self with mind, body
and uh and emotion. Anybody got any
question about that? Simple enough.
I think that was number three. I don't
know.
Anybody got any question? You can shout
it out and I'll handle it. All right,
we'll go back to the dactic because
Yeah, go ahead.
>> I notic when I get into that blue field
that you talked about, I get frightened
about
>> the field Lou.
>> Yes. Uh any of these meditative styles
will may take you through various uh
phenomenologic changes.
Also, you'll feel an emergence of
context. No matter which style you do,
all of a sudden you'll notice that the
cons context is suddenly enlarged
and it there can be a great feeling of
uh uh joy at it. There can also be
consternation.
Any meditative style, the expansion of
the overall context. Now in ordinary
life, you don't realize that you're
limiting the context of your
experiential
uh life at all. But in meditation, you
begin to become aware that there are
levels of expansion of the overall
field. You remember we did this morning
content and field. You're not aware
usually a field because you're so
focused on on the comedy going on there.
But as you become more of the field, uh
then you'll feel yourself just suddenly
with no warning. Wow. It's very there's
enormous expansion you know expansion of
context and the sense of self shifts to
the field shifts to the field
and then your friends say why do you
always have your eyes closed all the
time when we're having lunch
because you go into that field.
Yeah. All right. Um
this is correlation of the levels of
consciousness and the rate of happiness.
Uh we did it from various places. Time
magazine about six months ago had a
whole issue on happiness. It was quite
interesting and we had one calibration
set from there and then one set that we
had done oursel.
You see uh why should I go through all
the work of spiritual endeavor and
looking at myself and self-examination
and good god all that stuff um because
here here's the level of consciousness
uh and the logarithm of it and here is
the percent of happiness happiness I
don't think you can pursue spiritual
work just because you want to be happy
it's like going to this because you want
to be rich. Everybody wants to be rich.
That doesn't make you rich. Uh
the the reason to transcend the levels
is you see the the enormous shift here.
Uh people down here, I don't know how
they survive. They calibrate at
4% are happy.
Uh you see down here the level of
hatred. This is the levels of the
Taliban. These people, the terrorists,
they live and the same with chronic
criminals. They live down here. Uh, I
guess if you're not happy, it's not too
hard to blow up other people, but if
you're happy, it makes it really
difficult, isn't it?
Uh,
chronic grief at 75.
Uh, some people get happy because of the
suffering they extract. People learn how
to extract satisfaction out of suffering
itself. And some people make a life of
suffering. The chronic martyr
um the chronic person who's always
feeling insulted. The person is very
sensitive. Everything is insults them.
Everything is in the front.
All right. As you move up to fear, you
see the calibrated level at 10%. Anger.
Uh we we get up to 12% of people in
anger are happy
because you swell up with anger and you
feel a certain sense of satisfaction
that you're scaring people
of anger is to intimidate isn't it?
Okay. Uh pride at 175
uh 22% are happy.
those who are happy uh do so for very
they've learned how to extract a sense
of satisfaction.
So we didn't ask whether it's actual
happiness or subjective uh states of
happiness or whether it's their uh
opinion whether they're happy or not. So
there's a lot more can be done on on
this
uh
a new book just came out I got yesterday
by uh the guy who wrote bias. Who wrote
bias? Uh
Goldberg. Bernie Goldberg. Yeah, Bernie
Goldberg wrote a book called Bias. He's
got a new one called out the the hundred
people who are screwing up America.
Anyway, those 100 people calibrated
exactly 175.
Those 100 people. He's got a chapter on
each one. It's hilarious. Hilarious sad,
you know. Anyway, 20 20 22% of people uh
then are unwilling to give up pride
because those who are surviving in it
are making a living at it and u
it's self- serving. So this is a
difficult one to get across. So in
America 49% of the people uh transcend
this level at 200 uh in the world only
15%.
So the line should really be like right
right here. But anyway, so here we have
half the people in America. Half the
people in America get to this level. Uh
and at level 200,
uh about half the people are happy.
So half the people get here and half the
people who get here are happy. So
uh the level of courage that's personal
responsibility
and uh the rate of happiness goes up at
neutral which is okay if it goes this
way and it's okay to go that way it's a
very comfortable way to be uh 60% are
happy when you add the energy of
willingness to that neutral is like kami
kamsa I don't get this job I get another
one what's the big deal you know I mean
it's very comfortable
Neutral people are easy to get along
with. They won't help you carry out the
garbage. You got to get the willingness
for that one.
Neutral is okay if you struggle with it.
They'll stand there and watch you.
They don't feel guilt that they're not
helping you. They don't feel compelled
that they must help you. Neutral is a
small place to be.
be better to have your neighbors at
willingness though
at willingness you have a positive uh
input now and all close to 70%.
Acceptance then is a very great step.
This is responsibility. You accept the
responsibility for all that happens. You
realize that you are the source of the
power not out there.
By the time you reach reason about 80%
of people are reasonably happy. Can you
hear me? Okay. Is this machine working
here?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, okay. All right. It seems like it's
wiggling around in the air or something.
It's doing something on its own.
>> You need smaller ears or big ears? I
don't know. I used to know somebody
could wiggle their ears like Yeah, I can
wiggle my ears a little bit. Yeah,
this is America 421.
approximately 79% of the people uh you
know who reach this level doesn't mean
79% of the people in America are happy
but the people who themselves reach the
level of reason and logic
uh love the level jumps to close to 90%.
At joy it's practically 100%. And of
course at ecstasy it's 100%.
Now I hear somebody talking out there.
Who's that?
Oh, that's me. Okay.
All right. So, yes.
So, the we see it reflected in the the
inner state of joy and happiness and of
course eventually peace at 600. You
transcend all that and you
>> okay
>> hit the level called peace.
>> Hold on. I want to Okay, there you go.
>> Okay. That wiggle waggle thing there.
Okay.
Are we okay now? Yes.
>> You keeps moving.
>> I'm not moving.
>> Did you see me moving? I didn't move.
>> There's not enough sticker on it. What
you need is some uh
>> tape. Scotch tape. I got it.
>> Okay.
All right, let's go on to the next one.
>> All right, so
uh we always hit this one because um
what time do we take break for lunch?
>> Uh 12:30.
>> Oh, okay. All right. I I always include
this one. So many people fall by the
wayside. They fall by the wayside due to
ignoring these basic dictims. how to
differentiate an integrous spiritual
teacher, teaching organization,
enterprise, uh, from one that that is
less than that. And there's, you know,
there's a lot of them. They're very,
very common. We're not talking about
atypical.
You know, we get letters, pathetic
letters from people that have been
brainwashed by cults from all over the
country. Uh, how do we get out of this?
How how do we get out of this? Because
sometimes, you know, you get threatened
if you try to leave. You know, we'll put
a real rattlesnake in your mailbox or
something. They take it they take it
hard take it pretty hard when you go to
try to leave them. There was a local
guru that sold everybody suit everybody
that came out here with them.
Got them all to leave their enterprise
baggies. Come out here, start a
community. They turn around suit them
all. I mean, you know what I'm saying?
These were intelligent, highly educated,
successful people. Uh so the downside is
denial that it can't happen to you.
All right. So we we kept it impersonal.
We just stated certain principles and I
try to bring it up on each lecture at
least for a quick run through
that these principles uh are reliable.
You know we calibrated them all. they're
like 100% true and uh
it you can bypass all the um
detractions. The detractions are quite
heavy in our society. Many may we get a
lot of periodicals that look like
they're uh they look like they're divine
for sexual seduction. It'll tell you u
um the spiritual evolutionary journal.
And here's a girl half stripped and
she's
looks like Paris Hilton or something on
the cover. And I say, "What has this got
to do with spirituality?" I don't know.
But you'll notice a certain slickism and
a certain artistic style.
Uh I forget the name of that artist. I
think Brock knows the name of the
artist. They follow a certain kind of
very seductive style.
uh you know a spirituality doesn't have
to do with seduction and allure and
glamour although it's packaged and sold
that way it's very often packaged and
sold. Uh so spiritual truth is not
something that should be packaged as
alluring and attractive and seductive.
Uh because the energy field then what
they're doing is manipulating people
through the energy field of glamour. You
know glamour was a very famous book
written by
>> huh
>> Alice
>> Alice Bill yeah back about 1950 I think.
Anyway, uh we've referred to it before
that the glamour then is a specific
energy that you project onto things that
make them seem attractive and and
desirable.
And of course, every adolescent crush
discovers
uh that terrible boy that you thought
was walking, you know, on
six weeks later you hate him. He's a
creep. So, how could that be that you're
willing to die for him, defy your
parents, leave home, quit college uh for
this relationship and six months later
he's a creep?
Is it the same guy? Is it the same girl?
What has happened to their head? You
know, it's because of the glamour of
seduction and allure. All right. So, the
one thing about truth is that it's
always true. And we're going to talk
about We don't have time. We'll go into
it. I want to go into the void this
afternoon. Uh because not many teachers
go into the void.
It's a one-way trip, folks.
We'll take it together.
But before anybody is up to what we're
up to, disappear into the void
and they can't catch us there.
There's nobody there to catch.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
Hallelu.
Halle.
Hallelu
Hallelujah.