himself. Chipmunks. Hi. Chipmunks. They call these little chipmunks.
How you doing, sir?
Uh-huh. Hi, love. Hello. Yes? Hello?
Hi.
Hi, Doc.
How you doing?
Let's see.
Good morning.
How you doing, Doctor?
Guten Morgen, mein Herr.
Mein Guten, Herr.
Guten Morgen.
Hi.
Hello, Guards, everybody.
Look at all the people here.
Excuse me.
Good morning.
Good morning, Guards.
Hello.
You've got to be careful. They're out to get you.
Knock them over. Just knock them over. They're smaller than you.
If they're smaller than you, knock them over.
And if they're taller than you, bite their ankle.
How you doing, Doc?
They're smaller than you, knock them over.
They're bigger than you, bite their ankle.
That's my technique.
What do you do?
That's how to win in the world.
Hi.
Are we turned on? Is this thing turned on?
You're on now.
I'm on now. Okay. All right.
Thank you, sweetheart.
Hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey.
Here's the big guy.
When they get this big, you can only bite their ankle.
You can't knock them down.
I know.
We brought Chelsea with us today.
Thank you.
Good morning, sir.
Hi, hi.
How you doing?
Oh, yes.
T.U.S.
It's me, too.
I'm familiar face.
Oh, hi. Hello. Hello. Hello.
Hi.
Good to see you.
Hey.
Hello.
Yeah.
Oh, somebody got in line twice.
That's no fair.
Hi.
Oh, yes.
God bless you.
Hi, Doc.
Oh, my goodness.
They let anybody in here.
Doc, so good to see you.
The Nevada crew.
Thank you.
Hi.
How you doing, sir?
Good to see you, Doc.
Hi.
Did we make it?
I get to shake it twice.
Well, we did make it.
Let's see.
Okay.
Can I do an announcement real quick?
Sure.
Are you ready for me to do the announcements?
I guess so.
You're on, so watch it.
Good morning.
I see a lot of new faces and a lot of familiar faces and it's always nice to see all of
you come out, especially in this heat to Arizona.
I'm just here to tell you a little bit about the schedule.
The schedule is we'll have a break at 1115.
There will be a lunch break and a lunch break at 1130.
And I'm going to introduce you to the next three guests.
So, how are you going to do your lunch break?
We're going to have lunch break at 1130.
Are you ready for lunch?
We're going to start the lunch break.
Okay.
So, I'm going to introduce you to the next three guests on the menu.
And I'm going to introduce you to the next three guests on the menu.
at 11.30, and we'll resume at, or 12.30, I'm sorry, we'll resume at 11.30, it'll be a lunch break at 12.30, and lunches will be from 12.30 to 2. I ask that you turn off your cell phones, please, because that does interfere with the lecture, and we won't have Nico here today, he's attending his class reunion, 12 people graduated in this class,
and they only have one every 10 years, so, he wanted to attend the class reunion, he didn't know he'd be here the next 10 years to do it, so, and without you, this is my husband, Dr. Hawkins, and I got all dolled up for today, all dolled up, today the lecture is on, I can't remember what it was, serenity, oh,
it's helped by divine sedation, and so, how many people are new today, oh, my goodness, grace, it's me, all right, so, our style has been to recapitulate the basics for the people who are new,
also for the review by people who have been,
here before, and each time you re-review it, you sort of get a different understanding, and then we go on to some new presentation,
characteristically, we start out the lecture from the end of the lecture, and move back to the beginning,
because if you get the ending, you don't need to pay attention during the lecture, you get snoozed,
the main impediment to a group such as this,
is the impediment to a group such as this,
and very few people in our society transcend 499, the lecture,
very few people transcend the identification with mind, which calibrates in the 400s,
and spiritual reality really becomes emergent and dominant at consciousness level 500,
so 4% of the population ever gets to consciousness level 500,
0.4% ever gets to unconditional love at 540,
unconditional love is a very practical goal for people in this domain,
it's reachable, and even though the 0.4% only reaches it,
it is reachable by people who are spiritually aligned,
so the 0.4%, we never calibrated it, but,
it's probably made up primarily of people in classes like this,
and spiritually dedicated people around the world,
so unconditional love is really the crux of most religions,
the avoidance of sin, the alignment with unconditional love,
and then begins the transformation of consciousness,
in which things begin to appear quite differently,
and you sort of go on automatically,
automatic, automatic from that point on.
At level 600, you transcend the linear domain,
and you begin to understand and experience things,
that phenomena are occurring in a different way,
so the limitation of the intellect is its belief in causality,
causality, yeah, there's a this causing a that,
that's the whole basis of the,
argument of evolution, you know, and creationism,
and that argument is due to the dichotomy of dualistic thinking,
with this causing a that, if you transcend that,
you see quite clearly, and obviously, that evolution is creation,
I mean, duh, I wrote that note to Time Magazine,
but they didn't print it, letters to the editor,
and I purposely left duh in there,
I've written them erudite things in the past,
and they skipped it, so I thought, well, duh,
might get their interest, no, it didn't,
there's so much gain on either side, you know what I mean,
the world suffers, we don't need more freedom of speech, folks,
we need freedom from speech,
all right, to transcend then the limitation of causality,
the Newtonian paradigm of a this causing a that,
I'm not putting it down, all the wonders of modern science and medicine,
the great benefits to mankind have arisen out of science,
and logic, and reason, so we're not putting it down,
we're saying that for people who are aligned with reaching enlightenment,
then, it would be a stopping off place,
in which we see its great gift and its great benefit,
but we are so far not limited,
in our understanding of reality to the intellect,
in reality, the way things come about, including creation,
is that potentiality emerges as an actuality,
when conditions are appropriate,
what you're seeing is emergence,
this thing has the potentiality to emerge as that,
which then subsequently has the capacity to emerge and transform,
so you're witnessing
continuous emergence and transformation,
nothing is starting from nothing and then ending up as complete,
everything is in a process,
and you begin,
if you lead a contemplative lifestyle,
a contemplative lifestyle in which you're aligned with the field
rather than the content of the field,
this becomes an apparent phenomena,
you begin to witness that everything is spontaneously
and effortlessly,
becoming its potential as an actuality,
now you understand,
evolution and creation,
that evolution then,
is the way creation appears,
because,
what is sequential is the witnessing,
because you witness it, witness it, witness it,
you set it up in a time frame,
and then you add causality,
of a this causing a that,
because it precedes it,
doesn't mean that it causes it,
it's the preceding stage is not the cause of the subsequent stage,
potentiality is innate within the essence,
and then it unfolds,
is that clear,
yes,
it's pretty simple isn't it,
duh,
each thing is emerging,
so each potentiality within us then,
manifests,
and it does so,
when it's energized by intention,
so the whole process is,
speeded up by intention,
that's the power of intention,
Wayne Dyer's book,
Power of Intention,
is a,
the whole book is addressed to that specific,
specific aspect,
which we link,
with the Heisenberg principle,
so that you can be spiritual,
and same time,
respectively scientific,
and,
if somebody puts you down for being spiritual,
you tell them,
look I'm just applying the Heisenberg principle,
pardon me,
if I apply the Heisenberg principle,
to my life,
and the world,
and what do you understand,
by E equals times C squared,
that's your counter argument,
and what do you understand,
I can see Einstein getting emails saying,
I disagree with E equals MC squared,
kind of emails I get,
I disagree with it,
well you may,
that's freedom of speech,
from which we need protection,
so each one of us then represents,
an infinite potentiality,
and this world is,
perfect,
for bringing forth,
our potentiality as an actuality,
this brings up a doubt,
about wanting to change the world,
there are many people,
with placards and parades,
who want to change the world,
you would have to first understand,
what is the purpose of the world,
and what is the meaning of the world,
et cetera,
before you decide you want to change it,
so,
this is sort of like a jungle gym,
where we acquire gymnastic skills,
this is the maximum karmic opportunity,
where you have everything,
from the highest to the lowest,
thrown into juxtaposition,
and now,
you have the option at all times,
of choosing a this or a that,
the leading edge of the ego,
which I call the experiencer,
is constantly confronted with,
choosing a this or choosing a that,
it has to,
that's the way it's built,
because the emergence of life,
on this planet then,
began in a very,
very primitive form,
and so we like to recontextualize,
the evolution of the ego,
because it eliminates the downside,
of traditional religion,
traditional religion has had a,
great beneficial impact,
it's downside is that,
the ego,
and the animal nature,
becomes vilified,
because it becomes vilified,
and labeled as sin,
et cetera,
man then has to repress it,
say,
oh I don't have any of that,
and then project it onto the world,
I'm not cruel,
I'm not savage,
I'm not vicious,
et cetera,
it's the world,
so,
by making a,
in Freudian terminology,
ego alien,
in other words,
not acceptable,
what happens is,
the downside of our,
animal nature,
gets repressed,
when it gets repressed,
it gets projected onto others,
or,
projected against our self,
self-hatred,
so later on,
we'll talk about the dualities,
the levels of consciousness,
which is the book we just finished,
and,
we've been presenting that at lectures,
because each level of consciousness,
has attractions,
and it has aversions,
so we recapitulate,
the evolution of,
consciousness throughout all of time,
and there we see,
that the emergence of life,
which is unique,
solely possible via divinity,
the emergence of life then,
in its earliest form,
we calibrated it as protozoa,
at calibration level one,
the emergence of animal life,
is you do not have within yourself,
the energy necessary,
for your own survival,
when you understand that,
you end up with compassion,
for all of life,
because animal life,
is created deficient,
you're deficient,
the second you're born,
without your mother's milk,
you will soon die,
therefore,
we're created as deficient,
and needy,
so the core of the ego,
is neediness,
it must always get,
the energy from out there,
in the primitive form then,
this emerged as,
some way of sampling,
your environment,
is this edible or not edible,
is this compatible,
not compatible,
is this friend or foe,
so the experience here,
is like a,
information probe,
the advancing edge of the ego,
which we eventually,
identify as I,
and get stuck with it,
as a self definition,
which puts us in duality,
but the animal side then,
for eons,
the law,
it's law of survival,
is to get,
to be able to overcome that,
is extremely rare,
in society,
we say that,
to be able to get beyond,
the cravingness,
the fixation of the solar plexus,
of wantingness,
and then it gets transformed,
into symbolic form,
it transforms,
survival now,
is having a lot of money,
a big car,
wealthy,
having an education,
having political power,
so it gets transformed,
into symbols,
but the innate drivingness,
is still the same,
power over others,
see,
you know,
anybody in their right mind,
who want power over others,
is beyond me,
but,
it activates,
a lot of people's consciousness,
to have power over others,
as you can see,
the capacity for power,
within the self,
with a capital S,
is infinite,
once you realize that,
any offers of power,
are very unattractive,
I can remember it coming to me,
one time,
having transcended,
just about everything,
there was nothing left,
and out of the silence,
came a knowingness,
a temptation,
apparently,
one of the great temptations,
it says,
all power is yours now,
own it,
and I thought,
for what?
and so,
I turned it down,
now that you're not answerable,
now you realize,
that you're beyond personal karma,
all power is yours,
because you see,
love,
is a limitation,
if you're going to exploit people,
isn't it,
it's easy to throw them out,
on the street,
if you're not capable of love,
it's hard to throw them out,
on the street,
I would hate to be a slumlord,
it'd be a moral agony,
all the time,
you know what I'm saying,
you can't afford the rent anymore,
well,
it's out old lady,
you're on your own granny,
pack your bags and get,
seeing that everything,
that's merely the emergence,
of its own potentiality,
when the conditions,
are appropriate,
then you realize,
that intention,
is the empowerment,
that enables the manifestation,
to occur,
that which is held in mind,
tends to manifest,
the higher the level,
of consciousness,
the more that is so,
people of the high consciousness,
if you hold the thing,
even for a few minutes,
or seconds actually,
in mind,
it will tend to manifest,
in your life,
and therefore,
the wise,
watch what it is,
that they hold in mind,
we'll need the,
we'll need the things,
yeah,
what you hold in mind,
tends to manifest,
huh,
that's a reality,
and the greater,
why,
because the Heisenberg principle,
you see,
says that,
merely observing a phenomena,
already changes it,
what the Heisenberg principle,
doesn't go into,
is the power of the level,
of consciousness of the observer,
they were talking about,
scientists,
probably in the mid 400s,
astute scientists,
maybe around 450,
460,
that's astute science,
yeah,
when they look at it,
it changes the outcome,
what would happen with,
if somebody at 600,
looked at it,
or 550 or something,
it would be even more,
likely to manifest,
yes,
all right,
so for those who haven't,
been here before,
we're going to quickly,
recapitulate,
the levels of consciousness,
yeah,
and,
keep in mind,
these all have to be transcended,
if you want to reach serenity,
you have to get up,
early in the morning,
and work on it,
all day long,
you may not have serenity,
but you'll have exhaustion,
so you'll,
see,
yeah,
this of course,
is extremely well known,
in fact,
I see,
noetic sciences,
or somebody,
well,
I have a,
conference on,
maps of consciousness,
in,
Rhinebeck,
pretty soon,
all right,
so,
maps of consciousness,
are now,
therefore,
considered,
rather important,
why,
because,
it,
it's the open sesame,
to realizing the truth,
of just about everything,
that is,
the fact,
that there is such a thing,
see,
mankind has never known,
truth from falsehood,
never had any capacity,
and usually,
what is substituted,
is persuasion,
persuasion,
and then,
of course,
along came the intellect,
and you had,
some kind of,
academic proof,
but we had no way,
of discerning truth,
from falsehood,
so,
as a result,
of the evolution,
of consciousness,
of mankind,
a means,
of discerning truth,
from falsehood,
appeared,
within the consciousness,
of somebody,
in the planet,
who then,
wrote about it,
so others,
would know about it,
et cetera,
because,
it is not,
you know,
yours to hoard,
and keep secret,
but to share,
with the world,
for whatever benefit,
may accrue,
every advance,
in knowledge,
has a,
beneficial,
fallout,
sometimes known,
and sometimes,
completely unknown,
anyway,
what we discovered,
was,
in watching,
kinesiology,
is that,
it was not,
a local phenomena,
of a different kind,
but,
it was,
a local phenomenon,
of a different kind,
of a local phenomenon,
of a this,
causing of that,
on the contrary,
it was a response,
of the infinite field,
of consciousness,
itself,
to the presentation,
of a stimulus,
and,
the response,
was equivalent,
to the strength,
of the stimulus,
therefore,
we ended up,
a gradation,
from one to a thousand,
logarithmic,
and discovered,
that anything,
over 200,
was true,
and everything,
below 200,
was false,
so we ended up,
with a relative scale,
okay,
so,
kinesiology,
then,
was a clinical,
was clinical science,
not academic science,
academic science,
is limited,
to the 400s,
clinical science,
starts,
really,
at 500,
academic science,
the difference,
between a clinician,
who calibrates,
over 500,
and 100,
is quite remarkable,
because,
my witnessing,
I had the huge,
another piece,
some doctors,
got tremendous results,
with just about everybody,
even the most impossible cases,
and other doctors,
who are academically,
equally,
well-trained,
got relatively,
comparably,
miserable results,
so,
the energy,
of the healer,
the healing,
this,
then,
comes out,
of intention,
and the intention,
of caring,
for your patient,
and seeing them,
as well,
and being dedicated,
to them,
is why,
some doctors,
some doctors have rather incredible practices. Intention. So these are the
levels of consciousness and we calibrated them. They're pretty much
traditional throughout man's history, the alignment. In Columbia Psychoanalytic
these were called the emergency emotions and these are the welfare emotions. These
are the ones that bring you in to see the doctor and these are the ones that
take you out. I never saw any patients who suffered from serenity. Never did.
In fact their problem was they were allergic to serenity, you know. Serenity
is the last thing. A lot of people don't like serenity and although it's, you know,
we consider it an axiom in spiritual evolution, serenity frankly
frankly, is not sought by a large percentage of the population,
probably the majority.
The majority of the population really is not interested in serenity
because if they have the option, they turn it down all the time.
They turn it down all the time.
They'll pick an argument.
The TV shows are full of blood and murder and conflict.
So how to reach a state of serenity in a sort of chaotic appearing world, you see?
Because people of all different levels of consciousness and animal life, etc.,
is all thrown in together.
I mean, to get along here with people who are just like that is a snap, right?
Hang out with people that calibrate 350, your life is joyful.
They're cheerful, helpful, they volunteer.
They're the humanitarian.
So if everybody was right here at 350, this would be a great place.
Serenity would be sort of an automatic consequence.
No, what's happened is that in the world, 80% or so,
80% are below the level of truth, below this level.
So we're living in a world sort of like the bottom of the sea.
There are lots of sharks and octopuses and people out there.
I'll get you.
And the butterfly fish are up here.
I don't know.
All right.
But that's why it's maximum karmic benefit.
Because we have an infinite series of choices.
Because we can undo negative karma and gain positive karma.
This is a great benefit.
The Buddha said, how fortunate to be born a human.
How rare.
How rare to be born a human.
You think of all living things, the chances of being born a human is minute, minute, minuscule.
Point oh, oh, oh, oh, something.
And then to be spiritually aligned on top of that is rarer still.
And to choose to strive for enlightenment is the rarest of all.
Rarest of all.
Practically never happens.
And as we calibrated, the desire for enlightenment occurs in less than one in 10 million people.
Less than one in 10 million persons.
If you ask them, say, what's your greatest ambition to achieve in your lifetime, they
would say enlightenment, you know.
So consequently, it has been rare over time, you know.
All right.
So we've got this calibrated scale.
Now, I just want to say something about, turn off the light a second, about kinesiology
and the place of it in research, yeah.
It's a research tool.
The Institute for Consciousness Research.
It's based on.
The research's done using kinesiology.
Now, kinesiology is just like a tool, you know.
It's like a thermometer or something.
You're not supposed to genuflect in front of the thermometer.
It's just a handy, rough tool, you know.
Not perfected.
It's not the ultimate.
But it's quick and handy.
You don't, you know, go through a computer to decide what you're going to have for lunch.
Just say, well, I'll have this.
I'll have that.
My cholesterol's maybe a little high.
It's a lot of fish.
I mean, that's not a great big deal, you know what I'm saying?
So you don't have to make a big deal out of kinesiology.
It was useful in research.
Then I made the mistake of sharing it with the world.
Well, the mistake I made in the first book, Harvest is for Us, I presumed that everybody
could do kinesiology, you know, with relative ease or relative accuracy, and then discovered
that it was a good idea to do it in a different way.
And I did.
I did.
And I used the perfect method to build this book, Harvest is for Us.
I presumed that everybody could do kinesiology, you know, with relative ease or relative accuracy,
and then discovered later that it's only people who calibrate 200 and over.
In America, 49% of the population calibrates below 200.
So there goes 50%.
Then I found out about 10%, people for some karmic reason are unable to do it.
Then on top of that, your motivation has to be intense.
You have to have two integrous people who both calibrate over 200, and it can't be
stated as a question, it's made as a statement.
So to be able to pose a detached scientific question, that is also rare.
So kinesiology is very useful in research, and the reason that we wrote Truth Versus
Falsehood, because it realizes a lot of people don't have the time or the expertise, and
it's like riding a bicycle, some people just don't have it, you know.
Or horseback, I gave up on horses, you know, I got thrown about 18 times.
Horses are not my way, my path to salvation, and I gave them up.
So you have to take the word of others that are experienced with it, that the figures
are reasonably accurate.
Now again, we don't claim infallibility.
That's nowhere in the books do I claim infallibility, in a sense.
Therefore there's some errors, and there are some discrepancies in some of the calibrations,
partly due to my progressive age, partly due to the fact that Truth Versus Falsehood had
12 or 14 or 15 manuscript revisions, and there's typos and things.
So occasionally there will be something where I say the rhinoceros calibrates to something
here, and then I say it calibrates to something there.
But then we find some other things, too, that you can get different, specific calibrations
depending on the context.
So if I say, I make a list of good fatherhood, and then here's Joe Blow, he calibrates at
540, third father.
Then if I put here authors, and I put Joe Blow, because he also wrote a book, he may
only be 205, see?
So in what context do they calibrate?
I don't know.
They calibrate as such.
That's the latest thing we've learned.
We did know already, of course, that what you hold in mind can be held in various ways.
If I say, what does your mother calibrate?
Does that mean the memory of her, visual, auditory, emotionals?
People track stimuli.
Some people are primarily visual, some are auditory, some are feeling types, some are
tactile.
So it would be.
And at what age, see what I'm saying?
So you might get different calibrations of your mother, depending on one time you remember
how you felt when you came home after school, and you could smell apple pie cooking.
And then you might think of her at another time, visually, mad at you, saying you're
holding, so it depends on what context you hold her, what stage.
So anyway, I just want to say the calibrations are not written in stone.
They're not written in stone.
They're to give us a guideline.
So what does the calibrated number mean?
What it really means is it's an abstraction of an enormous complexity that gives us pretty
much a generality, although the number is numerical.
It's to give you a feeling for where that is, see?
When we said 350, 350 is a level, a characterizing number.
It's characterized by goodwill, helpfulness, positive, optimist, people who rescue teams,
you see?
Firemen, rescue divers, and people like that, that we all admire.
They're all at least 350 around.
What they represent is the willingness to serve.
So that's what we're trying to convey, is the general feeling of that field, and of
course.
You know, spiritual students, we're concerned with what is the long-term spiritual significance
of a number.
Very rarely does a small difference make any difference, unless you're doing micro-research.
If you're doing micro-research, then, then the specific number becomes more important.
And then you have to be careful to always hold the same context in mind.
If you're going to talk about mother, then disciple.
Then decide it's going to be how mother looked, and every time you ask about mother, or you
picture mother, don't go to a feeling state.
So research requires, then, more careful control of the context, huh?
But again, small discrepancies usually don't mean anything.
And the other thing is, in reading, you know, Truth Versus Falsehood, I notice some people
get lost in the trees and miss the forest.
I mean, what's the purpose of writing Truth Versus Falsehood?
I don't know.
It's not to document forever the calibrated number of everything on the planet, but because
it leads to a realization of truth and the pathway to truth.
So the overall thrust, you see, of the work, then.
So keep a balanced view that kinesiology is not the be-all, end-all of life.
And it's useful.
And it's prone to error.
It can be prone to error.
And you learn how to do it just like you do writing a bison.
Like you do riding a bicycle or riding a horse.
And some people are just no good at horses and, therefore, give it up.
Okay, so go on.
I just wanted to put a cautionary note that it's not written in stone.
And also, in writing the book, we did something like 14 or 15 manuscript revisions and thousands
of faxes back and forth.
And then it has to be put in a different form than it has to go in some kind of a file on
a computer thing.
And then it has to be put in a different form so that the printer, you can't just mail
it to him.
You know, he gives you a whole six pages of how he wants it sent to him.
So I just want you to understand the downside of trying to get everything perfect.
Okay.
We'll go to the next one.
For serenity, you have to give up being perfect.
It's okay to be fallible.
It's okay to be perfect.
It's okay to make a mistake.
You don't have to commit suicide because of it.
All right.
Calibrated level of consciousness, we went up to 600.
600 is the formal beginning of enlightenment.
Sat Chit Ananda, a state of bliss, the radiance of God shines forth, and all is still.
The letting go of attachments and aversions.
To that which is linear, then you move beyond the 500s.
The 500s are of course really the goal of most religions and spiritual people, to get
to unconditional love.
And beyond that, through devotion, to get to joy.
Miraculous begins to happen around 540.
540 and up.
The truly miraculous.
The truly miraculous begin to appear.
They occur spontaneously of themselves.
And we've spoken of them in previous lectures as the so-called siddhis, S-I-D-D-H-I-S, classically
paranormal, supernormal phenomena begin to appear.
It's the world of the miraculous.
Then you go through joy and in the very high 500s you go into ecstasy, a strange state.
540.
Hard to describe.
The joy of the presence of God as one's own creation is overwhelming.
And you become tireless.
You can dance for days nonstop.
No food, no water, no physical requirement.
It's because it's not your energy.
You're not dancing, you are being danced.
And any of you who have been into that state of ecstasy know
that the dancing now becomes effortless.
You're the witness of the dancing.
There is no you causing the dancing.
The dancing is happening of its own.
It's a fantastic experience.
How many people have had that from dancing?
Anybody here? Dancing, right.
The other thing you get is, what do you call that where you run all day, every day?
Running. What do you call that?
Huh? Running. What do you call that? Running.
The sport of running.
Jogging, jogging, jogging.
People.
People jogging and all of a sudden time stops
and the woods becomes transformed and they're being jogged.
It's effortless.
Yeah. It is a very achievable state.
I achieved it at age probably 16, yeah, working in a warehouse
in the tremendous heat at a pecanry.
You got an extra nickel everything over 12 hours, 35 cents.
And after working something like 14 or 15 hours, I said, I can't.
I cannot lift another box.
I can't.
And suddenly, the I can't, I broke through my sheer determination, the I can't,
and came into a wondrous space.
Effortlessly, the boxes lifted themselves.
And I kept working another, I think I worked about 20 hours nonstop.
Effortlessly.
And the heat didn't bother me at all.
So you break through, I call it the Roger Bannister barrier.
The mind has a conviction that it can't.
And you refuse the can't.
And you just right through it.
And then you enter an infinite silent state of spontaneity.
This is required eventually to reach enlightenment as well.
Therefore, I mentioned the Roger Bannister effect also applies to states of consciousness
where you can't, I can't this, I can't that.
And once you break through the I can't and realize that you can,
all the I can'ts in spirituality, if we hold a loaded gun to your head,
and give you the option, you're going to forgive that guy or I'll blow your brains out.
I forgive him.
So it isn't that you can't, it's that you won't.
And why won't you?
You won't because the ego gets so much juice from its positionality.
So what holds all these levels of consciousness in place then,
is that the ego is thriving off the juice.
Of injustice, righteousness, being right, winning.
All those positionalities that we're willing to die for.
People are willing to die for all kinds of things.
I say, good luck.
You haven't mentioned one that appeals to me yet.
I would like freedom from your speech.
You get free speech.
All right, so that's about 600.
And then these states go up.
And therefore, for the first time in history,
you can validate spiritual realities.
We'll move to the next thing.
You can validate spiritual realities.
So we said that close to 80% of the world's population.
You see, now this is not written in cement.
You know, not written in cement.
This means at the time we did this, probably five years ago.
Let's see if it's accurate now.
Oh, it's, no, I don't want to know it.
Maybe 79% or something.
Roughly, roughly 80% of the world.
That mankind is, that's the mass of mankind.
And about 15, this few percent, 22%, is above 200.
Now, the thing is, the power of these people
counterbalances the negative energy of these people.
The negative energy, we got that
without the emergence of the great avatars over time,
that mankind would have destroyed himself.
Mankind would have destroyed himself.
Especially, you give him an atomic bomb,
and he's controlled by a glow of consciousness,
and the end is in sight.
It doesn't matter how soon, yeah?
The evolution of consciousness, happily,
is expanding at a rapid rate.
And Daniel Lyons, who sent this to us, calibrated it.
He's an engineering student.
Here's the levels of consciousness over great eons of time,
which we'll quickly review again later.
And here it is against time,
and you see that right now,
it's rocketing up at an extremely rapid rate.
The consciousness level of all mankind right now is 207.
207. Let's see if it's still at 207.
It could have sneaked up while we were sleeping.
The consciousness level of mankind overall.
Do we have permission to do this?
Is it 207?
208?
207, okay.
207.
So you see, when we do kinesiology,
I ask permission.
Then we really phrase it, mentally or verbally,
in the name of the highest good.
And the name of the highest good is merely,
scientifically, you're trying to ascertain what is the truth,
and you don't have any stake in it one way or the other.
And the reason people get very far off answers
is they're putting a stake
in it, you see.
My daughter calibrates it over 900.
We get letters like that all the time.
The way to get over that is to calibrate your neighbor's daughter
and see what she comes out as.
No, it's only her daughter, yeah?
All right, so here we recapitulate.
I think because there's an enormous spiritual benefit
in realizing, what time is the break anyway?
1150?
Huh?
Oh, okay, all right.
So how much time have I got?
All right, so the people who are familiar with this,
we just want to quickly review.
The emergence of life,
these are the great, the oldest dates of rock,
rocks, and these numbers are so big,
I don't even know what they are, quadrillions or something.
Heptamillions.
Octamillions.
Octamillions of years.
There are decades.
Anyway, they're at the evolution of time.
You can see the calibrated level of consciousness
begins to rise over time.
And finally,
you see, here it is.
It shows up here as bacteria,
and then marine invertebrates,
such as the trilobite, etc., like that,
and the spiny fish and the amphibians,
and then it begins to climb to the present time.
So you see the scale of consciousness,
how it's rising continuously.
So the next slide.
So we are on the upside.
People alive today
then have the benefit
that there is an upward momentum
of consciousness itself,
and therefore the chances of reaching enlightenment now
are over a thousand times greater
than any time in the past
due to consciousness research,
due to the advance of the level of consciousness of mankind.
If you skip guilt about sin, etc.,
you can do it in 20, 30 weeks.
Yep.
Yeah.
Anyway, it saves you plenty of lifetimes.
How long does it take to become enlightened?
One second,
except that it takes you most of a lifetime
to get to that second.
All right, so I think this is,
you know, as a psychiatrist, psychoanalyst,
psychologist, physician, and researcher,
as well as a spiritual committed person myself,
I consider this very important, you see,
because here you have the emergence of the ego,
and you see its origin is in the animal nature.
Huh?
It's animal.
It's animal, see?
This guy isn't evil.
A shark isn't evil, is he?
No.
He just is being what he is.
Hmm.
Dolphins are not evil.
Polar bears are not evil.
Bears are not evil.
You see?
I don't see any evil there.
I see an animal being an animal.
So under 200,
these are the animals being an animal,
and it lives at the cost of the life of others.
Predation.
So these are characterized by predation.
All right.
Then at 200,
you see a major transformation,
not only in mankind,
but in the animal world.
All of a sudden,
you see the emergence
of the herbivore,
the grazer.
These are rapacious killers.
These just bunch their grass
and fertilize it all at the same time.
Who goes in one end,
fertilizer out the other.
So they're even-steven, you know?
They fertilize the grass while they eat it.
And of course,
that's why we have dairy cows.
then we get up to the higher animals,
the dogs and the cats
and the gorillas and Coco.
And let's see what Coco calibrates on.
Let's see.
If I think of Coco and Coco as an identity,
Coco calibrates over 400, 405, 406.
Okay.
If I think of Coco as gorilla,
Coco calibrates over 250, 260.
All right.
Okay.
So that's a discrepancy.
In one place,
I said Coco calibrated 250
and another 405.
Because when I said 250,
I was thinking gorilla.
And when I got 405,
I was thinking specifically Coco.
When we got 250,
I was holding a picture of a gorilla
and I wasn't making it Coco.
So, you know,
we hear about these discrepancies
and I feel obligated to explain them
and research them myself.
And we've learned a lot
about the discrepancies.
All right.
So Coco, then,
gorillas are somewhere else on here.
I forget where.
Anyway, you're safer with a gorilla
than you are with most people on the planet.
I don't know where the gorilla is.
Where's the gorilla?
All right.
So gorillas, depending on the gorilla,
and there's different kinds of gorillas,
there's highland and lowland, et cetera.
Anyway.
So I guess the bees,
you see, scientific research,
I'd have to say.
Highland and one country
versus the lowland
because there's a difference
between the highland gorillas
and the lowland gorillas.
And I don't know
whether Coco represents Coco.
I don't know.
So, you see,
she's sending me messages.
I get your message.
I didn't mean to insult Coco.
No.
All right.
You see, scientific research,
then we'd have to say,
Coco is a highland or a lowland.
And Coco at what age, et cetera, et cetera.
But we want to get a gist of it.
The gist of it is that these are rapacious.
These are benign.
And the corollary with human life is exact.
The correlation is 100%.
So that is certainly very something
we can learn from.
And we have a great parrot
we're playing with at home.
Broccoli.
What's your latest thing?
Go to work.
Get a job.
She's far right conservative.
I mean,
you want an apple,
get your own, you know.
Then we know the cat's fur
and the dog's wanging tail
is unique at 500.
Okay.
So the animal kingdom, then,
is corollary,
correlated with the human.
Ego, the development of the ego.
And I think that we just saw that,
didn't we?
Oh.
All right.
So that, all right.
So the great books of the western world.
I wanted to cover those things
that came up because of the errors.
I wanted to explain them.
The limitations of kinesiology.
The upside is it gives you access
to information never before available
to anyone anywhere.
And for which you have respect.
There's no limitation.
This has to do with
the quality of consciousness itself.
And again,
because people have requested
I'll repeat something
we've said in previous lectures.
How does it all come about?
The scale is,
is a scale aligned with
the energy of something
as compared to the absolute.
The absolute is infinite.
Therefore, there is no variation
in the absolute because
the omnipotence of consciousness,
the omnipotence, the omnipresence,
is the scale against which
we're calibrating truth.
Roughly equivalent to,
I'd say operationally,
to an electromagnetic,
the old speakers where the,
what do you call the speakers?
Electro something speakers.
It'll come to me.
So electrostatic, yes.
Electrostatic speakers.
So the greater the charge,
you remember how
the electrostatic speaker works,
is the greater the membrane,
the greater the electrons
on this membrane,
they can't touch the other side,
the greater the number
of protons will.
So the response is always exactly
consequent and aligned
with the stimulus.
So consciousness then.
So with kinesiology,
what you get is that the stimulus
you present, coco,
then brings up a response.
And that response is the equivalent
and we call that 400.
The infinite field of consciousness itself
has no beginning and no ending.
It is outside of time
and within it everything
is recorded forever.
Every hair on your head is numbered.
Numbered.
They get fewer.
Let's say it's not saying numbered.
Count it.
Everything that is done
is recorded in the infinite field
of consciousness forever.
Forever.
Consequently,
everyone is accountable
for their actions,
karmically responsible for their actions.
Culpability
changes depending on the circumstances.
Accountability does not.
Culpability is, of course,
the concept that one's degree
of knowledge or awareness
or ignorance at the time
has to be taken into consideration.
At a certain level, therefore,
all men are innocent.
All men are innocent
by virtue of the fact
that as Socrates said,
all men choose,
not only the good,
they choose what their experiencer pro
thinks is the best option,
believes is the best option
to take at any given moment.
So intrinsically the mind is innocent
and we've compared it many times
to the computer,
to the hardware of the computer
that the human mind
is not able to reach truth on its own
because like a hardware of a computer
it will play any kind of program
you put into it.
The computer has no,
its hardware has no means
of evaluating the value
or much less the truth
of any program.
So the mind, then,
can be programmed very easily.
It's programmed, in fact, automatically
as a consequence of its own nature.
Intrinsically, then,
the ego is set up
so that the mind is unable
to discern truth from falsehood.
It starts res interna from res externa.
The world as we see it
and the world the way it is.
There is a bridge
and no way to really cross it
until recently.
And actually,
with consciousness research
it's the first time we've been able
to cross the bridge.
How do we see it
and what does it calibrate out as?
And then when you see if there's a disparity
you can get why perception saw it that way.
And what you pick up
is a positionality within yourself
that there's some gain
that you're getting out of seeing it
the way you were seeing it.
You're getting some kind of gain.
So the mind, then,
is relatively immune.
It can't tell truth from falsehood
and that is the great tragedy
of human life.
For that reason,
all the great avatars appeared over time
and they were the only real avenues
of truth.
Real avenues of truth
without which man would have exterminated himself.
Alright, so the limitations.
And so,
how do things come about?
Spiritually? Karma?
The Christian world doesn't think
they believe in karma.
Of course they do.
All Christians believe in karma.
They just don't call it karma.
Heaven or hell, where the soul goes after death,
that's called karma, isn't it?
The reason to avoid sin
is you want to avoid the lower regions
because they're unpleasant.
You don't get to vote.
Alright, so to transcend the limitations, then,
of the human ego,
so consciousness research,
one of its benefits is it gave us a way
to access information not otherwise available.
The infinite field of consciousness, then,
which is a radiance of divinity,
is comparable to a giant electromagnetic field.
The spiritual dimension is comparable.
Infinite dimensions.
The power of God is infinite.
Alright, so by our choice,
by our own options of choice, then,
we determine, you might say,
our spiritual charge.
See, you might picture
that we're a little piece of metal fragment.
And every choice you make
influences your polarity.
And therefore, where you are
in the infinite field
is the automatic consequence of choices,
the collective consequences
of all the choices that you've made throughout time.
You become that which you have chosen.
And within an infinite field of power,
impersonally,
you are drawn and pulled to
that area of the electromagnetic field.
Therefore, you don't need an arbitrary,
judgmental God
because
the justice of God
is absolutely perfect.
Nothing happens and nobody goes
any place other than by their own choice.
There's nobody paddling the canoe but us.
You can't blame it on God.
See, the anthropomorphic God
is angry and jealous and all.
It comes out of sort of primitivism.
Primitive man saw volcanoes and floods and all,
postulated angry gods.
And so they sacrificed maidens and etc.
to satisfy the angry gods.
Maidens were always the favorite.
Maidens...
Innocent maidens were the favorite, for some reason.
A grizzly little guy doesn't seem to be much of a sacrifice, right?
Sexism goes way back.
Only virgin maidens.
Okay, next.
We want to define the relationship of context and...
See, content and context.
Content is linear, definable, calculable.
The world of science and mathematics.
The field is the overall context.
And as for spiritual evolution, therefore,
I've always recommended the contemplative lifestyle
in which you align with the field
rather than the content of the field.
That way you walk about in a style
and state of greater serenity.
If you're upset at everything that happens on the television,
you're not going to get to sleep, see?
But what you see is the panorama of the cacophony
of political maneuvering and game playing
because everybody wants power, you see?
And so you just assume, yeah.
But you see it's not affecting your serenity.
I mean, it's like a game.
So if you see it as a game,
your serenity remains the same.
If you take it seriously,
you'll be upset all the time.
Anybody here takes politics seriously?
No, you can't take it seriously
because everybody says what they think
will appeal to their own followers.
And it doesn't have anything to do with truth.
It has to do with winning.
Politicians are not here for your good, folks.
That's not their purpose.
Your good gets them elected.
Then, therefore, you're good.
No politician is aligned with truth
for the good karma of society.
All right, because he couldn't be able to sleep at night.
All right.
These are the functions of mind, you see?
There's various energy fields
that are controlled by what are called the tractor fields.
In that which seems scattered,
there is an overall organizing principle.
It's called an attractor field.
Attractor field comes from nonlinear dynamics.
That which appears to be sporadic,
nonlinear, unpredictable,
is off the chart,
being controlled by a higher field of context.
So if we calibrate,
we find that there's two levels to mind.
There's lower mind and higher mind.
Lower mind is the thinkingness of people below time.
It's like a 200, see?
And they go in for, let's say,
sympathy instead of empathy.
Big difference between sympathy and empathy.
Sympathy calibrates low.
Empathy calibrates high.
To be able to be sensitive to where other people are
therefore makes you a greater gift to the world.
Sympathy gets to be maudlin
and gets to be, it's a way of milking the situation.
And the crybaby society
is based on always milking the world for some sympathy
for something that happened to you in your life,
some circumstances.
And if that won't do it, you can always go back to ancestors.
There's always ancestors that have been screwed over.
If you run out of victim rolls,
I can, anybody short a victim roll,
I'll manufacture you a couple of them right away.
White males right now are the ultra-victim of our society.
Everybody, all white males have to apologize.
It's comical.
Alright, so the lower mind then is motivated more by animal kinds of wants
as they are elaborated by the prefrontal cortex.
So what happened is we watched the evolution of consciousness over time
and then emerges the hominids.
I don't think hominids are on there.
No, hominids aren't on that one.
So the hominids began about, I don't know,
the last guess I heard was three million years ago with Lucy,
which I don't think is fair either.
It could have been George, you know, if they got to be Lucy.
Anyway, Lucy was the first hominid.
And Lucy we calibrated the other day.
I forget what Lucy was at, around 65 or something like that.
Anyway, then we have the hominids appearing
the Neanderthal man, Homo erectus, about 85.
Homo erectus, I-delta, about 60,000 years ago.
And so we see the calibrated level of consciousness
evolving through the hominids.
Through the hominids.
And finally, region 205, where it is today.
Where's the next slide?
I went over that slide.
So on its way, no, we'll go back to the previous one.
On its way, then, to erudition, which is in the 400s,
it goes through lower mind,
where it tends to be naive, gullible, and impressionable.
And this is the world of rhetoric, persuasion.
How dare they? How can we do so-and-so?
It's a lot of drama and theater, you know?
And people then, they're coming mainly from emotion,
and fall for that.
People who are coming from the intellect and logic
are coming from a higher mind.
And what sells over here doesn't sell over here.
On the other hand, this sounds awful dry and unappealing
to people over here who are interested in
a cheering squad and emotion and the band playing, yeah?
Emotional band playing.
What happened to the great books of the Western world?
Did you do something with them?
She did something with the great books of the Western world.
We saw how, you know, through the emergence of the hominid,
the emergence of intelligence, calibrated levels constantly rising,
and probably the greatest, the height of human civilization.
To my mind, the height of human civilization was around 350 B.C.
It's frankly slowly going downhill soon.
That's not too optimistic of you, is it?
Right?
The roots, the paradigm for all of Western civilization
was set around in the 5th century B.C.
Plato and Socrates, etc.
And frankly, nothing has come out since then,
intellectually, that calibrates higher.
Nothing higher.
A lot of things have come out that are lower,
but nothing has come out higher.
Because the rules of logic,
the axiom categories, etc.
were discovered, and they're not going to change over time.
So, if somebody, if you quote Socrates,
some people say, well, that's so old-fashioned, you know?
You know, other truths were discovered at that time,
and frankly, it hasn't changed.
So, all right, we calibrated the great books of the Western world,
and that in itself is a really wonderful exercise.
You know, the great books are still available.
It's recommended you study them over a ten-year period.
You divide this up into ten,
and each year you spend,
okay, just reading, familiarize yourself with three or four writers,
and that's sufficient.
Therefore, you achieve what's really the ultimate goal
of the liberal education,
which is the establishment of the comprehension of Western society
and its intellectual basis.
A great deal, just studying the great books
of the Western world makes a profound difference
in how you see and understand the world.
Here we have Darwin at 450, you see?
And he's, of course, right in the middle of it right now.
And Copernicus at 455.
You see the great scientists.
Very amazing.
Aristotle at close to 500.
And Socrates is not on here,
because he never wrote anything.
So, somebody inquired,
and they discovered information about Socrates.
First of all, the encyclopedia,
which would answer the question,
where is it written about Socrates?
And, of course, that was written by Plato.
Darwin reading Plato's Phaedus, et cetera,
and Republic, et cetera,
you understand what Socrates said.
All right, so these things are very significant
because they're out of awareness.
And the whole world that we call civilization,
society being decent, rational, and reasonable,
is really the product of the intellects
of these people over time.
They calibrate collectively around 450, 455.
I don't want to give specifics anymore,
because somebody's going to send me an email,
I thought you said 455.
No, it's 460.
Therefore, all numbers will be roundabout.
Roundabout, the more, the mid-400s,
you have intellectual erudition.
Roundabout, and here, roundabout.
However, you do see people, Descartes at 490,
you see Freud at 499,
Sir Isaac Newton at 499,
develop the differential calculus.
So you see the great scientific minds,
Galileo, Galen, Hegel.
Hegel's principle, I always mention,
because he had a principle of the absolute,
and that principle of the absolute
is the whole basis of kinesiology.
Here you have the father of medicine.
So you really have the great and celebrated minds of history
who had a profound and positive impact on mankind.
With the exception of this ringer in here.
The Marxian dialectic materialism calibrates to 130.
And so the fallout of calibrated level 130
is about 100 million lives in my lifetime,
all of Marxism,
and of course the thousands of millions of deaths
that have come through.
And what's the problem with Marxism?
It's dualistic projection of the concept
of perpetrator and victim.
That's the downside of moral relativism as well.
It constantly sees a perpetrator and a victim,
and that divides people into warring factions.
So if you take Marx out of this,
they all calibrate, this calibrates around 450.
If you take out Marx,
collectively they calibrate around 465.
Therefore spiritual error
is a serious matter, is it not?
And Socrates said that one of his main purposes
was to destroy the gods of falsehood.
Destroy the gods of falsehood.
So Socrates being my brother,
I joined with him and say,
here you have at 130 one of the gods of falsity.
Mayo's Little Red Book.
How many millions? 30 million died just of starvation.
Just of starvation, forget war.
In the Cold War.
So the downside of falsehood is very serious, is it not?
You're talking about in my lifetime
at least 100 million people.
At least 100 million people have gone to their death
because of just this error here.
Just that error.
Therefore we don't hate negativity,
but I certainly respect it.
I respect that which is spoken in error,
especially if it's spoken with great fervor
and rhetorical skill.
Because it's instantly the Achilles heel
that can bring down our society as well.
And in our own research we said
the combination of totalitarian, you know,
theological totalitarianism on one side
and moral relativism on the other side,
by the sheer process of iteration,
where one, the apologist, opens the door to the other,
does have the capacity to destroy our society.
It does have the capacity to destroy our society.
By iteration.
The constant introduction of falsehood in the media,
the newspapers, the commentators,
and most dangerously at the university level,
academically,
to impair the reality testing of the student then,
by aligning it with falsehood.
So that is then the problem.
How to maintain serenity in the midst of all this is simple.
You just turn it over to God.
The purpose, therefore, to not be serene about it means
that you know more about the purpose of human life
than divinity does.
The purpose of human life does not seem to be
experientially, subjectively, emotionally serenity at all.
No.
Because serenity as a way of being in the world
doesn't really happen, you know,
until you get up into the 500s.
So serenity is really the world of maybe 3 or 4% of the people in the world.
For one thing, they choose serenity above the payoff of the ego.
So when we get back, I just want to recapitulate briefly.
What I call the experiencer edge of the ego.
It feeds off something out there.
It's constantly probing and looking.
It loves conflict.
It loves excitement.
It loves war and terrorism and all these wonderful things.
It lives off that juice.
Therefore, serenity seems to the ego like suicide.
The last thing the ego wants,
it feeds off the animal juice of excitement.
The last thing it wants is serenity.
And, of course, what brings about this serenity
is at consciousness level 200,
you get a transformation of brain physiology
because you have the introduction of a new energy,
spiritual energy,
classically called kundalini energy,
which completely changes and alters your brain function.
So the person above 200 and the person below 200
are even on the animal level different,
that the brain of this one is working different
than the brain of the other one.
So after the break,
we have that slide coming up.
Don't we, brain physiology?
Okay.
Okay, so I apologize to those who have heard this before,
except each time it's different
because you're a different person.
If you heard it before,
you're different than you were when you heard it,
or I missed my point.
I should have kept my own piece.
Hopefully, to have heard it,
you're different than you were before you heard it.
So therefore, you're not the same people
who heard this before.
You're different people.
And for you, it's the first time.
We'll take a break till what time?
Um, 53 and 59.
Fifteen minutes?
Y'all students,
we will commence again
from the middle.
We start from the ending,
then we recommence at the middle.
We try to cover the didactic material,
you know, for multiple reasons.
For instance, learning is facilitated by repetition.
And at first, what may sound amazing
or even challenging,
becomes, so what?
You become...
So you learn by familiarity.
There's one way that's linear,
sequential, logical.
And the other is just you get the whole thing
by familiarity, you know, familiarity.
And you say, yeah.
Like, you just accept the whole thing
and that's the way it is, so.
All right.
As time goes on,
we're going to reduce the amount of didactic time,
spend more time on spontaneous conversation and interaction.
We'll start that today.
Nico's not going to be here,
so we'll have a little more time for questions and answers.
Because, you know, in other words, time-wise,
because he's absent today.
But progressively, we'll spend more time
with spontaneous interaction with the audience, you see.
My favorite style, really,
is to just wander through the audience
and greet people and they come up with
whatever they come up with.
Because that makes it more alive
and, you know, experiential.
But we all need this kind of background.
And this background is information
never really before been accessible.
And it allows us to understand the human life,
from a different level,
which supports compassion.
Everybody knows that the ultimate spiritual state
they would like to reach,
that of the Buddha,
which is compassion for all of life.
But that can't be an artificiality.
Yeah, I think I'll be compassionate.
Compassion is the automatic consequence
of comprehension.
And when you comprehend the limitation
of human evolution,
the limitations intrinsic,
built into the computer,
software problem of the human mind,
you become compassionate for human error.
And you accept human fallibility.
You accept human fallibility.
And become compassionate.
So, once you become compassionate for others,
you also become more compassionate towards yourself.
And stop attacking yourself with guilt.
All humans are fallible.
All fallible. All fallible.
Nothing is set in stone forever, yeah?
We're all fallible.
So, if we take responsibility,
merely to correct our mistakes.
So, it isn't that you make a mistake,
it's that you take the responsibility
to correct it, you know?
If I put a dish in the wrong place,
I have to take it out and put it where it belongs.
I joke with her all the time about those things, you know.
But acceptance of fallibility,
the limitations of the human mind,
then allows for a certain serenity.
Socrates' dictum, which I quote constantly,
because once you've accepted it,
it solves a multitude of problems,
is that all men choose only what they perceive to be the good.
All men are intrinsically innocent by virtue of the fact.
They always choose what appears to be the best option at the time.
Which is another way of explaining
the same thing that I try to explain
using the analogy of the computer.
That the human mind cannot differentiate truth from falsehood
and it has no guards at the gate
to filter in the truth of what it's being programmed with.
Plus, the human mind is programmed
so rapidly that it's happened before you realize it.
You've already been programmed.
About the time you realize you've been programmed,
you've already been programmed.
And I'm programming you right now
to make you aware that the human mind
has a propensity to being quickly programmed.
Quickly programmed.
Innocently, because that's the way it's built.
As noted by Descartes,
the world you think you see
and the world the way it is
are quite disparate.
And very frequently they have no relationship
to each other at all.
That brings about a certain intrinsic humility.
So like compassion,
humility automatically ensues
from the comprehension and acceptance
of the limitations of the human mind.
Not only your own, but human mind over history.
Over all of history.
That fallacy has reigned for...
In human history, you realize,
peace has prevailed 93...
Peace has prevailed 7% of the time
in human history.
And war has prevailed 93% of the time.
If you're against war,
you're against normality, aren't you?
Man loves to be at war.
The glory of war.
The righteousness of it.
You know?
Of course, if this is a world
of great karmic opportunity,
war is one of the greatest karmic opportunities
that mankind has.
To undo negative karma
and to cross over the line
of 200 into integrity
and the valor of the heart
of the warrior, etc.
We'll celebrate that
at one of these coming lectures.
We're gonna have bagpipes.
Yeah?
Anybody hate bagpipes?
Some people hate them.
So I'm giving forewarning
that without being previously announced,
you may be hit by bagpipes
during any lecture.
Bagpipes calibrate about 510.
And if you understand
the energy of bagpipes,
you'll understand
a different dimension of war
that you don't understand before.
Because without the energy of bagpipes,
you can't really comprehend it, huh?
What war has always been about,
what the stereotype,
what the archetype of the warrior
is all about.
And its karmic upside
and its karmic downside, huh?
Also, you remember Jesus Christ said
he did not come with a sword of peace,
but a sword of truth.
Didn't he say that?
Any Christians here?
Hey, anybody?
Five out of six Americans are Christian.
Where are they?
I don't know.
We used to study scripture.
I guess that's old-fashioned.
I don't know, but he did say
he didn't bring a sword of peace,
he brought the sword of truth.
And I'm seeing contentious.
It can seem contentious.
It's not contentious.
It's only a challenge
to the ego's belief systems.
Okay, we go on.
We just wanted to point out
that because of animal nature,
80% of the people on the planet
are dominated
in such a way
that their brain processes
things differently
than other people's brains.
Below 200,
the brain processes
left brain style animal nature,
ruled by instincts, ruled by emotions.
You can see why reason does not prevail,
because the emotion here kicks in.
The information is very slow
through the prefrontal cortex,
very rapid to the emotional center,
so people react emotionally
with their solar plexus.
So rhetoric is aimed not at your head.
Rhetoric is aimed at your solar plexus.
Solar plexus.
Your emotional state
is aimed at lower mind.
So in the emergence of homo sapiens,
you see,
what happened was that
the prefrontal cortex was plastered
onto the old animal brain.
They didn't remove the old animal brain
and replace it with a prefrontal cortex.
They plastered it
onto the old animal brain.
So now you've got a thinking animal.
So the animal himself
could be quite dangerous.
But when you add thinkingness to him,
you've got modern man,
who is extremely dangerous.
Below 200,
he should really be put on a different planet.
But anyway,
that's my view of it. Sorry, God.
No, God says there's got to be
maximum opportunity
for all to evolve.
So this world is the ultimate
karmic potentiality.
That's why the Buddha said,
great fortune is it to be born a human,
because you were born in a realm
with maximum karmic opportunity
to undo your negative karma
and to gain positive karma.
Through evolution
and spiritual energy
finally emerges,
and through your own commitment
and your own choices,
you move into an energy field above 200,
and dramatic change takes place
in your brain function.
Very dramatic.
The people below 200
are not the same as you are.
They are not the same.
They are different.
They don't have the same vision
that you will see one way,
they will see another way,
because their brain processes it differently.
So it isn't that they're wrong
or evil or something,
it's just that they get it differently
than you get it.
They get it differently than you get it.
So this brain here now,
the fast-track is through
a comprehension
emotion is delayed,
and at consciousness level
200 you see the most profound change and that is the emergence of the etheric
brain an energy brain composed only of energy no protoplasm that's the
difficulty of science and consciousness science and theology is they don't get
that there's a major change there you can't explain consciousness in terms of
brain physiology all right so the etheric brain then very fast your
etheric prefrontal cortex is very fast and overlays the emotion so compassion
is that you see the self see the limitations of mankind is suffering
rather than as evil so instead of hating them you have a certain empathy I can
see how a person could be carried away by a certain emotion I can see that and
you can see the rhetoric that's designed to do that in fact you know the
political
has been to the argument is meant to bring up emotion and bypass your
intellect all right so here the more evolved person so the left brain person
is completely has a different physiology generally as well because he's always
releasing emergency emotions emergency emotions with consequences to the
immune system and the balance of the acupuncture system
below above 200 then where we value truth for its own sake you now tend to
release endorphins and you see that information is processed differently this
understanding this comprehension is primarily within the etheric brain the
etheric brain to which the neurons resonate by induction the etheric brain
it's relationship to the neuron to me is
analogous to a magnetic field creating electricity in a wire. A wire, if you move
it back and forth through a magnetic field, will create electricity.
Magnetism doesn't move through the wire, you understand? So research on the nature
of consciousness, which is always fixated on the neurons, they can't seem to get
off the neuron, it's because they're coming from the bottom up instead of the
top down is why, from the contextual viewpoint, is because consciousness
dominates and it's the etheric brain then is like a magnetic field, the neuron
is like a wire, and the ideation is a consequence of the influence of the
etheric brain on the physical brain, which is also in compliance with the
observations of famous Nobel Prize winners
that the
brain is a receiving instrument. The Buddha, you know, said there were six
senses and not man's traditional five and he conceived that the brain is a
receiving instrument for the mind. It's a receiving, a sensory, so the brain is a
sensory organ of thinkingness. So this major transformation here comes only
about through evolution of consciousness
when it begins to value truth over the personal gain of the selfish ego.
People think they're addicted to the world or attached to the world.
You're not.
You're not attached to the world at all.
You're attached to the ego juice.
You get off your perceptions of the world to be right or to get even
or to be rich or famous,
to have lots of followers, to be worshipped.
That's not what you're attached to.
You're attached to just one thing,
that all these positionalities give you an ego juice.
You're only addicted to one thing, and that's the ego juice
you get out of your positionalities,
which is important to know when we get to transcending the levels of consciousness.
People think, oh, I can't overcome all these attractions to the world
and all these lures and all that.
You don't have to.
Think.
Nobody would ever get enlightened if that was so.
You can't process multi-millions of data,
a great deal of which you've even forgotten is working unconsciously.
No, but you can let go and surrender to God the satisfaction
that you get out of these ego positions
of winning, of being right, of feeling sorry for yourself,
of being the martyr, of getting even, etc.
Okay, move on.
These are the higher levels of consciousness.
No, what is this here?
Oh, rates of happiness, right.
All right, so as far as out there-ness,
you can see the ego thinks that happiness is derived
from getting something from out there.
But you can see the more autonomous your state of happiness is,
it eventually doesn't depend on anything out there.
The percent of people happy at these various levels is quite considerable.
Oh, I know why.
It's because it's the other way around.
Okay, so in the lower levels, practically nobody's happy,
and those that say they are are lying or intoxicated and they're probably-
Quit that, what is, what's his name called, he calls it,
and quit that Kool-Aid and we'll see how happy you are, yeah.
The Kool-Aid people, he calls them, it's hysterical.
The Kool-Aid, yeah, Bill Riley, yeah.
The Kool-Aid people.
So down here, nobody's happy,
and here is still-
Nobody's happy, as you can see at these levels of negativity,
nobody's really happy.
You can see why intoxication then has such a tremendous draw.
The people become addicted to drugs and alcohol, et cetera.
It's because without them, you experience this,
and with them, you get an artificial euphoria.
Therefore, it's very difficult to get people to give them up,
because you go from feeling great to feeling horrible.
And who wants to feel horrible?
So personal willpower can't do it alone.
Nobody breaks addictions through personal willpower.
Personal willpower, personal will isn't strong enough.
The personal will only calibrates at the level of one's consciousness.
So you say to a person at this level of 50,
through willpower you should give up your addiction to something or other,
but this poor person only calibrates at 50.
Yeah.
It's going to take a bit longer and have an addiction to something or other,
but this poor person only calibrates at 50.
about, you know, something over 500 to break the addiction. Break the addiction takes over
500. 12-step groups all calibrate around 540. So it takes 500 to break it and you're asking
a person to break the addiction who only calibrates there. So you can see the propensity to addiction
then is quite severe. Then what happens here as you move into the field of integrity is
you see a huge jump in the rate of happiness. So rate of happiness is correlated, not with
socio-economic status or anything else although it reflects itself in the socio-economic status,
but a level of consciousness. So instead of happiness being a consequence of out there-ness,
you see that it's the consequence of that which you have become. So the spiritual person
is interested in becoming their karmic potentiality.
fulfilling their potentiality and through that you derive a happiness
which is independent of the world we'll move on whether you're rich or poor is
relatively irrelevant there's a lot of there's not a much enough said for
poverty you know or poorness when it's voluntary is joyful when it's
involuntary you feel sorry for yourself and resentful many people as they
spiritually evolved give away everything yeah give away six thousand
volume library you know give away give it all away and live on practically
nothing and then gradually start collecting books again you got to make
some money somewhere grow tomatoes and sell fruit something deliver manure is
so that you can afford to buy the books that you wish you hadn't thrown away
happily I came across
you know I'm not going to be able to afford to buy the books that you wish you hadn't thrown away happily I came across the
great books of the Western world when I was poverty stricken and I got it for a
song you know I got back some of what I gave away yeah anyway was one happier at
the top of society or with nothing at all practically frankly practically at
all nothing at all was terrific just deliver a couple loads of manure a week
and that was the end of your problem
at 40 bucks a load well now we wanted to go over I get lots of emails about
integrity and integrity of teachers etc what we've done is outline the the way
to define and identify integrity of teachers and teachings plus we've given
a list of a hundred people who calibrate you know very well mid 400s and up
integrus and truthful and time time-honored
somebody's always finding a book by some wacko out there and why me to
calibrate it you know so now I have a generic answer plus I've learned if I
give him a pretty I think he's sending me a personal letter you know dear
teacher what do you think of bongi whoa whoa
bongi whoa calibrates at 170 the next day it's all over the email all of the
internet you know I thought I'm responding to this guy personal
question so no more personal responses a hundred teachers is good enough
by the time you've worked through all 100 of them you let me know will you
because it'll be here you're 5090 and whether the world's going to end that
year it's another question I get do you think the world's gonna end in the year
5063 I'm what the hell does he care you'll get this I mean getting lost and
then you can't see the forest for the trees it's totally irrelevant you know
whether the world's gonna end people from the future in another dimension are
gonna get you ready to end you know
and all that's been going on you know for centuries for centuries you know the
fallacious so how can you tell the fallacious then without calibrating it
and he and these things are important because I think teachers are responsible
for warning the students of the downside therefore I've tried to want to remind
warn people of the downside so you don't get blindsided the downside of the
five-hundreds there's a downside to each level
consciousness and we covered in this book I'm finishing each each level has
its downside and its upside and we'll get to that by the end of lecture so
spiritual truth then is that which is universally been true throughout all of
time what Socrates saw as truth in 350 BC is no different than the truth as
verified by consciousness research or psychology or psychoanalysis it's
universally truth is always true
and of course the first spokesman of truth I don't want to emails on this the
first spokesman of truth as far as I know we're around 500 BC you know the
aryan great aryan sages in ancient India came out with the advanced levels of
truth the great sages throughout history are all self-realized and mystics and
together with
divine
divine incarnation.
For truth to be true, it has to be
universally so
throughout all of time.
It cannot depend on ethnic,
geographic belief
systems. It's not
exclusive. Nobody is excluded
from it. It's available to everybody.
It's open to all.
It can't be hidden, sold for a price.
And I'm holding
a real secret
for $50.
I'll come around and whisper to you.
Have your money handy.
Here's the message.
You've just wasted $50.
I can go in any
legitimate spiritual library,
pull out a book, take out
two sentences and do a workshop on it.
You know what I mean?
For $350, I'll tell you to be kind to your mother.
Okay, you knew that at the beginning, didn't you?
I'll tell you the value of workshops
that are for sale.
They often become
commercialized.
The value of a workshop is
that it's something you've heard and you knew
all along, but you never got around
to doing it. And now for $500
and doing it all
weekend, yeah,
you do it. So it isn't that
you've gotten something wonderful.
It's that now you've been forced to
sit down and practice it.
So it isn't the wonderment of this great
mystery being revealed to you.
It's just that you spend all this time
and energy and all that shot a whole weekend.
Now you're going to do it.
Now you're going to actually forgive everybody.
Oh, you knew that all along,
didn't you?
If we do a workshop in which you think up
everything that you haven't forgiven
and then we say, can you forgive that?
We just do that. We do this hour after hour.
We'll do it for a whole weekend
until you've run out of people that you're pissed at.
You're going to be
in a greater state of serenity.
Why? Because you did what
a person who lives the kind of
creative, spiritually oriented lifestyle
does anyway. As it comes up
they automatically process it.
Okay, so the workshop
gets you to do what you would otherwise
just say, oh, I know that, but not
do it.
Spiritual truth has nothing to sell,
nothing to gain or lose,
non-sectarian.
It's independent of people's opinion,
devoid of
positionality, no
requirements. Membership
regulations, you don't have to sign anything.
You don't have to sign anything.
You don't have to sign anything. Oaths, rules or conditions.
It was Jesus, somebody,
I always said never to take any oaths.
Somebody asked where did it come from.
I said, I don't know, I've just always known it.
And somebody who's Christian wrote me
and said, Jesus said that.
I said, wow, I knew I heard it someplace.
Non-controlling.
You hear of all
the cult leaders and gurus and all
that try to control their members
and even threaten them if they try to leave.
Why would anybody
be interested in the personal lives
of their followers or
students or whatever you want to call them?
You know, sex life,
what you eat, what you wear.
No desire to control
sex lives, economics,
family pattern, you should marry this person
and I'll marry this person,
etc. Free of force or
intimidation. No brainwashing.
You don't have to sit down and get brainwashed.
You don't have to memorize anything.
We're not going to do
an inculcated training ritual.
Which are really, actually
indoctrinations. Move on.
That's how Islamic
terrorists are recruited
by the way, by the repetition
of the Wahhabism.
Non-binding.
No regulations.
Complete freedom. People can come and go.
If you decide to leave, we're not going
to put a snake in your mailbox.
Avoids
glamorization. Truth attracts
by its own
intrinsic power.
The spiritually advanced person
when they're really advanced
sort of intuits it.
When they hear it, they go, wow.
When you hear what Socrates said, you say,
God, yeah, that's, you just instantly
see the truth of it.
Inspirational.
Non-materialistic.
Devoid of theatrics.
There's a lot of
seduction.
Seduction.
The spiritual teacher theater.
The theater of the spiritual teacher.
The theater of the guru.
It's really a
theatrical production.
You know, theatrical production.
All right.
It's benign.
It's detached. It's self-fulfilling.
It's non-materialistic.
Non-intentional.
Non-dualistic.
Equality. Non-temporal.
Beyond proof.
Ineffable.
And therefore, mystical.
The highest truths have always been
as a result
of the consequence of the presence
of the self, with a capital S.
When you remove
the interferences of the
ego positions, the source
of one's own existence shines forth
from within.
Traditionally called the self, with a capital S.
The pathway of
non-duality.
The pathway of the Buddha.
And some people, it's relied via
the
. Incarnation.
Jesus Christ was an incarnation.
But by that,
the radiance emanates
from within.
Simplistic, it affirms truth.
Doesn't do anything.
God doesn't do anything.
God is everything.
Huh?
To do, you'd have to have a dualistic
doer and a deed.
All is what it is.
What does anything mean?
What a thing means
is what it is.
What it is, is its meaning.
Ain't that cute?
I love it.
What it is, is its meaning
complete and total.
Anything you say about it is
is an encumbrance
that really beclouds the truth.
What does a chair mean?
What it means.
This is what it means.
Alright, what happened to our...
She took away the truth.
Truth. Truth.
It's down, huh?
Oh, these modern gadgets, I don't know.
What happened to it?
It went away.
Well, we'll see what does it.
The world of technology, I don't have a computer.
And I'm afraid of them.
I walk around them because they buzz
and make noises and flashlights and this
rattles me.
You could be doing something with it.
What does that mean?
Oh, well, we'll talk then.
Alright, so spiritual integrity then.
We've listed a hundred teachers
and frankly, after you've finished with all of them,
then write me about some guy who wrote a book
about other dimensions and other times
and all that stuff.
Okay.
When you've run out of it,
integrity teachers,
then write me and ask me what they got to write.
As I said, we used to answer them,
but then we find it's all over the email
and then you get,
oh, how come you said so and so, you know.
And I can't live in that world.
So, contention is not a happy lifestyle.
Contention is not conducive to peace of mind.