So this is a question about experience. When I saw up on the chart the different qualities of divinity, the experience of those qualities seems to be different than the experience of the functioning of allness, the oneness.
If the qualities are different from the functioning of the wholeness, and that's the difference in the experience.
The wholeness and the oneness doesn't function. It is.
Yes.
Isness doesn't function, doesn't do. There's no this to do with that. That's a dualistic conception.
The qualities of divinity are not the same as the essence of divinity.
Five foot eight by 110 pounds.
It's not your essence, it's a quality.
So divinity, the feeling of it is, even the presence of love is overwhelming.
At the same time, infinitely powerful cannot be described.
It'd be like describing an infinitely powerful powder puff. There's no way to really explain it.
It's infinitely powerful and exquisite and irresistible and omnipotent.
It is omnipotent.
Yeah, it's infinitely powerful.
At the same time, exquisitely loving and gentle, yeah.
Make sure you're talking to both microphones.
Put them closer together, maybe, so they don't clank.
Oh, you get feedback.
Yes.
First, thank you for that answer to my friend's question about the anxiety, because I'm going to have to play that over and over.
Oh.
This question has to do with a job, again.
I had a chance to pursue...
A job that was very linear, lots of left brain material, and I decided not to because I didn't want to put all my energy into that,
all my focus right now, at this point, into all that left brain.
Detail, huh?
So, can something like that actually hinder you spiritually if you don't feel inclined to go there?
You can't make a rule about it.
At one time, forcing yourself into...
Sequential linearity could, you know, will slow down the process
and shift your attention and energy elsewhere
that might be doing better in a more non-linear awareness consciousness program, you know?
Right.
So, it just depends where you are in your life and what you're...
Yeah, it depends on a multitude of factors.
I don't think it can really be answered.
Like, I have a stack of things in my desk at home.
I said, I can't get into it this week.
I got a lecture Saturday.
That's my excuse this week.
Next week, I'll find a new excuse.
Yeah.
There's a reluctance as you get more advanced.
There's like a reluctance to get into linear memorization and that kind of thing
because you're trying to be left brain when your energies are moving more right brain holistically.
It would have felt more like going to school.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Thank you.
I can see that, yeah.
It's a conflict, yeah.
Yeah.
Yes?
When I'm reading something of yours or listening to one of your lectures and I'm stuck and I know I can't understand what it is you're trying.
The issue is moralistic relativity and also...
What issue is what?
Moralistic.
I'm getting...
Oh, moral relativism.
Relativism, that's it.
Oh, yeah.
It's okay.
I can't even get it, say it right.
So, it's pretty much a good sign that I'm suffering from it when I can't understand what you're trying to teach about it.
So, I'm wondering if I may have started to seek some clarity or if you can clean me up here.
I'm wondering...
Tell me what you said.
I don't even know what you said.
Okay.
Straighten up what?
You promised moral relativism?
What is your problem with moral relativism?
It's rather clear and obvious, isn't it?
I think it's true if I say it's true and it's not true if I say it's not true.
And morality is idiotic.
It's an impairment of my entitlement to express myself.
Any way I want, because we have freedom of speech.
And physical physicality is symbolic speech.
How do you like my freedom to choke you to death?
I got it.
You see what I'm saying?
Yeah.
No.
In other words, there's no limitation, no wall that differentiates a livable environment.
There's truth.
At each level, there's its own truth.
And so, is there...
Is there that same moralistic...
Yeah, the MR.
The MR.
Is that occur at each level?
Or is that...
What?
Relativism.
No, no.
Moral relativism is below 200.
Okay.
Over 200 doesn't make any sense.
That's why the Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals calibrates very low.
If I say, you know, we have free speech.
If I say, action is symbolic speech, then I'm entitled to any action I want, right?
Because there's no right or wrong.
There is no criteria.
There's actually no law.
What you've just done is undone the nation.
Right.
Because now the nation has nothing upon which to rely.
Even the law, then, is just merely relativism.
I don't have to obey the law, because that's a restriction of my freedom.
And I have freedom of expression.
You understand?
Yeah.
And there's absolute...
But there's also absolute truth.
I mean, that's what kind of supersedes that, right?
Well, what they're talking about are statements, and statements about action.
They're not talking about truth.
They're talking about moral laws.
They're just playing a game, right?
In a way?
An ego game?
Lewis Carroll.
He was a looking glass.
Right.
The Mad Hatter says, well...
I think it was the Mad Hatter.
Who was it?
The rabbit says, when I say a word, it means what I mean it to mean.
Nothing more, nothing less.
The Mad Hatter.
So you're setting yourself up almost as divinity.
Reality is what I say is reality.
And it's not reality if I say it's not reality.
So it's the absurdity of the Mad Hatter that I pointed out to illustrate the absurdity of moral relativism.
Because moral relativism says that...
logic and reason are what?
An infringement of one's freedom.
But if all statements are questionable and untrue, then so is that statement.
Moral relativism has nothing to stand on because, like skepticism, it hangs itself by its own petard.
If there's no standard of truth, then the criticism of truth also has no standard upon which to stand.
Yeah.
That's what the rabbit has to say today.
The Mad Hatter.
The Mad Hatter, yeah.
The Mad Hatter said that?
Yeah.
Oh.
Yes.
You mentioned earlier that the chances were 1,000% easier now to reach enlightenment.
Is it getting easier to stay physical after enlightenment than it used to be?
I don't know about that.
The chances of reaching enlightenment are 1,000 times greater.
That we confirm many times.
Mm-hmm.
I don't know what question to ask about it.
I always feel, within myself, that there's like a, prior to this incarnation, there was
a commitment, an agreement, an understanding.
I think I find myself holding back.
Holding back what?
From wanting to reach enlightenment, because I don't want to leave.
You got a little work to do.
I'm too attached.
Hehehe.
Now eventually the body becomes immaterial.
If it keeps walking on, that's fine, and if it don't keep walking on, because you don't
even know what it's going to do.
The personal will doesn't even intervene.
I can remember walking down the aisle and turning around and didn't know whether one
would get to the end or not, out of curiosity, watch what happened.
I made 180 at the end and walked back again.
Other times the body will breathe again or it won't.
It's immaterial which way it goes.
No, if it breathes, it breathes, and if it doesn't, it doesn't.
Many times I've been just waiting to die and sat there waiting to leave, and it didn't
happen.
Darn.
The smoke is shooting out from the engine on fire, the smoke behind the dashboard, you
know.
There I am out, a million miles from anywhere, it's 110 out, I'm dehydrated, I've got nothing.
An annoyingness came from within.
Take a screwdriver and jam it through the bottom of the glove compartment, wham.
Now there's a couple of drops of coffee left in there, pour it through there.
I poured it through there, I was just sitting there waiting to leave, it said to do that,
so I did that.
Psst, the fire went out, it was an electrical fire, and the point where I drove the car
with the screwdriver was exactly over the fire, underneath the hood, the electrical
done on my old truck over the last 30 years, it was like a mass of wires, just the left
brain never could attract where it was coming from.
So was that asked for?
I don't know.
It just came on to do that, and I did that, and so the body's still going.
So you surrender your life to God, surrender your body to God, surrender your life to God,
whether it walks on or not.
It's been up to God.
And if you have a karmic role to play, you will obviously play it, you know?
And if you don't, you leave, so.
As I said, here's this mind right here, you know, and this guy looks at me, and we're
looking at each other, he says, well, what if we don't, we can't keep it away from the
ship?
I said, so we die.
Oh, he says, okay.
The total acceptance of it, he accepted it, and then I accepted it because of my experience
in the snowbank.
But in the energy.
In the energy of the acceptance, he was able to accept it, and he said, oh, yeah, right.
Okay.
It's okay if you want to leave.
You can leave anything you want.
Oh, you can hang in.
It didn't matter much to me.
Thank you.
You got permission to stay as well.
You don't have to feel guilty about staying.
Some people feel guilty that they haven't died yet.
You don't have to worry about it.
Thank you.
That was a fun question.
Yes?
Thank you to both of you for all of the work you've done.
On a couple of your Cs, I'm going to ask you a question.
I'm going to ask you a question.
On a couple of your CDs, you mention a couple of phrases that I particularly like, like
so I put them on a T-shirt for you, so, so what, and then it seemed like a good idea
at the time.
Seemed like a good idea at the time.
That's great.
Yeah.
That's how you forgive yourself for everything in the past.
It seemed like a good idea at the time.
Yeah.
And then I also heard that you like fortune cookies.
So, I mean, the toy business is all electronic fortune cookies.
I thought I would just give it to you.
Thank you, sir.
Yeah.
Thank you.
My question, I apologize for it, because I know a lot of people have asked it over the
months, but I still don't quite get it.
And you mentioned that your time of death is preset.
Yes.
And then on some of the tapes, you also talk about, you know, extreme sports or even the
colleagues you knew who lived in a bubble and kept getting smaller and smaller.
The things they'd eat.
So, I'm a bit confused on if your time of death is set, why the extreme sports would
make a difference.
Why?
What would make a difference?
When you said extreme sports.
Extreme sports.
If your time of death is already destined, set, then why would extreme sports make a
difference?
Well, the means of it is not set.
Hypothetically, there would seem to be a disparity there, see, but if you get into a context
beyond the two alternates.
You have a this versus a that, then you'll see they're both the same.
Okay.
Sometimes there's a, see, the deeper the fear, the greater the length you gotta go.
Some people have to go over Niagara Falls in a barrel to overcome that fear, see?
So you see extremes to overcome that fear.
People are driven to mad, mad extremes.
You know, some mountain where 76 people have already died.
You go up to that peak, and here they are at 20,000 feet with no oxygen.
And I'm looking, and they got a coach with them.
Where is this coach's head taking people up there at 18,000 feet with no oxygen?
Of course they're gonna get exhausted, of course they're gonna get confused, and they
charge money for that as a guide?
I want a refund.
I want oxygen over 10, you know, in a plane over 10,000 you get oxygen, not 18,000.
Kilimanjaro.
How many has Kilimanjaro killed?
How many people have died trying to climb Kilimanjaro?
Hundreds.
Look it up, it's sort of fun.
Slew of people.
This is the weight of certain death, okay, let's get back and go on it.
Would you also be willing to calibrate how much the consciousness of the group raised
today?
The consciousness of the group?
We haven't done that in a long time.
Uh, no, but I know what it is.
The great books of the Western world.
We're at the level of the great books of the Western world.
How's that for erudition?
We're over the great books of the Western world.
The consciousness level of this crowd is beyond that of the great books of the Western world,
the collective wisdom of mankind throughout the ages.
So we've evolved then into, the group has evolved into the 500s.
The group's gone into the 500s.
Thank you very much.
See, there's a couple of major jumps.
200.
Uh, then to get out of emotionality, running your life and get to rationality at 400.
Then to get out of linear cause and effect, which is the Newtonian paradigm at 499.
And the hardest jump is to make the jump from the 400s to the 500s.
That's the hardest one.
And a group like this naturally, yeah, evolves into the 500s.
Are we allowed to get photos?
You can have a photo.
Oh, come on.
Can I stand next to you?
Yeah.
Robert will help you.
He's good at that.
I want to focus.
You want, you want to be in the picture?
Come on.
See, you want to be in the picture.
Okay.
Where's my quack quack?
Where's my, anyway, thank you.
Doc, look at me.
Your fortune cookie.
Thank you very much.
My quack quack.
Computerized fortune cookie, yeah?
Remember what we said the calibrated level of fortune cookies was?
I forget.
Oh, honey, your book.
350 or something.
Over.
Yes.
Next question.
Well, if someone is on the spiritual path, and at the end of their life goes into a negative
dimension.
What does that mean for the consciousness?
Somebody's what?
In a spiritual path and at the end of their life or towards the end of their life, they
go into a negative...
Oh.
They fall, huh?
Well, they would then have the karma propensities of a person at that level.
We see that in the so called fallen gurus.
Who?
And I'm thinking of one now that hit 600 and then crashed below 200.
I'm thinking of another one that was in the 500, again crashed below 200.
So the great temptations come up, see?
The great temptations.
And as I said, as the Buddha called it, demons are looking through the chinks in your armor
to see where you're susceptible.
Vanity will give you a title, Grand Maha, Grand Mahatma.
And then we'll give you swirly clothes, and we'll let people go, wah, wah, wah.
And if that don't get you, then we'll try your money.
We'll pour money on you and see if that gets you.
And if that don't get you, how about a slinky girl who says,
sex is holy, let's get holy, you know what I mean?
So it keeps looking for a chunk, or vanity, vanity, vanity.
It keeps looking for where to get you.
I remember I explained to you the knowingness that came.
Now that you're not karmically answerable, all power is yours.
See, because love is a constraint.
Because of love, you'll only go so far with people.
But just your love of other people as fellow humans will curtail you.
You won't tear them to pieces with your teeth that you would below 200.
So this was a temptation of power.
And I remember, as I said, it was like a high pass.
I could see who had been through there.
And I saw Jesus Christ went there.
I saw exactly what he went through.
All power is yours.
All you have to do is be willing to sell out integrity and honor
and buy stocks in the right company.
I was thinking about a dementia, you know, a brain.
Dementia, yes.
Oh, that kind of deterioration.
Right.
That's of a different level.
See, there are levels.
There's the physical, mental, and spiritual.
You know, physicality.
Physicality would have a different karmic propensity, you know,
and it takes a genetic pattern, very often genetic pattern.
The person within is unaffected, you know,
and I used to be the only psychiatrist that would go to all the nursing homes
in Yavapai County.
I'm away home from the girls' ranch.
I had all of them all the way home.
I ever got home before dark, I don't know,
but 30,000 miles a year running around.
And the family would be all upset because mother, you know,
was forgetful and all this, didn't recognize me.
Well, that's their ego.
It just got hurt.
I'd say, mother, how is it here?
Oh, they're very nice to me.
Oh.
I said, do they treat you well?
Oh, yes.
Would you like to be someplace else?
No, no.
I think this is just fine.
She's perfectly at serenity and peace,
and I always feel like the spirit is already half gone over.
If she were agitated, would that be a different?
Agitation would be a different thing.
It would be a reaction to it, and therefore,
you could treat the agitation, yes.
You're wondering about the karmic implications of that.
Yes, sir.
I don't know.
I'd have to do a little research on it.
Right.
I doubt that your spiritual destiny is going to be determined
by the linear physicality of its expression.
Yeah.
As long as we remember who we are, we're okay.
Just remember that you're you.
Somebody says, who am I?
You say, I'm me.
Oh, you pass.
That's the test of the cat.
Yes.
Well, I've had this discussion with you lots of times.
You just haven't been there, so I thought I'd bring it up now.
What's that?
What discussion?
Kind of back to what the lady brought up before
about the day of our death, our physical death,
is written the day we're born.
It's not written.
It's recorded?
How do I think of it?
It's like a tape.
If you get a tape of a movie,
the end of the movie is already on the tape.
It's not an infinite tape.
It doesn't go on forever.
So every movie has a terminal point.
And it's sequential.
After this event, this event, this event.
And then after this event, that's the end of the movie.
With that in mind,
I keep wondering about our preoccupation
with this physical death.
When we look at what we like to term disasters,
we have a natural disaster and a thousand people die.
We have buildings fall in New York
and thousands of people die.
If those occasions hadn't arisen,
wouldn't all of those people have died from a heart attack
or something that day?
It's a hypothetical.
I don't know if that's a good question.
I don't know that I can answer it.
I see it more like group karma,
that it's not by accident.
Remember the bridge of St. Louis Ray?
Why were those, what was it, six people or so and so,
crossing the bridge when it collapsed?
Why those six people out of all the civilizations?
Karmic propensity and influences are hard to explain
within a logical, linear way.
They're subtle and more inferential.
You just happen to be
where those things happen.
You know, you could ask what is the karmic destiny
of somebody whose house blows down in a hurricane
and immediately they rebuild it in exactly the same place.
California coast, the mudslides.
One expensive house after another falls down.
So it's not that it's a specific day
these people are going to die.
It was after a series of events that they were killed.
I think it's more the fulfillment of a story than a date.
I have permission to ask this.
It's the fulfillment of the story that brings the story to the end.
Okay.
Yeah, that's a good question.
Cool.
So it's not stamped into like a date.
Yeah.
And if I might, one more.
If in fact there's no cause and effect,
what are we taking responsibility for
when we're taking responsibility not for only what we do
but previous lives that we didn't cause?
Well, that you're the source, let's say.
Not the cause, but you're the source.
Well, we share the karmic consequences of that
which we cheer on and align with.
So if you're a proponent of bullfighting,
then you share somewhat the karmic consequence
of that which okays cruelty to animals for amusement.
With the bullfighter.
Because what are they getting out of the bullfight?
Amusement.
An amusing afternoon for you, but not for the bull, yeah?
And often not for the matador either.
Unless they adopt children afterwards.
That's a fact.
On several occasions now,
while doing A Course in Miracle lessons,
I hear a voice and my question is whether or not
I should completely ignore this?
What do you mean here? Auditory?
Yes.
What kind of things does it say to you?
On a couple of occasions,
it's kind of pointing me to read something
or go someplace.
And other times it's maybe more fearful things.
It's like an inner voice.
Yes.
But it's experienced as though it's auditory.
Mm-hmm.
Let's see what we can figure that is.
That is...
I think I intuit what it is.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
What I'm holding is correct.
It's a segmentation.
It's a segmentation off of a piece of the personality.
I'd own it back as yourself.
Should I put faith in what I hear
or just kind of observe it?
No, no.
It's got nothing to do with what the content.
Mm-hmm.
It has to do with the phenomena.
All right.
So I have permission to ask this.
It's a dissociated aspect of its own personality.
It's a dissociated aspect of your own personality.
Like a separate self?
Like you've separated off from it
as though it is not you.
I get it's a dissociated small little part
of your personality.
I don't know.
I'd have to see in the office.
You'd have to lay down on the couch
in a couple of years and figure it out.
Why you, you know?
Yeah.
I think the way I heal it is I would deny
that it's separate from yourself
and own it that it is yourself.
And just as...
Because even if you heard it through another voice,
it's what you're holding in mind
that's sounding back to you.
It could be a dissociated thought
that you don't want to own, you know?
So is it as much of an unreality
as everything else that goes on in one's mind?
It's no more real nor unreal
than anything else that goes on in your mind.
You have dreams, right?
That doesn't mean you're loony.
It's just meaning you're having a dream.
So you're having an auditory dream while you're awake.
Yeah?
Thank you.
Yeah.
Own it back as a portion of your own personality.
That's, you know, that that is also me.
Just as your dreams.
You don't disown your dreams.
Whose dreams are they?
Waking dream.
Waking auditory dream.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Let's see.
That is quick diagnosis.
My goodness.
Yeah.
Thank you for giving this opportunity to come
and be able to say how grateful we are
to all that you've given to us.
Thank you.
Wonderful gift to have this time with you.
I was interested today as you were talking about,
you were talking about spiritual teachers
and I was, came to mind Victor Frankl
and his experience,
of having to, having, being able to find grace
in the middle of hell
and how that relates to your experience of finding grace.
Victor Frankl ended up writing a book.
He was at a concentration camp.
Right.
And he wrote about an aspect of psychology
that was really very important
and I can't specifically give you the exact name of it.
Logos, wasn't it?
That's maybe not the book but the concept.
Logos therapy.
Well, that's not what it was about.
I believe the title of the book was Man's Search for Meaning.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Oh, right.
Yes.
That looking for meaning is instinctual.
It's one of the instincts.
Freud did not mention it as an instinct.
He said it's sufficiently powerful
and I think that's true
because when we talk about spiritual fantasy,
see, it's like people are always looking for meaning
and if they can't find meaning, they'll invent one.
Man wants to know what it means.
So you get together the facts,
but what do they mean?
So, yes, I liked Frankl
and it was like the will to meaning is instinctual
and I agreed with him for the more advanced.
But you see, even primitive man wanted to know
what is the meaning of a volcano?
He invented angry gods and sacrificed maidens.
What is the meaning of natural phenomena?
You know, kinda like the problems and the problems and the answers.
Was that experience for him
of finding love and ultimate love in the middle of hell
similar to the experience you had
in finding God in the middle of hell
or was it a different experience?
Oh, I don't know.
Well, his was an external hell.
Mine was internal.
But internally, he experienced probably the same.
Extreme, extreme.
Thank you.
and I've forgotten about them.
Dr. Frankel wrote that man has an instinctive drive
to discern meaning.
Meaning.
Yeah.
Thank you both.
I have a very hard question for me.
I have intuited that some physical challenges
that have come up are a karmic undoing.
But my question is,
if I surrender the guilt
and ask for a miracle to have the guilt removed,
is that the right spiritual path to take
or do I need to unwork the karma?
How to process it?
I would work on all levels simultaneously.
I'd pray for a miracle to see it as it is in truth.
I would also,
I would also pray for whatever the negative side of this is
within yourself.
Assume it's something within yourself.
And pray for the opposite of that,
paradoxically, to undo it.
And keep reaffirming that you're an infinite being
and you're only subject to what you hold in mind.
And forgive yourself for whatever it is.
I felt like it wasn't just my own guilt,
but that I had an unforgiveness
from someone stabbing me in the back.
Yeah.
And back in a past life.
And the betrayal of that
was such a heart pain
that I haven't been able to let that go.
Betrayal.
Yes, betrayal.
And it wasn't the physical death,
but the betrayal.
No, it was the betrayal.
Yes.
All right, so you can undo the betrayal.
Think what Jesus Christ must have felt
when he was kissed by a friend.
So you share, you see,
how Christ suffered for all.
Betrayal by a trusted friend.
Yeah, pray for the forgiveness
of the one in you who betrays others.
Yeah.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
How does one best dissolve the duality
between oneself and God?
It isn't a duality.
That's a linguistic event you just recorded.
There is no duality between oneself and God.
But it seems that oneself is so small
in comparison to God.
The personal self.
Yes.
Yes, the personal self is small.
That's why they call it the small self.
Yes.
It's not a disparity.
It's like you are already within that
and have set up some falsity
so that you don't realize
that you are at one with the one,
that you're separate from the one.
You know, it's like,
it just takes constant spiritual work
of one kind or another
and then eventually that falls away.
Is it a matter of seeing oneself as limited?
Discrete, yeah.
Thank you.
Yes.
Last month,
you were talking about
the Buddha came to teach us enlightenment,
but Jesus came to teach us salvation.
Can you talk a little bit about
what you mean by salvation?
Salvation means that you,
in and of yourself,
haven't earned enough positive karma
to enter the kingdom of heaven.
Therefore, by your commitment to your teacher,
your teacher then becomes your advocate
before God at the right hand.
He speaks for you.
And she is dedicated to the truth.
And I will speak for her.
And therefore, you're admitted
because it's so,
it's the same in the Lotus Land Buddhism
where an aspect of the Buddha
is actually the Buddha.
This is your savior.
That you can get to this realm
and the savior then speaks for you.
That you, in and of yourself,
unaided, don't have enough karmic momentum
to enter that celestial domain, celestial.
So you're asking to enter the celestial.
The celestial can be entered
if you are under the tutelage of a master.
The savior then acts differently
than enlightenment.
Enlightenment on your own.
Thank you.
I will speak for you before the father
at the right hand of the father
because of your dedication to me.
Yeah.
Dr. Hawkins,
when you speak of forces that are hostile to us,
to an enlightened seeker
or a seeker of enlightenment.
Yes.
It kicks back in me
to old Christian teachings
that I judged were fear-based
being hostile beings.
Demons, possession, that type of stuff.
Is that what you're talking about?
And if so, are there practical defenses
that we who are not enlightened yet
can take or should take?
You just follow your spiritual path.
Then, like I say, power over the world,
power over the world,
is lost as integrity takes,
as integrity gets more and stronger
and stronger,
than as you saw on Wall Street,
real calm when all of them began to fall.
Therefore, they would consider integrity
to be their enemy
because it would be their unmasking.
It would be whipping the sheep's clothing
off the wolf.
Yes.
So this is more internal
as far as...
This isn't...
Yes, I know what you're talking about.
It's enough to make you paranoid.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
That's interesting.
What you're talking about
is the paranoia, the paranoid fear.
That as you reach a higher and higher level,
that which is...
It attracts that which is your antithesis
to try and attack it
because it feels threatened by you.
Yes, falsehood feels threatened by truth.
That is so.
And the more it feels threatened,
the more vociferous it gets,
the louder it yells,
and the more savagely it attacks.
Is that not so?
Yes.
How popular is...
How popular is it to quote from the Constitution
that Congress shall make no law
prohibiting...
No, establishing religion
nor prohibiting the free exercise thereof?
How popular is the last half of that sentence?
I haven't heard a one.
Even the conservative religious people
quote the Constitution correctly.
Nor prohibit the free exercise thereof.
I mean, can't they read English?
So, you know,
you see,
if I choose to emphasize that,
get to be a blogger,
blog it all over the place,
write letters to everybody,
I'll arouse that which is hostile to that viewpoint.
Yeah?
Nor prohibit the free exercise thereof.
Santa Claus.
Yeah?
Dr. Hawkins.
The study group that I belong to
has been...
focusing on prayer.
And there's an old saying
that we should pray
as though everything depends upon God
and work as though everything depends upon us.
And how does that calibrate?
That's a neat saying.
What's the first part of the sentence again?
You pray as though everything depends upon God.
Yes, yes.
You're totally dependent on God, yes.
Yes, work as though everything depended on you.
Oh, yes.
Put forth your most effort.
You want to know what that quote calibrates that?
Yes.
Okay.
We have permission to quote that.
It's over 350,
380,
390,
400,
395,
395.
Okay.
Does it change if,
instead of saying work as though everything depends upon us,
to say be,
to be,
does that alter the...
Does it change?
The call it calibration to be because to work is to do and to do calibrates lower than to be from...
It doesn't really matter what it calibrates.
It doesn't.
No, it's integrous.
Okay.
It's taking responsibility at the same time acknowledging the sovereignty of God.
So it's a very excellent saying, I think.
All right, thank you very much.
It's similar to the 12-step group say, you know,
you're responsible for the effort, but not the result.
So you're accountable for the effort.
The result is up to an altitude of forces, karmic and otherwise.
Yes.
That you can't have anything to do with it, but you're karmically rewarded by having done the best you can,
so far as you see your responsibility, yeah?
Yes.
Thank you.
Thank you, Susan.
Yeah.
I...
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Hawkins, in truth versus falsehood,
you included a chart calibrating ancient societies.
The ones that calibrated by far the highest was Atlantis.
When and where was Atlantis?
No, I didn't calibrate the level of Atlantis.
I calibrated Atlantis was an actual reality rather than a fantasy.
It says it was a reality.
Yeah.
You said it was a 295.
Did I?
I don't remember.
Right here.
Historical societies.
It calibrated 290, yes.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Just...
So, it did exist.
That's what we...
Yes.
In fact, we got a confirmation of its location, even.
Okay.
And that was where?
I forget now.
Is it...
I think they closed up now.
I don't remember.
Is it a very ancient society?
I mean, before our recorded history, or is it...
Before our recorded history, well, don't forget Plato.
Right.
Yeah.
You know, recounted the history of Atlantis.
Okay.
Yeah.
There is much...
Evidence.
And we did calibrate.
There was research that indicated its location.
And I forget where that location was.
There were several provisional locations.
They were not correct.
But there was one they did get the other correct.
I forget.
The Greek isle someplace.
We weren't supposed to share it.
That's what...
Oh, okay.
Okay.
I'm sorry about the question.
I didn't know anything about it.
Okay.
So, we got...
We couldn't share it, but...
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
All right.
Thank you.
Yep.
You're thinking of the...
You're thinking of Cayce.
Cayce's readings on Atlantis.
Yeah.
But I mean, we got...
Okay.
I got you.
Yeah.
Hi.
My question is in regards to the evolution of human consciousness and in regards to
group.
You say that we come all in together and sometimes we leave together.
Yeah.
It sort of is.
So, with realms ranging from the lower astrals all the way up to the celestial realms, what's
the difference?
Yeah.
What happens when we are not on the earth plane?
Do we...
Is there a human...
The classic answer is the inner planes, that you stay out, you're out, you're in spirit
and not a physicality and that you reincarnate when no group decides it's for the benefit
of everyone.
I don't know if they vote or what, everybody.
We tend to come in together.
Yeah.
I think by attraction.
All right.
We tend to group together by attraction, yeah.
It's our flock, and our flock is starting to leave, you know.
So if we're a bunch of pelicans and a bunch of them start to leave,
hey, we join the flock because everybody's going back, you know.
What about, you said that the human life is like a videotape
with an ending already apparently within it.
What about humanness as a reality?
What about what?
Humanness.
Like the physicality of humanness as a society.
Is there an end in the tape, our story?
And if so, would there be another realm with physicalness?
I don't know.
Evolutionary-wise, you mean as a group or as an individual?
As a group, as human.
As mankind.
Does mankind eventually, collectively, my picture of it,
I'd have to research it out,
my picture of it is that will they all eventually transcend physicality?
Well, it means that we're not done with what we've got to do,
but we're doing it in a different realm, in a higher dimension, you know.
Is the Earth the only, you said that there's infinite number of realities and realms.
Is Earth the only physical, karmic reality?
I never asked it.
I have permission to ask about Earth.
Earth is the only human, physical, planetary habitat at this time, or is this?
No, not.
Okay.
So, see?
Venus, maybe.
We'll see you on the planet called Platitudinous.
That's out of just west of Florinus in the north of Hopeful.
She's good-looking and smart.
Let's see, my question has to do with brain injury.
You mentioned that a little bit.
I heard about mild traumatic brain injury a couple years ago,
and I was just wondering if there's more, or, you know, like, what's more to do with it?
I've gone through a lot of therapy and treatment,
and I see it kind of two ways.
You had mentioned that possibly astral realms are more susceptible.
That could be in some cases, but there's karmic propensities there, too, you know.
I also see it as kind of like a blank slate, in a sense,
and it's an easier place to start over, so.
Well, there's, like, altered brain function, injury, temporal lobe, epilepsy, intoxication,
that is sometimes an avenue, but they heal up, and then the entity has to leave.
And then, going off some other questions, you had talked about the Robert Bannister effect.
Yeah.
And I can't differentiate between going to the top of Everest and the Robert Bannister effect.
The intention, the intention.
What's the intention?
Yeah, the intention is different.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
She said, I don't want to pay for the helicopter to go get him, for God's sake.
But he wants to climb the highest mountain to put a deposit.
Helicopter deposit.
If you return unscathed, you get your deposit back.
What do you call those big dogs that rescue the people in the snow?
St. Bernard.
They have to contribute to the St. Bernard Fund.
Okay, I'd just like to thank you for putting on this program for us today,
and Susan and your staff, we certainly appreciate you hosting this affair.
I just had one more question about having the time of death set.
So that's not a calendar date, then.
Is that more of a when it gets to the end of the year?
The end of the tape?
We get the, you know, we have permission to ask this.
It's when it gets to the end of the tape.
So therefore, it's not a calendar date, is it?
Yeah, it's not a calendar date.
Okay.
You can renew next year's calendar.
You can get a 2006.
Okay, very good.
Thank you.
Waste all that money on a 2006 calendar, and I'm leaving in December.
Okay.
Susan, you want to talk to us?
I have one quick question, and then I have a second one I'd like more elaboration on.
The first one is this change in intestinal motility, detecting lying.
Is that usually auditory or olfactory?
That's a very good question.
Thank you.
I have another question.
All right.
As would be the case of many people in this room, they calibrate higher than some of the teachers.
Can they still gain a lot, even if they may, if some people may calibrate higher than those teachers?
Yeah, sure.
The simple things of life often get overlooked and neglected, you know?
Who was the famous longshoreman, Eric Hoffer?
Yeah.
Eric Hoffer.
The simple but stark English.
That's definitely true, and people overlook that.
So, could a person who calibrates higher than Eric Hoffer give benefit by reading Eric Hoffer?
Yes, I think so, because none of us is total and complete in all the potentialities that we could be total and complete.
Yeah.
That's good.
Thank you very much.
I calibrated Eric Hoffer one time.
I forget what it was.
I think it was over 500.
500.
510.
505.
Mm-hmm.
I knew he was over 500.
That's for you, Susan.
Ah.
I came up here earlier in the year and spoke to you, and I was very, very nervous at that time.
But then, several months later, in the middle of the night, I woke up, and I re-experienced being here with you.
And at that time, it was timeless, infinite space.
Mm-hmm.
I got a little time capsule, and I got it later.
So.
Sweet.
I think this is just maybe like a little report.
So.
She got it.
I didn't want my wife to know about it.
That's great.
Thank you.
Yes, people do report those kind of experiences.
So later, subconscious.
Well, there's spirit.
There's spirit.
travels at night you know she was out of body traveling hello i just wanted to um give you the
gift of my music oh thank you and then i had to drum up a question because i felt silly coming up
but i do have a question that relates still to the gentleman before about non-duality
and then you're talking about as almost an entity in and of itself
uh it almost sounds like evil or temptation or falsehood you you've talked about that and then
it's an energy field yes it's an it is an energy field yeah i get 90. hatred is always an expression
of you might say lower astral level type energy energy field and those are susceptible
you might say lower astral level type energy energy field and those are susceptible to
it become captivated by the field and run by the field and promote hatred of all kinds
religious zealot bombers and baby killers good it's clear thank you got it so it is not in
conflict with non-duality and the no omnipresence omnipotence of god
no thank you that's great hi and i was wondering if you could tell
uh
me a bit more about the spiritual nights uh that you had um and there was a feeling of uh
temptation of succumbing to some sort of power that you mentioned the spiritual night i'm talking
about the archetype of the spiritual night the archetype in the spiritual night or he said there
was a power that you had to um that you tried not to succumb to it's when you when you know
your spiritual night comes up
well the spiritual night we're talking about an archetype we're talking about a chakra within the archetype the spiritual night can be either white or dark yeah yeah all right so the spiritual night comes up and uh fights for truth yeah and the black night comes up and fights for falsehood yeah and is there is it just uh um surrendering that uh is the choice
it isn't a matter of surrendering it's a matter yeah at a certain level of turning it over to god and seeing that it is not you know not your your uh cup of tea you know yeah okay thanks
very much i was complaining about having been caught in it for a period of time yeah i think that's just
you're like driven by it's like a rally because like driven by morality you know because like
take carried away by it yeah so it's you don't want to get carried away by it you want to recognize
uh the certain truth and falsehoods
and levels of integrity but not get carried away by it yeah because then what happens is you bring
up emotion and emotion now becomes irrational you know the emotion so you can be have a correct
premise but go down the twos because the emotionality behind the premise yeah okay thanks
okay i hardly ever have this problem that i've been wrestling with this question for two months
and i know the question inside but i haven't been able to put it in words and i've been praying that
it would be answered so i'm just asking for help and the question has to do with the essential
nature of the non-linear aspect of us and the aspect that we talk about as being human um i
don't seem to be able to grasp what would be the most important aspect of our life
what is the point of enlightenment if we are part of the one and we're coming and having a human
experience i'm not understanding are we human are we created in a certain essence on the other side
that has to go through natural evolution are we part of that essential part of god we're part of
the uh evolution see people get caught up in terminology and they learn uh that we're all
some aspect of god well that makes a cute thing to quote but what does that mean experientially
and intellectually you know we're a limited expression of potentiality and the point of
enlightenment is to realize the unlimited nature that one is the all of it and not just this
limited expression of it so on the non-linear dimension we are still in levels
of the non-linear dimension of the non-linear dimension of the non-linear dimension of the
of enlightenment like you had said that there are beings that from the time of mesopotamia
that are still oh those are entities in other realms you know astral realms here okay yeah
they talk to you from the other side and read your aura and read your dreams but when we come
back and forth into the human experience that essential part of us that's part of the oneness
goes well you're getting caught in terminology oneness is just a concept
all right you don't get caught in oneness well that's probably why i've had a problem
putting this into words yeah it's an erroneous statement that's why you can't make clarity out
of it okay the particular is not the expression of the totality that's correct okay but the only
reason you're particular is because you bought into the linear and when you decline the linear
you go back to the oneness out of which you
originate yeah until we don't have to worry about it right now
well one of the things that i feel that you brought me was spiritual sobriety and i want
to thank you for that and i wanted to ask if we could have a picture here picture
yeah
yeah thank you both you bet you bet wish i could have answered it
you did that's because we're limited in time i'll tell you any one of the questions that people
ask today i could talk for a good hour on easy i could go for a whole hour on that one well mine
will be fast because both the questions i had in mind were already asked and answered and they were
already asked and answered so okay so i appreciate all that you do for us thank you very much
thank you yeah hello doctor hello susan yes um i was thinking of what you said today that we are
reborn every ten thousand of a second yeah the ego is and the ego is yeah uh so uh the experience
is not the same what i experienced a ten thousand of a second ago is not the same ego that is experiencing
right now it's in it tends because of karmic propensity to re-identify with the movie
yeah and uh well my experience uh i started reading power versus force on 2001
and i got busy with all the the rest of the material and now i'm back reading it again
and it's overwhelming i feel like another it's another person that is reading and it's uh
understanding from a deeper deeper level of awareness and uh i realize sometimes what i'm
here is more clear and i think about arjuna when he was with krishna he came out and in this
deep levels of awareness in and out and i realize that it happens to me sometimes i mean i get busy
with the the
um
,
things and some all of a sudden this deep awareness uh comes just
from nothing yeah and it's amazing also i was reading again a book of alcoholics anonymous
called came to believe and it talks about spiritual experiences of the first members
and it's amazing to understand that there was a power of
850 making that possible and it's beautiful incredibly beautiful and my question is um when
you are able to step back and get to the witness experiencer witness observer what do you do next
don't do nothing
yeah
,
you know
hey
so
is there
um
something
una
that i had
the
ah
that
are
about
living
too
long
there is no you that is witnessing and watching then you draw back to
identification with consciousness itself not consciousness as a watcher or
experiencer or witness and it sounds easy but how how do you do it how did you
that sounds very easy but no it's not easy it's a contemplative lifestyle and
being contemplative even about one's own thoughts and thinking this and mental
function and the letting go of the identification and then you eventually
get into the identification with the quality of subjectivity itself how does
know how is knowing this even possible and you pull back more to the level of
consciousness itself thank you very much each thing has a higher level how do you
know what the mind is thinking because of consciousness how do you know you're
conscious because of awareness
how do you how do you know of awareness yeah so you pull back and the rest you
don't have to worry about okay this takes care of itself yeah this this
couple met at our seminar and we're married here at unity church this is
what can happen to you the seminar I congratulate the couple they met at a
lecture fell in love and got married this is what can happen to you
yeah yeah it's beautiful I thought I'd have a question by the time I get up
here but I'm glad to meet the two of you yeah is he questioning and we all want
to give you our love and congratulations so crowd god bless aha nice to be back
yeah
thank you as always yeah actually the last one just led into what I was going
to question and he's really on the subject of fear and anxiety and was
coming up for me recently is there's there's really no thinking going on but
there's that general sort of program it's sort of beneath conscious awareness
that seems to you running I've seen you becoming more aware of it and it seems
to be happening in our study group is a number of people the same things
happening for subliminal thinking this subliminal thinking the direct reality
a little yeah it's outside of awareness it's not like there's sort of a silence there but yet
there's still this anxiety and this leads to the root of my question is that in the root chakra
really or I guess perhaps I have this I guess for the past several years I've had this sort of
enlarged prostate it's benign but it just seems to never it just seems to constantly be there and I
have a feeling it's sort of related to this fear or this anxiety and I'm wondering if you could
talk to me about that if there is a correlation potentially there I don't know other than we tend
to manifest what's held in mind if you didn't have an enlarged prostate but I tell you watch
television you will diagrams I want to take for it so the suggestion is already imprinted so when
we talk about the collective
we're really talking about imprinting how long does it take to program you you just got programmed
that fast that's why the mind is innocent it can't look over and decide gee is that a healthy thought
that I want to entertain it already got the image you know the prostate photo diagram on TV you know
I've seen enough of it there it is right didn't have before you got it now so all you can do is
negate it that it doesn't apply to you that you're an infinite being
you're only subject to what you hold in mind and that you're not subject to this belief system that
all men get prostate trouble as they get older okay now is it in any way related to just generalized
sort of anxiety or fear because certainly in the literature some of the things you can look up from
the net saying you know maybe what certain emotional positions as a consequence is holding
certain positions you get an enlarged prostate like generalized fear or you know giving up oh
you get a thousand amateurish ideas about it
but it's the thought held in mind is a belief system breast cancer I mean all these things that afflict
mankind are part of the collective so once they're held in the collective they're given the authority
of multiple agreement well now they got great power you know okay so it's really bad any sort
of a relationship I've created it's best to sort of like I don't think it's individual I think you
just have to negate that you yourself are an infinite being and you're only subject to what
you hold in mind and you hereby declare that that's invalid
ok thank you meantime take your flumax
no I did
hello sir thanks for the talk today yeah my question I'm working on surrendering all my
meaningless thoughts as they come up and i've been doing it for a while ever since I got ran
into your teaching and
I've been pretty consistent with it.
And now the main things that I have trouble with
is surrendering my positionalities that I create
in regard to spiritual teaching.
And I don't know why that is.
I can't seem to get past it.
I pray about it.
Sometimes because it seems important.
And my spiritual knight had difficulty with that too.
False teachings.
Indignation would come up.
How can you mislead people
and take them out to these fantasy lands
and take their money
and watch them destroy themselves?
These cults, they all committed suicide at the same time
because they hail a bop comment or something.
It's hard to know about that
and not feel your gorge sort of rise with indignation.
How people could trick people into following them through
just for the sake of personal power.
The cults.
But I think that's a natural phase we go through.
I mean, that way you face that you do hold good and evil
and that it's real.
It's not just a conceptual
because you can feel indignation rise in you.
What about like, sometimes I just like,
within, like I'll have a talk with another spiritual student
and say they're doing the Course in Miracles
and then like maybe I'll just have a disagreement
and then I just constantly relive the conversation over and over again.
I guess because it's important to you.
You want to arrive at the truth.
So you just ask God to help you find what is the truth
and to recontextualize the argument for you.
Okay.
Yeah.
Okay, thank you.
No, it's natural.
I mean, if you're committed to spirituality,
you get into spiritual doubt, argument, discourse, disagreement.
Yeah.
About four or five months ago,
we formed a little group to work for God.
And then two months ago, your name just kept coming up.
And up and up.
So I'm here.
Our goal is to use technology to help shift human consciousness.
And having read your book, Eye of the Eye,
the 78% that are below 200,
we want to use some sort of technology to...
Technology?
Yes.
That's linear.
Yeah.
But can that be used to help...
People that are below 200?
And if not,
what do you recommend to help that...
The other population come up?
Surrender the world to God?
Surrender...
The world to God.
The world to God from them or from us?
We all do what we can,
depending on...
You see, whatever level of your consciousness.
You will see the requirements are different
at this level than this level.
This level, you're required...
You're required to do something about it.
This required level, you're required not to do something about it.
This level, you don't see there's anything that needs to be done about anything
because karmically, and by the nature of evolution,
human consciousness is going up like that, you see, without you.
Yes.
And so do we...
So you see, it's going up like so.
However, you could assist in the evolution.
Assist.
Yes, and that was our goal.
And so we were going to use technology as well as any other means.
And if the technology doesn't work,
is there anything else that you could recommend that we...
Yes, surrender the world to God, yes.
Let God worry about the evolution of human consciousness.
And so do we...
Do anything...
Education.
Education, yes.
So recommend...
For all of mankind, education, yes.
I think of all the things that people can do for others,
education is the only one that works.
So provide education so that they could...
Education is the only thing that works.
Okay.
There's no point in giving poor people money
because they will probably get poor all over again.
Right.
Because if they know how to handle money, they wouldn't be poor.
So you're giving it to their own person.
What you want to do is provide the circumstances for them to thrive.
And research education is the greatest, the greatest benefit.
Every dollar spent on education more than pays for itself.
So there is no technology available from your experience, exposure,
that has done any helping of anything...
I don't know of any technology.
Okay.
Well, thank you very much.
The steam engine, maybe.
The water wheel.
The wheel.
Yeah, by God, the wheel.
You're right, Steve.
The wheel.
Well, I want to thank you for all that you do
and thank you for answering so many questions.
I had a, you know, kind of a feeling or a knowingness that I came upon
a week or so ago, and I just wanted to discuss it
or see what you had to say with it.
And the idea is that I felt that if I'm able to transcend
this material experience form, if I transcend this form,
am I transcending all form at the same time?
If you transcend form as form, transcend the non-linear,
you're at 850.
Yep.
And then you don't have to worry about it
because it has no reality.
It isn't like you have to decline it.
It's not an option.
Thank you.
Yes.
I am a psychology student in Flagstaff,
and I was a little surprised that Freud calibrates at 499.
Who?
Oh, Freud, yes, 499, yes.
And then today when you had the slides up,
so Freud calibrates higher than what?
William James or Shakespeare.
And I know you said it means not better than.
Let's see, what is your question again?
Well, the question...
She wants to know why that Freud is at 499.
Freud calibrated at 499, yes.
What's the next thing?
He said he calibrated higher than Shakespeare.
Same thing.
Oh, I can't compare it with...
You can't compare apples and oranges.
Well, my question is, does that mean I have to hold
Freud's ideas with so much truth?
No.
Because a lot of his...
You can't compare it to...
Who was the other person?
I have no idea who you're comparing.
Wait a minute.
I'm not comparing him.
You said Freud at 499 and what?
She's just...
Does that mean I have to hold his...
No, no, who was the other person she compared him to?
William James.
William James, he was 490.
And that, you know, surprised me, but then...
These are different levels that they're expressing, see?
Freud, like Einstein.
Einstein is also at 499.
Also Sir Isaac Newton.
All geniuses...
Right.
...took the level of genius to the ultimate.
Then you've got to jump paradigms.
So does this mean I have to...
So at 499, Einstein said,
I prefer to believe that there's an independent objective universe out there
that exists independent of human consciousness.
And he rejected 500.
Because at 500, you move from the linear Newtonian paradigm
to subjectivity as the ultimate reality.
I don't live within symbols.
I live within subjective experiential.
Right.
That's over 500, see?
Yes.
So does that...
I guess I find so many of Freud's ideas nuts and...
You find Freud's ideas nuts?
So many of Freud's ideas I find nuts.
You mean as a concept?
Oh, yes.
Experientially, you ever go through a Freudian psychoanalysis?
You'll see how...
You'll find out different.
I guess that's my point then.
I mean, do I hold Freud as a genius like Einstein?
He is a genius, yes.
All right.
You see, you're too young to realize that.
You're too young to realize the impact he had on all generations.
Freud's discoveries of the unconscious turned everything around.
Had a major impact.
Changed the whole paradigm of responsibility, sexuality, intention.
Just like the women's revolution of becoming equal with men.
It just changes the whole thing.
It's just a whole different way of holding value and the...
Freud's main genius was in discovering the unconscious.
And the powerful effect that it has in the unconscious.
And the fact that the unconscious is unconscious.
Well, Carl Jung was...
Carl Jung was 520.
Well, Carl Jung also explored the unconscious, but he included the spiritual as a reality,
whereas Freud did not.
That's right.
Freud looked at the anthropomorphic God and said, because God is traditionally depicted
as anthropomorphic, obviously a projection of man's own unconscious.
Then he made the invalid conclusion, therefore God doesn't exist.
No, he should have said, therefore the irrational, you know, in my own writings,
I reject the anthropomorphic depictions of God as primitive projection from the, you know,
primitive onto divinity.
God makes the volcanoes, God makes the earthquakes, you know.
Yeah.
So put Carl Jung on the pedestal.
Carl Jung.
He's not up there.
Freud discovered the unconscious.
That was his main discovery and the power of the unconscious.
And then Jung carried it further and included it.
He included the spiritual dimension.
It was Jung that discovered synchronicity.
It was because of Carl Jung's honesty that the whole 12-step movement arose.
Without Carl Jung, Bill W. never would have gotten this over, nor would have anybody who
preceded him.
Yeah?
You're a psychology student, huh?
Oh, that's a fun trip.
It is.
It sure is.
God help you, woman.
The jungle of psychology, yeah?
All the different theories and, yeah.
Dr. Hawkins, before I have heard you speak about how one could own a quality of God,
be that quality kindness or politeness or love or another quality, is owning a quality
of God the same as contemplating on that quality?
Yeah.
Contemplating it, realizing it that is innate within yourself as well.
That that quality that we call divine is intrinsic to yourself also.
A mouse got caught in a mouse trap, you know, a sticky pad.
I couldn't come to the lecture until I went out and relieved the mouse of the slow torture
of slowly dying of suffocation and starvation and dehydration from the quick mercy death.
I can't stand the thought that he's going to be left there to suffer and suffer and
suffer.
On the other hand, that's also something you could let go of and say you're just projecting
that onto the mouse.
So you see how you handled it?
Is it merciful to put him to sleep?
Is it more merciful to let it be?
Should I surrender him to God?
It's God's problem if this mouse lays there and takes two weeks to die of dehydration,
right?
So you see the simplest thing.
It's how you hold it, how you see it.
Thank you.
I surrendered it to God and put it out of its misery.
Well, God has to do it.
He has to do it.
Thank you.
I surrendered it to God and put it out of its misery.
Well, God has to act through somebody.
He said, for God's sake, put him to sleep.
I'm like, mercy.
Good night.
Yeah.
Move along quickly now.
Yes?
Hi.
I had no idea that you would be so funny, so I was glad.
Paramahansa Yogananda, he called enlightenment superconscious.
Yes.
He called enlightenment superconscious union with God.
And sleep, deep, deep dreamless sleep, subconscious union with God.
Yes.
And encouraged his disciples to meditate as much as possible.
And sleep as little as possible.
Yes.
And I'm wondering what you think about that instruction, whether that does, in fact, increase
the possibility or the nature of the waking state toward the extension.
The intention behind it, of course, is to meditate as much as possible.
Yes.
And some spiritual divisions try to cut down on physical sleep.
I don't notice that there's any benefit one way or the other, frankly.
Okay.
Do you ever visit the center there in California?
No, I haven't been there, no.
Okay.
Thank you.
Autobiography of a Yogi, he wrote.
Yes.
Very famous book.
We're almost at the end.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
Just to go back to kinesiology.
We were at lunch this afternoon, and we were all in disagreement on calibrating by 150
points.
Yes.
So, the next question.
You're not too good at it.
Right.
But the point was none of us were, and I've been playing with this for 20 years, you know,
with applied kinesiology.
Now, the question is that, apart from just calibrating, you know, if I give, you know,
five members in the audience 10 or 20 yes or no questions to which we have yes or no
answers.
Yes.
They won't agree.
And how many of them will get 19 out of 20 right?
Or even 10 out of 20 right?
So, then the next question that becomes is what about the reliability of the test?
Because before we put our arm out here and test for something, you've got to make sure
the ruler is.
I can answer it, because I know your whole lecture.
Okay.
And it has to do with internal consistency.
That every two people have to be able to do it.
Right.
So, the question is, what about the reliability of the test?
Because before we put our arm out here and test for something, you've got to make sure
the ruler is.
I can answer it, because I know your whole lecture.
Okay.
That every two people will maybe vary from another two people, but they will be internally
consistent.
See?
Now, there's a proficiency and a skill.
Very few people, why were you doing this at lunch?
I know why you were doing it.
So that's why you're getting varying answers already.
I already got why you're doing it at lunch.
Actually, I wasn't doing it.
I was on looking as two other people were doing it.
And that's how it all came up.
Not by you.
I'm using the generic term.
The group.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I don't know.
I don't know the basics of kinesiology all the time.
Your intention has to be to just know the truth of a thing.
You can't have any gain in it.
You can't be out to try to prove or disprove that kinesiology works or is accurate.
You see, so many people come at it with a challenge.
The minute you come at it with a challenge, you just blew it.
It's a very simple thing.
I showed it so simply that it seems to me, you know, you've got to be really, really
stupid to not get it.
I'm going to show it one more time.
I'm going to show it one last time.
And if one more person brings up a question about kinesiology, I'm going to throw them
into the pits.
Good God.
I mean, it's so dumb.
Give me your arm.
Look at the top picture and now resist.
Look at the bottom picture.
Now resist.
I mean, Jesus, you don't have to go to college, do you?
To make it any more complicated than that is deliberate confusion.
That they project onto it because they want to adopt some kind of an argumentative position.
Forget it.
You just saw the truth of it.
End of the problem.
But did you see, it's not, I mean, you know, it's not as simple or as easy as that.
Oh, it is.
Yeah, that's what you think.
It is as simple as that.
No, no.
The point is.
Ah, he missed the point altogether, I see.
You want to turn it into an intellectual understanding?
No, no.
What is your problem?
My question is.
Yes.
On a clinical setting.
I mean, I deal with chronic pain.
We've done studies on this.
You know, so I've been with this for 20 years.
So I'm not just asking about it flippantly.
The question is that how does it become consistent?
How do you not let your own bias fly into the test?
That's just what I got through telling you.
Right.
You can't have a bias.
But it sometimes creeps in without even knowing it's creeping in.
Right.
And that's when the test becomes wrong.
Oh, that's a matter of integrity.
That's why people over, under 200 can't do it.
You know that people under 200 cannot be integrists?
They cannot make a statement without having a position about it.
It's not possible because they're wrong brain physiology from the left brain.
So when they try to imitate it, they always get a falsehood because they're supposed to.
It's only when you get over 200.
Right.
So when they try to imitate it, they always get a falsehood because they're supposed to.
It's only when you get over 200.
Can you adopt the positionality?
Could you vote for, let's say, a party that you think is the best for the government instead
of a party that's best for me?
Below 200, I vote for him because he's going to be good to the cab drivers.
Over 200, I vote for the mayor that I think is going to be the best for the city.
That's the difference.
All right.
Thank you.
And now we've got to stop.
They'll throw us out.
Be quick.
Yeah, I'll be quick.
We'll answer you quick.
Okay.
Actually, I'm afraid of being thrown into the pits now.
Uh-oh.
Now you might get it, yeah.
My question is regarding just research, the kind of research that you do.
Do you typically calibrate things yourself and have teams confirm it?
Do you just stick with what you know?
Well, we do it all different kinds of ways.
We've been doing it for some 25, 30 years.
And I learned it from other people who were already doing it.
I didn't invent it.
So what's the method that you're using now?
Well, we've been doing it for some 25, 30 years.
And I learned it from other people who were already doing it.
I didn't invent it.
So what's the method that you're using now?
Well, we do it all different kinds of ways.
We've been doing it for some 25, 30 years.
And I learned it from other people who were already doing it.
I didn't invent it.
So what's the method that you're using now?
I just demonstrated it.
I just got through demonstrating it.
No, I'm just talking about like with other people.
Do you, you know, having it confirmed or what's the method you use for confirmation?
I don't know if I want confirmation.
I don't want to know what somebody else gets because they're then running, see, it runs
on your own scale.
So, you know, I don't know if I want confirmation.
I don't want to know what somebody else gets because they're then running, see, it runs
on your own scale.
So you can adopt any scale you want.
You can say 10 is true and 1 is not true and 5 is halfway between.
You can set up your own scale.
All right.
Then you will be integrous within your own scale, but not in my scale.
If I set the barometric pressure as normal, so-and-so.
So if I have a different thermometer, if I say on my thermometer 0 is freezing and 212
is boiling, then that, on that thermometer, I will get that.
You can make your own thermometer and you'll get different figures.
Okay.
So you couldn't have people use your scale?
Yes.
Other people use our scale.
And I say, you know, based on this scale of 1 to 1,000, you know, this calibrates it,
so-and-so.
I don't see how you could get disparities if you're doing it integrously.
I went to a lecture recently and they were saying that you use teams to...
Oh, yes.
Well, because if you do it this way, yeah, you can also do it, you know, the O-ring.
You don't need a team.
Right.
All right.
So if I hold Abraham Lincoln in mind, I'm going to hold Abraham Lincoln in mind.
Now I'm holding somebody else in mind who says, we worship death.
There's no comparison.
The moment I hold this image in mind, I can't, I've got no strength.
But when I hold Abraham Lincoln in mind, it's simple.
Okay.
Do it by yourself.
You don't have to worry about teams.
Teams.
You just have people who work together and they get intuitively aligned with each other
and they can work very fast, you know.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Sometimes spouses can't work together for unknown reasons and the two of them have
to find a second, another person.
And if you get disparity, try working with yourself for a while until you get consistency.
There's a simpler method which I also explained last time and that's the end of the questions.
You don't have to be a genius to do this.
You lift the dictionary.
You hold Abraham Lincoln in mind, you know, big heavy dictionary.
And you see how much strength it takes to lift the dictionary with Abraham Lincoln.
Now you hold Bin Laden in mind and see how much strength it takes.
You'll see a marked difference.
I mean, you don't have to go to college.
You don't have to be a, you know, advanced physicist to do it.
Simple.
Because it's so simple, that's why it's hard to see.
And in doing that, I would get my own level of truth with regards to that.
Obviously, I might not get your level of truth because we're in different places.
Now, I'm a little bit more interested in yours than I am in mine.
You can say on a level of one to a thousand.
You see, according to this scale, this statement calibrates to start with as true or not true.
And then you can try to get a number.
Don't forget we've done it thousands of times.
Don't forget that I'm extremely intuitive.
I can see the essence of a thing before it speaks.
So, I mean, I've already got the number in my mind.
I don't tell her what the number is.
You know, we'll bring up something like this in my mind.
As I raise my hand, I've got, it's about 480 in my, you know, just a knowingness.
I don't tell her what I'm holding in mind, but it says the number.
And then she gets to 480.
It just confirms.
It doesn't mean I'm accurate all the time.
I trained myself to know the temperature.
I got an 84 caddy.
And the thing I liked about it best, other than the fact that it's low down and gorgeous,
.
Just got repainted, oh boy.
It's got a thermometer.
You push the button, it tells you the outside temperature.
So I trained myself, because I had to get up every morning in the dark and the cold and drive.
And I trained myself to say what the temperature is before I hit the button.
I found within a matter of months, I was so accurate,
I could predict the temperature outside within a degree or two almost 99% of the time.
I'd go out to the car, and I would just know it's 64.
I'd hit the button, it'd be 64.
So I did that over and over again to train myself.
And I did it as an experiment.
And then once you were trained, you knew you were trained, and you didn't need to be prepared.
So, yes, I trained myself.
And therefore, I could tell the temperature within a matter of degrees.
So that's just experiential.
See what I'm saying there?
It's experiential.
Trial and error.
And we've got to get out of here at 530, they say.
Thank you.
If you make it very fast, I mean by very fast, get to the essence of it quick.
Want a picture?
Do it quick.
What?
Don't lag.
Don't drag.
Jump along.
Step lively.
Slip lively.
Blast.
Slip lively, or it's the gangplank for you.
Yeah, that's it.
You're the last, though.
Okay, quick question.
Since we're talking about spiritual teachers, and you didn't have that other list that you mentioned.
Yeah.
I was wondering if,
because I've been following this path for a long time, for about 10 years.
Yes.
For the cryon energy, and the cryon channelings.
I want to know what they ...
It's a big, that's an entity on the other side?
Yeah.
Oh, I don't do channelers from the other side.
But it's interdimensional, and I've been following that path, and it says a lot of the same things you've been saying.
Okay, good.
Yeah, that's fine.
No more of you asking me.
So I want to know if it's higher or lower, or what.
I think that's legitimate to ask that.
The essence of the spiritual truth.
It's, for me, should I follow it anymore?
I'm sincere in what I do.
We can ask that one.
You can ask that one.
It would be ...
We have permission to ask the question.
It's for her to continue with this teacher, resist.
You asked.
Okay, thank you.
I'll tell you.
Come up.
I'll tell you what happens.
Is there ...
There's nothing wrong with following things that don't calibrate real high, because they serve a purpose up to a certain point.
You have to make a lot of mistakes.
Sometimes, you know ...
And it serves a purpose, because after all, first of all, you're intended for ...
It was her spiritual integrity that drove her to the teacher.
It isn't the teacher that has the spiritual integrity.
It's the student.
They follow all kinds of crooks out of their own inner honesty.
Come on, baby.
This is God's love.
Let's be godly.
I mean, it happens every day.
Women write books on, you know, gurus I've been seduced by.
There is a book.
I've got them at home.
You know, the story about all the gurus and the rap that he gave her.
It was her sincerity, her integrity, her honesty, her innocence that was ravished, you see?
So I think a teacher, you know, doesn't have to calibrate a 900 to be useful.
You can follow a false teacher for a while.
And now you've learned a lot.
You've learned a lot.
Because you've learned how to be a devotee.
You've learned self-sacrifice.
You've learned humility.
And now you move to a higher teacher.
But, so ...
Yes, higher teachers and myself.
I have a question here with an email answer in case I didn't get up here.
What?
My question is, why is Mary Baker Eddy not a part of the significant spiritual leadership
you calibrate?
Oh, I picked more ancient ones.
Mary Baker Eddy, of course.
Four of her students.
Joel Goldsmith.
Yeah, yes.
Phil Morris.
No, I forget.
I don't know why.
Probably just prejudice against women, you know.
That's what I thought.
I know her name wasn't ...
I thought there must be a really good reason.
No, because, you know, you have to know how we put this together.
That's 144, but we had hundreds, you know.
So, I think we just took every sixth name or something like that off of her.
I forget.
Mary Baker Eddy.
Well, you know, she founded the church.
She founded ...
Yes.
And ...
What, are you fishing for, or what?
No.
The Christian Science Monitor is a world-renowned ...
Yes.
My grandmother was a Christian scientist.
Christian Science Monitor magazine, you know, calibrates quite high.
Yeah.
Well, it's just an outstanding group of people and movement.
Yes.
And that's why, you know, I think ...
She began the whole New Thought movement, you know.
She should be, she ought to be calibrated.
I'd be very interested.
Mary Baker Eddy?
Yeah.
We have permission to do Mary Baker Eddy.
She's got her upside, she's got her downside.
We have permission to do Mary, we don't have permission to do her.
No, come on, I'll do it.
Mary Baker Eddy.
We have permission to do Mary Baker Eddy.
Mary Baker Eddy is over 200.
That's all you really need to know.
She's over 300.
All right.
She's over 300, 400, 500, 550, 560.
No, I'm getting false answers.
Getting false answers?
Yeah.
Because of the crowd and the answer.
I can't answer accurately right now.
We're all laughing and stuff like that.
Okay.
Okay, well, thank you.
She's a good person.
My grandmother was a Christian scientist, yes.
She used to read me Shakespeare, Christian science,
and take me to the Baptist church.
In the meantime, my grandfather was a Mason,
so I got it heavy from all sides, you know.
Did you good.
I think it's the dedication to the truth that you get out of it,
the pristine nature of truth itself.
Now, how it's expressed varies from teacher to teacher,
from era to era, from culture to culture.
But once you begin to value truth for its own sake,
because truth is one of the qualities of divinity,
you can follow then the love of truth and become devoted to truth.
So devotional non-duality is devoted to,
is the devotion to reaching the ultimate truth
that is knowable within this dimension.
And I want to thank you for the loveliness of this afternoon.
We want to congratulate the new couple.
So we say, Gloria in excelsis Deo.
You are God's gift to me.
Ah, yeah.
The child in us never dies, huh?
Every day is kindergarten to me.
Every day you discover something new and joyful about the world.
Yeah?