I didn't expect to be first.
Other than getting one's affairs in order and simplifying life, for people who are increasingly
experiencing non-dual reality.
You're increasingly experiencing what?
Non-dual reality.
What does that mean?
What?
Non-dual, non-duality.
Non-duality.
Oh, yes, yes.
Okay, got it.
And therefore find relationships and work and life structures as you previously knew
it relatively irrelevant.
Less attractive, yeah.
What guidance can you provide?
The motivation has to shift from gain, huh, and the various things that ordinarily
steer people through the linear world, and in their place to take on the value of non-linear
values, yeah.
In other words, to be of service to the world.
So you may hold the job out of gain, out of vanity for the title, out of desire, et cetera.
Then you transcend that level.
Now, of what meaning or significance is the same job.
It may transform in meaning, yeah.
Did that answer?
In other words, you're serving a function for humanity and society, and that becomes
the way you contextualize what you do, okay?
To be of service, then, no matter what you do, is really a being of service to life,
you know, in all of its expressions and forms.
Thank you.
It takes 20 workmen to lift a tent for the circus, you know.
Good question.
Okay.
All in general, it has to do with Alzheimer's and that condition, and one has the experience
that I've had a couple of times.
Okay.
This is a good one.
The Alzheimer's is a very good one.
What about it?
Well, patients that have Alzheimer's.
Yes.
Alzheimer's, you know.
Alzheimer's, yes.
I never can say that right.
It's got a Z, a Z in it.
Yeah, a Z.
Yes.
Okay.
Anyway, patients.
What about it?
Yes.
Can you tell them what is really happening with the soul, with people who have that disease?
Can you tell who's happening with whose soul?
Yours or the patient's?
No, the patient's.
The patient's.
Oh, the patient's soul.
Yes.
Yeah, what's happening with the patient's soul is up to the patient and God.
What would you want to know about it?
Well, she must know they're in pain, you know.
Oh, it's simple.
You know, I was the only doctor in the county, and they would go to the nursing home and
see the Alzheimer's patients.
So, I saw them all over the county, from Prescott on in.
There's still a lot of back talk in the background.
I found that most of it, that the anguish was on the part of the family.
The patient, I'd go to see them.
They'd say, oh, poor Aunt Granny.
She doesn't remember who she is anymore, and this and that.
And the family is all upset and wailing.
So, I'd go see Aunt Granny.
I'd say, how are you?
Oh, fine.
How do you like this place?
Oh, it's nice.
How's the food?
Fine.
You got any complaints today?
No, no, no, not really.
You know what day it is?
Oh.
You know how old you are?
She said, oh, I'm a lady.
I'm a lady.
I don't want to tell you.
You know, she doesn't remember how old she is, and who cares?
So, the subjective experiential of straightforward Alzheimer's.
There's senility, dimension, whatever you want to call it.
The main anguish is in the witness, because if you don't remember a lot of what went on,
what difference does it make?
As it is, most people don't remember what went on in their life.
You know that?
Can you give me a minute-by-minute, second-by-second recall, you know, of even one day in your life?
No.
You can remember a few highlights.
Yeah.
So, what people mourn is really the vanity of it.
You know, the vanity of it.
I remember I saw my grandmother.
She was 99.
And I went to see her, and she says, oh, you're from New York.
Oh.
I said, my grandson is a doctor in New York.
I said, well, yes, Granny.
And then I began to talk about who I was and all.
And all of a sudden, she said, all of a sudden, she started to cry.
Oh.
So, would you say there's no difference, then, between a gastrointestinal trance disorder or Alzheimer's?
Straight Alzheimer's.
You know, then there's Alzheimer's would disturb the emotionality and all, but that's irrelevant to the Alzheimer's,
because lots of people at the same age without Alzheimer's get the same thing, depression or agitation.
So, you treat the negative symptoms.
But Alzheimer's itself, I always felt as though the spirit has already left the body progressively, and there's very little left.
And, you know, Bill Wilson, who was the founder of AA, and I knew him for years before he died, and I was one of the doctors who used to see him.
And he would lapse periodically.
And he would say, he visited different realms of heaven, you know.
He would go into it like a lapse.
And he would say, it is true.
There are many mansions.
There are many mansions on my father's side, you know.
So, that there is, what he was saying, which we recently discovered with kinesiology, is that there are multiple heavens, multiple ends.
And so, as a clinician, in dealing with Alzheimer's, what is your recommendation?
Make sure they have breakfast and lunch and dinner.
Thank you.
Got enough socks for the week, you know.
Oh, I see.
You're bringing in books from another line here.
Yes, I am.
Okay.
That answers the mystery.
He'll just sign in.
He doesn't need it.
Oh, yeah.
Personal inscriptions.
That's all I can do to get him to sign his name.
Okay.
I did put it with best regards.
He did.
You're lucky.
He usually doesn't do that.
Yes.
On the one hand, one wants to serve the higher good without considering gain and loss.
But, on the other hand, one wants to live in abundance rather than in poverty.
How do you reconcile those two?
What have you got against poverty?
Well, it just feels nicer to have, you know, a credit card, be able to take an airplane.
That's not poverty.
That's lack of wealth, right?
Okay.
Poverty is something else.
Right.
Lack of wealth.
All right.
So, that's a very common problem.
Probably one of the most common problems.
Yes.
Okay.
Thank you.
That's probably the most common.
Sure.
You become, you fulfill your own potential to the greatest degree you can fulfill it.
And the consequences are automatic.
There's nothing you need to do to make it happen.
Because, because of the consequence of that which you are, you draw to yourself by attraction
that which will elude you if you seek it out of.
The gain.
The negativity.
See?
Besides, one should learn to enjoy what the world would call poverty.
The simplicity of it, the lack of demand of it, I mean what you need in the refrigerator
is a six pack of Pepsi and a piece of cheese, what else do you want?
I lived that way for years, and in those days I used to truck manure.
When I left the world, I left a grand lifestyle, more grand than you can even imagine.
I mean it was grand.
The club I belonged to was so exclusive, nobody knows the name of it to this day, but they
were the heads of all the great sources of wealth in the world.
And then I just put my tools in the back of the truck and drove away.
It was great.
Free as a bird, free, free.
I had to drive down the highway with a load of manure.
I got it for ten bucks, so they're the big dairy farm in McGuireville, and for ten bucks
they'd load up the back of the truck and I would truck it all the way to Sedona.
I was the manure baron of Sedona.
I controlled the market.
Nobody wanted to get their truck.
Pick up ten bucks.
Truck 30 with manure, so anyway, so I would sell it for 40 or 45, so I bought it for ten,
sold it for 45, and to do that I only had to drive eight miles.
I mean, you can't beat that.
And I was free as a bird.
I could do it when I wanted to do it, not do it when I wanted to do it.
If I didn't need money, heck with it.
You know?
Yeah.
Okay, thank you.
I lived that way for years.
Only reluctantly was forced to give it up, to tell you the truth.
Yeah.
So when you enjoy simplicity, so don't see it as poverty, see it as simplicity.
And this period of simplicity is a gift, and when you've extracted all there is to learn
from that, that learning phase goes over.
You may then have to learn how to be the responsible steward of abundance.
You'll be sorry you weren't the poor again, I'll tell you.
Yeah.
Hi, I'm Grant.
My name is Grant.
Thank you.
My name is John.
I'm honored and also a little bit intimidated being up here, so if my question doesn't make
any sense, just re-ask it.
It doesn't have to make sense.
Yes.
Yeah.
What you said earlier this morning about meditation, my spiritual ego felt a little
disparaged by that, an avid practicer of meditation myself.
And then with further reflection, what I got from what you said was that if all you did
was meditate, then that would mean nothing.
If it didn't translate in some change of behavior, some way of perceiving things, responding to
things, then it would mean nothing.
And in my sense of it is that it has helped me create a sense of equanimity about the
coming and going of things, processes in life.
So I myself have found it very beneficial.
I did it for 20 years, yeah.
Yeah.
And so the second part of my question was...
So it wasn't exactly a fizzle, though.
In your comments about it, it was somewhat negativistic about it.
And so I was wondering, did I perceive what you said upon further reflection to be more
accurate of what you were trying to say, to how would you say that the 20 years of meditating
two hours a day, did that have anything to do with how you are now?
It would be hard to say, because you see, it's the intention.
The intention with which you meditate, pray, walk the maze, asceticism, I also did asceticism,
and left my own devices, I'd weigh about 90, you know.
So asceticism can become a way of life.
Certain things are realized, I'm certain, as a result of the meditative state itself.
What I'm saying is how well does it transpose?
All right.
You meditate for an hour and you gain some interest.
Yeah.
You have interesting insights.
And then what?
Well, to me, it gives me practice at being in the audience looking at the movie, as opposed
to the actor.
It takes you into the field.
Okay.
So now, what you want to do, maybe I didn't make it clear, is translate what you saw from
meditation into contemplation so it becomes what you are in the world.
Yeah.
So I think that kind of augments that.
It's sort of a laboratory.
Well, also meditation trains you in one-pointedness of mind.
And that one-pointedness of mind later comes on usefully in other spiritual practices.
Because when you decide to make what I call the final run, when you decide to make the
final run, you're going to be walking the edge of the razor.
You're going to walk the edge of the razor and stay on the edge of the razor.
And you need that disciplined one-pointedness of mind to see the crest of each experience
arising and to release it as it arises.
And not to anticipate jumping to the front of the wave of experience, which is control
and also fear.
Nor is it hanging to the back of the wave, which is clinging to the past.
So to be on the wave of the presence of now is an expertise that can be learned in meditation.
Yes.
Then applied in the style of contemplation.
So contemplation is a way of being meditative about life and the past.
About life as you walk through life.
So it's only an artificial disparity.
What I was trying to point out is a lot of times people isolate that, you know.
Well, I meditate from here to there.
Then I'm who I always was until four.
And then I meditate from five to six.
It tends to get compartmentalized.
Right.
So if you don't change what you're doing, you're going to keep getting what you're getting.
Yeah.
So to apply that which you see to the way you are in the world.
So the contemplation.
And then it's the all-day fulfillment of what you've achieved within meditation, yes.
Yeah.
And in your third book, you talk about meditating in context rather than the content of a mantra or following the breath and such.
Where, without going into that, I don't mean to Bogart that.
No, each of these spiritual practices is befitting a certain level of the progression of consciousness.
So there are things that are useful at this level.
They're hanging to the past at this level.
Then there's things that will take you from this level to the next level.
So there's a time to walk the maze.
There's a time to do the rosary.
There's a time to do sackcloth and ashes.
There's a time to do asceticism.
There's a time to do selfless service.
And it's not a linear logical progression.
So something may be of need and appeal to you at a certain level.
Yeah.
And at other times, it could be an evasion.
So what is a spiritual, beneficial practice here could be an evasion here, see?
Yeah.
Great.
Thank you.
Good question.
Yeah.
That'd be a dollar.
No.
Yeah.
First, I just want to thank you for coming back into our world and writing those three incredible books.
And it seems like it must have taken an awful lot of effort because, you know, we're all in this together.
Right.
And I just, when I see you speaking and you seem to recall some of that time in your life before you came back, it seems like you really start to bliss out.
And you could just go out there and just stay there.
And I really appreciate you coming back and helping the rest of us.
You can't really talk about those states when they begin to take over.
Right.
I see that.
And therefore, you've got to draw back into, again, to the personage, you know.
And I remind myself.
I mean, the communicative transmitter of communication.
Yeah.
And besides, there's plenty of time on the other side.
Forever.
I mean, that's a while.
You've got forever when you get there, boy.
Well, my question is.
You've got to do what you've got to do while you're down there, you know.
Yes, Father.
My question is, I'm doing the lessons in the course.
And I haven't read the text.
I haven't read the text deliberately because of what you said about how it demonizes the ego.
Well, if you watch for the demonization of the ego, you'll see it there.
Right.
Yeah.
It's a mistake to set up a duality within yourself already, you know what I'm saying?
So is it worthwhile to read the text?
Or are you better off reading Huang Po or Maharachi?
Is it worth reading the text, I guess, is my point?
I'd have to reread it.
It's been many a year.
Okay.
I mean, it's interesting.
It's interesting.
Just don't fall in.
Just be aware of the demonization.
Just watch that downside.
That downside.
See, once you've heard the truth, anything that's in error in what you read will stand
out of its own, you know.
You'll say, well, that's demonizing the ego.
Yeah, you know, it shrieks and claws at you.
Well, this is, it's also true from a certain other level of abstraction.
The ego is the dragon.
It is the Komodo dragon.
Right.
And it will, frankly, throw you over the cliff to survive.
Rather than surrender, it'll throw you over the cliff.
It'll kill you over and over again.
I think I'll stay away from the text.
I don't want to demonize the text.
I'm just saying there is a fault in there.
You can do the workbook.
Well, you see, the textbook does calibrate 50 points lower than the workbook.
So it is reflected there.
And it sort of stands out.
Once you've heard the truth, you say, well, the interpreter, the translator maybe just
translated it incorrectly.
A man shrieks and claws at you in quotes.
And it's not really doing that.
But you perceive it as that.
So a clarification of that I think would help.
So if I had to rewrite that paragraph, I'd say you perceive it as shrieking and clawing
at you, et cetera.
Actually, it's not.
It's your projection.
That's how you're seeing the ego.
Okay.
I also heard something about a group OM.
I was wondering if we could maybe do that before we leave today.
Edward, you said you were going to hear OM?
I didn't say anything about having an OM.
Yes, you did.
Thank you.
Yes, she did.
Didn't he?
Yes.
I didn't say anything about an OM.
Thank you.
I was going to say MO, and I got it backwards.
You didn't say MO.
We met.
Oh, no, home.
I said we'd go home at 5.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
My name is Phyllis Hartzler.
I'm from Pennsylvania.
And I just wanted to thank you.
I don't really have a question that I can think of.
So I'll be quick.
Thank you very much.
Yes.
Thank you.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Well, what's the time?
Do we have time on the line?
Yeah.
My name's Locke, and I just live down the road in Cornville.
It's nice to meet you.
Thank you.
But it's nice to meet you.
You live in Cornville?
Yeah.
Oh, lucky man.
Good karma, huh?
It's nice out there.
I live at .
Mm-hmm.
You said something during the lecture about a bomb killing so many people and, so, what?
Not having a judgment about that.
And I remember in a previous lifetime I was a young pastor for a particular church, and
I was talking to this older pastor.
and a bird flew and hit the window and fell down into the bushes and he just
calmly he calmly got up and got the bird and held on to it until it woke up and
took off and I remember thinking I don't know I don't know shit about compassion
and and and and I guess my question is
you know how you know I mean I mean my my I was like so what so you know I've
seen birds hit the window all the time so but I think that so what that I was
having at that time is different than the so what that you're talking about
and I'm wondering if you could just sort of you know how can I be compassionate
without making a judgment about something how can you avoid making a
judgment
you know
well you just become compassionate towards all of life in all of its
expressions whether it's a busload of children being blown up or a bird
hitting the window you see that that is the interaction that's the way creation
unfolds and that's the karma of each entity you know physicality and the
temporality that goes with physicality that's one reason enlightenment is to go
beyond that physicality and so that you're not run over on the road anymore
see that bird had really good karma
that picked him up sure yeah really good karma and and and and the I mean I mean
I did the minister and you go oh my god I can't believe this cruel world and
birds hit the window oh yeah like that it was sort of like he just he just knew
what needed to be done he wasn't oh yeah judgmental place well no that's because
that's the way you are that's the way you are you cherish all of life in all of its
expressions and that's the way you are you cherish all of life in all of its expressions
you see it could be flowers it can be the bird you know compassion for all of
life in all its expressions it's just a way of being with the world you know
you already appreciate that so that means you're already that way yourself
otherwise you wouldn't have been impressed by what he did yes my name is
Jackie I'm from California I read your books in the end of last year and came
to my first seminar in December went home and all
heaven or hell broke loose big time yes I remember you saying that from the
December seminar two things I took home with me whatever isn't integrous in your
life in all areas in whatever area yeah would fall by the wayside the world
comes will show up yeah and and whatever happens just say so what I've been saying
so many times I've been saying so many times I've been saying so many times I've been saying so many times I've been saying so many times
so what every day you know I I'm an RN I had my own practice I closed that due
to other situations my husband had had an alcoholic problem for a long time and
I had told him he needs to do something about this or I was going to walk away
because I I felt it was infringing on even my health and my stress from it so
he said fine I'm going to do something about this because I felt it was
infringing on even my stress from it so I felt it was infringing on even my stress from it so I thought hey he went to a hey
I'll go to a hey he went to he stayed sober for a week came home and told me
her lectures can be helped by the
current marriage girl
this Oh I love
Okay, the prayer of permission to be released from the relationship
if the alcoholism couldn't be brought under control.
I didn't expect the other.
And then I had prayed a prayer similar to what you had said to pray,
which was the third thing I took home,
is whatever time I have left, I dedicate it all to your service.
Okay, good.
Whatever's left.
If I die tonight, that's okay.
C'est la vie.
And that's when everything hit the fan.
What's next?
I don't know.
You can talk then.
Can you talk then?
I'm at a loss to even know what's going to be next.
I don't know.
That's true.
You don't know.
You still don't know what it means.
You still don't know what it means to not.
You still don't know what it means to not resist it and to not seek it,
to be neutral.
Right, right.
So what is that neutral?
If it happens, it happens.
If it doesn't happen, it doesn't happen.
Well, it's okay that it's happened.
All right.
It doesn't throw you about in the boat, see?
No, no.
So you've maintained a certain equilibrium
at things that would throw in a lot of people themselves.
Yeah.
And now you're somehow liberated,
so you've got some kind of a freedom.
I'm free as a bird.
You're free as a bird.
Yeah.
You're free as a bird,
and now you just maintain your spiritual balance,
and what is ready for you will come upon you as the next hello,
you know, like that.
Hello.
And you just keep going along with it like that.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's all.
That's all I can do.
Okay.
There's a plan somewhere.
I have to somehow believe that.
There's a plan somewhere in the confusion,
because it wouldn't have blown up like that.
Yeah.
It must be a set trigger,
and you're taking a jump in consciousness that released it,
so that's all.
Yeah, that's very interesting.
We look forward to the next installment.
Maybe she should only come to every other lecture, okay?
You're speaking to both of us.
Right.
Do you want me to stand in front of this here?
Yes.
Wait, that won't go too well.
Yeah.
No, I'll stand here.
I didn't recognize that.
Is that something I wrote?
Yes?
No.
Thank you very much.
Amazing.
Okay, wait.
He has a question he wants to ask.
Yeah.
My question, you mentioned today
that we have a responsibility to respect our assets.
A responsibility, what?
To respect the assets that we are given,
to be stewards to our assets.
Yes, that's correct.
Yes.
How does one reconcile, for example,
if your asset,
is in the business world,
and your intention is enlightenment,
however it comes,
how do you reconcile
having a sense of responsibility
to participate in daily life,
activating your assets in the business world,
and yet at the same time,
reach a state of enlightenment,
which could render you completely unable
to fulfill those assets?
Right.
All right.
So it's a matter of attachment
and the way in which you contextualize its value.
I mean, you've got to do something with your body
while you hang out waiting to be enlightened,
you know what I'm saying?
And you might as well be using it for the good of mankind,
whether it's producing a product.
I mean, you know, I need a pen to sign things with.
Somebody's got to make the pen.
Somebody's got to ship it.
It has to be boxed.
I mean, you know, the qualities of human life are multiple.
So we serve each other in multiple ways,
multiple ways.
So I say if you're in business,
then see what that value is to the world,
the employee to the employees
as the source of employment, et cetera.
So it serves multiple functions.
And if you see its intrinsic value,
you have to,
you're neither attracted
nor do you have an aversion to it.
It's just what,
then after a while,
you stop identifying,
you're identifying with the body
and you see that's a phenomena.
It's a phenomena of its own.
It doesn't need a personal you to make it happen.
You may have initiated it,
but now it's going to have like a life
or an energy of its own
to which you have a certain responsibility.
Now, the degree of involvement is something different.
So responsibility is one thing.
Involvement is another.
If you can find somebody to run the factory
while you join an ashram,
so why?
So why not?
Thank you.
You can't find somebody to run the factory
and they're all going to lose their jobs
and the factory's going to close
and the townspeople are going to go poor.
That's going to hold you in there
until you find somebody, you know,
that can hold it together
for the sake of the town.
So once you've activated that energy
and then you are, in effect,
neutral to it,
you can then go on your own personal path
knowing that that asset of yours
is alive and has its own momentum.
Yeah, so you try to find
somebody that will fulfill that function for you
and thereby free yourself, huh?
You know, I was chief of staff
at Girls Ranch there in Prescott
for many years
because there wasn't any doctor around.
Well, how am I going to get out of there?
There's no other doctor around,
you know what I mean?
So you're like hooked
until you find somebody that could take over.
And the same with the nursing homes, you know,
until finally the county could find somebody.
So you sort of stayed out of a sense of responsibility
and obligation.
And then, eventually, you get released from it.
You get too old to do it, for God's sake.
Age releases you at the end, thank goodness.
You may be ready to quit,
but the old reaper is going to take you out of it.
Thank you, reaper.
You're a good friend of the reaper,
just when you need him.
Okay, baby.
Hooked you out again.
All right.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
I'm Beverly from Dallas.
We found your books this month.
And we watched your videos all for last year.
And I'm just so appreciative for what you've done
and for God giving me, you know, this chance again.
And so my question, I really formed at home.
I thought, well, I want to get a question
so I can talk to you.
And...
So my question, and I don't really care
whether it's right or wrong,
but can you reach enlightenment reading your books?
Hmm, interesting question.
I would presume that putting it into practice
is what makes the difference.
However, even to have heard of it already changes you.
You know, even the Buddha said that.
Rare is it to be a human being.
Extremely rare in the universe.
Rarer still.
Rarer still is it to have heard of enlightenment.
And rarest of all is having heard of it to pursue it.
Okay.
Therefore, it's a great gift to be a human being.
It's a great gift to even hear of enlightenment.
And it's certainly a great gift to be attracted to it.
You know, so...
Fortunate, karmically fortunate are we
that we've even heard of it and esteemed it
or respected, you know.
Yes.
When you start carrying around,
you know, Huang Po under your arm,
you know, you're getting there.
Right.
I haven't read that yet, but we've got it.
Huang Po or the aphorisms of, et cetera, you know.
They became enlightened in a different culture
and they expressed it in a different way.
And, but they become respected, you know,
ancestors respected, you know.
Well, I didn't want to cry because my husband is here
and we want to get a picture.
No, you can.
And he's got a dollar.
I don't have a dollar.
I don't either.
I'm resigning the dollar fee.
Well, no one else, you have to tell the story
because nobody else is going to buy it.
I won't tell.
No, I got it.
We put it in the dollar bank.
Okay.
All right.
Tell everyone the story.
Okay.
I can't tell you the whole story now.
All right.
It was in the Himalayas.
No, it was in the Alps.
No, it was...
It was in the Himalayas.
No other freaking place.
Machu Picchu.
Yeah.
Peru.
The Andes.
The high up in the Andes.
The Andes in Peru are just mysterious.
I mean, just wow.
And Machu Picchu, of course, is impressive.
Yeah.
Yes.
My name's Mike and I'm from Dallas.
And that beautiful spirit has been in my life for 40 years.
So we share a lot in common.
And I wanted to also thank you and express our gratitude
for what you...
Thank you.
You've meant to us as you've been in our lives.
The question I have is some clarification
in regards to causality versus intention.
Or causality and intention.
I've heard you say that when you snip the apple,
you didn't cause it to drop.
No.
The field did.
The gravity did.
Gravity did, yeah.
And then you've also said that when you have...
With the Empire State Bill,
that there was a an intention that went in there and into the field of an
infinite potentiality yeah right so my question is could the snipping of the
Apple be the intention in the infinite field of potentiality that yeah brings
the actualization of the intention well it was you see potentiality becomes
actuality when conditions are favorable oh so it's favorable because all you do
you're not going to cause the Apple to fall you're going to just change the
timing of it because come foot you know in autumn it's going to drop of its own
so you're just trying to jump it up so
intentionality then becomes potentiality when the conditions
to
facilitate that actuality are present so it doesn't like otherwise you would have
life going against itself you know I'm saying linear life at least going
against itself so the potentiality then is extremely powerful powerful you might
say all of creation is the actualization of the potentiality of the will of God
who only had to say yes to the spark and foreverness evolved
within the third three dimensional world okay a follow-up question is it
seemed like when you've talked about the lower levels of consciousness that that
that's a big attractor field and they get more of what were they're resonating
for their realizing isn't theontology I guess with the intention is it in Jagl
Arif this kind of thing or is there a but Minute
level consciousness and then the togetherness of the consciousness I can
potentiality is
potentiated at that point
at a higher level of consciousness?
Yes, because you contextualize the whole thing
different, your intention is different.
So I say the reason
you should prepare for enlightenment
is because
everybody here is already committed to it,
aligned with it, they're studying
it, practicing it, well, the end is
uncertain, unless you do something
to make it, you know,
to refuse it. It's going to constantly
unfold to you.
And whatever the way that you
need to see to go, it's going to be like
suddenly illuminated, you suddenly see this
pathway over here, and if you hadn't
chosen enlightenment, you wouldn't see that pathway
over there. So
those things are not definable,
but you've obviously
changed the course
of events, yeah?
Okay, very good, thanks again.
Dallas, eh?
Here?
It's all in this.
The chair is like right here.
Yeah, but the box is pointing
different. Well, I moved in because
everybody was sitting in the room. It's hard for them to get
in and out, but the chair is out that way.
Yeah.
Dr. Hawkins, I have
enjoyed your chanting Aum
when you have done so in the past.
With your permission, may we have quiet
from the audience, and would you give us
as comfortable as you can
a nice, long, and deep
Aum, also for the purpose
for those who purchase a tape,
so that we can listen to your Aum
at the end of the seminar later.
We can listen to your Aum
to our hearts content.
You told us that you aren't allowed to do the octopus
anymore, so
my friends and I would like to give you this.
Oh, isn't that adorable?
Thank you. My friends have the questions.
I don't have a question.
Thank you.
That's an adorable octopus.
I've always admired them.
Incredible entity.
Oh, look at the eyes here.
Yes.
Um,
my question is in regards to assets.
Is it important
to know your assets?
And I'm wondering,
is mediocrity an asset?
It's a great
liberation.
To be a virtuoso, an expert,
uh,
is quite a pressure, isn't it?
To be a world champion chess player once,
your life is screwed, you know?
Especially if you're beat by
Big Blue. Oh, boy.
Your life is hell, thenceforth.
Yes, no, mediocrity
is a way of being sort of at
neutral. And I think
sometimes the spirit, you know,
takes sort of a rest
and goes on vacation for a while.
You know, I think this one,
you know, when I just have a
easy life, have a good family,
a good job, and
let it be at that and learn to enjoy
what you are.
So, to enjoy that which
you are may be the lesson.
To appreciate and see the
value of enjoying of being nobody.
I tell you,
being nobody is wonderful.
Compared to being somebody,
it has a great payoff, yeah.
When you're driving down the road
in the truck and nobody knows you from Adam,
and you're not
beholden to anybody,
don't have to be anywhere, don't have to sign anything,
don't have to vote on anything,
don't have to be quoted, don't have to appear
on television or radio.
You're a free bird. Are you letting anybody
down by doing that?
Well, of course, the word needs you to save them,
but it'll do without you.
No, I mean, if you, like you talked about
being responsible for your
assets, right? Well, yes.
What is your asset? So, your asset is
the learning of the value
of just being ordinary.
So, it's learning
to live without specialness.
See, the ego wants specialness.
And it wants specialness of relationships
and goods and values
and titles and recognitions and
it wants to voice its opinion about
everything.
So, to learn to live
in that space is extremely valuable.
So, you can be with God
there. You just be with it
there. Thank you.
Any progressive demands will appear
only too soon.
The next emotional
tsunami. Thank you both
for being here today. Yes.
I have a question.
When you talked about working with the girls
at the ranch,
when we work with people that are
at these levels, I see today
that you have amusements. You can say,
you can laugh at people in
the below 200 non-integrist
levels.
But some of us in the trenches, it's hard
to maintain
a sense of
humor.
It's hard to continue in a
positive space when
you're working with a lot, especially
people in alcoholism.
Well, and some don't.
Do you have tools
in that area? Well,
professional detachment is something
you learn. And eventually
you learn compassion without attachment.
And attachment
is trying to exert your will on
outcomes. So
you learn to serve
whatever you can serve, because
it's your
turn to hold their hand, but you're
not the last one in line.
And they'll be going down to the next hands.
You understand?
So you serve your function to the best of
your ability, and
you convey the message. You can carry
the message, you can't carry the person.
Once you convey the
options, and many people
will choose the negative,
many people would rather die
than give in. You know that.
I tell them, you get behind the car
one more time, they're gonna
put you away for
five years. What do you
think the first thing you did when you got home was?
You got in the car.
So, you see, you can't
force them to be saved.
The other
question I had for you is about
location. You moved here from New York,
and are there different
places that are easier for us to work?
And when we're in certain places,
is
the job harder?
It seems to me sometimes it's harder. I'm in Phoenix
right now.
Is what harder? The environment?
Is the enlightenment harder?
The journey more difficult?
Because you convert it into
whatever it's gonna be.
You convert anything
anywhere to
subserve your overall
intention.
You pass through the
doorways
in multiple circumstances.
Alright, thank you.
The rich and the famous, the poor and the
infamous, it's all the same.
Yes? Hi. So, I'm in
the process of surrender
for spiritual
evolution.
And I seem to be
losing
parts of my right side
in the process. Your right thigh?
Side.
Like my right eye, my right
hand.
They seem to be busy somewhere else.
So, I wonder
if you could
explain surrender.
Maybe I'm confused on that.
Or is this just part of the
process? It has to do with the will.
Uh-huh.
All spiritual work
centers on the fulcrum of the will.
It's only by the ascent of the will.
And it's by the ascent of the will
that your karmic
destiny is
set, and the calibrated level of consciousness
is set, because the two go together.
It's only by the
will. So, the surrender
is surrender of what? It's
surrender of volition, of
will, and
trying to control. So, the will
expresses itself in ordinary life.
It's trying to control.
And willpower, you know, is very
weak. Everybody's tried
willpower, and so the
will of the ego
is relatively weak.
The will of the ego
calibrates at exactly the same level
as your personal level.
So, if you're at 205 and you exert
your will, the power of that will
is going to be at 205,
which may tip the balance.
The invocation, see,
will with a capital W is the will of
God. And when you surrender
to God's
will, that means you've removed
your own resistance and positionalities
and vanities. Now
you've opened the door,
and the spiritual
will, the will of God
as you experience it within,
calibrates at 850. Wow.
Well, 850 will
knock just about anything
off the path.
So, the personal will
then is insufficient to overcome
even a
bad habit.
The divine will, however, is enormously
powerful. So, when you invite in
divine will, then be prepared.
.
Be prepared when you invite in divine
will, because it may
sweep people right out of your
family situation, may sweep you right
from one part of the country to another, may change
your health. You may go from wealth
to poverty or vice versa.
And this is by volition.
Hmm? No, it's not
by volition, it's by the will of God.
Volition, then, is personal will.
You might say willfulness,
even though you purify
it with a spiritual sounding goal,
it's still willfulness.
It's willful
to even insist that you're going to be enlightened,
right? Who wants to be enlightened?
The ego wants to be enlightened, okay.
So, if you surrender
then the will to God, and you say
I align myself with
thee, O Lord,
that I may be thy servant,
that I may fulfill my infinite potential
to thy glory, you know, etc.
So, this as a way of being
in the world now
invites divine will.
And then, as I say, you're about
better be prepared, because whatever it takes
throwing you off a cliff to get it,
that's what happens, okay?
That's why the 12-step
programs are so powerful.
You admit that you're powerless,
well, then invoke the
will of God. So you're
getting rid of something that
calibrates below 200, or you wouldn't be
having a problem with addiction.
And you're inviting in the miraculous,
as everybody will tell you.
It was not of their own self
they recovered, it was
miraculous.
So, early on in your lecture
you calibrated that 90%,
only 90% of the
Oh, I'd say roughly 90% of the people in the
audience will reach enlightenment, yeah.
They're all destined, but only 90%
will get there.
Oh, so...
10% will stop over at the casino
for a few...
But will they
reach enlightenment at some point?
Are you worried about that?
No.
I let God worry about it.
Just curious.
It's just an estimation.
As I say,
we tend to sweep in together,
and
that 10%, maybe after a few
catastrophic disasters, will
shift, you know. But, you know, enlightenment
is a great rarity.
Only 1 in 10 million
even think of it as a plausible
alternative.
Yes, 10 million people
on the street. What is your main
ambition in life?
1 in 10 million will tell you
to realize God
or to become enlightened, or
you know. 1 in 10 million.
And that doesn't mean they're good
at it, either.
So, rare it is to be born a human
to have heard of enlightenment.
And rarest of all,
to be born a human, to have heard
it, and then to seek it.
And...
Those who call upon me
are dear to me, said Krishna.
The 91st Psalm
says the same thing.
To those who place all
their faith in me,
the miraculous shall be
spread before them. See?
The same thing is said in all
great religions.
Those who call upon divinity
surrender their life
to the service of divinity,
you become dear to divinity.
And divinity looks
after its own.
Maybe the 10% is unwilling to do that.
They wish to keep it as a function
of the personal world. See?
Enlightened will be
when I want it. No.
Enlightened may be never.
Is that okay with you?
Me? If I'm God and I say,
you surrender your enlightenment to me.
Sure. Okay.
And it may not happen at all.
Is that okay? Absolutely.
Okay. If it's okay not to become enlightened,
now you've earned the right to become enlightened.
Thank you.
May have to repeat the same grade, huh?
Yeah, a few times.
That's actually
my concern or question, I guess,
is about worry.
I worry a lot, and it just keeps
repeating itself over
and over and over again.
And I've noticed, or I guess I've
become aware how much I worry
and how much, I guess it's the attractor fields
that I attract to myself, like kind of the chaos.
I'm afraid, or I worry about
a lot of things, so I think I create
all this chaos. Okay, so it's basically
the unwillingness to surrender.
Also, the illusion
that constantly
working it over in your mind will
somehow solve it or change it.
Whereas the opposite,
if you surrender it to God and say, I can't do it,
call the plumber.
Then you surrender it to the plumber.
You don't hang over on the plumber and tell him which way to pick it.
Now,
worrying is a way of thinking
that if you just keep persisting
on it long enough, you will change the result
and gain control of it.
You don't. You just constantly entertain yourself
with that thought.
It's a way of getting hooked into trying to control,
trying to control
the outcome by sort of
worrying it and chewing it, chewing it over.
It's a natural human
characteristic.
So it's a control issue?
I would think so. Could you let,
to, the way really out of it is
to picture the worst possible
scenario. I do that a lot.
And surrender.
I don't want to do that anymore.
And surrender yourself to it.
And then ask for God, God for help.
And that's, and some of them,
the reason they don't resolve
is that there's karmic
blockages of why it's
hanging out with you.
A certain problem
will persist and persist and persist.
Sometimes for years.
And then finally, it relents.
It's like you pull the little props
out from underneath it and then finally
the whole avalanche collapses.
But, because you
experience it in time,
it seems trying, you know.
Is there any way
I can speed it up?
Well, you
quit wanting to speed it up, it'll disappear.
Stop resisting suffering.
Choose to suffer.
I love to worry.
I love the suffering of worry.
I love the anxiety of worry.
Well,
the way to get rid of a thing is by choosing it.
The way to experience a thing
is by resisting it.
So you only experience that which you resist.
So choose to worry.
Your problem is you don't worry hard enough.
Get up earlier, I want you to sit there
and I want you to really, really
worry. You're doing a
half-assed Jamba Queen.
Are you able to eat?
Oh yeah, I eat. You can eat?
Well, then you're not worrying hard enough.
When you're really worried,
you're sick and you lose your appetite, so
you're not worrying hard enough.
Worry harder.
I want you to promise me
that you're going to worry
harder.
Harder. Are you going to
promise me or not? I want you to
promise me that you're
going to worry harder.
Will you do that or not?
What did I say about the will?
Do you have to do that?
I'm asking you, would you please
worry harder? I'm the doctor.
You're the patient.
Yes. Alright, you can even worry
by the clock. I want you to keep
a diary of your worry time.
Alright,
worry you can also calibrate on a one to ten
like pain. What's your worry
at now? Five?
Four? Six?
Four or five. Five out of five.
Okay. You've got to focus on
worrying and worry up to about
a ten. I want you to really agonize
and worry over the damn thing.
When you lose your
appetite, you know you're at a ten.
I want you
to keep it up as long as you can do it.
Okay. Okay?
Are you serious? I am very serious.
I'm being videotaped.
I'm being
videotaped right now.
Alright.
I want you to promise
me you are going to worry hard.
Earnestly.
You're holding back.
Is this a joke?
It's your question. It's your answer.
If you're not going to stop worrying about you,
by God, I am.
I'm really worried about
this lady.
She won't worry harder.
And I'm really worried that if you don't worry
harder, you're going to be stuck with worrying this.
Work harder on worrying.
I want you to blow off the carbon on the highway.
Run a ride up to 90, 95 and don't take
your foot off the exhaust.
Don't worry about it.
That's the way you burn the carbon out of the valves, isn't it?
Oh yeah.
Get on the road and run it. Go.
Go for it.
And I've got to go to the diary. Time diary.
Just keep worrying.
And give me
a one to ten.
You disappear that which you choose
and you perpetuate that which you resist.
Dr. Hawkins,
I'd like to thank you for having
accrued the karmas that led you
to stick around.
I'm doing the Course in Miracles.
And I'm at a point where
I'm asked to
listen for the voice for God.
And
I'm having trouble
both believing that
God has a voice
and that I want to hear voices.
We've got
Cossack, we've got Thorothene.
Okay,
so it hasn't been revealed to you
what the voice of God sounds like.
That's true.
Did you hear it?
I heard that.
Merry Christmas.
Now do you hear the voice of God?
Yes. It's present.
And all that exists,
as it expresses it to you,
everything is divinity.
That's how you see the beauty
that exists in everything.
Divinity reveals itself
as exquisite beauty of all that exists.
The presence of God is innate
within sound as well.
All sound is
the voice of God.
You intuit the presence of God
in all that exists, all that speaks,
all that stands,
all that falls, all that breathes,
all that thinks.
There is no other voice.
That one I want to hear.
Thank you.
Dr. Hawkins, would you comment
on the relationship between
the calibration of art
and the calibration of the artist
that created it?
For example, I think that you have said
that Rembrandt's paintings calibrate
very high, perhaps 700.
Does Rembrandt calibrate 700?
No, I just calibrate the art.
Generally, the literary
product, the writing or the art
of a person will reflect exactly
their level of consciousness.
Generally, it's the same.
Because you would have to artificially
become that which you are not
to create something different
to what you are.
You have to be sort of a deliberate fake
or something.
Pretend you're stupid when you're not.
It's hard to do.
A lot of things become
obvious by paradox
and humor.
I think paradox and humor.
Everybody's into piety
and singing hymns
and all, but I think
through humor, paradox,
things become instantly
aware.
Yes?
Dr. Hawkins, when self-hatred
arises, how does one
work with that and accept it?
How do you handle it?
Well, what do you get out of it,
for one thing?
You get the fun of hating.
If hating wasn't enjoyable and fun,
people wouldn't indulge in it.
There's a payoff to hating.
First of all, you get to feel virtuous
that you're hating evil and stuff.
Then what you're hating
is perceptions of yourself.
You don't even know who you are.
So any kind of a hatred is
some kind of a perception, see?
You know, maybe a mistake
or, you know, something.
So you're misperceiving it.
So what you hate is a perception
because you don't know what the reality is.
You know, you say,
I hate myself because I'm selfish.
Well, the problem is you're not selfish enough.
Shall I practice
being selfish?
If being selfish is what you hate
about yourself, then be
more selfish.
Just be the epitome of greed
and gimme-ness.
I want more octopuses.
You see, because you're defeated
by paradox, by the alignment
of the fallacious and the imaginary
with the true, you know?
Pretty soon you'll laugh at it, you know?
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
It is so cute, isn't it?
Yes?
It's so nice to come visiting again.
Yes, indeed.
I have a question from
you.
You talked about ego death
and your ego death.
Oh, I have a question about
ego death.
About what?
Ego.
Your ego death.
Oh, my ego?
Yes, because reading the books
I got confused.
It sounded like it died twice.
The question is, you talked about
when you were in the pits of hell
and you were murdered,
but then you also talked about
Rothmans, and they sound similar.
The restaurant, Rothmans?
Oh, yeah, Rothmans, yes.
Rothmans.
Oh, those were different levels.
See, as you grow up, you know,
you experience
different levels.
It isn't like you go from this
to that as a total completion.
You wouldn't be able to handle that.
The nervous system wouldn't handle it.
You move until you see,
as I reported to the group,
the trap of the void.
Not trap, but the fallout of the void.
The void's at 850.
I mean, that's pretty impressive.
But it isn't the ultimate way.
So,
at various levels you experience
the flow of the kundalini energy
and you experience
the bliss at 600,
which, if the body moves
or doesn't move or breathes again,
it's irrelevant.
So each level is what it is
and you can't compare levels.
Yes?
So, from the pits of hell
and then that's when your ego died.
You surrendered completely.
Your ego death was in that
event.
Yes.
It was out of the pits of hell.
And you were an atheist before that?
Oh, yes.
By an atheist,
you meant you didn't believe in God
and this guy and that guy.
But what did you mean by atheism?
That's not an atheist.
Oh, really?
But you were meditating, like,
twice a day or something, right?
Oh, that was a different time period.
You're mixing time periods.
Don't forget, I've been around
close to 80 years, you know.
So there's a period of 10 years of this
and 10 years of that, 20 years of this.
By my age, you can live decades
at various levels.
Decades.
Well, that gives hope to most anyone then.
Oh, yes.
You can pull in what has to be
gone through.
All that stands between you and enlightenment
now gets summoned up.
And all the lifetimes and all the karmic propensities.
And just after you got everything all cleared,
you just undid the negative karma.
Something in the positive side comes through
and this may bring up
another karmic propensity.
You're clearing out the whole stack.
What a surprise.
A little surprise package?
I mean, it sounded like you were
like you might have been born
at least.
Oh, I don't know.
I told you what it was at age 3.
I came out of nothingness, void,
lifetimes,
a pathway of negation.
The ultimate reality was nothing.
Nothingness.
Total voidness.
And I came out of that at age 3.
Nothingness.
Into the realization of existence.
Which was shocking.
Not pleasing.
Like coming out of
the safety of
equanimity and
anonymity into somethingness.
As somethingness now.
You can stop, you know.
If you're a something, then you can also become a nothing.
So, out of
the void of
non-existence, nothingness
was the shock of existence.
Just like you've lived
forever in a dark cave and
suddenly somebody threw on Klieg lights.
It was shocking
and not pleasant.
On top of that,
there was this physicality
sitting in the little wagon.
The goddamn little body
went with this deal.
Which again was not pleasing.
No sooner was there
the shocking of awareness of existence
that then its alternative
came up.
If it had come about that I had
come into beingness and existence,
then it might have come about
hypothetically, theoretically,
at least to not have come into existence.
And therefore,
the fear of non-existence arose.
If you picture yourself
as existing,
now it brings up the corollary.
Therefore, what about non-existence
as a possibility?
Of course, that's a falsity.
But it's only a falsity at 850.
Not a falsity at 700.
It's not your problem.
But at 850, you're now accountable for that.
To resolve that duality.
Is that an explanation? Good.
It's really good.
It might take me a while.
Yeah, you never know when.
See, the ultimate experience
is the absolute allness.
The allness.
So I had to back off from that,
spend almost a lifetime
to transcend that error.
Because the ultimate state
is one of allness, totality,
all inclusiveness,
and the most telling
difference in quality
between nothingness and allness
is in allness,
the presence of the love of God
is overwhelming.
In voidness,
which is very, very impressive,
don't get me wrong,
it is very impressive,
it is an ultimate state.
And many people conclude that is it.
Except, I'd had the experience
earlier in life of experiencing the presence.
Therefore,
in the nothingness of voidness,
there was a quality,
an absent, a non-linear quality.
Which is the presence of divine love,
which is a meltingness,
exquisite,
infinitely powered by virtue
of its exquisite nature.
And that was missing.
And therefore,
one thought remained.
And it took me all the energy
I could summon up over the hours
to energize that thought.
And even then to energize
being attracted to that thought
to back out of the void.
I managed to attach
a sense of reality
to a linearity.
A thought.
I knew that thought was my only way out of here.
I needed a thought to get out of nothingness.
There ain't any thoughts in nothingness.
Quite a problem.
If you're looking for what to hang onto,
there's nothing to hang onto.
There was a non-linear volition.
The decision
to align one's life with God,
to surrender it all to divinity,
had brought in
a karmic...
Yes, I see it now.
It was a karmic consequence of that
that allowed me to have the one thought
for it to still be in the void.
Yes?
That's a very sophisticated question.
And it's one thought that brought you out of hell too.
Yes.
And you didn't go for the void then?
No, that was the opposite direction of the void.
I could have used the little void there.
What time do we have to quit?
Yeah, okay.
We'll be done just in a minute.
It always finishes just in time.
Dr. Hawkins, I have two questions.
One question is,
you mentioned that the consciousness
of the world increased
in the late 80's to 205.
And last year
to 207.
And the question I had then was
why do you think that's so?
Calibrated as so.
And the second question is,
I've heard that,
and I don't know if this is in fact
truth or not truth,
of indigo and crystal children
coming into the consciousness of the world
with the purpose of raising
the world's consciousness.
Yes.
Whether that's something that's not true.
It does not ring true with me.
Okay, that's what I wanted to know.
Crystal children and indigo children
would have to calibrate way, way up
to be raising the consciousness of all mankind.
I think what they really mean is that
they would have to calibrate
the consciousness of all to see them differently.
Okay, alright.
And thereby raise the consciousness level of the world.
Why do you think the world,
the consciousness has gone up since the 190's?
That's the province of divinity, you know.
You can ask God when you get there,
how come?
Okay.
I think because
the evolution of consciousness,
if we ask
by, you know,
is it intrinsic
the consciousness itself
to evolve and seek its own source?
We have permission to ask
that over there.
That is so, it is intrinsic.
It's intrinsic to the quality of consciousness itself
to grow and seek
its, to return to its source.
So we then
look forward to...
It negates any negation.
Increasing consciousness over time.
It happens of its own nature.
And you get swept along with it.
Nobody ever asked an octopus
if it wants to get smarter.
Nobody even consulted me, he says.
Nobody ever consulted me on the issue.
I'm sorry.
Hello.
I teach Reiki.
And
up until noon today
I would have listed that as an asset
of mine. But some of your
remarks, which I can't
perfectly remember,
kind of threw me.
And so I'm
wondering what to make of it.
Oh, it isn't discipline.
It's the misuse of the discipline.
It doesn't negate the value of discipline.
What about the business
of channeling? Because
as I'm told... I already told you what I think.
Yes, okay.
I told you how it
arose. I told you what
the error is. And you have to
sort of think about it.
Okay. Each of those things
you know, is not positive
or negative in itself.
Because such things are
a necessary experience as part of
spiritual evolution. You know.
Part of spiritual evolution
is you sort of get bit by the bug.
Now you start to explore everything.
You go to every consciousness festival
and, you know,
spiritual bazaar and
New Age festival.
And it's
aisle after aisle of exhibits
and parades and flashing lights and
smells and incenses and massages
and balancings. And it's
a whole area to explore.
The only thing wrong with exploring it.
How can you know what it is unless you check it out?
Yeah.
Check it out.
Do you think though that if she is a
practicing Reiki, is the intention
behind her to heal that person?
Of course the intention is what gives it the power.
You're correct. So it's not
magic. So, sometimes
it gets caught in magic, then it gets
commercialized, etc.
I'm really aware of the commercialization
and dislike it enormously.
But I was just wondering if this
was something that I should continue
doing because I see that as being
giving. Well, it depends on what it means
to you and the part it plays in your life.
So, another thing, you become
enthusiast to various things along the way
and then you outgrow them. See?
But I think the power
of Reiki is the intention.
The intense intention.
And then the energy summoned forth by that
intention. You know what I'm saying?
So, I would take it out of the realm of magic.
So, the only trouble with a lot of new age kind of
things is they really are
contextualized as a certain kind of magic.
Not for me.
Alright. Yeah.
I was concerned about...
The conscious utilization of energies
for a benign purpose. So, the intention
is very vigorous.
Also, because I don't support something, it doesn't
mean I oppose it.
I mean, I support vanilla, but that doesn't mean
I'm against chocolate.
Yes?
Do you have any advice for someone who is
dealing with ADD?
ADD?
Do you believe in it?
Do you think it's an impediment to awareness?
I've treated hundreds and hundreds of cases.
What is ADD? Attention Deficit Disorder.
Yes? Yes.
It causes impairment and suffering.
Impairment of functioning.
This creates a social
kickback, which may decrease the
person's self-esteem.
And the net result may be
primarily the loss of self-esteem
You can't keep up.
You're always getting D's.
You're always putting the dunce hat on.
You're always being the imbecile.
You're always being ridiculed.
So the punishment, the punitive reaction of society
to the disorder, unless it's corrected,
is often worse than the disorder.
I mean, so what if you can't concentrate
and you can't read?
So what?
In a society in which this is a necessity,
now you're at an impasse.
I would say if a thing can be cured
by a simple medication,
I see no reason why not.
The Course in Miracles
and everybody else says,
all things are physical, mental, and spiritual.
And it's arrogant to deny any one of the three.
So I would say,
if you've got ADD, you do all you can
behaviorally, medically,
spiritually.
The same as any other disorder.
A duodenal ulcer,
ADHD, you do the same thing.
Thank you.
I take things for something,
so what?
God bless you, Dr.
I have to convert styrofoam back into bone.
So, I mean, that requires,
you've got to put something in your nose.
And now it pulls calcium,
and it's a wonderment, see?
So you do that, you also pray,
and you also be careful.
Okay, I had a question about,
as students on the path to enlightenment,
we have the responsibility of walking the path
as straight as possible.
But when we're married, we have family,
and sometimes we tend to maybe
fall to the wayside,
embroiled in the problems of those loved ones.
And how to,
how do we walk that line?
You don't have to set it aside and compartmentalize it.
This is spiritual,
and this is daily life.
What you do is spiritualize your daily life.
The reason you're peeling potatoes
is being of service
to life in the form of this family, etc.
So what you do is spiritualize
your endeavors, so that you
contextualize them differently.
This is spiritual,
and this is family, see?
I argue for the sake of my family.
That's not spiritual.
Why are you arguing for the sake of your family?
Because you esteem it,
because you are dedicated to its well-being.
So spiritualize what you do,
and recontextualize it,
and you'll see everything you do is spiritual
if you contextualize it in such a way.
Everything you're doing is karma yoga
for the sake of your family.
Okay, I got that karma yoga part earlier.
When I'm making the lunches for my kids,
I'm making the karma yoga.
See, the maternal was the avenue
by which love entered the human domain.
There wasn't any love before the maternal.
Males do not love each other.
Not early in the game.
Only later, only later in evolution.
That's after the maternal
has already brought forth
love as a prevailing energy.
The first time the man experiences it
is via the mother.
Okay, thank you very much.
Hello.
Yes.
My question is in regard to self-inquiry.
In your book, you say that
the question,
how is it that I am aware
or even know that I exist
is a question that would lead you
all the way to the door,
or one of the only questions.
And I was curious if you could kind of elaborate on that,
and if I'm supposed to ask that
as kind of like a form of prayer to God,
for God to show me that,
well, it's moving,
I believe it's better to move from who I am
to what I am.
Ramana Maharshi apparently,
I think,
favored that.
Self-inquiry?
Who am I is already self-limiting
because the who is a linearity.
The what you are is a quality.
And when you experience the reality of the self,
it is not a who.
It is a what.
It is a quality.
It's a pervasive,
self-existent quality.
It's best to wonder who,
not who I am,
but what am I.
Because what is it that asks who am I?
You understand?
So you go back to the asker of the question,
and you're already out of the trap of the question.
Okay.
Because
what you are
is not a who, but a what.
Thank you.
With apologies to Ramana.
Hi.
Yeah.
I had a question.
I'm not exactly sure how to format this,
but you had talked about the calibration
of the United States being 420.
421.
And you've also talked about
how in advertising
you project to the audience
that you're trying to communicate with
and the other countries I know
ranked at different levels of calibration.
How is it that
the United States can calibrate
420,
and yet their methodology with dealing with
not only its own citizens,
but people of the world,
That's a judgment.
That's a judgment you're making.
That's your perception.
You have no idea what it is.
I want you to calibrate
the level of all the members of the cabinet,
the supreme court,
federal court, state court, judicial,
calibrate the ninth court,
circuit court of appeals,
calibrate all the leading people,
calibrate the speaking voices
of politics.
Then you can lay it out on a map
and you begin to see
an alignment of how
that prevails.
Because each is an expression
of a certain level of consciousness.
It's not a matter
of being right or wrong.
Not a matter of being right or wrong.
I guess, though,
when the President comes to the United States
or when he speaks to his people
and the whole level
of the fear level,
it seemed like
the way of getting the people
behind him
was through fear,
which is a lower calibrated energy.
I understand what you're saying
that you need to calibrate the individuals.
I do understand that.
When he tells you
a reality that threatens your existence,
the fear is
your idea.
If you go off the highway, you'll die.
Do I say that to make fear?
In fact, that's why we want guardrails.
See,
I cannot be responsible
for your decision
of how you want to emotionally react.
He's not creating fear.
You're creating the fear.
How you individually perceive
his message, but he also
perceives as well.
That's because
it's his responsibility.
That's why we said
to not know that there was
500,000
Chinese communist soldiers
north of the border in Korea
was a gross
dereliction of dirty duty.
If I ask you what does that calibrate,
you'll see it's about 180.
You want a surgeon that operates on you
at 180?
No.
Integrity means
that you must fulfill the obligation
of your office.
As a physician, I tell people
you take this, you get better.
You don't take it, you probably get a heart attack and die.
That's not to create fear.
I'm just telling them what the facts are.
My obligation is
to my role.
If you want to be afraid of what I said,
that's your option.
But I'm not trying to control
whether they take it or not
with fear.
That's not my intention.
If I take the medicine, the bones get stronger.
If I don't,
you can get what's called
fracture.
No, it's a fracture
Stress fracture, they call it.
I said,
do I have to put this stuff in my nose
and take this crap and all?
He said, well if you don't, you can be walking along
and your femur will just go crunch.
I said, well that's inconvenient
as all hell when I'm about to get on the bus.
I don't really want it to go crunch
all by itself out there.
So I take the sniffer.
But he's not controlling me with fear.
No, I
understand your point.
But if somebody,
let's say you calibrated somebody
that's making decisions like that
that affect the rest of the world
and they calibrate at 420, 421,
whatever.
Out of integrity
for themselves
and where they're calibrating,
don't they have the responsibility
to make integrity based
decisions that affect others?
Whatever they consider
their role
and integrity is their role.
If you're the mother
and the water's contaminated
and you tell them you drink that
you'll be dysentery and die.
That's your role as a mother.
If they're children
and they're your wards
is now your obligation to prevent them
from drinking the water
until they're smart enough
to not drink it themselves.
Also they don't have the strength
to protect themselves.
So as mother
in their behalf.
I see.
Okay. Thank you very much.
You have to read the oath of office.
And I'll tell you
he took the oath of office.
Yeah.
Well they don't understand triage.
Triage you don't understand
until consciousness level 390.
Anybody in power is often
between a rock and a hard place.
So he's gonna be
vilified whichever way he goes.
If you don't kill
480,000
or 180,000
or whatever Hiroshima was
180,000 voluntarily
you're gonna kill
7 million involuntarily.
So the rock and the hard place
of Truman
and I calibrated his decision.
His decision was at 485.
You have to have been in the military
to understand triage.
But I'll tell you when I was in the fleet
if you went over
to get you
I went over the side
swept between two ships
a steel cable almost snapped me in half
it just missed my head
it would have beheaded me.
Huge force. As this ship went up
the steel cable went like a shot
like a cannon.
It would have cut me right in half.
So I fell off the buoy
into the Huangpu River.
The Ganges is awful.
You fight your way between
the feces and the dead bodies
and the current is fantastic
and it takes you
and here I'm headed for a nest of ships
destroyers and sudden destroyers
fast little ships
anyway they're smashing
against each other
this one is smashing against each other
and these huge things are smashing
and I'm floating right for them
all 110 pounds
flailing in the water
and to help me
not only did I get off the buoy
before it would have cut my head off
the next thing is I'm floating
and I got floated right up to the very prow of this ship
like this
the Huangpu River current is going by
dead bodies are
oh sorry going by
we have to get them off
we need them off
there's the river now
laughter
what do we got for a mop?
anything?
moppity moppity mop
well we become part and parcel of our message don't we
laughter
I forgot what I was telling you about that
the water
it had to do with karma
yeah
so actually I got hung up there
like this
and they had to come out and rescue me
so I wasn't too great in the navy
they had to rescue me from the top of the mast
because I froze up there with fear
they had me as a deep sea diver
and they put this bell over my head
and the minute I got below water
I got hyperventilation
couldn't stop breathing
as a mesomorph I was a failure
I'll tell you that
thank you very much Dr. Hawkins
you honor me and we're all very fortunate
thank you Susan
you started this lecture saying
to make your life a mudra
to be one with the
absolute field
and I realized that
when this physicality that we call
Dr. Hawkins speaks
and is trying to elucidate
this concept
very little
reference is made to the I
and you speak in a very non-dualistic way
would it
improve our chances
help us in any way as a spiritual practice
to try to
speak this way
and not use the subject predicate form of language
which is in itself dualistic
I never thought of that
you're correct
I always explain things
sort of in the third person
you know
because I would witness the body
getting up and doing something
and ordinarily you would say I
it's sort of the detached witness
that you're the witness
of the phenomena
I never noticed that
but that's a fact
you don't language it
as a subject predicate
for an object
like who is this doing that
it's more or less I guess
what in language you would call the passive third person
or the passive third
in writing I forget what they call it
besides confusing
the passive third person
isn't that what it is
where you describe the phenomena
as the passage of equalities
and not necessarily a personal intervention
I guess you would say
that's typical of scientific writing too
right
sulfur were put in
with one sniff of potassium
and bright lights evolved
so would it benefit us
to do that
I never thought of it
as a tool or useful tool
it may well be
because I kind of surmised that
from my readings in the past
what do you suggest
we have permission to ask it now
we got no permission
one other thing then
below the level of 200
they act in concordance
with an attractor field
and have no personal karma
and thereby have no personal choice
then how do they take the leap
beyond 200
perhaps the evolution
of the field itself
in other words the fields themselves
you see the progression of consciousness
so progression
consciousness tends to
evolve into greater and greater
complexity and then beyond
complexity to simplicity
to return to its source
it could be the impersonal
consequence of the karma
there are many ancient references
to it they're not my personal experience
so I can't say
the Rig Veda says
that each thing by virtue of what it is
subserves higher life
and by subserving higher life
it earns the karmic
right to become the higher life
therefore
the lower life
which it surrenders itself
to be eaten by you
you don't see it
but it gives up its life
to God
and then
comes forth its human energy
and now has earned the karmic right
to eventuate into humanness
yeah
you might call it
the karma of sacrifice
each thing surrenders its life
to support the life
beyond it or above it
and by virtue of that earns the right
to become that which is above it
thank you very much
we have three minutes left
we got just enough time for the last
if we're quick as a wink we'll make it
in the book I
wrote that being in the presence
in the aura of the enlightened teacher
has a karmic imprint
can you expound a little bit on what that means
to the spiritual aspirant
it's a frequency
that's transmitted in the aura
so
in going into the state that occurred
in this lifetime
or undoubtedly the consequence of the energy
picked up prior
because in walking
through the final door
which was terrifying
and agonizing
for a few moments
there was the knowingness
with absolute certainty
walk through all fear
all fear is illusion
that came as a powerful certainty
concrete knowingness
and that
enabled the surrender
where did it come from
because there's no memory there
at that level your mind is silent
you think when I get there I'm going to remember it
you're not going to remember it
there's nobody there to remember it
there's no memory you can send forth
there's no thinkingness or thought or mind
the knowingness
so like the vibration is waiting for you
and when you need it
the vibration is like an encoded message
and the encoding opens up
as the knowingness of the presence
therefore it can only be transmitted
by those who have done it
it has to be somebody who has actually
done it
you can see
I will tell you
when you surrender your life to divinity
you will die
and be born
that's a fact
that you will die
it's the only death you can experience
and those are the doors that open
what is beyond
is beyond all description
so the knowingness
having heard it as the frequency
and the vibration is now recorded
in the field of consciousness forever
likewise am I responsible
karmically for having said it
and it's only with full awareness
that I even say it
yeah
first of all
I'd like to say I have tremendous
gratitude for the
spiritual guidance and awareness
that your consciousness brings to us
through your books
it's just amazing
but my question has to do with health
and I know you've written that historically
you had a plethora of health problems
that you went through
and I'm struggling
with a few things myself
they come and they go
spent many thousands of dollars
and still have it
still stuck with it
somehow I'm myself in this conundrum
don't quite know how to get myself out
of it
no matter how much money you spend on it
it still goes its merry way
thousands of dollars
I'm making doctors, chiropractors, acupuncturists
a bunch of people rich
and I'm still struggling
I was really drawn to what you had said
what do you mean struggle
why struggle
struggling to feel better I guess
struggling to feel better
struggling doesn't work
doesn't seem to be
surrendering
to resist
that means you're holding out against it
that would be my quick read
you can go through surgery
without anesthesia
so long as you don't resist
so long as you stay on the edge of the razor
the minute you get off the edge of the razor
agony
so
I would let go resisting it
if the bones turn to styrofoam
and collapse
well then you're a pile of stuff
laughter
in the meantime you do what you can
in the practical level
so you can keep riding out there
on the range as long as possible
you know what I'm saying
what else can you do
the ravages of age
that's what the Buddha said
sickness, old age and death
sickness, old age and poverty and death
is the karma
of reincarnating
as a linearity human
yeah
on the plus side it gives you another
shot at it
laughter
okay we got
that's enough
you got another shot at it
you're going down the tubes
go down the tubes
laughing and whistling
namaste from Ann Arbor, Michigan
my name's David
and I'm part of David Hawking's study group
that meets every Thursday
way better than going to church
it's growing and we wondered
if you had any advice for us
oh Ann Arbor yeah the university area
Fred Sauer started one group
and it got too big so now there's another
oh yeah yeah
well you do the same you do with any
information of value
you
if you can calibrate
do that way
you calibrate the energy of
the validity of a teaching
and give it
the attention that that calibration
deserves
if I get that something calibrates
at 700 or 800 or 900
I'm probably going to give it more attention and value
than something at 250 but
something at 250 may be
necessary to master before I can move
there so there's no point
in jumping the gun either
I say take the simplest
things and practice them until they
become who you are
and then the next thing will present itself
when you see the intrinsic beauty
of all that exists you see
the intrinsic quality of divinity
that shines forth of all things
the next move opens itself up
to you see
because you've asked
God haven't you
you've asked God
that's all you got to do
they say when you pray for
rain grab a hole
I'll make this quick
could you just say something about the power
of forgiveness
say something
I could say a couple
hours about it what would you like
in particular
I'm an addictions therapist
and in helping
addicts forgive themselves
yes
can you offer any help
in how to help them
forgive themselves for what being an addict
or the things they did as an addict
or
if you understand the quality of addiction
forgiveness comes about
just as a consequence of
of information
you see the brain cell will prefer
the substance
you can raise neurons
cerebral neurons in a petri dish
and gradually increase
the level of opium in the petri
let's say it was opium
eventually those neurons
will become dependent on the presence of that opium
and if you begin to withdraw
the opium from the culture media
the neurons will shrink up and die
so
the personal self
has gotten addicted
but so has the physiologic self
that to me is true addiction
what people call addiction
it's just bad habits a lot of it
now true addiction
you're physiologically addicted
and you stop the addiction
the person will go into grand malconvulsions
and die
so you're not dealing with just a fantasy
you're also dealing with reality
the proven way
is via the 12 step program
and forgiveness comes about
through inner honesty
you're taking the steps
doing the 3rd and the 4th and the 5th
and following that up with the 10th step
all error comes out of ignorance
the teenage boy who starts to drink
for the excitement
the high being part of it
being socially acceptable
because it's valued it's cool
your old fraternity does it
I had no idea he was playing with fire
he doesn't realize it until he's hooked
that's why I say don't play with the devil
because he's been at it
longer than you've been alive
and the built in temptations
are seductive
but it's too late by the time the person discovers that
so forgive them
for they know not what they do
if you said to somebody at 15
would you like to drink
and become a sick dependent alcoholic
and have grand malconvulsions
if you quit they'd all say no
then you have congenital
and ethnic
and cultural proclivity
the farther north
your ancestors come from the north pole
the greater your chance of addiction to alcohol
chances if you're
from Alaska
Eskimo tribes
Native Americans that live near the north pole
the likelihood of drinking
and not becoming addicted
is practically zero
on the other hand if your ancestors
come from closer to the equator
the Mediterranean sea
the likelihood of addiction is much less
you can be Italian
and drink wine every day of your life
so addiction
seems to be related to latitude
and longitude
whatever it is
North Pole-ism
I call it North Pole-ism
so North Pole-ism
so
if your grandparents
are of Irish extraction
you know right from the beginning
in Iceland
in Iceland I used to
treat a patient from Reykjavik
and he would fly over once a month
to see me from Iceland
the addiction there was 50%
50% of the population
is addicted to alcohol
so they have an endemic
genetic
cultural
so it seems to me
the government and the education system
should make you aware of that
that you are born to a certain
genetic strain
that these types of substances
are dangerous for you
thank you
you answered a question that I actually didn't ask
ok thank you
alright so
we give thanks to the Lord
for thy presence
for thy love
for thy blessing
in being here
each and one of you who is here
does thereby your presence bless me
and thereby do we
bless each other
and dedicate our lives
to God
to the pursuit of the divine truth
and we do that
all together
we have come in together
and we tend
like swooping in birds
coming in together
we are sort of a cultural unit
and what holds us together is sort of this alignment
and although
by the arm we got today
we are going to lose a few
they can sign up for other venues
but
the propensity of this group is to spread out
over time
over great eons of time
and spread the truth of God throughout
the whole world
Amen
ok wonderful