So
here
I'm
I'm going
I'm going to
I'm going to go
I'm going to go around
I'm going to go around and
I'm going to go around and say
I'm going to go around and say hello
I'm going to go around and say hello to
people.
>> I
>> I need
>> I need gay
>> I need gay worthy.
>> Hi.
I'm
I'm dressed
I'm dressed like
I'm dressed like a
I'm dressed like a dude
I'm dressed like a dude today,
I'm dressed like a dude today, huh?
Yeah.
>> I'm
>> I'm uh
>> I'm uh These
>> I'm uh These are
>> I'm uh These are my
>> I'm uh These are my dude
>> I'm uh These are my dude duds.
>> Cool
>> Cool dude
>> I'm uh These are my dude duds.
>> Cool dude duds.
>> Cool dude duds. You
>> I'm uh These are my dude duds.
>> Cool dude duds. You like
>> Cool dude duds. You like them?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
>> New
>> New jacket
>> Oh, yeah.
>> New jacket and
>> New jacket and everything.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> New jacket and everything. Hi.
Hello.
Hello. Hi.
Hello. Hi. How
Hello. Hi. How you?
Uhhuh.
Hi.
>> Ah,
>> Ah, there
Hi.
>> Ah, there we
>> Ah, there we are.
>> Hey.
Hi.
>> Nice
>> Nice to
>> Nice to meet
>> Nice to meet you.
>> Nice to meet you. Thank
>> Nice to meet you. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> You
>> You can
>> You can leave
>> You can leave the
>> You can leave the music
>> You can leave the music on.
>> You can leave the music on. It's
>> You can leave the music on. It's okay.
>> You
>> You can
>> You can leave the music on. It's okay.
>> You can leave
>> You can leave the
>> You can leave the music on. It's okay.
>> You can leave the music
>> You can leave the music on.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. How
>> Hi. How are
>> Hi. How are you?
>> We're
>> We're not
>> Hi. How are you?
>> We're not letting
>> We're not letting go.
>> Hey.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
God
God bless
God bless you.
>> God
>> God bless.
>> Yeah.
>> Michigan
>> Michigan friends
>> Yeah.
>> Michigan friends are
>> Michigan friends are here.
>> Michigan
>> Michigan friends
>> Michigan friends are
>> Michigan friends are here.
>> Michiganis,
>> Michiganis, huh?
>> Michigan friends are here.
>> Michiganis, huh? Michiganis,
>> Michiganis, huh? Michiganis, huh?
>> Michiganis
>> and
>> and Ianis.
>> Wisconsin.
>> Wisconsinis.
>> Colorado
>> Colorado over
>> Colorado over here.
>> Colorado over here. Colorado
>> Colorado over here. Colorado is
>> I
>> I was
>> Colorado over here. Colorado is
>> I was from
>> I was from Wisconsin.
>> Australia.
>> Yes.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, how
>> Yes.
>> Oh, how wonderful.
>> Australia.
>> I
>> I don't
>> Australia.
>> I don't know how
>> I don't know how those
>> Australia.
>> I don't know how those people
>> I don't know how those people survive.
They
They don't
They don't fall
They don't fall off
They don't fall off the
They don't fall off the planet.
They don't fall off the planet. You
know,
>> they're
>> they're upside
>> they're upside down.
>> they're upside down. What
>> they're upside down. What keeps
>> they're upside down. What keeps them
>> they're upside down. What keeps them on
the
the planet?
>> they're upside down. What keeps them on
the planet? I
the planet? I don't
>> they're upside down. What keeps them on
the planet? I don't know.
>> I
>> I think
>> I think we're
>> I think we're on
>> I think we're on top.
>> Hey.
Hey,
Hey, sweetheart.
Wow.
We'll
We'll start
We'll start from
We'll start from the
We'll start from the ending
We'll start from the ending as
We'll start from the ending as as
We'll start from the ending as as is
We'll start from the ending as as is our
custom.
Everybody
Everybody starts
Everybody starts from
Everybody starts from the
Everybody starts from the beginning.
Everybody starts from the beginning. And
how
how far
Everybody starts from the beginning. And
how far does
how far does it
Everybody starts from the beginning. And
how far does it get
how far does it get them?
You
You want
You want to
You want to go
You want to go from
You want to go from here
You want to go from here to
You want to go from here to there?
You want to go from here to there? Why
not
not just
You want to go from here to there? Why
not just go
not just go there?
So
So we
So we start
So we start from
So we start from there.
This
This is
So we start from there.
This is a
This is a subtlety.
It's
It's a
It's a contextualization.
And
And if
It's a contextualization.
And if you
And if you get
It's a contextualization.
And if you get it,
And if you get it, it'll
It's a contextualization.
And if you get it, it'll save
And if you get it, it'll save you
It's a contextualization.
And if you get it, it'll save you 500
lifetimes.
Everything
Everything is
lifetimes.
Everything is happening
Everything is happening of
lifetimes.
Everything is happening of its
Everything is happening of its own.
Everything
Everything is
Everything is spontaneously
Everything is spontaneously being
Everything is spontaneously being what
it
it is.
All
All what
All what appears
All what appears to
All what appears to be
All what appears to be consequences
All what appears to be consequences of
that
that are
All what appears to be consequences of
that are the
that are the consequence
All what appears to be consequences of
that are the consequence of
that are the consequence of that
All what appears to be consequences of
that are the consequence of that which
it
it is
it is not
it is not that
it is not that which
it is not that which it
it is not that which it does.
Uh
Uh all
it is not that which it does.
Uh all things
Uh all things are
it is not that which it does.
Uh all things are happening
spontaneously.
Nothing
Nothing is
spontaneously.
Nothing is being
Nothing is being caused
spontaneously.
Nothing is being caused by
Nothing is being caused by anything
else.
else. Everything
else. Everything is
else. Everything is only
else. Everything is only just
else. Everything is only just being
else. Everything is only just being what
it
it is.
As
As a
As a consequence
As a consequence of
As a consequence of that
As a consequence of that which
As a consequence of that which it
As a consequence of that which it is
everything
everything around
As a consequence of that which it is
everything around it
is
is correlated
as
as a
is correlated
as a consequence
as a consequence of
is correlated
as a consequence of the
as a consequence of the field.
The
The you
The you the
The you the person
The you the person that
The you the person that you
The you the person that you think
The you the person that you think you
are
are doesn't
The you the person that you think you
are doesn't cause
are doesn't cause anything.
Everything
Everything is
Everything is happening
Everything is happening spontaneously.
You
You say
Everything is happening spontaneously.
You say but
You say but what
Everything is happening spontaneously.
You say but what about
You say but what about when
Everything is happening spontaneously.
You say but what about when I'm
deliberate?
deliberate? You're
deliberate? You're spontaneously
deliberate
deliberate idiot.
What
What about
What about when
What about when I
What about when I make
What about when I make a
What about when I make a decision?
You're
You're spontaneously
What about when I make a decision?
You're spontaneously making
You're spontaneously making a
What about when I make a decision?
You're spontaneously making a decision
is
is the
is the consequence
is the consequence of
is the consequence of that
is the consequence of that which
is the consequence of that which you
are.
So
So everything
So everything radiates
So everything radiates forth.
So everything radiates forth. the
So everything radiates forth. the energy
of
of that
So everything radiates forth. the energy
of that which
of that which it
So everything radiates forth. the energy
of that which it is
which
which interacts
which interacts with
the
the presence
which interacts with
the presence and
the presence and the
which interacts with
the presence and the energy
the presence and the energy of
everything
everything else
everything else that
everything else that is.
So
So what
everything else that is.
So what you're
So what you're seeing
everything else that is.
So what you're seeing then
So what you're seeing then is
everything else that is.
So what you're seeing then is an
interaction
as
as a
interaction
as a consequence
as a consequence of
interaction
as a consequence of that
as a consequence of that which
everything
everything is.
The
The reason
everything is.
The reason of
The reason of behind
everything is.
The reason of behind all
The reason of behind all that
everything is.
The reason of behind all that is
The reason of behind all that is the
infinite
infinite field
infinite field of
infinite field of consciousness
infinite field of consciousness which
infinite field of consciousness which is
everywhere
everywhere present
infinite field of consciousness which is
everywhere present beyond
everywhere present beyond time
infinite field of consciousness which is
everywhere present beyond time and
location
which
which is
location
which is nonlinear
of
of infinite
of infinite power.
of
of such
of infinite power.
of such dimension
of such dimension as
of infinite power.
of such dimension as to
of such dimension as to be
of infinite power.
of such dimension as to be beyond
comprehension.
This
This lifetime
comprehension.
This lifetime was
This lifetime was unusual
from
from a
from a statistical
from a statistical viewpoint
and
and um
from a statistical viewpoint
and um rather
and um rather profound
from a statistical viewpoint
and um rather profound experiences
and um rather profound experiences began
extremely
extremely early
extremely early in
extremely early in life.
extremely early in life. First
extremely early in life. First one
extremely early in life. First one was
at
at age
extremely early in life. First one was
at age three
and
and then
and then later
and then later in
and then later in life
and then later in life in
and then later in life in teenage
uh
uh there
and then later in life in teenage
uh there was
uh there was a
and then later in life in teenage
uh there was a huge
uh there was a huge storm.
and then later in life in teenage
uh there was a huge storm. I
uh there was a huge storm. I was
and then later in life in teenage
uh there was a huge storm. I was out
uh there was a huge storm. I was out in
the
the country,
the country, Wisconsin,
you
you know,
the country, Wisconsin,
you know, like
you know, like zero
the country, Wisconsin,
you know, like zero blizzard,
you know, like zero blizzard, no
the country, Wisconsin,
you know, like zero blizzard, no lights
on.
on. There
on. There was
on. There was no
on. There was no electric
on. There was no electric on
on. There was no electric on the
on. There was no electric on the highway
and
and uh
on. There was no electric on the highway
and uh I
and uh I just
on. There was no electric on the highway
and uh I just wanted
and uh I just wanted to
on. There was no electric on the highway
and uh I just wanted to get
and uh I just wanted to get out
on. There was no electric on the highway
and uh I just wanted to get out of
and uh I just wanted to get out of the
wind.
wind. So
wind. So there
wind. So there was
wind. So there was a
wind. So there was a huge
wind. So there was a huge snowbank.
wind. So there was a huge snowbank. So
wind. So there was a huge snowbank. So I
just
just dug
wind. So there was a huge snowbank. So I
just dug a
just dug a little
wind. So there was a huge snowbank. So I
just dug a little place,
just dug a little place, you
wind. So there was a huge snowbank. So I
just dug a little place, you know,
just dug a little place, you know, just
to
to get
to get out
to get out of
to get out of the
to get out of the wind.
to get out of the wind. I
to get out of the wind. I wasn't
to get out of the wind. I wasn't near
death
death or
to get out of the wind. I wasn't near
death or anything.
death or anything. I
to get out of the wind. I wasn't near
death or anything. I was
death or anything. I was just,
to get out of the wind. I wasn't near
death or anything. I was just, you
death or anything. I was just, you know,
cold
cold as
cold as all
cold as all get
cold as all get out.
And
And I
cold as all get out.
And I just
And I just uh
cold as all get out.
And I just uh got
And I just uh got out
cold as all get out.
And I just uh got out of
And I just uh got out of the
cold as all get out.
And I just uh got out of the wind
and
and then
and then a
and then a phenomena,
an
an incredible
presence
presence of
presence of love
presence of love overtook
presence of love overtook everything.
All
All uh
presence of love overtook everything.
All uh personal
All uh personal self
presence of love overtook everything.
All uh personal self disappeared.
There's
There's only
There's only the
There's only the infinite
There's only the infinite presence
There's only the infinite presence of
love
love which
There's only the infinite presence of
love which is
love which is what
There's only the infinite presence of
love which is what you
love which is what you are
There's only the infinite presence of
love which is what you are and
love which is what you are and in
There's only the infinite presence of
love which is what you are and in that
condition
condition which
condition which lasted
condition which lasted outside
condition which lasted outside of
condition which lasted outside of time
was
the
the infinity
the infinity of
the infinity of foreverness
in
in the
the infinity of foreverness
in the realization
in the realization that
the infinity of foreverness
in the realization that that
in the realization that that which
the infinity of foreverness
in the realization that that which I
in the realization that that which I am
existed
existed before
existed before all
existed before all universes
existed before all universes and
existed before all universes and will
exist
exist after
existed before all universes and will
exist after all
exist after all universes
existed before all universes and will
exist after all universes have
disappeared.
Let's
Let's see
disappeared.
Let's see if
Let's see if that
disappeared.
Let's see if that is
Let's see if that is correct.
We
We have
We have permission
We have permission to
We have permission to ask
We have permission to ask that
We have permission to ask that word.
Resist.
Resist. That
We have permission to ask that word.
Resist. That is
Resist. That is absolute
We have permission to ask that word.
Resist. That is absolute truth.
Resist. That is absolute truth. Resist.
That's
That's the
That's the absolute
That's the absolute truth.
If
If that's
That's the absolute truth.
If that's the
If that's the absolute
That's the absolute truth.
If that's the absolute truth
If that's the absolute truth for
That's the absolute truth.
If that's the absolute truth for me,
then
then it
then it is
then it is for
then it is for you
then it is for you also.
Uh
Uh so
the
the presence
the presence then
the presence then wiped
the presence then wiped out
the presence then wiped out all
thinkingness,
thinkingness, all
the presence then wiped out all
thinkingness, all thought,
thinkingness, all thought, all
the presence then wiped out all
thinkingness, all thought, all mind,
a
a condition
a condition that
a condition that later
a condition that later recurred
and
and we
a condition that later recurred
and we necessitated
and we necessitated leaving
a condition that later recurred
and we necessitated leaving the
and we necessitated leaving the world
frankly.
And
And at
frankly.
And at that
And at that time
frankly.
And at that time Sedona
And at that time Sedona was
frankly.
And at that time Sedona was a
And at that time Sedona was a small
town,
town, 3,000
town, 3,000 people,
town, 3,000 people, no
town, 3,000 people, no stop
town, 3,000 people, no stop lightss
town, 3,000 people, no stop lightss and
no
no lights
town, 3,000 people, no stop lightss and
no lights in
no lights in town
town, 3,000 people, no stop lightss and
no lights in town after
no lights in town after dark.
There
There was
There was one
There was one restaurant
There was one restaurant in
There was one restaurant in town
There was one restaurant in town open
There was one restaurant in town open in
the
the winter
There was one restaurant in town open in
the winter closed
the winter closed at
There was one restaurant in town open in
the winter closed at 8.
So
uh
uh that
So
uh that condition
uh that condition then
So
uh that condition then prevailed
uh that condition then prevailed and
So
uh that condition then prevailed and it
was
was no
was no longer
was no longer possible
was no longer possible to
was no longer possible to function
was no longer possible to function in
the
the world
was no longer possible to function in
the world and
the world and uh
was no longer possible to function in
the world and uh to
the world and uh to walk
was no longer possible to function in
the world and uh to walk away
the world and uh to walk away from
was no longer possible to function in
the world and uh to walk away from a
rather
rather incredible
rather incredible lifestyle
rather incredible lifestyle and
rather incredible lifestyle and uh
rather incredible lifestyle and uh and
rather incredible lifestyle and uh and I
bought
bought a
rather incredible lifestyle and uh and I
bought a cat
bought a cat a
rather incredible lifestyle and uh and I
bought a cat a cot
bought a cat a cot in
rather incredible lifestyle and uh and I
bought a cat a cot in the
bought a cat a cot in the dime
rather incredible lifestyle and uh and I
bought a cat a cot in the dime store
and
and uh
and uh some
and uh some bidding
and uh some bidding and
and uh some bidding and um
the
the charity
and uh some bidding and um
the charity place
the charity place and
and uh some bidding and um
the charity place and some
the charity place and some silverware.
And
And in
And in the
And in the refrigerator,
And in the refrigerator, I
And in the refrigerator, I had
And in the refrigerator, I had a
And in the refrigerator, I had a piece
of
of cheese
And in the refrigerator, I had a piece
of cheese and
of cheese and a
And in the refrigerator, I had a piece
of cheese and a six-ack
of cheese and a six-ack of
And in the refrigerator, I had a piece
of cheese and a six-ack of Pepsi.
of cheese and a six-ack of Pepsi. And
what
what more
what more did
what more did you
what more did you need?
I
I lived
what more did you need?
I lived that
I lived that way
what more did you need?
I lived that way for
I lived that way for quite
what more did you need?
I lived that way for quite a
I lived that way for quite a while.
Occasionally,
Occasionally, there
Occasionally, there would
Occasionally, there would be
Occasionally, there would be a
celebration,
celebration, an
Occasionally, there would be a
celebration, an apple.
Tonight,
Tonight, we'll
Tonight, we'll have
Tonight, we'll have an
Tonight, we'll have an apple.
Great
Great excitement
Tonight, we'll have an apple.
Great excitement in
Great excitement in the
Tonight, we'll have an apple.
Great excitement in the monastery
Great excitement in the monastery there.
So,
So, it
So, it was
So, it was a
So, it was a monastery.
So, it was a monastery. Monastery
So, it was a monastery. Monastery for
one.
And
And I
And I can
And I can remember
And I can remember in
And I can remember in the
And I can remember in the monastery
And I can remember in the monastery uh
it
it was
And I can remember in the monastery uh
it was actually
it was actually built
And I can remember in the monastery uh
it was actually built somewhat
it was actually built somewhat like
And I can remember in the monastery uh
it was actually built somewhat like a
mon
mon monastery
mon monastery and
mon monastery and uh
mon monastery and uh and
mon monastery and uh and walked
mon monastery and uh and walked past
mon monastery and uh and walked past a
mirror
mirror and
mon monastery and uh and walked past a
mirror and I
mirror and I was
mon monastery and uh and walked past a
mirror and I was shocked
mirror and I was shocked to
mon monastery and uh and walked past a
mirror and I was shocked to see
mirror and I was shocked to see somebody
was
was in
was in the
was in the in
was in the in the
was in the in the building.
Those
Those are
was in the in the building.
Those are just
Those are just fun
was in the in the building.
Those are just fun things
Those are just fun things to
was in the in the building.
Those are just fun things to talk
Those are just fun things to talk about,
you
you know.
But
But um
in
in the
in the snowbank
in the snowbank was
in the snowbank was the
in the snowbank was the first
in the snowbank was the first at
in the snowbank was the first at age
three
three was
in the snowbank was the first at age
three was the
three was the experience
in the snowbank was the first at age
three was the experience of
three was the experience of the
in the snowbank was the first at age
three was the experience of the void.
You
You know
You know that's
You know that's where
You know that's where I
You know that's where I ended
You know that's where I ended up
You know that's where I ended up in
prior
prior lifetimes
You know that's where I ended up in
prior lifetimes at
prior lifetimes at the
You know that's where I ended up in
prior lifetimes at the void.
prior lifetimes at the void. The
You know that's where I ended up in
prior lifetimes at the void. The pathway
of
of negation
of negation will
of negation will take
of negation will take you
of negation will take you to
of negation will take you to the
of negation will take you to the void
and
and I
of negation will take you to the void
and I warn
and I warn about
of negation will take you to the void
and I warn about it
and I warn about it in
of negation will take you to the void
and I warn about it in the
and I warn about it in the books
of negation will take you to the void
and I warn about it in the books that
and I warn about it in the books that I
write.
write. The
write. The one
write. The one I'm
write. The one I'm completing
transcending
transcending levels
write. The one I'm completing
transcending levels of
transcending levels of consciousness
write. The one I'm completing
transcending levels of consciousness is
almost
almost edited
almost edited and
almost edited and devotional
almost edited and devotional on
almost edited and devotional on duality
the
the first
almost edited and devotional on duality
the first draft
the first draft is
almost edited and devotional on duality
the first draft is done
the first draft is done and
almost edited and devotional on duality
the first draft is done and in
the first draft is done and in both
almost edited and devotional on duality
the first draft is done and in both of
them
them I
them I point
them I point out
them I point out that
them I point out that a
them I point out that a calibration
level
level 850
them I point out that a calibration
level 850 if
level 850 if you
them I point out that a calibration
level 850 if you assiduously
level 850 if you assiduously follow
them I point out that a calibration
level 850 if you assiduously follow the
pathway
pathway of
pathway of negation
pathway of negation uh
pathway of negation uh you
pathway of negation uh you will
pathway of negation uh you will end
pathway of negation uh you will end up
at
at nothingness.
Nothingness
is
is not
Nothingness
is not the
is not the ultimate
Nothingness
is not the ultimate state
is not the ultimate state of
Nothingness
is not the ultimate state of the
is not the ultimate state of the Buddha
believers
believers to
believers to the
believers to the contrary.
believers to the contrary. It
believers to the contrary. It is
nothingness
nonlinear,
infinite
infinite and
nonlinear,
infinite and profound
and
and incredible.
Without
Without forewarning,
and incredible.
Without forewarning, without
Without forewarning, without prior
knowledge,
knowledge, one
knowledge, one would
knowledge, one would assume
knowledge, one would assume this
knowledge, one would assume this is
knowledge, one would assume this is the
great
great state
knowledge, one would assume this is the
great state of
great state of enlightenment
knowledge, one would assume this is the
great state of enlightenment itself.
And
And of
And of course,
And of course, many
And of course, many people
And of course, many people did
And of course, many people did go
And of course, many people did go as
And of course, many people did go as far
as
as 850
And of course, many people did go as far
as 850 and
as 850 and stop
And of course, many people did go as far
as 850 and stop there.
as 850 and stop there. And
And of course, many people did go as far
as 850 and stop there. And they
as 850 and stop there. And they probably
are
are nowhere.
They're
They're not
are nowhere.
They're not thinking,
They're not thinking, of
are nowhere.
They're not thinking, of course,
They're not thinking, of course, but
are nowhere.
They're not thinking, of course, but are
hung
hung up
hung up in
hung up in the
hung up in the void.
hung up in the void. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. If
hung up in the void. Yeah.
Yeah. If the
Yeah. If the void
hung up in the void. Yeah.
Yeah. If the void was
Yeah. If the void was real,
hung up in the void. Yeah.
Yeah. If the void was real, you
Yeah. If the void was real, you could
stay
stay there.
stay there. It's
stay there. It's not
stay there. It's not real.
stay there. It's not real. That's
stay there. It's not real. That's why
I'm
I'm alive
stay there. It's not real. That's why
I'm alive today.
Go
Go transcend
Go transcend that
Go transcend that error,
Go transcend that error, you
Go transcend that error, you know.
Go transcend that error, you know. Yeah.
So
the
the secret
the secret to
the secret to it
the secret to it was
the secret to it was the
the secret to it was the experience
the secret to it was the experience in
the
the snowbank
the secret to it was the experience in
the snowbank because
the snowbank because in
the secret to it was the experience in
the snowbank because in the
the snowbank because in the snowbank
there
there was
there was also
there was also nonlinear
there was also nonlinear nothingness,
there was also nonlinear nothingness, no
nothingness,
just
just an
just an infinite
just an infinite field
just an infinite field like
just an infinite field like the
just an infinite field like the radiance
of
of sun.
just an infinite field like the radiance
of sun. You
of sun. You might
just an infinite field like the radiance
of sun. You might say,
of sun. You might say, the
just an infinite field like the radiance
of sun. You might say, the radiance
of sun. You might say, the radiance of
the
the sun.
But
But one
the sun.
But one of
But one of the
the sun.
But one of the most
But one of the most impressive
the sun.
But one of the most impressive things
about
about this
about this quality
about this quality of
about this quality of love
about this quality of love was
about this quality of love was its
infinite
infinite power.
Its
Its infinite
Its infinite power.
Its infinite power. And
Its infinite power. And we
Its infinite power. And we talked
Its infinite power. And we talked about
the
the power
Its infinite power. And we talked about
the power of
the power of the
Its infinite power. And we talked about
the power of the infinite
the power of the infinite field
Its infinite power. And we talked about
the power of the infinite field of
consciousness.
Um
the
the quality
the quality of
the quality of love
the quality of love then
the quality of love then when
the quality of love then when when
the quality of love then when when you
reach
reach the
the quality of love then when when you
reach the ultimate
reach the ultimate state
the quality of love then when when you
reach the ultimate state the
reach the ultimate state the the
the quality of love then when when you
reach the ultimate state the the quality
of
of love
of love is
of love is profound.
of love is profound. It's
of love is profound. It's nothingness.
It's
It's nothingness.
of love is profound. It's nothingness.
It's nothingness. It's
It's nothingness. It's void
of love is profound. It's nothingness.
It's nothingness. It's void except
It's nothingness. It's void except for
the
the presence
the presence of
the presence of love
the presence of love which
the presence of love which is
overwhelming.
And
And the
And the quality
And the quality of
And the quality of that
And the quality of that love
And the quality of that love is
And the quality of that love is it's
infinitely
infinitely powerful,
exquisitely
exquisitely gentle.
exquisitely gentle. It
exquisitely gentle. It like
exquisitely gentle. It like melts
exquisitely gentle. It like melts you
with
with its
exquisitely gentle. It like melts you
with its exquisite
presence.
And
And its
presence.
And its power
And its power simultaneously
presence.
And its power simultaneously is
And its power simultaneously is infinite
and
and like
and like rock.
and like rock. Nobody
and like rock. Nobody knows
and like rock. Nobody knows that
and like rock. Nobody knows that except
somebody
somebody who's
and like rock. Nobody knows that except
somebody who's been
somebody who's been there.
and like rock. Nobody knows that except
somebody who's been there. That
somebody who's been there. That is
and like rock. Nobody knows that except
somebody who's been there. That is soft
and
and exquisite
and simultaneously
and simultaneously its
and exquisite
and simultaneously its power
and simultaneously its power is
and exquisite
and simultaneously its power is like
rock.
And
And what
rock.
And what do
And what do I
rock.
And what do I mean
And what do I mean by
rock.
And what do I mean by that?
And what do I mean by that? I
rock.
And what do I mean by that? I mean
And what do I mean by that? I mean that
it's
>> sorry
>> irresistible.
>> Is
>> Is that
>> irresistible.
>> Is that better?
>> How
>> How were
>> How were your
>> How were your last
>> How were your last moments
>> How were your last moments on
>> How were your last moments on this
planet?
planet? Okay.
You
You see,
You see, everything
You see, everything happens
You see, everything happens as
You see, everything happens as a
consequence
consequence of
You see, everything happens as a
consequence of that
consequence of that which
You see, everything happens as a
consequence of that which they
consequence of that which they are.
You see, everything happens as a
consequence of that which they are. As
consequence of that which they are. As a
consequence
consequence of
consequence of that
consequence of that which
consequence of that which she
consequence of that which she is.
consequence of that which she is. She
automatically
automatically does
consequence of that which she is. She
automatically does things.
automatically does things. As
consequence of that which she is. She
automatically does things. As a
consequence
consequence of
consequence of that
consequence of that which
consequence of that which I
consequence of that which I am,
I
I automatically
consequence of that which I am,
I automatically do
I automatically do things.
I
I have
I have no
I have no say
I have no say about
I have no say about it.
And
And neither
I have no say about it.
And neither does
And neither does she.
As
As a
As a consequence,
As a consequence, I
As a consequence, I can't
As a consequence, I can't make
As a consequence, I can't make her
As a consequence, I can't make her wrong
because
because she's
As a consequence, I can't make her wrong
because she's not
because she's not responsible
As a consequence, I can't make her wrong
because she's not responsible for
because she's not responsible for her
own
own behavior
own behavior either.
She's
She's just
own behavior either.
She's just being
She's just being who
own behavior either.
She's just being who she
She's just being who she is.
Wow.
Wow. Thank
Wow. Thank goodness.
I
I don't
Wow. Thank goodness.
I don't know.
I don't know. I
Wow. Thank goodness.
I don't know. I would
I don't know. I would would
Wow. Thank goodness.
I don't know. I would would have
I don't know. I would would have gotten
here
here today
here today otherwise
this
this way
here today otherwise
this way the
this way the door.
here today otherwise
this way the door. Oh,
this way the door. Oh, okay.
Yeah.
Yeah. Before
Yeah. Before I
Yeah. Before I lecture
Yeah. Before I lecture the
Yeah. Before I lecture the the
Yeah. Before I lecture the the state
resumes
resumes and
Yeah. Before I lecture the the state
resumes and so
resumes and so I've
Yeah. Before I lecture the the state
resumes and so I've had
resumes and so I've had to
Yeah. Before I lecture the the state
resumes and so I've had to learn
resumes and so I've had to learn how
Yeah. Before I lecture the the state
resumes and so I've had to learn how to
be
be in
be in the
be in the world
be in the world and
be in the world and same
be in the world and same time
be in the world and same time in
be in the world and same time in that
presence
presence simultaneously.
All
All things
All things are
All things are only
All things are only being
All things are only being that
All things are only being that which
they
they are.
They
They can't
They can't help
They can't help being
They can't help being what
They can't help being what they
They can't help being what they are
They can't help being what they are at
the
the moment
because
because as
because as a
because as a consequence
because as a consequence of
because as a consequence of that
because as a consequence of that which
they
they were,
because as a consequence of that which
they were, they
they were, they are
because as a consequence of that which
they were, they are now
they were, they are now that
because as a consequence of that which
they were, they are now that which
they were, they are now that which they
are
Americans,
Americans, the
are
Americans, the western
Americans, the western world
are
Americans, the western world doesn't
understand
understand karma.
understand karma. Unfortunately,
karma
karma is
understand karma. Unfortunately,
karma is the
karma is the totality,
understand karma. Unfortunately,
karma is the totality, complete
karma is the totality, complete totality
of
of everything
of everything that
of everything that preceded
of everything that preceded this
of everything that preceded this moment.
The
The last
of everything that preceded this moment.
The last moment
The last moment was
of everything that preceded this moment.
The last moment was part
The last moment was part of
of everything that preceded this moment.
The last moment was part of the
The last moment was part of the karma
of everything that preceded this moment.
The last moment was part of the karma of
this
this moment.
It's
It's transmitted
karmically
through
through genetic
karmically
through genetic inheritance.
It's
It's not
It's not an
It's not an accident.
It's not an accident. You
It's not an accident. You just
It's not an accident. You just happen
It's not an accident. You just happen to
get
get born
It's not an accident. You just happen to
get born in
get born in a
It's not an accident. You just happen to
get born in a certain
get born in a certain place
It's not an accident. You just happen to
get born in a certain place or
get born in a certain place or with
It's not an accident. You just happen to
get born in a certain place or with a
certain
disability
disability or
certain
disability or whatever.
disability or whatever. Huh?
And
And if
And if you
And if you research
And if you research it,
And if you research it, you'll
And if you research it, you'll find
everybody
everybody is
And if you research it, you'll find
everybody is what
everybody is what they
And if you research it, you'll find
everybody is what they are
everybody is what they are as
And if you research it, you'll find
everybody is what they are as a
consequence
consequence of
consequence of that
consequence of that which
consequence of that which they
consequence of that which they were.
They
They couldn't
consequence of that which they were.
They couldn't help
They couldn't help being
consequence of that which they were.
They couldn't help being what
They couldn't help being what they
consequence of that which they were.
They couldn't help being what they were
when
when they
when they were
when they were that.
when they were that. Nor
when they were that. Nor can
when they were that. Nor can they
when they were that. Nor can they help
being
being what
when they were that. Nor can they help
being what they
being what they are
when they were that. Nor can they help
being what they are now.
being what they are now. See
consequence.
consequence. There's
consequence. There's no
consequence. There's no point
consequence. There's no point in
vilifying
vilifying everybody
consequence. There's no point in
vilifying everybody because
vilifying everybody because they
consequence. There's no point in
vilifying everybody because they are
only
only being
only being what
only being what they
only being what they can
only being what they can be
only being what they can be at
only being what they can be at the
moment.
moment. You
only being what they can be at the
moment. You know,
yeah,
yeah, I
yeah, I always
yeah, I always say,
yeah, I always say, but
yeah, I always say, but hypothetically
they
they could
yeah, I always say, but hypothetically
they could be
they could be different.
Could
be
be more
Could
be more peanut
be more peanut butter
Could
be more peanut butter on
be more peanut butter on the
Could
be more peanut butter on the sandwich.
You
You know what
You know what I
You know what I mean?
All
All right.
You know what I mean?
All right. It's
All right. It's It's
You know what I mean?
All right. It's It's important
All right. It's It's important then
You know what I mean?
All right. It's It's important then for
forgiveness.
forgiveness. People
forgiveness. People try
forgiveness. People try to
forgiveness. People try to forgive.
forgiveness. People try to forgive. You
can't
can't really
forgiveness. People try to forgive. You
can't really forgive
can't really forgive somebody
forgiveness. People try to forgive. You
can't really forgive somebody you
can't really forgive somebody you still
see
see as
see as evil.
see as evil. You
see as evil. You know,
you
you can
see as evil. You know,
you can forgive
you can forgive them
see as evil. You know,
you can forgive them for
you can forgive them for being
see as evil. You know,
you can forgive them for being evil.
It's
It's okay
It's okay to
It's okay to be
It's okay to be evil.
However
However you
It's okay to be evil.
However you see
However you see him,
It's okay to be evil.
However you see him, it's
However you see him, it's okay
It's okay to be evil.
However you see him, it's okay to
However you see him, it's okay to see
him
him that
him that way.
him that way. Okay.
him that way. Okay. So,
him that way. Okay. So, you
him that way. Okay. So, you don't
him that way. Okay. So, you don't have
to
to make
him that way. Okay. So, you don't have
to make yourself
to make yourself wrong.
him that way. Okay. So, you don't have
to make yourself wrong. They
to make yourself wrong. They make
yourself
yourself wrong,
yourself wrong, you
yourself wrong, you get
yourself wrong, you get stuck
yourself wrong, you get stuck in
yourself wrong, you get stuck in it.
Therefore,
Therefore, however
yourself wrong, you get stuck in it.
Therefore, however you
Therefore, however you see
yourself wrong, you get stuck in it.
Therefore, however you see it
Therefore, however you see it is
yourself wrong, you get stuck in it.
Therefore, however you see it is however
you
you see
you see it
you see it because
you see it because you're
you see it because you're only
you see it because you're only being
what
what you
you see it because you're only being
what you can
what you can be
you see it because you're only being
what you can be at
what you can be at the
you see it because you're only being
what you can be at the moment,
what you can be at the moment, too.
you see it because you're only being
what you can be at the moment, too. So,
you're
you're only
you're only being
you're only being what
you're only being what they
you're only being what they can
you're only being what they can be.
you're only being what they can be. And
you're
you're only
you're only being what they can be. And
you're only being
you're only being what
you're only being what they can be. And
you're only being what you
you're only being what you can
you're only being what they can be. And
you're only being what you can be.
you're only being what you can be. As
you're only being what they can be. And
you're only being what you can be. As a
consequence
consequence of
consequence of that
consequence of that which
consequence of that which you
consequence of that which you become,
phenomena
phenomena are
consequence of that which you become,
phenomena are influenced
phenomena are influenced and
consequence of that which you become,
phenomena are influenced and radiated
out
for
for eternity.
out
for eternity. Right?
for eternity. Right? Eternity.
out
for eternity. Right? Eternity. What
for eternity. Right? Eternity. What you
do
do has
do has consequences
do has consequences for
do has consequences for eternity.
Indeed,
that
that which
that which you
that which you do
has
has consequences
that which you do
has consequences forever.
Whoa,
Whoa, man.
Whoa, man. That's
Whoa, man. That's scary,
Whoa, man. That's scary, isn't
Whoa, man. That's scary, isn't it?
Well,
Well, we
Whoa, man. That's scary, isn't it?
Well, we not
Well, we not we
Whoa, man. That's scary, isn't it?
Well, we not we notice
Well, we not we notice that
Whoa, man. That's scary, isn't it?
Well, we not we notice that the
Well, we not we notice that the infinite
field
field of
field of consciousness
field of consciousness records
field of consciousness records all
field of consciousness records all that
happens,
happens, all
field of consciousness records all that
happens, all this
happens, all this thought.
It
It It's
It It's all
It It's all knowing.
It It's all knowing. It's
It It's all knowing. It's omnipresent.
Omnipresent.
Omnipresent. It
It It's all knowing. It's omnipresent.
Omnipresent. It records
Omnipresent. It records everything.
Every
Every hair
Every hair on
Every hair on one's
Every hair on one's head
Every hair on one's head is
Every hair on one's head is literally
counted.
So,
So, as
So, as a
So, as a consequence,
So, as a consequence, you
So, as a consequence, you know,
So, as a consequence, you know, like
So, as a consequence, you know, like a
CD
CD or
So, as a consequence, you know, like a
CD or whatever
CD or whatever they
So, as a consequence, you know, like a
CD or whatever they call
CD or whatever they call those
So, as a consequence, you know, like a
CD or whatever they call those things
nowadays,
nowadays, you've
nowadays, you've inherited
nowadays, you've inherited this
nowadays, you've inherited this disc
when
when you
nowadays, you've inherited this disc
when you get
when you get here
and
and now
and now you
and now you push
and now you push the
and now you push the on
and now you push the on button
and now you push the on button and
and now you push the on button and this
this
this lifetime
and now you push the on button and this
this lifetime begins
this lifetime begins to
and now you push the on button and this
this lifetime begins to play.
this lifetime begins to play. Huh.
Today's
Today's um
Today's um topic
Today's um topic is
Today's um topic is called
Today's um topic is called alignment.
I
I never
Today's um topic is called alignment.
I never pay
I never pay attention
Today's um topic is called alignment.
I never pay attention to
I never pay attention to the
Today's um topic is called alignment.
I never pay attention to the names
I never pay attention to the names of
the
the lectures
the lectures but
the lectures but today
the lectures but today I
the lectures but today I noticed
I
I said
the lectures but today I noticed
I said what
I said what are
the lectures but today I noticed
I said what are we
I said what are we talking
the lectures but today I noticed
I said what are we talking about
I said what are we talking about today
it
it says
it says alignment.
it says alignment. Okay.
All right.
All right. So
it says alignment. Okay.
All right. So what
All right. So what we
it says alignment. Okay.
All right. So what we said
All right. So what we said then
it says alignment. Okay.
All right. So what we said then has
All right. So what we said then has to
do
do actually
do actually with
do actually with the
do actually with the field
do actually with the field of
do actually with the field of alignment.
Uh
Uh because
do actually with the field of alignment.
Uh because people
Uh because people interact
do actually with the field of alignment.
Uh because people interact with
Uh because people interact with each
other.
other. They're
other. They're involved
other. They're involved with
other. They're involved with each
other. They're involved with each other
but
but they're
other. They're involved with each other
but they're not
but they're not aligned
other. They're involved with each other
but they're not aligned with
but they're not aligned with each
other. They're involved with each other
but they're not aligned with each other.
So
So there's
So there's two
So there's two kinds
So there's two kinds of
So there's two kinds of alignment.
So there's two kinds of alignment. It's
what
what I
So there's two kinds of alignment. It's
what I call
what I call horizontal
So there's two kinds of alignment. It's
what I call horizontal and
what I call horizontal and vertical.
So there's two kinds of alignment. It's
what I call horizontal and vertical. All
right.
right. And
right. And here
right. And here we
right. And here we have
right. And here we have a
right. And here we have a whiteboard.
Happily,
I
I just
I just knew
I just knew it
I just knew it would
I just knew it would be
I just knew it would be there.
I just knew it would be there. And
I just knew it would be there. And here
it
it is.
I just knew it would be there. And here
it is. Wow.
So,
let's
let's say
here's
here's two
here's two people
and
they're
they're involved
they're involved with
they're involved with each
they're involved with each other.
They
They have
they're involved with each other.
They have a
They have a relationship
and
and you
and you see
and you see the
and you see the relationship
and you see the relationship is
and you see the relationship is more
and you see the relationship is more or
less
less horizontal.
This
This person's
This person's solar
This person's solar plexus
This person's solar plexus interlocking
with
with that
This person's solar plexus interlocking
with that person's
with that person's solar
This person's solar plexus interlocking
with that person's solar plexus.
with that person's solar plexus. So
they're
they're involved
they're involved with
they're involved with each
they're involved with each other.
they're involved with each other. What
people
people think
they're involved with each other. What
people think if
people think if you're
they're involved with each other. What
people think if you're involved
people think if you're involved now
you're
you're now
you're now you
you're now you got
you're now you got a
you're now you got a relationship.
You
You do.
you're now you got a relationship.
You do. Yeah.
You do. Yeah. Anyway,
so
so these
so these people,
so these people, you
so these people, you see,
so these people, you see, this
so these people, you see, this one's
always
always interacting
so these people, you see, this one's
always interacting with
always interacting with this
so these people, you see, this one's
always interacting with this one.
always interacting with this one. But
so these people, you see, this one's
always interacting with this one. But I
like
like it
like it this
like it this way.
like it this way. Yeah,
like it this way. Yeah, but
like it this way. Yeah, but I
like it this way. Yeah, but I like
like it this way. Yeah, but I like it
this
this way.
like it this way. Yeah, but I like it
this way. Well,
this way. Well, you
like it this way. Yeah, but I like it
this way. Well, you got
this way. Well, you got it
like it this way. Yeah, but I like it
this way. Well, you got it that
this way. Well, you got it that way
like it this way. Yeah, but I like it
this way. Well, you got it that way last
time.
time. No,
time. No, it's
time. No, it's my
time. No, it's my turn
time. No, it's my turn now.
time. No, it's my turn now. Oh,
time. No, it's my turn now. Oh, you're
always
always trying
time. No, it's my turn now. Oh, you're
always trying to
always trying to pressure.
time. No, it's my turn now. Oh, you're
always trying to pressure. You're
always trying to pressure. You're trying
to
to get
to get your
to get your way.
to get your way. Uh,
to get your way. Uh, etc.
to get your way. Uh, etc. So,
to get your way. Uh, etc. So, there's
to get your way. Uh, etc. So, there's a
horizontal
horizontal solar
to get your way. Uh, etc. So, there's a
horizontal solar plexus
horizontal solar plexus mutual
manipulation.
manipulation. See?
manipulation. See? And
manipulation. See? And control
manipulation. See? And control going
manipulation. See? And control going on.
Control
Control going
manipulation. See? And control going on.
Control going on.
They
They fight.
They fight. They
They fight. They make
They fight. They make up.
They fight. They make up. They
They fight. They make up. They cry.
They fight. They make up. They cry. It's
It's
It's horrible.
He
He goes
He goes and
He goes and gets
He goes and gets drunk.
He goes and gets drunk. She
He goes and gets drunk. She gets
He goes and gets drunk. She gets even.
He
He has
He goes and gets drunk. She gets even.
He has an
He has an affair.
He goes and gets drunk. She gets even.
He has an affair. She
He has an affair. She leaves
He goes and gets drunk. She gets even.
He has an affair. She leaves him.
He has an affair. She leaves him. He
cries.
cries. He
cries. He threatens
cries. He threatens suicide.
cries. He threatens suicide. She
cries. He threatens suicide. She goes
back.
back. He
cries. He threatens suicide. She goes
back. He beats
back. He beats her
cries. He threatens suicide. She goes
back. He beats her up.
back. He beats her up. You
cries. He threatens suicide. She goes
back. He beats her up. You know
back. He beats her up. You know what
cries. He threatens suicide. She goes
back. He beats her up. You know what I
mean?
Routine
Routine marriage.
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, alignment.
Alignment
Alignment is
All right. So, alignment.
Alignment is like
Alignment is like this.
All right. So, alignment.
Alignment is like this. Right?
They're
They're both
They're both going
They're both going in
They're both going in the
They're both going in the same
direction.
direction. They're
They're both going in the same
direction. They're both
direction. They're both aligned
They're both going in the same
direction. They're both aligned with
direction. They're both aligned with the
same
same goal.
same goal. They
same goal. They don't
same goal. They don't bump
same goal. They don't bump into
same goal. They don't bump into each
other
other because
same goal. They don't bump into each
other because they're
other because they're both
same goal. They don't bump into each
other because they're both aligned
other because they're both aligned with
each
each other.
each other. So
each other. So if
each other. So if the
each other. So if the other
each other. So if the other person's
happiness
happiness satisfaction
each other. So if the other person's
happiness satisfaction is
happiness satisfaction is what
each other. So if the other person's
happiness satisfaction is what you're
interested
interested in
interested in and
interested in and they're
interested in and they're interested
interested in and they're interested in
your
your happiness
interested in and they're interested in
your happiness and
your happiness and satisfaction,
interested in and they're interested in
your happiness and satisfaction, you
don't
don't have
don't have any
don't have any problem
because
because they're
don't have any problem
because they're aligned
because they're aligned with
don't have any problem
because they're aligned with the
because they're aligned with the goal
don't have any problem
because they're aligned with the goal of
the
the relationship
the relationship which
the relationship which is
the relationship which is mutual
happiness.
happiness. So
the relationship which is mutual
happiness. So if
happiness. So if your
the relationship which is mutual
happiness. So if your goal
happiness. So if your goal is
the relationship which is mutual
happiness. So if your goal is that
happiness. So if your goal is that the
person
person that
person that you're
person that you're with
person that you're with their
person that you're with their happiness,
it
it makes
person that you're with their happiness,
it makes you
it makes you happy
person that you're with their happiness,
it makes you happy to
it makes you happy to make
person that you're with their happiness,
it makes you happy to make them
it makes you happy to make them happy.
Now
Now you
Now you got
Now you got a
Now you got a golden
Now you got a golden relationship.
If
If my
Now you got a golden relationship.
If my happiness
If my happiness is
Now you got a golden relationship.
If my happiness is to
If my happiness is to make
Now you got a golden relationship.
If my happiness is to make somebody
happy
happy and
happy and their
happy and their happiness
happy and their happiness is,
happy and their happiness is, you
happy and their happiness is, you see
what
what I
happy and their happiness is, you see
what I mean?
what I mean? To
happy and their happiness is, you see
what I mean? To make
what I mean? To make me
happy and their happiness is, you see
what I mean? To make me happy.
So
So there
So there you
So there you have
So there you have alignment.
So there you have alignment. So
alignment
alignment then
So there you have alignment. So
alignment then is
alignment then is different
than
than involvement.
So
So you
than involvement.
So you see
So you see in
than involvement.
So you see in the
So you see in the above
than involvement.
So you see in the above person
So you see in the above person they're
always
always trying
always trying to
always trying to control
always trying to control each
always trying to control each other
force.
force. So
always trying to control each other
force. So they're
force. So they're using
always trying to control each other
force. So they're using force
force. So they're using force and
always trying to control each other
force. So they're using force and what's
the
the force
the force they
the force they use?
the force they use? Emotional
the force they use? Emotional force,
moral
moral blackmail.
Most
Most violence
Most violence that
Most violence that ends
Most violence that ends up
Most violence that ends up in
Most violence that ends up in death,
domestic
domestic batter,
Most violence that ends up in death,
domestic batter, etc.
domestic batter, etc. Starts
Most violence that ends up in death,
domestic batter, etc. Starts out
domestic batter, etc. Starts out as
Most violence that ends up in death,
domestic batter, etc. Starts out as you
forgot
forgot to
forgot to bring
forgot to bring pick
forgot to bring pick up
forgot to bring pick up the
forgot to bring pick up the bread
forgot to bring pick up the bread today.
That's
That's all
forgot to bring pick up the bread today.
That's all it
That's all it takes.
I
I did
I did not
I did not forget.
I did not forget. You
I did not forget. You did?
I did not forget. You did? Well,
I did not forget. You did? Well, you
forgot
forgot it
I did not forget. You did? Well, you
forgot it last
forgot it last time.
I did not forget. You did? Well, you
forgot it last time. You
forgot it last time. You forgot
I did not forget. You did? Well, you
forgot it last time. You forgot to
forgot it last time. You forgot to tell
me.
me. I
me. I left
me. I left the
me. I left the note
me. I left the note out.
me. I left the note out. Yeah,
me. I left the note out. Yeah, I
me. I left the note out. Yeah, I didn't
see
see the
me. I left the note out. Yeah, I didn't
see the note.
see the note. The
me. I left the note out. Yeah, I didn't
see the note. The hell
see the note. The hell do
me. I left the note out. Yeah, I didn't
see the note. The hell do you
see the note. The hell do you think
me. I left the note out. Yeah, I didn't
see the note. The hell do you think I
am?
am? Jesus
am? Jesus Christ
am? Jesus Christ here
am? Jesus Christ here or
am? Jesus Christ here or what?
You're
You're so
am? Jesus Christ here or what?
You're so stupid.
You're so stupid. I
am? Jesus Christ here or what?
You're so stupid. I can't
You're so stupid. I can't stand
am? Jesus Christ here or what?
You're so stupid. I can't stand your
dumb
dumb arguments
dumb arguments all
dumb arguments all the
dumb arguments all the time.
dumb arguments all the time. You're
always
always forgetting
dumb arguments all the time. You're
always forgetting stuff.
always forgetting stuff. If
dumb arguments all the time. You're
always forgetting stuff. If it
always forgetting stuff. If it wasn't
for
for me,
for me, you'd
for me, you'd be
for me, you'd be dead
for me, you'd be dead already.
for me, you'd be dead already. Yeah,
well,
well, if
for me, you'd be dead already. Yeah,
well, if it
well, if it wasn't
for me, you'd be dead already. Yeah,
well, if it wasn't for
well, if it wasn't for me,
for me, you'd be dead already. Yeah,
well, if it wasn't for me, you'd
well, if it wasn't for me, you'd still
be
be working
be working in
be working in the
be working in the coal
be working in the coal mines.
So
you
you listen
you listen to
you listen to this
you listen to this craziness,
you listen to this craziness, you
you listen to this craziness, you know,
you
you see
you listen to this craziness, you know,
you see it
you see it all
you listen to this craziness, you know,
you see it all the
you see it all the time
you listen to this craziness, you know,
you see it all the time on
you see it all the time on television.
They
They have
They have these
They have these movies,
They have these movies, Hollywood
They have these movies, Hollywood movies
they
they call
They have these movies, Hollywood movies
they call them,
they call them, and
They have these movies, Hollywood movies
they call them, and they're
they call them, and they're full
They have these movies, Hollywood movies
they call them, and they're full of
they call them, and they're full of all
this
this conflict
this conflict and
this conflict and and
this conflict and and you
this conflict and and you see
this conflict and and you see the
this conflict and and you see the people
interacting
interacting this
this conflict and and you see the people
interacting this way,
interacting this way, you
this conflict and and you see the people
interacting this way, you know,
interacting this way, you know, push
this conflict and and you see the people
interacting this way, you know, push and
pull
pull and
pull and push
pull and push and
pull and push and pull
pull and push and pull instead
pull and push and pull instead of
pull and push and pull instead of being
this
this way
pull and push and pull instead of being
this way where
this way where they're
pull and push and pull instead of being
this way where they're both
this way where they're both if
pull and push and pull instead of being
this way where they're both if you're
both
both trying
both trying to
both trying to make
both trying to make the
both trying to make the garden
both trying to make the garden grow,
then
then you're
both trying to make the garden grow,
then you're both
then you're both make
both trying to make the garden grow,
then you're both make trying
then you're both make trying to
both trying to make the garden grow,
then you're both make trying to make
then you're both make trying to make the
garden
garden grow.
garden grow. If
garden grow. If you're
garden grow. If you're trying
garden grow. If you're trying to
garden grow. If you're trying to make
garden grow. If you're trying to make a
better
better garden
garden grow. If you're trying to make a
better garden than
better garden than her
garden grow. If you're trying to make a
better garden than her garden,
better garden than her garden, then
garden grow. If you're trying to make a
better garden than her garden, then you
sneak
sneak over
sneak over at
sneak over at night
sneak over at night and
sneak over at night and tweak
sneak over at night and tweak some
sneak over at night and tweak some of
her
in
in order
in order to
in order to be
in order to be right.
So
So involvement
in order to be right.
So involvement then
So involvement then involves
in order to be right.
So involvement then involves being
So involvement then involves being right
and
and wrong.
and wrong. And
and wrong. And people
and wrong. And people would
and wrong. And people would rather
and wrong. And people would rather die
than
than be
and wrong. And people would rather die
than be wrong.
Millions
Millions of
Millions of people
Millions of people die
Millions of people die rather
Millions of people die rather than
Millions of people die rather than being
wrong.
wrong. In
Millions of people die rather than being
wrong. In my
wrong. In my lifetime
Millions of people die rather than being
wrong. In my lifetime watched
wrong. In my lifetime watched a
Millions of people die rather than being
wrong. In my lifetime watched a 100red
million
million or
million or maybe
million or maybe 200
million or maybe 200 million
million or maybe 200 million die
million or maybe 200 million die rather
than
than admit
million or maybe 200 million die rather
than admit you
than admit you were
million or maybe 200 million die rather
than admit you were wrong.
Yeah.
Not
Not realizing
Yeah.
Not realizing that
Not realizing that a
Yeah.
Not realizing that a leader
Not realizing that a leader is
Yeah.
Not realizing that a leader is not
Not realizing that a leader is not the
great
great leader
great leader but
great leader but a
great leader but a megalo
great leader but a megalo maniac.
The
The refusal
great leader but a megalo maniac.
The refusal to
The refusal to see
great leader but a megalo maniac.
The refusal to see that
The refusal to see that cost
great leader but a megalo maniac.
The refusal to see that cost you
The refusal to see that cost you 100
million
million people.
million people. 100
million people. 100 million
limmings
limmings going
million people. 100 million
limmings going over
limmings going over the
million people. 100 million
limmings going over the side
limmings going over the side saluting
million people. 100 million
limmings going over the side saluting as
they
they go
they go to
they go to the
they go to the great
they go to the great leader.
Great
Great leader.
they go to the great leader.
Great leader. And
Great leader. And over
they go to the great leader.
Great leader. And over they
Great leader. And over they go
they go to the great leader.
Great leader. And over they go by
Great leader. And over they go by the
millions.
millions. Millions.
millions. Millions. The
millions. Millions. The bombs
millions. Millions. The bombs go
millions. Millions. The bombs go off.
They
They blow
millions. Millions. The bombs go off.
They blow up
They blow up bus
millions. Millions. The bombs go off.
They blow up bus loads
They blow up bus loads of
millions. Millions. The bombs go off.
They blow up bus loads of children.
All
All the
All the fun
All the fun of
All the fun of being
All the fun of being right,
which
which is
All the fun of being right,
which is sort
which is sort of
All the fun of being right,
which is sort of an
which is sort of an addiction.
All the fun of being right,
which is sort of an addiction. So
which is sort of an addiction. So the
human
human mind
human mind is
human mind is addicted
human mind is addicted to
human mind is addicted to being
human mind is addicted to being right.
You
You can't
human mind is addicted to being right.
You can't really
You can't really be
human mind is addicted to being right.
You can't really be aligned
You can't really be aligned if
human mind is addicted to being right.
You can't really be aligned if you're
addicted
addicted to
addicted to being
addicted to being right.
How
How does
addicted to being right.
How does the
How does the ego
addicted to being right.
How does the ego get
How does the ego get such
addicted to being right.
How does the ego get such a
How does the ego get such a grasp?
addicted to being right.
How does the ego get such a grasp? The
ego
ego will
ego will takes
ego will takes takes
ego will takes takes people
ego will takes takes people to
ego will takes takes people to death
ego will takes takes people to death by
the
the hundreds
ego will takes takes people to death by
the hundreds of
the hundreds of millions.
ego will takes takes people to death by
the hundreds of millions. Do
the hundreds of millions. Do you
understand?
understand? And
understand? And they
understand? And they all
understand? And they all die
understand? And they all die because
understand? And they all die because of
the
the eagle.
understand? And they all die because of
the eagle. There
the eagle. There was
understand? And they all die because of
the eagle. There was no
the eagle. There was no other
understand? And they all die because of
the eagle. There was no other thing.
The
The bomb
The bomb is
The bomb is only
The bomb is only the
The bomb is only the mechanism.
The
The bullets
The bomb is only the mechanism.
The bullets are
The bullets are only
The bomb is only the mechanism.
The bullets are only the
The bullets are only the mechanism.
Starvation
Starvation and
Starvation and AIDS
Starvation and AIDS are
Starvation and AIDS are only
Starvation and AIDS are only the
mechanism.
That's
That's only
That's only the
That's only the mechanism.
That's only the mechanism. See,
That's only the mechanism. See, when
That's only the mechanism. See, when you
get
get beyond
That's only the mechanism. See, when you
get beyond causality,
get beyond causality, you
That's only the mechanism. See, when you
get beyond causality, you don't
get beyond causality, you don't see
That's only the mechanism. See, when you
get beyond causality, you don't see a
this
this causing
this causing it
this causing it that.
this causing it that. You
this causing it that. You know,
each
each thing
this causing it that. You know,
each thing is
each thing is pulling
this causing it that. You know,
each thing is pulling to
each thing is pulling to itself
this causing it that. You know,
each thing is pulling to itself from
that
that which
that which it
that which it is.
So
So you
that which it is.
So you see
So you see the
that which it is.
So you see the mechanism
So you see the mechanism involved
that which it is.
So you see the mechanism involved in
having
having to
having to be
having to be right
having to be right has
having to be right has to
having to be right has to do
having to be right has to do with
having to be right has to do with the
fact
fact the
having to be right has to do with the
fact the ego
fact the ego is
having to be right has to do with the
fact the ego is quite
fact the ego is quite addictive.
having to be right has to do with the
fact the ego is quite addictive. So
that's
that's really
that's really the
that's really the thrust
that's really the thrust of
that's really the thrust of what
that's really the thrust of what I
that's really the thrust of what I want
to
to talk
that's really the thrust of what I want
to talk about
to talk about today
is
is how
is how does
is how does it
is how does it get
is how does it get to
is how does it get to be
is how does it get to be so
is how does it get to be so tenacious?
How
How does
is how does it get to be so tenacious?
How does the
How does the ego
is how does it get to be so tenacious?
How does the ego get
How does the ego get such
is how does it get to be so tenacious?
How does the ego get such a
How does the ego get such a grip
is how does it get to be so tenacious?
How does the ego get such a grip on
How does the ego get such a grip on you
that
that you
that you can
that you can spend
that you can spend 50
that you can spend 50 or
that you can spend 50 or 100
that you can spend 50 or 100 lifetimes
intense
intense spiritual
that you can spend 50 or 100 lifetimes
intense spiritual work
intense spiritual work just
that you can spend 50 or 100 lifetimes
intense spiritual work just trying
intense spiritual work just trying to
transcend
transcend some
transcend some simple
transcend some simple desire?
transcend some simple desire? Mahatma
Gandhi
Gandhi at
transcend some simple desire? Mahatma
Gandhi at 76
Gandhi at 76 or
transcend some simple desire? Mahatma
Gandhi at 76 or something.
Gandhi at 76 or something. He's
transcend some simple desire? Mahatma
Gandhi at 76 or something. He's still
can't
can't overcome
can't overcome uh
can't overcome uh sexual
can't overcome uh sexual desire.
can't overcome uh sexual desire. He
can't overcome uh sexual desire. He was
still
still battling
can't overcome uh sexual desire. He was
still battling it.
still battling it. I
can't overcome uh sexual desire. He was
still battling it. I think
still battling it. I think when
can't overcome uh sexual desire. He was
still battling it. I think when he
still battling it. I think when he was
in
in his
in his 70s,
in his 70s, wasn't
in his 70s, wasn't he?
in his 70s, wasn't he? Uh
in his 70s, wasn't he? Uh just
in his 70s, wasn't he? Uh just one
in his 70s, wasn't he? Uh just one one
desire
desire can't
in his 70s, wasn't he? Uh just one one
desire can't seem
desire can't seem to
in his 70s, wasn't he? Uh just one one
desire can't seem to get
desire can't seem to get off
in his 70s, wasn't he? Uh just one one
desire can't seem to get off it.
desire can't seem to get off it. So
in his 70s, wasn't he? Uh just one one
desire can't seem to get off it. So the
reason
reason uh
reason uh we
reason uh we go
reason uh we go back
reason uh we go back into
reason uh we go back into the
reason uh we go back into the evolution
of
of consciousness
reason uh we go back into the evolution
of consciousness is
of consciousness is because
reason uh we go back into the evolution
of consciousness is because without
understanding
understanding it
understanding it you
understanding it you really
understanding it you really can't
transcend
transcend its
understanding it you really can't
transcend its grip
transcend its grip on
understanding it you really can't
transcend its grip on you.
Do
Do we
Do we have
Do we have uh
Do we have uh the
Do we have uh the slide
Do we have uh the slide uh
Do we have uh the slide uh that
Do we have uh the slide uh that goes
from
from bacteria
to
to people?
Uh
Uh the
to people?
Uh the evolution
Uh the evolution of
to people?
Uh the evolution of consciousness.
Uh the evolution of consciousness. Um
animal
animal kingdom
animal kingdom number
animal kingdom number nine.
animal kingdom number nine. Huh?
animal kingdom number nine. Huh? We
animal kingdom number nine. Huh? We got
number
number nine.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. You
>> Okay. You see
>> Okay. You see people
>> Okay. You see people think
>> Okay. You see people think this
>> Okay. You see people think this is
academic.
academic. It's
>> Okay. You see people think this is
academic. It's not
academic. It's not academic
>> Okay. You see people think this is
academic. It's not academic because
Once
Once you
Once you understand
Once you understand something,
Once you understand something, it
Once you understand something, it loses
its
its uh
Once you understand something, it loses
its uh hold
its uh hold on
Once you understand something, it loses
its uh hold on you.
its uh hold on you. You
Once you understand something, it loses
its uh hold on you. You can
its uh hold on you. You can see
Once you understand something, it loses
its uh hold on you. You can see how
its uh hold on you. You can see how this
planet
planet was
planet was a
planet was a whirling
planet was a whirling mass
planet was a whirling mass of
planet was a whirling mass of uh
planet was a whirling mass of uh gas
planet was a whirling mass of uh gas or
something
something and
planet was a whirling mass of uh gas or
something and then
something and then it
planet was a whirling mass of uh gas or
something and then it condensed
something and then it condensed the
planet was a whirling mass of uh gas or
something and then it condensed the hot
lava
lava which
lava which is
lava which is still
lava which is still around
and
and after
lava which is still around
and after eons
and after eons of
lava which is still around
and after eons of time
and after eons of time the
lava which is still around
and after eons of time the crust
and after eons of time the crust of
lava which is still around
and after eons of time the crust of the
earth
earth formed
earth formed and
earth formed and it
earth formed and it was
earth formed and it was s
earth formed and it was s suitable
earth formed and it was s suitable for
the
the emergence
earth formed and it was s suitable for
the emergence of
the emergence of life.
The
The interaction
The interaction of
The interaction of the
The interaction of the radiance
The interaction of the radiance of
divinity
with
with matter
is
is the
with matter
is the source
is the source of
with matter
is the source of life.
is the source of life. There
with matter
is the source of life. There is
is the source of life. There is no
with matter
is the source of life. There is no s
source
source of
source of life
source of life other
source of life other than
source of life other than divinity
because
because life
source of life other than divinity
because life is
because life is a
source of life other than divinity
because life is a consequence
because life is a consequence of
divinity.
divinity. It
divinity. It cannot
divinity. It cannot be
divinity. It cannot be destroyed.
We
We have
divinity. It cannot be destroyed.
We have permission
We have permission Lord.
divinity. It cannot be destroyed.
We have permission Lord. Life
We have permission Lord. Life is
incapable
incapable of
incapable of being
incapable of being destroyed.
incapable of being destroyed. Resist.
You
You see
incapable of being destroyed. Resist.
You see human
You see human humans
incapable of being destroyed. Resist.
You see human humans been
You see human humans been around
incapable of being destroyed. Resist.
You see human humans been around a
You see human humans been around a long
time.
time. They
time. They don't
time. They don't even
time. They don't even know
time. They don't even know that
time. They don't even know that they
know
know the
law
law of
law of survival
law of survival of
law of survival of energy
law of survival of energy and
law of survival of energy and matter.
They
They don't
law of survival of energy and matter.
They don't know
They don't know anything
law of survival of energy and matter.
They don't know anything about
They don't know anything about the
law of survival of energy and matter.
They don't know anything about the law
of
of survival
of survival of
of survival of life.
How
How can
of survival of life.
How can we
How can we be
of survival of life.
How can we be alive
How can we be alive this
of survival of life.
How can we be alive this long
How can we be alive this long and
of survival of life.
How can we be alive this long and not
even
even realize
even realize that
even realize that even
even realize that even a
even realize that even a moth
even realize that even a moth knows
even realize that even a moth knows it.
You
You swat
even realize that even a moth knows it.
You swat him
You swat him and
even realize that even a moth knows it.
You swat him and he
You swat him and he just
even realize that even a moth knows it.
You swat him and he just goes
You swat him and he just goes flying
even realize that even a moth knows it.
You swat him and he just goes flying in
his
his etheric
his etheric body,
his etheric body, comes
his etheric body, comes back
his etheric body, comes back in
his etheric body, comes back in another
physical
physical body,
his etheric body, comes back in another
physical body, doesn't
physical body, doesn't know
his etheric body, comes back in another
physical body, doesn't know this
difference.
Moth
Moth knows
difference.
Moth knows it.
Moth knows it. We
difference.
Moth knows it. We don't
Moth knows it. We don't know
difference.
Moth knows it. We don't know it.
Moth knows it. We don't know it. How
difference.
Moth knows it. We don't know it. How can
that
that be?
All right.
All right. So
that be?
All right. So millions
All right. So millions and
that be?
All right. So millions and millions
All right. So millions and millions of
eons
eons ago
eons ago life
eons ago life emerged
eons ago life emerged then
eons ago life emerged then and
eons ago life emerged then and so
eons ago life emerged then and so we
eons ago life emerged then and so we see
from
from this
eons ago life emerged then and so we see
from this chart
from this chart the
eons ago life emerged then and so we see
from this chart the first
from this chart the first cons
eons ago life emerged then and so we see
from this chart the first cons first
conscious
conscious life
conscious life was
conscious life was bacteria
conscious life was bacteria calibrates
at
at one
prior
prior to
prior to that
prior to that it
prior to that it had
prior to that it had no
prior to that it had no consciousness.
It
It was
prior to that it had no consciousness.
It was but
It was but it
prior to that it had no consciousness.
It was but it you
It was but it you know
prior to that it had no consciousness.
It was but it you know now
It was but it you know now what's
prior to that it had no consciousness.
It was but it you know now what's the
what's
what's what
what's what does
what's what does life
what's what does life need
what's what does life need to
what's what does life need to survive
what's what does life need to survive on
a
a foreign
what's what does life need to survive on
a foreign planet?
a foreign planet? Let's
what's what does life need to survive on
a foreign planet? Let's say
a foreign planet? Let's say we
what's what does life need to survive on
a foreign planet? Let's say we were
going
going to
going to colonize
going to colonize Mars
going to colonize Mars or
going to colonize Mars or something.
going to colonize Mars or something. uh
your
your problem
going to colonize Mars or something. uh
your problem would
your problem would be
going to colonize Mars or something. uh
your problem would be survival,
your problem would be survival, wouldn't
it?
it? So
it? So you
it? So you have
it? So you have just
it? So you have just one
it? So you have just one orientation
it? So you have just one orientation and
one
one drive
it? So you have just one orientation and
one drive and
one drive and that's
it? So you have just one orientation and
one drive and that's survival.
one drive and that's survival. Survival
has
has to
has to do
has to do with
has to do with learning
has to do with learning how
has to do with learning how to
has to do with learning how to get.
Therefore,
Therefore, the
has to do with learning how to get.
Therefore, the core
Therefore, the core of
has to do with learning how to get.
Therefore, the core of the
Therefore, the core of the ego,
has to do with learning how to get.
Therefore, the core of the ego, the
basis,
basis, the
basis, the illusion
basis, the illusion of
basis, the illusion of the
basis, the illusion of the ego
basis, the illusion of the ego is
basis, the illusion of the ego is that
life
life is
basis, the illusion of the ego is that
life is dependent
life is dependent on
basis, the illusion of the ego is that
life is dependent on getting.
life is dependent on getting. Getting
means
means controlling
means controlling it
means controlling it too,
means controlling it too, making
means controlling it too, making it
means controlling it too, making it hold
still.
still. Yeah,
that's
that's what
that's what the
that's what the tiger
that's what the tiger has
that's what the tiger has to
that's what the tiger has to do
that's what the tiger has to do with
that's what the tiger has to do with the
rabbit.
rabbit. He
that's what the tiger has to do with the
rabbit. He doesn't
rabbit. He doesn't kill
that's what the tiger has to do with the
rabbit. He doesn't kill a
rabbit. He doesn't kill a rabbit.
that's what the tiger has to do with the
rabbit. He doesn't kill a rabbit. He
rabbit. He doesn't kill a rabbit. He has
to
to hold
to hold the
to hold the bloody
to hold the bloody thing
to hold the bloody thing still
to hold the bloody thing still because
you
you can't
to hold the bloody thing still because
you can't eat
you can't eat it
to hold the bloody thing still because
you can't eat it while
you can't eat it while it's
to hold the bloody thing still because
you can't eat it while it's running
you can't eat it while it's running all
over
over the
over the place.
We've
We've gotten
over the place.
We've gotten over
We've gotten over and
over the place.
We've gotten over and over.
So
So the
So the core
So the core alignment,
So the core alignment, we're
So the core alignment, we're talking
about
about alignment.
So the core alignment, we're talking
about alignment. The
about alignment. The alignment
So the core alignment, we're talking
about alignment. The alignment of
about alignment. The alignment of the
ego
ego is
ego is survival.
ego is survival. It's
ego is survival. It's very
ego is survival. It's very very
primitive.
primitive. It
ego is survival. It's very very
primitive. It goes
primitive. It goes back
ego is survival. It's very very
primitive. It goes back for
primitive. It goes back for eons.
And
And because
And because it's
And because it's been
And because it's been that
And because it's been that way
And because it's been that way for
And because it's been that way for eons,
it's
it's difficult
And because it's been that way for eons,
it's difficult to
it's difficult to overcome.
It
It presents
It presents its
It presents its hold
It presents its hold on
It presents its hold on us
It presents its hold on us as
It presents its hold on us as desire
It presents its hold on us as desire and
wantingness
wantingness and
It presents its hold on us as desire and
wantingness and cravingness
have
have to
have to have.
Why
Why do
have to have.
Why do people
Why do people get
have to have.
Why do people get so
Why do people get so frantic
have to have.
Why do people get so frantic about
Why do people get so frantic about it?
People
People will
People will do
People will do anything
People will do anything to
People will do anything to get
People will do anything to get like
People will do anything to get like an
extra
extra million
People will do anything to get like an
extra million dollars
extra million dollars or
People will do anything to get like an
extra million dollars or something,
extra million dollars or something, you
know,
know, $100
know, $100 or
know, $100 or whatever.
know, $100 or whatever. They'll
know, $100 or whatever. They'll kill
each
each other
know, $100 or whatever. They'll kill
each other for
what
what they
what they want.
what they want. Kill
what they want. Kill a
what they want. Kill a rival.
Last
Last night
what they want. Kill a rival.
Last night we
Last night we were
what they want. Kill a rival.
Last night we were walking
Last night we were walking watching
what they want. Kill a rival.
Last night we were walking watching the
chimpanzees
chimpanzees on
chimpanzees on History
chimpanzees on History Channel
chimpanzees on History Channel or
chimpanzees on History Channel or Nature
Channel.
Channel. And
chimpanzees on History Channel or Nature
Channel. And the
Channel. And the chimpanzee
chimpanzees on History Channel or Nature
Channel. And the chimpanzee is
Channel. And the chimpanzee is just
chimpanzees on History Channel or Nature
Channel. And the chimpanzee is just like
people
people except
people except they're
people except they're more
people except they're more hairy.
They're
They're busy
people except they're more hairy.
They're busy raiding
They're busy raiding each
people except they're more hairy.
They're busy raiding each other
They're busy raiding each other and
rival
rival tribes
rival tribes and
rival tribes and and
rival tribes and and they
rival tribes and and they found
rival tribes and and they found a
rival tribes and and they found a lone
male
male by
rival tribes and and they found a lone
male by by
male by by himself.
rival tribes and and they found a lone
male by by himself. So
male by by himself. So the
rival tribes and and they found a lone
male by by himself. So the these
male by by himself. So the these males
from
from this
from this tribe
from this tribe first
from this tribe first beat
from this tribe first beat him
from this tribe first beat him up
from this tribe first beat him up and
then
then killed
from this tribe first beat him up and
then killed them
then killed them and
from this tribe first beat him up and
then killed them and then
then killed them and then uh
from this tribe first beat him up and
then killed them and then uh chopped
them
them up
them up and
them up and tore
them up and tore them
them up and tore them pieces.
them up and tore them pieces. So
uh
uh it's
them up and tore them pieces. So
uh it's not
uh it's not exactly
them up and tore them pieces. So
uh it's not exactly a
uh it's not exactly a correlary
them up and tore them pieces. So
uh it's not exactly a correlary to
uh it's not exactly a correlary to human
behavior.
behavior. It
behavior. It is
behavior. It is human
behavior. It is human behavior.
Has
Has men
behavior. It is human behavior.
Has men evolve
Has men evolve far
behavior. It is human behavior.
Has men evolve far from
Has men evolve far from the
behavior. It is human behavior.
Has men evolve far from the chimpanzeee?
No.
Still
Still run
No.
Still run by
Still run by the
No.
Still run by the same
Still run by the same drive.
No.
Still run by the same drive. Threatened
by
by other
by other males,
by other males, hostile,
by other males, hostile, territorial,
willing
willing to
by other males, hostile, territorial,
willing to kill,
willing to kill, willing
by other males, hostile, territorial,
willing to kill, willing to
willing to kill, willing to murder,
and
and even
and even beyond
and even beyond murder.
and even beyond murder. Willing
and even beyond murder. Willing to
mutilate
mutilate the
and even beyond murder. Willing to
mutilate the dead
mutilate the dead body.
and even beyond murder. Willing to
mutilate the dead body. You
mutilate the dead body. You know,
characteristic
characteristic of
characteristic of other
characteristic of other cultures,
we
we see
characteristic of other cultures,
we see the
we see the tenacity
characteristic of other cultures,
we see the tenacity then
we see the tenacity then with
characteristic of other cultures,
we see the tenacity then with which
we see the tenacity then with which the
ego's
ego's holds
ego's holds on
ego's holds on to
ego's holds on to things
ego's holds on to things because
ego's holds on to things because it
ego's holds on to things because it gets
pleasure.
Whoa.
Whoa. So
Whoa. So there's
Whoa. So there's two
Whoa. So there's two kinds
Whoa. So there's two kinds of
Whoa. So there's two kinds of energy.
We're
We're artificially
Whoa. So there's two kinds of energy.
We're artificially artificially
semantically
semantically there's
semantically there's two
semantically there's two kinds
semantically there's two kinds of
energy.
energy. You
semantically there's two kinds of
energy. You might
energy. You might say
semantically there's two kinds of
energy. You might say spiritual
energy. You might say spiritual energy
and
and primitive
and primitive life
and primitive life energy.
and primitive life energy. They're
really
really not
and primitive life energy. They're
really not two
really not two two
and primitive life energy. They're
really not two two different
really not two two different energies
but
but up
but up to
but up to consciousness
but up to consciousness level
but up to consciousness level 200
but up to consciousness level 200 we
call
call it
but up to consciousness level 200 we
call it animal
call it animal and
but up to consciousness level 200 we
call it animal and from
call it animal and from 200
but up to consciousness level 200 we
call it animal and from 200 and
call it animal and from 200 and up
but up to consciousness level 200 we
call it animal and from 200 and up it's
uh
uh more
uh more human.
So
So the
uh more human.
So the drive
So the drive then
uh more human.
So the drive then is
So the drive then is to
uh more human.
So the drive then is to get
once
once the
once the mind
once the mind thinks
once the mind thinks it
once the mind thinks it needs
once the mind thinks it needs something
or
or gets
once the mind thinks it needs something
or gets it
or gets it or
once the mind thinks it needs something
or gets it or wants
or gets it or wants it.
once the mind thinks it needs something
or gets it or wants it. It
or gets it or wants it. It starts
once the mind thinks it needs something
or gets it or wants it. It starts with
uh
uh anticipation
uh anticipation and
uh anticipation and imagining
uh anticipation and imagining it.
uh anticipation and imagining it. It
then
then builds
uh anticipation and imagining it. It
then builds up
then builds up an
uh anticipation and imagining it. It
then builds up an appetite
then builds up an appetite for
something.
something. And
something. And then
something. And then comes
something. And then comes the
something. And then comes the desire.
Then
Then comes
something. And then comes the desire.
Then comes the
Then comes the need.
something. And then comes the desire.
Then comes the need. Then
Then comes the need. Then comes
something. And then comes the desire.
Then comes the need. Then comes the
craving,
craving, the
craving, the have
craving, the have to
craving, the have to have.
craving, the have to have. And
craving, the have to have. And God
craving, the have to have. And God help
anybody
anybody who
craving, the have to have. And God help
anybody who gets
anybody who gets in
craving, the have to have. And God help
anybody who gets in the
anybody who gets in the way.
It's
It's so
It's so voracious.
It's so voracious. It
It's so voracious. It will
It's so voracious. It will kill
It's so voracious. It will kill other
people
people to
It's so voracious. It will kill other
people to get
people to get what
It's so voracious. It will kill other
people to get what it
people to get what it wants.
It's so voracious. It will kill other
people to get what it wants. It
people to get what it wants. It will
cheat,
cheat, lie.
It'll
It'll get
cheat, lie.
It'll get up
It'll get up there
cheat, lie.
It'll get up there and
It'll get up there and make
cheat, lie.
It'll get up there and make absolute
false
false statements
false statements and
false statements and swear
false statements and swear that
false statements and swear that they're
true.
true. It's
false statements and swear that they're
true. It's staggering
true. It's staggering what
false statements and swear that they're
true. It's staggering what the
true. It's staggering what the human
mind
mind will
mind will do
mind will do in
mind will do in order
mind will do in order to
mind will do in order to win.
Why
Why does
mind will do in order to win.
Why does it
Why does it have
mind will do in order to win.
Why does it have such
Why does it have such a
mind will do in order to win.
Why does it have such a tremendous
power?
power? Because
power? Because the
power? Because the ego
power? Because the ego gets
power? Because the ego gets juice
power? Because the ego gets juice out
power? Because the ego gets juice out of
its
its positions.
It
It loves
It loves suffering.
It loves suffering. It
It loves suffering. It loves
It loves suffering. It loves injustice.
It
It loves
It loves suffering. It loves injustice.
It loves hate.
People
People scream
People scream with
People scream with excitement
in
in frenzies
People scream with excitement
in frenzies of
in frenzies of hatred.
They
They have
They have whole
They have whole parades.
They have whole parades. They
They have whole parades. They love
grief.
grief. They
They have whole parades. They love
grief. They love
grief. They love mourning.
They have whole parades. They love
grief. They love mourning. They
grief. They love mourning. They love
sadness,
sadness, sickness,
sadness, sickness, suffering,
sadness, sickness, suffering, and
some
some of
sadness, sickness, suffering, and
some of you
some of you don't
sadness, sickness, suffering, and
some of you don't even
some of you don't even know
sadness, sickness, suffering, and
some of you don't even know died.
some of you don't even know died. And
there's
there's whole
there's whole up
there's whole up and
there's whole up and down
there's whole up and down the
there's whole up and down the street.
There's
There's trades
there's whole up and down the street.
There's trades and
There's trades and trades
there's whole up and down the street.
There's trades and trades of
There's trades and trades of people
there's whole up and down the street.
There's trades and trades of people all
mourning
mourning and
mourning and crying.
mourning and crying. They
mourning and crying. They don't
mourning and crying. They don't even
know
know the
mourning and crying. They don't even
know the guy.
He's
He's the
He's the great
He's the great leader
He's the great leader or
He's the great leader or something.
He's the great leader or something. So,
they're
they're crying
He's the great leader or something. So,
they're crying about
they're crying about the
He's the great leader or something. So,
they're crying about the pope.
they're crying about the pope. I
He's the great leader or something. So,
they're crying about the pope. I said,
"Are
"Are you
"Are you Catholic?"
"Are you Catholic?" He
"Are you Catholic?" He says,
"Are you Catholic?" He says, "No,
why
why are
"Are you Catholic?" He says, "No,
why are you
why are you crying?"
"Are you Catholic?" He says, "No,
why are you crying?" Cuz
why are you crying?" Cuz everybody's
crying.
crying. So
crying. So you
crying. So you get
crying. So you get mass
crying. So you get mass hysteria.
Everybody
Everybody starts
crying. So you get mass hysteria.
Everybody starts crying.
Everybody starts crying. Everybody
weeps.
weeps. Everybody
weeps. Everybody mourns.
weeps. Everybody mourns. And
weeps. Everybody mourns. And the
weeps. Everybody mourns. And the ego
loves
loves it.
weeps. Everybody mourns. And the ego
loves it. The
loves it. The ego
weeps. Everybody mourns. And the ego
loves it. The ego loves
loves it. The ego loves suffering,
weeps. Everybody mourns. And the ego
loves it. The ego loves suffering, loves
loss,
loves
loves hatred,
loves all
loves all these
loves all these things,
loves all these things, loves
loves all these things, loves greed.
So
So the
loves all these things, loves greed.
So the energy
So the energy behind
loves all these things, loves greed.
So the energy behind the
So the energy behind the ego
loves all these things, loves greed.
So the energy behind the ego then
So the energy behind the ego then is
based
based on
based on primitive
based on primitive survival.
Because
Because the
based on primitive survival.
Because the ego
Because the ego doesn't
based on primitive survival.
Because the ego doesn't get
Because the ego doesn't get fed
spiritual
spiritual energy.
spiritual energy. Spiritual
spiritual energy. Spiritual energy
doesn't
doesn't start
spiritual energy. Spiritual energy
doesn't start till
doesn't start till consciousness
spiritual energy. Spiritual energy
doesn't start till consciousness level
200.
If
If you're
200.
If you're under
If you're under 200,
200.
If you're under 200, then
you're
you're stuck
you're stuck with
you're stuck with only
you're stuck with only one
you're stuck with only one fuel.
In
In order
you're stuck with only one fuel.
In order to
In order to survive,
you're stuck with only one fuel.
In order to survive, you
In order to survive, you got
you're stuck with only one fuel.
In order to survive, you got to
In order to survive, you got to feed
this
this ego
this ego constantly.
So
So it
this ego constantly.
So it goes
So it goes from
this ego constantly.
So it goes from one
So it goes from one craving
this ego constantly.
So it goes from one craving to
So it goes from one craving to the
this ego constantly.
So it goes from one craving to the next.
You
You fulfill
You fulfill this
You fulfill this craving,
You fulfill this craving, then
You fulfill this craving, then this
craving.
craving. Wantingness
You fulfill this craving, then this
craving. Wantingness is
craving. Wantingness is where
You fulfill this craving, then this
craving. Wantingness is where it
craving. Wantingness is where it lives.
You
You can't
You can't satisfy
You can't satisfy them.
You can't satisfy them. You
You can't satisfy them. You can't
satisfy
satisfy wants.
You can't satisfy them. You can't
satisfy wants. Uh
satisfy wants. Uh because
You can't satisfy them. You can't
satisfy wants. Uh because they
satisfy wants. Uh because they will
You can't satisfy them. You can't
satisfy wants. Uh because they will only
create
create a
create a new
create a new want.
create a new want. It's
create a new want. It's an
create a new want. It's an endless
create a new want. It's an endless the
more
more you
create a new want. It's an endless the
more you want,
more you want, the
create a new want. It's an endless the
more you want, the more
more you want, the more you
create a new want. It's an endless the
more you want, the more you want.
more you want, the more you want. A
create a new want. It's an endless the
more you want, the more you want. A need
is
is something
is something different.
is something different. A
is something different. A need
is something different. A need is
is something different. A need is only
is something different. A need is only a
decision.
Like
Like you
Like you need
Like you need a
Like you need a new
Like you need a new watch
Like you need a new watch cuz
Like you need a new watch cuz your
Like you need a new watch cuz your one's
broken
broken down.
Like you need a new watch cuz your one's
broken down. That's
broken down. That's different
Like you need a new watch cuz your one's
broken down. That's different than
broken down. That's different than a
cravingness
cravingness that
cravingness that you
cravingness that you have
cravingness that you have to
cravingness that you have to have
cravingness that you have to have a
Rolex
Rolex or
cravingness that you have to have a
Rolex or you
Rolex or you can't
cravingness that you have to have a
Rolex or you can't go
Rolex or you can't go to
cravingness that you have to have a
Rolex or you can't go to the
Rolex or you can't go to the party.
What
What do
What do people
What do people do
What do people do at
What do people do at parties?
What do people do at parties? Run
What do people do at parties? Run around
looking
looking at
What do people do at parties? Run around
looking at each
looking at each other's
What do people do at parties? Run around
looking at each other's wristwatch.
looking at each other's wristwatch. I
never
never could
never could figure
never could figure it
never could figure it out.
never could figure it out. What
never could figure it out. What what
kind
kind of
never could figure it out. What what
kind of a
kind of a wristwatch
never could figure it out. What what
kind of a wristwatch have
kind of a wristwatch have you
never could figure it out. What what
kind of a wristwatch have you got?
kind of a wristwatch have you got? You
know,
know, do
know, do they
know, do they run
know, do they run around
know, do they run around looking
know, do they run around looking at
know, do they run around looking at the
in
in the
know, do they run around looking at the
in the garments
in the garments where
know, do they run around looking at the
in the garments where they
in the garments where they were
know, do they run around looking at the
in the garments where they were made
in the garments where they were made or
something?
something? How
something? How do
something? How do they
something? How do they live?
something? How do they live? I
something? How do they live? I don't
understand.
Anyway,
Anyway, it's
Anyway, it's a
Anyway, it's a bizarre
Anyway, it's a bizarre world.
Mhm.
Mhm. So,
Anyway, it's a bizarre world.
Mhm. So, it's
Mhm. So, it's based
Anyway, it's a bizarre world.
Mhm. So, it's based on
Mhm. So, it's based on gain.
Anyway, it's a bizarre world.
Mhm. So, it's based on gain. All right.
So,
So, the
So, the core
So, the core of
So, the core of the
So, the core of the ego
So, the core of the ego is
So, the core of the ego is gain.
So, the core of the ego is gain. And
So, the core of the ego is gain. And the
gain
gain it
So, the core of the ego is gain. And the
gain it gets
gain it gets is
So, the core of the ego is gain. And the
gain it gets is the
gain it gets is the juice,
So, the core of the ego is gain. And the
gain it gets is the juice, the
pleasurable
pleasurable juice,
pleasurable juice, the
pleasurable juice, the energy
pleasurable juice, the energy then
pleasurable juice, the energy then of
pleasurable juice, the energy then of of
the
the ego
pleasurable juice, the energy then of of
the ego itself,
the ego itself, which
pleasurable juice, the energy then of of
the ego itself, which is
the ego itself, which is an
pleasurable juice, the energy then of of
the ego itself, which is an animal
energy.
energy. Last
energy. Last night
energy. Last night I'm
energy. Last night I'm watching
energy. Last night I'm watching the
chimpanzees,
chimpanzees, their
energy. Last night I'm watching the
chimpanzees, their faces
chimpanzees, their faces covered
energy. Last night I'm watching the
chimpanzees, their faces covered with
glee.
glee. They
glee. They found
glee. They found a
glee. They found a lone
glee. They found a lone male
glee. They found a lone male by
glee. They found a lone male by himself.
So
So this
glee. They found a lone male by himself.
So this crowd
So this crowd of
glee. They found a lone male by himself.
So this crowd of of
So this crowd of of guys
glee. They found a lone male by himself.
So this crowd of of guys comes
So this crowd of of guys comes across
this
this poor
this poor son
this poor son of
this poor son of a
this poor son of a gun,
this poor son of a gun, begin
this poor son of a gun, begin beating
him
him up.
this poor son of a gun, begin beating
him up. They
him up. They take
this poor son of a gun, begin beating
him up. They take turns
him up. They take turns jumping
this poor son of a gun, begin beating
him up. They take turns jumping on
him up. They take turns jumping on top
of
of them
of them and
of them and one
of them and one guy's
of them and one guy's beating
of them and one guy's beating beating
them
them for
of them and one guy's beating beating
them for a
them for a while
of them and one guy's beating beating
them for a while so
them for a while so he
of them and one guy's beating beating
them for a while so he gets
them for a while so he gets out
of them and one guy's beating beating
them for a while so he gets out of the
way
way so
way so the
way so the next
way so the next guy
way so the next guy can
way so the next guy can come
way so the next guy can come get
way so the next guy can come get some
beats
beats in.
They're
They're all
They're all into
They're all into beat
They're all into beat up
They're all into beat up and
They're all into beat up and they're
They're all into beat up and they're all
in
in a
They're all into beat up and they're all
in a frenzy
in a frenzy of
They're all into beat up and they're all
in a frenzy of excitement.
in a frenzy of excitement. Finally,
They're all into beat up and they're all
in a frenzy of excitement. Finally, this
poor
poor thinker
poor thinker dies
poor thinker dies now.
poor thinker dies now. They
poor thinker dies now. They start
tearing
tearing them
poor thinker dies now. They start
tearing them apart.
tearing them apart. See?
Looks
Looks like
Looks like al-Qaeda
Looks like al-Qaeda video.
Slowly
Slowly saw
Looks like al-Qaeda video.
Slowly saw its
Slowly saw its head
Looks like al-Qaeda video.
Slowly saw its head off.
Slowly saw its head off. You
Looks like al-Qaeda video.
Slowly saw its head off. You know
Slowly saw its head off. You know what
Looks like al-Qaeda video.
Slowly saw its head off. You know what I
mean?
mean? Slowly
mean? Slowly bite
mean? Slowly bite his
mean? Slowly bite his head
mean? Slowly bite his head off.
mean? Slowly bite his head off. Don't
bite
bite his
mean? Slowly bite his head off. Don't
bite his head
bite his head off
mean? Slowly bite his head off. Don't
bite his head off but
bite his head off but slowly
mean? Slowly bite his head off. Don't
bite his head off but slowly bite
bite his head off but slowly bite it
off.
So
So out
off.
So out of
So out of savagery
off.
So out of savagery then
So out of savagery then out
off.
So out of savagery then out of
So out of savagery then out of guilt
off.
So out of savagery then out of guilt out
of
of hatred
of hatred out
of hatred out of
of hatred out of all
of hatred out of all the
of hatred out of all the ego
of hatred out of all the ego positions
the
the ego
of hatred out of all the ego positions
the ego gets
the ego gets what
of hatred out of all the ego positions
the ego gets what it
the ego gets what it needs
of hatred out of all the ego positions
the ego gets what it needs to
the ego gets what it needs to survive
of hatred out of all the ego positions
the ego gets what it needs to survive as
far
far as
far as it's
far as it's concerned
far as it's concerned because
far as it's concerned because it's
deprived
deprived of
far as it's concerned because it's
deprived of spiritual
deprived of spiritual energy.
far as it's concerned because it's
deprived of spiritual energy. Spiritual
energy
energy is
energy is of
energy is of a
energy is of a different
energy is of a different sort
altogether.
We
We have
We have a
chart
chart on
We have a
chart on brain.
chart on brain. We
We have a
chart on brain. We have
chart on brain. We have a
We have a
chart on brain. We have a chart
chart on brain. We have a chart for
everything.
everything. Name
everything. Name it.
everything. Name it. We
everything. Name it. We got
everything. Name it. We got a
everything. Name it. We got a chart.
everything. Name it. We got a chart. Uh
brain
brain function
23.
All
All right.
23.
All right. Below
All right. Below 23
23.
All right. Below 23 then
All right. Below 23 then uh
23.
All right. Below 23 then uh I
All right. Below 23 then uh I mean
23.
All right. Below 23 then uh I mean below
slide
slide 23.
Uh
Uh slide
slide 23.
Uh slide 23.
Uh slide 23. Yeah.
slide 23.
Uh slide 23. Yeah. Anyhow.
Uh slide 23. Yeah. Anyhow. All right.
slide 23.
Uh slide 23. Yeah. Anyhow. All right. So
the
the ego's
the ego's only
the ego's only source
the ego's only source of
the ego's only source of survival
the ego's only source of survival then
is
is the
the ego's only source of survival then
is the gratification
is the gratification it
the ego's only source of survival then
is the gratification it gets
is the gratification it gets from
the ego's only source of survival then
is the gratification it gets from the
energy,
energy, the
energy, the pleasure
energy, the pleasure it
energy, the pleasure it extracts
even
even from
energy, the pleasure it extracts
even from suffering
even from suffering itself.
energy, the pleasure it extracts
even from suffering itself. People
even from suffering itself. People get
addicted
addicted to
addicted to suffering,
addicted to suffering, become
masochistic
masochistic in
addicted to suffering, become
masochistic in their
masochistic in their whole
addicted to suffering, become
masochistic in their whole life.
masochistic in their whole life. They're
always
always losing
always losing the
always losing the great
always losing the great losers
always losing the great losers in
society.
society. They
always losing the great losers in
society. They go
society. They go from
always losing the great losers in
society. They go from loss
society. They go from loss to
always losing the great losers in
society. They go from loss to loss
society. They go from loss to loss to
loss
loss and
loss and all
loss and all right.
loss and all right. So
loss and all right. So it's
loss and all right. So it's what
loss and all right. So it's what they
are
are pulls
loss and all right. So it's what they
are pulls that
are pulls that to
loss and all right. So it's what they
are pulls that to them
are pulls that to them because
loss and all right. So it's what they
are pulls that to them because in
are pulls that to them because in a
loss and all right. So it's what they
are pulls that to them because in a way
they
they are
they are the
they are the vessel.
they are the vessel. They
they are the vessel. They are
they are the vessel. They are the
servant
servant of
they are the vessel. They are the
servant of the
servant of the pleasurable
they are the vessel. They are the
servant of the pleasurable energy
of
of survival
of survival emanating
of survival emanating from
of survival emanating from the
of survival emanating from the ego.
of survival emanating from the ego. Then
when
when you
of survival emanating from the ego. Then
when you add
when you add a
of survival emanating from the ego. Then
when you add a prefrontal
when you add a prefrontal cortex
of survival emanating from the ego. Then
when you add a prefrontal cortex to
when you add a prefrontal cortex to it,
the
the animal
the animal ego
the animal ego can
the animal ego can now
the animal ego can now become
the animal ego can now become quite
elaborate.
elaborate. Quite
the animal ego can now become quite
elaborate. Quite elaborate.
elaborate. Quite elaborate. You
the animal ego can now become quite
elaborate. Quite elaborate. You know,
you
you can't
you can't live
you can't live unless
you can't live unless you
you can't live unless you got
you can't live unless you got a
you can't live unless you got a new
computer.
I
I don't
I don't know
I don't know how
I don't know how to
I don't know how to work
I don't know how to work a
I don't know how to work a computer.
I don't know how to work a computer. I'm
paranoid
paranoid about
I don't know how to work a computer. I'm
paranoid about them.
They're
They're out
They're out to
They're out to get
They're out to get me
now.
now. So
They're out to get me
now. So you
now. So you have
They're out to get me
now. So you have it's
now. So you have it's it's
They're out to get me
now. So you have it's it's the
now. So you have it's it's the world
They're out to get me
now. So you have it's it's the world of
have
have to
have to and
have to and the
have to and the world
have to and the world of
have to and the world of survival.
Now
Now the
have to and the world of survival.
Now the ego
Now the ego therefore
have to and the world of survival.
Now the ego therefore is
Now the ego therefore is literally
addicted
addicted addicted
addicted addicted to
addicted addicted to its
addicted addicted to its positionality.
It's
It's addicted
addicted addicted to its positionality.
It's addicted not
It's addicted not to
addicted addicted to its positionality.
It's addicted not to the
It's addicted not to the positionality
at
at all.
at all. It's
at all. It's addicted
at all. It's addicted to
at all. It's addicted to the
at all. It's addicted to the juice
at all. It's addicted to the juice it
gets
gets out
at all. It's addicted to the juice it
gets out of
gets out of the
at all. It's addicted to the juice it
gets out of the So
gets out of the So the
at all. It's addicted to the juice it
gets out of the So the ego
gets out of the So the ego like
at all. It's addicted to the juice it
gets out of the So the ego like puts
gets out of the So the ego like puts out
little
little doses
little doses of
little doses of heroin.
little doses of heroin. See,
when
when you
little doses of heroin. See,
when you get
when you get what
little doses of heroin. See,
when you get what you
when you get what you want,
little doses of heroin. See,
when you get what you want, you
when you get what you want, you get
little doses of heroin. See,
when you get what you want, you get a
dose.
dose. You
dose. You You
dose. You You punch
dose. You You punch him
dose. You You punch him and
dose. You You punch him and kill
dose. You You punch him and kill him.
Bango.
Bango. Take
dose. You You punch him and kill him.
Bango. Take that,
Bango. Take that, man.
dose. You You punch him and kill him.
Bango. Take that, man. You
Bango. Take that, man. You get
dose. You You punch him and kill him.
Bango. Take that, man. You get a
Bango. Take that, man. You get a dose.
I
I know.
I know. I
I know. I kill
I know. I kill I
I know. I kill I told
I know. I kill I told you
I know. I kill I told you that
I know. I kill I told you that lifetime
I
I put
I know. I kill I told you that lifetime
I put the
I put the sword
I know. I kill I told you that lifetime
I put the sword right
I put the sword right through
I know. I kill I told you that lifetime
I put the sword right through this
I put the sword right through this guy's
groin,
groin, man.
groin, man. I
groin, man. I The
groin, man. I The juice
groin, man. I The juice of
groin, man. I The juice of victory.
groin, man. I The juice of victory. Wow.
Even
Even Harry
groin, man. I The juice of victory. Wow.
Even Harry Kerry,
Even Harry Kerry, you
groin, man. I The juice of victory. Wow.
Even Harry Kerry, you know,
Even Harry Kerry, you know, I
groin, man. I The juice of victory. Wow.
Even Harry Kerry, you know, I did
Even Harry Kerry, you know, I did that
one,
one, too.
A
A thrill.
Victory.
Victory. Victory.
Victory. Victory. Victory.
Victory. Victory. Victory. victorious.
Never
Never have
Victory. Victory. Victory. victorious.
Never have to
Never have to cross
Victory. Victory. Victory. victorious.
Never have to cross that
Never have to cross that level
Victory. Victory. Victory. victorious.
Never have to cross that level again
having
having done
having done it
having done it once.
having done it once. Up
having done it once. Up came
having done it once. Up came ecstasy.
Ecstasy.
So
the
the ego
So
the ego then
the ego then is
So
the ego then is addicted
the ego then is addicted to
So
the ego then is addicted to negativity
because
because it
because it gets
because it gets pleasurable
because it gets pleasurable a
pleasurable
pleasurable energy
because it gets pleasurable a
pleasurable energy out
pleasurable energy out of
because it gets pleasurable a
pleasurable energy out of it.
pleasurable energy out of it. Yeah.
You're
You're not
You're not addicted
You're not addicted to
You're not addicted to hatred,
You're not addicted to hatred, anger,
selfishness,
selfishness, resentment.
You're not addicted to hatred, anger,
selfishness, resentment. It's
selfishness, resentment. It's just
You're not addicted to hatred, anger,
selfishness, resentment. It's just that
you've
you've learned
you've learned that
you've learned that those
you've learned that those things
you've learned that those things will
get
get you
you've learned that those things will
get you the
get you the juice.
Satisfaction
Satisfaction and
Satisfaction and pleasure.
Satisfaction and pleasure. The
Satisfaction and pleasure. The biggest
one
one in
Satisfaction and pleasure. The biggest
one in relationships
one in relationships destroys
Satisfaction and pleasure. The biggest
one in relationships destroys alignments
is
is being
is being right.
People
People will
is being right.
People will do
People will do anything
is being right.
People will do anything to
People will do anything to be
is being right.
People will do anything to be right.
Unbelievable.
Unbelievable. I've
Unbelievable. I've watched
Unbelievable.
Unbelievable. I've watched people
Unbelievable. I've watched people give
give
give up
give up idyllic
give up idyllic life
give up idyllic life situations
uh
uh just
give up idyllic life situations
uh just over
uh just over being
give up idyllic life situations
uh just over being right
uh just over being right over
give up idyllic life situations
uh just over being right over some
trivial
trivial positionality
or
or provoke
trivial positionality
or provoke the
or provoke the other
trivial positionality
or provoke the other person
or provoke the other person to
trivial positionality
or provoke the other person to the
or provoke the other person to the point
of
of homicide.
And
And of
of homicide.
And of course
And of course now
of homicide.
And of course now victorious
And of course now victorious says
of homicide.
And of course now victorious says you
lay
lay there
lay there and
lay there and he
lay there and he stabs
lay there and he stabs you.
lay there and he stabs you. Now
lay there and he stabs you. Now you
really
really got
lay there and he stabs you. Now you
really got him,
really got him, baby.
I
I mean
I mean you
I mean you really
I mean you really got
I mean you really got him,
I mean you really got him, didn't
I mean you really got him, didn't you?
Any
Any sacrifice
I mean you really got him, didn't you?
Any sacrifice is
Any sacrifice is worth
I mean you really got him, didn't you?
Any sacrifice is worth it.
Any sacrifice is worth it. Any
I mean you really got him, didn't you?
Any sacrifice is worth it. Any sacrifice
is
is worth
is worth it.
people
people will
is worth it.
people will give
people will give up
is worth it.
people will give up anything.
So
So then
So then what
So then what we're
So then what we're talking
So then what we're talking about
So then what we're talking about truly
is
is the
So then what we're talking about truly
is the ego
is the ego is
So then what we're talking about truly
is the ego is an
is the ego is an addiction.
So then what we're talking about truly
is the ego is an addiction. What
is the ego is an addiction. What happens
then
then is
then is we
then is we get
then is we get addicted
then is we get addicted to
then is we get addicted to the
pleasurable
pleasurable juice.
then is we get addicted to the
pleasurable juice. The
pleasurable juice. The negative
then is we get addicted to the
pleasurable juice. The negative what
pleasurable juice. The negative what we
view
view from
view from a
view from a higher
view from a higher level
view from a higher level negative
payoff.
payoff. The
view from a higher level negative
payoff. The ego
payoff. The ego views
view from a higher level negative
payoff. The ego views it
payoff. The ego views it as
view from a higher level negative
payoff. The ego views it as a
payoff. The ego views it as a positive
payoff.
payoff. You're
payoff. You're addicted
payoff. You're addicted to
payoff. You're addicted to the
payoff. You're addicted to the juice
payoff. You're addicted to the juice not
to
to the
payoff. You're addicted to the juice not
to the positionality
to the positionality or
payoff. You're addicted to the juice not
to the positionality or the
to the positionality or the view
payoff. You're addicted to the juice not
to the positionality or the view but
to the positionality or the view but the
juice
juice you're
juice you're getting
juice you're getting out
juice you're getting out of
juice you're getting out of it.
juice you're getting out of it. This
juice you're getting out of it. This can
lead
lead you
juice you're getting out of it. This can
lead you to
lead you to ridiculous
juice you're getting out of it. This can
lead you to ridiculous extremes.
Statements
Statements to
Statements to the
Statements to the media
Statements to the media that
Statements to the media that is
Statements to the media that is so
absurd
absurd you
Statements to the media that is so
absurd you can't
absurd you can't imagine
Statements to the media that is so
absurd you can't imagine how
absurd you can't imagine how anybody
with
with an
with an IQ
with an IQ over
with an IQ over 60
with an IQ over 60 could
with an IQ over 60 could have
with an IQ over 60 could have said
with an IQ over 60 could have said it.
And
And it's
with an IQ over 60 could have said it.
And it's all
And it's all across
with an IQ over 60 could have said it.
And it's all across the
And it's all across the media
with an IQ over 60 could have said it.
And it's all across the media for
And it's all across the media for days.
Like
Like you're
Like you're a
Like you're a star
Like you're a star or
Like you're a star or something.
Like you're a star or something. It's
hilarious.
hilarious. Anyway,
Like you're a star or something. It's
hilarious. Anyway, so
hilarious. Anyway, so here
Like you're a star or something. It's
hilarious. Anyway, so here we
hilarious. Anyway, so here we see
Like you're a star or something. It's
hilarious. Anyway, so here we see that
um
um the
um the at
um the at 200
um the at 200 we
um the at 200 we have
um the at 200 we have this
um the at 200 we have this profound
change.
change. The
um the at 200 we have this profound
change. The purpose
change. The purpose of
um the at 200 we have this profound
change. The purpose of spiritual
change. The purpose of spiritual work
number
number one
number one is
number one is to
number one is to transcend
number one is to transcend consciousness
level
level 200.
number one is to transcend consciousness
level 200. below
level 200. below 200,
number one is to transcend consciousness
level 200. below 200, you're
level 200. below 200, you're really
frankly
frankly an
frankly an animal
frankly an animal in
frankly an animal in a
frankly an animal in a human
frankly an animal in a human body.
There's
There's no
frankly an animal in a human body.
There's no difference
There's no difference between
frankly an animal in a human body.
There's no difference between the
behavior
behavior of the
behavior of the chimpanzeee
behavior of the chimpanzeee I
behavior of the chimpanzeee I watched
last
last night
behavior of the chimpanzeee I watched
last night and
last night and humans.
behavior of the chimpanzeee I watched
last night and humans. No
last night and humans. No different
behavior of the chimpanzeee I watched
last night and humans. No different at
all.
all. Today's
all. Today's news
all. Today's news real
all. Today's news real today's
all. Today's news real today's news
all. Today's news real today's news and
yesterday's
yesterday's chimpanzees
all. Today's news real today's news and
yesterday's chimpanzees are
yesterday's chimpanzees are exactly
all. Today's news real today's news and
yesterday's chimpanzees are exactly the
same
same story
same story except
same story except they're
same story except they're fuzzier.
I
I was
same story except they're fuzzier.
I was sat
I was sat sort
same story except they're fuzzier.
I was sat sort of
I was sat sort of sad
same story except they're fuzzier.
I was sat sort of sad not
I was sat sort of sad not to
same story except they're fuzzier.
I was sat sort of sad not to have
I was sat sort of sad not to have fur.
One
One thing
One thing I
One thing I don't
One thing I don't like
One thing I don't like about
One thing I don't like about being
One thing I don't like about being a
human
human is
One thing I don't like about being a
human is you
human is you don't
One thing I don't like about being a
human is you don't have
human is you don't have fur.
One thing I don't like about being a
human is you don't have fur. I
human is you don't have fur. I mean,
everybody
everybody else
everybody else says
everybody else says fur.
everybody else says fur. Kitties
everybody else says fur. Kitties have
fur,
fur, doggies
everybody else says fur. Kitties have
fur, doggies have
fur, doggies have fur,
everybody else says fur. Kitties have
fur, doggies have fur, and
fur, doggies have fur, and you
everybody else says fur. Kitties have
fur, doggies have fur, and you walk
around
around like
around like a
around like a naked
around like a naked idiot,
around like a naked idiot, you
around like a naked idiot, you know what
I
I mean?
So
So stupid
So stupid not
So stupid not to
So stupid not to have
So stupid not to have fur.
So stupid not to have fur. Apparently,
we
we had
So stupid not to have fur. Apparently,
we had to
we had to give
So stupid not to have fur. Apparently,
we had to give up
we had to give up fur
So stupid not to have fur. Apparently,
we had to give up fur to
we had to give up fur to get
So stupid not to have fur. Apparently,
we had to give up fur to get brains.
we had to give up fur to get brains. I
don't
don't know
don't know whether
don't know whether we
don't know whether we won
don't know whether we won or
don't know whether we won or lost
don't know whether we won or lost on
that
that one,
but
but here
but here we
but here we know
but here we know below
but here we know below 200.
Uh
Uh here
but here we know below 200.
Uh here is
Uh here is the
but here we know below 200.
Uh here is the animal.
Uh here is the animal. Here's
but here we know below 200.
Uh here is the animal. Here's 80%
Uh here is the animal. Here's 80% of
but here we know below 200.
Uh here is the animal. Here's 80% of the
of
of 80%
of 80% of
of 80% of the
of 80% of the world's
of 80% of the world's population
of 80% of the world's population right
now.
now. 80%
and
and 50%
and 50% of
and 50% of people
and 50% of people in
and 50% of people in America
and 50% of people in America are
dominated
dominated by
and 50% of people in America are
dominated by the
dominated by the animal
and 50% of people in America are
dominated by the animal perception
dominated by the animal perception going
through
through the
through the relay
fast
fast to
through the relay
fast to the
fast to the emotional
through the relay
fast to the emotional center
fast to the emotional center and
through the relay
fast to the emotional center and they
react.
The
The inlet,
react.
The inlet, the
The inlet, the prefrontal
react.
The inlet, the prefrontal cortex
The inlet, the prefrontal cortex is
slow.
slow. You
slow. You see
slow. You see here's
slow. You see here's the
slow. You see here's the input.
slow. You see here's the input. You
slow. You see here's the input. You see
something
something and
slow. You see here's the input. You see
something and the
something and the fast
slow. You see here's the input. You see
something and the fast action
something and the fast action is
slow. You see here's the input. You see
something and the fast action is to
something and the fast action is to the
emotional
emotional reaction.
emotional reaction. This
emotional reaction. This is
emotional reaction. This is the
knee-jerk
knee-jerk reaction.
emotional reaction. This is the
knee-jerk reaction. So
knee-jerk reaction. So you
emotional reaction. This is the
knee-jerk reaction. So you kneejerk
emotionally.
Belatedly
Belatedly the
emotionally.
Belatedly the information
Belatedly the information gets
emotionally.
Belatedly the information gets processed
by
by the
by the cerebral
by the cerebral cortex.
by the cerebral cortex. But
by the cerebral cortex. But by
by the cerebral cortex. But by then
by the cerebral cortex. But by then it's
already
already happened.
by the cerebral cortex. But by then it's
already happened. It's
already happened. It's happened
by the cerebral cortex. But by then it's
already happened. It's happened and
already happened. It's happened and now
it's
it's stored
it's stored in
it's stored in the
it's stored in the hippocampus.
So
So in
it's stored in the hippocampus.
So in the
So in the hippocampus
it's stored in the hippocampus.
So in the hippocampus in
So in the hippocampus in the
it's stored in the hippocampus.
So in the hippocampus in the memory
So in the hippocampus in the memory now
you
you have
you have a
you have a memory
you have a memory of
you have a memory of an
you have a memory of an unpleasant
situation
situation because
you have a memory of an unpleasant
situation because it
situation because it went
you have a memory of an unpleasant
situation because it went in
situation because it went in there
you have a memory of an unpleasant
situation because it went in there got
stored.
Now
Now the
stored.
Now the cortex
Now the cortex comes
stored.
Now the cortex comes around
Now the cortex comes around with
stored.
Now the cortex comes around with but
didn't
didn't you
didn't you sign
didn't you sign a
didn't you sign a contract?
Didn't
Didn't you
didn't you sign a contract?
Didn't you sign
Didn't you sign an
didn't you sign a contract?
Didn't you sign an agreement
Didn't you sign an agreement to
didn't you sign a contract?
Didn't you sign an agreement to that
after
after you
after you told
after you told him
after you told him to
after you told him to go
after you told him to go to
after you told him to go to hell?
after you told him to go to hell? Uh
after you told him to go to hell? Uh oh
yes
yes I
after you told him to go to hell? Uh oh
yes I did
yes I did sign
after you told him to go to hell? Uh oh
yes I did sign the
yes I did sign the contract.
Uh
Uh so
Uh so this
Uh so this is
Uh so this is belatedly
Uh so this is belatedly now
Uh so this is belatedly now and
Uh so this is belatedly now and and
Uh so this is belatedly now and and you
make
make up
Uh so this is belatedly now and and you
make up excuses
make up excuses and
Uh so this is belatedly now and and you
make up excuses and and
make up excuses and and try
Uh so this is belatedly now and and you
make up excuses and and try to
make up excuses and and try to save
yourself.
yourself. All right.
yourself. All right. Below
yourself. All right. Below above
consciousness
consciousness level
yourself. All right. Below above
consciousness level 200
consciousness level 200 the
yourself. All right. Below above
consciousness level 200 the spiritually
aligned
aligned person
aligned person now
aligned person now is
aligned person now is transformed.
aligned person now is transformed. His
brain
brain physiology
aligned person now is transformed. His
brain physiology is
brain physiology is transformed.
See
See this
See this person
See this person lives
See this person lives off
See this person lives off adrenaline
stress
stress and
See this person lives off adrenaline
stress and fight
stress and fight and
See this person lives off adrenaline
stress and fight and alarm
stress and fight and alarm reaction
See this person lives off adrenaline
stress and fight and alarm reaction and
uh
uh he
uh he has
uh he has disrupted
uh he has disrupted acupuncture
uh he has disrupted acupuncture and
meridians.
meridians. And
uh he has disrupted acupuncture and
meridians. And with
meridians. And with kinesiology
uh he has disrupted acupuncture and
meridians. And with kinesiology it
meridians. And with kinesiology it makes
you
you go
you go weak.
you go weak. If
you go weak. If I
you go weak. If I hold
you go weak. If I hold somebody
you go weak. If I hold somebody below
200 in
200 in mind,
you go weak. If I hold somebody below
200 in mind, I
200 in mind, I say
this
this person
this person calibrates
this person calibrates the
this person calibrates the word
this person calibrates the word 200.
this person calibrates the word 200. If
they're
they're below
this person calibrates the word 200. If
they're below 200,
they're below 200, my
this person calibrates the word 200. If
they're below 200, my arm
they're below 200, my arm goes
this person calibrates the word 200. If
they're below 200, my arm goes weak.
These
These people
These people make
These people make you
These people make you go
These people make you go weak.
These people make you go weak. You
understand?
understand? 80%
These people make you go weak. You
understand? 80% of
understand? 80% of the
These people make you go weak. You
understand? 80% of the people
understand? 80% of the people in
These people make you go weak. You
understand? 80% of the people in the
world
world will
world will make
world will make you
world will make you go
world will make you go weak
world will make you go weak with
kinesiology.
kinesiology. 50%
world will make you go weak with
kinesiology. 50% in
kinesiology. 50% in America.
All
All right.
All right. So
below
below 200
All right. So
below 200 then
below 200 then you
All right. So
below 200 then you have
below 200 then you have left
All right. So
below 200 then you have left brain
dominance.
dominance. This
dominance. This is
dominance. This is a
dominance. This is a linear
dominance. This is a linear world
dominance. This is a linear world of
cause
cause and
dominance. This is a linear world of
cause and effect.
cause and effect. Fight
dominance. This is a linear world of
cause and effect. Fight or
cause and effect. Fight or flight.
People
People live
People live right
People live right on
People live right on the
People live right on the edge
People live right on the edge of
People live right on the edge of alarm.
All
All you
People live right on the edge of alarm.
All you have
All you have to
People live right on the edge of alarm.
All you have to do
All you have to do is
People live right on the edge of alarm.
All you have to do is make
All you have to do is make a
People live right on the edge of alarm.
All you have to do is make a noise
All you have to do is make a noise and
watch
watch everybody
watch everybody startle.
You
You ever
watch everybody startle.
You ever notice
You ever notice that?
watch everybody startle.
You ever notice that? All
You ever notice that? All you
watch everybody startle.
You ever notice that? All you have to
You ever notice that? All you have to do
is
is make
is make a
is make a noise.
is make a noise. People
is make a noise. People I
is make a noise. People I mean
is make a noise. People I mean they're
like
like a
is make a noise. People I mean they're
like a scared
like a scared rabbit.
All right.
All right. This
All right. This is
All right. This is prone
All right. This is prone to
All right. This is prone to disease
All right. This is prone to disease and
all
all right.
All right. This is prone to disease and
all right. So
all right. So now
All right. This is prone to disease and
all right. So now above
all right. So now above consciousness
level
level 200
level 200 which
level 200 which is
level 200 which is it
level 200 which is it really
level 200 which is it really starts
level 200 which is it really starts with
taking
taking responsibility.
Below
Below 200
Below 200 you
Below 200 you blame.
Below 200 you blame. You'll
Below 200 you blame. You'll depend
Below 200 you blame. You'll depend on
blame.
blame. That
Below 200 you blame. You'll depend on
blame. That makes
blame. That makes you
Below 200 you blame. You'll depend on
blame. That makes you very
blame. That makes you very weak
Below 200 you blame. You'll depend on
blame. That makes you very weak because
blame
blame makes
blame makes you
blame makes you weak.
Blame
Blame and
blame makes you weak.
Blame and excuses
Blame and excuses make
blame makes you weak.
Blame and excuses make you
Blame and excuses make you weak.
blame makes you weak.
Blame and excuses make you weak. Once
you
you start
you start taking
you start taking responsibility,
you start taking responsibility, now
you're
you're at
you start taking responsibility, now
you're at 200.
you're at 200. At
you start taking responsibility, now
you're at 200. At 200,
you're at 200. At 200, you
you start taking responsibility, now
you're at 200. At 200, you get
you're at 200. At 200, you get a
you start taking responsibility, now
you're at 200. At 200, you get a total
transformation.
The
The input
transformation.
The input is
The input is very
transformation.
The input is very fast,
very
very fast.
very fast. And
very fast. And what
very fast. And what happened
very fast. And what happened now
very fast. And what happened now at
very fast. And what happened now at 200
is
is you
very fast. And what happened now at 200
is you developed
is you developed an
very fast. And what happened now at 200
is you developed an atheric
is you developed an atheric brain,
very fast. And what happened now at 200
is you developed an atheric brain, which
is
is a
is a spiritual
is a spiritual energy
is a spiritual energy brain.
is a spiritual energy brain. and
is a spiritual energy brain. and the
information
information goes
is a spiritual energy brain. and the
information goes very
information goes very fast
uh
uh through
uh through the
uh through the preffrontal
uh through the preffrontal cortex
uh through the preffrontal cortex and
the
the athetheric
uh through the preffrontal cortex and
the athetheric brain.
the athetheric brain. And
uh through the preffrontal cortex and
the athetheric brain. And so
the athetheric brain. And so now
uh through the preffrontal cortex and
the athetheric brain. And so now you
have
have greater
have greater immunity,
have greater immunity, right
have greater immunity, right brain
dominance
dominance and
have greater immunity, right brain
dominance and your
dominance and your brain
have greater immunity, right brain
dominance and your brain is
dominance and your brain is putting
have greater immunity, right brain
dominance and your brain is putting out
endorphins
endorphins and
endorphins and positive
endorphins and positive emotions.
Uh
Uh and
endorphins and positive emotions.
Uh and with
Uh and with kinesiology
uh
uh you
uh you go
uh you go strong.
The
The addiction
uh you go strong.
The addiction then
The addiction then is
uh you go strong.
The addiction then is not
The addiction then is not to
uh you go strong.
The addiction then is not to the
behavior
behavior or
behavior or to
behavior or to a
behavior or to a positionality
behavior or to a positionality but
behavior or to a positionality but to
the
the pleasure
behavior or to a positionality but to
the pleasure of
the pleasure of it.
behavior or to a positionality but to
the pleasure of it. All
the pleasure of it. All right.
behavior or to a positionality but to
the pleasure of it. All right. So
the pleasure of it. All right. So when
you're
you're trying
you're trying to
you're trying to do
you're trying to do spiritual
you're trying to do spiritual work,
you're
you're trying
you're trying to do spiritual work,
you're trying to
you're trying to transcend
you're trying to do spiritual work,
you're trying to transcend the
you're trying to transcend the levels
you're trying to do spiritual work,
you're trying to transcend the levels of
consciousness
and
and evolve
consciousness
and evolve and
and evolve and you're
consciousness
and evolve and you're stuck
and evolve and you're stuck with
something.
something. You
something. You think
something. You think you're
something. You think you're stuck
something. You think you're stuck with
what
what do
something. You think you're stuck with
what do you
what do you think
something. You think you're stuck with
what do you think you're
what do you think you're stuck
something. You think you're stuck with
what do you think you're stuck with?
Anybody
Anybody here
Anybody here stuck
Anybody here stuck with
Anybody here stuck with anything?
Impatience,
Impatience, hating
Anybody here stuck with anything?
Impatience, hating your
Impatience, hating your mother-in-law,
God
God knows
God knows what.
Hating
Hating the
God knows what.
Hating the enemy,
Hating the enemy, whatever.
You
You think
You think that's
You think that's what
You think that's what you're
You think that's what you're stuck
You think that's what you're stuck with,
but
but that's
You think that's what you're stuck with,
but that's only
but that's only the
You think that's what you're stuck with,
but that's only the linear
but that's only the linear content.
You're
You're not
You're not stuck
You're not stuck with
You're not stuck with that.
You're not stuck with that. It's
You're not stuck with that. It's you're
stuck
stuck with
You're not stuck with that. It's you're
stuck with the
stuck with the energy,
You're not stuck with that. It's you're
stuck with the energy, the
stuck with the energy, the pleasure
You're not stuck with that. It's you're
stuck with the energy, the pleasure you
get
get out
get out of
get out of it.
get out of it. people
get out of it. people that
get out of it. people that the
get out of it. people that the uh
get out of it. people that the uh drugs
and
and alcohol
get out of it. people that the uh drugs
and alcohol know
and alcohol know that
get out of it. people that the uh drugs
and alcohol know that in
and alcohol know that in the
get out of it. people that the uh drugs
and alcohol know that in the beginning
they
they can
they can only
they can only drink
they can only drink uh
they can only drink uh so
they can only drink uh so and
they can only drink uh so and so
bourbons
bourbons you
they can only drink uh so and so
bourbons you know
bourbons you know you
they can only drink uh so and so
bourbons you know you know
bourbons you know you know very
they can only drink uh so and so
bourbons you know you know very fancy
they're
they're very
they're very selective
they're very selective as
they're very selective as life
they're very selective as life goes
they're very selective as life goes down
pretty
pretty soon
they're very selective as life goes down
pretty soon they'll
pretty soon they'll drink
they're very selective as life goes down
pretty soon they'll drink anything
then
then they
then they got
then they got a
then they got a hangover
then they got a hangover they
then they got a hangover they start
taking
taking pills
their
their preference
their preference is
their preference is perkadan
their preference is perkadan let's
their preference is perkadan let's say
but
but they
their preference is perkadan let's say
but they can't
but they can't get
their preference is perkadan let's say
but they can't get any
but they can't get any perkadan
their preference is perkadan let's say
but they can't get any perkadan well
they'll
they'll take
they'll take anything
so
so the
they'll take anything
so the addiction
so the addiction then
they'll take anything
so the addiction then becomes
so the addiction then becomes more
they'll take anything
so the addiction then becomes more and
more
more non-
more non- selective
Whatever
Whatever gets
more non- selective
Whatever gets you
Whatever gets you stone,
more non- selective
Whatever gets you stone, man,
Whatever gets you stone, man, that'll
do.
Who
Who cares
do.
Who cares what
Who cares what it
do.
Who cares what it is?
Back
Back east,
Back east, get
Back east, get a
Back east, get a new
Back east, get a new batch
Back east, get a new batch of
Back east, get a new batch of LSD
Back east, get a new batch of LSD or
measculine
measculine or
Back east, get a new batch of LSD or
measculine or something.
measculine or something. And
Back east, get a new batch of LSD or
measculine or something. And there
measculine or something. And there was
Back east, get a new batch of LSD or
measculine or something. And there was a
kid
kid that
kid that hung
kid that hung out
kid that hung out with
kid that hung out with the
kid that hung out with the druggies
kid that hung out with the druggies in
the
the park
kid that hung out with the druggies in
the park and
the park and they
kid that hung out with the druggies in
the park and they would
the park and they would try
kid that hung out with the druggies in
the park and they would try it
the park and they would try it out
kid that hung out with the druggies in
the park and they would try it out on
him
him first.
New
New batch
him first.
New batch acid.
New batch acid. They
him first.
New batch acid. They would
New batch acid. They would run
him first.
New batch acid. They would run through
him
him and
him and see
him and see if
him and see if he
him and see if he survived,
him and see if he survived, managed
him and see if he survived, managed to
continue
continue breathing.
him and see if he survived, managed to
continue breathing. Literally,
continue breathing. Literally, they
him and see if he survived, managed to
continue breathing. Literally, they they
used
used him
used him as
used him as a
used him as a guinea
used him as a guinea pig
used him as a guinea pig and
used him as a guinea pig and would
used him as a guinea pig and would run
it
it through
used him as a guinea pig and would run
it through him.
Whoa.
Whoa. And
Whoa. And uh
All
All right.
Whoa. And uh
All right. So,
All right. So, whatever
Whoa. And uh
All right. So, whatever gives
All right. So, whatever gives you
Whoa. And uh
All right. So, whatever gives you that
thrill,
thrill, that
thrill, that sat
thrill, that sat that
thrill, that sat that ego
thrill, that sat that ego juice
thrill, that sat that ego juice uh
you're
you're going
thrill, that sat that ego juice uh
you're going to
you're going to get
thrill, that sat that ego juice uh
you're going to get what
you're going to get what you
thrill, that sat that ego juice uh
you're going to get what you think
you're going to get what you think is
addicted
addicted to
addicted to that.
addicted to that. So,
addicted to that. So, we
addicted to that. So, we can
addicted to that. So, we can short
circuit
circuit all
addicted to that. So, we can short
circuit all of
circuit all of that
addicted to that. So, we can short
circuit all of that spiritual
circuit all of that spiritual work
addicted to that. So, we can short
circuit all of that spiritual work and
just
just see
just see you've
just see you've only
just see you've only got
just see you've only got one
just see you've only got one addiction,
only
only one
just see you've only got one addiction,
only one problem,
only one problem, not
just see you've only got one addiction,
only one problem, not hundreds
only one problem, not hundreds and
thousands.
thousands. That's
thousands. That's why
thousands. That's why nobody
thousands. That's why nobody gets
enlightened.
enlightened. For
thousands. That's why nobody gets
enlightened. For God's
enlightened. For God's sake,
thousands. That's why nobody gets
enlightened. For God's sake, you're
working
working on
working on these
working on these thousands
working on these thousands of
working on these thousands of problems.
You
You only
working on these thousands of problems.
You only got
You only got one
working on these thousands of problems.
You only got one problem.
You're
You're hooked
You're hooked on
You're hooked on the
You're hooked on the juice
You're hooked on the juice of
You're hooked on the juice of being
right.
right. You're
You're hooked on the juice of being
right. You're hooked
right. You're hooked on
You're hooked on the juice of being
right. You're hooked on the
right. You're hooked on the juice,
You're hooked on the juice of being
right. You're hooked on the juice, the
payoff.
payoff. Sadness,
payoff. Sadness, loss,
payoff. Sadness, loss, bankruptcy,
whatever
whatever your
whatever it
whatever it is.
Once
Once you
whatever it is.
Once you see
Once you see you've
whatever it is.
Once you see you've only
Once you see you've only got
whatever it is.
Once you see you've only got one
problem,
problem, you
problem, you see
problem, you see how
problem, you see how simple
problem, you see how simple it
problem, you see how simple it makes
problem, you see how simple it makes it.
Now
Now the
problem, you see how simple it makes it.
Now the question
Now the question is,
problem, you see how simple it makes it.
Now the question is, how
Now the question is, how do
problem, you see how simple it makes it.
Now the question is, how do you
Now the question is, how do you get
unhooked
unhooked from
unhooked from being
unhooked from being hooked
unhooked from being hooked to
unhooked from being hooked to the
pleasure,
pleasure, the
unhooked from being hooked to the
pleasure, the juice?
Now
Now that
Now that you've
Now that you've taken
Now that you've taken out
Now that you've taken out 150
Now that you've taken out 150 things
Now that you've taken out 150 things you
don't
don't have
Now that you've taken out 150 things you
don't have to
don't have to process
Now that you've taken out 150 things you
don't have to process and
don't have to process and you're
Now that you've taken out 150 things you
don't have to process and you're down
don't have to process and you're down to
one
one thing,
one thing, all
one thing, all the
one thing, all the people
one thing, all the people in
one thing, all the people in the
one thing, all the people in the drugs
and
and alcohol
one thing, all the people in the drugs
and alcohol are
and alcohol are hooked
one thing, all the people in the drugs
and alcohol are hooked on
and alcohol are hooked on one
one thing, all the people in the drugs
and alcohol are hooked on one thing
only,
only, intoxication.
That's
That's all.
only, intoxication.
That's all. They're
That's all. They're not
only, intoxication.
That's all. They're not hooked
That's all. They're not hooked on
bourbon
bourbon or
bourbon or cocaine
bourbon or cocaine or
bourbon or cocaine or meth
bourbon or cocaine or meth or
bourbon or cocaine or meth or whatever.
They're
They're hooked
bourbon or cocaine or meth or whatever.
They're hooked on
They're hooked on the
bourbon or cocaine or meth or whatever.
They're hooked on the state
They're hooked on the state of
intoxication.
intoxication. Period.
intoxication. Period. Anything
intoxication. Period. Anything that'll
get
get you
intoxication. Period. Anything that'll
get you intoxicated.
Guy
Guy says,
Guy says, "Man,
Guy says, "Man, I
Guy says, "Man, I really
Guy says, "Man, I really I'm
Guy says, "Man, I really I'm really
Guy says, "Man, I really I'm really in
bad
bad shape.
Guy says, "Man, I really I'm really in
bad shape. Got
bad shape. Got anything?"
Guy says, "Man, I really I'm really in
bad shape. Got anything?" Yep.
What
What is
What is it?
What is it? I
What is it? I don't
What is it? I don't know
What is it? I don't know what
What is it? I don't know what the
What is it? I don't know what the hell
it
it is.
Take
Take it
Take it for
Take it for Christ's
Take it for Christ's sake.
Wow.
You
You get
You get me
You get me another
You get me another dozen
You get me another dozen of
You get me another dozen of them.
How
How much
You get me another dozen of them.
How much are
How much are they?
$500.
$500. Okay.
$500. Okay. Okay.
You'll
You'll start
$500. Okay. Okay.
You'll start willing
You'll start willing to
$500. Okay. Okay.
You'll start willing to pay
You'll start willing to pay any
$500. Okay. Okay.
You'll start willing to pay any price
for
for the
for the reexperience
for the reexperience of
for the reexperience of that.
for the reexperience of that. What's
happened
happened then
for the reexperience of that. What's
happened then is
happened then is that
for the reexperience of that. What's
happened then is that the
happened then is that the consciousness
level
we
we really
level
we really need
we really need uh
level
we really need uh chart
we really need uh chart one
level
we really need uh chart one levels
we really need uh chart one levels of
consciousness
consciousness on
consciousness on um
consciousness on um oh
consciousness on um oh my
consciousness on um oh my god
consciousness on um oh my god you
consciousness on um oh my god you that
mind
mind reader.
consciousness on um oh my god you that
mind reader. So
mind reader. So what's
consciousness on um oh my god you that
mind reader. So what's happened?
mind reader. So what's happened? You
see,
see, if
see, if you're
see, if you're down
see, if you're down here,
if
if you're
see, if you're down here,
if you're down
if you're down here,
see, if you're down here,
if you're down here, you
if you're down here, you don't
experience
experience that
experience that joy.
experience that joy. So,
experience that joy. So, what
experience that joy. So, what you
experience that joy. So, what you do
experience that joy. So, what you do is
you
you take
experience that joy. So, what you do is
you take something
you take something that
experience that joy. So, what you do is
you take something that that
artificially
artificially then
artificially then uh
artificially then uh blocks
artificially then uh blocks off
artificially then uh blocks off this
part
part of
artificially then uh blocks off this
part of thing
part of thing and
artificially then uh blocks off this
part of thing and you
part of thing and you now
artificially then uh blocks off this
part of thing and you now experience
those
those energies
those energies and
those energies and you
those energies and you ascribe
those energies and you ascribe them
those energies and you ascribe them to
the
the drug.
those energies and you ascribe them to
the drug. You
the drug. You think
those energies and you ascribe them to
the drug. You think it's
the drug. You think it's the
those energies and you ascribe them to
the drug. You think it's the drug
the drug. You think it's the drug that
is
is causing
is causing that.
is causing that. No.
is causing that. No. What's
is causing that. No. What's happening
is causing that. No. What's happening is
this
this clever
is causing that. No. What's happening is
this clever drug
this clever drug blocks
is causing that. No. What's happening is
this clever drug blocks out
this clever drug blocks out everything
under
under let's
under let's say
under let's say ecstasy.
under let's say ecstasy. Huh?
under let's say ecstasy. Huh? There's
ecstasy
ecstasy up
under let's say ecstasy. Huh? There's
ecstasy up in
ecstasy up in here.
under let's say ecstasy. Huh? There's
ecstasy up in here. Now,
ecstasy up in here. Now, if
under let's say ecstasy. Huh? There's
ecstasy up in here. Now, if I
ecstasy up in here. Now, if I invent
under let's say ecstasy. Huh? There's
ecstasy up in here. Now, if I invent a
drug
drug that
drug that blocks
drug that blocks off
drug that blocks off everything
drug that blocks off everything below
here,
you're
you're going
you're going to
you're going to think,
you're going to think, "Wow,
you're going to think, "Wow, that
ecstasy
ecstasy is
you're going to think, "Wow, that
ecstasy is coming
ecstasy is coming from
you're going to think, "Wow, that
ecstasy is coming from the
ecstasy is coming from the ecstasy."
you're going to think, "Wow, that
ecstasy is coming from the ecstasy." H
ecstasy
ecstasy is
ecstasy is coming
ecstasy is coming from
ecstasy is coming from you.
The
The high
ecstasy is coming from you.
The high of
The high of any
ecstasy is coming from you.
The high of any high
The high of any high is
ecstasy is coming from you.
The high of any high is coming
The high of any high is coming from
yourself.
That
That simplifies
yourself.
That simplifies transcending
That simplifies transcending the
yourself.
That simplifies transcending the ego.
Then
Then when
Then when you
Then when you see
Then when you see that
Then when you see that what
Then when you see that what you're
addicted
addicted to
Then when you see that what you're
addicted to is
addicted to is the
Then when you see that what you're
addicted to is the sensory.
addicted to is the sensory. It's
Then when you see that what you're
addicted to is the sensory. It's really
a
a sensory
a sensory phenomena.
A
A sensory
a sensory phenomena.
A sensory phenomena
A sensory phenomena of
a sensory phenomena.
A sensory phenomena of pleasure
and
and the
and the ego
and the ego has
and the ego has learned
and the ego has learned how
and the ego has learned how to
and the ego has learned how to get
and the ego has learned how to get it
for
for reasons
and the ego has learned how to get it
for reasons of
for reasons of survival.
Yeah.
From
From below
Yeah.
From below 200
From below 200 people
Yeah.
From below 200 people below
From below 200 people below 200
uh
uh people
uh people interact
uh people interact this
uh people interact this way
horizontally.
Below
Below 200
Below 200 it's
Below 200 it's only
Below 200 it's only control
and
and must
Below 200 it's only control
and must have
got
got to
got to have
got to have her
got to have her or
got to have her or I'll
got to have her or I'll die.
got to have her or I'll die. He's
got to have her or I'll die. He's got
her
now.
now. He
now. He beats
now. He beats her
now. He beats her up.
Right.
Now
Now he
Now he beats
Now he beats her
Now he beats her up.
Now he beats her up. Yeah.
Now he beats her up. Yeah. Then
Now he beats her up. Yeah. Then she
leaves
leaves him.
Now he beats her up. Yeah. Then she
leaves him. Then
leaves him. Then he
Now he beats her up. Yeah. Then she
leaves him. Then he threatens
leaves him. Then he threatens to
Now he beats her up. Yeah. Then she
leaves him. Then he threatens to kill
himself
himself if
himself if she
himself if she don't
himself if she don't come
himself if she don't come back.
himself if she don't come back. I
himself if she don't come back. I mean,
I
I used
himself if she don't come back. I mean,
I used to
I used to treat
himself if she don't come back. I mean,
I used to treat all
I used to treat all kinds
himself if she don't come back. I mean,
I used to treat all kinds of
I used to treat all kinds of those
himself if she don't come back. I mean,
I used to treat all kinds of those sick
relationships.
U
U murder
relationships.
U murder and
U murder and suicide
relationships.
U murder and suicide and
U murder and suicide and battering
relationships.
U murder and suicide and battering and
self-pity
self-pity and
self-pity and drugs
self-pity and drugs and
self-pity and drugs and suicide
self-pity and drugs and suicide attacks
and
and um
that's
that's involved
that's involved involved
that's involved involved but
that's involved involved but it's
that's involved involved but it's not
aligned.
aligned. Not
that's involved involved but it's not
aligned. Not aligned.
aligned. Not aligned. So
that's involved involved but it's not
aligned. Not aligned. So alignment
aligned. Not aligned. So alignment means
once
once you
once you spiritualize
once you spiritualize the
once you spiritualize the energy,
once you spiritualize the energy, once
you
you invoke
once you spiritualize the energy, once
you invoke energies
you invoke energies from
once you spiritualize the energy, once
you invoke energies from 200
you invoke energies from 200 and
once you spiritualize the energy, once
you invoke energies from 200 and up,
you invoke energies from 200 and up, now
you're
you're capable
you're capable of
you're capable of alignment.
you're capable of alignment. Alignment
you
you see
you're capable of alignment. Alignment
you see at
you see at level
you're capable of alignment. Alignment
you see at level neutrality,
you see at level neutrality, neutrality
is
is okay
is okay if
is okay if it's
is okay if it's this
is okay if it's this way
is okay if it's this way and
is okay if it's this way and it's
is okay if it's this way and it's okay
if
if it's
is okay if it's this way and it's okay
if it's that
if it's that way.
See,
See, below
See, below 200,
See, below 200, if
See, below 200, if she
See, below 200, if she doesn't
See, below 200, if she doesn't cook
See, below 200, if she doesn't cook it
your
your way,
See, below 200, if she doesn't cook it
your way, you
your way, you push
See, below 200, if she doesn't cook it
your way, you push it
your way, you push it aside
See, below 200, if she doesn't cook it
your way, you push it aside and
your way, you push it aside and she
See, below 200, if she doesn't cook it
your way, you push it aside and she goes
and
and cries.
I
I spent
and cries.
I spent all
I spent all afternoon
and cries.
I spent all afternoon making
I spent all afternoon making that
and cries.
I spent all afternoon making that for
me.
me. You
me. You know,
neutrality.
It
It doesn't
It doesn't make
It doesn't make any
It doesn't make any difference.
What's
What's for
It doesn't make any difference.
What's for dinner?
The
The other
The other thing
The other thing is
The other thing is important
The other thing is important is
The other thing is important is that
there's
there's going
The other thing is important is that
there's going to
there's going to be
The other thing is important is that
there's going to be something
there's going to be something for
dinner.
Is
Is there
dinner.
Is there something
Is there something for
dinner.
Is there something for dinner?
Is there something for dinner? Yep.
Okay.
Okay. So,
Okay. So, if
Okay. So, if you're
Okay. So, if you're aligned,
Okay. So, if you're aligned, you
Okay. So, if you're aligned, you know
the
the other
Okay. So, if you're aligned, you know
the other person
the other person is
Okay. So, if you're aligned, you know
the other person is going
the other person is going to
Okay. So, if you're aligned, you know
the other person is going to do
the other person is going to do the
Okay. So, if you're aligned, you know
the other person is going to do the best
they
they can
they can to
they can to make
they can to make the
they can to make the dinner
they can to make the dinner as
they can to make the dinner as good
they can to make the dinner as good as
possible.
possible. You
they can to make the dinner as good as
possible. You see?
possible. You see? So,
they can to make the dinner as good as
possible. You see? So, there's
possible. You see? So, there's the
beginning
beginning of
beginning of faith
beginning of faith and
beginning of faith and confidence.
Whether
Whether it
beginning of faith and confidence.
Whether it works
Whether it works out
beginning of faith and confidence.
Whether it works out or
Whether it works out or not
beginning of faith and confidence.
Whether it works out or not is
irrelevant
irrelevant because
irrelevant because you
irrelevant because you know
irrelevant because you know what
irrelevant because you know what the
intention
intention was.
irrelevant because you know what the
intention was. So
intention was. So you
irrelevant because you know what the
intention was. So you know
intention was. So you know it
irrelevant because you know what the
intention was. So you know it burned
intention was. So you know it burned a
little
little bit
little bit on
little bit on the
little bit on the edges.
little bit on the edges. I
little bit on the edges. I mean
little bit on the edges. I mean so
little bit on the edges. I mean so what?
So
So you
little bit on the edges. I mean so what?
So you cut
So you cut the
little bit on the edges. I mean so what?
So you cut the edges
So you cut the edges off.
little bit on the edges. I mean so what?
So you cut the edges off. It's
So you cut the edges off. It's no
little bit on the edges. I mean so what?
So you cut the edges off. It's no big
deal.
deal. You
deal. You know
I
I once
deal. You know
I once knew
I once knew somebody
deal. You know
I once knew somebody that
I once knew somebody that if
deal. You know
I once knew somebody that if his
I once knew somebody that if his wife
cooked
cooked a
cooked a thing
cooked a thing not
cooked a thing not correctly
cooked a thing not correctly he
cooked a thing not correctly he would
take
take it
cooked a thing not correctly he would
take it take
take it take the
cooked a thing not correctly he would
take it take the whole
take it take the whole roast
cooked a thing not correctly he would
take it take the whole roast and
take it take the whole roast and throw
it
it out
it out the
it out the window.
Here
Here take
it out the window.
Here take a
Here take a whole
it out the window.
Here take a whole roasted
Here take a whole roasted beef.
Sixth
Sixth floor.
Sixth floor. Cold
Sixth floor. Cold water.
Sixth floor.
Sixth floor. Cold water. Walk
Sixth floor. Cold water. Walk up
Sixth floor.
Sixth floor. Cold water. Walk up lower
Manhattan.
Manhattan. Lower
Manhattan. Lower east
Manhattan. Lower east side
Manhattan. Lower east side of
Manhattan. Lower east side of my
Manhattan. Lower east side of my head,
you
you know.
Manhattan. Lower east side of my head,
you know. And
you know. And he
Manhattan. Lower east side of my head,
you know. And he was
you know. And he was just
Manhattan. Lower east side of my head,
you know. And he was just a
you know. And he was just a tyrant.
Literally.
Literally. And
Literally. And he
Literally. And he if
Literally. And he if he
Literally. And he if he got
Literally. And he if he got mad,
Literally. And he if he got mad, he
would
would throw
Literally. And he if he got mad, he
would throw furniture
would throw furniture out
Literally. And he if he got mad, he
would throw furniture out the
would throw furniture out the window.
He
He he
He he would
He he would he
He he would he would
He he would he would take
He he would he would take a
He he would he would take a chair
He he would he would take a chair and
throw
throw it
He he would he would take a chair and
throw it through
throw it through the
He he would he would take a chair and
throw it through the window.
like
like an
like an animal.
like an animal. See
like an animal. See animal.
All right.
All right. So
at
at neutrality
at neutrality uh
at neutrality uh you
at neutrality uh you can
at neutrality uh you can get
at neutrality uh you can get along.
Courage
Courage really
at neutrality uh you can get along.
Courage really is
Courage really is admitting
at neutrality uh you can get along.
Courage really is admitting uh
responsibility.
Uh
Uh you
responsibility.
Uh you say
Uh you say I
responsibility.
Uh you say I I
Uh you say I I forgot
responsibility.
Uh you say I I forgot the
Uh you say I I forgot the pick
responsibility.
Uh you say I I forgot the pick up
Uh you say I I forgot the pick up the
bread.
bread. Yeah.
bread. Yeah. That's
bread. Yeah. That's honesty.
bread. Yeah. That's honesty. Now
bread. Yeah. That's honesty. Now below
200.
200. You
bread. Yeah. That's honesty. Now below
200. You didn't
200. You didn't forget
bread. Yeah. That's honesty. Now below
200. You didn't forget to
200. You didn't forget to get
bread. Yeah. That's honesty. Now below
200. You didn't forget to get the
200. You didn't forget to get the bread.
You
You didn't
You didn't forget
You didn't forget to
You didn't forget to get
You didn't forget to get the
You didn't forget to get the bread.
Somebody
Somebody stole
You didn't forget to get the bread.
Somebody stole the
Somebody stole the note
You didn't forget to get the bread.
Somebody stole the note or
Somebody stole the note or something.
You
You find
You find some
You find some excuse.
You find some excuse. There's
You find some excuse. There's blame.
Well,
Well, I
You find some excuse. There's blame.
Well, I felt
Well, I felt too
You find some excuse. There's blame.
Well, I felt too sick
Well, I felt too sick to
You find some excuse. There's blame.
Well, I felt too sick to stop.
Well, I felt too sick to stop. I
You find some excuse. There's blame.
Well, I felt too sick to stop. I mean,
whatever
whatever goes
whatever goes to
whatever goes to your
whatever goes to your mind.
whatever goes to your mind. I
whatever goes to your mind. I had
whatever goes to your mind. I had a
headache,
headache, so
whatever goes to your mind. I had a
headache, so I
headache, so I didn't
whatever goes to your mind. I had a
headache, so I didn't stop
headache, so I didn't stop at
whatever goes to your mind. I had a
headache, so I didn't stop at bashes.
Get
Get you
Get you know
Get you know any
Get you know any kind
Get you know any kind of
Get you know any kind of excuse.
Get you know any kind of excuse. So,
this
this is
Get you know any kind of excuse. So,
this is the
this is the world
Get you know any kind of excuse. So,
this is the world of
this is the world of lies.
Get you know any kind of excuse. So,
this is the world of lies. This
this is the world of lies. This is
Get you know any kind of excuse. So,
this is the world of lies. This is the
world
world of
world of truth.
world of truth. You
world of truth. You can
world of truth. You can become
world of truth. You can become aligned
with
with somebody
world of truth. You can become aligned
with somebody who's
with somebody who's willing
world of truth. You can become aligned
with somebody who's willing to
with somebody who's willing to has
world of truth. You can become aligned
with somebody who's willing to has the
courage
courage to
courage to tell
courage to tell the
courage to tell the truth.
Beyond
Beyond that,
courage to tell the truth.
Beyond that, you
Beyond that, you move
courage to tell the truth.
Beyond that, you move into
Beyond that, you move into neutrality,
which
which is
which is very
which is very comfortable.
which is very comfortable. uh
which is very comfortable. uh even
beyond
beyond that
which is very comfortable. uh even
beyond that is
beyond that is willingness.
which is very comfortable. uh even
beyond that is willingness. Willingness
and
and acceptance
and acceptance of
and acceptance of how
and acceptance of how things
and acceptance of how things are.
and acceptance of how things are. Then
you
you begin
and acceptance of how things are. Then
you begin through
you begin through reason
and acceptance of how things are. Then
you begin through reason to
you begin through reason to see
and acceptance of how things are. Then
you begin through reason to see that
everyone
everyone is
everyone is exactly
everyone is exactly the
everyone is exactly the way
everyone is exactly the way they
everyone is exactly the way they are
everyone is exactly the way they are for
the
the reasons
everyone is exactly the way they are for
the reasons that
the reasons that they're
everyone is exactly the way they are for
the reasons that they're that
the reasons that they're that way.
What's
What's that?
What's that? Men
What's that? Men are
What's that? Men are from
What's that? Men are from Mars
What's that? Men are from Mars and
What's that? Men are from Mars and women
are
are from
What's that? Men are from Mars and women
are from Jupiter
are from Jupiter or
What's that? Men are from Mars and women
are from Jupiter or something.
are from Jupiter or something. Women
What's that? Men are from Mars and women
are from Jupiter or something. Women are
from
from Venus
from Venus and
from Venus and men
from Venus and men are
from Venus and men are from
from Venus and men are from Mars.
from Venus and men are from Mars. Is
that
that right?
Well,
Well, whatever
Well, whatever it
Well, whatever it is,
I'm
I'm okay
Well, whatever it is,
I'm okay about
I'm okay about whatever
Well, whatever it is,
I'm okay about whatever it
I'm okay about whatever it is
Well, whatever it is,
I'm okay about whatever it is in
neutrality.
I'm
I'm willing
neutrality.
I'm willing to
I'm willing to think
neutrality.
I'm willing to think it's
I'm willing to think it's okay
neutrality.
I'm willing to think it's okay and
accept
accept whatever
accept whatever it
accept whatever it is.
Anyway,
Anyway, I
accept whatever it is.
Anyway, I thought
Anyway, I thought it
accept whatever it is.
Anyway, I thought it was
Anyway, I thought it was a
accept whatever it is.
Anyway, I thought it was a good
Anyway, I thought it was a good book
because
because it
because it made
because it made relationship
understandable
understandable for
because it made relationship
understandable for the
understandable for the first
because it made relationship
understandable for the first time
understandable for the first time to
many
many people
many people in
many people in the
many people in the country
many people in the country that
many people in the country that people
deny
deny u
uh
uh differencing
uh differencing men
uh differencing men and
uh differencing men and women.
uh differencing men and women. I
uh differencing men and women. I guess
in
in mathematical
uh differencing men and women. I guess
in mathematical ability
in mathematical ability he
uh differencing men and women. I guess
in mathematical ability he had
in mathematical ability he had gotten
uh differencing men and women. I guess
in mathematical ability he had gotten is
what
what look
what look what
what look what that
what look what that led
what look what that led to
what look what that led to and
what look what that led to and uh
he
he didn't
what look what that led to and uh
he didn't hear
he didn't hear the
what look what that led to and uh
he didn't hear the last
he didn't hear the last lecture
what look what that led to and uh
he didn't hear the last lecture we
he didn't hear the last lecture we told
everybody
everybody to
everybody to her
everybody to her wonderful
everybody to her wonderful life
everybody to her wonderful life all
everybody to her wonderful life all you
got
got to
everybody to her wonderful life all you
got to know
got to know is
everybody to her wonderful life all you
got to know is one
got to know is one sentence
everybody to her wonderful life all you
got to know is one sentence you're
got to know is one sentence you're right
dear
president
president Harvard
dear
president Harvard just
president Harvard just should
dear
president Harvard just should have
president Harvard just should have said
you're
you're right
you're right dear
she
she should
you're right dear
she should have
she should have said
you're right dear
she should have said to
she should have said to the
you're right dear
she should have said to the president
she should have said to the president of
Harvard
Harvard you're
Harvard you're right
it
it was
Harvard you're right
it was such
it was such a
Harvard you're right
it was such a so
it was such a so what
Harvard you're right
it was such a so what I
it was such a so what I couldn't
Harvard you're right
it was such a so what I couldn't believe
what
what they
what they made
what they made out
what they made out of
what they made out of it.
what they made out of it. You
what they made out of it. You know
what they made out of it. You know that
there's
there's differences
what they made out of it. You know that
there's differences between
there's differences between men
what they made out of it. You know that
there's differences between men and
women.
women. They
women. They just
women. They just noticed
women. They just noticed that
women. They just noticed that or
something.
Oh
Oh golly.
Oh golly. All
Oh golly. All right.
Oh golly. All right. That's
Oh golly. All right. That's neutrality.
So
So from
Oh golly. All right. That's neutrality.
So from here
So from here up
Oh golly. All right. That's neutrality.
So from here up you
So from here up you can
Oh golly. All right. That's neutrality.
So from here up you can have
So from here up you can have an
alignment
alignment because
alignment because willingness
alignment because willingness is
alignment because willingness is you
have
have the
alignment because willingness is you
have the willing
have the willing to
alignment because willingness is you
have the willing to make
have the willing to make it
alignment because willingness is you
have the willing to make it look
have the willing to make it look uh
work.
work. Willingness
work. Willingness is
work. Willingness is the
work. Willingness is the willingness
work. Willingness is the willingness to
overlook
overlook where
work. Willingness is the willingness to
overlook where other
overlook where other people
work. Willingness is the willingness to
overlook where other people are
karmically.
karmically. They're
karmically. They're just
karmically. They're just where
karmically. They're just where they
karmically. They're just where they are
right
right now.
karmically. They're just where they are
right now. So
right now. So acceptance
karmically. They're just where they are
right now. So acceptance is
right now. So acceptance is saying,
karmically. They're just where they are
right now. So acceptance is saying, "Oh,
well
well that's
well that's where
well that's where they
well that's where they are
well that's where they are right
well that's where they are right now."
Okay,
Okay, that's
well that's where they are right now."
Okay, that's where
Okay, that's where they
well that's where they are right now."
Okay, that's where they are
Okay, that's where they are right
well that's where they are right now."
Okay, that's where they are right now.
Chimpanzees
Chimpanzees are
Chimpanzees are chimpanzees
Chimpanzees are chimpanzees because
that's
that's where
Chimpanzees are chimpanzees because
that's where they
that's where they are
Chimpanzees are chimpanzees because
that's where they are in
that's where they are in evolution.
Chimpanzees are chimpanzees because
that's where they are in evolution. I
don't
don't have
don't have to
don't have to call
don't have to call them
don't have to call them bad.
I
I don't
don't have to call them bad.
I don't have
I don't have to
don't have to call them bad.
I don't have to beat
I don't have to beat up
don't have to call them bad.
I don't have to beat up gem
I don't have to beat up gem chimpanzees
for
for beating
for beating up
for beating up people.
We
We do
for beating up people.
We do that,
We do that, don't
for beating up people.
We do that, don't we?
We do that, don't we? We
for beating up people.
We do that, don't we? We beat
We do that, don't we? We beat up
for beating up people.
We do that, don't we? We beat up people
for
for beating
for beating up
for beating up people.
Okay,
Okay, so
for beating up people.
Okay, so willingness
Okay, so willingness is
here.
here. You
here. You got
here. You got the
here. You got the courage.
here. You got the courage. So
here. You got the courage. So here's
here. You got the courage. So here's the
addictions.
addictions. The
here. You got the courage. So here's the
addictions. The addictions
addictions. The addictions are
here. You got the courage. So here's the
addictions. The addictions are you're
hooked
hooked on
hooked on the
hooked on the juice
hooked on the juice of
hooked on the juice of anger,
hooked on the juice of anger, being
right,
right, craving
hooked on the juice of anger, being
right, craving this,
right, craving this, wanting
hooked on the juice of anger, being
right, craving this, wanting this.
right, craving this, wanting this. And
you
you see
you see why
you see why it's
you see why it's so
you see why it's so frantic.
you see why it's so frantic. It's
you see why it's so frantic. It's so
frantic
frantic because
you see why it's so frantic. It's so
frantic because throughout
frantic because throughout all
you see why it's so frantic. It's so
frantic because throughout all of
evolutionary
evolutionary time,
evolutionary time, unless
evolutionary time, unless the
evolutionary time, unless the ego,
unless
animal
animal life
animal life got
animal life got what
animal life got what it
animal life got what it wanted,
animal life got what it wanted, it
animal life got what it wanted, it died.
That's
That's why
animal life got what it wanted, it died.
That's why your
That's why your ego
animal life got what it wanted, it died.
That's why your ego is
That's why your ego is so
animal life got what it wanted, it died.
That's why your ego is so frantic.
That's why your ego is so frantic. Why
it
it clings
it clings with
it clings with such
it clings with such tenacity?
it clings with such tenacity? Because
it clings with such tenacity? Because to
the
the ego,
it clings with such tenacity? Because to
the ego, to
the ego, to not
it clings with such tenacity? Because to
the ego, to not get
the ego, to not get the
it clings with such tenacity? Because to
the ego, to not get the new
the ego, to not get the new couch,
it clings with such tenacity? Because to
the ego, to not get the new couch, you
will
will die.
will die. Now
will die. Now that
will die. Now that sounds
will die. Now that sounds ridiculous.
But
But the
will die. Now that sounds ridiculous.
But the ego
But the ego only
will die. Now that sounds ridiculous.
But the ego only hears
But the ego only hears one
will die. Now that sounds ridiculous.
But the ego only hears one thing.
But the ego only hears one thing. You
either
either get
either get or
either get or you
either get or you don't
either get or you don't get
either get or you don't get what
either get or you don't get what you
crave,
crave, want,
either get or you don't get what you
crave, want, and
crave, want, and need.
either get or you don't get what you
crave, want, and need. And
crave, want, and need. And then
either get or you don't get what you
crave, want, and need. And then how
crave, want, and need. And then how you
program
program that
program that want
program that want is
program that want is etc.
program that want is etc. uh
program that want is etc. uh you
program that want is etc. uh you know
program that want is etc. uh you know is
irrelevant.
It
It only
It only has
It only has one
It only has one program.
It only has one program. I
It only has one program. I want
It only has one program. I want it.
It only has one program. I want it. If
It only has one program. I want it. If I
want
want it,
It only has one program. I want it. If I
want it, I
want it, I have
It only has one program. I want it. If I
want it, I have to
want it, I have to have
It only has one program. I want it. If I
want it, I have to have it.
want it, I have to have it. I
It only has one program. I want it. If I
want it, I have to have it. I need
want it, I have to have it. I need it.
And
And if
And if I
And if I don't,
And if I don't, I'll
And if I don't, I'll get
And if I don't, I'll get frenetic,
And if I don't, I'll get frenetic, go
into
into a
And if I don't, I'll get frenetic, go
into a panic
into a panic because
And if I don't, I'll get frenetic, go
into a panic because I
into a panic because I will
And if I don't, I'll get frenetic, go
into a panic because I will die.
into a panic because I will die. The
And if I don't, I'll get frenetic, go
into a panic because I will die. The ego
is
is right.
is right. If
is right. If it
is right. If it doesn't
is right. If it doesn't get
is right. If it doesn't get what
is right. If it doesn't get what it
wants,
wants, it
is right. If it doesn't get what it
wants, it dies.
So,
So, you
So, you have
So, you have to
So, you have to sneak
So, you have to sneak carefully
So, you have to sneak carefully around
the
the ego.
Why
Why are
Why are you
Why are you forgiving
Why are you forgiving that
Why are you forgiving that guy?
Why are you forgiving that guy? He
Why are you forgiving that guy? He don't
deserve
deserve it.
Why are you forgiving that guy? He don't
deserve it. I'm
deserve it. I'm not
Why are you forgiving that guy? He don't
deserve it. I'm not really
deserve it. I'm not really forgiving
him.
him. I'm
him. I'm just
him. I'm just I'm
him. I'm just I'm just
him. I'm just I'm just being
him. I'm just I'm just being trying
him. I'm just I'm just being trying to
avoid
avoid trouble,
him. I'm just I'm just being trying to
avoid trouble, you
avoid trouble, you know.
him. I'm just I'm just being trying to
avoid trouble, you know. Oh,
avoid trouble, you know. Oh, okay.
him. I'm just I'm just being trying to
avoid trouble, you know. Oh, okay. Well,
you're
you're not
you're not forgiving
you're not forgiving him.
you're not forgiving him. I
you're not forgiving him. I don't
you're not forgiving him. I don't catch
you
you forgiving
you're not forgiving him. I don't catch
you forgiving this
you forgiving this son
you're not forgiving him. I don't catch
you forgiving this son of
you forgiving this son of a
you're not forgiving him. I don't catch
you forgiving this son of a He
deserves
deserves it.
God
God did
deserves it.
God did what
God did what he
deserves it.
God did what he did.
God did what he did. Should
deserves it.
God did what he did. Should fry
God did what he did. Should fry and
deserves it.
God did what he did. Should fry and you
know
know where.
All right.
All right. So,
know where.
All right. So, to
All right. So, to tell
know where.
All right. So, to tell the
All right. So, to tell the truth
know where.
All right. So, to tell the truth then
down
down here,
down here, you
down here, you can't
down here, you can't believe
down here, you can't believe people
down here, you can't believe people are
addicted
addicted to
down here, you can't believe people are
addicted to this,
addicted to this, but
down here, you can't believe people are
addicted to this, but they
addicted to this, but they are.
down here, you can't believe people are
addicted to this, but they are. They
are.
are. I
are. I noticed
are. I noticed that
are. I noticed that when
are. I noticed that when I
are. I noticed that when I was
are. I noticed that when I was in
are. I noticed that when I was in the
Navy
Navy in
are. I noticed that when I was in the
Navy in World War
Navy in World War II,
are. I noticed that when I was in the
Navy in World War II, uh,
Navy in World War II, uh, we
are. I noticed that when I was in the
Navy in World War II, uh, we used
Navy in World War II, uh, we used to
shoot
shoot craps
shoot craps for
shoot craps for mutant.
And
And I
shoot craps for mutant.
And I would
And I would notice
shoot craps for mutant.
And I would notice that
And I would notice that the
shoot craps for mutant.
And I would notice that the same
And I would notice that the same guys
always
always lost.
I
I would
always lost.
I would also
I would also notice
always lost.
I would also notice that
I would also notice that the
always lost.
I would also notice that the same
I would also notice that the same guys
were
were always
were always broke
were always broke by
were always broke by Friday
were always broke by Friday after
payday.
payday. Same
were always broke by Friday after
payday. Same guys
payday. Same guys always.
It
It was
It was the
It was the It
It was the It was
It was the It was them.
It was the It was them. It
It was the It was them. It was
It was the It was them. It was them.
Huh?
Huh? They're
It was the It was them. It was them.
Huh? They're hooked
Huh? They're hooked in
It was the It was them. It was them.
Huh? They're hooked in a
Huh? They're hooked in a certain
behavior.
the
the chronic
behavior.
the chronic loser.
Shame
Shame and
Shame and guilt.
Shame and guilt. People
Shame and guilt. People become
Shame and guilt. People become addicted
to
to guilt
out
out there.
out there. There's
out there. There's guilt
out there. There's guilt mongers.
Guiltmongers
Guiltmongers live
out there. There's guilt mongers.
Guiltmongers live off
Guiltmongers live off your
out there. There's guilt mongers.
Guiltmongers live off your guilt
Guiltmongers live off your guilt and
they
they love
they love creating
they love creating guilt.
You
You went
they love creating guilt.
You went and
You went and forgot
they love creating guilt.
You went and forgot it
You went and forgot it again.
they love creating guilt.
You went and forgot it again. Stupid.
Create
Create guilt.
Create guilt. So
Create guilt. So this
Create guilt. So this is
Create guilt. So this is controlling
people
people with
Create guilt. So this is controlling
people with guilt
people with guilt and
Create guilt. So this is controlling
people with guilt and shame.
people with guilt and shame. You
Create guilt. So this is controlling
people with guilt and shame. You control
people
people with
people with shame.
people with shame. You
people with shame. You control.
people with shame. You control. So
people with shame. You control. So the
ego
ego gets
people with shame. You control. So the
ego gets a
ego gets a great
people with shame. You control. So the
ego gets a great deal
ego gets a great deal of
people with shame. You control. So the
ego gets a great deal of juice
ego gets a great deal of juice out
people with shame. You control. So the
ego gets a great deal of juice out of
controlling.
controlling. Controlling.
controlling. Controlling. In
controlling. Controlling. In fact,
controlling. Controlling. In fact, it
thinks
thinks if
controlling. Controlling. In fact, it
thinks if you
thinks if you don't
controlling. Controlling. In fact, it
thinks if you don't control,
thinks if you don't control, I
controlling. Controlling. In fact, it
thinks if you don't control, I won't
survive.
survive. I
survive. I will
survive. I will die.
survive. I will die. I
survive. I will die. I want
survive. I will die. I want you
survive. I will die. I want you to
survive. I will die. I want you to see
that
that the
survive. I will die. I want you to see
that the drivenness,
that the drivenness, the
survive. I will die. I want you to see
that the drivenness, the drivenness
having
having nothing
having nothing to
having nothing to do
having nothing to do with
having nothing to do with rationality.
The
The drivenness,
having nothing to do with rationality.
The drivenness, the
The drivenness, the must-have,
having nothing to do with rationality.
The drivenness, the must-have, the
frantic
energy
energy behind
frantic
energy behind the
energy behind the ego.
That's
That's why
That's why he
That's why he have
That's why he have trouble
That's why he have trouble transcending
it.
It
It has
It has a
It has a tenacious.
It's
It's convinced
It has a tenacious.
It's convinced that
It's convinced that if
It has a tenacious.
It's convinced that if it
It's convinced that if it doesn't
It has a tenacious.
It's convinced that if it doesn't get
what
what it
what it wants,
what it wants, it
what it wants, it will
what it wants, it will die.
Consequently,
Consequently, it's
what it wants, it will die.
Consequently, it's willing
Consequently, it's willing to
what it wants, it will die.
Consequently, it's willing to sell
Consequently, it's willing to sell out
even
even its
even its soul.
even its soul. Below
even its soul. Below 200
even its soul. Below 200 is
even its soul. Below 200 is willing
even its soul. Below 200 is willing to
sell
sell out
even its soul. Below 200 is willing to
sell out its
sell out its soul
even its soul. Below 200 is willing to
sell out its soul for
sell out its soul for gain
even its soul. Below 200 is willing to
sell out its soul for gain or
sell out its soul for gain or sell
even its soul. Below 200 is willing to
sell out its soul for gain or sell out
yours
yours if
yours if he
yours if he can
yours if he can get
yours if he can get you
yours if he can get you to
yours if he can get you to go
yours if he can get you to go along
yours if he can get you to go along for
the
the ride.
All right.
All right. So
people
people get
All right. So
people get hooked
people get hooked on
All right. So
people get hooked on guilt,
the
the guilty
the guilty lifestyle.
It's
It's the
the guilty lifestyle.
It's the downside
It's the downside of
the guilty lifestyle.
It's the downside of religion,
It's the downside of religion, getting
people
people hooked
people hooked on
people hooked on guilt.
people hooked on guilt. There's
people hooked on guilt. There's many
reasons
reasons to
people hooked on guilt. There's many
reasons to give
reasons to give up
people hooked on guilt. There's many
reasons to give up sin.
reasons to give up sin. Guilt
people hooked on guilt. There's many
reasons to give up sin. Guilt is
reasons to give up sin. Guilt is far
probably
probably the
probably the poorest
probably the poorest one.
It's
It's probably
probably the poorest one.
It's probably the
It's probably the poorest
probably the poorest one.
It's probably the poorest one.
Guilt
Guilt should
Guilt should only
Guilt should only be
Guilt should only be a
Guilt should only be a signal
Guilt should only be a signal that
Guilt should only be a signal that you
got
got to
Guilt should only be a signal that you
got to look
got to look at
Guilt should only be a signal that you
got to look at that.
got to look at that. It
Guilt should only be a signal that you
got to look at that. It shouldn't
got to look at that. It shouldn't be
Guilt should only be a signal that you
got to look at that. It shouldn't be a
hangout
hangout place
hangout place where
hangout place where you
hangout place where you wallow.
Wallow
Wallow in
hangout place where you wallow.
Wallow in guilt.
Wallow in guilt. Huh?
That
That is
That is what
That is what I
That is what I call
That is what I call the
That is what I call the Gothic
That is what I call the Gothic side
That is what I call the Gothic side of
Christianity.
The
The downside,
The downside, wallowing
The downside, wallowing in
The downside, wallowing in guilt,
penance,
etc.
etc. So,
etc. So, Protestantism
etc. So, Protestantism was
etc. So, Protestantism was really
etc. So, Protestantism was really in
etc. So, Protestantism was really in a
way
way a
etc. So, Protestantism was really in a
way a response
to
to the
to the over
to the over Gothicness
to the over Gothicness of
to the over Gothicness of of
to the over Gothicness of of the
to the over Gothicness of of the Roman
church.
And
And then
And then the
And then the more
And then the more recent
And then the more recent churches
And then the more recent churches such
as
as unity
And then the more recent churches such
as unity and
as unity and religious
And then the more recent churches such
as unity and religious science
as unity and religious science and
And then the more recent churches such
as unity and religious science and all
emerged
emerged as
uh
as
as a
as a reaction
as a reaction to
as a reaction to the
as a reaction to the downside
as a reaction to the downside of
Protestantism.
Uh
Uh hating
Uh hating sin,
Uh hating sin, you
Uh hating sin, you know,
Uh hating sin, you know, hating
Uh hating sin, you know, hating sin.
Well,
Well, hate
Uh hating sin, you know, hating sin.
Well, hate is
Well, hate is hate,
Uh hating sin, you know, hating sin.
Well, hate is hate, folks.
Well, hate is hate, folks. Whether
Uh hating sin, you know, hating sin.
Well, hate is hate, folks. Whether you
hate
hate sin
hate sin or
hate sin or hate,
hate sin or hate, whatever
hate sin or hate, whatever you
hate sin or hate, whatever you hate,
hate
hate is
hate sin or hate, whatever you hate,
hate is hate.
hate is hate. So,
hate sin or hate, whatever you hate,
hate is hate. So, uh,
hate is hate. So, uh, guilt
hate sin or hate, whatever you hate,
hate is hate. So, uh, guilt and
hate is hate. So, uh, guilt and sin
hate sin or hate, whatever you hate,
hate is hate. So, uh, guilt and sin then
have
have not
have not had
have not had I
have not had I I
have not had I I I
have not had I I I don't
have not had I I I don't think
have not had I I I don't think much
have not had I I I don't think much of
have not had I I I don't think much of a
very
very good
have not had I I I don't think much of a
very good consequence
very good consequence with
have not had I I I don't think much of a
very good consequence with human
very good consequence with human nature
and
and the
and the world
and the world becomes
and the world becomes progressively
and the world becomes progressively more
secular.
Yeah,
Yeah, I
Yeah, I should
Yeah, I should think
Yeah, I should think it
Yeah, I should think it would.
Yeah, I should think it would. If
Yeah, I should think it would. If your
choice
choice is
Yeah, I should think it would. If your
choice is penance
choice is penance and
Yeah, I should think it would. If your
choice is penance and guilt
over
over the
over the pleasures
over the pleasures of
over the pleasures of the
over the pleasures of the ego,
over the pleasures of the ego, which
would
would appeal
over the pleasures of the ego, which
would appeal to
would appeal to you?
over the pleasures of the ego, which
would appeal to you? Yeah,
it's
it's true.
it's true. Classic
it's true. Classic religions
it's true. Classic religions also
it's true. Classic religions also had
their
their mechanism
it's true. Classic religions also had
their mechanism for
their mechanism for undoing
it's true. Classic religions also had
their mechanism for undoing forgiveness
and
and salvation
and salvation and
and salvation and confession
and salvation and confession etc.
and salvation and confession etc. It
and salvation and confession etc. It had
its
its mechanisms.
and salvation and confession etc. It had
its mechanisms. Okay.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So these
All right. So these levels
All right. So these levels here
All right. So these levels here then
All right. So these levels here then you
would
would say
All right. So these levels here then you
would say how
would say how could
All right. So these levels here then you
would say how could people
would say how could people desire
All right. So these levels here then you
would say how could people desire them
or
or get
or get stuck
or get stuck in
or get stuck in them?
or get stuck in them? And
or get stuck in them? And it's
or get stuck in them? And it's because
they
they all
or get stuck in them? And it's because
they all have
they all have the
or get stuck in them? And it's because
they all have the same
they all have the same payoff.
or get stuck in them? And it's because
they all have the same payoff. All
they all have the same payoff. All below
200.
Scorn,
Scorn, hate,
200.
Scorn, hate, craving,
Scorn, hate, craving, anxiety,
200.
Scorn, hate, craving, anxiety, fear,
despair,
despair, they
despair, they all
despair, they all are
despair, they all are have
despair, they all are have a
despair, they all are have a big
despair, they all are have a big payoff.
And
And the
despair, they all are have a big payoff.
And the these
And the these this
despair, they all are have a big payoff.
And the these this is
And the these this is what
despair, they all are have a big payoff.
And the these this is what is
And the these this is what is going
despair, they all are have a big payoff.
And the these this is what is going on
in
in the
in the consciousness
in the consciousness level.
in the consciousness level. So
in the consciousness level. So whatever
you're
you're caught
in the consciousness level. So whatever
you're caught on
you're caught on in
in the consciousness level. So whatever
you're caught on in working
you're caught on in working through
in the consciousness level. So whatever
you're caught on in working through your
spiritual
spiritual work,
spiritual work, whether
spiritual work, whether it's
spiritual work, whether it's grief
spiritual work, whether it's grief or
loss
loss of
spiritual work, whether it's grief or
loss of somebody
loss of somebody or
spiritual work, whether it's grief or
loss of somebody or a
loss of somebody or a failure
spiritual work, whether it's grief or
loss of somebody or a failure of
loss of somebody or a failure of a
spiritual work, whether it's grief or
loss of somebody or a failure of a gain
or
or guilt
or guilt or
or guilt or anxiety,
or guilt or anxiety, uh
it
it there's
or guilt or anxiety, uh
it there's always
it there's always some
or guilt or anxiety, uh
it there's always some energy
it there's always some energy payoff
you're
you're getting
you're getting out
you're getting out of
you're getting out of it.
you're getting out of it. So
you're getting out of it. So forget
you're getting out of it. So forget what
the
the matter
you're getting out of it. So forget what
the matter of
the matter of it
you're getting out of it. So forget what
the matter of it is
the matter of it is and
you're getting out of it. So forget what
the matter of it is and notice
the matter of it is and notice that
you're getting out of it. So forget what
the matter of it is and notice that it
always
always has
always has the
always has the same
always has the same payoff.
always has the same payoff. Now
always has the same payoff. Now all
always has the same payoff. Now all you
have
have to
always has the same payoff. Now all you
have to do
have to do is
always has the same payoff. Now all you
have to do is become
have to do is become unaddicted
always has the same payoff. Now all you
have to do is become unaddicted to
have to do is become unaddicted to the
ne
ne to
ne to the
ne to the energy
ne to the energy of
ne to the energy of the
ne to the energy of the ego.
ne to the energy of the ego. The
ne to the energy of the ego. The payoff.
How
How do
ne to the energy of the ego. The payoff.
How do you
How do you get
ne to the energy of the ego. The payoff.
How do you get un
How do you get un how
ne to the energy of the ego. The payoff.
How do you get un how do
How do you get un how do you
ne to the energy of the ego. The payoff.
How do you get un how do you extinguish
it
in
in and
it
in and of
in and of itself?
it
in and of itself? The
in and of itself? The ego
it
in and of itself? The ego can't.
in and of itself? The ego can't. You
can't.
And
And there's
can't.
And there's no
And there's no no
can't.
And there's no no point
And there's no no point in
can't.
And there's no no point in beating
yourself
yourself up
yourself up for
yourself up for not
yourself up for not being
yourself up for not being able
yourself up for not being able to
yourself up for not being able to to
transcend
transcend it
yourself up for not being able to to
transcend it because
transcend it because you
yourself up for not being able to to
transcend it because you can't.
transcend it because you can't. The
yourself up for not being able to to
transcend it because you can't. The ego
in
in and
in and of
in and of itself
in and of itself does
in and of itself does not
in and of itself does not have
sufficient
sufficient power
in and of itself does not have
sufficient power to
sufficient power to transcend
in and of itself does not have
sufficient power to transcend its
sufficient power to transcend its own
addiction.
It
It takes
addiction.
It takes the
It takes the energy
addiction.
It takes the energy of
It takes the energy of the
addiction.
It takes the energy of the spiritual
will.
will. Only
will. Only one
will. Only one human
will. Only one human mechanism
will. Only one human mechanism has
will. Only one human mechanism has the
power
power to
will. Only one human mechanism has the
power to overcome
power to overcome addiction
will. Only one human mechanism has the
power to overcome addiction to
power to overcome addiction to the
will. Only one human mechanism has the
power to overcome addiction to the ego
and
and that's
and that's the
and that's the will.
The
The spiritual
and that's the will.
The spiritual will
The spiritual will calibrates
and that's the will.
The spiritual will calibrates at
I
I have
I have permission
I have permission over
I have permission over 850
I have permission over 850 851
I have permission over 850 851 860.
Spiritual
Spiritual will
I have permission over 850 851 860.
Spiritual will calibrates
Spiritual will calibrates at
I have permission over 850 851 860.
Spiritual will calibrates at 850.
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, you
All right. So, you say,
All right. So, you say, "Well,
All right. So, you say, "Well, I
All right. So, you say, "Well, I should
really
really give
All right. So, you say, "Well, I should
really give up
really give up booze
All right. So, you say, "Well, I should
really give up booze because
really give up booze because it's
costing
costing me
costing me my
costing me my health
costing me my health and
costing me my health and my
costing me my health and my wife's
costing me my health and my wife's left
me
me and
costing me my health and my wife's left
me and I've
me and I've been
costing me my health and my wife's left
me and I've been fired
me and I've been fired and
costing me my health and my wife's left
me and I've been fired and then
me and I've been fired and then I've
been
been in
been in jail
been in jail 14
been in jail 14 times
and
and by
been in jail 14 times
and by God,
and by God, I'm
been in jail 14 times
and by God, I'm going
and by God, I'm going to
been in jail 14 times
and by God, I'm going to give
and by God, I'm going to give it
been in jail 14 times
and by God, I'm going to give it up."
That's
That's reason
That's reason at
That's reason at 400.
Reason
Reason at
That's reason at 400.
Reason at 400
is
is trivial.
Addiction's
Addiction's been
is trivial.
Addiction's been going
Addiction's been going on
is trivial.
Addiction's been going on for
Addiction's been going on for billions
of
of years.
of years. What's
of years. What's your
of years. What's your lousy
of years. What's your lousy little
reason
reason at
of years. What's your lousy little
reason at 400
reason at 400 going
of years. What's your lousy little
reason at 400 going to
reason at 400 going to do?
A
A pipsqueak.
A pipsqueak. The
A pipsqueak. The eagle
A pipsqueak. The eagle laughs
A pipsqueak. The eagle laughs at
A pipsqueak. The eagle laughs at reason.
Haha.
He
He took
He took another
He took another pledge.
He took another pledge. Eh.
He took another pledge. Eh. Huh?
I'll
I'll never
He took another pledge. Eh. Huh?
I'll never do
I'll never do it
He took another pledge. Eh. Huh?
I'll never do it again,
I'll never do it again, sweetheart.
You
You know,
You know, wife
You know, wife abuse.
You know, wife abuse. I'll
You know, wife abuse. I'll never
You know, wife abuse. I'll never do
You know, wife abuse. I'll never do it
again.
You
You know,
You know, once
You know, once somebody
You know, once somebody hits
You know, once somebody hits you,
You know, once somebody hits you, watch
it.
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, means
All right. So, means they've
All right. So, means they've broken
All right. So, means they've broken out
of
of the
All right. So, means they've broken out
of the barriers.
Therefore,
Therefore, it
Therefore, it takes
Therefore, it takes the
Therefore, it takes the spiritual
Therefore, it takes the spiritual will
at
at 850.
The
The spiritual
The spiritual will
The spiritual will is
The spiritual will is nonlinear.
The spiritual will is nonlinear. See,
reason
reason is
The spiritual will is nonlinear. See,
reason is linear.
reason is linear. These
The spiritual will is nonlinear. See,
reason is linear. These things
reason is linear. These things are
The spiritual will is nonlinear. See,
reason is linear. These things are all
linear.
linear. Reason
linear. Reason is
linear. Reason is linear.
linear. Reason is linear. Well,
linear. Reason is linear. Well, I
linear. Reason is linear. Well, I should
give
give it
linear. Reason is linear. Well, I should
give it up
give it up cuz
linear. Reason is linear. Well, I should
give it up cuz I'm
give it up cuz I'm gaining
linear. Reason is linear. Well, I should
give it up cuz I'm gaining too
give it up cuz I'm gaining too much
weight
weight and
weight and the
weight and the the
weight and the the boss
weight and the the boss threatened
weight and the the boss threatened me,
etc.,
etc., and
weight and the the boss threatened me,
etc., and they
etc., and they cancel
weight and the the boss threatened me,
etc., and they cancel my
etc., and they cancel my insurance.
That's
That's reason.
That's reason. That's
That's reason. That's a
That's reason. That's a weaky.
That's reason. That's a weaky. Nobody
gives
gives up
That's reason. That's a weaky. Nobody
gives up what
gives up what they're
That's reason. That's a weaky. Nobody
gives up what they're addicted
gives up what they're addicted to
That's reason. That's a weaky. Nobody
gives up what they're addicted to for
that.
that. I've
that. I've treated
that. I've treated 10,000
that. I've treated 10,000 10,000
addicted
addicted people.
that. I've treated 10,000 10,000
addicted people. 10,000.
And
And uh
And uh I
And uh I can
And uh I can remember
And uh I can remember they've
And uh I can remember they've been
And uh I can remember they've been in
prison
prison five
And uh I can remember they've been in
prison five or
prison five or six
And uh I can remember they've been in
prison five or six times.
prison five or six times. They
And uh I can remember they've been in
prison five or six times. They told
prison five or six times. They told them
one
one more
one more time
one more time and
one more time and you're
one more time and you're there
one more time and you're there forever.
And
And the
one more time and you're there forever.
And the day
And the day they
one more time and you're there forever.
And the day they get
And the day they get out,
one more time and you're there forever.
And the day they get out, they're
And the day they get out, they're drunk.
The
The very
The very day.
The very day. Yeah.
The very day. Yeah. So
The very day. Yeah. So that
The very day. Yeah. So that craving
The very day. Yeah. So that craving this
cannot
cannot become
The very day. Yeah. So that craving this
cannot become overcome
cannot become overcome by
The very day. Yeah. So that craving this
cannot become overcome by reason.
cannot become overcome by reason. That's
the
the basis
the basis of
the basis of the
the basis of the faith-based
the basis of the faith-based uh
faith-based
faith-based uh
the basis of the faith-based uh
faith-based uh recovery.
faith-based uh recovery. A
the basis of the faith-based uh
faith-based uh recovery. A a
faith-based uh recovery. A a is
the basis of the faith-based uh
faith-based uh recovery. A a is the
faith-based uh recovery. A a is the is
the
the is
the is the
the is the model
the is the model of
the is the model of it.
the is the model of it. We
the is the model of it. We admitted
the is the model of it. We admitted we
were
were powerless.
the is the model of it. We admitted we
were powerless. We
were powerless. We admitted
the is the model of it. We admitted we
were powerless. We admitted we
were powerless. We admitted we were
powerless.
powerless. And
powerless. And without
powerless. And without God's
powerless. And without God's help,
without
without God's
powerless. And without God's help,
without God's help,
without God's help, we
powerless. And without God's help,
without God's help, we were
without God's help, we were a
powerless. And without God's help,
without God's help, we were a goner.
That's
That's a
That's a statement
That's a statement of
That's a statement of truth
That's a statement of truth the
That's a statement of truth the minute
you
you say
That's a statement of truth the minute
you say that.
you say that. So
That's a statement of truth the minute
you say that. So if
you say that. So if you
That's a statement of truth the minute
you say that. So if you say
you say that. So if you say to
That's a statement of truth the minute
you say that. So if you say to yourself,
I'm
I'm powerless
I'm powerless over
I'm powerless over envy,
I'm powerless over envy, hostility,
desire,
uh
uh getting
uh getting hooked
uh getting hooked on
uh getting hooked on excitement,
gambling,
gambling, whatever
uh getting hooked on excitement,
gambling, whatever you're
gambling, whatever you're hooked
uh getting hooked on excitement,
gambling, whatever you're hooked on.
gambling, whatever you're hooked on. And
without
without God's
without God's help,
without God's help, it's
without God's help, it's hopeless.
without God's help, it's hopeless. And
now
now that's
without God's help, it's hopeless. And
now that's a
now that's a statement
without God's help, it's hopeless. And
now that's a statement of
now that's a statement of truth.
without God's help, it's hopeless. And
now that's a statement of truth. You
just
just said
just said the
just said the truth.
just said the truth. The
just said the truth. The minute
just said the truth. The minute you
just said the truth. The minute you said
the
the truth,
just said the truth. The minute you said
the truth, you're
the truth, you're already
just said the truth. The minute you said
the truth, you're already over
the truth, you're already over 200.
Without
Without God's
Without God's help,
Without God's help, I
Without God's help, I cannot
Without God's help, I cannot overcome
the
the endless
Without God's help, I cannot overcome
the endless wantingness
the endless wantingness and
Without God's help, I cannot overcome
the endless wantingness and desire
the endless wantingness and desire for
money
money and
money and success
money and success and
money and success and worldly
money and success and worldly fame,
money and success and worldly fame, and
I'm
I'm worth
money and success and worldly fame, and
I'm worth millions
I'm worth millions now,
money and success and worldly fame, and
I'm worth millions now, and
I'm worth millions now, and I'm
money and success and worldly fame, and
I'm worth millions now, and I'm plotting
how
how I'm
how I'm going
how I'm going to
how I'm going to destroy
how I'm going to destroy that
how I'm going to destroy that company
and
and get
how I'm going to destroy that company
and get their
and get their millions.
You're
You're like
You're like hooked
You're like hooked on
You're like hooked on it,
You're like hooked on it, you
You're like hooked on it, you see.
All
All right.
Without
Without God's
Without God's help.
Without God's help. So
Without God's help. So when
Without God's help. So when we
Without God's help. So when we turn
Without God's help. So when we turn to
divinity,
that's
that's humility.
that's humility. That's
that's humility. That's surrender.
that's humility. That's surrender. And
it's
it's accepting
that's humility. That's surrender. And
it's accepting truth.
it's accepting truth. The
that's humility. That's surrender. And
it's accepting truth. The truth
it's accepting truth. The truth is
without
without divine
without divine intervention,
without divine intervention, frankly,
your
your chances
without divine intervention, frankly,
your chances of
your chances of transcending
without divine intervention, frankly,
your chances of transcending anything
your chances of transcending anything in
this
this lifetime
this lifetime are
this lifetime are slim.
How
How many
this lifetime are slim.
How many saints
How many saints do
this lifetime are slim.
How many saints do you
How many saints do you know?
Pope
Pope at
Pope at 570
Pope at 570 was
Pope at 570 was saintly.
Pope at 570 was saintly. Yeah.
The
The head
Pope at 570 was saintly. Yeah.
The head of
The head of the
Pope at 570 was saintly. Yeah.
The head of the Tibetan
Buddhist
Buddhist uh
>> Dal
>> Dal Lama
>> Dali
>> Dali Lama
>> Dali Lama was
>> Dali Lama was 570.
>> Dali Lama was 570. The
>> Dali Lama was 570. The Pope
>> Dali Lama was 570. The Pope was
>> Dali Lama was 570. The Pope was at
>> Dali Lama was 570. The Pope was at 570.
Interestingly,
Interestingly, saintthood
>> Dali Lama was 570. The Pope was at 570.
Interestingly, saintthood is
Interestingly, saintthood is at
>> Dali Lama was 570. The Pope was at 570.
Interestingly, saintthood is at 570.
Father
Father Peio
Father Peio is
Father Peio is at
Father Peio is at 570.
Father Peio is at 570. And
Father Peio is at 570. And at
Father Peio is at 570. And at 570
Father Peio is at 570. And at 570 the
miraculous
miraculous begins
Father Peio is at 570. And at 570 the
miraculous begins to
miraculous begins to happen
Father Peio is at 570. And at 570 the
miraculous begins to happen because
miraculous begins to happen because the
condundalini
condundalini energy
condundalini energy now
condundalini energy now begins
condundalini energy now begins to
condundalini energy now begins to to
move
move out
condundalini energy now begins to to
move out into
move out into the
condundalini energy now begins to to
move out into the world
move out into the world and
condundalini energy now begins to to
move out into the world and uh
move out into the world and uh so
condundalini energy now begins to to
move out into the world and uh so the
miraculous
miraculous becomes
miraculous becomes possible
and
and uh
miraculous becomes possible
and uh then
and uh then it
miraculous becomes possible
and uh then it becomes
and uh then it becomes continuous
and
and then
and then eventually
and then eventually it's
and then eventually it's it's
and then eventually it's it's what
and then eventually it's it's what life
is
is one
and then eventually it's it's what life
is one endless
is one endless miracle.
How
How we
How we get
How we get from
How we get from one
How we get from one moment
How we get from one moment to
How we get from one moment to the
How we get from one moment to the next
is
is actually
How we get from one moment to the next
is actually a
is actually a miracle
How we get from one moment to the next
is actually a miracle isn't.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So here's
All right. So here's how
All right. So here's how relationship
works
works then
All right. So here's how relationship
works then with
works then with alignment.
All right. So here's how relationship
works then with alignment. Here
works then with alignment. Here you
don't
don't have
don't have alignment.
don't have alignment. Here
don't have alignment. Here you
don't have alignment. Here you have
mutual
mutual self-interest.
Uh
Uh but
Uh but here
Uh but here now
Uh but here now from
Uh but here now from courage
Uh but here now from courage to
Uh but here now from courage to tell
Uh but here now from courage to tell the
truth
truth to
Uh but here now from courage to tell the
truth to accept
truth to accept your
Uh but here now from courage to tell the
truth to accept your limitations.
truth to accept your limitations. Yeah,
I
I I
I I guess
I I guess I'm
I I guess I'm not
I I guess I'm not too
I I guess I'm not too smart
I I guess I'm not too smart at
I I guess I'm not too smart at that.
Maybe
Maybe it'd
I I guess I'm not too smart at that.
Maybe it'd be
Maybe it'd be better
I I guess I'm not too smart at that.
Maybe it'd be better if
Maybe it'd be better if you
I I guess I'm not too smart at that.
Maybe it'd be better if you took
Maybe it'd be better if you took care
I I guess I'm not too smart at that.
Maybe it'd be better if you took care of
the
the checkbook
the checkbook or
the checkbook or whatever.
the checkbook or whatever. You
the checkbook or whatever. You know
the checkbook or whatever. You know what
I
I mean?
the checkbook or whatever. You know what
I mean? It
I mean? It isn't
the checkbook or whatever. You know what
I mean? It isn't my
I mean? It isn't my forte.
the checkbook or whatever. You know what
I mean? It isn't my forte. So
I mean? It isn't my forte. So you
the checkbook or whatever. You know what
I mean? It isn't my forte. So you each
sort
sort of
sort of divide
sort of divide up.
sort of divide up. Uh
sort of divide up. Uh one
sort of divide up. Uh one person's
sort of divide up. Uh one person's good
at
at this,
sort of divide up. Uh one person's good
at this, one
at this, one person's
sort of divide up. Uh one person's good
at this, one person's good.
at this, one person's good. So,
sort of divide up. Uh one person's good
at this, one person's good. So, we're
not
not just
not just talking
not just talking about
not just talking about men,
not just talking about men, women.
not just talking about men, women. We're
talking
talking about
not just talking about men, women. We're
talking about all
talking about all relationship
not just talking about men, women. We're
talking about all relationship uh
talking about all relationship uh on
your
your job,
your job, at
your job, at work,
your job, at work, with
your job, at work, with fellow
your job, at work, with fellow workers.
Uh
Uh look,
your job, at work, with fellow workers.
Uh look, you're
Uh look, you're a
your job, at work, with fellow workers.
Uh look, you're a better
Uh look, you're a better framer
your job, at work, with fellow workers.
Uh look, you're a better framer than
than
than I
than I am.
than I am. I'll
than I am. I'll do
than I am. I'll do the
than I am. I'll do the finishing.
than I am. I'll do the finishing. You
than I am. I'll do the finishing. You do
the
the framing.
than I am. I'll do the finishing. You do
the framing. You
the framing. You do
than I am. I'll do the finishing. You do
the framing. You do the
the framing. You do the plastering,
than I am. I'll do the finishing. You do
the framing. You do the plastering, I'll
do
do the
do the painting.
do the painting. So,
do the painting. So, you
do the painting. So, you divide
do the painting. So, you divide up.
do the painting. So, you divide up. So,
you're
you're aligned
do the painting. So, you divide up. So,
you're aligned with
you're aligned with each
do the painting. So, you divide up. So,
you're aligned with each other
you're aligned with each other and
therefore
therefore you're
therefore you're successful.
In
In a
therefore you're successful.
In a successful
In a successful company
therefore you're successful.
In a successful company or
In a successful company or corporation
or
or enterprise
or enterprise or
or enterprise or relationship
or enterprise or relationship or
or enterprise or relationship or family,
uh
uh people
or enterprise or relationship or family,
uh people are
uh people are aligned
or enterprise or relationship or family,
uh people are aligned as
uh people are aligned as far
or enterprise or relationship or family,
uh people are aligned as far as
uh people are aligned as far as their
intention,
intention, their
intention, their intention.
intention, their intention. All right?
So
So then
intention, their intention. All right?
So then you
So then you move
intention, their intention. All right?
So then you move up.
So then you move up. First
intention, their intention. All right?
So then you move up. First you
So then you move up. First you tell
intention, their intention. All right?
So then you move up. First you tell the
truth.
truth. Now
truth. Now it's
truth. Now it's okay
truth. Now it's okay however
truth. Now it's okay however it
truth. Now it's okay however it is.
truth. Now it's okay however it is. Here
you're
you're willing
truth. Now it's okay however it is. Here
you're willing to
you're willing to face
truth. Now it's okay however it is. Here
you're willing to face things
you're willing to face things and
truth. Now it's okay however it is. Here
you're willing to face things and accept
them.
them. You're
them. You're even
them. You're even willing
them. You're even willing to
them. You're even willing to be
reasonable.
reasonable. And
them. You're even willing to be
reasonable. And then
reasonable. And then finally
them. You're even willing to be
reasonable. And then finally you
reasonable. And then finally you do
them. You're even willing to be
reasonable. And then finally you do it
out
out of
out of love.
out of love. And
out of love. And a
out of love. And a lifestyle
out of love. And a lifestyle led
out of love. And a lifestyle led this
way
way brings
out of love. And a lifestyle led this
way brings uh
way brings uh joy.
So
So relationship
So relationship then
So relationship then can
So relationship then can be
So relationship then can be the
So relationship then can be the model
So relationship then can be the model in
which
which you
So relationship then can be the model in
which you transcend
which you transcend from
So relationship then can be the model in
which you transcend from self-interest
to
to unselfishness.
Unconditional
Unconditional love.
to unselfishness.
Unconditional love. Unconditional
Unconditional love. Unconditional love
calibrates
calibrates at
calibrates at 540.
540.
540. That's
calibrates at 540.
540. That's enough
540. That's enough to
calibrates at 540.
540. That's enough to get
540. That's enough to get you
calibrates at 540.
540. That's enough to get you into
heaven.
That
That Jesus
heaven.
That Jesus uh
That Jesus uh Yes.
heaven.
That Jesus uh Yes. Jesus
That Jesus uh Yes. Jesus taught
heaven.
That Jesus uh Yes. Jesus taught that.
That Jesus uh Yes. Jesus taught that. He
says,
says, "Avoid
says, "Avoid anything
says, "Avoid anything that
says, "Avoid anything that makes
says, "Avoid anything that makes you
says, "Avoid anything that makes you go
weak
weak with
says, "Avoid anything that makes you go
weak with kinesiology."
weak with kinesiology." That's
says, "Avoid anything that makes you go
weak with kinesiology." That's what
weak with kinesiology." That's what he
said.
That's
That's what
said.
That's what he
That's what he said.
said.
That's what he said. Avoid
That's what he said. Avoid anything
makes
makes you
makes you go
makes you go weak
makes you go weak with
makes you go weak with kinesiology.
Don't
Don't curse
makes you go weak with kinesiology.
Don't curse it.
Don't curse it. Don't
makes you go weak with kinesiology.
Don't curse it. Don't hate
Don't curse it. Don't hate it.
makes you go weak with kinesiology.
Don't curse it. Don't hate it. Don't
curse
curse it
curse it and
curse it and hate
curse it and hate it.
curse it and hate it. He
curse it and hate it. He said
curse it and hate it. He said just
curse it and hate it. He said just stay
away
away from
curse it and hate it. He said just stay
away from it.
away from it. There's
curse it and hate it. He said just stay
away from it. There's no
away from it. There's no point
curse it and hate it. He said just stay
away from it. There's no point in
away from it. There's no point in hating
it.
it. He
it. He just
it. He just said
it. He just said avoid
it. He just said avoid it.
it. He just said avoid it. Avoid
it. He just said avoid it. Avoid it.
Avoid
Avoid it.
it. He just said avoid it. Avoid it.
Avoid it. Why?
Avoid it. Why? Because
it. He just said avoid it. Avoid it.
Avoid it. Why? Because that
Avoid it. Why? Because that per
otherwise
otherwise it's
otherwise it's going
otherwise it's going to
otherwise it's going to hook
otherwise it's going to hook in
otherwise it's going to hook in your
ego.
ego. You're
otherwise it's going to hook in your
ego. You're going
ego. You're going to
otherwise it's going to hook in your
ego. You're going to get
ego. You're going to get into
otherwise it's going to hook in your
ego. You're going to get into an
interaction
interaction and
interaction and lose
interaction and lose your
interaction and lose your alignment.
So
So horizontal
interaction and lose your alignment.
So horizontal alignment
So horizontal alignment then
interaction and lose your alignment.
So horizontal alignment then is
So horizontal alignment then is the
interaction and lose your alignment.
So horizontal alignment then is the way
in
in which
in which most
in which most people
in which most people especially
in which most people especially under
200 interact
200 interact with
in which most people especially under
200 interact with each
200 interact with each other.
in which most people especially under
200 interact with each other. And
vertical
vertical two
vertical two side
vertical two side by
vertical two side by side.
vertical two side by side. Now
vertical two side by side. Now they
vertical two side by side. Now they both
are
are standing
vertical two side by side. Now they both
are standing for
are standing for the
vertical two side by side. Now they both
are standing for the same
are standing for the same principles.
The
The success
The success of
The success of this
The success of this relationship.
The success of this relationship. My
happiness
happiness depends
The success of this relationship. My
happiness depends on
happiness depends on your
The success of this relationship. My
happiness depends on your happiness.
Right?
Right? First
Right? First your
Right? First your happiness
Right? First your happiness is
Right? First your happiness is just
Right? First your happiness is just your
happiness.
happiness. And
Right? First your happiness is just your
happiness. And then
happiness. And then if
Right? First your happiness is just your
happiness. And then if mama
happiness. And then if mama ain't
Right? First your happiness is just your
happiness. And then if mama ain't happy,
nobody's
nobody's happy.
I
I wonder
nobody's happy.
I wonder where
I wonder where where
nobody's happy.
I wonder where where Broccoli
I wonder where where Broccoli learned
that.
Look,
Look, Rocky's
that.
Look, Rocky's latest
Look, Rocky's latest thing
that.
Look, Rocky's latest thing is,
Look, Rocky's latest thing is, "Mama's
not
not happy.
not happy. Nobody's
not happy. Nobody's happy.
Mama,
Mama, say
not happy. Nobody's happy.
Mama, say it
Mama, say it how
not happy. Nobody's happy.
Mama, say it how he
Mama, say it how he says
not happy. Nobody's happy.
Mama, say it how he says it."
Mama, say it how he says it." How's
not happy. Nobody's happy.
Mama, say it how he says it." How's it?
>> Say
>> Say it.
>> Say it. Say
>> Say it. Say it.
>> Mama's
>> Mama's not
>> Say it. Say it.
>> Mama's not happy.
>> Mama's not happy. Nobody's
>> Say it. Say it.
>> Mama's not happy. Nobody's happy.
>> That's
>> That's right.
>> That's right. Mama's
>> That's right. Mama's not
>> That's right. Mama's not happy.
>> That's right. Mama's not happy. Nobody's
happy.
And
And his
And his other
And his other new
And his other new thing,
And his other new thing, guess
And his other new thing, guess where
And his other new thing, guess where you
learn
learn that
And his other new thing, guess where you
learn that one,
learn that one, too,
And his other new thing, guess where you
learn that one, too, is
learn that one, too, is put
And his other new thing, guess where you
learn that one, too, is put it
learn that one, too, is put it on
And his other new thing, guess where you
learn that one, too, is put it on the
credit
credit card.
I
I forget
credit card.
I forget what
I forget what time
credit card.
I forget what time we
I forget what time we take
credit card.
I forget what time we take a
I forget what time we take a break.
>> Oh
>> Oh yeah,
>> Oh yeah, put
>> Oh yeah, put it
>> Oh yeah, put it on
>> Oh yeah, put it on the
>> Oh yeah, put it on the credit
>> Oh yeah, put it on the credit card.
Okay,
Okay, you're
>> Oh yeah, put it on the credit card.
Okay, you're right.
You're
You're right,
You're right, honey.
Mom
Mom ain't
You're right, honey.
Mom ain't happy,
Mom ain't happy, nobody's
You're right, honey.
Mom ain't happy, nobody's happy.
Mom ain't happy, nobody's happy. And
You're right, honey.
Mom ain't happy, nobody's happy. And put
on
on the
on the credit
on the credit card.
on the credit card. What
on the credit card. What more
on the credit card. What more do
on the credit card. What more do you
need
need for
on the credit card. What more do you
need for domestic
need for domestic bliss?
That's
That's how
That's how you
That's how you get
That's how you get to
That's how you get to be
That's how you get to be unbeatable.
Any
Any guy
That's how you get to be unbeatable.
Any guy like
Any guy like that,
That's how you get to be unbeatable.
Any guy like that, his
Any guy like that, his wife's
That's how you get to be unbeatable.
Any guy like that, his wife's never
going
going to
going to leave
going to leave me.
All right.
All right. So,
going to leave me.
All right. So, mutuality
All right. So, mutuality then
going to leave me.
All right. So, mutuality then means
All right. So, mutuality then means that
the
the two
the two of
the two of you
the two of you reciprocally
the two of you reciprocally are
the two of you reciprocally are aligned
with
with each
the two of you reciprocally are aligned
with each other's
um
innate
innate the
um
innate the truth
innate the truth of
um
innate the truth of who
innate the truth of who you
um
innate the truth of who you are.
innate the truth of who you are. So,
The
The more
The more the
The more the two
The more the two people
The more the two people are
The more the two people are are
The more the two people are are stop
being
being horizontal
The more the two people are are stop
being horizontal with
being horizontal with each
The more the two people are are stop
being horizontal with each other
being horizontal with each other and
both
both start
both start becoming
both start becoming ver
both start becoming ver vertical
both start becoming ver vertical and
both start becoming ver vertical and of
course
course spiritual
both start becoming ver vertical and of
course spiritual alignment
course spiritual alignment then
both start becoming ver vertical and of
course spiritual alignment then begins
to
to transcend
to transcend all
to transcend all other
to transcend all other motivations
and
and therefore
to transcend all other motivations
and therefore winning
and therefore winning is
to transcend all other motivations
and therefore winning is irrelevant.
Uh
Uh you
Uh you win
Uh you win or
Uh you win or you
Uh you win or you lose.
Uh you win or you lose. So
you
you win
Uh you win or you lose. So
you win or
you win or you
Uh you win or you lose. So
you win or you lose.
you win or you lose. So
I
I teach
I teach a
I teach a game
I teach a game which
I teach a game which we'll
I teach a game which we'll talk
I teach a game which we'll talk about
after
after the
I teach a game which we'll talk about
after the break.
after the break. I
I teach a game which we'll talk about
after the break. I don't
after the break. I don't know
I teach a game which we'll talk about
after the break. I don't know if
after the break. I don't know if I
I teach a game which we'll talk about
after the break. I don't know if I got
time
time to
time to talk
time to talk about
time to talk about it.
time to talk about it. Uh,
time to talk about it. Uh, and
time to talk about it. Uh, and then
time to talk about it. Uh, and then what
have
have we
time to talk about it. Uh, and then what
have we talked
have we talked about?
time to talk about it. Uh, and then what
have we talked about? And
have we talked about? And then
time to talk about it. Uh, and then what
have we talked about? And then what
have we talked about? And then what do
you
you remember?
you remember? Anybody's
you remember? Anybody's talking
you remember? Anybody's talking about
And
And then
you remember? Anybody's talking about
And then what?
>> Yeah.
>> How
>> How many
>> Yeah.
>> How many people
>> How many people remember
>> Yeah.
>> How many people remember talking
>> How many people remember talking about?
And
And then
And then what?
And then what? Oh
And then what? Oh my
And then what? Oh my god,
And then what? Oh my god, they
And then what? Oh my god, they were
listening.
listening. Uhoh.
Anyway,
Anyway, I
Anyway, I want
Anyway, I want to
Anyway, I want to rerun.
Anyway, I want to rerun. And
Anyway, I want to rerun. And then
Anyway, I want to rerun. And then what?
Because
Because it
Anyway, I want to rerun. And then what?
Because it takes
Because it takes us
Anyway, I want to rerun. And then what?
Because it takes us through
Because it takes us through all
Anyway, I want to rerun. And then what?
Because it takes us through all these
levels.
levels. Takes
levels. Takes us
levels. Takes us through
levels. Takes us through all
levels. Takes us through all levels.
levels. Takes us through all levels. You
forgot
forgot the
levels. Takes us through all levels. You
forgot the bread
forgot the bread and
levels. Takes us through all levels. You
forgot the bread and then
forgot the bread and then what?
levels. Takes us through all levels. You
forgot the bread and then what? You
forgot the bread and then what? You see?
And
And then
And then she'll
And then she'll be
And then she'll be mad
And then she'll be mad at
And then she'll be mad at you.
And then she'll be mad at you. And
And then she'll be mad at you. And then
what?
what? And
And then she'll be mad at you. And then
what? And then
what? And then she'll
And then she'll be mad at you. And then
what? And then she'll leave
what? And then she'll leave you.
And then she'll be mad at you. And then
what? And then she'll leave you. And
then
then what?
then what? And
then what? And then
then what? And then you'll
then what? And then you'll be
then what? And then you'll be lonely
then what? And then you'll be lonely and
miserable.
miserable. And
then what? And then you'll be lonely and
miserable. And then
miserable. And then what?
And
And if
And if you
And if you follow
And if you follow every
And if you follow every sequence
And if you follow every sequence of
And if you follow every sequence of and
then
then what
And if you follow every sequence of and
then what and
then what and surrender
And if you follow every sequence of and
then what and surrender to
then what and surrender to to
And if you follow every sequence of and
then what and surrender to to and
then what and surrender to to and then
what
you
you surrender
what
you surrender each
you surrender each thing
what
you surrender each thing to
you surrender each thing to God.
And
And if
And if you
And if you go
And if you go through
And if you go through a
And if you go through a stack,
And if you go through a stack, if
And if you go through a stack, if you
don't
don't get
And if you go through a stack, if you
don't get the
don't get the job,
And if you go through a stack, if you
don't get the job, you'd
don't get the job, you'd be
And if you go through a stack, if you
don't get the job, you'd be broke.
don't get the job, you'd be broke. And
then
then what?
then what? Then
then what? Then I'll
then what? Then I'll have
then what? Then I'll have to
then what? Then I'll have to borrow
money.
money. And
then what? Then I'll have to borrow
money. And then
money. And then what?
then what? Then I'll have to borrow
money. And then what? Then
money. And then what? Then I'll
then what? Then I'll have to borrow
money. And then what? Then I'll go
bankrupt.
bankrupt. And
bankrupt. And then
bankrupt. And then what?
bankrupt. And then what? Then
bankrupt. And then what? Then I
bankrupt. And then what? Then I won't
have
have any
bankrupt. And then what? Then I won't
have any credit
have any credit rating.
bankrupt. And then what? Then I won't
have any credit rating. And
have any credit rating. And then
bankrupt. And then what? Then I won't
have any credit rating. And then what?
Then
Then I'll
Then I'll have
Then I'll have to
Then I'll have to give
Then I'll have to give up
Then I'll have to give up the
Then I'll have to give up the business.
And
And then
Then I'll have to give up the business.
And then what?
And then what? Then
Then I'll have to give up the business.
And then what? Then I'll
And then what? Then I'll be
Then I'll have to give up the business.
And then what? Then I'll be poor.
And then what? Then I'll be poor. And
then
then what?
then what? Then
then what? Then I
then what? Then I can't
then what? Then I can't get
then what? Then I can't get the
then what? Then I can't get the car
fixed.
fixed. And
then what? Then I can't get the car
fixed. And then
fixed. And then what?
then what? Then I can't get the car
fixed. And then what? Then
fixed. And then what? Then I'll
then what? Then I can't get the car
fixed. And then what? Then I'll have
fixed. And then what? Then I'll have to
take
take the
take the bus.
take the bus. And
take the bus. And then
take the bus. And then what?
Then
Then I'll
take the bus. And then what?
Then I'll get
Then I'll get poorer
take the bus. And then what?
Then I'll get poorer and
Then I'll get poorer and poorer
take the bus. And then what?
Then I'll get poorer and poorer because
I
then
then I
I
then I can't
then I can't afford
I
then I can't afford health
then I can't afford health insurance.
And
And then
And then what?
And then what? Can't
And then what? Can't afford
And then what? Can't afford to
And then what? Can't afford to go
And then what? Can't afford to go to
And then what? Can't afford to go to the
doctor.
doctor. And
And then what? Can't afford to go to the
doctor. And then
doctor. And then what?
And then what? Can't afford to go to the
doctor. And then what? Then
doctor. And then what? Then for
And then what? Can't afford to go to the
doctor. And then what? Then for after
doctor. And then what? Then for after a
while
while I
while I can't
while I can't even
while I can't even afford
while I can't even afford to
while I can't even afford to eat.
while I can't even afford to eat. And
then
then what?
while I can't even afford to eat. And
then what? And
then what? And then
while I can't even afford to eat. And
then what? And then I'll
then what? And then I'll starve
while I can't even afford to eat. And
then what? And then I'll starve to
death.
death. And
death. And then
death. And then what?
death. And then what? And
death. And then what? And then
death. And then what? And then you'll
die.
die. So
patients
patients used
patients used to
patients used to say
patients used to say to
patients used to say to me
patients used to say to me in
patients used to say to me in the
office,
office, "Well,
patients used to say to me in the
office, "Well, what
office, "Well, what if
patients used to say to me in the
office, "Well, what if it
office, "Well, what if it doesn't
patients used to say to me in the
office, "Well, what if it doesn't work?"
I
I said,
I said, "Well,
I said, "Well, then
I said, "Well, then you
I said, "Well, then you die."
>> That's
>> That's the
I said, "Well, then you die."
>> That's the big
>> That's the big question.
I said, "Well, then you die."
>> That's the big question. People
>> That's the big question. People that
I said, "Well, then you die."
>> That's the big question. People that are
smart
smart look
smart look at
smart look at that
smart look at that one
smart look at that one and
smart look at that one and then
smart look at that one and then one.
smart look at that one and then one. You
know,
know, it
smart look at that one and then one. You
know, it really
know, it really gives
smart look at that one and then one. You
know, it really gives you
know, it really gives you the
smart look at that one and then one. You
know, it really gives you the willies
when
when you
when you watch
when you watch the
when you watch the the
when you watch the the karmic
when you watch the the karmic risk
people
people take
when you watch the the karmic risk
people take is
people take is in
when you watch the the karmic risk
people take is in extreme
people take is in extreme positions.
when you watch the the karmic risk
people take is in extreme positions. The
things
things that
things that they
things that they say
things that they say and
things that they say and my
things that they say and my god,
things that they say and my god, it's
like
like they're
things that they say and my god, it's
like they're completely
like they're completely oblivious
things that they say and my god, it's
like they're completely oblivious to
like they're completely oblivious to any
consequences
consequences of
consequences of their
consequences of their action.
consequences of their action. They
think,
think, well,
consequences of their action. They
think, well, if
think, well, if it's
consequences of their action. They
think, well, if it's legal,
think, well, if it's legal, you
consequences of their action. They
think, well, if it's legal, you can
think, well, if it's legal, you can say
it.
it. I
it. I mean,
it. I mean, that's
it. I mean, that's the
it. I mean, that's the smallest
it. I mean, that's the smallest part
it. I mean, that's the smallest part of
it.
it. If
it. I mean, that's the smallest part of
it. If it's
it. If it's legal,
it. I mean, that's the smallest part of
it. If it's legal, what
it. If it's legal, what that
it. I mean, that's the smallest part of
it. If it's legal, what that got
it. If it's legal, what that got to
it. I mean, that's the smallest part of
it. If it's legal, what that got to do
with
with it?
Uh
Uh yeah,
with it?
Uh yeah, I
Uh yeah, I sometimes
with it?
Uh yeah, I sometimes shudder
Uh yeah, I sometimes shudder when
with it?
Uh yeah, I sometimes shudder when I
Uh yeah, I sometimes shudder when I hear
things
that
that people
things
that people say
that people say and
things
that people say and I
that people say and I said
things
that people say and I said my
that people say and I said my god
what
what is
what is the
what is the karma
what is the karma of
what is the karma of that
what is the karma of that you
what is the karma of that you know
what is the karma of that you know what
is
is the
what is the karma of that you know what
is the karma
is the karma of
what is the karma of that you know what
is the karma of that?
is the karma of that? So
what is the karma of that you know what
is the karma of that? So the
is the karma of that? So the downside
what is the karma of that you know what
is the karma of that? So the downside of
western
western society
overall
overall in
western society
overall in my
overall in my view
western society
overall in my view is
overall in my view is this
western society
overall in my view is this lack
overall in my view is this lack of
awareness
awareness of
awareness of karma.
awareness of karma. And
awareness of karma. And what
awareness of karma. And what is
awareness of karma. And what is karma?
Karma
Karma is
awareness of karma. And what is karma?
Karma is nothing
Karma is nothing but
awareness of karma. And what is karma?
Karma is nothing but accepting
Karma is nothing but accepting the
inevitability
inevitability of
inevitability of responsibility
and
and being
inevitability of responsibility
and being answerable
and being answerable for
inevitability of responsibility
and being answerable for one's
and being answerable for one's decisions
and
and actions.
and actions. In
and actions. In the
and actions. In the east,
and actions. In the east, it's
and actions. In the east, it's more
common
common for
and actions. In the east, it's more
common for people
common for people to
and actions. In the east, it's more
common for people to be
common for people to be aware
and actions. In the east, it's more
common for people to be aware of
common for people to be aware of the
karmic
karmic consequences.
But
But in
karmic consequences.
But in the
But in the west,
karmic consequences.
But in the west, people
But in the west, people like
karmic consequences.
But in the west, people like are
unconscious
unconscious of
unconscious of it
unconscious of it that
unconscious of it that every
unconscious of it that every action
unconscious of it that every action has
its
its has
unconscious of it that every action has
its has an
its has an effect
unconscious of it that every action has
its has an effect and
its has an effect and these
unconscious of it that every action has
its has an effect and these uh
its has an effect and these uh collect
over
over time.
over time. See
over time. See because
over time. See because we
over time. See because we all
over time. See because we all began
over time. See because we all began as
that
that first
over time. See because we all began as
that first primordial
that first primordial energy
over time. See because we all began as
that first primordial energy of
that first primordial energy of life
which
which had
which had to
which had to get
which had to get in
which had to get in order
which had to get in order to
which had to get in order to survive
which had to get in order to survive at
the
the cost
which had to get in order to survive at
the cost of
the cost of others
which had to get in order to survive at
the cost of others and
the cost of others and therefore
which had to get in order to survive at
the cost of others and therefore was
voracious
voracious and
voracious and then
voracious and then we
voracious and then we evolved
voracious and then we evolved to
voracious and then we evolved to more
greater
greater spiritual
voracious and then we evolved to more
greater spiritual dimensions.
greater spiritual dimensions. One
voracious and then we evolved to more
greater spiritual dimensions. One of
greater spiritual dimensions. One of the
greatest
greatest benefits
greatest benefits I
greatest benefits I think
greatest benefits I think to
greatest benefits I think to spiritual
work
work is
greatest benefits I think to spiritual
work is you
work is you slowly
greatest benefits I think to spiritual
work is you slowly dimly
work is you slowly dimly and
greatest benefits I think to spiritual
work is you slowly dimly and then
work is you slowly dimly and then become
very
very quite
very quite consciously
very quite consciously aware
very quite consciously aware that
everything
everything has
very quite consciously aware that
everything has an
everything has an energy
very quite consciously aware that
everything has an energy to
everything has an energy to it.
Everything
Everything has
Everything has a
Everything has a calibrable
Everything has a calibrable energy
Everything has a calibrable energy of
it.
it. Uh
Everything has a calibrable energy of
it. Uh everything
it. Uh everything is
Everything has a calibrable energy of
it. Uh everything is going
it. Uh everything is going to
Everything has a calibrable energy of
it. Uh everything is going to have
it. Uh everything is going to have a
consequence
consequence over
consequence over eons
consequence over eons of
consequence over eons of time.
Oh,
Oh, eons
consequence over eons of time.
Oh, eons of
Oh, eons of time.
consequence over eons of time.
Oh, eons of time. Yeah.
Oh, eons of time. Yeah. Few
consequence over eons of time.
Oh, eons of time. Yeah. Few people
Oh, eons of time. Yeah. Few people have
experienced
experienced eons
experienced eons of
experienced eons of time.
experienced eons of time. You
experienced eons of time. You can
experience
experience eons
experienced eons of time. You can
experience eons of
experience eons of time
experienced eons of time. You can
experience eons of time in
experience eons of time in a
experienced eons of time. You can
experience eons of time in a state
experience eons of time in a state such
as
as I
as I had
as I had in
as I had in the
as I had in the snowbank.
as I had in the snowbank. That
experience
experience was
as I had in the snowbank. That
experience was out
experience was out of
as I had in the snowbank. That
experience was out of time.
experience was out of time. Was
as I had in the snowbank. That
experience was out of time. Was like
eons.
Then
Then at
eons.
Then at a
Then at a much
eons.
Then at a much later
Then at a much later date
in
in the
in the depths
in the depths of
in the depths of hell
in the depths of hell trying
in the depths of hell trying to
in the depths of hell trying to went
in the depths of hell trying to went to
the
the depths
in the depths of hell trying to went to
the depths of
the depths of hell
in the depths of hell trying to went to
the depths of hell past
the depths of hell past the
in the depths of hell trying to went to
the depths of hell past the upper
levels,
levels, medium
levels, medium hills,
past
past hopelessness,
levels, medium hills,
past hopelessness, past
past hopelessness, past despair
again
again into
again into foreverness.
again into foreverness. Yeah.
The
The foreverness
again into foreverness. Yeah.
The foreverness of
The foreverness of the
again into foreverness. Yeah.
The foreverness of the pits
The foreverness of the pits of
again into foreverness. Yeah.
The foreverness of the pits of hell
The foreverness of the pits of hell are
beyond
beyond description.
Few
Few people
beyond description.
Few people go
Few people go there
beyond description.
Few people go there and
Few people go there and then
beyond description.
Few people go there and then come
Few people go there and then come back
to
to television.
to television. And
to television. And what
to television. And what what's
to television. And what what's scary
when
when you
to television. And what what's scary
when you hear
when you hear somebody
to television. And what what's scary
when you hear somebody do
when you hear somebody do make
to television. And what what's scary
when you hear somebody do make such
when you hear somebody do make such a
serious
uh
uh breach,
serious
uh breach, such
uh breach, such a
serious
uh breach, such a breach
uh breach, such a breach is
serious
uh breach, such a breach is you
uh breach, such a breach is you realize
the
the karmic
the karmic future
the karmic future they've
the karmic future they've just
the karmic future they've just laid
the karmic future they've just laid out
for
for themselves.
the karmic future they've just laid out
for themselves. It's
for themselves. It's almost
the karmic future they've just laid out
for themselves. It's almost scary.
for themselves. It's almost scary. You
know what
know what I'm
know what I'm saying?
know what I'm saying? The
know what I'm saying? The more
know what I'm saying? The more evolved
you
you get,
know what I'm saying? The more evolved
you get, the
you get, the more
know what I'm saying? The more evolved
you get, the more you
you get, the more you see,
know what I'm saying? The more evolved
you get, the more you see, you
you get, the more you see, you know,
that
that everything
that everything is
that everything is has
that everything is has a
that everything is has a consequence
that everything is has a consequence as
a
a consequence
that everything is has a consequence as
a consequence of
a consequence of that
that everything is has a consequence as
a consequence of that which
a consequence of that which it
that everything is has a consequence as
a consequence of that which it is.
a consequence of that which it is. It's
impersonal.
impersonal. As
impersonal. As a
impersonal. As a consequence
impersonal. As a consequence of
impersonal. As a consequence of that
which
which you
impersonal. As a consequence of that
which you are,
which you are, certain
impersonal. As a consequence of that
which you are, certain things
automatically
automatically follow
automatically follow and
automatically follow and those
automatically follow and those track
automatically follow and those track you
over
over great
automatically follow and those track you
over great periods
over great periods of
automatically follow and those track you
over great periods of time.
over great periods of time. Yeah.
automatically follow and those track you
over great periods of time. Yeah. So
over great periods of time. Yeah. So now
we're
we're going
we're going to
we're going to take
we're going to take a
we're going to take a break
we're going to take a break for
we're going to take a break for how
long?
>> We're
>> We're going
>> We're going to
>> We're going to take
>> We're going to take a
>> We're going to take a break
>> We're going to take a break for
>> We're going to take a break for 15
minutes
minutes and
>> We're going to take a break for 15
minutes and anybody
minutes and anybody who's
>> We're going to take a break for 15
minutes and anybody who's late
minutes and anybody who's late gets
>> We're going to take a break for 15
minutes and anybody who's late gets a
demerit
11:30
>> 11:30
>> 11:30 11:30
>> 11:30 11:30 Yeah.
There's
There's the
>> 11:30 11:30 Yeah.
There's the crow
There's the crow flies.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
Hallelu.