song.
Okay, we better hustle along. So, we'll
move on to the next thing. Uh
uh this is a a review of spiritual
truth. All right. So the work I've done
has been devoted to the delineation uh
calibrating the levels of truth
calibrating levels of consciousness
you know and comparing uh things with
the absolute Hegel's principle the
absolute is correct the absolute is the
infinite field of consciousness it
manifests up to consciousness level
1,000 in this domain 1,000 are the few
avatars throughout history rare does
Does it ever go over 600? Very rare.
Rare is still 700 or 800. Extremely
rare. 850 or over. Okay. Out of all of
that has been distilled a combination of
really powerful truth which can be
verified and some myths and fallacies
because religions were established in
in ancient times and those were times of
great religious myth. And so a lot of
old religious treatises include ethnic
and geographic myths, historic myths,
uh, rather than verifiable truth. So in
the book we just going to be published
soon, truth, truth versus falsehood, we
try to differentiate that which is
verifiably truth in the world's great
literature. Yeah.
And out of it, we distill what is truth.
You know, what is the nature of
spiritual truth? integrous teachers and
teachings. You know, uh this is
important to know because the early
spiritual devote tends to wander off
into, you know, psychic readings and the
astral circus,
new age u carnival and they go from one
thing to another. They're all novel.
They're all attractive and and what
happens is they get glamorized by that
which no doesn't fit the paradigm of
logic and reason. So, it's an exciting
new discovery and that can take you out
of the
that can take you out of the running for
enlightenment uh for quite a while. Some
people get stuck there for a lifetime
after a lifetime. Many of them that were
doing it in Mesopotenia are still doing
it. They're still on the other side. Uh
they don't have, you know, the same
physicality, but the same consciousness
and now they are masters on the other
side and they channel all kinds of
mystical things, stuff.
>> All right. So then what by what way can
we know? It used to be um faith and
integrity in the religion or the teacher
in modern society that's been brought
into question
and there is obvious error too. So how
can you tell what is truthful because
the mind unaded is unable to discern uh
perception or appearance from essence.
So we have certain principles that uh
calibrated maybe at a thousand. All
spiritual truth is always universal.
Truth is the same truth is always true
forever.
And the enlightened mystics have
appeared throughout history separated by
different sides of the globe maybe 500
or a thousand years. the the great
mystics area and mystics of ancient
pre-India
uh
calibrated you know 8 900s
uh 5,000 BC
totally separated from Europe or the
rest of Asia
the truth is described by the great
Aryan mystics in the yupanads
I like the yupanads because what Krishna
is saying is exactly how it is And
so truth is true at all times in all
places independent of the culture,
opinion, personalities or circumstances.
It's not exclusive. Nobody owns it. It's
non it's not a secret. And it's non
sectarian. Truth is shared with
everyone.
Available to be open to all people, not
exclusive. You got to pay money to get
the inner secret. And then you get to be
a super buma. And for another 5,000,
we'll train you to be a uh uh
that which is true is free and available
to all people with no requirement.
Integrity of purpose. There's nothing to
gain or lose. Now, what would a true
teacher gain if you agree to them or
don't agree with them? He couldn't care
less.
some guy called last sent an email that
he was doubtful or dubious about
something. So I said, you know, that's
his problem, isn't it? But they do their
ego comes on like, gee, you don't you
haven't convinced me like it's my
problem now.
What do I want to convince them for?
It's your karma, buddy.
Come back again. Come back again. Come
back again.
The planet will still be here. Yeah.
Five more incarnations. Yeah. I'm not
convinced yet. Well,
okay. There's nothing to gain or lose.
There's no point in gaining followers,
glamorizing it, wearing strange
clothing, having theatrical
presentations.
Uh, you have nothing to gain. Some
people like your books. Terrific.
Some people don't like your books.
Terrific. My integrity requires that I
state what I know to be the truth and
when I leave I've done it.
The rest is up to everybody else. So the
see your commitment is to yourself to
the integrity of your purpose. Uh
there's no point in trying to gain
people or win pro ties. Uh it's non
sectarian not explos doesn't
exploit limitation
independent of opinion it's nonlinear
not subject to people's intellect has no
positionality truth is true and not
anti- anything it is what it is
falsehood is not the opposite of truth
it's the absence of truth it's the
absence of truth once you see it's an
absence then there's nothing to get uh
lined up about has no requirements, no
required memberships. You don't have to
sign up. You don't have to any pledges.
You don't have to swear any oaths.
Non-controlling spiritual purity has no
interest in the personal lives of
others. What to wear, who to go to bed
with, what kind of sex to have, how you
should comb your hair, whether you
should have a beard, wear a hat,
what day of the week you should eat,
what
what would An enlightened mystic care
about what the hell you eat for dinner.
Non-controlling means that the guru has
something to gain. You know, control
over people. Tell them how to live, how
to breathe, what to do, how to have sex,
what to wear, whether you should have a
beard, not wear a beard. Free of force
or intimidation. There's no threats, no
brainwashing,
no agilation. Ooh.
No training rituals. We don't have to
brainwash people, indoctrinate them or
intrude into their private life. And
what would a teacher care about your
private life? What you do with it is,
you know, cuz he only interested in
spiritual principles that you lead your
private life with consideration and love
and caring for others. You know,
non-binding. There's no uh you don't
have to sign up for anything and there's
no consequences if you decide you're not
interested. There are many cults around
man and you you try to leave them you
can get killed. Literally killed.
Literally killed. Some are not far from
here either. Cost you your life. Yes.
You think I'm kidding.
Free to come and go. No intimidation or
consequences.
Commonality.
Huh?
>> Recognition of truth is a consequence of
what one has become. Oh wow. The minute
the condundalini energy pours in, what
was nonsensical over here now is
obvious. Of course, makes sense. Common
sense, non-materialistic,
uh, inspirational.
So the truth itself because the truth
let's say calibrates at 850 or over that
truth itself is inspirational to merely
have heard it to know it you know is
already plus your own intention
it's so therefore self-fulfilling
don't need any pump you don't need
parades
it's not involved in world affairs you
know we don't have a a website pro or
for anything, you know, pro or for
anything.
Uh non-intentional, does not intervene
or have an agenda or a purpose. Does not
inflict itself, promulgate.
Uh and so it's non-political.
It has no enemies,
non-dualistic.
All transpires comes about by virtue of
its karmic propensity within the overall
field which manifests as actuality there
other than by cause. So it's non-causal
non-dualistic. We'll go to the next one.
And it's devotional.
Why? Because as the spiritual energy
comes in, you now begin to you develop
the capacity for devotion. So it isn't
just the truth itself but once devotion
to it one's devotion
as I say if you do one stanza one verse
from the 91st psalm for a week
and then the next week you go to the
next one and then you do maybe Socrates
you pick out something of a very high
teaching out of the
uh out of the let's say and you just
live with that for a week well your
intention plus that principle
now activates the field. You don't have
to think about what it means. Things
begin to happen that way.
That's the course of miracles that when
you hit that level, the miraculous is
how everything is.
It always was that way. You just noticed
it.
Tranquility and peace. There are no
issues. You don't get involved in them.
Equality.
uh all of express in reverence for all
of life the sacredness of all of life.
So you can do another month in which you
do nothing except
increase your awareness of the intrinsic
beauty of all that exists the intrinsic
design. You can see the intrinsic design
in the architect manifesting. When we
went to Unity Village, it was
interesting because you see like Italian
Renaissance
inspired architecture and yet it's at
the same time modernistic. So here it is
modern but innately the essence of it is
Italian Renaissance. You go it's like
Italian Renaissance without all the
without all the carving. So the beauty
was still there.
All right. uh
equality then of all of life
non-temporal.
Life is eternal and physicality is
temporal. And then an axiom of life that
for amazing reasons has never been
discovered by mankind. That like energy
and matter, life is indestructible.
The law of you know of law and matter
and energy cannot be destroyed. They can
only change form. And for some reason,
mankind has never discovered, although
spiritual people have, of course, that
that life is not destroy destroyable.
You cannot destroy life. You can swat
the moth, but it'll go right along
flying in his atheric body and not even
notice.
>> Okay.
The law that I just pronounced
calibrates at a thousand resistance.
scared me for a second. If karma had
gone weak,
I would have to kill myself right now.
The karma of lying to all these people.
My god, I want survived that long. All
right. Life is eternal. That which is
provable, we've already said, is linear,
not subject to proof. And therefore,
it's called mystical. It's a spontaneous
radiating inner awareness. And it comes
forth from within. Comes forth within.
Ineffable means that it is not definable
in ordinary terms. William James in his
book varieties of
religious experience, you know, made
that very clear. Ineffable means it is
not within the linear. It is not
definable. It is not describable.
You cannot circumscribe it. You can't
catch it.
It's the way you are. So by intention
then your life becomes
becomes that intention. You become it.
You are the prayer.
Instead of praying from a me to a that
uh you become that. You are it.
Therefore, as you walk through the
woods, do you know that the plants
uh know that
the first time I went to that state, I
walked through the woods, all of life
was like worshipful, worshipful of the
presence of divinity and was very
conscious and aware of it. Very
conscious of it. And it was also
conscious and aware of the divinity of
everything else that exists.
Now universe is conscious. It is
conscious and aware. A tree does know
does actually know what you are.
Let's see if that's so.
Oh, that's a fact. Oh Lord, resist. It's
a fact.
When I first saw it shimmering forth, I
thought this is like a psychedelic
cartoon or something.
I expect to hear the yellow submarine in
the background.
The tree is vibrantly aware that divi
that it is in the presence of divinity.
It has no problem with it. It because of
its nature because of its because of the
source of its creation
which is the same source as your
creation. It knows its own in life.
uh reverence is life above 200 below 200
is different story. All right, so that's
enough for lunch. Uh I'm happy we
weren't wrong by I think today.
I hate to have lightning interrupt a
lecture.
You just made a boo boo at a thousand.
>> What time do we resume? Uh 2:00.
>> Is that so? Okay. So, we got plenty of
time for lunch and uh
>> it's been a wonderful morning. You know,
Everyone is here.
We're going to get into the dualities
that uh hold the levels of consciousness
where they are. People are interested
now. I see the pattern. You know, how do
I transcend the stairway? The stairway
to God, that's what I call it. You know,
calmary levels of consciousness.
How do you transcend the stairway?
The power of intention of course will
align you with the correct way to go
because it affects the field.
It's a field effect.
Then decide to lead a contemplative
lifestyle. You see people chop up
spirituality into intense meditation and
then back to usual and then some prayer
meeting and then back to usual and uh it
doesn't really work that way. It uh the
the enthusiasms come and go
and
it's a lifestyle. It's a lifestyle which
is oriented towards
the realization of spiritual truth from
within.
You mentioned contemplative means it's
like you can pick a phrase. I did I
think I spent a month originally on the
91st psalm
uh to contemplate it for and then it's
truth reveals itself. So you don't try
to understand it with the intellect and
what happens is you hold it in mind
divinity like reveals to you. So you're
riding the subway and all of a sudden
the whole subway is transformed
and it comes out of nowhere. See doesn't
come about as linear thinking or logic.
However in the lectures we try to tie
the the the is yet unknown to the known.
So we try we try to connect it with
archaeology and biology and evolution
and mathematics and science and logic
and quantum mechanics
and so
it's
it's like planted the roots are in the
known see and then you can
see how it evolves and then you don't
have to think about it you just know it.
Okay. So the next slide
we'll uh
that's not new.
Oh yeah.
All right. So all the levels have an
attraction and an aversion.
What keeps the experience? We talked
about what is the ego? The ego
experientially is the experiencer.
Like the leading edge of the ego
is very much like the shellfish at the
bottom of the sea. It's out there. It's
like a probe and it's always seeking
experiencing.
So instead of worrying about the whole
ego, you just worry about the
experiencer. The experiencer
is where you have invested your energy
and your identification. It's not with
the whole ego. It's really just with the
experiencer.
The experiencer is always searching for
a payoff.
No matter what the situation,
it's looking for a gain.
The experience here is like a screen
and it is one 10,000th of a second
removed from the reality.
Therefore, the ego never experiences
what is.
It experiences its experience of one
Therefore, it's not experiencing that
which is being recorded. It's
experiencing
the playback
off the tape recorder. You know, in a
tape recorder, you can plug it in and
hear what was just recorded.
So that the ego is experiencing
that which was just recorded 110,000th
of a second ago.
Doesn't seem like much except that the
quality changes completely.
this side of the one 10,000 of a second.
The trees look like trees.
They look like flowers.
On the other side of that one tenth of a
second, they radiate out divinity
and that gets screened out because the
TV station doesn't record those
qualities. It records linearity and
emotion like I watch in regular
television.
Enlightenment is to bypass the
experiencer.
The experiencer just suddenly goes out
like that.
It doesn't get weaker and weaker and
weaker. It just suddenly out.
And then the mind goes silent in awe.
Wow. So
in the books I've just finished you know
the focus the whole chapter is on the
experiencer.
All right. So the experiencer is always
seeking
and it's seeking experience. So the gain
that you have to surrender is
experiencing itself.
which to the e which the ego will not go
along with.
It will not readily extinguish itself.
You have to beat it up a little bit and
threaten it anyway. So the experiencer
is the leading edge of awareness.
The experiencer is like an information
probe. So you see, for life to survive,
it had to constantly obtain data.
Edible, not edible, friend, foe. You
know what I mean? It had to sense its
environment. It had to imitate the
environment. The octopus or some other
animal at the bottom of the sea
is full of spiritual wisdom. They're
great things to watch because suddenly
it reveals to you the innate
intelligence of creation. And it's a
discernment of beauty and line. It's
aesthetic. You look at the creatures,
the incredible beauty of them, you know,
they just didn't come out in crazy blobs
like this. They come out. You look at
the face of a tiger, man. It's like a
what a creative genius, you know.
All right. Where were we?
before we get carried away by the tiger.
Do do not play with tigers by the way.
No, admire them from a distance. Okay.
Uh so this is general attraction and
aversion of applicable to the entire all
the ego's programs. Then the next one
after this we will start at the bottom
of the of the list and see how it
applies specifically
uh to shame. Yeah, this is the
generality
and then we'll do we'll apply these
concepts to each level of consciousness
and you begin to sort of intuit it how
it um how it all uh
takes its place in in the psychic
economy.
The attraction is always to that which
is familiar. First thing you do when you
come into a crowd, you look around for
familiar face, right?
uh the aversion is to uncertainty. I
mean what if I go there and I don't see
anybody I know
right
therefore we cling
uh to that which is known and are really
actually fearful of the future. The past
is like certainty and the future is
uncertainty and the ego likes to be
certain. So it doesn't like it doesn't
really like the new
the ego is attracted to what's easy and
has an aversion to effort.
It's easier just to go along with some
old way than to put forth effort. So
we're going to look today at how to
decrease effort so that aversion doesn't
prevail to the same degree. It's a
resistance. Okay?
Because attention begins to diminish a
thing automatically.
If you want to reduce the number of
cookies you eat every day,
let's say you've been eating overeating
cookies for 20 years now. I'm going to
quit cookies someday. You're never
you're not going to do that.
You're lying to yourself. You are not
going to quit cookies.
You've been eating 50 cookies a day for
20 years. You are not going to quit
cookies.
Therefore, I tell people, don't waste
your seeming willpower, which is going
to bring you guilt and feeling of
failure. Don't bother. What you do is
you merely start counting the cookies
you eat every day, but don't try to do
anything about it.
No. So,
you lay out the cookies.
20 in each box. The end of the day, you
count how many cookies you ate. 68.
Tuesday, 64 cookies.
Thursday, a bad day. 72.
Now, I don't want you to try to do
anything about it. That's the whole
point. Enlightenment is very easy. It's
a letting go. And everybody struggles
and struggles. And then finally one day
you let go and think looks at you.
So I want you to just pay attention. So
anything you don't like about yourself,
you just note down how many times a day
you do it. Getting annoyed with people
swearing, you know, hit your thumb. Oh
Jesus Christ. Oh God, I'm sorry. Please
forgive me. How many times you swore
today? All right. You just start
tracking it and paying attention. That's
it. Just notice it. Now, don't tell me
you can't do it because anybody can
notice it. You notice that you're eating
100 cookies a day. That's why you're
worrying about it. Of course, you can
notice it. So, all you have to do is
make a mental note and write it down on
a calendar.
Monday, 63 cookies.
Tuesday, 18 cookies. Oh, wow. And then
Wednesday, back to usual, 58 cookies.
What will happen is by virtue of
intention effortlessly the Heisenberg
principle begins to apply. Awareness
itself begins to diminish it. By the end
of a month you'll be down to 14 cookies.
The end of another month or two you'll
be down to 60 16 cookies. Six cookies I
mean. And all of a sudden you say what
the f I don't need cookies.
It was all effortless. You don't have to
struggle sackcloth and ashes
cudled yourself, you know, manipulate
yourself with guilt.
You just notice, just notice. And if you
notice it effortlessly, the Heisenberg
principle, it begins to apply. Why?
Because by your intention. You see, so
what you've done is finesse the power of
the field instead of relying on the ego.
Let the field do it. You pay your taxes.
What the hell?
That the
government's supposed to do it, ain't
it? That the feels of government. You
just show the government what your
problem is and the government's going to
take care of it. Yeah.
All right. So, you call in the
government and you do that by
the Heisenberg principle, which is
effortless.
All you have to do is
Note it. Pay attention. Huh? So, it's
actually easy, but you avoid it because
it seems like effort because you're
going at it the hard way, trying to lift
yourself by your bootstraps.
The attraction of anger is because it
feels to people like strength.
Of course, it's a losery.
However, the animal swells up with
anger, tries to intimidate others, and
the aversion, the fear is of being seen
passive or weak. Being seen passive or
weak. In certain cultures, that'll get
you killed, too. Being seen as passive
or weak. We're experiencing that in
other parts of the world. If you're seen
as passive or weak, they kill you.
and certain neighborhoods in the inner
city. Allowing yourself to be dissed,
that's that's the last thing you
remembered.
>> Allowing yourself to be dissed is fatal.
So the reality above 200 is totally
different than the reality below 200.
The naivity,
political naivity especially, is to
presume that other people are the way
you are.
They are not.
They aren't the opposite.
You think it's good to pay your bills,
they think you're an idiot for doing it.
Oh,
you think telling the truth is integrous
and they think it's being stupid. So
therefore,
strength then anger is is seductive and
addictive because you puff up. The
animal puffs up and he's fear the fear
is being seen passive or weak. All
right. It's important here to win and
the dread is losing
the that they're not aware of win-win.
In a dualistic world, one wins and the
other one loses.
That's from materialistic linear
perception.
Karmically, a loss may be the biggest
gain of your life.
Because the world is what it is. It's
the optimum theater for karmic benefit.
It's the optimum place for the undoing
of negative karma and the gaining of
positive karma. Therefore, wanting to
change the world doesn't make much
sense. You know, Ramanar, she says,
"The world you see doesn't even exist.
Save yourself the trouble and surrender
it to God. So if the purpose of the
world is to provide an optimum
opportunity for the undoing of negative
karma,
all your dogooderism is going to
sentence those people to a continuation
of bad karma. Is it not?
They can't kill themselves on the street
car. They'll do it on the bus. They'll
drive off.
Oh Lord. So
all right, win and lose is the ego's
perception because you don't know uh
what seeming loss is going to be a
tremendous gain. Mhm. You don't know
what's seeming loss is is going to open
the door. So it's by loss that the
doorway to the new is open because
otherwise the ego is going to constantly
cling to the past. It's going to cling
to the familiar and we'll never know
what freedom is like. Huh?
uh importance the idea that you have to
be important and here you might be
nobody see uh you got to be noticed and
uh that's the whole world of glamour to
be noticed and so the basic here thing
about the ego which has been ever since
the beginning of time is it constantly
seeks for gain and its fear is one of
loss it clutches
so the ego is characterized by
clutchingness it wants to control.
Well, the minute the ego thinks a thing
is mine, it totally changes dimension.
H the magic of mine instantly changes
it.
That's just a watch.
But if it's my watch, uh-oh, now it's
special.
Now it's my sentimental watch. Now it's
old granddad's watch.
Oh wow. Now it began it's ego you know
it's ego inflation
the minute you add mind. Therefore the
body should be referred to as an it.
Whatever it's doing is really not all
that interesting if you watch it. It
it does what it's supposed to do.
And when the ego sort of resolves into
just sort of a oneness, uh you watch it
walking around and it's like a windup
toy. You see it's still you still doing
it
for decades. It just wander. It walks
around by itself.
Does whatever it's going to do. It
points with this thing.
I mean it's a marvelous mechanism. I
don't want anything to do with it. But
there it goes on its own.
Win and lose importance the idea. So if
you say my body
or my mind, my possessions, my the
minute you add the word my, you're
stuck.
First of all, nothing belongs to you.
Nothing.
Everything belongs to God.
You have temporary custody.
Temporary custody. Yeah. You are the
steward of these things.
See yourself as the steward rather than
the owner.
It's the body and it's the mind.
And when you stop referring to it as me,
it loses its attractive ego investment.
It's a body and it's the body and it's
the mind.
Well, to be hypnotized by the mind is to
think these are my thoughts.
The thoughts emanate from the field of
consciousness impersonally.
The minute you connect with a certain
level of consciousness, you're connected
to an attractor field. That attractor
field has the same thoughts and has
always had them,
you know, for thousands of years.
There's nothing novel about it. It's
mine and I'll kill you. You think that's
your thought?
Did you invent that thought? Something
new in man's history.
That prevailing thought field thinks
that way. Those thoughts belong to the
field they're not yours. So don't claim
ownership for that which over over which
you have no ownership.
Nothing belongs to anyone.
Everything belongs to divinity. You have
temporary custody. temporary
stewardship.
So to give up your life for something
which isn't even yours is a little
ridiculous, you know.
Oh lord.
So the importance then is uh this is
self-importance.
So the ego is designed to gain uh money
of course is a very big one. Money,
excitement, all these things are very
big.
When we get to the levels of
consciousness correlating with
happiness, you will notice that
happiness is almost one to one
correlated with level of consciousness
and with nothing else.
Does not correlate with wealth. Not even
correlated with health. Not correlated
with success. It's correlated with level
of consciousness. Period.
Period. Yeah. So just advance your
consciousness and think of all the work
you save yourself.
I mean, you know, you can be delighted
with nothing.
The less you got, the better. You can
live with a cot, a blanket you got from
the Goodwill, a box, an apple, and a
six-pack, a pep.
And to add to to your heavenly abode,
you get a cat. Yeah. So now you got
everything. You get a piece of cheese,
some Pepsi, a cat, a cot, and uh a
candle. There you go.
>> Do you need anything to read? No. Do you
need television? No. Do you need a
radio? No. Do you need to read the
paper? No.
I didn't even know Regan had been shot
for weeks later.
In coffee shops I mention reg.
All right. So the ego is invested in in
in all these various levels with being
important being noticed with gain. It
fears loss and money is the magical road
to happiness. Money
The experiencer in order to justify its
own existence seeks the energy that it
pulls out of excitement and it dreads
boredom. Dreads boredom.
The way out of boredom is to allow
yourself to be bored and investigate why
you feel bored and what that emotion is.
If you want to discover what the
experiencer does,
allow yourself to instead of escapism,
allow yourself to be bored and just
contemplate
on what is boredom and what is it I'm
experiencing and why do I have an
aversion to it?
That's a very rapid way to find out
exactly what the experiencer is, what it
does, and what it observes.
What is and then you say, well, what is
it that's bored?
What what is it? What aspect of myself
is it that's bored and complaining and
what is it complaining of? There's
nothing interesting going on.
What do I get out of interest?
What do I get out of things that are
interesting?
a sense of aliveness and excitement of
the spirit or of the ego. Uhhuh. So you
see
it's the animal
wanting constant entertainment.
All right. It likes excitement and it
dreads boredom because boredom is almost
like death. It works off desire and it
has afraid fears it won't get. It looks
for status and fears being a nobody. It
wants to be noticed and is afraid it'll
be ignored.
It wants to express its opinions about
everything and it dreads just being
ordinary.
Free speech is
circus. Yeah. I had a good friend I knew
for many years and he came to me one day
and he said, "I just made the most
amazing discovery." I said, "What is
it?" He says I don't have to have an
opinion on everything.
He said, 'I never experienced such
freedom. You I no I don't have a view
have to have a viewpoint. I don't have
to have an opinion. I don't feel called
upon to express my free speech, take a
stand and get out there with a plaque
card.
Uh so it was freedom.
All right.
Not. You don't have to have an opinion.
And it's okay to be ordinary. It's okay
to be ordinary.
In fact, it's really good to be ordinary
for when they're looking for who to
shoot. It this pays off.
Otherwise, you said you with the pink
mustache and the red hair standing on.
Come over here, you son of
No, you want to blend in. My My survival
technique when I was young was to blend
in with the woodwork.
Blend in with the woodwork.
In boot camp, it's below zero in Great
Lakes, pitch black in the morning. They
get you all up. You got to run around
the the the thing a lap, a mile.
No breakfast, nothing in the black at
Timber.
So I discovered the way to do is just
blend in, not be noticed. And they had
lockers and you could open the locker
and as they went out.
I did that all through boot camp.
You just blend in. They'll never notice
you. See, if they notice you, they would
be out in the field and they'd say,
"Where's Hawkins?" You know. No, by
being anonymous, he never noticed it.
One time I did get caught and I had to
do two laps around. But but most almost
the whole time except that once
the way to survive is to become
invisible. See, that's the value of
camouflage.
So, if you're aggressive, you stand out
there and you avoid an aggression. See?
And if you're good, well camouflaged.
That's why I'd like to be an octopus. If
I was going to be something, you just
like look like everything else around
you.
All right?
So, we seek status. We want to be
noticed. We want to have an opinion. The
ego is constantly craving things. And it
dreads frustration. It dreads not having
it. And therefore, to achieve all of the
above, it wants control. It wants
control.
And it has an aversion to accepting.
It wants to control the world and
control out there instead of
change the world instead of changing
yourself.
If you don't like the world the way it
is,
then change yourself.
Do the world a favor.
All the wondrous dogooders, the great
monarchs, the great rulers, all the
dogooders are dead.
Their dynasties are dead
to establish the greatest nation on
earth. They're all dead. They're all
dead.
All dead.
Instead of changing the world, change
yourself.
If the word God over the courthouse
makes you uncomfortable,
then change yourself.
Why would it make you uncomfortable? And
what do you care?
There's always protesters out about some
issue that doesn't even involve their
life. It's all in their head, you know.
All in their head.
Oh god. So it craves and what it wants
is control. So the one of the biggest
surreners you can make is letting go,
wanting to control things. Letting go,
wanting to control because evolution is
evolving in a certain way. And therefore
to try and control it, you don't even
know what you're asking for.
You know, you're grabbing onto a high
voltage wire when the minute you try to
control things. And the karmic
consequences are so the best wisdom is
to surrender it to God as surrender the
world to God. Huh?
The ego doesn't like that. The spiritual
ego wants to save the world. Save the
world.
What are you going to save it from?
from what
the Buddha
Jesus Christ all the great avatars
Socrates
said the only problem that that exists
in the world is ignorance so if you're
going to sol do anything for the world
all you could do is try to o to educate
and overcome ignorance huh the world you
see doesn't even exist see you see it as
injustices
and that's from your position You see
there's an injustice from this position
over here. It is justice.
Interesting program the other night.
Very good one on slavery.
Best one I never saw slavery explained
that way. I think on the history channel
contextualize it in terms of the
economics of the day. Uh the religious
beliefs of the day. Uh the United States
had more money invested in slaves than
in any other industry. It was the
biggest industry of the entire economy.
All different aspects
which I'd never seen before until it was
contextualized
uh from a greater dimension.
Its economic weight, its impact on every
just about every aspect of society.
Therefore, relinquishing it was not just
a religious
uh belief of equality. It had to do with
pulling the drain on the entire economy,
the entire economy. So now you
understand it a little bit differently.
You feel a little less judgmental about
it. All those bad southerners and all
this.
And when it's recontextualized now, it
takes on a different significance and a
different meaning. different meaning.
All right. So, it was the economy of the
day.
The ego likes novelty, hates boredom and
sameness, and it gets addicted to
thrills. Afras is going to miss out on
something.
The sound of the motorcycle raising.
That's a come on, boys. Get get into the
excitement. Get into the risk. Get into
the danger. Uh yeah, the novelty,
addicted to thrills. People will go to
such extremes, it's uh mindboggling.
Uh this guy, this Frenchman that has a
compulsion to climb all the tallest
buildings in all the major cities in
Europe
like a human fly,
goes up the outside of these marble
buildings
and they keep arresting him and bringing
him down. And in China or someplace,
they put him in jail and beat him with
rods to make him stop doing this thing.
and he wouldn't stop. As soon as he's
out, he's back doing it again, you know.
Oh, yeah.
So, he has an addiction to the thrill.
The attraction here is to be aggressive.
The fear is passivity.
Here, you want to gossip and here you're
afraid you're going to be left out of
what's going on. The addiction to want
to be fashionable instead of being drab.
And of course, it's very necessary to be
right. In fact, being right is more
important than life itself.
Oh yes, people lay down their lives by
the tens of millions.
By the tens of millions, whole
generations, whole societies, whole
cultures, whole nations,
rather than admit they were wrong.
Isn't that something?
>> The ego's out to kill you.
Better to be dead and right
then wrong and live. Huh? Yeah.
Realize how powerful that is. Whole
regimes, whole political parties,
multi-millionaires,
all kinds of people stake their entire
life on being right. And they will lie
through their teeth. They will perure
themselves. They'll put their hand on
the Bible and swear to tell the truth
and lie through their teeth.
When you know how to do kinesiology,
it's always fun to watch the there's
always a major mystery murder murder on
trial.
There's always some some kind somebody
is up on some kind of major trial. And
of course, within seconds of
kinesiology, you can tell whether
they're guilty or not, you know. So this
guy did it or not. You got it. Now it's
going to take these 12 people
couple million dollars worth of time,
lawyers fees and all. Hey, you already
got it.
All right. So being right is very
important to be superior because by
being right you become superior and you
dread being common. What is that dread
of being common? Being looked over, not
being special.
If you let go of that one, you let go of
the attraction of a lot of positions.
It's better to be anonymous.
You live a lot longer if nobody knows
who the hell you are.
You don't have to go around the the
track below zero.
All right? So it wants to be superior
and for some reason it just hates being
common. It wants to speak up instead of
shutting up.
99% of speech is really non-intigorous.
If you calibrate the level of free
speech as a concept,
it's like I don't know 340 or something.
If you calibrate it as it is practiced
in the United States right now, it's
about 187.
Now, people talk about free speech is
that as though that is the highest prize
of civilization.
Think about it. Is that the highest
prize of civilization?
That any idiot can go on TV and just
rattle away?
Is that the highest good of mankind?
Should we die for that?
Speaking up is usually about 99% ego and
1% fact. 1% fact.
1% fact. The rest is people like to hear
the hear themselves talk. Huh?
So being silent then is anathema to the
ego. The ego is stubborn. Hates to give
in. wants to be famous, hates the idea
of being anonymous.
All right. The attra attraction to
change here is resisting and to defend
defend your position rather than to give
in because to give in is giving up being
right.
And it views success as getting what it
wants. So whatever the ego decides it
wants, that is success. Huh? And it
believes that that is happiness. more
money, more sex,
more whatever.
The attraction to the ego is that of
specialness. It has an aversion to
commonness. It wants more and is afraid
of having less.
I don't know. Didn't the ego ever have
less? I mean, it's great
less. There's lots of things. Just think
how wonderful it would be if you had
less of them. All right. To own a thing
then is its claim of specialness. And in
reality, it doesn't want to look at the
fact. It only has temporary stewardship.
No matter what you own, it's only a
temporary stewardship.
Temporary stewardship. You can't
actually own anything. To own it, you
would have to be it.
That's a nicity of comprehension.
To own this, I would have to be it.
Otherwise, all I have is a claim. Claim.
The attraction is to attraction itself.
The aversion is to plainness and
ordinary words.
The ego with the wind will like to warp
facts and it really dislikes the truth.
It dislikes the truth.
We'll see what the reaction is to the
book going all culting truth versus
falsehood.
We'll see how popular the truth is.
Right.
>> Couple weeks through soon. Anyway, all
right.
It wants to warp facts and every night
you can hear that on television. Uh the
interviewer asks the person the
question, he doesn't answer the
question. He sidesteps it and gives you
some alternate subject.
That's you can tell he's a politician
right the way.
The ego wants to condemn rather than
forgive.
So how can we forgive such violations of
the truth? It's because we see that the
ego unabated
is addicted and has to win. It doesn't
have any choice. It chooses only the
good and the good is to win. Therefore,
we forgive the politician for lying
through his teeth and
with his hand on a Bible lying through
his teeth. And you say, "God,
the karma of that, you know, when you
get on the other side,
when you get on the other side, but
we're spiritually aware." All right. So,
we know that there are karmic
consequences.
To warp the facts then is what politics
is all about. The ego wants to condemn
rather than forgive. It doesn't want
excuse. And the pop the populace
has like a dread of what if a guilty guy
goes free?
You hear almost a panic, emotional panic
that a guilty guy went free. So
So he went free. Yeah, he went free in
the perceptual world, but he did not
escape the karma. All right. Because
All right. So we can forgive. Realize
that people are driven by choosing what
they see as the good. And if the good is
to win, they will sell their soul. They
will sell their soul.
You know the opera Dr. Fostus, you know,
Fostus sells out his integrity of his
soul for temporary gain.
And the end of the opera
is payoff time.
And the doors to hell open. And now now
it's time to pay. Now now it's time to
pay. Yeah. Very interesting. Karmically
correct. And if you calibrate it is
true. All right. It wants to hold on to
things rather than let go.
It wants to dominate rather than
succumb.
It's interested in the linear content
and not the field. Therefore, to win an
argument, you'll notice politically
people always ignore the context. They
always ignore the context
because if they included context, what
they're saying would be idiotic. Huh?
Yeah.
I won't go into current examples, but
they're pretty glaring.
It wants abundance and does dislikes for
reality. It wants to be the martyr. If
you can't win, then you can still juice
it by being the martyr and the loser.
And best of all, and very the top of the
popularity list is victim.
You get to be victim instead of being
responsible.
You know who's to blame? It's funny.
watch listening to television, you hear
some catastrophic event, the first thing
the announcer says, "Who's to blame?"
The Brooklyn Bridge fell down. Who's to
blame?
I mean, who cares who's to blame? But
the vindictiveness of the ego, it
instantly looks for who are we going to
blame? And then we're going to hate them
and take revenge on them and beat up.
That's the ego's game. It loves to blame
somebody cuz now you can guiltlessly
hate them and beat up on them and seek
revenge.
You can electrocute them. That's a cool
way to go.
never been demonstrated that capital
punishment has prevented crime at all.
At one time there were 300 different
crimes that all call for capital
punishment.
Did the incident in those crimes
diminish or they did not?
300 crimes were capital. You look at
feudal Europe. You look at the history
of Europe. uh there were monarchs in
which there were hundreds of things for
which you get home etc. and people went
right on doing it anyway.
Right now we have three times an outlaw.
Right?
Twice he's been in prison now. He goes
back. The apologists say you can't put a
man in prison for stealing a pizza.
He had one down, two down, and he cannot
stop stealing a pizza.
Aha.
That shows a mental defect, does it not?
Faced with horrible torture beyond
belief,
traitorism
flourish in the feudal in in the
monarchies of Europe. Knowing that
you're going to be slowly torn to death
and boiled in oil and gruesome deaths,
people did it anyway.
Who the hell? What would you Who cares
who's president?
To get your guy in means you're going to
have your tongue torn out, your eyes
poked in, your ears ripped off, slowly
gutted, and racked on the rack.
People do that all the time.
Huh? All the time. Thousands go to the
guillotine. Go to the Why? Because they
want to be important and be right and in
their eyes save the world.
All right. Conflict is what the ego
likes. It just dislikes peace.
You can see the Middle East, they've had
an aversion to peace for, you know,
thousands of years. And they go into
peace frights periodically, but they
they quickly manage to have a riot and
get rid of it. So
yeah, peace would be the end of the
reason for their existence. Raan and
Tendre of
the fellow that just died there. He
lived off hate and conflict and peace
was the last thing he wanted.
Blame, conflict, the past. The ego loves
to cling to the past and it it avoids
the present. It actually clings to fear
based on the idea that it is because of
fear that you survive. It doesn't see
that merely anticipation and planning is
sufficient. But it hangs on to fear.
Planning and caution is all that's
necessary to cross the street safely.
You don't have to stand on the curb
shaking with fear. You anticipate the
oncoming. You're anticipating. So you
act from caution rather than fear.
Caution. Huh? That's something the ego
never thinks about. It thinks it's
either, you know, it's only got this or
that.
Ego looks to excuse itself for
responsibility
and it hates being accountable.
Therefore, it likes to deny things
rather than admit and it's impatient and
it hates to wait. Yeah. So, those are
the characteristics generally. Is that
the last one on the tractions and
aversions?
>> Yes.
>> Huh?
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Is that the one we just did?
>> Except we will do a specific one.
>> Did we just do do this or not?
>> We did it.
>> I'll change it.
>> I don't remember doing it.
>> Everybody who thinks we just did it,
raise your hand.
>> Okay, you win.
I would have sworn we haven't done it
yet. Okay,
which was the next one, Betty?
>> Uh,
hey,
>> what?
>> Oh, we're going to look at uh No, we
want to look at um
>> it was 44.
Well, it's a news slide.
Uh 45. We want
>> Yeah, 45. We want to look at shame. We
have two slides on shame.
I was too ashamed to show up. Okay.
Shame is ashamed of itself. I'm ashamed
to be shamed.
>> You can't get to 45.
What?
>> Oh, there's no rush.
>> There's no rush.
The ego's always in a hurry.
We're in no hurry, right?
How can you get a chance to just sit and
do nothing? I mean, it's great.
We got to hurry up because we got Nico
about 10 after 3.
>> Yes, about 10 after. So, we have about
15 minutes.
>> Well, shame seems to have taken a
holiday.
>> I thought we'd start at the bottom.
shame because shame often o shows up as
disgrace, depression, hopelessness,
apathy sometimes takes clinical forms
not infrequently ends up as suicide
or the failure to take the necessary
steps to survive.
Shame is banishment.
In primitive society, your life depended
on the integrity of the tribe,
the local tribe. And
shame, you were banished. When you were
banished from the tribe, you died.
You had no means of survival. The wild
animals got you. You died of starvation.
Uh so shame was equivalent to death.
And shame is at calibration 20 is very
close to death.
People shrink with shame. They
disappear. They try to become invisible.
Self-hatred, the giving up of all hope.
Clinically, it requires treatment. Why?
Because the person in shame is lacking
energy and doesn't even have the energy
to avail themsself of available energy.
It can't even take advantage of what is
available.
Therefore, it is the lowest level. Huh?
Disgrace, banishment, shame, despair,
and hopelessness are the bottom of the
box.
not infrequently leads to death.
>> Clinically, uh it means if you see them
clinically, yeah, uh it's a
pharmacologic problem. It also has
correlated correlations in brain
um chemistry, neurochemistry.
The depletion of necessary
neurochemicals
allows one to drop to the depths.
The alternative actually is death
itself. And unless someone takes action
on the person's behalf, they will die.
This is a consequence of many things.
Denial of God is one thing.
Karmic consequence is another
abandonment.
Karmic consequence can be quite severe.
It is also paradoxically the degree to
which some people have to hit bottom for
the ego to give up.
It's only when
you're clinging to life by one or two
fingers that you're willing to let go.
The depths of hell,
hopelessness and despair
beyond description,
and the hopelessness and the despair and
the agony is eternal.
At that level, you get what that means.
Forever
you are condemned to the dark, to the
blackness, to hopelessness
without the possibility of any
intervention from anywhere.
And time stops.
And just like the top levels of
consciousness are beyond time, you
experience eternity. Anybody who's had a
near-death experience knows what that
is. It's outside of time. At the bottom
of the pits is the same timelessness.
The soul is lost and abandoned
forever.
As you descend to through hell,
the top level is agony,
suffering, torture,
child's play, jacks for openers.
What the real considers hell is
just the opening chapter.
Then it gets more severe and the agony
is beyond description. And then time
stops.
As I've mentioned before, as you descend
into the pits of hell,
you come to a knowingness which Dante
knew.
Abandon all hope, ye who enter here.
There it was, just as plain as day, is
all written on a bulletin board. How
Dante knew it, I don't know.
And from there, it gets bad.
And then you experience like damnation,
hopelessness for eternity.
Out of the eternity of hopelessness,
then out of nowhere arose a voice that
said, "And if there is a God, I ask him
for help."
And then all of it blacked out.
And the next thing was
standing in the full radiance of
divinity as the allness of creation and
life itself.
If that's what it takes, then that's
what it takes.
I wouldn't recommend it, but
if that's what it takes, that's what it
takes. Therefore, when I see people do
serious violations, serious spiritual
violations that I know have very bad
karmic consequences, it makes me shudder
because I know what's coming.
Remember that kid who was executed?
What did he do? Blow up a building or
something? And he said, "Well, I know
I'm going to hell, but there'll be good
company there." When he gets there,
you'll find it isn't that way at all.
It's agony. So if that's what it takes.
So some people
uh at the bottom of the have to go all
the way to the bottom
in order to find God.
The ego's struggle for survival at least
in this case was ferocious.
It was ferocious. It was
it would not let go.
That's what it took to make the ego let
go. Huh? Usually just swimming it on the
fingers will do it, but no.
Oh god, I must have had the ego of a sea
urchin or something out of the sea, you
know.
All right. So the attractions a shame is
held into place besides karmic factors
which in this case was the karma of
having denied the reality of God in
other lifetimes having defied and
perhaps even worse than that. Uh so that
was the undoing of that. All right.
One thing attractive about shame is you
get to punish yourself.
Therefore, to forgive yourself would be
just what you won't do.
The attraction is to stay depressed. The
aversion is to choose life. Sometimes it
takes electric shock treatments to take
the person out of that.
The attraction is judgmental and being
judgmental against yourself instead of
surrendering to God's mercy.
The attraction here is to be negative
rather than let go of your position
shame. You sh you you shrink. You hide
and you don't want the light on you to
be visible. You see yourself as
worthless and your aversion is to affirm
the gift of life itself.
Here your view of self is unforgiving
and rigid and you don't want to correct
it and be flexible.
So if somebody's stuck in this and I
tell them what Socrates teaching is,
they'll say, "Well, that's okay." But
they won't apply it. Huh? So they cling
to it. A rigid self view.
Rather condemn than forgive.
It seeks mortification
rather than to choose self-worth.
The physicality was a gift of being a
human.
What would be the point of mortifying
it? But the downside, the Gothic side of
religion at one time was very into
mortification of the body. Sackcloth and
ashes, hair shirts. Huh.
The attraction here is to denigrate
value and worth rather than to honor
yourself.
All spiritually aligned people owe it as
an obligation to honor oneself to honor
one's dedication.
You owe it to yourself out of honor.
Yeah. To honor. Yeah. Here I'd rather
denigrate
because then it can indulge in
self-hatred.
The ego loves hatred.
It loves negativity. The ego survives on
the juice it gets out of its positions.
See the ego has no condundalini
spiritual energy from which to thrive
only animal energy. So it has to extract
juice every ego position in order to
survive.
The condundolini energy is some
completely different. All you have to do
is say yes to it and it influences the
field and things come about
effortlessly.
The downside is it loves severity rather
than being benign.
You see the severity selfagulation
suicide
and the downside of current war it's in
balanced and it doesn't want to see both
sides. Doesn't want to hear the other
side of the story. wants to keep
maintain a distortion. Next slide.
>> That's it for you.
>> That's the next slide.
>> So, keep going.
>> Is this a different slide?
>> Oh, okay.
It's a different slide. All right. Here
you like to blame yourself
rather than blame the ignorance of the
ego. So that you refute Socrates wisdom.
Socrates wisdom is at 570. And if you're
more higher than 570, it's okay to
refute Socrates.
I hate somebody at 170 telling me
Socrates don't know what from us.
Yeah.
All right. So blame the self instead of
seeing that that we all make the best it
seemed like the best decision at the
time. So to blame yourself you have to
to stop blaming yourself you have to see
that the context was different and the
person you are now is not the same as
the person you were then. See who you
are now is not what you were. So what
you were was uh more limited. Huh? And
okay so it wants to maintain its partial
selective view to justify rather than a
balanced. It wants to see the self as
loser rather than see himself as
corrected.
It wants to see life as the end of the
road instead of the opening to the new.
I'll tell you in the pits of hell I had
no idea that was the road to the opening
of the new.
the opening of the new wife. Here you're
absolute absolutely unlovable
and you deny your worth as a child of
God. All that exists arises out of one
source. So it's a denial of the truth of
who you are. Here you see error as
unforgivable.
Here you see it as a lesson. Well, leion
is correct too.
All right. So, so all these ego, this is
a narcissistic orientation. It's all me.
Oh, me my guilt. Oh, me my error. Oh, me
how unforgivable. You see how me that
is? It's just me all over the place.
Instead of being concerned for others
here, you're serving your personal self.
Here you're going to serve life. You can
see this is an enormous self-indulgence
to wallow in guilt and shame and penance
and sackloth and ashes and drag yourself
around as the poor suffering martyr.
I know people have tragedies, routine
tragedies which everybody has to face 30
years ago and they're still juicing
them. Still juicing them,
you know, still juicing them.
All right? Because it's selfindulgent.
It sees self as center of life rather
than just a part participant.
It focuses on oneself instead of on
others. So you're constantly dumping
your misery of what happened 30 years
ago and trying to milk people in the
present. Huh? And here you got
retrospective falsification when you say
should have rather than real realizing
you were not able to at the time when
you I mean you believe what you thought
was true at the time and you acted to
the best whether it turns out to be an
error later is you know something
differentable. So you have to get off
the self-indulgence, the attraction.
>> What?
>> Yeah, we're going to have Nico next.
So all right. So that's the first bottom
ego position. Shame. You see, it's
attraction. It's with a group like this.
It's not where you live, but it's a
temporary thing that comes up. You
recall something from childhood. Some
selfishness. you know, you took the last
kit cookie and your little sister cried
and you're ashamed of that. So, it comes
up as a fluctuation,
but at the time you were only four years
old.
>> Yeah. And if you didn't get the cookie,
you thought your mother didn't love you.
I remember my sister's birthday. I was
like three or something or four and I
started to cry. My sister's birthday.
So, I started to cry and I said, "Why
you why you crying?" I said, "Cuz
everybody's bringing her presents.
I didn't realize that has to do with
birthday." So, she had to explain to me
what birthday means. You know what I'm
saying?
>> Yeah.
>> So, what you were at the time at four, I
didn't understand that that's an annual
event and people bring everybody was
coming to see her and give her presents
and I wasn't getting anything and
nobody's paying attention.
So when you're looking at your past,
just remember that you were only a
three-year-old at the time.
>> That was a bad stock to buy, right?
So you got real calm and it became worth
22 cents. Well, at the time that's what
seemed the right thing to do. So to
forgive yourself you have to remember in
the context of the time who you are and
what you believed that's why you acted
that way. So it's a falsification now to
project the past because the past is not
the same as the present you know. All
right so we're going to break. Nico is
going to chant and after that we're
going to have questions and answers.
I don't want to forget my I don't want
to forget that. I have to collapse it.
I have to collapse it. Yeah.
Let's see. I got to move these things
out of the way. All right.
>> Everybody relax.
after that.
So, uh I would like to have everyone
hold in mind after what was just talking
about and we're going to take a giant
leap, okay? and
of our consciousness.
And the Buddha said, "Sit upright,
chant the sutra,
and recognize
that this is the last moment of your
life."
And a common mortal since time without
beginning
will emerge
your eternal self.
Go there with me.
foreign.
Day
one day and all day and all day
and all day and all day
all Back home
day.
Foreign
speech. Foreign speech. Foreign speech.
You opening
You need
a woman.
going
for
God.
No.
me.
No
meow.
Horing miracle.
Deep breath.
Enjoy your break.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.