Thank you so much for helping me.
And my question has to do with prayer.
That's right.
Prayer.
My question has to do with prayer.
And since September 8th is going to be a big unity prayer day,
I feel compelled to participate in the prayer day.
And my question is, in a group like this, with all of us together with intention of prayer,
could we raise the consciousness of the world by joining together on that day to pray?
It's not a cause and effect relationship.
It's a contribution.
By ourselves, we can't lift the level of the ocean.
But all of humanity together by intention constantly raises the level of the ocean.
And everyone floating on the ocean gets lifted.
But not by cause and effect.
But by virtue of that which you have become.
By your intention of what you have become.
So you contribute to the overall field, and the field is what lifts people.
So if we did it in a group, if I went to a group to pray, the intention of the group...
I don't know whether...
See, that's numerical causality again.
Okay.
You know, we have permission to ask this.
A group prayer is more efficacious.
More efficacious in raising the level of mankind than just individual prayer resistance.
Group prayer is, yes, efficacious.
And I'm glad you mentioned it.
Because what is the date again?
I forgot it.
September the 8th.
September the 8th is Unity Prayer Day.
I forgot to mention it.
I had that on my list to mention it.
Unity, annual Unity Prayer Day.
Right.
So that's a powerful time for all of us.
That is an excellent time to pray.
Yes.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Hi, Doctor.
Hi, Susan.
Well, my question is, I'm an interpreter.
I speak several languages.
And to work, I do it automatically.
So I can be...
I'm able now to just witness the interpretation process and step back of it and just witness what's going on.
And when I started...
When I started reading and studying your material, I realized that it was good for me to start knowing something about meditation because I was clueless and I started working on the Course in Miracles.
So all of a sudden, one day I was driving and I realized for a second that there's no separation.
There is no out there and in the in here, and I felt a huge vertigo, like I need to hang on to and hold on to something because I felt like it was weird.
Am I on the right path or I need a doctor?
Yeah, you're on the right path.
Meditating when you're driving may not be the best deal.
Yes, there's a reorientation because of the shift of context.
And when you go into a really incredible space, you may not be able to function for periods of time because where you are in space and people keep talking to the body and you've got nothing to do with the body and they think it's you.
So it has to do with reorienting yourself within a new context.
The sense of strangeness disappears.
You just keep surrendering and praying.
And then it settles down.
It settles down.
It's like wearing...
different glasses, very similar to wearing different glasses.
You can actually see better than you could before, but there's a reorientation and that's how you felt was that reorienting yourself to a shifted context.
Also, devotion and spiritual will.
Is devotion a quality of the spiritual will?
Or is it the same thing where I just forget about it and just keep doing what I'm doing?
Will is more like a stated intention, a decision.
And devotion is more dedication and love.
When you combine the two, you have devotional non-duality, which is the book I'm finishing now.
You have devotion to truth.
You have devotion to truth, see?
What gives it power is not only intention, which can be just mental.
But also the will.
And devotion comes from the heart.
So the power of the heart then energizing the will and reason and intellect.
Yeah.
Thank you.
You got it right.
I've heard you talk a lot about the 400s and the 500s, but between 500 and enlightenment is the 600s.
And you haven't mentioned much that I've heard about that.
Are there any milestones in the 600s or things to let go of?
Yeah.
Yes.
Those are, we're going to, we're doing the levels now.
Yeah.
In the beginning, we do the levels below 200.
Then we go from 200 up to 600.
All right.
From 600 up are the levels, specifically, formally, those of enlightenment.
Sat Chittananda, Silent Bliss is at 600.
The problem of how to get from 600 on up is infrequent because most people leave at that point.
Some continue on, you know.
But without motivation to do.
In 600, there is no motivation.
Everything is perfect, still, infinite, peace.
It would not come up that there is anything further.
So anything you learned about it would probably be useless.
But anyhow.
There is that which is, it does not seem possible to the ego that there is anything beyond 600.
Because everything is peaceful.
There's nothing that you desire.
There's nothing you fear.
Whether the body continues on or not is irrelevant.
Infinite stillness, peace, and bliss.
Consciousness, then, of its own.
But apparently, if it's not.
But apparently, if it's karmically attuned to do so, will continue on its own.
And even rarer still, it will go on up higher and higher.
Usually in the 700s, it will stay there.
The best known sages of recent decades.
In 700 and something, it just stays there.
It's just a karmic propensity.
And then it may start, extremely rarely, to move on up even higher.
You know when it's doing that.
Because there's a considerable discomfort at 800.
The nerves feel like they're on fire.
The slightest thing that's out will make it quite severe, in fact.
And you're beyond personal karma.
Now what's holding you up is something from the collective consciousness of mankind.
To which you have ascribed due to humanness.
At 800, you begin really sort of agonizing.
And the dedication to continue on is what drives you through it.
At that level, I remember.
The information needed to transcend that level came in the form of finding a copy of a Buddhist text
in the drawer of some foreign country.
And recalling that the Buddha said his bones felt like they were broken.
At that point, it became okay.
Thank you.
Yes?
A group of us who are here today, some of us are here today,
recently were around a swami who manifested jewelry and vibhuti, holy ash.
Yes.
And we want to know if this phenomenon of manifesting
can happen when the teacher is below 540.
And perhaps more importantly, what is the purpose of manifesting these objects
if it is indeed happening?
What does this really have to do with enlightenment?
I don't know what all that has to do with enlightenment.
But we have permission to do vibhuti.
Vibhuti calibrates over 200.
199.
Vibhuti calibrates around 200.
Anyway, it has to do with confusing.
It's really, it has to do, I've written a chapter on the cities.
S-I-D-D-H-I-S.
So these are the phenomena, paranormal phenomena.
They begin to occur in the 500s.
Become quite marked around 570.
Become almost continuous.
The miraculous is continuous.
You're clairvoyant, clairaudient.
The miraculous is the common.
You hold a parking place in space in mind.
And when you get there, there it is naturally.
Various phenomena.
The so-called miraculous occur.
These are the consequences of kundalini energy.
It has nothing to do with you.
If a person identifies them and begins to,
you have no control over them.
The energy does what it does under the direction of the Holy Spirit.
Yeah?
Yeah.
So what she's talking about is,
it has to do with magic control.
It has to do with the egotism of the cities.
It has to do with claiming the cities
as a consequence of one's personal self.
Yes, that's okay.
So it's a...
It's what impresses the public.
Right.
So it, could it be then dangerous because it...
To seek it for its own sake, yes.
Because to seek the cities is obviously an ego,
attraction to the spiritual ego.
To merely want to be able to levitate, fly,
and all those things,
is obviously an attraction to the spiritual ego.
Those things are spontaneous.
Spontaneous.
Just like the miraculous is spontaneous.
Somebody is brought to have lunch with you.
You look at them and suddenly you get from the energy
they've brought you...
They brought her because she has something terribly wrong
and they're hoping for a miracle.
So you look at the person with the love you feel towards all
and include them in the divinity of the presence
and then either cures or doesn't cure.
It's got nothing to do with you at all.
Sometimes they walk away cured.
It happens of its own.
So there is no person doing miracles.
There is no performer of miracles
because the miraculous is the consequence
of the presence of divinity as the whole field
which then pulls forth the karmic,
the karmic propensity.
So the apple falls from the tree
when it's karmically ripe.
Not because you are causing it.
So we witness the miraculous.
And it's always spontaneous of its own.
There's no me causing that.
There's no this causing that.
So why jewelry?
I don't know. The glamour of it?
Okay.
Glamour of it.
Theatrics of it.
Thank you.
Yeah.
How can I hide this?
Oh, here, huh?
I have a question that's along the lines
with what we were just talking about, levels.
And in reading your material and your lectures
you state that the ego gets transcended
at level 600.
And something that keeps sticking to my mind
when you talked about Muhammad,
when he calibrated at 700
and through almost a simplistic misinterpretation
of the sword of truth made a great fall.
He was attacked by the Luciferic energy.
Because as you get higher, you get attacked by that
which is the enemy of truth.
Because truth will reduce its dominion.
You're attacked by the demons.
Okay.
I mean, a book on truth versus falsehood,
how popular do you think that's going to make you?
Right.
That's why I waited until I was older.
You see?
When you tell the truth, quickly you leave town.
So I'm prepared, you know.
So it has nothing to do with ego.
It has nothing to do with an ego structure
where something was offered, you know,
in some sort of power, you know, control.
Or anything like that.
It was more of an attack, you said.
You're saying that happened to Muhammad.
I think he had a vulnerability
and the Luciferic saw the energy and shot into it.
The same happens with alcohol intoxication.
You know, demonic possession is very frequent in intoxication.
And then he will take over the domination.
So when he had a temporal epileptic fit, see,
his defense was down and the energy saw fit.
So it reversed mercy and turned evil into good.
That's the classic Luciferic conversion.
The worship, you know, as Ben Laden says when he comes on,
we worship death, you worship life.
That is the difference.
You can see that is not a traversable.
That is not a traversable track.
Do you understand that?
That is not traversable.
Not yet.
It's 180.
How do you traverse 180?
Okay.
Thank you.
I've told you what happened with this person,
this entity here, you know.
In a very high space, beyond all personal karma,
came out of nowhere a silent knowingness
in the form of a temptation.
I mean, I see it as a temptation.
It came as a silent attraction
via a non-verbal knowingness.
Now that you realize you've transcended all personal karma,
that there is no accountability,
all power is yours, own it.
That's what the knowingness said.
Inasmuch as I couldn't see what the hell you want to do with power,
it'd be a drag and a nuisance,
and the self is all that is,
I turned it down.
Also, very few people have been there,
so I saw who was there,
and I saw the answers they gave, yeah?
Mm-hmm.
That's called the Luciferian temptation, yeah?
It came to Jesus Christ in the Gethsemane.
So as you advance, we haven't gotten that far yet.
But when we get advanced to the levels,
we sort of look at, we did the levels below 200,
because they're the most painful,
when people get their foot out of the bear trap.
But then the higher levels will go,
and then the very highest levels.
In transcending levels of consciousness,
I go into the 600s, 700s, 800s,
and up, and I do in devotional non-duality.
That's a very limited audience for that kind of information,
so I'm not going to take up the public's time with it.
But for people who are driven,
driven in sort of a spiritual insanity,
you're willing to go through hell to get to it.
Some people will get there.
To have heard of the truth will then
summon forth from the vibration and the aura
to the knowingness of what to do with that temptation.
Why would you choose that which you already are?
That would be denying the reality of what you are already,
to say, well, I choose power over others.
That's a very hot question.
How about an easy one?
I'll see what I can do.
First, I want to thank you again
for the incredible work you do.
You just helped me in my life in so many ways.
This book, Truth vs. Falsehood,
really forced me.
I'm glad you put the caveat in the beginning.
Yes.
You do pay attention to the caveat.
Yes, I paid attention,
and I waited until I could handle it,
which I don't know if I still could,
but thank you.
Somebody said,
it's just ouch, ouch, ouch, taking off band-aids.
That's all.
We got an email this week that said,
reading your book is ouch, ouch, ouch.
It's like ripping off band-aids.
Very true.
See, people get so attached to their view
that it's painful to let their view go.
You see what I'm saying?
Yes.
I actually wrote a letter of apology
to President Bush
because I felt so bad.
Okay?
So, okay.
He's a human being like you or I.
Probably does the best he thinks
in the situation he's in,
and I wouldn't take his job
for all the money in the world,
I tell you.
Because no matter what you do,
you're going to be made wrong,
you know?
Very true.
I have one comment.
Yes.
I'm a little disappointed
in the book.
Oh.
Just because you have the Fortune 500 companies.
I work for Best Buy.
They weren't listed there.
I was waiting to see.
They're not in there.
Do you know what they calibrate at?
Yeah, I do.
Oh, no.
Don't.
I think we did some of them in there.
Yeah, there's some,
but Best Buy wasn't listed.
And not the one that you want to buy,
yeah?
No.
Not the one that you want to buy,
yeah?
Well, no.
I work for them.
Oh, you work for them.
Yeah.
You see,
if you read literature like this,
you develop an intuitive eye.
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah, you know, that's a fact.
I mean, you know,
we've done thousands.
Yeah.
And somebody will hand me a book
and say,
what do you think this calibrates?
A number shoots into my head already,
240.
I already know what it's likely going to be.
Mm-hmm.
But I wait until I verify it, see?
You know,
and as I start to turn to her,
as I start to use the arm,
we'll go up, see?
And I say,
it's 270,
it's 275,
it's 280.
She goes down at 280.
She said,
it went out at 275.
The energy shot down at 275,
but it takes the muscles that long to respond.
But she got the flash of the energy.
Yeah.
Okay.
You work for a specific company or a group?
No,
Best Buy Company Incorporated.
Okay.
That's what they are.
Oh,
the yellow tag people?
Yes,
yellow tag people.
Oh,
yeah,
yeah.
Yes.
They're the one that have the,
what do you call a squad now?
Yeah,
the Geek Squad.
What do you call it?
The Geek Squad.
Geek Squad.
Oh,
I love the idea of a Geek Squad.
I would go for them just for the Geek Squad.
All right.
We had a couple of Geek Squad people come to our house from playing.
Man,
they were good.
Shoot,
man,
all of our staff,
you know,
we were completely puzzled.
These guys,
they're real,
they really are good geeks.
Thank you.
So,
just the fact that you added geeks,
I'll vote for you.
All right.
Okay.
Now,
my actual question is,
Yeah.
when the spiritual intention is set,
or the spiritual will and intention is set,
does it kind of speed up karma,
karma clearing?
Does karma just kind of,
as you're moving forward,
karma just kind of come up quicker and quicker?
Well,
each step,
you know,
eases,
opens the door to the next.
It like waits,
because it's like a sequence.
So,
as you move this,
you move,
remove that block,
and that avalanche falls of its own weight.
Yeah.
Thank you.
I intuit that it's an interiorist company.
Okay.
That's good.
Thank you.
I'll keep my job.
Let's see.
It's an interiorist company.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
You know,
I just get the energy of it,
you know.
I mean,
just the geek squad alone will tell you.
These are sharp people,
probably in the 400s,
you know.
You got to be at least in the 400s to be a geek.
It takes brains.
You can't be a dumbbell and be a geek.
And dumbbells wouldn't work for a dumb company.
So,
just the fact that geeks work for it,
already tells me something about the company.
Go ahead.
A while back,
I heard you talk about recontextualizing
maybe my own situation
or someone else's.
And the other day,
I was in the lunchroom
and someone's going on and on
about the wrath of God.
And I opened my mouth.
And I said,
I said,
God is love to him.
Yeah.
Instead of wrath.
And after I went home,
I was thinking,
well,
it got carried away,
the conversation.
You punched him?
Anybody who thinks God's love is going to get it from me.
Didn't you say a while back
that when you're in that type of situation
that someone who's aware of what's going on,
they just say,
so,
so it seems
or something like that.
It just,
right?
Yeah.
It just,
it just,
right?
He should have let that opportunity go.
They should have said,
also,
see,
you know,
Oh,
yes.
Well,
yeah,
they brought up your spiritual night
and you defended the truth,
you know,
Okay.
Yeah.
I felt kind of bad.
I quit giving up,
getting up the night,
see.
I had a terrible time with the night,
you know,
because I hadn't looked at the world,
in a long,
long time.
And then when I did
God you know okay yeah thank you yeah thank you very much yes since I've met
you the first time I recognize a lot of distractions in my life mainly mental
distractions and I want to know is there anything what I can do what kind of
mental disruptions like watching TV like gossiping like too much working at the
computer this kind of stuff Oh distractions you know I see what you're
saying yeah you get caught in distractions yeah yes instead of being
focused on the spiritual work yeah okay so you apply the spiritual principles to
the distractions
that's all what does this mean it means what are you juicing out of it the
excitement the drama the glamour are you willing to surrender that let it go you
know what do you get out of it again what do you think is the game could you
surrender the game yeah and then again on the other side what is the aversion
let's say people seek entertainment all the time that's the attraction the
excitement that the vicarious participation
and other people's lives in the drama then the aversion is to let it go
because then I'll be bored well I think about I'll start thinking
about my worries instead of the distraction so you look at what's the
attraction and what's the aversion see what is the attraction and what is the
aversion yeah what's the resistance what's the pull this way and what's the
resistance to be free of the world is not a
attachment, to have neither attraction nor aversion, which is different than non-attachment,
which is different, I'm sorry, than detachment.
Detachment is more like neutrality, but its downside can be flatness, non-participation.
It can lead to a sort of a voidness, a negation.
It's better to be neither attracted nor have an aversion.
I have the feeling I can see it quite clearly, but it feels like a lack of surrender.
But it feels like what?
Lack of surrender.
What is the resistance of surrendering?
It's the fear of...
Yes, you've got to become conscious of it.
You have to...
In your investigation, what is the reluctance to surrendering?
It means you want to maintain control, yeah?
Yeah.
And what is your fear of letting go of control?
That's...
See, so you go inside questioning yourself.
That's how you find the answer.
The ego survives on control, naturally.
It's going to resist, yeah?
The ego is not going to be happy that you want to...
Reduce its dominance in your life, huh?
So it's a natural resistance of the ego.
The ego is narcissistically sovereign.
It's not going to welcome your attempts to transcend it.
It will find excuses, huh?
Yeah.
That's all it is.
Thank you very much.
Can you put that to John?
This is to our...
Just normal resistance.
Put it to John in the morning.
Huh?
Attempt to transcend.
Address this to John.
It's the guy who does our videos.
Will you...
Oh, yeah.
Sure.
Thank you.
Yes.
Hi.
Yeah.
This has to do with my job.
So much confusion.
It's a good job, and I think the company's integrous.
I think the job's integrous.
But it's just ordinary.
It's not...
I feel like I'm not really contributing.
I'm just...
I'm there eight hours a day, every day.
Monday.
Yeah.
And I feel like...
Am I wasting my time?
I mean, the one good thing is it allows me to come here.
I can come to all the talks.
That's the best thing about it.
But am I just wasting my life in this job?
Well, it depends on how you contextualize this work.
How do you contextualize this?
Is it being of service to others?
Is it fulfilling the...
Your own potential?
Yeah.
Is it fulfilling your own potential?
Is it just carrying forth responsibility towards yourself and your family for survival?
Is it the best utilization of your skills?
You know, how you contextualize this value.
I feel like I'm not utilizing my potential, but I'm not sure what I should do, yet it's
integrous.
Yes.
I feel the job is still integrous.
It's just ordinary.
Oh, the ego hates that.
Ordinary.
I know there's
plenty of ego there too
okay so it's because you contextualize
it as being ordinary mundane
pedestrians right
you'll have to learn how to recontextualize
its value
it serves you and the world
it serves survival
it's an expression of your
value of your life to others
you're a valuable cog in the wheel
right
yeah
not everybody has
a life's work
sometimes people say
I was born to do this
we can't all be helicopter pilots
you know
rescue swimmers
those are the heroes aren't they
most of us lead rather mundane lives
you know
we go to work every day
and perform whatever skills we have
you know
and then you know
if you can intuit an alternate
you know
when I'm saying through prayer
you say good lord
is there anything else
you would wish me to do
while I'm here
with my time
and my energy
and my body
I'd surrender my life to thee oh lord
so you pray for God's guidance
in the 12 step group
that's the 11th step
ask God for direction
you know
so you do
you meditate
ask God for direction
and then you let it go
and nothing happens
and then one day
you pick up a magazine cover
and flash
that's it
you know
you just got it
but it's not
cause and effect
it's not volitional
it's not linear
when you let go
and forget about it
trust that God will review
what
God's will is for you
see
and then forget about it
thank you
when it comes up
and hits you in the head
like a
step down a hole
oh that's it
yep
that's what I'm waiting for
thank you
may not be so dramatic
those also serve
who stand in wait
yes
okay
thank you
for your patience
steadfastness
Mary steadfastness
I
I've sort of
confused about something
actually two things
one is
ever since I've been a child
I've been very worried
about the environment
so I'm worried
environment
the environment
yes
and
looks pretty good
the environment here
oh are you talking about
the world's environment
pollution
are you worried
about the world
yeah
oh okay
so
everybody's got to
worry about something. So when I was a child, yeah, I tried to get my friends to take
care of things and critters. Yes. And now I have a cable show where I interview
people to show what's wrong with the environment, what we could do. And I start
feeling sort of, hmm, I don't know if that's the right way to do it. I'm really
confused about whether or not, quote, the environment needs help or what the
status of that is. Well, you see, you walk about in a state in which you see the
sacredness, holiness, deservingness, and divinity of all that exists, and you treat
it accordingly. And then what you do is a consequence of how you, how you
understand it and grasp its significance. Yeah? You serve, you serve all of life
and all of this.
Expressions. Yes? So would you say that the environment is in trouble? Our planet?
You can't be so general. You're asking, you know, is the planet in trouble? I don't know, I couldn't tell you.
All right. Is, uh, are there... The green stuff? Yeah. The animal stuff? Yeah. The oxygen? Yeah.
Everybody does what they can to contribute to the best of their comprehension of
their function in the world. I mean, I see myself automatically
picked up by the world. I mean, I see myself automatically picked up by the
world. I see myself automatically picking up trash because I, I think, you know, it, it conceals the beauty of the world, you know? You find yourself automatically trying to serve the world as best you can just because that's your nature. It's not because of what you do, because of what you are, huh? Divers need a home, so you find yourself hanging in birdhouses. It's not to help the environment, that's, that's too much of a generality, you know?
Well, how it fumes and cars and emissions and smokestacks and greenhouse effects?
What is the cause of all that? We are.
And who is we? Me, yeah. No I'm not.
You weren't. The totality of the population. We didn't have the problem
when I was born, there was only one-one billion people I think.
1.5 billion. No, it's 6 billion. So the problem is not the planet
and the pollution. The problem is people.
You've got so many people, that pollution is automatic. You can't do anything about...
the forests and the pollution and the environment.
When you've got a population running like this,
the problem I see is this population.
Where's the pollution of the ocean come from?
Not people, lots of people.
Southern Asia, there is a cloud,
a dust cloud of haze, etc.,
three miles high.
Three miles high.
Why? Because of the enormous population density.
So, to me, it's foolish to worry about the environment
without first taking care of the population problem.
I can't do anything about that.
I guess I could.
Well, you're going to put your effort somewhere.
Yeah, right.
Why not put it where it counts?
Yeah, that's true.
If you don't want to be poor,
have two kids instead of six.
It's easy.
If you don't want pollution,
don't ask so many people to live by the Ganges River.
Now, I think the crux of it,
environmentalism,
is population sprawl.
Population, you know.
Population.
You know where it's people.
They have to have a living,
so they have to go through the Amazon forest in Brazil.
They have to knock down the forest
because they have to have room for crops to raise the people.
Therefore, the wild animals have to escape.
But is the problem tearing down the Amazon forest,
which is the main source of oxygen?
The Amazon forest is the source,
I don't know, 50% of the world's oxygen or something.
Destroy it, you know.
So why do the people keep pushing in and destroying the forest?
Because there's so many of them.
So you've got good intention.
Why don't you put it to the source instead of the effect?
The environmental impact is the effect.
It's too late already.
Okay.
A hundred kids is going to make a lot of garbage.
Ten times more than ten kids.
And that's all it wants to.
I mean, that's my take on it.
Sounds logical.
The goodwill of your efforts is, you know, laudable,
but I think futile.
While you have a party for the environment,
the bulldozers are relentless.
Giant iron monsters are running,
tearing down the Amazon forest,
which is the main source of oxygen on the planet right now.
So it would seem like education,
education of responsibility.
Yeah?
Yeah.
It's not responsible to have...
It's responsible to have big kids when you can only afford two.
So to somehow raise the educational level.
So what does that is education.
They found that education does more than anything else.
The Celtic, the Celtic tiger turnaround of Ireland
after two centuries of extreme poverty was due to free education.
The higher the education, the less the overpopulation,
the less the pollution, the less the environmental damage.
So I would start more to a central point of where it's all coming from.
Yeah?
Otherwise, you're bandaging things without getting to the fact
that you've got a central infection.
Cure the infection, you don't have all these things to handle.
It's just more efficient.
I see environmentalism running here, running there, running there.
In the meantime, the main faucet is still running, you know?
That's just my take on it, but you asked me.
Well, thank you very much.
Thank you so much for contributing.
All right.
Hey.
Yes.
Dr. Harkins?
Hey.
Yes, indeed.
You have said many times that only 0.4% of the world's population
ever gets to 540 or unconditional love.
Yeah, true.
Given the world's population, though, that's 25 million people.
Good, good math.
All right.
Yet at 60 points higher, at 600, when you wrote Truth Versus Falsehood,
there were only six people there.
What makes that 60 points higher?
Yeah.
So, what makes that 60 points of consciousness so extraordinarily hard
that we start with 25 over one line and we only get six over another line?
To develop from 540 to 600?
Yes, sir.
Well, that's unconditional.
You see, sainthood is at 55-55.
Right.
All right.
Unconditional love is 540.
That itself is extremely unusual, as you know, to 0.4%.
That, to go from there, means practicing spiritual principles
with no exception.
No exception.
Hmm?
Uh-huh.
It means very strict allegiance to spiritual pathway, truth, and techniques
with no variation.
And it means mounting dedication.
Now, from 540, saintliness is around 570.
Then, from there up, you encounter joy.
I forget what joy is that, 580 or something?
Is that ecstasy?
Anyway, from there, you, having let go of all the things that are deterrents,
you go into a state of joy that is not the consequence of anything.
It's the arising of an energy of the realization of the divinity of God
within as the source of one's existence.
This, as you continue to surrender to it, continues on up, gets more than that,
and it becomes ecstasy.
Ecstasy is over 580, 585, 590, 595.
Ecstasy is over 590.
Ecstasy is very close.
Ecstasy is 595, 998, anyway, 598.
The ecstasy itself is extraordinary.
It cannot really be differentiated except by a sophisticated spiritual community
from maybe spiritual mania or something.
In this book, the last book, I wrote how to differentiate spiritual states from pathologic states.
You go from joy, which is relatively impossible to function in the world,
and then you move to ecstasy, where it is impossible to function in the world.
When you go to ecstasy, you go into a state that I cannot hardly describe.
It is ecstatic.
Also, you're tireless.
You can dance forever.
You can dance in front of the altar at midnight to the candlelight
in the ecstasy of the awareness of the presence of God,
and you can do that tirelessly, hour after hour.
You don't have to eat anything.
You don't have to drink anything.
You don't dance.
You are danced by the ecstasy.
Certain symbols from ancient India come to your mind.
Divinity and its expression.
In the Hindu language and religion, culture has certain expressions and styles.
That state, you can become addicted to it.
The ecstasy is so ecstatic that the thought of existing without it is not even thinkable.
Then comes the knowingness in that extremely high state.
This, too, must be surrendered to the ecstasy.
See, O Lord.
And the ecstasy is surrendered to God,
and then you come into the state of profound and infinite peace and bliss.
Absolutely still, exquisite.
You don't need to eat, drink, breathe, or nothing.
Whether the body survives or not is irrelevant.
You're merely the witness.
Sat-cittananda.
State of infinite bliss.
The opportunity to leave, in fact, almost a beckoning to leave, is there.
Most people leave there.
A few remain.
So there's very few, over 600, because of karmic propensity,
because of, I wouldn't say desire to leave, but the option to leave.
Right now, I think there is.
I forget how many.
There were six.
Yes, that's correct.
But you know, when you wrote your first book, there were 12 over 700.
But they leave, they leave, they leave, you know.
Now, they only stay in that state for a certain length of time.
And there's been considerable periods of time when nobody over 600 was on the planet.
Right now, six is quite a few.
Very often annoying.
Centuries go by with not a single enlightened sage.
And you see how rare they are throughout history.
If you take all the greatest sages of history,
put them all together over a time track, you see.
I guess we always thought there were a lot more.
They were just hidden somewhere.
Now, they send off such an energy that they don't just remain suddenly hidden in a cave.
Somehow it radiates out.
Yeah.
Thank you.
The joy is surrendered to ecstasy.
And then the ecstasy is surrendered to God.
You don't know for what.
And then,
is the peace beyond all understanding.
The peace of God, that's 600, yeah.
On the last four charts that you showed,
it seemed to me like the consciousness on the left side was about 190,
and on the right side was about 290.
Which means that the right side becomes another bunch of shoulds,
which then become limitations.
And it seems to me like you need to be neutral,
like the self-forgiveness.
Oh, yeah.
Are you talking about attractions and aversions?
Yeah.
Oh, yes.
So it seems to me even on the right side of the chart,
you need to be neutral to forgiving yourself or not forgiving yourself.
Yeah, it's a very high state.
Yeah.
There is nothing to forgive.
There is no decision to make.
That which you are is perfect.
Yes.
Good for you.
God bless you.
Thank you.
Yes.
Yeah.
Let me see.
Anybody who writes, beats up a book like this deserves a question.
This is the raggedy one I've ever seen.
And it's new.
Thank you for the compliment, yes.
You're welcome.
Yeah, yeah.
I think the main thing is one time you said that
truth is the highest expression of divinity on this plane.
No, not necessarily.
It's only one of the aspects.
It's not the highest?
You can't say, see that's projecting the linear to the non-linear.
There is grace, there is love, there is divine order, harmony, infinite mercy, compassion,
infinite love.
You can't really say that one is higher than the other.
Okay.
In a certain extent, they're all the same.
Different expressions of the same energy.
This way it looks like love, this way it looks like truth, this way it looks like compassion,
this way it looks like forgiveness.
Again, this way it's mercy.
But it's only the same way of being, you know, type of existence.
One is not really higher than the other.
You can choose the option to try to approach enlightenment via one pathway or the other,
which is more individual proclivity.
Many people are more heart people.
Other people would maybe go through the intellect and become Zen,
you know, go for Zen.
Some would go through selfless service.
So the various yogas, selfless service, meditation, bhakti yoga,
would be sort of personal proclivity, you know what I'm saying?
And truth is always relative to the absolute?
Yeah.
It's expression in this plane.
Is relative to the absolute.
Is relative, you know, relative to the absolute, yeah.
Thank you.
See a diamond, this way it looks that way, this way it looks this way.
But it's all the same diamond, what do you call it?
Love, compassion, mercy, omnipotence, omniscience.
They're just different facets of the diamond, you know.
Yes.
Hi.
Very nice to be here.
On the videos you've mentioned several times about the 91st Psalm.
Yes.
So I brought one.
It's from the internet and you probably could link to it.
Uh-huh.
And so I brought one just in case you wanted to make a comment.
I can link on your website.
Yes, thank you so much.
And it's a little bit crumpled from the airplane and everything.
Uh-huh.
Quite a bit crumpled.
So all of the questions that I had, you've already answered.
So every time I have a question at home, I watch a video and the answer comes.
Yeah.
So I have no questions.
Yeah, it's very good for you.
I bet every, I'm constantly surrendering and talking to God.
Yeah, yeah.
And I had some questions.
Yes.
I had a question.
I had some hopes, but then I surrendered them too.
I had hopes of finding a husband, and then after eight years, I had to, I think that
everybody I met was undoing past karma.
There was a lot of .
So again, I surrender even wanting a husband, but it would be very nice.
Oh.
I would.
Oh, then we'll get you one.
Okay.
Thank you.
I think she should have what she wants.
The sweet, adorable lady.
Boy, sweet, adorable ladies.
Where are you?
You better get them while you can.
Thank you.
Thank you very much, Susan.
You know she'll find them.
Mmm.
Yeah.
Okay.
Both of them.
Both of them?
Okay.
My name is Louis.
Thank you very much for being available to us after your, this incredible work and all
the reading I have done.
It's incredible research.
I'm very impressed about that.
I've been a follower and the leader of spiritual group in the past.
In where?
In the spiritual groups.
Yes.
And the spiritual groups have been very helpful to me.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
in a way of a spiritual group, okay? It was Eckengard, okay?
Oh, Eckengard. Yes.
Oh, yeah, yeah. Okay.
My question, I have two or three questions. Can, when we have faith in a spiritual leader,
and I had the experience of grace of God many years ago, and I will never forget about that.
Can, do you understand that? Yes?
She'll tell me what you say.
Okay.
Not Jackson. She tells me what people are saying all the time.
Is it possible that our faith could only lead us to this sense of grace of God and not the leader?
Can we project the faith? Is it based on the grace of God or is it based on the leader of the group?
That's what he's asking.
It's the grace of God. Yes.
So you karmically
embody
the level that you're at, will attract or be attracted to a teacher of that level, see?
But does my faith could make me feel the grace of God even if that leader could be not?
Oh, if the leader is not sufficient for you, then you'll be called away by another leader.
Yes. Somebody will say, you know, so-and-so and, you know, calibrate it and see where it's at, and
then you go through. Yes.
I'm a little disillusion, but, in the end. I remember somebody saying,
yes, he's a great teacher, except he has no energy around the heart. Bang.
And when we are followers, and I was a leader in my area, so are we limited to the level
of consciousness, of the group, or we can transcend this level?
You'll go to it. You'll go in accord of what you're attracted to and if you evolve.
beyond it, you'll lose your interest and find something more exciting and more appropriate, yeah.
So staying could be a drag on my spiritual evolution.
Staying might be a drag on that spiritual effort to transcend.
Yes, that's true. That's true?
Yeah, you know, when it's time to change, somehow it comes to you, it's time to change.
Okay, even if I'm responsible with some people in my area, because I feel a bit responsible also, so...
It would take a little consultation to resolve what you're talking about.
You're talking about multiple issues now.
Appropriateness of the teacher, the appropriateness of the group, and the appropriateness of your role, you know what I'm saying?
It's a little complicated.
Okay. Okay, thank you. You answered most of my questions.
Thank you.
Thank you very much again.
When it's time to move on, it sort of comes in some way to you.
Okay.
Yeah.
Something else begins to click.
Yeah, he got involved with an Eckhart group, now he's lucky to move on.
So nice to be here.
Yeah.
I was wondering about praying for the dying. Is that a good practice? Or would it be helpful?
You know the admonition, pray ceaselessly.
Just pray all the time for everyone?
It is advantageous, we have permission to ask this, it is advantageous to pray for the dying, resist. Yes?
I'm asking because my mother seems to be in that process, and I don't know what, I don't really know how to pray.
I'm used to praying for myself, you know, ask God for help for this and that, but not for other people, because I feel like I'm interfering.
Like I don't know...
You're butting into their karma.
Oh, yeah. Like, how do I know what...
Well, you ask for the highest good for this person and hold them alive.
That's what we did when we did the Ohms, right?
Oh.
I don't know what's the highest good for these people.
Yeah.
Maybe to crash in despair and say, dear God, I ask you, only you, no one else can, you know, in despair.
It's called hitting bottom. So many people find God through hitting bottom.
You can take a typhoon, a hurricane, starvation, and being shot. Just as your body falls over, you got it. So who knows, huh?
Well, I found on the river doing that.
I found on the river doing that, that beautiful Ohm prayer that I was holding in mind these people crying for help.
Yes.
And could I have a different visualization be more beneficial? I mean, what could I...in my mind, I had an image of...
You're trying to control it. Just be who you are with it. Your intention is to help these people and pray for them. That's good enough.
But...
Let God worry about it.
Okay.
I can see you saying thank you to the assistant. She didn't pray very good that time, did she?
Or do you think she's got a scoreboard?
Your intention is the goodwill to express unconditional love towards the people. That's sufficient. The intention is what does it.
Okay.
Yeah.
Would it be all right to use the...to do the Ohm? Because I thought it was wonderful.
You can do whatever you like. You can stand on your head.
You know, cranking a prayer wheel calibrates at 540.
Oh.
Yes. It's the intention. It's not the mechanicalness. It's just a tin thing with things written on it.
It's the intention.
The intention. You know, the intention of genuine reflection. The intention of prayerful hand-plast.
The intention is 540. So the intention of however you pray is sufficient. Okay?
And it seems like prayer helps...
Stop questioning and doubting about it. Just stop and do it at the end.
Don't make it complicated. You're making it complicated.
Okay.
You better see a priest. He'll tell you how to pray.
Let's see. Let's see.
I'm on page 342 here.
This is called the prayer for the sick and dying. I can get you any prayer book. Look it up.
It's called prayer book. Prayers for the sick and dying. Prayers for the deceased.
That's a good place to start.
Take any of them.
Why don't you get a prayer book?
Okay.
They've got it listed. Prayers for the sick and dying. Prayers for certain people in surgery. Prayers for people in pain.
They've got prayers for specific things. So have a professional set up a prayer for you.
That's it. One up for a dollar and a half. Twenty-two bucks.
I'll give you twenty-two bucks.
Get a prayer book.
Okay. Thank you.
Unity should help you too. I mean, you know, Unity has got prayer books for all that stuff. Don't you have a minister around you?
I don't. I've never gone to church.
This lady needs a minister. Hello.
A soul that needs rescuing.
I don't go to church.
I'm selling her for a dollar. Anybody can have her.
There's prayer groups. Like Unity has a prayer group.
Yeah.
You need a prayer book.
There's other denominations.
You need a prayer book. Just an ordinary prayer book.
And if you don't know how to pray for them, then you can have a prayer group.
Yeah. I'll tell you how. It's easy.
Pray book. So, you know, there's other...
Ordinary prayer book. Okay?
Who can?
There's people that will pray for your mother.
Stop in the nearest hotel and look in the drawer next to the bed.
Okay. Thank you, Sarah.
Thank you.
She's sweet.
Yes.
I have a question about surrendering.
Yeah.
It seems like I have selective surrendering.
Some things go away and stay away, and some seem to come back repeatedly.
So maybe...
Repeat that again.
When I surrender some things, they seem to go away and stay away, but others seem to come back over and over.
Others come back?
Yeah. So I was hoping...
You didn't surrender.
Well, not good enough.
When you surrender, it doesn't come back.
True. So maybe you can go over the mechanics of surrendering.
I think I should go over the mechanics of surrendering one more time because some of these things keep coming back.
You may have to do it repeatedly.
Dear God, I ask you to help me let go my attachment to this.
Look at what the payoff you're getting from clinging to it or what the aversion is to letting it go.
You've got to look deeper within yourself to see what the obstruction is, the resistance is.
Some things require repeated surrendering, repeated surrendering because it's a big stack.
It's a big stack.
If it's a short stack of short duration, you can let it go with a few surrenders.
You can do it in an instant.
But if it's a big one, a big one, you may have to do it over and over again and ask for God's help each time.
Then decide what is the quality of that which you're attached to.
You think it's the thing.
It's the thing.
It's not the thing.
It's the juice you're getting out of your attachment to the thing.
That's what you're not willing to surrender, including feeling guilty that you haven't surrendered it.
You know what I mean?
You've got to look at the payouts on both sides.
Thank you.
Some things require persistence.
Just be persistent.
Have you ever got a spiritual counselor?
No.
That's the trouble with today's world.
When we have a spiritual counselor, people really benefit from a spiritual counselor.
They benefit from a spiritual confidant.
Someone with whom to bounce back things.
Everybody really, in my view, needs a mentor.
Everybody really needs a confidant, a confessor.
If you're not Catholic, become one and go to confession.
You know what I'm saying?
Everybody needs sort of a feedback.
In the 12-step groups, everybody has a sponsor.
Everybody does it on their own.
Everybody shares what they're working through.
And then they get feedback from the older, wiser.
See?
The mentor is sadly lacking in today's society.
Everybody needs a mentor.
Or a trusted older friend, confidant.
Somebody who you know has your best interest at heart.
You know?
And you can share their wisdom.
That helps you grow.
It's good.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
The bartender used to serve that assumption, but they...
It's against the union rules now.
Why?
Because if he gives you advice and you take it and it doesn't work, you can sue the bartender.
So bartenders are no longer allowed to be spiritual counselors.
You used to be a bartender.
I was a bartender.
I frankly did give out the best advice I could.
Why?
Because here's a fellow human being in trouble asking you, you know, for...
Feedback.
So if you're just an ordinary human, you feel for the, you know...
Not through sympathy, but through empathy.
I know what it must feel like to have your wife leave you and get fired and all that
all on the same day, you know?
Yeah?
Hi, Doc.
Okay.
Thank you.
Doc, I was recently listening to a lecture, a recorded lecture of the workshop, Intention.
And...
Yeah.
Near the beginning, you said something to the effect that you are going to just tell
us what is going on.
What you're going to do in the workshop is you're going to just tell us what's going
on in the world, consciousness with the ego.
And all you ask us to do is just pay attention and notice it, and that you don't want us
to think about it.
I'm helping to...
I wonder if you can help me understand that without thinking about it.
No, just go ahead.
He said that in the video, Power of the Intention, that you told them that all you wanted them
to do is sit back and listen and absorb it and not really think about it.
Okay.
Fine.
Yes.
What did you do?
Think about it?
Yeah.
I knew I needed help.
Okay.
Thank you.
Bye.
This is why I'm here.
I'll tell you what.
You heard it, that what you heard is imprinted as a frequency vibration in your aura.
When you need to know it, it speaks forth to you from within.
Okay?
Not from memory, because that's either aura or duality.
It's like a knowingness.
Just like, oh, you know what to do.
Okay?
Mm-hmm.
Don't think about it.
Not even a little bit.
Don't think about thinking about it. No, he got it in his heart. He's conscious of the realization.
I'm just here to say, you know, I love what you do and I love who you are
and I don't have a question and I want to cast a vote. I vote for you to, next year,
when you do this six times instead of doing half a day, to do a full day. That's my vote.
His suggestion would serve the highest good.
All right, we'll compromise. I'll talk for in the morning, but all afternoon will be spent with the
group, conversation, being with each other, mingling, sharing, discussing, if we can arrange it.
Thanks a lot.
I didn't ask if it
served the highest good.
It serves my highest good.
It serves my highest good, to agree.
All right.
Thank you, sir.
I knew you were going to get off your feet.
Yeah. Well, I don't know. I'm always afraid. I'm afraid I'm being repetitious, you know,
that I'm repeating many of the same things again. I think other, you know, yeah.
Thank you.
Did you hear what she said?
Surrender.
I can't surrender unless I resist, so I got something to surrender.
Yeah.
My issue is some kind of a reaction that I have if I'm in, let's say, a little group.
It could be a spiritual group and somebody asks a question.
And that is, it's been answered a lot.
Absolutely.
or repeated a lot of other times I'm gonna have to listen to the long answer
I tend to get up and walk out of the room or just feel great impatience when
I also feel that with other drivers sometimes especially when the driver
honks at me and I haven't done much I keep observing this but I keep reacting
impatience you're talking about yeah yeah yeah well impatience is what
willfulness uncurbed willfulness uh-huh there's a child then yeah what went on
about that with you as a child with your mother or your father did you just keep
hollering and yelling to get your way what went on no I think I had a hard
time doing certain things I had a hard time doing it right so I
I
was criticized if you didn't get your way yeah so impatience if you didn't do it
right if you didn't do it right yeah but I don't see these people aren't doing it
right with the questions they ask it's the insensitive so you get impatient
about being bored is that right that's right well what is boredom about
you
what is it about boredom it must be about juicing the ego resisting boredom
yeah I resist boredom yeah you're resisting boredom yes oh who is it this
board what is it this board it's really that leading edge of the ego yeah the
leading edge yeah yeah mm-hmm the leading edge is reporting to you what it
thinks is happening that's not what happening it's reporting to you what's
it's not reporting you what's happening that's why you get bored with it I think
you have to learn to quit thinking
underneath the thinginess is an infinite silence right this instant I'm
tuned into the silence nothing at all is happening do you like that no TV on no
dog barking no nothing going on yes what happens with that in that space basically
Nothing's happening.
Everything's peaceful and quiet.
Is that okay with you?
Yes.
Okay, live there.
Stay there.
Get what that space is and carry it with you as that which you are.
Don't think that peace and silence is out there, it's within you.
Good.
Thank you.
See, the silence is just underneath the thinkingness and the amusement service.
Stay within that.
And whatever goes on is irrelevant.
They're killing each other out there and you say, yeah, uh-huh.
And the water's getting here, right, uh-huh.
And the bullets are flying.
You say, yeah, all right.
Yeah.
So?
All right, so learn how to say so.
Because that negates the value of thinkingness.
So?
So.
Yes.
I'm going to kill myself.
So?
What do you want me to do about it?
Call the cops?
Call the cops or something?
You know what I mean?
Just say so to whatever conversation is going on, in or out, and live in the silence.
The reason why people say it doesn't bother me is I haven't in this life paid any attention
to it.
You look interested, but you don't have any investment in it.
You make appropriate social responses, you're going to kill yourself.
Yes?
Why is that?
You know?
You see, people try to jerk you around and play you with their drama.
When you refuse the drama game, you can live in a peaceful silence and the whole thing's
amusing.
So instead of being impatient and driven, you know, be like the witness of it.
You're just the witness.
From the silence, you witness it all.
The birds come, the birds nest, spring comes, fall comes, wars come, peace comes, the parades
go by.
They pile up the caskets.
It's all the same.
Okay?
Okay, that's good.
Stick with it.
Just stick with what I'm telling you.
Don't try and elaborate.
I will.
Thank you.
Just stay with what I said to you.
Okay?
Thank you.
Okay.
They come, they go.
The seas rise, the seas fall.
The birds fly, the birds fall.
Hello.
Hmm?
Yes?
This morning you talked about the surest way to kill a sunset is for people to talk
about it.
Yep.
Um.
What's the best way to kill a sunset?
As time goes on, I tend, I'm tending to see beauty in just about everything.
As time goes on what?
You've seen the beauty in everything.
Yeah, you see the beauty, right.
Mm-hmm.
And then the tendency of people is to, is to talk about it.
Yeah.
What's, uh, I'm finding annoying.
So it's, I'm wondering how that gets resolved.
Um, it doesn't really.
I told you today, I think it's, I'm not telling you how it's going to be resolved.
I don't know.
I just, you know.
I just don't know.
I don't know.
But I'm trying to think.
that gets resolved? It doesn't really. I told you today, in the great cathedrals of the world,
and I told you if I had to be reborn, I'd like to be a janitor in Shark Cathedral. That would
be the most exquisite possible job, you know what I'm saying? At midnight, nobody's there.
There's yourself in the entire cathedral. Yeah, I've done that, and that sends you
into ecstasy, and there's nobody in the cathedral except yourself, and you go right into ecstasy,
tireless, infinite ecstasy. Yeah, so you can look around the noise that's being made. I mean,
you know, we were there a couple years ago, and you look around the nuisance,
as I say, the same thing happened in front of the Statue of Lincoln in Washington, D.C. there.
Incredibly impressive. Just what it is stands out to you. It's so stunning,
and you wonder how people can be even thinking of what they're talking about, you know? So you
look beyond it, okay? Beyond it. Okay, thank you. Go back at midnight.
The Church of the Red Rocks, I used to do that. The music would go all night long,
and the candles were on, and nobody was there. Yes, okay, yeah, I'm sure they're there.
From a personal point of view, there are days, for example, when I feel as an individual that
everything is going perfectly well. You know, you're floating down the river. You're not trying
to swim upstream, you hear some music on the radio, it's beautiful, or you see the sunset
without comment, but there are also days when that's not true, so would you perhaps help
explain, on days which that's not true, am I getting in my own way, is it something...
And the days when it's not true, it's just something coming up that you need to process,
and it's calling for attention, this aggravates me, or this bothers me, or I feel attached
to this, I have an aversion to that, it just brings up what you need to work on, see sometimes
you get above your karma, and everything's peaceful and nice, and now you've used up
your good karma, and now the next stack is coming up for recognition, you're temporarily
above it, but it isn't done yet, so the self wants to see you continuously progress, so
it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives
you a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives you a
chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to
progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and
it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives
you a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance
to progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to progress,
and it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and it
gives you a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives you
a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to
progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and it gives you a chance to progress, and
have to be more alert not to get in your own way
or not let those obstacles come up
that you were talking about this morning?
Well, when you say the disturbance comes up,
you have to look at what is the disturbance
and why the disturbance is going on,
and you work on that.
Then that will disappear,
and life will be happy and cheerful and chipper,
and you can sing songs,
and then the next thing will come up.
Okay. All right.
It's okay. It's a long process.
It's a growth process.
It's a process.
Okay. Thank you very much.
I appreciate so much what you do.
Yes.
Thank you, sir.
Yeah, it's a lifelong process.
When it gets to be so nice like that, you see,
why didn't it stay that way?
Yeah.
May I ask one quick question before my main question?
Before what?
The main question.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
In your 1996 video, Power Versus Force,
you had this blonde that helped you.
Can you teach me how to enter into her field
and do anything I'm going to have to do to get out of what?
He had a blonde in that video.
Yes.
He wants to know how to enter into her field.
I don't know what you mean by enter into her field.
How about a telephone number or a...
You don't even know who he's talking about.
I don't see her in the audience here.
Yeah, what is your real question?
Okay.
Yeah.
I'm involved in three areas of research and practice now.
One is using the mind mirror to look at brain waves patterns.
Another is using genograms for family constellation work.
And the third is I'm a Western and Vedic astrologer
trying to integrate the two disciplines into a higher astrology.
In your book, Truth and Falsehood,
you calibrated astrology, I think, between 205 and 410,
and is it possible to create a higher astrology?
There are various levels of astrology.
When people talk about astrology,
they're not talking about just one thing.
There's the astrology in the newspaper.
That calibrates the lowest sort of pop astrology.
Then there's astrology based on more ancient wisdom,
which really is going beyond astrology,
looking at contextual understandings.
It's not a linear causality anymore.
Right.
I think that when I said that the consciousness level of mankind
went from 190 to 205,
that was about at the time the harmonic concordance,
but not caused by it.
Then again, in November of what was it,
203, we were in San Francisco,
it went from 205 to 207.
That was again at the time of,
I don't know if I'm using the correct terminology,
harmonic concordance.
Yes.
So aligned with that, at the same time,
because if the universe is doing this,
then these things are both moving as a consequence of this,
not because this is causing this.
You understand what I'm saying?
The understanding and the astrological sign
are appearing because they are both being swung this way.
You understand?
This is not causing that.
This is concomitant.
Very often the ego confuses concomitant with causal.
Is it possible to present astrology
in a new context so it has a higher calibration?
I don't know.
I think it would be significance and meaning.
The limitation of astrology as I see it is causality.
You lost your job because the moon is going over your backyard.
You know what I mean?
That's causality.
That constellation is not causing anything here at all.
So if you move beyond duality,
you could move it to a higher...
Astrology could work out as,
you know, a concordance in which you pick up rhythms
which are the consequence of greater rhythms,
or the consequence of even greater rhythms.
Eventually you reach the mind of God
who will tell you to forget about astrology.
What about brain wave patterns?
That's interesting, yes.
Is it worthwhile to pursue?
It depends on what context.
Looking at brain wave patterns of people at different disciplines
and different levels.
And different accomplishments and different contributions?
I don't know.
It would be some kind of research.
I don't know what the purpose would be.
To find out different skills.
The whole area of brain research
is emerging rather rapidly.
So I'd have to know more about it.
I've lost track of where it's at right now.
Thank you.
Yeah, it takes this moment to express my deepest love
and gratitude to God and to God's teachings.
Yes.
Yes, thank you.
Because in the last few months, my life has changed.
I have two questions.
The first question is about the calibration
on the transcendental meditations.
Transcendental meditations?
TM.
Yes.
Oh, yes, yes.
So it is very low.
It's over 200, yeah.
I read some of their material.
They are practicing, you know, promote peace.
And...
What is the question?
The question is, why is the TM calibrated so low?
What do you mean by so low?
What is the number?
It's like 200-something on your slide.
It's over 200.
200 is...
Truth is 200 or not.
Okay, okay.
Yeah.
It wasn't created by the Buddha.
You know what I'm saying?
Okay.
Yeah, in my mind, I thought it should be higher.
So the second question is about the jaya,
the jaya hypothesis, is this?
Jaya hypothesis?
Yes, yes, yes.
Yes.
Can you...
The Earth is a living organism.
Yeah.
Can you share some light on this?
It calibrates as negative.
You hear it breathing...
Is that a fantasy or a reality?
Is jaya a living organism?
My understanding is that it is.
What does it calibrate?
I don't know.
I'm coming to you to ask for your calibration.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
Can you give me theting of what you're calibrating?
Oh, you want me to calibrate.
Oh, I see.
We have permission to calibrate the concept of your...
We have permitted to calibrate the concept of yours.
No?
So, what does that mean?
I don't know.
It means we gotta know.
We cannot calibrate it?
I can't calibrate it right now.
We've gotta know.
It's a concept.
Yeah.
What does it, what difference does it make you is what I wanna know?
Yeah, I come from the science background.
Okay.
Yeah, but then recently after studying your teachings, I feel like I made the transition to the nonlinear domain.
Yes.
And because of this, I see that there was a merging between science and spirituality,
and I see the Gaia hypothesis actually bring an opportunity to this endeavor.
He feels that the Gaia...
The Gaia is a living single organism, is the concept, correct?
Yes.
Gaia means that all that exists as the Earth is one single unit. Is that true?
Do you have the same karma as the bacteria, the octopus, the snake, the fish, the killer, the bandit, the murderer?
Do you share the same karma with all of them? Are you one with them?
Yes.
Then by your own definition, you are. They'll have to serve you where you are now.
How come you caused all that disaster?
In New Orleans, eh?
Because we will learn something from it.
Because we learned something from it?
Yeah.
Yeah?
What is the value of holding the concept of Gaia? What is the value of it?
Yeah, my...
As a scientist, you know?
Yes. Personally, I feel like the science is hitting a wall, and it's convergence of these two domains may bring a new consciousness to our being.
It's a working concept.
I think it's a useful concept, yes. Whether it's a self-existent reality or something else, but it certainly is a useful concept. You treat the whole thing as if it's one. That's fine.
Will it bring more unity consciousness by advocating this?
We don't know. We don't know if it's going to bring unity.
I mean, you're free to hold your concept about what the world is and what it means and what its significance is, you know.
Yeah, it depends on age, sophistication, education, many things, you know.
Thank you.
Yeah.
But we can't calibrate it so we can't go any further with it. We've got to know that...
It's useful to him. It's useful to him right now.
But if it's useful to you...
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
I haven't heard that concept in a while.
The Gaia?
Yeah. Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Hi. You have described the experience energetically of the high 500s.
And specifically the energy as it travels up the spine.
Yeah. Kind of leaning in. Yes.
As this intense, exquisite experience.
Yes.
Is it always present in that way in the high 500s?
Nothing is always anything.
Okay.
Characteristically, that's how it is. That's how experienced it was.
Very exquisite, frankly.
And specifically up the spinal column like that?
No.
It was experientially. It flowed up the back.
Mm-hmm.
And into the brain.
And if you thought of the left side of the brain, it poured into the left side of the brain.
If you thought of the right side of the brain, it poured into the right side of the brain.
Then it came down and began to go out into the world.
Mm-hmm. Okay.
Mm-hmm.
And if you shut your eyes, it got even more intense.
I'm trying to just formulate another question.
Because there are times when I feel...
I remember as a kid watching Sylvester the Cat, I think, in cartoons.
And his tail would go into the outlet and he would fry with electricity.
Do you need me to repeat it? No?
No, she'll have to tell me what to say.
Okay.
So there are times when I experience that.
And I'm trying to understand is that...
Is there a resistance?
You mean like an energy surge is what you feel?
Mm-hmm.
No.
Not really a surge.
More just like a huge overload.
More.
And trying to understand is it resistance?
Could be, yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
What happens if you just continuously surrender to it and let it be whatever it is?
Well, then it seems to spread out more and dissipate.
I mean...
Sometimes, like I'll need to lay down on the floor sometimes.
Yeah.
And sometimes after 10 or 15 minutes of that...
You just surrender to it no matter what form or expression it takes.
Okay.
No, that's the right thing to do.
Mm-hmm.
You know, and you ask God for, you know, understanding and revelation of its meaning and significance.
All those things, I've found, just don't resist them.
Because one usually evolves into something else.
Right.
You don't have to worry about it, because it's gonna stay anyway.
Okay.
Thank you.
It's transitional, so don't worry about it.
Okay.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Hi.
I work in a hospital, and I'm exposed, I guess.
I'm surrounded by viruses and bacteria, and they calibrated a one.
Yeah, that's right.
Well, no, there just seems to be a lot of attention within the healthcare system.
Yeah.
And I'm also within the health system that I'm...
In a hospital?
In a hospital.
You're working in a hospital, is that what you're saying?
Yeah.
Yeah, what is the question?
And there seems to be a lot of attention, if a virus and bacteria calibrated a one...
Yeah.
There seems to be a lot of attention paid to something that calibrates at a one.
We're giving it a lot of power, it seems.
Does it have that much power, or are we just giving it the power?
No, it doesn't have power.
It doesn't have power.
No.
So, pneumonia isn't real?
You can...
You...
using force and power. And it's not the bacteria, it's the body's reaction to it, yeah? You're
confusing power and force. Bin Laden calibrates at 20, and 9-11 is the consequence. So you
see what I'm saying? That which is by virtue of its form is destructive, not by virtue
of its power.
So just by, like it calibrates at a 1. So just being at a 1.
Bacteria are at a 1 as far as their level of consciousness, yes.
It's like a tack, a tack doesn't calibrate very high, but under the tire of your car,
it isn't that it has the power to destroy your life, you understand? It's just the consequence
of its linear characteristics. A nail in the road, and your tire hits it, now you can
turn over. So you're misconceiving it, you're misconceptualizing it by saying, look, the
nail has the power to kill five people in the car.
That's...
That's a metal game you're playing with it.
Well, not all viruses are bad, either. Some viruses are...
Yeah, I know, but I get what she's saying. She's misconceiving power.
Yeah.
Doesn't have the power.
Well, it just seems we focus a lot of attention on it, you know?
Oh, yes, we do with nails in the tires, too. I sweep them out of my driveway all the time.
Okay, thank you.
Yeah, I understand her question. It comes up once in a while. Because of the form, say.
I want to thank you for your books and your work, and it's been a great deal to me, and
I appreciate that. I have a question, and I'm not sure how to ask it, so I'll just talk
around it, and hopefully it'll come out in some meaningful way. One of your helpers said
I needed to ask you personally because you don't answer email very much, so I figured
I'd come up and ask the question. It has to do with the calibration charts and...
You're a walking email, eh?
Mm-hmm.
Now they walk around in a human body. They'll do anything to get their... Yeah, go ahead.
Just don't press the delete button. The calibration charts were... On one level, they make a great
deal of sense. In other words, I can tell that certain levels have more energy than
others, and it just makes a lot of sense.
You can intuit it, yeah.
Correct. My question has to do with how accurate is this depending on what one's level is,
in other words...
The higher your level, the more accurate it is.
Exactly. I'm finding that, for example, within a circle of friends, there'll be just a wild
range of interpretations about, well, I'm obviously a 600. I'm below 600. I'm below...
Anybody else had that experience? I don't know, but it just seems to be whoever's doing
the interpreting is going to be higher and higher and higher depending on where they're
coming from.
Exactly.
It just seems to me that there's...
Well, look, it comes with wisdom and experience.
Right.
I tell people, don't bother calibrating yourself, because you're not going to get an accurate
number. Besides, it's irrelevant. When it doesn't mean anything to you anymore, you'll
suddenly know it.
One of the questions I have was this misinterpretation of the different calibration levels. Maybe
they didn't do it back then, but something along that line, which led to the caste system
in India, for example.
Which led to what?
Something where...
The caste.
The caste system.
Where you're labeling people, like, they're untouchables here, or this person's a merchant,
this person's a private level, that type of thing.
Oh, yeah. That's...
Yeah. What about it?
It seems to me that the misuse of such a calibration could lead to something like
that.
The misuse of anything, including holy water, can drown you.
That's true.
It can drown in holy water. Babies do it all the time.
Blessing this baby. I had to run to the bathroom for a second. I come back.
I'm sorry.
It's floating in the christening thing.
I guess that answers my question.
What can be done with truth in what way. You know what I'm saying.
Back...
Affirmative.
It's misused or abused you know. But you're mixing classes now. Categories.
I'm just thinking in Sedona a million years from now when they unearth
it.
you know, Hawkinology, you know, and find that this work existed, and trying to make something out of it, I was wondering how they're going.
What kind of ology?
Hawkinology.
Yeah?
Now I'll leave some relics.
Yeah.
You mean they'll still be here?
They can be here.
Thousands of future generations can verify them.
And I've been working on a book, actually, for ten years, too.
I've been doing kinesiology for a while.
And I wanted to ask your permission to use some of your writing in the book.
Just send me the quotes you want.
Okay.
And we'll give you formal permission.
Right.
Okay.
Thank you, sir.
Yeah.
Hawkinology.
That's cute.
Okay.
Thank you.
See, it's the intention with which you use it that determines the result.
Yeah.
Hello.
Thank you for your work.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
Can you expand a little bit on the...
Can you expand a little more on intention?
Maybe the mechanics of it?
On what?
Intention.
Does it matter how long you hold the thought or from what level it comes from?
Well, intention means what your purpose, your goal is.
See?
For instance, if your intention or your goal is to disprove kinesiology, you can do it
quickly.
How many pennies have I got in my pocket?
I mean, I don't know.
How many times have I heard that?
If your intention is to learn, you see, you can tell right away the intention.
One is a declaration, one is a denomination, the other one is a question.
You can tell right away before they even open their mouth.
This person asks a question, this person makes a negative declaration.
See?
If you want to understand something, you go to the man, the best person who can understand
it, the best person who knows about it, and you ask them about it.
Yeah?
It's easy.
Okay.
Also, I wanted to...
Some people complicate it.
I don't know why they complicate it.
Yes, and I also would like to extend an invitation to you from Mary Olmwake and the Unity Church
of Kahului in Maui to come visit.
Oh, Maui.
Maui, well, yeah.
Are you a good swimmer?
Am I a good swimmer?
I don't know if I can make it all the way to Hawaii, yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
I have been in Hawaii since World War II.
I went out through Pearl and I came back through Pearl.
Susan's been to Hawaii.
Yeah.
I have a daughter there.
Might be doing school there next year.
Yeah?
Uh-huh.
Okay.
Did we do it?
Did we finish it?
Yeah.
I think we did.
Yeah?
Such a pleasure and such a joy.
Because you're God's gift to me, thank you.
Thank you.
Oh Lord.
For the divine presence in the form of these magnificent people.
And we do again, hold in mind, those in need of the love, the feeling of the presence.
You see, because you can go through anything, anything when you feel the presence within
you, any kind of agony, any kind of forgiveness, so we pray that the people who need it feel
Feel the strength of God's love.
The strength of God's love.
Everybody thinks of God's love as a set of flowers and we'll sing pretty songs.
No.
Love is powerful.
In a snowbank, everything stopped.
The presence of divinity was overwhelming.
Exquisite.
Melted.
It melts with its infinite power.
It's exquisitely gentle.
Exquisitely soft and gentle.
Simultaneously, infinitely powerful like ultra steel.
You have to experience it to understand what seems like an ambiguity.
How can that be soft, ultra gentle?
So exquisite that it melts.
Melts one.
At the same time of infinite power.
Seems like a strange paradox.
Those who have been there will tell you that's what it is.
Exquisitely sensitive.
Gentle.
Healing.
Warm.
And of infinite power.
And that's what the people need.
We pray for it.
Oh Lord.
Amen.
Yeah.
Thank you so much.
Where did they find this lovely, uh, did Gabe find this?
I forgot who found this pillow.
Gabe, I think.
Is that Gabe there?
I don't know.
I can't see.
I can't see where he was.
Who are you looking for?
Is that Gabe there?
Yeah, that's Gabe.
I didn't know where he got this pillow.
Where does this go, Gabe?
Got it.
Okay.
That was great.
Yeah, we had another day, huh?
Absolutely.
Thank you.