The implications of knowing the distribution of the levels of consciousness in the world are
the purpose of it is the science of peace.
There's no science of peace, no science of diplomacy.
And we just invented it.
What we do is we calibrate the level of consciousness.
This is international relationships. You can use it in politics.
In politics, you can say, what is the average consciousness level of the voter?
Therefore, where must our platform be to appeal to the voter?
Hey, isn't that simple?
The people with the biggest mouths are down here.
The electorate is up here.
Shaking your fist with emotion doesn't appeal to these people.
They think you need a doctor.
So it's applicable.
It's applicable to politics, to business, to advertising.
You know, who are you?
Who is your target audience?
And what does our advertisement calibrate at?
I see idiot advertisements out there.
Here's this big chunky guy with little blue wings.
And pregnant women are wandering back and forth.
There's all kinds of phenomena going on.
And then there's three initials that keep coming across.
I don't know what they stand for.
Middle soup.
Nuts?
What does this stand for?
I don't know.
Calibrate is at 135.
I'm seeing millions spent on that stupid ad.
Anyway, all right.
So use your advertising budget wisely.
Use your energies wisely.
Use your efforts wisely.
This is your program for a school district.
Here it is.
Who do you have to sell it to?
Here's the school board here.
Here's the parents here.
Here's the community here.
Where is your program if you want to win?
International diplomacy.
We already gave examples this morning of why trying to sell democracy in parts of the world is idiotic and stupid.
Giving every man equally a vote, you got to be out of your mind, you know.
Sounds stupid.
What we consider to be reality in other cultures is called stupidity.
Sucker and dumb.
And they wouldn't be caught dead telling the truth.
You mean they're told the truth?
Told the truth in court?
Yeah.
Take them out.
You realize he's dangerous?
You know what they do with truth tellers?
They take them out.
The boys take you out.
You cannot be trusted.
Once you get, you're at a 180 with the world.
So here's America at 421.
And these are the calibrated levels of various countries.
And you can see, therefore,
what kind of a program, what kind of languaging,
you can see what the prevailing sense of reality is.
By knowing that, by writing about it,
sort of poking in a people's face by publishing it,
provocatively,
it is possible to have a science of diplomacy
that might give you some chances of success.
Chances of success.
You have to, before you can sell something,
you've got to know who you're dealing with.
Who you're dealing with.
That tells you how to phrase it, how to present it,
how to be with it.
And it also precludes the egotism
of thinking that our truth is superior to other people.
You know, the abrasive quality of Americanism in the world,
which has always been an embarrassment to me since World War II.
So.
And to which the French reacted strongly,
and they haven't recovered from World War II either.
De Gaulle, you know.
He's saving France, yeah, right.
He was elsewhere.
Elsewhere.
He wasn't a freedom fighter in Paris.
Okay, so.
This tells us who we are.
This could be our company here.
Here's Walmart.
Everybody hates that.
Walmart haters.
They're big, successful, and they're American.
Oh.
Plus they make a profit.
God.
Man.
That is hateful, ain't it?
Like it or not, bite the bullet.
Here's Walmart.
Stick that where the sun don't shine.
Well, you can calibrate all the companies you invest in.
Take out your stock portfolio, and you'll be selling and buying soon.
Yeah, all the ones that collapsed.
We were working on the book back in, what, 2002 or something.
We did all the major corporations in the world.
And there was a lot of them under 200, you know.
Under 200.
Which we didn't print or publish.
But we didn't have the stock in it.
But we told people to sell it.
There's a lot of companies that didn't do too well.
World Comm and all.
So, all right.
Appearance is the stock value.
Essence is what the company calibrates at.
So, all your stocks.
Why?
Because it's not greed, you see.
If you demonize the ego, you get paralyzed with greed and guilt.
No, you have a responsibility, especially if you're destined to be enlightened,
to be the steward of your assets.
Forget about winning.
Get out of the solar plexus.
Solar plexus is about winning and fear of losing and greed and all that.
And even if you succeed, you end up with guilt.
You end up with guilt.
Why?
Because your increase is the price of somebody else's decrease.
No, you have to re-contextualize your assets.
What are your assets?
Time, how many years you got left.
How many hours in a day.
Assets, financial.
Personality-wise.
If you're six foot six and fast on the court,
you have an obligation to respect that capacity, that talent.
If you're good at taking shorthand, whatever it is.
So, your talents, your abilities, your assets.
Instead of greed now, you respect them.
You're grateful for them and you handle them with respect and honor.
You owe that respect to yourself and to your destiny.
You can't waste years.
Playing around in casinos and things when there's far more important things to do.
That's why I say don't waste time exploring the astral domains.
New age-ism, all kinds of psychics, healers, peddlers, circus clowns on the other side.
Play at it if you want.
So you blow a few more lifetimes, you know.
Except they're more clever at it than you are.
Therefore, it's arrogance that makes you think you can play with the astral domains and not get singed.
I don't know of anybody who's played with the astral domain that has not been singed.
Nobody.
They've been at it for eons.
The slightest hesitation tells you exactly why you're going to be a buyer of sweetness and light.
Because I have come from another dimension to tell you.
Of the revelations of Whoopah.
The ancient mysteries of Whoopah.
You see, you just got glamorized, didn't you?
Why?
Because it's from a different dimension, you're automatically glamorized.
The child in you is still enamored of magic.
Oh, in a physical universe, you can get a psychic reading that says,
I see your grandmother came from Ireland.
Ooh, shit, she did.
How does she know that?
And your father, who's still in the lodge on the other side, wants you to so-and-so.
Whoa, that's a fact.
You just got hooked.
Hook, line, and sinker.
Why?
Because all the information about you is public domain.
Don't you know that?
I just got through telling you.
You can calibrate the level of truth of anything that's ever existed in time, energy, or anywhere, even a thought.
Being psychic is nothing at all.
There's a whole level of consciousness where your psychic is all hell.
In the mid-500s, as this kundalini energy comes up, you develop the so-called siddhis, S-I-D-D-H-I-S, paranormal capacities.
The kundalini energy flows through you.
You become psychic, clairvoyant.
You can go anywhere out of body.
You can go inside of something, read it, come back out again.
I did it in front of witnesses all over the place.
What's in the box?
I'll tell you in a second.
It says, hello.
Right.
How do you know?
Because I went there, idiot.
Why do you think I'm paying the money to learn how to do it for?
So that is not.
You see, you get mystified and impressed and glamorized by natural domains.
Some of those entities have been there, I hate to tell you, they were old at the time of Mesopotamia, and Mesopotamia was their high point.
Don't forget how expert people can be at what they do.
I was a psychiatrist.
I had the biggest practice in the United States, practiced 50 years.
By the time a person made the appointment, I already knew what was wrong with them.
I already got it.
I want to see you on Thursday.
Why is that?
Well, I've been getting this and that.
I've already got what it is.
If it's a patient I'm treating, my office, there was a wooden hallway leading into the main clinic and rows of offices and labs and stuff.
To get to my office, they had to walk down the row past all the labs and offices and all.
They walked across the floor to my office, which was somewhat remote.
By the sound of the footsteps, I can already tell you whether they're better or worse.
I can already tell you what I'm going to have to do with the dose of the med.
I already got it.
I got them on the wrong med.
I better try something different.
There's no one working.
People are really expert.
There are people, by the time you say hello, they already read you.
Entities on the other side have been doing that for eons.
A little naive.
You're going to pay your ticket and get your order read.
Give me a break.
If you could do that without getting entranced, okay.
But you're going to get entranced.
You're already entranced by the magic of it, by the fact that you went there for a reading, aren't you?
They already got you by curiosity.
All right.
So the evolution of consciousness goes through evolution, including the spiritual aspect of your own development.
That which is spiritual begins as naive, childish, the wonderment of it all.
I went to see this psychic, and she said, your uncle got hit in a motorcycle accident.
I said, just wow.
Everybody know that experience?
Liars.
Truth tellers.
Everybody's had that experience.
You haven't been glamorized by a psychic.
You ain't lived yet.
I'll see you later, and I'm going to read your future, okay?
I can get what happened.
I can get what happened and where it was.
Why?
Because the infinite field of consciousness includes everything known about everything.
All right.
So I just thought I'd tell you a few things.
Okay.
Go on.
What's the next one?
I got five minutes.
Next one.
This is the rate of happiness.
This is not only the percentage of happiness, but to see what makes a person happy here
will make you feel guilty up here.
And vice versa.
So you have a reverse morality.
Here, to not get is a matter of shame and guilt.
Here, to get creates guilt because you think, oh, that's my solar plexus.
Oh, I was wanting gain.
That's the vanity of the ego, et cetera.
Dear Lord, please help me get over that.
Wanting to win the lottery.
Okay.
Next.
Hmm.
Level of happiness.
And related happiness.
Which we saw on the other one.
We'll go to the next slide.
That was, skip that one.
That's incongruity.
We'll skip this one.
Skip this one.
That's him saying, I should have left the body.
Why the hell didn't I?
Okay.
We'll stop here.
We'll stop the slides here.
We'll resume later.
And see, by knowing the basic dictums.
The basic truths.
Then, you don't have to go there.
You'll have to sacrifice the kick out of the experience.
You don't have to go over Niagara Falls in a barrel for kicks.
And if you're spiritually aligned, you can't afford it.
You can't afford it.
What turns you off about doing that is the disrespect for the divinity of his own creation.
He has so little respect for yourself that you would put yourself in such extreme injury.
For both death and damage.
As well as forcing the commitment of society to come in and save you.
And then bury you at tax payers cost.
You know, the sheer disrespect of it.
For the transitory solar plexus kick.
So, spiritual evolution does require somewhat declining.
And some of the novelties and kicks that come along the way.
Be thankful then and respect that your destiny is to become enlightened.
That's the destiny of 90% of the people here in the room.
And the rest of the people are going to go back to the bar.
And come back next time.
All right.
We'll see you after lunch.
What time is lunch?
What time do we resume?
Huh?
We have an hour and a half.
Thank you so much.
I prepare people for their inevitable future.
We know what everybody's future is here.
At least 90%.
10% are going to chicken out.
Smart chicken out now.
Yes.
To be prepared.
Okay.
And to be prepared.
You've chosen the way to God.
And this is going to realign your life.
The sequencing is not going to be the same as it would have been.
Huh?
So you prepare for it.
Okay.
Mm.
We also can talk about what spirituality is.
Not.
Yeah?
There's a lot that is not.
And it's labeled as such.
Peddled as such.
Merchandised as such.
Huh?
As you know from some of the ways I communicate,
spirituality does not mean a feat.
Hearts and flowers.
And we're all going to be happy now.
And we'll all sing a song.
And we'll all sing a song like this is the maypole and this is kindergarten.
Now, you know where the sun don't shine, that's English.
No, spirituality does not require being a feat and delicate
and like a wispy little flower singing hymns around the clock.
It requires strength, courage, valor as you get to extremely high levels.
It requires the capacity to experience actually physical pain and various agonies
and to allow nothing to deter you along the way.
So that is anything but a feat, I'll tell you.
It takes everything you've got.
And without divine help, it's not even possible.
Not possible.
It's not possible to calibrate below 200 and become enlightened.
It doesn't have the karma, go for it.
We were talking about the level.
It emerges around the level that the people call sainthood,
around the high 500s, you know.
When that kundalini starts to flow.
We didn't talk about that energy, did we?
No.
We didn't talk about it.
But the many of the things that you pick up later in the astral circus
were actually phenomena that were derived from those states
because...
You feel this exquisite sensation running up your spine.
Not having read anything about kundalini.
I didn't get glamorized by it, I'll tell you.
Anyway, there's just an exquisite sense of pleasure
that runs up your back, runs up your whole back
and it runs up into your head, like into your brain.
And if you focus on the left side of the brain,
it tends to go in that side.
So this exquisite sensation
is like a flowing energy, is all I can say.
And it's extremely exquisite.
Therefore, you really value that state
because it has that quality that goes with it
that you've never experienced before,
except maybe in some incredible psychedelic conditions
or states of intoxication.
Well, you got a glimpse of it.
Well, that's why they're intoxicating.
You're not intoxicated by the substance.
You're intoxicated by the quality of subjectivity.
When you're beautifully still with the right combination of everything
and the music is perfect,
you are in like an incredible state.
If only it were possible to stay there.
But it goes.
Now, having once experienced that state prematurely,
now you can...
You go into anguish and despair
because when you have to stop the substance,
that state is no longer accessible.
But now, you have experienced that
and therefore, nothing less will ever do in overtime.
Therefore, at least energy 540,
which is supplied by the 12-step groups,
you begin to feel naturally that which was artificial before.
That condition keeps coming.
It's going from unconditional lovingness.
As I say, that energy begins to flow.
Around 560, around 570.
And it's exquisite.
Also, the energy is not yours.
It is a quality of phenomena.
And the quality,
one of the things the energy does is
you become clairaudient, clairvoyant.
You know, you can go inside a box.
We were talking about it at lunch.
You know, there's a message in a closed box.
You can look at the box, project yourself in there,
read it, and come back out and say, it says, hello.
And they open the box.
There's a thing that says, hello.
No problem.
So, you can go where you've never been
and know exactly how to get there.
All you do is hold the destination in mind
and you automatically see exactly where to park
in front of Lincoln Center.
And as you get there, the first car on the right-hand side,
the nearest, most wonderful parking place of all time,
in front of Lincoln Center, is the Lincoln Center.
Just as you drive up, they pull out and you drive in.
And it's all normal.
Life just unveils that way.
And that's why they call it the course of miracles
because that becomes normal, normal.
And not that you have an expectation.
You're not, there's nobody trying to make it happen.
The phenomena occur of their own.
One of the side phenomena of the cities is,
I've described before, it would like flow out.
It would like flow out.
It would like flow out from the heart chakra.
And it would go places and bring about healings
and the miraculous and, you know, phenomena
that from the Newtonian paradigm would be called miraculous.
In its own paradigm, it's natural.
But outside of that paradigm, they'd say,
how did you do that?
Well, you didn't do it, you know.
That's the whole thing.
The phenomena is of its own.
It's a divine energy.
And I always got that the people to whom it flowed had been praying.
It would be like you're an antenna.
And the car is turned upside down as you turn the corner.
And the highway, the wheels are actually still spinning right here on I-17.
And you feel the energy shoot out and shoot into the people within the car.
And then all of a sudden, the energy stops.
And you got the people in the car were praying, dear God, please help us.
That energy just shoots directly.
So you're like the nearest sending radio antenna.
And the program goes to them, you know.
So it's not any personal self.
That fact is obvious.
It performs.
I could keep you the rest of the afternoon
and tell you how the phenomena it would do.
It fixed 100-watt hi-fi amplifiers.
The energy was going there, and the amplifier was blown out.
And somebody said, there's something wrong with the amplifier.
And I say, oh, yeah?
All of a sudden, the amplifier go on.
The guy said, I saw that.
That's what actually happened.
Radio repair, he said, I saw that.
He says, that was a miracle.
He said, somehow the subject of the course of miracles comes up.
And I said, oh, it's just what the world calls the miraculous.
Oh, wow, he says, I'm really interested in that.
I had one copy, extra copy left of the course of miracles.
I said, well, here, here, this is what you're looking for.
And he said, oh, thank you very much.
You see how just one thing?
I mean, the only reason he came there
was to make contact with the course of miracles and get that.
And the phenomena just was a phenomena.
Those phenomena happen of their own, yeah.
The trick is, don't be glamorized by them.
Don't try and sell them and realize that they are not you.
So somebody we were talking earlier about,
some entities on the other side, you see,
the mistake they made because they didn't have a teacher that
forewarned them in advance not to get glamorized or personalized
the cities when they arrive.
They lack that education.
Therefore, they're innocent by virtue of not
having known the difference.
But when they come on, you realize it's equality,
but it's not personal.
.
own them as a personal power, then you
freeze it there and now you become a
psychic, you know, eons after eons, you
know, you're giving readings in the year
892 and you're still giving them, because
you're stuck in the glamorization and
the power of that, you know, seeing the
definition of yourself is a psychic
clairvoyant and all that. So everybody in
the high 500 has become psychic
clairvoyant, I mean there's nothing,
everybody's telepathic and in that
state you always know what question the
person has in their mind, you know
exactly what they're thinking, I mean
it's just natural to the field,
everybody's telepathic. You can
experience that even way before the high
fives, 500s, so-called silent retreats, or
you go away for a weekend somebody's
house with half a dozen people and you
don't speak from, you know, Friday till
Monday morning or something, everybody
becomes telepathic, I mean it's
nothing,
everybody very quickly too, within 24
hours, you know, you think salt and at the
tenor table and then just as you think
it, somebody hands you the salt shaker, I
mean it's normal. So it's not a unique,
it's when you get out of the linear, the
nonlinear takes over. So a lot of things
are known by the field and it's not the
person, it's the field, and so that was the
precaution.
About getting glamorized by all that, you
see, the other thing about truth is it
doesn't need to be glamorized. So let's
do the next, let's do the next slide, you
got another slide? That's how the professor
knew he was about to lose his
position, he ran out of slides. So that
brought up then, by consciousness
calibration plus the knowingness from
within.
There is an awareness of spiritual
integrity, what is integrous and what is
not integrous, and you can sense it, but
in the beginning, if you don't believe it,
you can calibrate it. The calibration
level of various things then, by
experience, having been up and down the
scale, then you develop what's called
discernment, the opening of the third eye
of the Buddhic body is called discernment.
You'd be able to be, you sense the real
from that which is searching for
advantage and gain, you know. That which
is the real is all that is and has
nothing to gain, and then by that you can
identify it. Nothing to gain, doesn't have
a program going for itself, isn't trying
to promote, isn't trying to proselytize,
isn't trying to glamorize, isn't trying to
tell you, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Seduction, that's called seduction, see?
The truth, because it's completely satisfied by the fulfillment of its own potential,
has no gain, doesn't need conversation, doesn't need votes, doesn't need members,
doesn't need to proselytize, doesn't need to sign you up,
doesn't need to control you or intimidate you
or pose hypothetical threats whereby to control you.
So he's not interested in your sex life, your personal life,
what you wear, eat, dress, and where you go, what you have for dinner.
Doesn't care whether you're a vegetarian, whether you give up sex,
or sex is your lifestyle.
Somebody's got to do something, I mean, you know.
Somebody's got to repopulate the earth, you know.
They've got nothing better to do anyway at that age, do they?
So everybody serves in their own way, so.
You get called out of stud service over the years.
The world has to get along without your divine gifts.
The responsibility of the teacher, then, is to give certain understandings
that preclude their later being taken advantage of and falling off.
I always feel sorry for fallen gurus because I see the mistake they made,
I know why they made it,
and I know the teacher,
and I know the teaching that they were missing.
Therefore, my obligation is to share with you all that I know about the,
you know, likelihoods along the way because all likelihoods are held in place.
On one side, there's the temptation that gives it attraction.
On the other side, there's a loss or a pain that is the aversion.
So we'll get to that.
That's the last slide today, the dualities of attractions and aversions.
Having aligned yourself now with the truth, then,
you become dedicated to it, and the way, now, what is the way to where you want to go?
You've picked your destiny, and you've committed yourself,
and now, how do you know which is the right roadmap?
And therefore, I've tried to provide a reliable roadmap.
We've done some of them before.
But some people here are new, and it's all new to them.
That which is true is true all the time, everywhere, for everyone.
Therefore, every advanced mystic is the same, no matter what century,
no matter what part of the world, it's always the same.
There is only one absolute reality, and it reveals itself in various dimensions.
Therefore, the inner subjective awareness and experience of an enlightened master in,
let's say, 4000 BC in India should be the same as 1936 in Chicago.
There's no difference at all.
The presence shines forth, unmistakably has what it is.
It's true at all times, all places.
There's nobody that possesses the truth.
So, you know, there's various claims.
We got the truth.
And they shoot each other and blow each other up.
If you don't blow my truth, I'm going to blow you up.
They do.
They're probably doing it right now.
You got to have something to do.
You blow up infidels, I guess.
I'll keep you busy.
The world's full of infidels.
If your trip is blowing up infidels, your life's work is cut out for you.
Get up early, go to bed late.
Making bombs and all the fuses.
They work their fingers to the bone making bombs to blow up children with.
God bless them.
Universality.
Okay, it's always true, not exclusive, all-inclusive, not secretive, and not sectarian.
Nobody owes it.
Nobody's got an exclusive.
There's nothing to peddle and sell because the truth is obvious, clear, available to
anyone, anytime.
All they need is by integrous dedication, they'll really re-experience it themself.
And it's always the same.
There's nothing secret about it.
There's no mystery about it.
In fact, all those who experience it, they're going to experience it.
They're going to experience the truth, proclaim it.
The Buddha said, it is the most wondrous of the wonderful.
Everyone precludes it.
He didn't keep it a secret.
Oh man, I really got enlightened and too bad about you.
No, he rejected the Hindu teachings which he thought were incorrect, bowed his inner
muse and arrived at the ultimate state.
He then proclaimed it to the world.
So, one thing.
One thing that one does is to proclaim its pristine excellence.
There is no mystery.
Therefore, there's nothing to sell about it, you see.
The truth is available to all and the doorway to the truth is open to all.
With no secrets, there's nothing to sell.
There's no stratification, you know, junior master, middle master, higher master, super
master.
.
I can jump you from master to super master and it's only 5,000 for the workshop.
Anybody want to give me five grand, I'll make you a super master right now.
.
I'll tell you what, better yet, I want to make everybody here a super master and now
you better live up to that title.
You are now all going to be masters in the future.
That's a fact.
Everyone here already has the energy of that.
.
And the reason you're here is to shine that forth through generations to come.
That's the purpose of enlightenment.
All right.
It's open to all.
No secrets.
Nothing is hidden, sold.
There are no magical formulas or mysteries.
What is there about a mystery?
I know it and you don't.
I'll tell you who's throwing the mysteries.
Kindergarteners.
I've got a secret, Sylvia.
I've got one too, Betty.
Betty, let's form a club.
The secret club.
We'll call it the Triple Bunny Club.
They got three members.
No, we'll keep it a secret who's members.
We'll have a sign like that.
Symbols and signs and secrets.
Oaths.
Oh, yeah.
Swear upon your Oz book that you will not relate to anybody that you're a secret member of this society.
The Wizard of Oz.
Purpose.
Nothing to gain or lose.
Once the bowl is full, there's nothing more it would want, would it?
There's no difference between yourself and that which is all that is.
Consequently, it's a nuisance to have to own something.
I mean, it's really a drag.
It really is.
To have to own it and get legal papers and the whole business.
It's nicer to look.
You own it.
When I need a piano, I'll borrow it, okay?
Otherwise, you got to...
You got to own all the pianos in the world and life gets heavier.
Non-sectarian.
Therefore, it's not limited geographically or culturally or ethnically.
Many of the religions, you know, became ethnic, secularized.
They really became...
And I'll tell you what the error was and it is very prominent today.
Instead of worshiping God, they worship the religion.
Religionism.
It replaces God.
It releases truth.
You're worshiping the priests and the holy places.
You want to walk where Baba walked.
I mean, people really, they go all across the planet to walk where Baba walked.
There's nothing about Baba there anymore at all.
If you calibrate the holy lands, you'll find they're about 182 or 210 or something.
Nothing holy about the holy lands at all.
People have been blasting each other to death on the holy lands.
You got to walk over the dry blood.
So,
what isn't a space or locality or personage is nothing that's owned.
There's nothing, no ritual you have to do.
All right.
To be a member of our class, you got to say regimentary backwards.
No, that's why you have such a small class.
Okay.
So, there's no code words.
There's no secrets, non-sectarian.
It doesn't depend on opinion.
Truth is non-linear, not subject to opinion.
Not subject to opinion.
So, the downside of religion then is actually, if you look at it, you'll see the politicalization of religion.
Now, the non-integrist ego uses religion for its own non-integrist purposes,
to control other people, to gain property, to get money out of the peasants,
to control the serfs.
And the serfdoms, the fiefdoms, to hand out the titles, it seeks worldly, secular power.
It glamorizes itself and it aggrandizes itself.
It gives itself incredible titles.
Emperor of all of creation, I am the emperor of Europe.
And that's when Napoleon went from 460 down to 160 or whatever he was,
for the people.
And that's when Napoleon went from 460 down to 160 or whatever he was, for the people.
Napoleon was incredibly integrist, contributed a great deal to Europe.
And then when he crowned himself emperor, he defied the sovereignty of God,
because the ruler came via divinity, and divinity in those days was known via the church.
And it was the pope that declared you emperor.
When Napoleon declared himself emperor, and crowned himself, his consciousness calibration went from 460 to 160.
450 or 60, down to 160, and therefore at the Battle of Waterloo. At Waterloo,
Napoleon was counting on the power he once had. You know, he was a magical,
mystical midget, right? I mean, when Napoleon stood in front of his troops,
his troops adored him. They adored him. He was a wondrous and marvelous human being,
you know, and I loved Napoleon before he crowned himself. He was a
great figure, you know, but in that sodoing, he usurped the power of God as
represented in the culture of its time and he found really the sovereignty of
God. So, and then at Waterloo, of course, he was mincemeat. Okay. No requirements or
demands. You don't have to promise anything. No membership.
You don't have to sign anything.
You don't have to take any secret oaths.
There's no regulations, no rules or conditions.
Nobody gets expelled.
Prison can screw up really awful.
We don't care.
Say you're sorry that you killed those eight people.
Come on now.
I'm sorry.
Okay, come back.
A decent regret.
What stands traditionally is all that's really necessary.
Not to grovel, because that's another ego game.
You know, you've groveled your way through, I don't know,
how many pairs of knee pads in front of the cathedral.
I mean, what a grand display.
Why, you flagellate yourself, you know.
I mean, that's all the drama.
That's all ego drama.
Non-binding.
You don't have to sign any oaths, contracts.
Freedom.
Everybody's free to come and go as they wish.
Oh, commonality.
Nobody's special.
People have a function to do.
Function to do.
I got to give the lectures.
I mean, if I don't give the lectures, who's going to give them?
You know what I mean?
I got to.
So, you are what you do, what purpose you serve.
You know what I mean?
But nobody's like ooh la la by virtue of a title.
You know, you're the sixth patriarch of the eighth descendant
of the third incarnation of Baba Bum Bum.
Yeah, right.
First of all, the truth is non-linear, so you can't transmit it.
There's no linear, linearity by which to transmit it.
It doesn't get transmitted.
You bump into the Buddha, you were ready for the enlightenment,
you got the enlightenment.
It wasn't transmitted from him to you.
You walked into the field by karmic design.
It isn't like a this Buddha gives enlightenment to a that.
Devate.
Isn't that right?
No.
The difference is there's a difference.
There's a difference.
Devate's vibration and frequency rises to a certain level and welcomes that.
And then in the presence of the teacher, becomes energized by that aura, that vibration.
You don't know when you'll need it.
It could be ten lifetimes.
Or it could be tomorrow.
Just as your car turns over, as it goes off the cliff.
And the third flip, you got it, baby.
You watch the car roll along in the bottom.
You go.
Big deal, big deal, big deal.
Freedom.
Commonality.
Inspirational.
It's partly the job of a teacher to try to present information in such a way that it is cognizant of that which is listening to it.
It's one thing to say it well and good for yourself.
It's one thing to be integrous and to state the truth.
But you can't ignore the audience.
Huh?
So I say things.
I say things that are not considered spiritual, yeah, amongst your feet, you know, where the sun don't shine.
That ain't fancy language.
But that's one reason we have a lot of men in our groups.
A lot of, well, a lot of motivational speakers.
You see the, you know, you see the video, you taste them on TV, and they're like 90% women.
And the guys are sitting there like they've just been dragged to the opera, you know.
You look at the next one, you see.
You see the guy sitting there.
Kind of look attentive to please her, and he's being polite to the speaker, and it's vaguely interesting, but it's not really his, his thing.
It ain't his shtick, you know.
So I also speak to men, because there's also men out there.
We don't live in the world of daisies and flowers.
They're living the world of make a mistake, and you're no longer president of this corporation, buddy.
So, okay.
Freedom.
Free to come and go.
Commonality.
Recognition is the consequence of what you do and what you become.
We inspire each other by the example of who we have become.
It's not materialistic.
You don't have to build great edifices.
Not that there's anything wrong with that, because human nature wants to put in the linear
world representational.
That which is representational.
Of.
Worship.
So the great cathedrals are awesome, see.
National Cathedral in Washington, D.C. is an exact Gothic you'd think you were in the
14th century in Europe.
Incredible, because that design has come to mean devotion, dedication, worship, and the
Christian ideal of, the essence of Christianity.
To worship, so it is a symbolic.
So.
In and of itself, then, it represents an expression, an art form.
Architecture is an art form.
Non-temporality.
Equality.
Equality means this understanding that all of life is equally of value.
So during lunchtime we went out in the back, and here was a stunning, I guess what the
world would call a weed or something.
And both of us looked at it, and its perfection was incredible.
And little berries in the middle of it.
So you see the perfection, the presence of divinity as perfection.
In all that exists, it's not exclusive.
Spiritual truth is not provable.
Proof belongs to the world of cause and effect.
The Newtonian paradigm.
It can be demonstrated, it can be verified, but you cannot prove it.
You can become it.
You can calibrate the likelihood of its presence.
That still doesn't prove, prove.
So proof is a different dimension.
Beyond 500, you can't really prove anything anymore.
You can only become it.
You can't prove love.
You become loving, and it's your experience, your reality.
But you can't prove it.
So 500 and up is not provable.
It's beyond proof.
Mystical.
What does mystical work mean?
It means it did not come about as a consequence of the Newtonian cause and effect.
Improbable.
Unlikely.
Statistical likelihood.
Mystical is sort of a kicked about word.
In its true meaning, it means to realize from within.
Which is mysterious to the intellect, but not to the mystic.
.
What's mystical, mysterious to the mystic is how people could still fall for the sequential
linearity of the ego.
Yeah.
So the mystic then has a tradition in Christianity.
There are the great mystics that are revered.
Mysticism, if you look it up in the Dictionary, the Encyclopedia, a lot of the phenomena that
I experienced and I describe in various books is the very same.
The various ailments that come and go.
And the higher you get, the more they can be.
Like all your nerves are on fire.
So I warn people of that too.
Once you decide to drive the whole way, the nervous system is not used to handling energies
of that dimension.
Don't forget these are logarithmic progressions.
Logarithmic.
So the difference between 785 and 790.
.
785 and 790 is considerable.
And at about 850, it becomes quite a challenge.
Which we wrote about in this new book, how to handle those levels.
Because everybody here is going to be enlightened, I'm telling you about it now.
Don't worry about it when you get there.
But there is a sensation like you're burning from within.
I'll tell you how to transcend it.
It means that.
from what level on you're pulling up from the collective
unconscious of mankind. It's not your personal
karma anymore. It's not your stuff. You already
cleared that already.
You start pulling from the collective
over 700, over
750,
800.
You start pulling from the
collective from over 650,
660.
Right in there?
Yeah?
Okay, so you see you've already
cleared all this stuff in yourself.
itself. So it's a
mystification. Why am I
experiencing this pain?
Any kind of a spiritual error brings up pain.
If you're holding
something somewhere in your consciousness
that is not aligned with the absolute truth,
it brings up pain. That forces
you to go within and ask God,
Almighty God, creator of the universe,
and all things visible and invisible,
you are the son of the Lord Jesus Christ.
I pray that you will
bring forth into my awareness
what it is that
is not aligned with truth.
Something will come out
of some archetype deeply buried
in the collective unconscious.
And in my own experience,
the
spiritual night was the
toughest.
The spiritual night kept coming up.
I'd be burning all over.
I'd forgiven everything
decades ago. What am I indignant
about? All of a sudden, like a
rage, an indignation
at the violation of the truth of God
came up over and over.
Man, it practically fried my nervous
system to death.
Indignation
at the desecration
of truth
and the glee at doing
so, that was bad
enough. But then the agreement
of large percentage of the population
with it was what brought up the outrage.
Had a heck of a time.
Was it a personal me, which has long
since given it up?
But beyond a certain level,
you're like bringing it up
for the collective consciousness
of mankind, as described by Carl Jung.
As you see, the
calibrated level of consciousness of mankind
has slowly been rising. Not slowly,
been rising rapidly.
Because each being of advanced
awareness now begins to
take responsibility for some
portion of the collective.
I don't remember it being volitional. I'll have to look
into that. But...
laughter
odd illnesses and strange
passing phenomena,
you suddenly get red and hot and
sweat and your nervous system goes to
the blink. So with prayer
then, you sort of become aware.
It's not within the
intellectual domain. You wake up
in the morning and you suddenly see
what it is. You see what it
is. You see what it is.
That if I was really a warrior
of truth, I would be
defending their right
to forgiveness instead
of making them wrong. You see a
different kind of an understanding will come up.
And all of a sudden, the energy disappears.
Then you may be okay for days, weeks,
hours, and it may start again.
So I'm just telling you. And the
Buddha wrote about it. As I said, when it
became severe, we were in Korea.
And Susan pulled out of the side
table, opened it to
the Buddha. And the Buddha said his bones
felt like his bones were
cracked. And I said,
whoa, yeah, right.
And then it was okay.
All right. So now
what holds people at the various
consciousness levels is
usually a duality. There
is an attraction and an aversion.
So
the pathway to enlightenment is constantly
one of surrendering
both attractions and aversions.
The attraction is to pay
off. Every ego position
has a payoff. The
payoff of feeling right.
The indignity of my
spiritual night.
The desecration of what they've done.
They've grown
up the great Buddha of
Afghanistan. I mean, one thing
after another, these people were like
pushing you to see how far they could
push you. So
you have to
give up that indignation.
The pleasure of that indignation.
And the seduction
of it. You see the seduction of being
right. And
surrender to
humility. With
humility and the surrender then,
there comes a realization
of a different dimension.
And that realization
is of a different dimension
and it's beyond the duality.
Beyond the duality.
Okay.
So as you evolve then, you're lifting others.
Each one
lifts the other.
So what can people do to help
the people that are downtrodden in the world
and all? Aside from
the physical support
and very obvious things
you can do, is
by our combined intention,
by that which we have become,
we lift the level of the sea.
We all lift the level
of the sea. And as the level
of the sea rises, it lifts
up all the ships on the ocean.
So the consciousness
level of mankind
went from one,
I forget what it was, over the centuries.
In the
late 80s, it suddenly jumped
from, I think, 190.
Yeah, 190. It was stuck.
It was stuck at 190 for many centuries.
And then suddenly in the late 80s
went, bang, up to 205.
Then in
October, I think it was last year,
it suddenly went to 207.
So you see, the sea is rising.
The consequence of the sea
being rising, however,
is that it precipitates catastrophe
all over the place.
Yeah.
At 190, Enron wouldn't have fallen
in a rule of calm.
At 205, it falls.
Yeah.
The payola works
until you're
at the level of integrity.
Now payola doesn't work.
You go to the clink.
Poor Liddy.
Oh, yeah.
So here are the,
we put them as the classic dualities.
We could,
you know, spend a lecture on any one
of them. We all like
that which is familiar and secure.
And we don't want to really make a change.
There's a resistance to change.
So here's the attraction.
I want to be where I'm familiar.
I want things to stay the same.
And I really
don't want to
change. That applies
to you as a person.
Yeah.
I don't really want to give up being a pickpocket.
I had
to do that in France in one lifetime.
Give up being a pickpocket.
Boy, I was good at it, too.
Clever pickpocket.
And they still play the same
games that we used to play.
So this is familiar
way of life, and you've got to change.
The attraction is
therefore clinging to things
and the fear of the new.
Even
spiritual work brings up
as much as you don't like
a certain way of being, nevertheless
it's familiar, habitual.
And there's a certain comfort in that.
And one has to then surrender that.
Because this way is easy,
and this one seems to take effort.
Seems to take effort
to correct myself.
Every time I make the same
mistake, put it in the wrong place,
I have to now put the effort forth.
It doesn't go on the third shelf,
it goes on the second shelf.
However,
after a couple of times, you automatically put it
in the right place. In the end, it's rewarding.
Because it increases
your pride.
Now, the attraction of pride is,
it's the energy
of the thing itself.
So all these so-called negatives,
it isn't what they are,
it's the payoff
juice. It's the ego's
payola. You lack
the sensation and the pleasure of it.
You're hooked on the pleasure.
Alright, so you'll do
anything on the left side here
to get that payoff.
You'll win, you'll be right, you'll be successful,
prove that guy wrong, whatever.
Because the
payoff is always the same.
Alright, so
pride doesn't like to look
at the possibility of humility.
And it confuses
humility with humiliation.
It means to the ego
to be less than.
Not realizing that humility
allows you to be greater than.
Greater than.
Out of humility, you are greater than that.
Yeah.
So pride is
an illusion. It's a self-puffery.
And it's the way the ego
keeps going.
And it also can be quite proud of its
humility, as we all know.
One of the
aspects of the ego
is the substitution by
spiritual pride.
And it's very hard for
a group of intelligent people
not to get some degree of it,
at least on the intellectual level.
I've heard that, yes.
I've been there, I heard that speaker.
Or
a
,
they read that book, they're familiar.
And of course, if you know a lot of Sanskrit,
that definitely makes you better than other people.
A lot of Sanskrit.
Okay.
People like anger
because then it gives them a false sense of strength.
You feel, when you feel angry.
So the animal with anger puffs up.
The rooster puffs up, the gorilla puffs up.
The idea is to intimidate your enemy
to appear stronger than you are.
Anger then, one of the things you get out of it,
one of the payoff,
is an illusion of strength.
Now anger is not strength, as you well know.
In fact, as an opponent,
as an opponent,
a trick is,
he didn't see that,
but I just got him pissed off.
Now that I got him pissed off, I got him skewered.
See, the coach didn't see that.
I tried to sneak in, to get him into anger.
See, the coach didn't see that. I tried to sneak in, to get him into anger.
Because in anger, I can skewer him in a second.
In anger, you take a position, see?
If you don't take a position, you can't be hit,
because you intuitively get how he's coming at you,
and you intuitively move aside.
The kung fu of survival.
You have to know before he strikes,
where the strike was coming from,
and you have to intuit what it was about you
that was attracting the strike in that area.
And you pick out that you took some kind of a stance, okay?
It was your stance that he read,
and therefore he came back in that space which you created, huh?
All right, so anger then is a weakness.
In a combative situation,
other than decoy deception,
which is always worth the try,
you always try to get him mad.
You kick him where the coach can't see it.
Now you got him.
He comes in with anger.
He says, gotcha.
With anger, you skewer yourself.
So it is not a strength.
A strength is wisdom.
Ah, wisdom, that is strength.
The guy just stands there and reads you
before the bout starts.
Watch him.
I did boxing years back, you know?
And if the guy's reading you, look out,
because he isn't coming on with bravado.
He's not coming on with anger.
He's coming on with cool calculation.
Dangerous, all right.
So strength then is staying cool.
The attraction here, of course, is to win,
which everybody sees as a gain,
and the fear, of course, is loss.
And that's the whole world we live in,
the world of gain and loss.
The stock market, everything else is win and lose.
All right, the other gains are feeling important.
One of the reasons we like to win is we feel important.
It gives us a temporary sense of empowerment.
Empowerment.
There is a legitimate side to winning as respect,
the recognition that the consequence was as a result
of your own dedication and effort.
That's a recognition, which is different than a vanity.
The attraction of money, excitement,
of desire itself, status, these are familiar,
and I'm working on them for the next book, because each of these,
are aligned with certain levels of consciousness.
We're going to stop a few minutes early,
because we don't have time for Nico to chant.
And so we're going to stop at 5 or 2.
People love opinions.
Stop any person on the street,
and they've got an opinion on everything.
I remember an old friend of mine that became seriously involved
in a recovery group, spiritual group.
And he came over to my house one day, and he says,
you know, Dave, I've just stunned and knocked out.
I said, what is it?
He said, I just realized I don't have
to have an opinion on everything, and I feel so free.
I'm not obligated to have one.
I don't have to fight for one, stand for one, defend one,
create one, position one.
I don't need to have an opinion.
What do you think about the election?
I don't think anything about it.
Democracy in action, how does that sound, you know?
About catastrophes, well, you know, as Ramana Maharshi says,
the world you see, you think you see, doesn't even exist.
And his recommendation is that you surrender it to God.
His recommendation is.
Because you don't know what's right and wrong.
You don't know what's the undoing
of bad karma or good karma.
What looks to you like a catastrophe to other people,
it's frankly salvation.
Anybody who's been on the edge
of catastrophe has been on the edge of catastrophe.
Anybody who's been on the edge of catastrophe has been on the edge
Remember, it was the edge of the catastrophe the guy should let go
and got you the salvation.
Without that catastrophe, without your feet being held
to the fire, you weren't about to quit, were you?
Oh, he's holding people's feet to the fire.
Isn't God cruel?
Yeah, right.
I remember when I became an atheist,
I went from a devout religionist,
as I've told you before, and walking through the woods one day,
out of nothing, out of nothing,
I wouldn't think about anything,
came to me the revelation of the totality
of the suffering of mankind throughout all of time.
It was like the opposite of what was later realized.
It was like it's denial or opposite.
When I saw the totality of the agony, the totality of the agony
of all of mankind's suffering over eons of time, it was staggering.
I went into like shock.
Instantly, I became an atheist.
No God who allowed or created that could I worship,
and I became an angry atheist, angry that God could allow.
So I held God responsible for what is really the consequence
of the human ego.
I was looking at the consequences
of the collective human ego.
I wasn't looking at the divinity of creation.
Huh?
The ego held God responsible.
So you see how spiritual ignorance, then,
we can fall into the depths.
I was a serious atheist for 20 years.
To get out of it actually took me to the depths of the lower hells,
not the hells of agony, the hells far beyond agony,
far beyond, indescribable, which go on for eons.
The foreverness of hopelessness,
is out of time.
And out of that, a voice arose, out of somewhere.
Some good karma somewhere.
Thank you, old ancestor, for worshiping the bear God
or something, because out of somewhere,
there is a God I ask him to help me.
And then came the great, incredible experience,
and the going through the valley of death and the death.
And that which you are, literally,
does die.
The experience of that which you are does die.
And that opens the opposite of that vision,
of the presence which wipes out everything,
other than its own reality and truth, yeah.
Okay, so then, as a consequence of that,
comes the commitment, yes, to share that which you have
experienced, witnessed, can verify,
and willing to put your hand on the Bible about.
And then to combine that with a verification coming about,
through some objective means, such as the intellect,
utilizing the scientists, et cetera.
In the meantime, the personage accomplishes this
in the world, and having done all that,
I have fulfilled my dedication to you,
as a teacher, this day.
Yeah, I dedicate it to you, and to your obvious future,
and what you will be doing for others,
because it goes on and on and on and on through eternity.
That which you will become will become
that which triggers that which will become,
which will become, and so you'll see yourself
as part of the evolution of consciousness.
That's creation and evolution are one and the same thing.
So, all right, we're gonna stop, and allow a chanting,
which is a unique experience.
As you know, Niko chants the Lotus Sutra in Sanskrit.
Gives yourselves notice that your chairs
are just totally accepting of you, as is divinity.
And just lean in the, you know, open,