Hawkins I deal with some people who have Tourette syndrome and do you have any
suggestions that I may pass on to them Tourette nothing special no I have
research to it hey my question is about the angels incarnating in the physical
is that similar to the human incarnation are they born to parents and live alive
well angelic is calibrated from 500 no in other words people who are motivated
primarily by love and especially if their pathway is karma yoga the pathway
of service it to them it's natural to stop and help us danger and trouble so
they don't realize they're angels or angelic no they don't they just they
just that's the way they are the same reason I stopped and turn over beetles
just
who you've become automatically does those things yeah cool you've become
automatically does those things because that's the way you contextualize it yeah
can we share a codec moment I mean you know you see yeah you see the response
of America to Katrina and various disasters around the world
oh both of us are you had to pull the
whatever
benevolence is automatic once you're calibrate you know really in the high
300s yeah my question is how does one transcend lust or sexual desire then
sends sexual desire depends on what how old you are
or if it's even necessary time will take care of it yeah all right it has to do
with the projection of specialness it has to do with what we're talking about
during lecture it's a projected projection of specialness the allure of
desirability is a projection
that you project onto the object the motivation is the animal motivation of
lust itself and then you projected onto that and think that person has sex
appeal that person is a tough for a lot of you and you think it's
got sex appeal to see yeah can I get a picture as well actually it's a hard one
to get rid of when you're young
ok ok celibacy is a tongue twister that's what you're talking about is religious celibacy is conversation and form and so on and now we've got all of these things that are connected to the divine power.
Celibacy is a discipline, you know, Ramakrishna, the Ramakrishna order, which I looked into when I was younger, you had to be under the age of 24 or something like that, you weren't allowed to touch money, the rule was celibacy, and you weren't even allowed to touch money, if money had an energy, which Ramakrishna thought, was so seductive to people.
So his solution was to completely avoid it, completely avoid it, detach from it, and avoid it, you know?
Hi, Dr. Hawkins. I work with troubled teenagers that are involved with drugs, and I guess I'm looking for some wisdom as to how to encourage them to raise their consciousness, to, you know, to look beyond that and find something, especially if they're depressed, one of them just lost his best friend, use that as an excuse to go get on drugs.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you for your life and for your teachings, I appreciate them so much.
My question has to do with the relationship of the teaching...
teachings and the whole process of enlightenment,
and how that relates to developing an organization, a clinic, a hospital.
How that relates to a hospital or a clinic?
Yes.
It doesn't relate to it.
Okay.
I'm wondering, other than having staff who have maximum consciousness,
is there anything in particular, obstacles that I can be aware of
to help improve the ability of a clinic to bring healing to persons?
Well, the clinical reflects who you are,
and the clinic I had back east reflected, in all of its functions,
that which I had become.
I was spiritually oriented, so I encouraged the Course in Miracles people
to establish an attitudinal healing center.
All the AAs in Long Island used to come there,
and we gave free B12 shots once a month.
You know?
That kind of thing.
So, we encourage people to do the Course in Miracles.
You've got a hopeless disease.
What can you do about it?
I suggest you take the Course in Miracles.
If you recover, it's terrific, and if you don't, you won't care.
If you do the Course, you're not going to give a damn one way or the other.
So, you uplift people by that which you have become.
So, you get the leader.
The leader is going to radiate out the energy.
So, we favored everything.
Free, alternative, anything that would help.
Standing on your head and eating oatmeal upside down.
If that helped, we'd try it.
You know?
And we tried all kinds of things that other people would consider wacky.
Rotation diets, cerebral allergy.
I had patients that would get, you know, we'd take 1 to 10,000 dilution of potato.
I remember putting it under his tongue, and he became psychotic right on the spot.
So, we gave him a neutralizing dose, and the psychosis disappeared.
These are all things that traditional medicine pooh-poohed, you know?
Yes.
And I told the story many a time about the lady who was getting the 5-hour glucose tolerance test,
and we would do serial electroencephalograms.
And during the fifth hour after her blood sugar shot down like this,
she tore all her clothes off and ran down Northern Boulevard.
Stark naked, running down the sidewalk.
And the lab director, as I say, he was like Ichabod Crane, about 6'6", in a big skinny pole.
In his white coat, flying behind him.
Come back, Mr. Crane.
Come back, Ms. Dawson.
And the cars jammed each other under her butt.
Now, the traditional medical person was pooh-poohing hypoglycemia.
This woman became psychotic.
Ran down the street stark naked.
So, you're going to pooh-poo it?
No, sir.
I'm not going to pooh-poo it.
And the blood sugar goes from, you know, 160 and rockets down to 60 in a matter of minutes.
You can become very psychotic.
Violent.
Yeah.
So, the dedication to do everything you can to be of help to the patient and their family.
Everything that's spiritual, consciousness, psychological, physical.
Everything that's physical, mental, and spiritual.
And if you're doing what you can do for a patient, you've got to be operating on all three.
Yes.
Plus, the energy field of the doctor has a bigger impact than the modality used.
I heard he fired scotches by the desert.
Some of them had terrific responses on almost everybody, and others just constantly didn't.
So, if you hold in mind who you are, holds in mind that this person's going to get better and improve and fulfill their potential,
the doctor's attitude has a bigger, you know, because of the Heisenberg principle.
Now, the Heisenberg principle hasn't been studied from the viewpoint of the consciousness level of the observer.
So, let's take the average scientist, you know, at 400.
He's an integrist as far as he understands truth, but he's not a walking miracle worker at 400 either, see?
So, you can have somebody who holds in mind great love for all of his patients, and he treats them because he loves them all.
And his patients recover all the time.
Yes.
And if they don't, they don't care.
I used to train them.
If you can remember things again, it's going to be swell.
And if you don't, what the hell's the difference?
You're right.
I'd say to the wife, don't let them drive anymore, that's all.
Thank you so much.
I kept practicing because a couple of my old-time patients were so dependent on me, I couldn't dare to wait until they died, and then I quit.
The guy used to smoke with the oxygen tank.
I had to wait until he left the planet.
Thank you so much.
So, the love, you know, you have a love for your patients.
You hold them in that love.
Not a possessive, controlling love.
But sort of.
Holding them in the light of divine love, you know.
And don't forget, everybody is fulfilling their own karmic destiny.
The fact that a patient doesn't get better is not exactly a catastrophe.
You pray for somebody to get sober.
They don't.
They roll over a car.
Just as they roll over the car, they get it.
And then the car crashes and they're dead.
They got it.
So, from your viewpoint, you think it was a failure.
You got it.
Hey, I got it.
Hey, whoop.
I got it.
In this door, you get it.
Flash.
Oh, wow.
Success.
So, unless you use kinesiology to diagnose how the case went,
you don't know whether it was a success or a failure.
Sometimes intervention prevents a person from learning the karmic lesson
that the whole thing was set up to provide for them.
Okay.
Thank you.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
I just want to thank you so much for your books.
They're a gift to humanity.
And we all appreciate them very much.
I feel compelled to ask you where my vibration is.
Huh?
I feel compelled to ask you what my calibration is.
Oh, no, we can't do that.
No.
We don't do that.
Okay.
You look on the level of consciousness.
Look what your predominant attitude is.
Okay.
How you see God.
Right.
How you see your fellow man.
Your prevailing emotionality.
Okay.
And you can pretty much guess it.
Yeah.
If you're angry all the time, that's where you are.
Yeah, so you're not there, so don't worry about it.
You wouldn't be here if you were below 200 anyway, so don't worry about it.
Okay.
The only thing you've got to, you know, worry is not the right word.
The only thing to be concerned about is whether you're above 200 or not.
When they're on, the rest is obvious.
Okay.
Once you're over 200, the rest is certain.
It's getting over the 200, that's it.
Right.
Because the lure and the seduction of power over people and the fun of cruelty and winning
at any cost and killing your enemy, I mean, you know, the payoff.
So if you can get off the payoff of below 200, the rest you don't have to worry about.
Once you're over 200, you don't have to worry unless you fall for some major trap, you know.
Going to bed with your followers and some craziness.
Thank you.
Here.
Oh, don't be.
You're friendly.
Really.
You're friendly, aren't you?
No, I'm not friendly.
You are.
My question is, are we supposed to protect ourselves or is there a way to protect ourselves
from falling to a lower level of consciousness?
Spiritual integrity is the only thing you can follow.
Okay.
And then, of course, spiritual education.
We weren't born with a spiritual education.
Okay.
We are that.
Due to good karma, we pull to ourselves teachings and teachers that provide us with the information
that we need, you know.
Right.
Yeah.
We follow, you know, our belief systems to the best we can, you know.
And you pray for help.
Don't forget you're praying for divine help all along the way.
Right.
Thank you.
My question is concerning prayer, and I know there's been some things talked about, about
prayer today already, and like if it raises the calibration of your food and stuff, I
know it will.
works but if we can't pray for karma to interfere with karma some somebody else or ourselves or
praying for selfish things like a new car or whatever can you give me some feedback on
the importance why we pray and what for and whatever pray for it you can pray about it but
not for it so what's the general no you just surrendered to god's will yeah i have an issue
with that i have a hard time with that
sorry that's true of everything currently well you'd see you you work on surrendering god's will
it's running to god's will about such matters and you hold in mind you hold in mind
that which you value and desire what you desire and value what you hold in mind tends to manifest
when you've
got karmic permission see having cheated a lot of people for a lot of lifetimes you may have to
wait a while before you get wealthy in this lifetime that's it yeah okay i've noticed some
of those things that you said the things you hold in mind or your esteem will come what you hold in
mind tends to manifest i've noticed that already and then you pray and then you pray for and you
surrender your will to god you know and you say you know if it's your will for me then
you're not going to be able to do that you're not going to be able to do that you're not going to
be able to do that so you pray about it yeah you pray about it you know you picture what you want
and if it's karmically permitted it manifests sometimes years later you can picture the ideal
situation and then it doesn't manifest for some time you know right but in the meantime you just
hold it in mind okay um also i brought along a dollar first one today i see oh it's got forbidden
words on it can we okay let me and who we trust
oh mail this to michael
it says those horrible words cross them out crossing it out and mailing it to michael
i shouldn't make beat up on michael do i get the hug though he wants a hug you have to be very
gentle yeah yeah okay okay yeah thanks we shouldn't beat up on michael oh wait
Hello. Thank you for your teachings. I appreciate it.
My question is, there's something I'm trying to clear up.
There's something I'm trying to clear up, a life situation.
About two years ago, I sold my business, and I figured I wanted to dedicate my life to God.
I wanted to dedicate myself to enlightenment, to truth.
And I figured I will find work that will help me do that.
And it's been two years, and I'm still not working.
I just want to know, is it calm?
Everything's supposed to happen on its own.
Is this supposed to be that I'm not supposed to be working?
Well, you know, you're making it too linear.
It's not what you do, it's how you are within the world.
What you become within the world.
Because of what you've become, it's irrelevant what you do.
Whether you work in a factory, whether you're a shoemaker, whether you're a clerk.
It makes no difference what you do.
I noticed the lack of graciousness in society is such that when you are really appreciative of somebody,
they about fall over, they about fall over.
What do you mean, nobody's nice to this clerk all day?
Because when you say, you know, I think this is the greatest store.
There's a store in town that I just love, and I think the people there are just stunning, you know?
And I say, wow, where did all these people come from?
No matter what you do, they say, can I help you?
Amazing.
I went to a hardware store.
Hardware store?
Yeah, no matter what they do.
I wanted to get a scissors, Jack.
He says, I'll get it for you.
He sees me as an elderly gentleman, you know, he's in his early twenties.
And he goes over and picks up the scissors, or whatever you call it.
No matter what I did, somebody was there to like quickly help.
So there's like an energy in the place that they all are aligned with that energy.
So it's like, for me not to work is a positionality that I'm holding.
That I feel that it would hold me back in some way.
Yeah, it won't hold you back because you can be benevolent wherever you go.
So it's best just to find a job and work.
You can be in the boardroom of a giant corporation, and your benevolence and your integrity influences others, you see?
You become the obstacle to their non-integrity.
They've got to get past your vote.
So work to not to work is irrelevant.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's how you are within the world.
Yeah.
You know, that store that I'm speaking of, they think I'm a funny character too.
In fact, my wife went in there later to get something.
And they told him about this.
Some gentleman was in here and just bought it.
And he wasn't supposed to be driving all by himself in town either.
Really funny.
So how does it work?
Work will come to me that I'm supposed to be doing?
Or just something I have to go out and just grab?
I don't know. Why don't you get a job?
I'm worried about that.
Where do you live?
I live in Washington, D.C. I mean, I live in Seattle, Washington.
Oh, Seattle. Oh, yeah.
All right. So anything appeal to you? No?
Well, I used to do computers.
I can go back to doing that.
Mm-hmm.
No, it's the energy with which you do a thing and the way you are with it, see?
What you are to the company.
What you're saying is I don't want to just punch a keyboard all day, and I can understand that.
What you want is something with grace.
Something with greater human interaction.
Well, I would prefer that.
Okay, so then there's all kinds of humanitarian societies that I'm sure would be happy to start you.
Mm-hmm.
That's where I'd start.
Okay.
I like the Salvation Army.
I always envy them at Christmas.
You get to stand there with a kettle.
I think it's great.
Wouldn't you like to be a Salvation Army person?
I think it's fantastic.
And you bless all the people and send them love, and they put money in the pot, and you take the money pot home,
and that helps poor people.
I mean, you know, isn't that great?
So I suggest you sign up for the Salvation Army for the holidays.
Okay, very good. Thank you.
It's fun.
Also, you give back what you give out.
In other words, if you volunteer to help, say, in a homeless shelter, you give that back in some other way.
So, you know, since you have been working for two years, it might be good to volunteer some more.
Yeah.
Okay, very good. Thank you.
I like to sell poppies for the VFW.
I like to collect money for the Salvation Army.
I like to collect money for the Boy Scouts.
Hi.
Yeah.
I have to collect my question.
You got it.
It's just, it's going to take time.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
Surrendering everything to God, and then asking to see it differently.
That's why I think the Course in Miracles works, because the Holy Spirit recontextualizes it,
and now when it's recontextualized, you see there's nothing to forgive.
Yeah.
Everybody's just being what they want to be, what they think they need to be, what they feel called to be.
And then there's times where I just feel like crying, and so I do, and then I feel like, ah, ego got me, you know?
I mean, it's okay, because crying is an emotion, but you don't want emotions to run you.
Okay.
I got it.
Okay?
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
Is this mic positioned correctly?
It's my cheek.
Okay.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Hello.
My question is about desire.
I've always been told that in order to bring about manifestation, you have to have a lot of strong emotions to desire.
No.
And according to your...
Desire holds it away.
Desire is negating that it belongs to you.
You deserve it.
Desire is a negation, because when you become all that you can be, all that you could possibly seek is given to you,
by virtue of the fact that you hold it in mind, that's all.
So holding something in mind with strong emotions doesn't tend to...
Forget the strong emotion.
Forget the emotions, huh?
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Drivenness is another issue.
There are moments when drivenness is the way you break through a barrier, so that isn't
the whole answer that I give you.
Roger Bannister effect.
Is it gritting your teeth and deciding you will not accept the limitation and you drive
through it with...
Yeah.
Sure.
When I contemplate the field or the context, it becomes difficult to think sometimes,
which is fine.
That's not a complaint.
And it's wonderful.
I love being in that mode.
The work I do for a living...
Yeah.
...is intensely mental.
You have to tell...
Yeah.
Okay now?
What you do for a living is what?
Intensely mental.
Mentally.
Yeah.
Okay.
And I'm wondering if it's possible to stay in that contemplative mode where I'm more
attentive to the context and do mental work, or is it time for me to look for different...
Generally not.
But if you become quite advanced at it, yes, you can do it all by yourself because you
don't identify with the linear processing.
Because you no longer identify with the mind.
So mentalization, left brain linear processing, you don't identify with it.
It's like breathing.
You just witness that it's a phenomenon going on.
Yeah.
But at a certain point of spiritual evolution, you may not be able to do left brain linear
processing.
Yeah.
I was afraid of that.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Susan...
It's very difficult for you sometimes.
Yeah.
So...
If it comes with an instruction book, I'm not going to take it out of the package.
Yeah.
The fact that you can live in this aura and be functional is such a gift to the rest of
us.
Thank you so much.
I don't always do it well.
She blisses out.
I got to...
I'm sure she does.
Yeah.
Hello.
Dr. Hawkins, last month, you told us that the group as a whole, Nan Callaghan, is a
whole.
Nan calibrates at 500.
The group...
It's the beginning of the lecture.
The group calibrates...
Yeah.
The group...
This group started out at about 400.
Right.
And it's now just over 500.
Could you say about what that means?
What it means?
Well, yes.
Because generally, people first are readers.
So they'll read something like Power Versus Force, and they'll say, wow.
And then, you know, then they'll find the author wrote something else.
And then they discover the...
Yeah.
And they slice the...
They practically give them the power...
That's what I'm saying here.
That's just a reporter's job.
Well...
About...
About 200 million Baht's of money.
Bulany, yeah.
Yeah.
And in, you know, approximately 300 million dollars worth of resources.
So now...
I don't know...
One hundred and...
Yeah.
I think...
Now what you mean...
Let's go to another boy who's at...
Okay.
Yeah.
A...
People call him Bill Lpatte.
Bill Lpatte's uh...
The pilot.
In the movie.
The pilot movie.
He leads everything from Disney, right?
Yeah.
Right.
they're karmically destined
I think this is a karmically
as far as karmic destiny
this is a gifted group myself
what are the chances
we figured out
I think it was in power versus force
the chances of becoming serious
actually interested in enlightenment
seriously oriented towards enlightenment
are less than 1 in 10 million persons
10 million people
you can say
what is the foremost
your ultimate ambition in life
1 in 10 million
will tell you to reach enlightenment
so to even be here
you see how unusual that is
all the 1 in 10 millions
are here right now
each one here represents
10 million people out there
let's see if that's a fact
we have permission to ask this
in the name of the highest good
what was just
stated as a fact
my god yes
each one of us represents
10 million
therefore a group like this
influences the collective consciousness
of all of mankind
a group such as this
influences the collective consciousness
of all of mankind
not as a consequence of what we do
say or believe
but by virtue of our intention
and that which we have become
to fulfill the potential
which Jesus Christ
the Buddha
Krishna
all the great teachers
taught us over time
we say yes to it
and we join in fulfilling that potential
that fulfills the vision of the Christ
and the Buddha for all of us
you see
so we become the fulfillment of
we can't say the intention of divinity
we can say of the
intrinsic potential
intrinsic to this
to the source of our own creation
you see that which you affirm
becomes more powerful
within yourself
if you affirm
each and any of us
every one of us here
is karmically destined for enlightenment
each and every one of us here
is destined for enlightenment
otherwise you wouldn't be here
that's a fact
this is a course in tennis
you see
who would be at a tennis class
except future tennis players
this is a course on how to reach
enlightenment
in the straightest
narrowest way that I know
therefore the karmic destiny
has brought us all together
that's why I say
everyone here is a gift to me
and you're a great gift to me
you're a great gift to me
the innocence and trustingness
of your love shines forth
you understand
shines forth
and it's with reverence
that I'm aware of it
with such trust
goes great responsibility
and the innocent are given to you
the responsibility is heavy
thank you
thank you for your trust and love
you see
the fallen guru savages the trust
the innocent trust
I put my life in your hands
my god what more could you ask
you see the responsibility
and you see the severity
of the consequence of violating it
you see the responsibility and you see the severity of the consequence of violating it
that's why a guru doesn't drop from 700 to 698
he usually drops from 700 to 135
because to violate the trust at that level
that's very heavy-duty energy to screw it up
to want to do it
this morning you mentioned the third eye of the Buddhic body
what is that Dr. Hawkins
well I shouldn't use that terminology
it's sort of a colic
sort of esoteric rather esoteric
not a colic but esoteric
it comes out of the buddha body it comes out of the buddha body it comes out of the buddha body it comes out of the buddha body it comes out of the buddha body it comes out of the buddha body
it comes out of the buddha body it comes out of the buddha body
it comes out of the bailey material
the white brotherhood material
it's describing various phenomena within the etheric body
the etheric body occupies the same physicality
and within the etheric body there is the chakra system
which most people are familiar
the base chakra the spleen the solar plexus the heart the heart the throat
and then there are beyond the crown chakra
more spiritual bodies of even higher dimension
going up to lower mental, higher mental
I can't recall the terminology at the moment
I think it's in the book though
yes I do in one sentence list all the various bodies
from the crown chakra up
one of the bodies on the way up
there's the Christ body, the etymic body
the top is the etymic body
below that is the Christ body, the Buddhic body
the higher mental, the lower mental
and then there's one in between that I'm blanking on
causal body, yeah right
so when spiritual advancement reaches a certain point
the capacity for discernment opens up
you don't have to calibrate a thing
you can tell by looking at it
this is not a person I want to hang out with
it's like you get what the energy is
you get what the essence is
the essence of it is just sort of intuitively
so the nearest thing to it in a spiritually aligned person
is to trust your intuition
or at least use your intuition
as a likelihood of God's trying to speak to you
through some modality that is non-linear
some people are very adept at that
Susan is very adept at that
I mean she knows the non-linear just through a knowingness
a knowingness
I don't know I get a bad feeling about you taking that highway
sure enough
on the evening news
there was a three car crack up on it
I mean you know she like knows it
but it's not through linear processing left brain
not through intellectual
so because you're aligned with integrity and divine love
the higher regions tend to respond to you you might say
the higher regions tend to
I say dear God I ask for your will in this matter
and then I wait for an answer
I say I ask for your will in this matter
and then I stop thinking about it
then I go out in the garden and I turn on a light
and suddenly as I'm turning the light on bang
I got what the answer is
it goes out of nowhere
so it's not a linear process
so prayer tends to intensify that
asking God for God's will
what is God's will for me
that's part of the 12 step program too
11th step we ask through conscious meditation
increase our conscious contact with God
asking only for God's will for me
for knowledge of his will for us
this couldn't be a better prayer
I can't think of a better one
well
excuse me
the original question I was going to ask
actually has already been answered several times
while I was standing in line
must have been a good question
well it was about
a relative of mine
a close relative has recently been diagnosed with schizophrenia
and I was going to ask how best
what sort of attitude or orientation to adopt
to best help this person
I guess to help me accept it and manage the situation
as well as to help this person
grow and develop to their potential spiritually
yeah you do the best you can
physical, mental and spiritual
that's what I got
get the best doctor you can
put them on the best medication you can
put them on every psychological
assist health group therapy individual
and then pray on top of it
and does
and illnesses like that
sometimes have a somewhat bizarre karmic
antecedent
so you don't know exactly what it is
to pray for
you know what I mean
yeah that's what
that was a confusing point as well
if you
you know wish the best for somebody
do you really know what that means
yeah then you
then you take the first step
in the
Al-Anon program for instance
you know you surrender them to God
and you pray for them
send them love
and surrender them to God
and you pray for them
and you surrender them to God
and give them the best doctor you can
the best treatment
what about
you know
spiritual insight versus intellectual insight
in terms of
spiritual development
of somebody that doesn't have that intellectual insight
are they still
you know like
when
with schizophrenia
they don't sometimes have that
I don't know how to answer
you don't know
so can you still
have a spiritual
oh yeah sure
insight
even though the intellect is gone
yeah
okay
, yeah
and I experienced many miraculous things
in treating schizophrenic patients
okay
I've told them
I you know brought in
and wrapped up in wet sheets
and
and squirming on the ground
totally demented
and I said within myself
I held his mudra
and then I got
I got the spirit within
instantly
you could see the peace within
another time
patient's laying on the floor
catatonic
the nurse is in the nursing office
and I'm holding in mind for him
I could see
I could intuit what was going on
I said you're blaming God
for what is the consequence of the ego
all of a sudden he jumped off the floor
and began talking
the nurse crossed herself
and
yeah
so all those things are at one time
what you can do for them
yeah
you know
and it was
it was
getting better
actually
it was
getting better
and maybe those things
they do
never
ever
two of you, and my brother. Oh, sure. Thank you. Yeah, what fun to be with people in the picture.
You know, isn't that fun? As a kid, you love it. Did you ever grow out of it? No, I don't think so. Smile for the camera. I quit combing my hair about it, though.
I have a booming voice. I should probably slide back. First, thank you for the guidance you gave me in Henderson.
It's been.
Thank you. Helpful. And my question relates to this as a purgatorial realm. Your description of the ego and its primary desire to be recognized for its divinity, to supplant God, is strikingly similar to the Genesis account of Satan's fall from grace.
That's it. You got it.
Is there an entity, or is that just a description?
No, that was Satan.
He just suffered from the same delusions that we do?
Creation creates all possibility. All possibility without limitation, right?
Right.
So you can refuse God or choose God. You can align with him. You can become polarized.
That which seeks to dominate, what was Lucifer's fall from the angelic realm, was really the sovereignty of God.
So, you see, the Satanic and the Luciferic. Satanic has to do with cruelty, war, sex, lust, tantalizing.
Addiction.
Addiction, yeah. And the Luciferic has to do really with a higher level, a really much higher level than Satanic. Satanic is just, you know, cheapo.
Let's get stoned and you know what, round the clock, and you know, it's all cheap stuff.
No, that's...
The Luciferic challenges dominion, challenges God's dominion, and the narcissistic ego, which is intrinsically secular because it hates God,
because to accept God means that the core of the narcissistic ego is not divinity, that you are not God.
And you see how this ego here, during the years of being an atheist, you know, you see the grandiosity of it.
How could one dumb intellect like this one, you know, know whether there is such a reality as divinity or not, in and of itself?
I mean, it's pomposity at its most ridiculous, isn't it, to be an atheist?
That's why agnostic Calvary is much higher.
Agnostic, you're beginning the road of humility.
I, of myself, am unable to know or verify divinity, you see?
That's the beginning of honesty.
Honesty, the mind.
It's not capable of knowing the divine.
The intellect is on this level, and it's not capable of knowing it, so...
The road back, then, is through humility.
So, all spiritual pathways are founded on humility.
Without humility, there's no progress of any kind.
You said the road back, which leads me into the second half of my question.
Did we, at some point, are we the one-third angels that followed him?
Did we, at some point, fall from grace, and this is, this purgatorial realm is a second chance?
I don't know.
Not sort of conjectural.
All I know is, we're here.
If we ask, is this a recycling center, we'll get a yes.
We have permission to ask this.
This is a karmic recycling center, is this, yep, where you get a chance to choose again,
to undo the negative karma of the past, and to gain positive karma, so the Buddhist tradition
of seeing.
In the Eastern, in the East, karma is just a given, nobody even questions about it.
It's only in the Western world.
However, here, we accept karma post-mortem, because certainly, where you go after death,
whether it's hell or heaven, is a karmic consequence of what you've chosen in this lifetime.
It's just that Christianity doesn't include a previous one, it is thought.
That is not a fact.
We inherit.
We inherit it across theду matter.
You make absolute day, I couldn't get it.
I would emissions theannonce license of garden of Eden.
Right.
I would talk about, you say you don't believe in karma, what about the garden
of Eden.
The original start.
Why do you need to save your in the first place?
If it wasn't for the garden of Eden, so Christianity does teach karma.
Just doesn't like the term, sounds too weirdo.
Without a savior, man fell from grace.
How did he fall from grace?
Because the garden of Eden was nonlinear.
To choose good and evil, to either funded itself.
I believe we errored.
It doesn't.
the fruit of good and evil was to buy the linear it wasn't all good versus evil in eden that's the
duality all right so the serpent the serpent tempted what man's fall was due to the intrinsic
innocence just what socrates said the intrinsic innocence of the child within so the serpent knew
that the innocence of the child was the way to get in there that wouldn't you like to eat of the tree
of knowledge yeah of good and evil there you go so the fall was then inferred allegorically
that we were once in a non-linear reality and by some kind of temptation fell from grace
into the linear and once you're into the linear the way to hell of course is paved see because
you're into right and wrong right and wrong puts you into hate puts you into enemy and friend i
so it's okay for me to have resentment against adam then okay so it's adam against adam
no it was eve
now i'll tell you what it was the serpent knew the intrinsic vulnerability the very thing i teach
during these classes the ego in and of itself cannot discern truth from falsity so the serpent
knew the downside uh
the human and the serpent got into the child the curious child it was the child that fell for the
serpent's temptation uh-huh yeah thank you that which i just described was correct oh lord amen
that was correct fell from the non-linear to the linear i'm watching the time okay
she beats up on me about the time poor me poor me poor me
poor me oh dear thank you for the question it's a very high it's a very advanced question
i don't know that i really completely answered it you know because i think only god knows the
answer to that question yes um i'd like to know um what the connection is between a creative
project and spiritual progress like writing or poetry or dance
and how that connects with spiritual uh pursuits or how how i can make the connection artistic
activity yes is not intrinsically divine no so you can use it for whatever ends it depends on
how you contextualize it you see if you dance to exhibit your joy if you dance to exhibit your joy
the ecstasy of the awareness of your own creation because the source of your own
existence stems from within once you once you realize that you can dance endlessly non-stop
and does your digit level of consciousness affect what you create i don't know any of that sort of
an academic question if you're dumb i guess you draw dumb pictures you know what i mean
is there a i guess what i'm asking is there is there a
are we ever sort of channels for divinity is that what you were saying ben
all of existence arises out of the presence of divinity so in a certain context all that occurs
as a consequence is done so under the ordinance of divine will understand what i'm saying the
overall context means that it happens is divinity that it happens at all is an expression of
potentiality actualizing because it's facilitated by local conditions yeah
so when you said um the creations of michelangelo for instance calibrate high
is that simply because he was um open to divinity or i don't know you're trying to put into the
intellectual terms that which is not really intellectual and not controllable i guess
so maybe i mean you can't you can't yeah so what did it happen your your artistic expression would
be an expression of that which you are that what you would become you know what i'm saying there's
no like purpose to it you draw because you're you're creative you're artistically you know
designed or you compete in the olympics because that's how you express your you know what i'm
saying you dance because you like to dance because that's the joy i express your joy
and then you just surrender it i wouldn't conceive of not surrendering it what was in that one
okay thank you you see
you yourself your life is is an artistic expression you are you are that
are you not it please join me in being it stop denying that you're not what you are
thank you thank you bye you see drama unfolds of its own about the intention
her intention my intention it wasn't thought of by either one of us it happened spontaneously
either one of us said the slightest idea of it beforehand you know yes okay my question
um in the bible jesus says something to the fact i am the way the truth and the light yes
no one comes to the father except through me but how does that square with other religions
in the world it's always with other religions yeah like i'm interested in buddhism i i like
the thought process and the clarity well the christ body is as we said is one of the highest
religious bodies right before the ethnic you don't get to the ethnic body without going through the
christ body but then what about all these other religions they don't believe in jesus christ
they don't believe in jesus christ that doesn't you know jesus christ is just a nominalization
you could remove the name jesus christ and it still is an energy field that you go through
okay yeah to let go of the selfish to let go of the egotistical to let go of the linear
the expression of the source of your own creation you can label it that anything
Buddhist you can label it anything the labels don't mean anything don't forget
all labels are only historic designations of all time we're already
in existence 10,000 BC they come very close to a thousand ten thousand BC but
Jesus Christ came to speak to a certain group of people he didn't appear in
India where the gurus already were had Dominion he came to the people that
needed to hear him they were worshiping the golden calf and they needed the
world the words of Jesus Christ you see the people today seem to need some
people yes people that I so we're attracted to that which I think would
serve the greatest good
you know you said they all calibrated a thousand the highest within to me so
whether you pursue you have one pathway or the other I think you're relevant I
think you know there's so much karmic influence on that you know so much
karmic influence what you've done what you've tried what you fell at each one
to provide something you want to really learn about yourself forgiveness
certainly Jesus Christ
forgiveness see so all that which is unforgivable comes up in a person who's
destined for Christianity because Socrates and Jesus Christ all taught the
same thing the Buddha said there's no point in attacking you know your enemies
because they will bring themselves down by their own hand so collectively when
you become sufficiently advanced they're all saying the same thing different
language thanks for being here yes I have a question I've been reading about
Robert Monroe the Monroe Institute yeah yes and I have his book you know but I
was thinking of going there because they have they do like a week where you can
be I'm both attracted and repulsed yeah I both want to go and not go I was just
kind of wondering what's your what's your take on this a feedback I don't
not sure how to ask the question but I have a question well Monroe was a unique
individual journeys out of the body a naive engineer suddenly he starts
astral projecting all over the place having wild adventures erotic adventures
he gets back into his body and there's his wife next to him in the bed and he's
had all these erotic adventures out there so he's struck by guilt besides in
those days nobody heard anything about such things so he was a pioneer all
right
, so Monroe was wandering around the astral dimensions you see and there
wasn't any information about it so and then he would come back in the body he's
an engineer so he'd make careful notes of you know scientific notes of what
phenomena very interesting you saw your heart started goes out to him because of
his naivete yeah he also gets involved with some rather negative energies you
know climb on his back and try to claws claw him out to death etc then Monroe
found that by creating a dissonance between the two hemispheres you know
sonic dissonance you could potentiate an altered state of consciousness and you
had different levels level 12 level 10 etc that plus self-hypnosis and using
the the art stimulation so you lay on a mat for 10 days and you do the practice
all this you learn how to do it at will now what's what do you learn from it
mainly intellectual curiosity I would say primarily intellectual curiosity
if other dimensions in the physical seems unreal to you once you go out of
body that you'll drop that one there are other dimensions a plenty and and as I
said in previous lectures that Monroe had the most incredible voice but Rose
voice had a profound intrinsic piece to it was that I've never heard a voice
like that Monroe just had a because you've worked with them yourself I did a
you know
but the Monroe Monroe he just had this incredible voice of stillness and peace
great and is it any use not really excepting to realize that there are
other dimensions I've gone out of body several times spontaneously as a result
of illness so it wasn't exactly a new to me but the fact that you could do it at
will then some people go out of body quite easily there's a sort of karmic
inheritance or
she's going to body and I think back here you
I was just a bit of my not my way back
no you're trained you're trying to get a claim to come back and they wouldn't
they don't let you out on your own until
like a double whistle on that was so you come back in the body and as i've said
that previous lectures i remember coming back in the body upside down
yeah this will came and I forget where I was up
We had made an agreement to meet somewhere out there in the semi-astral domain.
And all of a sudden we heard the whistle.
So I come back in the body and I'm looking out the back of my skull at the floor.
I had to back out of the body, go 180 and go back in again.
If you're scientifically trained such as I was, it's very interesting, of course, to the intellect.
I've been doing this work for 30 years, all kinds of discoveries.
The T.A. Gestalt and Fritz Perls and Erickson and all these things.
But I've never done Monroe stuff.
Anyway, Monroe's fun and it was enjoyable.
It won't bring you closer to enlightenment, but it will satisfy your curiosity.
One more thing.
One more doubt hits the dust.
Okay, thanks.
Thank you.
We've talked about astral projection.
Sure.
Yeah.
The level of consciousness remains the same before and after going out of body.
Whereas the calibrated level is a major difference before and after the near-death experience.
Near-death experience is a major jump in consciousness.
Astral projection, the reason it doesn't make a jump in your consciousness,
and we tested that, I think, with Yaron last lecture,
is because you knew it all the time that you're spirit.
You spend most of your time out there as a spirit
and very short amount of time as a body.
It was no surprise to you when you find yourself back into that which you've been for eons.
Yeah.
Hi there.
Your book, I, Reality and Subjectivity, calibrates at a very lucid 999.8.
And you also published that there are six people on Earth currently that calibrate above 600.
Only one above 900 would have seen it.
There were, at the time we did it, I forget, I used to have it on the blackboard.
I forget how many were over.
There was three between 600 and 700,
one between 700 and 800,
one between 800 and 900,
one between 900 and 1,000 at the time I wrote the book, yes.
Okay. Would it seem reasonable that the one that is over 900 is in Sedona at this time?
I have no idea.
Pardon me?
Yeah.
Doctor, you've spoken many times about males having war to be able to transcend up to the 200 level.
What did I say?
Males having to go to war in order to transcend.
Oh, to transcend.
200.
They don't have to, but it is a very common way.
In which many a man, you bite the bullet, man, you conquer fear right then and there.
You say, for God, for country, for the queen.
And you walk right into it.
Bam.
You never have to cross that line again.
Women do in childbirth more often, I think.
Traditionally, at least.
Believing that we're going to have war with terrorism, with the Al-Qaeda,
with the more radical elements of Islam for possibly generations,
and that we have hundreds of thousands of young men and young women who are in the military,
and who are defending us in Afghanistan and Iraq right now,
and wherever the battlefield will be in generations.
What are the karmic implications for the soldier of killing?
Everything subserves a karmic purpose.
Intention is what it's about.
Okay, intention.
There is a level at which you surrender the personal will for a greater good.
See?
War is hard to explain.
You've got to really be pretty sophisticated to understand war.
First of all, it's a karmic unfoldment of mankind in general.
I think, as we've mentioned, 93% of human history there's been war.
93% of the time.
Therefore, peace is an abnormal condition.
Everybody's too apathetic to fight, huh?
Malnutrition reigns instead.
7% of the time.
It's as though that's the only way certain things can be expressed.
Because the emergence of the ego, as you saw on the first slide,
is out of the animal kingdom.
Out of the animal kingdom, through the left brain in the human then,
arises contention.
If you don't have enough aggression to get what you need to survive,
you don't live long enough to become a warrior.
You've got to have been pretty successful.
And have been pretty successful for a couple million years to even survive.
So, first comes survival.
Then comes transcending survival of the physicalness of the animal, the left brain.
And at level 200, transcending into a new dominion of the province of spiritual reality.
To do that, war is almost inevitable.
War is almost inevitable.
Have you ever seen any, you know,
animals not fighting each other?
No, because territory is territory.
Territory is territory.
Whole continents are warring tribes, warring tribes.
They're still warring.
The other side of the world, they're still warring.
It's like they're stuck back where we were not long ago.
They're still warring.
Who's going to have dominion over the turf?
These are all turf wars, aren't they?
Turf wars.
The left side of the brain sees turf.
And it fights over turf.
So, when you say intent is a major part of the karmic potential for the soldier killing,
I have acquaintances who are soldiers, are police officers, who have killed.
Some have no hatred for the enemy.
Others have intense hatred for the enemy.
Yeah.
So each one is different then, isn't it?
Oh.
Yeah.
In World War II, we didn't hate them.
The kamikazes came over, and you get strafed.
I mean, you know, or you get blown up by a mine.
I was on a minesweeper.
So sudden death was there all the time.
Sudden death, sudden death was there.
And you learned to live with sudden death, learned to live with it.
So if you go up in pieces, you go up in pieces, you know?
Yeah.
So, a soldier who has an intent, who has no hatred,
but gets the bloodlust up in the middle of battle.
They're going to be working through different archetypes within yourself.
Different chakras and different archetypes.
There comes the time when you reach the level of valor.
Certainly the police and the firemen in 9-11 in New York City showed us what valor looks like.
Climbing a ladder in jeopardy of your own death and many, many hundreds of them dying, you know?
They did so and sacrificed their personal self to integrity, duty, and your fellow man, you know?
They fulfilled a very great karmic propensity.
Thank you, doctor.
Traditionally, the warriors, you know, dance around and get themselves into an agitated hate-the-enemy state.
But a very successful warrior doesn't need that at all.
You don't have to hate the enemy.
Your duty is to sink that submarine, and that's what you do.
You don't hate them.
You feel sorry for them.
Thank you, Susan.
It's a lousy way to go on a submarine.
It really is.
We used to drop depth charges, I'll tell you.
Man, Christ.
What a way to go, you know?
Alice Bailey spoke on glamour.
What's the title, the complete title?
Briefly, what is it about?
What is she asking?
Alice Bailey's book, Glamour.
Yeah.
I've never read it, I don't know what it is.
What about it?
I would like to read it.
That is the title.
Oh, that is the title?
Oh, okay.
Yes.
That's my question.
Glamour.
It means that you project a specialness.
You desire a thing, not because it's desirable, but because you project a desirability on it.
Now it has like a magical allure and an aura.
Okay.
Television specializes in it.
Madison Avenue.
Specializes in it.
That specialness, the allure, the glamour.
Glamour is like, okay.
Okay, thank you very much.
Yeah.
Okay.
The specialness.
The Course in Miracles addresses that specialness, too.
Stay well.
Yeah.
We project specialness onto others and crave it because of the specialness that we put
onto it in the first place.
Yeah.
We're going to make it, and I don't want to hear any more about it.
Thank you.
Yeah, right.
Say thank you.
Thank you.
Yeah.
That's very nice being here.
Yes.
And I was wondering after you've serving to God, is it okay You surrendered to God,
was it okay in Christ Jesus being me?
may the mind that was in Christ Jesus be in me.
Yeah, that's okay to say what, in Jesus Christ what?
May the mind that was in Christ Jesus be in me.
Yes.
That's perfect.
So what would the writing be?
Would that be a thousand?
Asking Christ Jesus.
Oh, he wants to know what that would calibrate as.
Oh, asking Christ Jesus to be your Savior or to come into you?
Right.
Oh, that's about the top of the scale.
There's much more you can ask.
No, I am that I am.
That statement, would that be about the same?
What does he say, I am that I am?
I am that I am?
Who do you say you are?
I am what I am.
If you asked who...
Yes, well, it depends on what you mean by that.
That's in the Bible, too.
Yes, but I think asking Christ...
The realization that...
Christ is the perfect manifestation, the fulfillment of being.
That which is the source of his own creation.
That would be higher.
Good.
Very nice.
See you again.
As it says in the Bhagavad Gita,
that Krishna says,
all who consider me as divinity are dear to me,
by whatever name they call me.
The 91st Psalm says the same thing.
Those who put their life in my hands are mine.
Yes.
I'm curious to know what...
If...
Are there any other animals on the planet
that have access to salvation?
I don't know of any.
We calibrated all the levels of all the animal kingdom, yes?
You see that they eventually arrive at 200.
Therefore, 200 is the beginning of spiritual reality.
So my personal way of seeing it
is that they are evolving to the level of humanness eventually.
Okay, so they may not be able to reach salvation in this lifetime,
but they could be reborn and reach salvation.
That's conjecture.
I don't know.
We'd have to research it.
I'd have to take a little time to research it.
Okay.
Can you go directly from being a cow to the celestial realm?
I sort of doubt it.
Well...
From 200 up, you would say.
Now the animal is in an evolution.
The animal is in an evolutionary sequence
that eventually is going to end up as humanness.
Yeah.
Okay.
The chart that you get that's given in Truth vs. Falsehood with the animals,
that's the current consciousness level of the group calibration of animals.
The group of the species, yes.
But like a human being can reach the level of 1000.
Could animals, their bodies, could they reach higher levels?
Like, could they hold the consciousness level?
No.
No?
The species, we do the species.
And the species is characteristic of that level.
Then when your consciousness moves higher, you evolve into a higher species, you know?
That's the purpose.
That's what I quoted from the Rig Veda, that you evolve from below on up,
and you become your potential.
Your potential, huh?
Okay.
Do you remember being an animal?
Not very clearly.
No, huh?
Well, if you keep at it, you'll find out.
Well, it's...
I had permission to mention my memory was this.
I had permission to mention that memory was this.
You won't believe it anyway, so.
Okay.
Yes.
In other words, I think that we evolve through the entire cycle.
I think that we evolve through the entire cycle.
Yes.
Mm-hmm.
Right.
I think you can find that in your spectrum.
Yes.
Because our source is divinity, and divinity is all that it is.
It's not exclusionary so why couldn't I just be a tiger at one time and a buffalo at another
time?
Why can't I emerge in humanness at the lowest level of a captured slave?
Because I was there.
I had to transcend that of a captured slave and become eventually a captain of a ship.
So you evolve.
It's hard to see.
see evolution is simple isn't it? Well you're making it complicated. You're trying to make it
specific instead of seeing it as a... Yeah. Gracias.
I'm wondering, do you believe in synchronicity events? Synchronicity seems to be a verifiable
reality, yeah. So it is a truthful statement that it does exist? Yeah. Carl Jung first wrote about it.
Okay, okay. Have you heard of bio-residence or bio-feedback? Well, I got it.
Yeah, speak into the mic because no one can hear you. Yeah, let me make sure I'm getting it right
because I'm getting senile. I don't feedback, I know about it. Oh yeah.
Yeah. Bio-residence.
Do you, have you heard of the concept of bio-residence? No. It's a machine that creates
cycles that's... No. No, you have not. There's a lot of those machines out there. Right, right, but you're
unfamiliar with bio-residence. Okay, do you believe in attacking the condition of bipolar
that vitamins therapy might be... Attacking the position? No, I don't
believe in attacking any position. No, no, no attacking the condition... The condition.
... of bipolar illness? Yes, it's a condition, yes. What is that? Do you believe vitamin therapy is a viable
process by which you can reduce the condition of bipolar? I didn't work with
it in the realm of bipolar, I worked it in the realm of schizophrenia. Okay, so
there's the, in your mind there is a difference. Well, bipolar,
I think it's a different chemistry. Yes, bipolar is a different chemistry than schizophrenia, yes.
Okay, so you couldn't really take a position on treating bipolar in terms of vitamin therapy.
No.
Do you think Linus Pauling might have a position? He's dead, I know, I know.
Do you think he would have a position, his position would be different than yours?
I don't know. We didn't look at bipolar.
Okay, okay, well thank you very much.
Bipolar, you know, schizophrenia, bipolar response to like, you know, like lithium or something like that.
Hi doctor.
Yeah.
There seems to be a conflict between remaining in the world versus surrendering the world to God.
There's not a conflict.
I mean, sometimes is it more effective to remain in the world and then just radiate spiritual energy out?
You don't have any say over it.
But...
Let's say if I surrender, sometimes my mind will ask, if I surrender, then will I disappear and become non-available to other people?
Don't worry about other people, let God worry about other people.
Surrender the world to God, including your own existence.
So that is the...
You get permissions to leave, and you'll either leave or not leave.
If you leave, it's fantastic, and if you don't leave, it's fantastic.
What's the difference?
Your karmic destiny may...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You don't care whether you are to stay or not to stay.
It has nothing to do with what you want.
It's your karmic destiny.
Whether you're here to enlighten other people or whether you go, if that's your karmic destiny, you're not going to have any say over it.
With complete surrender, you don't know what's going to happen.
You may walk on, you may not.
So the error is the mind presumes that it knows the way to help other people?
Yeah.
So that's the block to be surrendered?
The mind doesn't know which is better, you know.
Sometimes it serves people best to leave.
So it's on your karmic destiny as to which path you follow.
You get to heaven, they say, I see you did the world a favor, right?
Your karma, as a person, will take over, and you will know when it's right or wrong.
If you love the world, leave it, yeah.
So...
Sorry.
Oh, yeah.
I understand in my individual sense.
And then would like the right white brotherhood be not legitimate to kind of postpone their own evolution and then remain...
It's not up to us to say what's legitimate.
One has freedom of choice.
Right.
You got something better to do?
Like what?
Okay, that's enough.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Ever since I met you, my life keeps getting worse.
Oh, that's good.
Good sign.
That's good.
Speeding up karma, huh?
I guess.
Yeah.
Since my last update, I had emergency surgery, I almost died, lost a good friend, and I lost
my job.
Yeah.
Other than that, things are good.
You're moving along.
But I want to get as much as I can out of, I want to learn something from it.
And here is specifically my question.
I'm not that kind of person.
I don't do anything.
Okay.
Recently I was accused of sabotage and conspiracy in this company that I was in.
You said that whatever you affirm in yourself evokes its opposite.
So like I affirmed lovingness in myself about a year ago, and that's when everything fell
apart.
And so I'm wondering, do I ever see anything purely, or is everything I see a projection
of myself?
That is to say-
Everything you see is a projection.
Everything.
Yeah.
So if someone is accusing me of conspiracy and sabotage, is that something that's actually
in me that's being-
I don't know.
It's something you yourself could have done in the past, see?
I would pray for forgiveness for the one in me who's falsely accused others.
You see, now you're talking about one of the commandments.
To bear false witness.
It's very unlikely that any of us got this far in evolution without having borne false
witness in the past.
No question.
Very unlikely.
Right.
And therefore, I would say, oh Lord, I pray for forgiveness for the one in me who may
have borne false witness against others, and I ask for their forgiveness.
Forgive me, brother, for I was only seeking self-gain.
Whatever happens, do you presume that that was yourself in the past?
And pray for forgiveness as though you were currently guilty of it.
As I say, if everybody, you know, is cheating you, I say, you know, pray for the one in
you who's cheated others in the past, because this is karma coming back, you know, see?
So it's not necessarily a current condition, but it's a reflection of something.
No, you're obviously, because of your spiritual intention, pulling up all this negative karma.
That's what you're doing.
You're exhilarating it.
And just keep forgiving it as it arises, and give thanks to the Lord that you have forgiven.
That you have a chance to undo all this negative karma, because nothing happens by chance.
So therefore, it's coming up for reasons.
When you get involved in spiritual work, you can exhilarate the stack coming up.
Those of you who have done this know about the stacks.
And sometimes they're, you know, a big stack, big stack.
Loss, gain, false witness.
The reason the commandments are commandments is because they are the most common ailments
of mankind.
Aren't they?
The lie, the stupid, the very false witness.
Absolutely.
You're going to do that in politics all day long.
Get up there and absolutely lie right through their teeth.
Lie right through their teeth.
You say, God Almighty, the moxie, where do they get the moxie to do that?
I don't know.
Because the video from yesterday shows you saying what you just denied saying, you know
what I'm saying?
So that takes some balls, you know what I'm saying?
The Mexican word for that is more acceptable.
Yes, it is.
What do they call a Mexican?
What's it called?
Cajones.
Yeah, yeah, right.
All right.
So you're uncorking a lot of karma.
Just go through it with grace.
Yeah.
Pray for grace.
Right.
Forgiveness, grace.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
You're undoing a whole stack.
Undoing a whole stack.
Sometimes it comes up in big stacks like that.
I have a thousand questions, but neither one answer is going to help me.
I don't think I...
It's all curiosity.
I don't know.
Can I ask a favor?
Can I ask a favor instead?
It's a rhetorical question, or are you asking a question?
I don't know.
Yeah.
I ask you a question.
Can I ask a favor?
Go ahead.
I have spent a lot of time and money trying to grow, and I feel stuck.
My mind go like a thousand miles a second.
I can't concentrate.
Yeah.
Could I get a little jump by osmosis?
Could you get what?
She gets it.
Can she get a jump by osmosis?
Yes, you can.
You hang out with spiritual groups where peace, equanimity, easy does it, live and let live
are the rule, and you absorb the energy, but you get it by osmosis.
There are groups that say, bring the body, you get it by osmosis.
Before you know it, you have identified with the field, and your own consciousness is now
dominated by the field.
Pick a spiritual group that calibrates over 500 and hang out with them.
All right.
In the right place, then.
Yeah.
You hang out with a field that's over 500, and their way of being, their attitude, see,
because who we are expresses itself in multiple ways, not just verbiage, see, words.
Words are cheap.
How you are with everything that exists with your eye lingers over beauty or does not linger
over beauty.
You understand what I'm saying?
In a thousand subtle ways, you're demonstrating that which you are.
You'll go through a point where the beauty of a thing absolutely paralyzes you.
You can't look at it because you can't function.
After that, you learn to live with the beauty because you see the essence, the incredible
perfection of all things shine forth, and you see that all is divinity in its expression,
however it is expressed.
So you hang out with groups that hold to high spiritual values.
Hold to high spiritual standards.
A lot of people in their spiritual pathway visit everybody.
They go to this church.
They go to that church.
They go to a bar mitzvah.
They go to whatever spiritual group.
There was a time in my life when I went to a different spiritual group every night.
All different ones.
New age, old age, Mexican, Christian, it didn't matter.
I even said I put on a yarmulke.
I had the white thing and I did the Passover service.
So there's a period of investigation and the feeling out what's common to all of spiritual
integrity.
There's a commonality no matter what they call themselves, Jewish or Christian or Islamic
or whatever.
There's a commonality.
Will you turn over the beetle or not?
I'm moving to Sedona to be here.
Yes.
So I guess I am the right.
Already found it.
Yes.
If you're looking for a place of high spiritual intention, this is a place of high spiritual
intention.
It is.
Thank you.
Even Sedona Tyren Auto.
Sedona Tyren Auto.
They do the Buddhist meditations there.
Yeah.
That's about as spiritual as you can get I guess.
Thank you both for your love.
Thank you.
Yes.
Great.
Moving on to another point.
Okay.
Last question.
You've talked about the experiential awareness of the unfolding of the divinity as the void
is transcended.
Does that differ in any sense from the experiential awareness of divinity at, for example, the
six hundreds or seven hundreds before we would transcend the void?
Yes, each one is different.
And then that book Transcend the Levels as I G Nazar Golden.
I think I go into each level.
In the book that's forthcoming after this one, called Devotional Non-duality, I treat
them rather extensively, how to transcend the void and how to avoid the trap of the
void.
So your subjective experiential awareness of divinity at 860 is different to the awareness
of divinity at 600?
Yes.
They're all fantastic.
860 ain't better than 600, it's just different.
Thank you.
Like a hippopotamus ain't better than an elephant, it's just different.
Sure.
Yeah.
Hippopotamus and elephant are both just profound.
They're different.
Yeah.
Thank you, Robert.
Yes?
Okay.
We're at the end.
Is that it?
One more?
Yes, come on, hurry up.
Hustle-y bustle-y, hustle-y bustle-y.
We can only go to a quarter hour.
Honey.
I already know that.
Thank you for taking me there.
You promised me you were not going to say anything.
The question is about karma?
Yes.
How do you know that there is karma?
How do you know if there's karma?
You're here, aren't you?
How did you get here?
I was born.
That's right.
That's a karmic inheritance.
To become a human being, you got born.
I am really asking a question about this one thing to have an idea about karma and to see
it in a mental way and how it all fits, but how do you know?
You don't know until you become more advanced in your consciousness and then it becomes
stunningly apparent.
It's obvious.
Stunningly.
And is there something in developing consciousness that does that for you?
The awareness increases and then it becomes obvious that there isn't such thing as an
isolated slice of all of time.
There is no isolated slice of all of time.
Everything is a slice of a continuity, is it not?
Could this exist all by itself, no past, no future?
No.
So it becomes obvious, stunningly obvious, that everything is evolutionary.
You see the wrinkles?
What does that mean?
That I was just born?
You've been here a long time.
Thank you.
So evolutionary.
A long time.
A time.
You just have to say a long time.
Anyway.
Thank you.
Even within one human existence, you see the evolution of the child becoming the girl,
becoming the adolescent, and then eventually the old lady.
So right now, for me, it's just a matter of faith that that will occur to me.
Oh, you don't have to believe it.
Not necessary.
Not necessary to believe it.
If you live it as though it's true, you'll come out way ahead rather than living it
that it's not true.
Why?
Because everyone is accountable.
You see, the field of consciousness is infinite.
Anything that's ever happened anywhere in time or time or space is recorded forever.
Recorded forever.
The questions that you're asking me now have already gotten recorded in consciousness forever.
10,000 years from now, we could ask, did such and such a thing occur on this stage in this
place?
And you'll get an answer.
It's recorded now forever.
You understand?
So you're accumulating a record forever.
If that don't do for karma, I don't know what will.
Well, thank you.
Thank you for letting me come.
I appreciate it.
Thank you.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
That's it.
Hmm.
For their support.
Yeah.
Come on.
Do something.
Please do something.
You know.
Yes?
I would just like to thank everyone for your support.
Some of you may not know.
Some of you have made some very generous donations to us and have made it possible
for us to offer classes free to the public.
And we want to thank you from the bottom of our heart.
This is something the doctor and I have been trying to accomplish for about three years
now to where we can give free classes.
And due to your generosity, it has been possible.
And I want to thank all of you for supporting the work.
Yeah.
Thank you.
As a living prayer, which collectively has become a living prayer, it is influencing
all of mankind at the fact.
Resist.
It is saying to me, what can I do to be that which you can karmically fulfill?
See?
And in that way, you're profoundly influencing.
What can you do for people in the flood?
Be the most loving human being you can be right here.
You're already raising the level for everyone, see?
Compassion then arises out of our compassion.
So we radiate forth into the world a powerful energy.
A collective such as this has a very powerful effect on the world and worldly events.
So we pray for the things that we think will bring about peace.
I myself am saying a prayer of thankfulness.
For the king of Saudi Arabia, yes?
Abdullah, yes?
Who now is the centerpiece for the entire Islamic world to try and resolve the source of all the violence in the world.
That's certainly, I pray for him.
Fulfillment of his desire to fulfill the potential of Islam.
Which essentially is a religion of peace.
Religion of peace.
And therefore, like we said, whatever is integrous seems to pull up its opposite to try to seize control of it.
Christianity went through that phase as long as it's currently going through that phase.
Whatever is pristine, just like the pieta, tends to bring forth, you know.
Therefore, if we hold in mind, if we hold in mind, what we hold in mind tends to manifest.
We hold in mind the peaceful coexistence.
Peaceful coexistence.
And by holding it in mind, then it manifests as the king of Saudi Arabia using his linear domain to bring it about as an actuality.
So, all together then we have a profound effect.
So I give thanks and I conclude as I began.
Glory and exultius, Dio.
Glory to God in the highest.
And I give thanks, O Lord, for all of you.
It is my prayer coming true.
And you are God's gift to me.
For which I give thanks.
Amen.
All right, look at that thing.
Oh, isn't that fun?
Thank you.