I was looking for some advice in dealing with the lunatic fringe.
I moderate the David R. Hawkins fan group,
and there's quite a lunatic fringe out there.
It makes me question what good, if any, the group serves sometimes
because they're just out there in force right now,
which I'm sure you know.
And sometimes I get the same emails.
But, I mean, how do you deal with that?
Sometimes it's like, do I help them?
You have to do it with intention.
What is the intention behind the comment?
What is the intention of the question?
What is the intentionality of the positionality?
What is served by that, you see?
It's obvious.
What we're presenting is the consequence of 50 years of psychiatry,
psychoanalysis, psychology, psychotherapy, individual and group.
It is.
As well as my own personal psychoanalysis,
as well as transformative spiritual experiences,
as well as 25 years in consciousness research.
So it's a really formidable body of work.
And somebody will pick out some trivial things.
Exactly.
That's what's frustrating about it.
And the problem is not being able to tell the forest from the trees.
Exactly.
And it isn't the trees, it's the forest that impact.
It's the impact of the work all together.
Yeah, yeah.
So some of them are quite against the grain to where sometimes they feel
like maybe I should just kick them out of the group.
Well, they have the same, but most, what I've been doing is I just ignore them
and then they leave on their own.
Or they get abusive, you know.
Yeah, exactly.
When they get abusive, you say, what's the point of being abusive, you see?
Exactly.
Because it's not a psychotherapy group.
So, you know, you've got all kinds of un-
It's a psycho group.
You know, I sometimes advise psychotherapy.
Frankly, your question really requires psychotherapy.
It's not really an answer having anything to do with the work, you see what I'm saying?
It's irrelevant.
You know, like this guy, what does he think he's going to get to God, whether it depends
on whales or dolphins?
I mean, you know, it's got nothing to do with the thrust of the work.
Exactly.
You know what I mean?
What's it got to do with realizing the presence of God within as the self of the capitalist,
you see?
So, what you're dealing with is the ego, and the ego is impersonal.
And don't forget, this work is the direct antithesis of the ego.
So, what you're getting-
It's too true.
The work threatens the narcissistic core of the ego.
That's the basis of all what you're dealing with.
Within itself, the ego considers itself sovereign.
All right?
So, any kind of spiritual work is going to trigger hatred from the narcissistic ego,
who says it is God.
That's why the secular hates divinity, because it contradicts the ego's positionality that
it is the source of your life.
It is the creator.
All right.
The malignant narcissistic mania, see?
As you see it, like, what's his name coming up for trial now?
It's Adam.
Yeah.
So, you see, there you're going to see the narcissistic ego laid bare.
What you're dealing with is minor expressions, but it's coming from the same motivation.
So, any time we get a negative email, we'll ask what political position this person has.
They all come from the same political position.
So, what you've said antagonizes their view that narcissism should be the law of the land.
See?
So, when dealing with that-
Yeah.
I mean, is it more of a go on a case-by-case basis, what I feel the intention might be,
or is it just be more strict on the guidelines?
Well, we have this-
My purpose is I want the groups to serve the highest good.
That's where you go.
And we have the same discussion sometimes, you see.
How is, what's the best way to answer this, you know?
Yeah.
And see that the person, you know, is the victim of their own ignorance, you see.
First of all, they will make negative comments.
And they haven't even read the book.
Okay.
Let's get-
The percentage of people who have been vociferously antagonistic to the book,
more than 2% have read the book.
None of them have read the book.
No.
They open to Chapter 9, they look up what their favorite positionality is,
find you don't agree with it, then they write you a nasty letter.
They didn't even read the book yet.
And you can tell by their commentary that they have no familiarity with the whole subject
about which they're commenting.
Well, here's another minor question.
Being that the name of the group is the Fan Group, and fan is short for fanatic,
is that a good name?
Maybe I should change it to the Hawkins Enthusiast Group or something.
I think just discussion, you know, is fine.
Yeah, that works too.
I think the work should be discussed, see.
Because in the discussion, you see the air compelling.
Now, the intentionality behind it is what reveals.
So what sounds like an ignorance can actually,
to be a legitimate request for information.
Yeah.
There's some of that, but it's very...
There's really some serious people out there.
Yeah.
Actually, too.
All right.
All right, well, that works for me.
I love you, man.
I know what you mean, because we get some funny ones.
Thank you, too.
And some of them are so far out, we have what we call a Noodleheimer file.
I could probably add some names to that list for you.
Yeah.
We do have, and that's actually what it's called.
It's called the Noodleheimer file.
And those are from, you know, far out in left field.
Yeah.
I don't even know if they're on the ballpark, but...
I was counting them.
Well, we see 50% of the people are below 200, see.
Now, the way I tried to screen them out in the first place
was I put in the beginning and the end of all my books,
Gloria in excelsis Deo.
In fact, that doesn't fry out an atheist.
Then, he's got what's coming to him if he turns the next page.
Yeah.
Couldn't have said it better myself.
You could remind people of that.
What is the first salutation in the books?
Straight and narrow is the path, you know?
And Gloria in excelsis Deo.
So, why did you read any further?
Yeah.
Thank you.
This is the first German book.
Yeah.
Honey, don't know what you like.
Just leave it.
Just this one.
It's too hard to read.
That's the German.
Yeah.
Let's see.
It says,
Das alle Sehende Auge.
Oh, the all-seeing eye.
Das all Sehende.
That's C.
S-E-H-E is C.
And Auge is A-U-G-E is I.
It's the all-seeing eye when translated into German
instead of the eye of the eye.
That's very nice.
Dr. Kallenbach arranged that translation.
Supervised.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
Thank you so much.
Thank both you and Susan so much for all your work.
I have a question from a friend.
And he's a religious science minister.
Jack Blackman from Albuquerque, New Mexico.
Religious science, yes.
Yes.
And he asked me to ask this question for him.
He says that every day he prays
to surrender his body,
his mind,
his spirit,
his will,
his ego,
his everything to God.
Yes.
And he says that after a while,
he started wondering,
since everything is God,
what is he surrendering?
Illusion.
He's surrendering his illusions.
Well, that was his question.
Now, you know, for instance,
he's surrendering his personal self.
Well, inasmuch as there is no such thing as a personal self,
I see what his paradox is.
But so long as he thinks that it's there.
Also, God really doesn't need verbalization.
That is a fact.
God gets intention without verbalization.
He's putting it in a linear.
Therefore, I advise to live one's life as a mudra.
In other words, when you get up in the morning,
you picture yourself this way, the divinity,
and divinity just got it.
He could try it non-verbally as a way of being instead of verbally.
Instead of using prayer.
In which you yourself become a supplication,
without verbalizing it.
Okay.
Thank you very much for answering his question.
Non-verbal. Supplication.
Let's say the kitty comes up to me and goes,
what can you do?
What can you do?
It's time to be a big kitty and just purr up.
I'm going to go to the storm and golly room.
That's wonderful. Thank you so much.
I'm sure he'll appreciate everything you've said.
Non-verbal.
Just to be that way.
Thank you so much.
Yeah, I like religious answers.
We've spoken a lot at our churches, too.
Yes.
You kind of answered my question, sort of, with hers.
And that was, how do we go about praying for each other?
And where do we go about praying for each other?
Where do we stop?
How do you pray for each other?
Well, for others.
How do we, how, in, in.
Yeah, like what?
How would you pray for them?
For their highest and best good.
What is in their highest and best good?
Say, when you pray for your children, for instance.
All right.
So, I tend to non-verbalize it, see?
And more to hold it, to hold it forth.
Okay.
And that which you hold in mind tends to materialize.
It tends to come in.
It's not a manifestation.
Okay.
So, if I picture the person as well, because, you know, a lot of times people are brought
around for healing.
Right.
And I merely picture them as well.
Now, the rest is a karmic propensity.
It's not up to that which I, you know, to the personal self.
So, it isn't like an I wants to make a them better.
That's a dualistic positionality.
That which I am sees them in their fullest.
And sometimes it happens.
Sometimes it doesn't, because it's also a karmic propensity, you know?
Mm-hmm.
And then, where do you stop?
I mean, not, I mean...
Having done it once, it's sufficient.
Okay.
Thank you.
However, you can remind God once in a while, you know?
And Nellie's arthritis.
You haven't forgotten it, God.
First of all, I'd like to say thank you, and I love you.
And I'm grateful for all of your teachings.
Thank you.
I love teaching, and the sharing.
Also, I'm on task, from the Maui Group, to invite you once again to Maui to visit us.
I'm sure Wayne Dyer would love to have you stay with him.
Where is that?
Where is Maui?
Maui.
Oh, Maui!
I thought you were playing you were a kitty.
Maui.
My question is, recently I was reading Ramesh Bhalsakar in Consciousness Speaks, and he
stated that there is no individualized soul, and that the concept of a soul accumulating
negative or positive karma was bullshit, those were his words.
And upon reading that, I put all my books away, I could no longer read anymore, and
kind of went through a bit of a hell for a few days, and that's real different than
what you teach.
Yes.
So could you clarify that?
I mean, I've kind of come to a recontextualization on my own, but could you clarify what he means
by that?
No.
That there's no individualized soul?
This is a subtle question.
We notice that at the moment of birth, people calibrate differently.
Hmm?
How does that come about?
Well, my understanding through my recontextualization is that consciousness is expressing through
that what he calls, Bhalsakar calls, the body-mind organism.
You just said there's no karma.
How about the body-mind organism, where'd that come from?
It didn't pre-exist, this life.
What do you mean?
The body-mind organism comes out of creation, comes out of consciousness.
Everything is consciousness.
That's what he states.
All right.
So then, it's an accidental universe.
No, it's not accidental.
Random.
No.
It's kind of random.
It's not random.
There is divine harmony and concordance, therefore.
It's like the Buddhic idea of karma being a circle.
You could be reborn a rabbit or a chicken or something, see?
So therefore, there would be no karmic responsibility.
Hmm.
There's no karmic responsibility.
There's no point to the teachings of Jesus Christ or the Buddha.
So I don't agree with what he said.
Okay.
Can I tell you my recontextualization?
Yeah.
Sure.
Because it was really devastating for me to read that.
I kind of went through this thing of almost becoming an atheist again, because it seemed
like that kind of put it back to you're just being used by God.
That's nihilistic.
Yeah.
That's a nihilistic notion.
But when I recontextualize it in that, the field of consciousness expresses through us.
And so because that there is all of us, all of that that can be expressed through us,
which is like that's why we have all of the different things on the scale, on the map
of consciousness that we can experience.
Yeah, like the collective consciousness of man.
Yeah.
And so through karmic merit, like in the next life or this life, you experience a more
positive life through that.
Karmic merit is individual.
So I shouldn't read Bhalsakar anymore?
It contradicts every spiritual teaching I'm aware of.
No, because I focused on your works very seriously for the last year.
It contradicts every spiritual teaching I've ever experienced.
I've read or studied or discovered through research.
Yeah, well it didn't make sense to me either, and that's why I came here.
Why didn't the Buddha teach what he taught, you see?
To avoid reincarnation.
Right.
So who is it that's avoiding reincarnation then?
The individual soul, isn't it?
But if everything is God and everything is consciousness and we all go back to oneness...
That's a random intellectualization, you see?
It's confusing the real with the hypothetical.
That's hypothetical.
That's not the real.
Okay.
Because when you're born, you're born with a calibrated level of consciousness.
Right.
And you weren't born in Las Vegas on a green table.
No.
No, I wasn't.
No, I'll take the words of Jesus Christ and the Buddha over Ramesh.
I spent some days with him, and at that time he was in a pretty good state.
Yeah.
Well, it served me in that it helped break through a lot of ego and victimhood stuff
that I worked out.
Thank you.
Please come to my meeting.
We go through all those phases.
Thank you, sir.
That's really nihilistic.
I don't know if he's still living or...
Hello.
First of all, I want to sincerely thank you for sharing with us and being here.
I truly appreciate it.
It's certainly changed my life.
Mm-hmm.
The question I have is, you speak of natural, spontaneous, spiritual phenomenon happening
as you're on that path to enlightenment.
Good.
And as you speak of it, I have a very deep, profound understanding of it, although I can
honestly say I don't think I've ever experienced that.
And my question is, can you intuitively share that experience with a wise, mystic teacher,
Avatar, without actually going through it yourself to still be on that path?
Or is it necessary?
Share what?
In other words, for instance, like you even talk about kundalini energy.
I'm not sure I know what that is.
Is it necessary to experience that, to be on the path?
Or can one intuitively share that experience?
The kundalini energy automatically begins to flow at consciousness level 200.
Out of it creates the etheric body, the etheric brain.
Prior to consciousness level 200, people have a group karma.
So, I didn't finish answering what she said, but below 200, what we get is you have group
karma.
All right.
So, below 200, if you calibrate at 140, you share the karmic consequences of that group.
Animals have a group karma.
It's only over 200 that you have an individual karmic destiny.
What I said was the truth.
So, the sheep inherit sheepness.
Yes.
And they are all sheepnesses together.
But over 200, now you're personally accountable.
You're personally accountable.
Everything has a karmic consequence.
Yeah?
So, now you have individual responsibility, not just group.
So, the human has both individual and group karmic propensities.
That which has been earned, that which is still due.
So, you're saying that,
you know, you have the ability to progress, for lack of a better word, and I know that's
not probably the correct word, but you will naturally have those phenomenon?
Yes.
The emergence is at level 200.
You don't really experience it as the so-called cities until maybe 550.
I don't know.
They start flowing around 550.
No.
They start flowing over 500.
Yeah.
As you get into the 500s, you begin to feel this exquisite energy.
And will you always recognize that?
Yes.
Oh, yeah.
Sorry.
It beats orgasms all of a sudden.
I'm not going to debate it.
Oh, thank you.
Plus, it's continuous, continuous, continuous.
Yes?
Dr. Hawkins, did the level of karmic karmic propensities,
did the level of consciousness of the world rise after the World Day of Prayer this last
September the 8th?
It rose the last time we were in San Francisco.
What, November 2003?
I forget.
Yes, 2003.
There was the Harmonic Concordance at that time, World Day of Prayer.
And it went up two points, right?
But, you know, 515, it was 205.
And at 530, it was 207.
It was amazing.
Oh, the Unity Day of Prayer?
On the 8th of September.
Oh, I don't know.
I doubt the One Day of Prayer.
The consciousness level of mankind, we have permission to ask that, is still at 207.
It's at 208.
It's still at 207.
We just dropped something.
No, that's all right.
Thank you.
Thanks.
You see, you can't look at it as cause and effect in a mathematical, like arithmetic.
It's more like...
Snow piles up, and then when the temperature and humidity and all is right, the avalanche occurs.
But today didn't cause the avalanche.
So the collective positive karma of mankind, you might say, when large groups pray, you're building it up.
And then it breaks forth at the propitious time.
I don't think it's immeasurable, you know, from day to day in sort of a mathematical kind of a way.
Thank you.
You might say you get like a collective merit, and eventually the momentum of it brings it across the line.
Hello?
Yeah.
I want to see a picture.
Sure.
What's happening?
We're taking pictures.
Oh, pictures, pictures.
You know how to work those machines.
The kind I get in Walgreens, my cameras, I get them in Walgreens, use them up, and throw them away.
That looks good, yeah.
Yeah.
Ready?
Thank you so much for your teachings.
I was last here in April, and started to come back.
I have a question.
Can one person steal or draw energy from another person?
People below 200 drain energy.
People above 200 give energy.
So if you spend time with people below 200, they would drain your energy if you're above 200?
Yes, unless you have some particular – see, when I was a psychiatrist and I was dealing with it, practically everybody was below 200.
But I was protected by – let's see.
I was protected by the role – oh, I was protected by the energy field of the role, R-O-L-E.
Yeah, I was protected by the energy field of the role.
Now, if instead of treating them in the office, I was partying with them someplace, I probably would have had my energy drained by it.
So it's wise to stay away from people with low energy?
Is that true?
Let's see how to ask that correctly.
It depends on the field you're interfering with.
Well, let's –
The capacity.
Let's see.
In general, you see, the basic teaching is to stay with holy people.
Hang out with holy people.
And avoid those which are negative.
And that teaching is correct.
We get fleas that lie down with dogs, eh?
So the basic teaching is to hang out with holy people.
And to say goodbye to those that are less than 200.
You do what you can for them, and then you send them out of your way, huh?
Very good, thank you.
Yes, because the energy drain gets to be endless.
First they borrow the money.
Then they don't pay the money.
Then they borrow your car.
Then they –
Well, they've got your car.
They don't fix your car.
I lent it to a guy one time.
I felt sorry for him.
Watch out.
The minute you feel sorry for somebody, you're being hit.
So I felt sorry for him.
So I lent him my car.
Two months later, I had to get somebody else to drive me over to his house.
The car was in his driveway with the keys in it, the windows open, the rain and all coming in all of a sudden.
And I had to retrieve my own car.
See?
It gets worse and worse.
The next thing I know, he reneged on a note.
The next thing I know, he'd left the country, escaped to Canada.
He probably had so much behind him.
So that's its own answer.
It doesn't get better, huh?
Well, Jesus said not to oppose them but to avoid them is what he said.
Hi.
Okay.
Yes.
What advice would you give to someone approaching the recovery of an ear?
Who is what?
Who is approaching the recovery of an eating disorder.
Yes.
What advice would you give?
Well, the eating disorders, you know, are a complicated treatment program.
And when I was a psychiatrist at a place called Pia's Place, we treated lots of them.
It's a complicated problem and a complicated treatment.
And I was never really enthusiastic about it, frankly.
So do you have, like, a method you would recommend or you just don't know how to do it?
I don't know.
Nothing like that.
But I was never really enthusiastic about it, frankly.
So do you have, like, a method you would recommend or you just don't know?
It's usually a composite of individual therapy, sometimes psychopharmacology and group therapy
all at the same time.
Uh-huh.
Thank you.
In the meantime, as you just prepped a storm, yes.
It was always difficult and complicated.
Not a simple one to one kind of thing.
I come bearing the gift of my two favorite beverages.
So when I discovered that-
And I may share.
Oh, espresso.
Thank you.
My favorite beverage is my brother.
I felt so much better.
Ah, yes.
Thank you.
So thank you for validating that part of me.
Oh, yeah.
Late last summer, or this summer,
as I was reading the book for the first time,
I wrote you an email that went something like this.
Ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch.
Band-Aid.
Like ripping off Band-Aids.
That was a cute one.
She was.
We put it up on the bulletin board.
This is the sound of me reading your book.
Thank you, I think, is I believe how the rest of it went.
It was a cute email.
This morning you mentioned about being enamored,
and I'm still enamored with something,
and I'm hoping you can help me with it.
Because it's not specifically mentioned.
I'm a big fan of the Book of Job.
Book of Job.
I like his story.
Is that in the Old Testament?
Yeah.
I like his story,
because it has a happy ending.
And because it mirrors my experience
of when I began to seek God,
my life fell apart in oh so many ways.
And that continues to be my experience.
Though my reaction to it changes.
So, do I need to let go of that one, too?
My enamoredness of the book?
Well, it isn't the book itself.
What is it about the book that you like?
Is it true?
Is it integrity?
No matter how awful things got,
that in the end, how did Job make out?
Well, he made out really well.
It has a happy ending.
It has a happy ending?
Yeah.
All was restored.
Did I read that correctly?
Yes.
Well, then why worry about it?
Well, does it calibrate high enough to still be included?
Because you didn't mention it, and that made me...
Oh, oh.
It made me nervous.
That it was more fantasy than...
It was really a test of his faith, wasn't it?
Yes.
No matter what happened, Job chose God.
So, that's a very positive thing.
Now, hang on to that one.
Yeah.
Appreciate it.
No matter what happened.
That's one of my favorites, too.
In the pits of hell,
where there isn't even the thought of God,
I pray to God.
Abandon hope, all ye who enter here.
That was the gruesome truth.
I'd like to thank both you, Dr. Hawkins and Susan,
for everything that you've done.
I have a question.
I can't recall you addressing,
and I'm taking this to a great length,
but the period of time between incarnations is...
As individuals, do we wait until there's that...
the best time, best circumstances to be born into?
I'm not an authority on it.
I know that when you leave the body,
like goes to like.
You gravitate to a spiritual realm
that is aligned with...
with what you have become, yeah?
Yes.
Now, from some of them,
my intuitive understanding is
it's optional, resist.
But it's optional.
Hmm?
Okay.
And if you're still attached to things of this world,
you're gonna naturally choose yes.
On the other hand, this world calls...
affords optimal modes of karmic resolution,
restitution for a negative karma.
Right.
So some people might choose it,
because this is my opportunity,
to undo that which I wish I had not done at the time.
Resist.
Yes.
So because of the karmic opportunity here...
Okay, thank you very much.
So to get over the guilt of undoing what I had done to others,
okay?
Mm-hmm.
Because I know at a certain level of consciousness
where I would get these terrible pains all over,
I would calibrate the one in me
who was violently abusive to others,
and I would get yes.
Yes, you were.
Because I experienced violent abuse myself.
And I thought, where did I come from?
I haven't been violently abusive to anybody in this lifetime.
Right.
Yeah.
So it could be in this lifetime we get to undo.
Undo.
So we may choose the karmic option to undo
for the sake of our own spiritual salvation.
Okay.
And if we own up to some of those things,
as you said, you begin to experience those feelings
that you'd never acted on any of those.
So just the realization that you had done those things
in another lifetime...
I think if you see it within your own consciousness,
you can undo it with strictly spiritual.
You can do it with strictly spiritual techniques, resist.
See, there's two things.
There's responsibility and there's answerability.
That's not the correct word.
There's responsibility...
And then there's the degree of guilt in court.
What do they call that word?
Culpability.
Culpability, yes.
So I think we can undo one by spirituality.
And I think the other one you may have to undo.
Okay.
So it has to do with the balance between culpability and responsibility.
So I may innocently kill somebody
and not be really culpable.
But I'm still responsible.
Yeah.
Thank you very much.
So culpability is the degree of knowingness
with which a thing is done, see?
Right.
So...
But still, you owe a lifetime.
Oh, so even if accidentally...
Well, even, you know, you still didn't pay off the note,
even though you went...
You didn't mean to go bankrupt,
but you still owe the money, see?
Oh.
So there's a degree of guilt in courts, say.
You know, the circumstances, the degree of culpability.
So I think choosing reincarnation has to do with that balance
between culpability and responsibility.
So you may not be able to undo a certain thing just with good wishes.
You may have to actually do it, be of service to others, you know?
I'm not an authority on the inner planes.
Thank you very much.
Thank you both again.
I have a question about allness and nothingness.
Mm-hmm.
When I was a young boy,
I realized that I was.
You realized what?
Yeah.
Then I used to wake up at night in a cold sweat,
realizing that maybe I wouldn't be,
and the thought of nothingness...
Right.
...scared the poop out of me.
Your teaching has helped me greatly.
All fear is an illusion.
There is a conservation of life.
But in the back of your new book,
you say now even at a higher level,
there was again that fluctuation between allness and nothingness.
Could you help me with that?
Mm-hmm.
Allness versus nothingness comes up at about 850.
It's the ultimate reality.
It's the error of the void.
The error of the void.
The pathway of negation is to negate the reality of all that is linear.
See?
Wang Po, the aphorisms of Wang Po,
will take you to 850.
But then you're in the void, eh?
Mm-hmm.
The void is extremely impressive.
Very, very impressive.
I mean, very impressive.
Non-linear, eternal, ultimate peace.
But it was lacking the energy of love,
which is overwhelming.
So, early in life, I'd experienced the presence as infinite.
The kind of love which cannot be described beyond all description.
Therefore, the void was sterile in comparison to the presence.
Therefore, I backed out of it.
It wasn't easy.
There was exactly one thought left in the space,
and it took me hours to give that thought energy
and pull myself back out of nothingness, eh?
Wang Po himself, interestingly,
if you follow Wang Po, the pathway of negation,
you'll end up in the void.
Wang Po himself later evolved to like 960.
Wang Po stopped writing at that point.
But then he himself went on later and transcended 850.
And he himself got up to about 960 before he died.
But he didn't write after that.
So everybody thinks that Wang Po,
which we call as the Wang Po, is the ultimate.
No, it's the ultimate to the void,
but the void is not the absolute.
It's a very interesting story
that later after he stopped writing,
he realized the mistake, see?
Now this will be in my aura,
so whenever that occurs, I will know.
The thing about the void is it's infinite,
still, eternal, out of time, out of space.
There is no personal self, you know?
The arhat, A-r-h-a-t, is an adept who reaches 800,
and to them that is the ultimate state.
It is not the ultimate state.
The Buddha himself calibrated a thought,
and he himself calibrated a thousand, see?
So did Jesus Christ.
So 850 is not the ultimate state,
but it's extremely impressive.
I wouldn't fault anybody for not thinking
that is the enlightened state
because it is very, very, very, very profound
and eternal, and eternal, and eternal.
And it's only because of the prior experience
that I realized there was something missing.
The mistake is in seeing love
as an attachment.
And there's a local teacher who was in a good space
until he began to teach that.
Love is an attachment, yeah?
Personal love is an attachment between a me and a you.
It's dualistic.
I've got to have you, baby.
You try and leave me, I'll kill you, etc.
Or I'll kill myself, you know what I'm saying?
You're right.
It's a cleanliness.
So that kind of love, yes, you should release on, see?
But what's the lack of knowledge is that
the presence of divinity is the infinite presence of love.
So if you avoid love as a reality,
you've just avoided one of the major qualities of divinity.
So that teacher later went down
as a result of that mistaken teaching.
Yeah?
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
Refuse anything as the ultimate, be grateful for it,
but demand that that which is love be present, see?
And the presence of God tells you it is the presence of love of God.
The presence of the infinite state is so radiant with love
that it's unmistakable.
There is no question.
Great.
The void is very impressive.
I'm not putting it down.
Very, very impressive.
Went into it in this lifetime back a couple times
going through the path of re-indigation.
It would recur.
This time I knew the difference.
And you've taught us.
Thank you.
That's a very advanced question.
Dr. Hawkins, sometimes there's present this very dark energy.
There's what?
A dark energy.
Yes.
And it feels like it's from without,
just spitting out hatred towards me and life in general.
Is it all the way without
or is it somewhat a projection from within to without?
How does that work?
You experience it in a space
or within your aura or?
It seems like it's just out here attacking.
It's an out there-ness.
Yes.
And is it non-human?
Yes, just dark, this dark blob.
Dark blob of energy.
Yeah.
I see.
So you concretized it, yes,
given it a certain linearity, pictorial.
You want to know if it's out there?
Refuse it.
I do.
She has a karmic right to refuse it.
She has the right to refuse it,
rebuke it,
and demand that it leave her.
You can demand it and order.
There is in Christianity called,
what is it, the verification of spirits,
something like that.
People in the audience or somebody knows what it is,
in which I ask,
do you worship Jesus as Lord?
You can demand of a spirit.
You can demand that it speak.
That which is not of Jesus Christ or of the Lord or of God
cannot say yes.
It cannot say yes that it is.
And then you demand that it leave.
And demand that in the name of Jesus Christ
and the Lord God Almighty and the Holy Spirit
that you leave me now.
And that it must leave.
You have the karmic power and right to that.
She has the karmic right to it.
Yes, you have the karmic right.
I will.
Demand that it leave.
It will.
Same with discarnates.
They'll try and hang out with you
and you demand that they leave.
I hereby demand in the name of Jesus Christ,
the Holy Spirit,
whatever you call divinity,
that you leave me now.
And it must leave.
I know why it must leave,
because if it was of the highest order,
it wouldn't be hanging around around you
to torment people.
No, you demand that it leave.
It's called, what is it,
the clarification of spirits,
or the...
Discernment.
The what?
Discernment of spirits, yes.
The discernment of spirits.
You just demand that it leave.
And it will leave.
It has to leave.
If it doesn't, you call me up,
I'll come over and kick the hell out of you.
We'll get the bagpipes.
That's it.
That's Jesus.
We'll call up the bagpipes.
Just march.
Turn 180 and march, march away.
Bye-bye.
Thank you, sir.
Yes.
Thank you, Susan.
Thank you.
What did they say of spirits?
Discernment.
I always forget the word discernment.
I always think it's clarification of spirits.
Discernment.
Yeah.
I have a question about kinesiology.
I've had several healthcare people use it on me,
and it was always incorrect.
I just became crazy.
What is it?
Isn't that what you're talking about?
Yes, go ahead.
I know.
Yeah.
And I was listening to your CD,
and in there you said I think 10% of people wasn't able to use kinesiology.
There's 10% of the population in general,
for reasons unknown, karmic generally.
Actually, about a third of the population is all that can do it.
People below 200 can't do it.
That gets you to 50%.
So is it them or is it me that they can't ... It doesn't seem to ever be correct.
I just get sicker.
Well, who's using the kinesiology?
You or the practitioner?
The practitioner.
And the practitioner's answer is that you were wrong?
Well, I get sicker rather than it helping me.
And I know other people who have gone to these people and seemingly have gotten help,
but it's never worked for me.
Well, it may not be the right pathway for you.
I don't know.
That's my question.
Well, there's many reasons why a person gets sicker well,
having nothing to do with that.
Well, they're usually advising me to take certain vitamins or certain supplements.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You know.
Yeah.
Well, people put over expectations on nutrition a lot of times.
They are helpful.
They won't cure a brain tumor.
You know what I'm saying?
They're helpful.
Yeah.
It sets up the environment to be favorable for healing, but it may not be sufficient
in and of itself, depending on what the diagnosis is.
Okay.
So I'm still kind of confused as that's not the road for me to go or ...
Well, you're just talking about holistic health.
You're not talking about a doctor prescribing a medication, right?
Well, they're practitioners.
They're not.
They're not an MD who's prescribing a drug.
But it's a chiropractor or ...
That's right.
So why don't you try a regular MD?
Well, they don't use kinesiology.
Look, if you've got something wrong with you, any doctor can diagnose it and treat it.
It's not exactly out of this world in this mystery.
You know what I mean?
Well, can you do it to yourself?
Is there a way of testing yourself?
Why don't you just worry about getting well and forget about all these diagnostic techniques?
Well, it probably sounds like what I'm saying.
That's what I've finally come to that conclusion.
If you've got migraine, you take Imatrix.
It cures it in 20 minutes.
You know what I'm saying?
I don't have to go to a practitioner.
I have to do the kinesiology.
I don't have to take the nutritionist.
I can cure it in 20 minutes flat.
Try that.
Like that.
You know what I'm saying?
Can you do it to yourself?
Is there a way of testing yourself?
Why don't you just worry about getting well and forget about all these diagnostic techniques?
Well, it probably sounds like what I should do.
That's what I've finally come to, that conclusion.
If you've got migraine, you take Imatrix.
It cures it in 20 minutes.
You know what I'm saying?
You know what I'm saying? I don't have to go to a practitioner, I don't have to do a physiology, I don't have to take a nutritionist, I can cure it in 20 minutes flat.
Try that.
I'm going to have the headache cured before they've even finished with all this crap, you know what I'm saying?
Well, these are long-standing health issues that I've had.
Well, I don't know, you're being too vague about it, that's too much of a generality, I can't answer you on a generality.
What kind of health issue? There's no such diagnosis, specifically what you're talking about.
Well, I had irritable bowel.
Are you on any kind of medication for it?
At this time, it's doing okay.
At this time, what?
It's doing alright at this time.
I kind of have to figure out for myself what's the right.
Alright, so your intention, eventually you're going to win with it, right?
Yes.
It's spasmodic, you watch the things that aggravate it.
I have lots of allergies.
Well, the trouble with alternate medicine is a lot of times it gets into a make-wrong of traditional medicine.
With traditional medicine, I usually had a person cured before they could make the appointment with the alternate medicine.
You know what I'm saying?
So, if traditional medicine doesn't work, you try alternate.
If you're phobic about medical doctors and scared of them, and a lot of people are.
No, I'm not.
Then you try the long way around.
But by the time nutrition gets around to healing something, you're going to be considerably older than you are now.
Well, I'm not old enough, but...
All those things are supportive, but they're not curative.
See?
And a lot of times, all you need is the support and the situation will resolve itself.
But then sometimes you need a specific on top of that.
I used to treat complicated mental disorders.
And all the holistic things we did were added to the traditional.
So it was very hard not to recover if you followed what we did there.
Or a person would be on a traditional treatment, and as soon as we added the nutritional, they promptly got better.
So you try to treat the overall person, and at the same time the specifics as well.
I would go both traditional and non-traditional simultaneously.
A good holistic practitioner isn't going to feel offended if you're also seeing a regular doctor.
Not if he's integrous.
I mean, my patients, anything they can do to make them better, I'm all for that.
Well, I just thought, I just was curious if I was one of those that it just isn't readable.
I doubt it, I doubt it, I doubt it, I doubt it.
I doubt that you're, you know, incurable.
Oh, well, I am.
Thank you.
You're better already.
You're better than you were five minutes ago.
I brought you some gifts.
My group in Youngstown, Ohio sent those to you and Susan.
I hope you enjoy them.
This is the same one I have on.
And we have a study group of your book, Eye of the Eye, which is really good.
Oh, yes, okay.
And we're studying the Quartz and Miracles at the same time.
Good.
And the question that I have, I was fascinated by your horse story.
By my what?
The horse story.
You know, you didn't get along with horses.
Oh, yes.
And they didn't like you.
It sounded to me like you changed your karma today when you forgave the horses so that
you could get along with the horses.
I love that.
I'm curious.
Is that the same way or the same technique that I can use to change karma that I have
in my life?
You forgive everything.
In yourself.
In my...
Whatever happens to you, the safest presumption is that what you've done to others.
So you're going to have to heal your guilt about having done that to others and the undoingness
of that and that you refuse that way and you choose instead to be kindly and forgiving.
Okay.
Can I get concrete about that?
Because I'm not quite sure.
I mean, like I was killed in a car crash when I was 18.
I can't understand what you're saying.
She was killed in a car crash.
Yes.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
Which means probably in a much earlier previous life, I probably killed that particular person.
And so what I need to do is just forgive any of those types.
See, I'm lost.
Tell me again.
I don't get the question.
She's alone.
You said you were killed in a car crash when you were 18.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
What was your question?
What's your question?
You're a teenager.
You're 18.
Yeah.
And I'm just using that.
So did you have an out-of-body experience?
Yeah.
Okay.
She was killed in a car wreck and had an out-of-body experience so she figures that she was
In this life time?
Yes.
In this life time.
So she figures that
How were you killed?
By a drunk driver.
Her part probably stopped and she had an out-of-body experience and then came back into her life.
You mean you died and then revived again?
Uh-huh.
And what is your question?
You have questions?
I guess that undid that one, huh?
She felt that maybe she had done that to someone else.
I think very likely.
She says maybe she had done that to someone else, and that's what the karmic...
Yes, I think so.
Always presume that whatever happens to you
is either the consequence of something you're holding in mind,
or it's the undoing of some karmic thing.
So the presumption is,
the reason I didn't get along with horses
is because I've been brutal to horses.
So when I asked for kinesiology,
in previous lifetimes, was I brutal to horses?
I said, yes, you'd get drunk, and you'd be angry, and you'd beat the horse.
No wonder the horse killed me.
No wonder I couldn't get along with horses in this lifetime.
So I had to forgive the one of me who was brutal and cruel to animals,
forgive the horses for protecting himself,
and since then, I've got a picture at home of kissing a horse,
which I never could have done before.
Okay.
Just an animal.
An attitude of forgiveness about everything, huh?
Yeah, sure.
That's why the cars and miracles works, you see.
Yeah.
But the presumption, the presumption,
that if everybody's rude to you,
you have to forgive the one in you who is rude to others,
and unfeeling towards hurting their feelings.
For all lifetimes.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And that will...
That will undo it.
Undo it.
All you need is the willingness.
Okay.
Because, you know, see, one of the things I don't want to do
is to...
Is to come back here.
I don't mean here.
I wouldn't resist it, you know.
You wouldn't resist.
You get what you resist.
Yeah.
Now, whether you return or not, I'll leave up to God's will.
Okay.
I could probably make a better decision.
Just kidding, just kidding.
I know what you're kidding.
David, it's already worth it.
I know.
You're always doing this to me.
Thank you.
I'm the timekeeper.
I know.
All right.
We'll move faster.
Faster, faster.
It's because he asked me such interesting questions.
Yeah, go ahead.
I have two questions.
One's individual and one's global.
The first is, in my current level of being,
there seems to be some experiences.
I know your level of being draws your life
from what you're saying in the material
and others are saying as well.
So, it seems as though,
and I haven't tested my level of beingness,
that you experience sometimes different levels,
even though your level is in a,
as you're progressing.
Good.
That's true, okay.
That's good.
And the second question is,
I don't understand,
if you can explain to me,
you talked about someone with a presence
that is up in the upper hundreds,
counteracting the negativity of many,
many people.
What happens, globally,
when you have a loss of many people from the Earth,
number one,
and number two,
when someone who has a high level of being
leaves the planet?
You're talking about the collective consciousness level of mankind.
Yes.
It's sustained, yes, considerably,
by just a few, very advanced, yes,
because their energy field is so powerful.
Now, when they leave the planet,
will the collective energy field,
yeah, I don't think so, no,
the collective energy field will remain the same,
because the vibration and the frequency of the aura
is now in the collective.
Okay.
Yeah.
The teachings of Jesus Christ go down centuries,
even though he's not physically here anymore.
So, it's like the aura, the energy field,
the vibration, the frequency,
sustains that of mankind.
Because otherwise,
otherwise mankind,
in fact, we even asked one time,
if it had not been for the great,
great teachers,
mankind would have extinguished itself by now,
and we always get yes.
Well, I think,
He would have killed himself off, yeah.
Excuse me.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
I think of teachers such as yourself
or Father Thomas Keating leaving the planet,
and I wonder,
how will we be affected?
Oh, I think the aura,
the energy field is still there.
Okay.
Yeah.
I'll call him.
Oh, no.
I'll give him a ring.
Let's not go at the same time, okay?
No, I got to meet him,
you know,
and be with him up in Colorado.
Colorado.
That's where I'm from.
Yeah.
We got,
we were at the,
what's the name of it?
St. Benedict's?
St. Benedict's.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
My question is similar to the previous one.
I believe that evolution of consciousness,
evolution of consciousness is accompanied by discharging pain
as we go through levels.
And you said that the pain that one experiences at 800 and above
is of the collective consciousness.
Can you differentiate those higher levels with lower levels?
Let's say if you move to forgiveness,
then you will also come up with the guilt
of all the times you were not forgiving.
See?
It isn't that it's causing the pain,
but now through self-awareness.
So part of spiritual work is overcoming the reluctance
to look at the errors.
That's why it can't be done without self-forgiveness.
The reason we stress the innocence of the consciousness of mankind
is because the human mind,
the way it's put together,
cannot tell when it's making an error
without correction and information from outside.
So someone who has a higher level of consciousness
experiences the collective unconsciousness pain,
or collective consciousness pain?
No.
The pain is because it's inclusion in purity
of something that's not pure,
and that impurity burns.
And so you look at it and see what it is.
The biggest problem I had was with
the Heart of the Spiritual Warrior.
Indignation.
I paid no attention to the world for a long, long time.
Then I began to re-examine it,
especially when I did Truth vs. Falsehood.
And indignation would come up out of my spiritual warrior.
And I had to constantly clear that,
to stop seeing people who create pain
and suffering for others,
stop being angry or indignant at them, see?
That didn't come up until that level,
then it came up.
I wasn't personally indignant at it,
but collectively, I was.
Most of this lifetime,
I've been doubting my own intuition.
And in the early part of this year,
there was a period where that seemed to lift.
I was doing calibrations, and they tied in,
and a lot of things happened.
And then that came in doubt.
And I notice you don't have doubt
up there.
I was wondering when it calibrated that.
And also...
There's all kinds of doubt.
And then there's different expressions,
like cynicism, skepticism.
Skepticism is about 60.
Doubt can be a consequence of integrity,
or it depends what the motivation is behind it.
It seems to be connected with despair,
in my case, anyway.
That's where it leads to.
So that would be the level, then.
Despair about what?
Life, or where I'm going,
or my connection to God, or...
That would really take a little spiritual counseling
to get to the basis of it.
The doubt, then, is a lack of faith.
Because you're making faith conditional.
Why don't you make faith unconditional?
So you think if you pray,
your leg's gonna get better.
No.
It may not.
You see my thumb return?
No.
Gone forever.
Bye-bye.
So it's what your expectation is of divinity.
Disillusionment means that you're putting something on God.
If I pray up a storm,
God will let such and such thing happen.
It's not about praying for me.
It's about...
In terms of connecting with the inner self,
or the intuition,
and trusting that.
Yeah.
And it's...
I get it's going external,
and checking if it...
It only takes something outside that
to question it, and then...
I don't know.
It would require a session with you
to really get to the basis of this.
I'm finishing a book called
Transcending Levels of Consciousness.
In fact, this is finished.
In which we cover these subjects.
You don't have the time today,
but there's a whole chapter on this very thing
with the various things that could be leading to it.
And if we had time,
we would go through them.
Any one of them can be triggering it.
And once you see it, you say,
oh, oh.
One I got earlier was the question,
what's the juice in it?
What's the juice of doubt?
And I got that it's being the victim,
and therefore getting people to be sorry
as a way of extracting...
Yeah, whether it could be
unconscious motivations, yeah.
Thank you.
You're working on it, though.
You're working on it.
That's it.
Mm-hmm.
You're working on it.
All right.
We won't have time for questions.
Dr. Hawkins, my question pertains
to the calibration of consciousness
of groups of people.
You've indicated that excluding Karl Marx,
the great book's author's calibration goes up a bit.
If you take out Marx, yeah,
Marx at 130 brings down the whole level.
Right.
And then you take out Engels at 200.
The whole level,
the collective goes up, you know.
Right.
Yeah.
The collective level of mankind right now
is where it is,
because there's so many people at a very low level.
It brings down the overall average, yeah.
You've also calibrated the United States at 421,
and that half of the people in this country are under 200.
Is it useful to calibrate,
the folks in the United States are over 200
and have another calibration?
I don't make sense of the question.
Oh, it's the same thing that you're doing
with Karl Marx and the great book's authors.
Mm-hmm.
Taking like a country out of that,
would the world calibrate higher?
Oh, yeah.
If you take the lowest countries off the planet, yeah.
What would the calibration of the folks in the United States be
excluding the 50% that are under 200?
I don't know.
Oh, I was wondering about that.
It's too hypothetical for me.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
Is it useful to do that sort of thing, or?
Could, I don't still get the question.
Could you do that sort of thing,
and it's a hypothetical question.
All right.
If you take out all the people that are below 200.
Right.
Then what would the calibrated level of mankind,
of America be?
Right.
Yeah.
I think I did do it one time.
You did?
Yeah.
We can answer that.
We did do it one time.
It would be over 475, 480.
It would be around 475 instead of 421.
Also, is it useful to use the mode and the median also besides the mean?
Because this is the mean, but it's a logarithmic scale.
No, no.
You're confusing mathematics and statistics with consciousness level.
It's a different thing.
It's not comparable.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Take a second.
Just one question each because we only have about 15 more minutes.
Don't get over it.
I will be very quick.
I have no question.
Only thank you very much for blessing from last year.
Here is the book for children about unconditional love.
I had experience with that.
When I said I give the Holy Spirit in a moment, I feel huge powerful field of energy.
powerful, but peaceful. So my book was there up, so I don't know what happened with me.
Very good. Thank you very much. And I have eight books for anybody who likes, loves cats.
Like cats, right here. Like cats.
It's a kitty book.
So I don't know if I could give to anybody. And thank you very much.
Thank you for the kitty book. My kitty thanks you, I thank you.
It keeps us human, pets, doesn't it? Keeps us considerate of others.
People who live alone and get depressed, I say to them, do you have a dog?
No, I say, well I'm not going to treat you unless you get a dog or a cat.
I'm not going to treat you unless you get a dog or a cat.
They would get better right away, you know.
I have one question.
Yeah.
Who and why create other dimension, astral and entities?
Who creates what?
I don't know about other dimensions. I got enough trouble with this.
Who created other dimensions?
I couldn't tell you. That's not my province.
I have enough trouble with this dimension. You?
Just curious about this.
I teach avoid other dimensions, see. Avoid investigating the paranormal.
Yeah, I know, but it's just who created.
Because I don't think it's good.
People, you've got to be an expert, an expert, expert, expert.
Very few people are super expert, you know.
Thank you.
They don't even know they're out of body. They tell you about astral realms.
They think they went there, their astral body went there.
And people who visit those places and come back with all their earth prophecies are dead wrong.
California did not fall off in the ocean and all the rest of the crap that went on in the 80s.
Just slide up because we need you closer to the mic.
We should have guys at Sedona there, give you a date when Sedona,
California's going to fall off in the ocean, Phoenix is going to be a harbor, you know what I mean?
There's going to be ravaging gangs, pillaging, and there's going to be this and that.
And...
When the time for this event came and went and it didn't happen,
he would just change the dates and go on giving lectures.
Go ahead.
Asking about an avatar in India by the name of Sri Kalki Bhagavan and his wife Amma.
And at the age of four, he told his parents he was going to enlighten the world.
He's now in his 70s or 80s and is having his followers perform what he calls a diksha or diksha.
Oh, yes.
Where they...
Yes.
Hands on where they open the...
Oh, God, yeah.
For $5,500, you can go there.
Right.
Okay.
So...
For $5,500, you can get diksha.
He says that...
I'm going to give you a diksha for a dollar and a half.
You want a buck?
Yeah.
I hereby bless you.
God bless you, my beloved, in your perfection.
So he says that...
Besides all the wisdom of eternity.
You don't need to go for diksha.
You just got it.
I just got it.
Yep.
Thank you.
She just got diksha.
You did.
You can tell by her eyes she got diksha.
I can tell by her eyes.
Yeah, I like that.
She's so...
Yeah.
Yeah, she's the...
Hello.
Yeah.
On one of your videos, you mentioned to work on the resolve, but it's your final moments
to work on the resolve
to die for God
to get that now
if you're presented with that
I don't think I have
but
but fears
arise on their own
fear of death
fear of non-existence
fear of leaving the illusion
that I wish to
I wanted to know
I know fear is an illusion
but do I meet that fear
or do I just
oh it's very innate
very deep
it's the basis of all fears
I teach a mythic call
and then what
so you say you can lose all your money
and then nobody will want to know me
and then what
and then I'll be lonely
and I won't be able to get a job
and then what
and then I won't have any money
then I'll have to live in a park
and be friendless
and then what
and then I'll get sick
and then nobody will care for me
and then I'll get a disease
and then I'll starve to death
and every single fear you'll find
will come down to a fear of death
that underlies every fear
but how do you work to transcend that fear of death
you keep surrendering to the
and then what
I'll tell you it's great to be a bag man
I'll tell you how you live
you live in the park
it's fantastic
you go to the bank
you read the wall street journal
they have free cookies and free coffee
I mean it's cool being a bag man
I'm telling you
I'm not worried about form life
it's the cross over
the death that I
I mean I guess my question is
meeting the fear of death
not the things leading to that
alright so it's only a fear like any other fear
alright
the way to surrender fear
I'll just finish the chapter on it
is stop calling it anything
don't call it fear
you're not experiencing fear
that's a label
that's a nominalization word
F-E-A-R
you don't experience fear
you don't experience F-E-A-R
no
you experience a particular set of symptoms
let go of resisting the symptoms
if you completely let go of resisting the symptoms
the symptoms will go away
and so will what you call fear
that's how you can disappear anything
if you're presented with what you think is
you're not going to face dying
I don't think that's surely
but if you come up to me and say
if you come up against what you feel
is the necessity to surrender your life to God
then you do so
because you can't die
I know that
it's not a possibility
but it's an experiential reality
it's only when you face it
and when you actually die
you feel yourself die
you literally do die
there's an agony of death
and then eternal life
keep that in mind
is on the other side of the door
but you can't cheat your way through it
I thought you were going to tell her
okay that's right
no you're right on it
underlying every fear is fear of death
and once you lose your fear of death
you know
nothing can really get to you anymore
that's why people who have had near death experiences
lose their fear of death
you know
this guy in the world
here's this live mind waiting to go off any second
I look at that guy and says
somebody blow up, blow up
he goes
ha ha ha
my acceptance of it
facilitates his acceptance of it
and both of us
through the without fear
okay
thank you
mm-hmm
I mean worst thing to happen is you die
so
yeah
Susan how are you?
Dwal Kul in one of the Alice Bailey books
said that
Jesus and the Christ were two separate entities
and that the Master Jesus incarnated
to offer his body
at a later date to be overshadowed by the entity that we call the christ
is that true it's always the theory you don't need to even know it
you see jesus christ is an incarnation he's an incarnation the process of incarnation so that
is a unique condition your incarnation different than what the buddha stated happened to him and
different from krishna because jesus was both man and god simultaneously right yeah so within the
man arose the presence of divinity so he was incarnate incarnate the buddha did not claim
he was incarnate jesus christ came for a specific purpose to teach salvation he did not come to
teach enlightenment jesus christ taught salvation
in and of yourself without the help of a savior the likelihood of you getting to heaven is slim
that's the truth therefore on judgment day the christ will speak for you and be your advocate
yeah it's an honor yes um i have here a publication um published in 1968 um that i have
a question about 68
1968 and it was attained in a very unusual fashion very remarkable circumstances
um the title of it is the vitamin b3 therapy a second communication to a a physicians
from bill w who we now know as bill wilson the founder of paul it's anonymous
um it goes on to say that um alcoholics suffering from depression anxiety tension
and exhaustion can can be helped with these these techniques yeah sugar-free diet you're going to be
a fascination
so the question is um would you still still support this this publication because you
there's a couple articles in here authored by you and and um do you have any further comments
for for about about b3 therapy no this was uh our clinical experience at this time
so we got hopeless hopeless uh psychotic alcoholics etc from all over the place the first thing we'd do
time so we got hopeless hopeless uh psychotic alcoholics etc from all over the place
The first thing we did is took them off, you got to stop all sugar and sweets, take big
doses of vitamin B3, and if you need the pharmacologic agent to stop being crazy, then you do that
too.
And we had a tremendous recovery with hopeless cases, see.
And Bill Wilson was the first one, because Bill suffered intractable depression.
Here's the founder of AA, who himself had a high, very high experience.
The energy of those worms lighting up like that radiated out into the recovery of millions
of people, the power of that light in that room in Towns Hospital.
But Bill himself had intractable depressions after that, tried everything.
And then came upon, I forget the name of the two doctors now, who recommended niacin.
Their names are probably in here.
I'm just not thinking at the moment, because of the time pressure.
Anyway, so niacin, sugar-free diet, niacin recoveries, we covered the depression.
Yeah.
And Bill told people about it, and we tried it on lots of people, and by God, it worked.
Thank you.
Hi, Doctor.
Mm-hmm.
Back in the mid-'80s, I had a tattoo put on my back, a full mural I put on my back.
And it was kind of my conception of creation and destruction and life and death at the
time.
The yin and yang of it all, eh?
Kind of the yin and yang, the alpha omega.
The dance of Shiva.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
And since, everything has changed for me.
Yeah.
Completely.
I mean, this represented complete opposites, you know.
Okay.
Creation, destruction, life, death, the road of life, and so forth.
Mm-hmm.
And I was just wondering.
I think there's some negative images.
Mm-hmm.
I think there's some negative images in there.
I know there is some negative images amongst this.
Yeah.
We need a good artist to create them differently.
Put a mustache on them or something.
There, you got it.
I mean, that's what I'm thinking, that I'm going to modify it now.
I would.
Because it bothers you mentally.
Well, it doesn't really bother, you know, it's like I don't even.
Yeah, it does.
It doesn't really bother me mentally.
Yeah.
But I know that the images are negative now.
And I know that negative images have an energy.
All right.
So intention, intentionality, I'd have an argument.
Intentionality.
How can we make this look more benign, you know.
Right.
Like I want to take out the image.
Well, look, that's your.
It's your intention, it's purification, so.
Right.
You're just carrying forth your intention, redemption.
OK.
Mm-hmm.
All right.
It's a pure intention.
OK.
Thank you very much.
Mm-hmm.
Yep?
OK.
What's so weird about beardless hair?
Colors.
friend yes my question is on behalf of my son and has been covered almost about the question
about jesus and buddha and in one of your books i think you said that jesus came straight from
heaven yes was jesus the man reincarnated or it doesn't make him incarnated not reincarnated
so he came as an entire he came to heaven to teach salvation say and was incarnate incarnate
so the divinity was within him the man because jesus is the only one says i am the son of god
and the son of man nobody else says that i am both the son of god and the son of man
yes a unique contribution thank you very much and thank you for today it was only by doing that that
he could bring about the salvation of mankind thank you that's why he taught salvation yeah
this is her dollar 25
you
and i have a question is there a limitation now for women as far as a peak level of consciousness
in this realm never was there weren't many lady plumbers either i mean they just didn't go for it
well because we kind of heard that there was we we that a female could only go so far up to
740 no no no if you
you know that's historically
i think.
were you just get what it was because that's the way it was in those days
trap
yeah honey i mean they're very mystic scenery
uh...
no way says so far no anoteric sometime period
dubbled forum and we tried to biopark the cake one that so root
strange on fitness is doing it we did it
there are many was ever selling either
Wieder underexplored by the sun nglada assemblies is her金山
I mean, they just didn't go for it, you know.
I mean, they just, they weren't in the pipeline.
You know, I think people...
So that's possible.
I didn't know any of the people who wanted to die under you,
they weren't.
So you're saying it's possible.
Huh?
Okay.
Oh, yeah, I don't think there's any limitation, no.
Okay, good, thanks.
Good, great, go.
No, there's a legitimate thing.
I don't think God is a sexist, no.
God is beyond gender.
That's the joke of it all, you know.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
God is beyond gender.
Gender is way down in the linearity.
Okay.
As you can see, in non-linearity,
gender is not a possibility, folks.
Yeah.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
I've been studying your past lectures,
and you said thoughts arise out of a field,
and it's automatic, and it just comes.
Does that, what thoughts come to you from that field
based on your past?
And recent karma, and your level of awareness?
Well, that's a complicated question,
and I wrote extensively about it in one of these books.
I don't remember which one.
I filter out the thoughts.
You understand the nature of the thought field.
Maybe the next lecture we should do that.
The thoughts are the production of many things,
karmic propensity.
But thoughts are arising out of an energy field,
which is non-linear.
And then it's given definition and becomes progressively more
and more.
More linear, see?
And eventually, you will find that it's your intentionality
to think due to what you get, due to the payoff
of the thinkingness, and the surrender of the payoff
of the thinkingness, and owning yourself as source
and not victim of the thinkingness gives you the power
to refuse it.
Is every thought, big, small, complex, whatever,
is it strictly to juice the ego?
Is that what you see?
Are all thoughts the juice for the ego?
As I say, I don't think I can answer it in a couple of senses.
It's a propensity, it's a habit, it's an addiction.
It's because of the payoff of the thinkingness.
Also, it's due to ignorance, not realizing that you don't have
to think.
You can choose, you can refuse to think without trying
to stop thoughts.
And I've explained it in lectures.
The thoughts are like the flying fish coming out of the sea.
If you focus below thoughts, right now your mind is silent.
I got your mind, it's saying nothing.
Now you gotta give it a thought.
But it was saying nothing when I caught it.
You gotta catch it where it's not thinking.
So the silence is below the thinkingness, not prior to it.
That's the misconception of Buddhism, it's not prior.
It's underneath.
In the background, if nobody's in this room,
it's the underneath silence.
I can focus in on the silence.
I can hear the silence.
Aside from the noise, can't you?
If it wasn't for the silence, you couldn't hear my voice.
So there's a knowingness of the silence.
The same silence is in your mind, or you wouldn't know what you're thinking.
Focus on the silence in the room.
If it wasn't for the silence, you couldn't hear my voice.
If you're walking through the woods, the only reason you can hear the bird
is because of the silence of the forest.
So instead of focusing on the bird, focus on the silence of the forest.
That's all you gotta do.
It's just a matter of focus.
All of a sudden, you'll get, yeah, right.
There's nothing going on in the Coliseum.
There's nobody here.
You know?
Thank you very much.
Okay.
Well, okay.
Yeah.
It's actually already been done.
Thank you.
My question is, is the new king of Saudi Arabia more
integrous than King Faisal, who recently passed away?
New king of Saudi Arabia?
I can't tell you.
Okay.
I know that the one that I did calibrate was at 480.
And I think Nixon screwed it up on that one, wouldn't it?
Yeah.
I don't know.
Anyway.
Okay.
You know, he was very integrous.
And somehow we broke our faith with him.
And that was a big mistake.
Because he was integrous.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Caused the resentment.
Great.
So you're gonna calibrate him?
I think I did write about it in the book, you know, about that particular event.
Unfortunately, for the West, we were not integrous in maintaining our promise to the people.
Okay.
So I would expect him, the new king, Abdulaziz, I believe is how you pronounce it, to be calibrated
soon.
Only because I'm moving to Saudi Arabia.
Oh, you're moving to Saudi Arabia.
We have a mission.
The new king is of a high caliber.
The new king of Saudi Arabia is of a high caliber.
Okay.
He's of a high caliber.
That's very good news, isn't it?
That's good news.
Thank you.
That's the way it is today.
Yes.
Today.
You think it's changed around the world pretty fast.
Yeah.
Thanks for your work, doctor.
Thank you, Susan.
My question is about the muscle test.
I don't have any idea what I calibrate at, but I'd like to be able to use the muscle
test.
And with a third of the population not being able to use it, I'm afraid to ask almost,
you know, what my calibration is.
But can you tell me how I would start on the path of using the muscle test, learning about
it, certifying, you know, how to use it?
Yeah.
Well, first of all, I think it's very important to know what you're doing.
You know, it's very important to know what you're doing.
It's very important to know what you're doing.
In the new book I've got, I describe a sort of revised section on kinesiology, including
using the O-ring method, you know.
The O-ring method I hold in mind of Bin Laden and I pull, and then I hold in mind Ben Franklin
and I pull.
And I see the difference.
All right.
There's a very simple way I just discovered recently.
I don't know if you have any books around here.
All right.
You hold Bin Laden in mind.
I just use him as a bad example currently because Hitler's dead, you know, but I...
Hitler used to be a real man.
He wasn't very reliable, but he left us, so a bad example, you know.
All right.
So I've got a big, heavy dictionary at home.
So I hold in mind a statement.
Now I lift the book.
Now I hold in mind the alternate to that statement and I lift the book.
With very little experience you'll get, when I hold Jesus Christ in mind, the book comes
up pretty easily.
When I hold Bin Laden in mind, it takes up more muscle power.
So the simplest, fastest way I've discovered most recently is just lifting.
You know, things that are heavy.
And you notice that when you're thinking something positive, you're much stronger.
I always tell people, you know, if you're in sports, at the starting gun, hold in mind
the victory of your country, God, womanhood, whatever.
Something beyond your personal self to win because if I want to win, that's already kinesiologically
knocked me out and I just lost a tenth of a second.
Mm-hmm.
No.
If I do it for my university, for the good of mankind, if I do it for womanhood, then
I've already got more power.
I tell a woman athlete, do it for, you know, womanhood.
That instantly gives her more power.
If a dude does it so I get to win the tennis championship, she's already weak.
So at the starting gun, the one who does it for a higher purpose has more power, measurable
power.
Thank you, Doctor.
Yeah.
When you run, run for God, you'll see.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Hi, my question has to do with, I've been kind of having like some spiritual experiences
where I become aware of like my heart chakra.
I guess I don't know what to call it, but that's kind of how I word it.
And when it happens, I feel like my heart is like overjoyed with love.
And then like sometimes an hour, sometimes a day.
It's like I still feel that same heart.
And it's almost like it's black or dead.
I don't know, like, but then it comes back again and it fluctuates like constantly throughout
the day sometimes.
And sometimes it's more constant.
And I'm just kind of curious if you have anything to say about that.
I don't know if that's really a question, but.
How to handle this kundalini energy.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
You can breathe it up to our chakras.
The idea that it's gone, it's not gone.
It's gone.
Mm-hmm.
It's not gone.
Uh, I don't know.
It really, you really require sort of a teacher of the, of that kind of a technique.
I would breathe it up to the higher chakras all the time.
Okay.
Because the heart is, is, is very, very good.
But you can go breathe it to the crown chakra.
Mm-hmm.
Sometimes I feel it there.
Do it to the throat.
You know, do it to the third eye.
Try that.
Just breathe it up.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you.
I wanted to ask you a question about my five pregnancies.
About?
About what? Pregnancies. I had three pregnancies during the 20-year use of drugs and alcohol that ended in abortion.
The last, after February the 8th of 89, I cleaned up and two years later had a son in two years.
And I'm wondering what you can tell me about that karma or maybe the purposes of the two sons that lived.
I don't understand the question. Some lived, some died?
Two. I have two now that are alive.
Two boys are alive and yet she did have some...
Stillbirths or something?
Abortions.
So what is your question about it?
Yes.
Abortions before three months, it doesn't matter.
Well, the amount of guilt you feel about it, you know.
Our research is that the spirit doesn't enter the embryo until the third month.
It's only, you know, it's the physicality which becomes human.
But the spirit won't enter the fetus until the third month.
Because we got, you know, we did test that out.
We were testing out contraception,
first trisemester, so a late abortion has a different karma consequence, I believe.
Forgive yourself anyway, no matter what you did.
I think all women deserve it.
I think they have a good karma just for birthing the human race, for God's sake.
Hi. I have a question about kinesiology.
When you are doing a calibration,
and someone is in the room that has an attachment
to what the result might be, does it, can it skew the results?
Not their being in the room, no.
Okay. If they're part of the test, either the arm or...
If they're part of the test, sure, that's going to throw it off, you know.
Okay.
No, you just, you can't have a stake in the results.
And I tell people, forget any stake in the result.
Just try to find the absolute truth.
And then, and then if the answer isn't what you want,
you can begin to ask more questions.
And by the time you finish those questions,
then the way you contextualize it will have changed.
And it'll be okay that you got what you got.
Okay. Thank you.
It's like you missed the plane.
With kinesiology, you find that that plane was scheduled to crash.
So, you know, it's okay.
Thank you for your teaching. I love you both.
You said something earlier that I missed.
Your voice dropped at the end of a sentence,
and I just wanted to ask you what it was that you said.
You said that it's only coming out now,
but that nine people at the highest levels of government that are...
And I didn't get the rest of what you said.
There are moles.
Yeah.
Yeah, we picked out moles in the past.
You know, in fact, it's on the record.
And I think we did on power versus forest, one of the first ones.
We picked out two very famous ones.
Okay.
One was...
What the hell were they?
Richard Aldrich.
Yeah, one was Aldrich.
And the other was Aldrich...
One was Aldrich James, and the other one was Hanson.
Hanson.
Okay. Well, I just...
We picked them out years ago.
And then we said when we wrote the book,
currently, how many is there?
Nine.
I think one came out this last week, didn't it?
Yeah, in the White House.
In the FBI.
Thank you so much. Thank you so much.
Yep.
I mean, where else would you find them?
If I was a spy, I wouldn't be out in the garage.
I'd be in the White House with you.
I'd be at Los Alamos with you.
That's where they were, Los Alamos.
Of course.
Where do you think they're going to be?
You talked about what you hold in mind is what you experience.
And I thought after finishing the Course in Miracles,
I want to take a specific phrase from your teaching.
That is, nothing is causing anything.
And you know the whole thing.
Everything is happening.
Everything is happening spontaneously of its own,
and as expression of divinity.
And the question is, should I do it like the Course in Miracles,
that I replace every thought with the phrase,
or just hold it in mind silently,
because then it's nondualistic, you know?
When doing the Course in Miracles, does he...
Well, actually, it has nothing to do with the Course in Miracles.
I don't quite get the question.
Does he mean doing the lessons?
Yeah, but...
Pulling the lessons as a fact?
Pardon?
Instead of a probability.
We're a little confused on the question.
I want to take the phrase from him,
that nothing is causing anything,
and take this phrase and hold this phrase in mind.
Yeah, you can meditate on a phrase, yeah.
Yeah.
And the question is, should I do it like the Course in Miracles,
that replace every thought and everything with the phrase?
You could, yes.
Or like more...
Hold it silently, because then it's nondualistic.
Mm-hmm.
Either way.
Doesn't matter.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Okay, now I got it.
So I have the commitment now to do it.
Mm-hmm.
It's a vis-a-vis to the Guru, you know?
So my ego can...
Good luck.
So my ego cannot escape now.
You hold in mind, you hold in mind the optimal, see?
And then it's up to God.
Yeah.
Hello.
I first have a confession.
I realized recently that my devotion has been to getting spiritual experience.
And because I see all the description of the defined state,
like the allness, the void, the beauty, the unconditional love,
I was attracted to all those.
So I was doing all kind of practice, meditation, breathing,
contemplation in order to get those.
And I realized it wasn't the right direction.
The devotion should be to nonduality instead.
And those experience follows.
Yes or no?
That's true, true.
And so I'd like to share that first of all.
Yeah, yeah.
That's a wonderful insight.
See, the reason I call it devotional nonduality is because there's the way of negation, see?
But the way of devotion is coming from the heart.
Instead of negating love, it's love that motivates the desire to become enlightened, let's say.
So you use the power of the heart rather than just spiritual ambition.
Right.
I have a question for people below 200.
Are they accountable for what they do?
Yes.
So what they do and choose have consequence.
But they reject that responsibility.
Yeah, but they're still responsible.
In other words, they didn't mean to skid on the ice, but frankly, your car is overturning,
blocking traffic.
So it may be an innocent intention, but nevertheless, you're still responsible to call a tow truck,
get your car pulled away, see?
Mm-hmm.
And what advice would you give to those below 200 if they want to be above 200?
Hmm.
Make the right choice.
Pray, yeah, yes.
Well, the collective spiritual energy, the collective spiritual energy of groups is very
influential.
Below 200, I tell people, join the nearest 12-step group, the First of Miracles group,
go to church.
Put yourself in the energy field, you know, and then sometime when you're not even trying
it, all of a sudden, you sort of get it.
You get it.
It's called getting it by osmosis.
Mm-hmm.
So I tell people, immerse yourself in a spiritual group of high integrity and follow their teachings
to the best of your possibility, and the rest will be up to God.
Mm-hmm.
You get it by osmosis.
Just cutting out.
Okay.
Yeah.
Yes, I do.
I have one more internal...
It went out to the microphone.
No mics?
Yeah.
Okay.
That's it.
Quick.
All my copious notes, I have not been able to formulate an actual question.
Yeah?
Yes.
The area of interest or elucidation is the spiritual will, my spiritual will.
Karmic propensity and the paradigm shifts you speak of.
Mm-hmm.
Specifically, in my case right now, the burning sensation with the purification process.
All of these things attract, get my attention.
Mm-hmm.
Like I said, I haven't been able to correlate a thought.
To ask a direct question.
Mm-hmm.
What's a direct question?
Does the brain physiology as consciousness advance, and the praying for...
My brain burns.
I've had brain burns.
Yeah.
I've had brain burns for the past two years.
I've been in almost constant meditation and prayer.
What I'm thinking I hear in this lecture is resolution of karmic propensity through intense
prayer and meditation.
Uh-huh.
If you're moving too fast, you're gonna stress yourself, so you're complaining about the
stress.
Relax.
I like that answer.
All right.
Relax.
Yeah.
So, there's attraction.
Yin instead of yang.
You're going at it too yang.
Yin is, I invite thee, oh Lord.
Yang is, say you're too yang.
Okay.
Try being more yin.
See?
Your life becomes a prayer, a devotional mudra.
By my positionality, do I invite thee, oh Lord, who reigns over all.
Huh?
So, it's more like supplication, invitation, the power of the yin.
You're going at it like that.
Yeah.
On the other hand, every question that's answered brings up a new question,
which, of course, is again my delight.
So I want to tell you how much I enjoyed being with you today.
It was sort of a different experience, experiential this morning, experiential this afternoon.
And I do give thanks to thee, O Lord, for this, thy gift to me, those assembled.
You are God's gift to me.
Thank you.
Thank you for the bag, Clive.
It was my joy.
I had trouble talking after that, you know, because it brings up tears and everybody a lump in their throat.
I had a hard time continuing to talk after that.
Look at what we got. Isn't that cute?
Is that cute or what?