So
here heal.
Glory and excelsius to you. All glory be
to thee, oh Lord.
All glory be to thee.
The problem with the world is it says
all glory be to me.
Thee, not me. That is the difference
between enlightenment and hell.
Little technicality there.
All right. So, thank you. Get down in
the
uh the lecture today is about something
or other.
Let's see what the hell it says here.
Oh, uh
what does it say here? Oh,
what does it say the lectures about
today?
spiritual practice in everyday life.
Okay.
That ought to be interesting.
We'll see what what comes up.
How many are new today?
Oh, so we always have a sprinkling of
new. Okay. Well, uh we have um the the
subject for today is going to take up
most of the time. So we won't do as much
a review as we have usually done in the
past. We'll just put up slide one for
sake of familiarity and reexlain it.
Uh because we're going to spend more
time on spiritual practice in everyday
life because that's what it's what it's
all about.
Now the map of consciousness is a
exponential
logarithmic I don't know logarithm. It
it goes from one to a thousand.
Goes from one to a th00and.
The numbers
are to the base 10. So
150 means 10 * 10 * 10 150 times.
Uh
400 means 10 * 10 * 10 400 times to the
exponent 400.
Uh therefore
an increase in a level of consciousness
is very very significant.
Even a few points makes a tremendous
difference. We noticed that in in we
we're going to be doing a lecture in AC
in medicine and uh academic medicine
calibrates at 440.
uh
uh holistic medicine kind of practice
calibrates at about 445
and uh it's not just academic it's
experiential. So
the extra five points doesn't sound like
much, but when you're you're talking 450
five times that from any number, you can
see it's quite a bit of difference and
the clinical response is quite a bit bit
different between academic medicine and
clinical medicine.
>> And my ear's falling off again. Right.
Okay.
The other thing we want to clarify is
that the the kinesiologic response is uh
kinesiologic response is uh extremely
useful.
Uh it is not a personal response. A lot
of people will write me and they'll say
how come you calibrated something at so
and so you know like I have a personal
stake in it. I couldn't care less. It's
just a number. It's just a number.
The number is independent of opinion.
The number indicates essence. The
difficulty with the human life is the
differentiation between perception and
essence. Ego takes care of perception in
in the internet all the blog the blog
mania that goes on there uh is the ego.
Essence has to do with the reality the
inner reality.
how to differentiate appearance from the
reality and that's the whole point of
spiritual work is to be able to
distinguish the difference
other than this particular kinesiologic
response.
Uh I know of no other way of
differentiating truth from falsehood
because man's opinion is frankly uh
worthless. I hate to tell that to all
the bloggers out there, but
it's frankly worthless
because we read things, you know, it's
obvious that the writer hasn't the
slightest understanding of what they're
writing about, but they don't let that
interfere with expressing their opinion.
And that's part of the indulgence of
narcissism, you see. Um, all right.
So today we'll be talking about
spiritual practice in everyday life and
uh
the kinesiologic response is uh also
correlated with the pupilary response.
Uh somebody incorrectly compared it to
dowsing. It is not dowsing. Dowsing is a
whole different matter and nor does it
have anything to do with the
unconscious.
Had nothing to do with the unconscious.
It has nothing to do with dowsing.
uh it's a response of
the energy field of life itself,
consciousness itself.
So today I think in between during some
of the breaks we're going to be doing
are we be going to be doing some
pupilary testing?
>> Is that right?
>> Yes. Uh we have a slit lamp. Well, we
did we did some
so the pupil responds to truth and and
falsehood differently. So it contracts
with one and dilates with the other and
I don't remember which way it is.
But we have people here who know. So
that's
there's somebody that knows I don't have
to bother knowing because if they know
it's taken care of.
There's many physiologic responses and
of course we're going to do one chart
this morning that demonstrates it. And
um there are many physiologic responses
and of course the reason we use the
kinesiologic response is because it's
quick and easy and I just want to
restate I don't have any personal
investment or personal stake in the
calibrations. I mean it's irrelevant. Uh
if it comes up with something you don't
like
uh forget it.
Yeah, I always get a kick out of the
emails we get because it never dawns on
the critic that they could be in the
wrong.
It tells how come you're wrong and
calibrated something at so and so, you
know, how come you're wrong?
The attitude of the student, of course,
is to learn all they can learn and then
wait to grad school to decide if you're
wrong or not. See?
All right. So we've gone over this chart
many times so I won't go over it again
but it is just a point of reference.
Um
so the kinesiologic response what you're
asking is what is the essence of that?
What is the essence of it? Not what is
the appearance of it.
Okay. So
these may look gorgeous but they may not
be safe to eat. You know what I'm
saying?
All right. So, we'll go to the next one.
And uh
yes, this is just spiritual practices in
general which we have done before and we
won't we'll get to the new slides later.
Uh this is just to give you a
calibration, a feeling of spiritual
endeavor.
uh the Lord's prayer 650
uh has to be pronounced correctly uh all
the banana mham gaggorian chant and
Jesus prayer
and saying the rosary
and doing the 12 steps
and the golden rule and transcendental
meditation
and the prayer of Jabz and walking the
labyrinth and
genulection kneeling to pray
devotional acts. So you see where a
person who's literal
doesn't get what spirituality is all
about. So the criticisms that we get of
the work as bizarre as they get are
really limited to people who are limited
their only reality is the pedestrian
linear
uh concrete
world and they're unable to to intuit it
context spiritual reality.
So there's all kinds of things attacking
these things as being unscientific. How
can turning a prayer wheel affect God?
To logic and the skeptic, of course, it
sounds ridiculous
and bathing in the Ganges, etc.
So to the literalist and all this is
meaningless and I advise them, stay away
from spiritology and religion.
If you don't like God, stay away from
him. That's all.
Don't get involved. Okay. Next thing is
there's all kinds of apologies
for what the world calls evil. There's
all kinds of apologies for things that
calibrate extremely low. I mean,
extremely low, bizarrely low. Has it
apologies.
Yeah.
And there seems to be you might say the
human condition is really really the
people above 200 visa v the people below
200. That's really what it amounts to.
The current calibration of mankind
was up to
207.
It now has come down to 204.
Yes.
That is correct. It's come down to 204.
From 207 to 204,
the consciousness in America has come
down from 426 to 421.
And that's correct. Yes. 421. Uh-huh.
So, what goes up can come down again.
And it shouldn't be too difficult
to figure out the likely reasons why.
Yes.
The difficulty with being the difficulty
of trying to cross a a bridge, which
there isn't really a true crossing, is
that above 200 the brain physiology is
different than below 200.
That gives you sort of a limited
expectation. Then to people below 200,
is anything you're saying, does it make
any sense?
No, it does not make any sense. You can
talk yourself blue in the face and they
think you're an idiot.
Is that discouraging?
>> No, it's realistic.
Part of being spiritual is to get real
and stop pretending
that this is a a dance around the maple
this world.
And the difficulty then is the impass
physiologically
that even the brains function
differently above and below 200 and
because of that we get the various
physiologic responses that differentiate
truth from falsehood of which
kinesiology is just the most obvious and
easy to demonstrate.
I mean, you can't ask people questions
and lay them down and run a slit slit
lamp, check check their brain chemistry,
but so this is a very quick and ready uh
way of discerning truth and falsehood.
All right, so that's enough on the
brain.
Uh let's see. This isn't supposed to be
up next, I don't think. Uh
what the heck does this say here? Well,
let's see.
says um
spiritual practices, brain function.
It does say spiritual teachers. I don't
know why, but it does.
All right. Uh we'll get back to that. Um
the spiritual teachers we have
demonstrated and uh we we tried to
provide a list so that people don't have
to poke through a spiritual library.
Uh a spiritual library has thousands of
books in it. and and where which one do
you start? So, let's go to the next
slide because we can come back to this.
We just wanted to to reaffirm
over we have over a hundred bonafide
spiritual teachers.
No matter how exhaustive we make the
list, somebody will find some weird guru
somewhere in Pooky Doom.
Baba Gumpgump.
I say I don't know about Baba Gump.
You got over 105 good ones here. I mean,
can't you find something in English?
How about gum gum?
I was finding a weirdo. I don't know
where they find them. Some closet
somewhere. There's
somebody
who's here from a UFO from the future to
tell us what to do. Okay.
They knew what to do. They wouldn't be
here from a UFO from the future. They'd
know better. Okay, let's go on to the
next thing.
Uh
these Yes. Well, those who doubt the
divinity of uh of divinity,
uh this is just a a reaffirmation
uh that they all calibrate, you know,
850 and and higher. What What's the next
uh I'm screwed up on these things today.
Spiritual writings.
>> Hey, brain function.
>> Spiritual writings is the next slide.
>> Spiritual what?
>> Writings.
>> Well,
is that what it says?
It does say that.
We got a whole another slide of great
spiritual teachers and scriptures.
Therefore,
a person who's really spiritually
committed says, "Look, this has all been
researched already. Pick one that
appeals to you. There is no der of
bonafide spiritual teachings that
calibrate high."
So these books that get a lot of hype in
the media, you know, the latest
discovery, the lost something or other,
something or other, you know, are all
facious. They're all fiction and they
appeal to the adventurous child in us
who doesn't want to face the fact that
it's all very simple, has been written
out for hundreds and thousands of years.
And the point is, you have to apply it.
Oh.
Uhoh.
But it's so much fun to read books and
argue.
We can have theological arguments.
Well, if you get through reading all
this, if you still have any arguments,
call me.
Yes.
Okay. Move on to the next
spiritual practices.
These uh we've done before. This is sort
of a repetition just a reaffirmation of
the calibrated levels of all the
spiritual practices because we're going
to be talking about them today. Uh
what's the next slide after this one?
Oh, oh yeah. So, we were going to you
were just going quickly over the u
fundamentals. So, you pick a good uh
teacher and to me a good teacher uh
fulfills the obligations of the
spiritual teacher. It's not one way,
it's two-way. A teacher, he doesn't
teach all by himself in the middle of
the desert. A teacher by definition is
one who mixes with students and shares
what he's what he's learned and
experienced and knows.
So we put in the obligations of the
spiritual teacher and that is to be
integrous to stick to the truth as he
understands it and has experienced it as
it's been revealed to him. Uh and so
not
Yeah, you can tell a spiritual teacher
by the he he takes responsibility
uh stewardship of the knowledge, moral
moral and ethical conduct.
Pedophilia is not really the indication
of a good teacher.
He doesn't exploit others with money,
sex, telling them what to do, what to
wear, whether to get married, whether to
have sex, etc.
They explain the teachings makes them
available via multiple ways.
Uh and we have a certain dedication a
dedication to the student and to each
other. I never know whether we're having
a lecture or party here.
Neither do you want students to become
dependent on you.
Uh we like to see autonomous study
groups
uh acknowledge the source of the
knowledge and
it has nothing to do with personal
credit. The p the person is not involved
and to share the means of access to the
truth. That's what we're going to do
today. Okay, let's go on to the next.
Oh, I
these don't seem to be the ones I
picked.
Yeah. Provide means of verification of
truth. So that's books and videos and
stuff.
Uh explain the pitfalls along the way.
Um
should be transparent.
Avoid seduction by mystification.
Rejects commercialization.
Maintain simplicity of life. Avoid
glamorization and pomposity.
And to me, a a a Jewish teacher should
be completely transparent.
There's nothing to hide. There's nothing
uh no facade necessary because the
teacher is the reality that has come to
take place and
replace the personal ego that was there
before.
Uh yeah, I am having difficulty because
I can
>> read these things. You want me to read
it?
um spiritual practices. Well,
uh
due to protoplasmic difficulties,
I now have this uh
uh
did we do slide 86?
>> Okay, I see. Now it's making sense.
Okay.
>> Well, all right. All right.
like Sherlock Holmes. Yeah.
All right. This is what we're talking
about today. We finally got to it. I
thought we'd get to it. Uh, how do you
make spiritual practice party? How do
you make it real? How do you make it
real?
We said that in in traditionally
religion tends to get compartmentalized
you know to Saturday or Sunday uh and
then the rest of the week you get back
to reality which is business and you
don't have to feel guilty about about
things that you would if it was Sunday.
All right. So the first the first thing
you want is education. So that's why we
provide a list of affirmed hundreds of
teachers and hundreds of teachings and
writings. Uh so the in the beginning you
you seek education, you explore things
and I also warn people about the
pitfalls. Don't fall off into the
glamour
uh and the mystification and the magic
of new age phenomena
and avoid all that. Avoid it because
number one, it's a waste of time. Number
two, it calibrates below 200. And
thirdly, you can get hooked in it
without thinking that you got hooked.
You say, "Oh, I walked in out there and
and I didn't believe any of it." Except
now you've got a frequency and a
vibration in one of your or chakras that
you didn't have before.
Because they it they collect all kinds
of debris,
spiritual debris.
So then you have to decide
through education to choose the teacher
and uh what is the pathway and what is
the pathway that's con comfortable for
you. I think in a group like this is
pretty eclectic and uh people come from
a diverse backgrounds
uh and they practice diverse many many
different ways. Many of us have been I
was a member of the first Zen institute
in America and
Zen monasteries. We do various kinds of
meditation. We're also come from
Christian and Jewish and Hebrew
backgrounds and Buddhist backgrounds and
every other kind of the Sufis uh all
different kinds of backgrounds.
Uh
eventually you get attracted to one
usually one predominant pathway.
Now the work uh that we've done what
we've trying to tried to do is distill
the essence of truth in all of the
pathways and that saves you a couple of
lifetimes
because there is a core of confirmable
spiritual truth within all pathways. So
instead of fooling around with the
externals, you go direct to what is the
spiritual core that's intrinsic to all
to any verifiable pathway. What is the
intrinsic core that eventually leads you
to the search for enlightenment
and that eventually leads you to the
pathway of non-duality
to let go your attachment to the linear
and to realize the source of your
existence as the nonlinear. H
so the alignment with the pathway the
pathway we we talk about then is the
direct pathway to enlightenment and
according to our understanding according
to understanding according to our
understanding according to this
understanding
the following the direct pathway speeds
up the likelihood of enlightenment more
than 1,000 times just the likelihood of
enlightenment
was so rare that when it had did happen,
centuries went by which it no one became
enlightened. Now the chances are more
than a thousand times greater. More than
a thousand times greater because we've
defined what is the essence of truth
that prevails in all spa pathways no
matter what they are. The truth of the
realization of the Sufi should be the
same as the truth of the realization of
the Buddhist.
your uh little things
>> I'm falling apart
>> just a minute I want to so everyone can
hear you because you're not coming
across okay
>> they heard me say oh glory be to me oh
lord
the culture of narcissism people say why
is the level in America coming down it's
because of narcissism and it's
prevailing more and more of course the
pope noticed that and I agree with him.
Uh, all glory be to me, oh Lord, that's
so funny.
So, you find a pathway that appeals to
you. What is the core and essence of all
spiritual pathways? And you find one
that you feel comfortable with. And uh
well, you see uh well, I guess
I had
What happened to our pathways?
That's the pure. This is the purest of
all the pathways.
Completely nonlinear.
So you you find what you're comfortable
with and you find a teacher that you're
comfortable with whose teachings are
available and who can be corroborated.
Uh I wouldn't study any teacher that I
didn't authenticate and I don't even
read any book. Somebody people send me
all kinds of books and I say this one's
250. Okay, put it on the pile.
the 250 pile and because you don't have
time to read everything and if it's at
250 it's not I mean it's good but it's
not going to get you to enlighten
so you align with the pathway
and then you commit to it and then you
begin to institute a daily routine I can
tell you the routine I followed for a
long time was an hour meditation in the
morning an hour meditation every
afternoon when I was fully engaged in
the world uh with a giant psychiatric
practice
plus in the evening going to one
spiritual group or another and I'd
rotate spiritual groups you know when
12step groups or meditation group or est
uh you know there was always some
spiritual group and you finally get a
sort of a group of people that go from
one uh spiritual group to another uh
that's called keeping holy company which
we'll get to.
So there's finally a commitment that
ends up as a daily routine in which
meditation and we've spoken about
meditation before
and I'll make it I'll just say simply
meditation you can sit and do it
anywhere anytime. Uh the simplest way is
to close your eyes and if you look
straight ahead with your eyes closed
you'll see very tiny tiny little lights
very tiny little fos jeans or something
they call them and uh you look beyond
that and eventually
you you just don't try to do anything at
all except to be with the visual field
in which nothing is happening which is
quite boring and therefore
you eventually uh uh let go of thinking
this And meditation is a whole subject.
Uh and we've spoken about it that the
mind eventually comes to a stop when you
realize that below the mind there's an
infinite space of silence.
The thinkingness then interrupts the
silence. And how to get beyond the
thinkingness to the realization
of the infinite silence that's below it.
This is done through meditation and
contemplation
and prayer and supplication.
The contemplation we've also spoken as a
lifestyle. To contemplate a thing is to
sort of hang in with it, to hang in with
it, to be with it, not to try to do
anything with it, not to try to
understand it, not not to process it. Uh
let's say we take glory to thee, oh
Lord.
Glory to thee, O Lord. All glory be to
thee, oh Lord. All glory be to thee, oh
Lord.
Now you don't have to. There's nothing
to think about that, is there?
Doesn't present anything to think about.
It's more a positioning of yourself
visav life. Huh? Glory be to thee, oh
Lord. All glory be to thee, oh Lord.
Somebody wrote me wants me to say it to
you, oh God. No, I don't want to say to
you, oh God. I want to say to thee, oh
Lord.
Why?
Because if there's a you calling God a
you,
then there's a me. You set up duality
instantly.
If I talk to you, there's got to be a me
separate from the you. It sets up
separation as a premise.
Besides, God is generic. It's been all
kinds of gods, Germanic gods, mythic
gods,
all kinds of gods.
God is very generic.
When you pray, you want to pray to
divinity. Divinity is thee, not you.
What do you say to God? Hey you.
So thee
infers the divinity that is being
addressed.
Glory be to thee.
Why Lord instead of God?
Because God doesn't have anything to do
with you. God exists independently.
Many gods,
Greek gods, Germanic gods,
all kinds of gods.
But Lord relates to you. Means your
Lord. It's not your God but it's your
Lord. Yeah. Whoever chooses your Lord is
your Lord.
So that's personal. The O Lord
expresses tender, tenderness,
mutual ownership, mutual mutuality.
Yeah.
All glory be to thee,
O Lord,
the Lord of all. Then relates to you
directly
in all the scriptures from no matter
what the origin says.
Those who
turn to me are mine.
So now you're saying that you are owned
by the Lord. When you call the Lord the
Lord, now you're
defining the relationship to divinity,
which is not a me and a God, which is
not any relationship at all. Like me in
the wall.
Unto thee, oh Lord. Unto thee, O Lord.
Majest is Lord. The Lord cannot refuse
your intreaty.
I have permission to ask this.
What I just said is true.
Addressed as thee, oh Lord, divinity
cannot refuse the infrin the intreaty.
That is a fact. Oh Lord. Amen.
That is a fact. Oh Lord.
You, oh God, is a separate thing.
And he's not obligated.
He gets off the hook.
He's like, "And God other than God
prayers." He sits up there twiddling
some cherubs on his toe.
Oh, another old you God prayer
to thee, oh Lord. Uh-oh. Now he's got to
put the cherabs down
and open himself because
divinity responds to supplication.
So contemplation is a b a contemplative
lifestyle as I've said before is a very
yin way. It's like your life becomes a
mudra by which your supplication
the lord
automatically responds.
Yes.
>> To thee, oh Lord, you don't have to
worry if God is listening
to thee, oh Lord.
God hears. Resist
to you, oh God.
God is not obligated. Resist.
He's not obligated. He's not involved.
You see, you're talking to yourself.
You're telling to yourself.
All right. So the O Lord indicates
devotion. Devotion. And all the great
the great Krishna everyone. Those who
are devoted to me are mine.
That's enough to contemplate on for the
next couple years.
If you just contemplate that knowingness
and just hold it, eventually you reach a
state of extreme joy.
Joy.
When divinity reveals its essence,
one goes into a state of wonderment
which is paralyzing wonderment.
And after you reach that state, you have
to stop it or you can't function in the
world.
Because as the divinity of all that
exists reveals itself to you, you're
stunned and into awe in silent awe and
the mind never says anything again
on its own. There is no person to think
having witnessed the reality. Yeah, it's
silenced forever.
So contemplation plus prayer. And you
notice I said supplication,
supplication
to thee, oh Lord, do I devote my life.
There's nothing beyond that that you as
a human can say. There's nothing beyond
that. That is the ultimate you can say.
Yeah.
That is the ultimate that can be said
resist.
I like precision.
Oh god.
With humility goes humor. Goes humor.
Goes humor. Nobody thinks of humor as a
spiritual practice. To me, it's one of
the most powerful ones. There's nothing
the narcissistic ego hates more than
being laughed at.
You know it was it Nero that declared
himself God. Yeah he declared himself
God. So he must have said to me oh God
we will destroy all of Rome. Uh to me oh
God.
Uh I think humor is one of the greatest
benefits. it be. Why? Because humor is
always contrasting essence with with
perception.
It's always contrasting how the world
view or you view something and what the
reality is. You know what I'm saying?
And then it's the contrast that makes it
funny. It's the contrast that makes it
funny.
People that are very, very serious about
life all the time are dangerous.
You never know. Did you ever notice
Hitler laughing?
Stalin joking.
Chairman Mayo.
Peasants. Peasants. I will lead you to
freedom.
How many people died on his great march?
The great leader,
what was it? 30 thou 30,000 died on the
trip
Mayo's great trek across you know I
think 30,000
I don't imagine I would call a guy who
would lost 30,000 of his troops just
going from here to there a great leader
I'd call him in for a hearing
you lost 30,000 troops from here to
Phoenix.
I don't think I would call him the
great.
Ah, yes. So, humility and humor.
Humor and humility go together. You see
what I'm saying? When you take yourself
too seriously, you can be carried away
with yourself.
And when you see how imbecillic you are,
makes you laugh. And then you're fine.
dedication to the path. dedication.
Along the pathway, you you become
increasingly aware of beauty. That first
of all, there's the humor. That's the
human perception projected onto life.
And you see the humor of the contrast
between reality and perception.
Eventually, you become very dedicated.
The pathway or the teachings that I
ascribe uh is the pathway to God through
absolute confirmable and verifiable
truth. truth itself. Truth itself is the
pathway to God. Um
there are various ways to the truth of
essence.
If you're devoted to integrity and to
honesty and the truth and the perfection
etc. You become increasingly
uh sensitive to beauty
and the beauty of every of all that
exists.
Become increasingly so
I always advise people become aware of
the beauty of each thing. If you don't
project anything onto it, you see its
absolute perfection.
I think this takes a while for some
people.
Everything
is what what it means is what it is.
So everything is perfect the way it is.
If a shirt is tattered,
I like it that way.
You reach for your favorite shirt.
You're not going to the doctor that way.
You're not going to the doctor just like
that.
All right. So,
she sees beauty uh in beauty. And I see
beauty in in torn old shirts.
Well, it's actually not beauty. It's
attachment. Attachment to a nice old
shirt.
But you see that it's a perfect old
shirt. You understand?
shirt.
>> A perfect old shirt. I mean, it's a
perfect raggedy old shirt. A nice new
crispy shirt. Isn't like a nice raggedy
old one that's been washed 50 times. You
know that yourself.
Isn't that true?
You note the perfection of everything.
And
what I've all, you know, emphasized
almost every lecture is to get beyond
the delusion of cause and effect. That's
a hard one for modern man to get you in
a scientific world to stop seeing things
in terms of cause and effect.
What what happens is certain conditions
increase likelihoods, but they don't
cause them. Nothing causes.
Nothing causes anything. Nothing has a
cause. Everything has a source and an
origin. The s the source in of the
universe is divinity.
out of the godhead
nonlinear godhead. The godhead doesn't
do anything. Doesn't even create
universes.
Out of the godhead emerges the
potentiality
of divinity as creator. The creator then
becomes the source which is present
continuously at all times.
Out of the infinite power of the source,
all existence source
potentiality
actualizes
as an actuality.
Now because the power of the presence is
so powerful,
potentiality actualizes because of the
power of the consciousness of divinity
as the constant source.
You know you have to be get beyond the
idea of a linear universe in which there
was before time then suddenly God
emerged created a linear universe that
starts there stops here and then God
exits. I mean that's a juvenile
grade school concept.
It's because it's seeing
reality as linear whereas reality is
nonlinear.
The infinite potentiality exists beyond
all time. It has no beginning. There is
no first cause. Nor does it have an end.
Yeah. It's not possible for that which
is alwaysness and foreverness to have a
beginning or an end. And I realized that
experientially
at age 12 or 14 or whatever.
I experienced it before that too. but
very vividly
as a young teenager when time came to a
stop and an infinite presence beyond all
description
um
prevailed
and the knowingness was that that which
I am existed before all universes and
will exist after all universes have
disappeared.
That which I am is beyond time, beyond
causation
is not different than infinite love and
infinite power.
And the infinite power of infinite love
is strange because like that which is
the most gentle, exquisitly gentleness
that melts you, it is simultaneously
infinitely powerful and cannot be
resisted.
That which is infinitely soft and
exquisite is simultaneously more
powerful than steel. There is no way you
can alter it in the slightest. No power
power on earth because it is infinitely
powerful. Uh
uh
you note the perfection and the beauty
of all things and then you begin to
notice that each thing is occurring as
an actualization of a potentiality
and there's no cause for anything. So
once you get beyond cause the world your
understanding of the world becomes
transformed.
The spiritual practices in daily life
are assisted by certain things.
This is the practice and certain things
get in your way. So we wanted to list
the things that we should let go of and
the things that we should accept.
To let go of what I've just spoken about
is the idea that there is a cause for
anything. There is that which is
antecedent and then there is that which
is subsequent. But cause is a magical
notion of the mind and it's projected
into the world. You cannot find cause
anywhere in the world. You can only find
sequence.
You cannot find any cause there any
cause there. That's a mental projection.
All right. Um, so you have to be willing
to surrender
the negatives. So we sort of started at
the bottom of the the scale of
consciousness. You have to be willing to
surrender
uh hatred. And how do you do that? By
humility, you surrender to God's will.
How can you what can you say? Why why
would people hang on to hatred? Because
hatred
uh pumps up the egotism, the egotism of
the narcissistic core, the ego. Because
people enjoy hate, people love to hate.
You can see every night on television,
big demonstration, some capital of the
world, throwing rocks, bottles, killing
police, setting fires, looting, etc.
People love hate. Just try and take hate
away from them. Oh boy, you're gonna
have a hard time. Most dangerous thing
is to try and take hate away from
people. They'll kill you.
They will.
They love to hate. And the only way you
can hate is to blacken something and
vilify it. So to get them off hate, you
would have to they would have to stop
vilifying, which again is impossible.
Why? Because the ego gets such a charge,
excitement, and so much energy out of
hatred. It loves hatred. It loves war.
It loves killing. Loves murder,
stabbing, suicide, shooting.
It loves it.
It loves it. Once you see that people
love it, then it sort of changes how you
you you view them. It's an addiction.
They're hooked on hate. Hooked on hate.
And they're always looking for something
new to hate.
And the blogger blogger land is full of
uh something good comes up. The minute
something is labeled as good, the haters
come up.
It's bad to label anything as good. Do
not label anything as good.
Everybody hates good. Everybody hates
successful.
Worst thing in the world is to be good,
successful, rich, famous, any of those
things. And many of the people that way
hide out. You don't see them in the
media. The media are celebrities. That
people are really uh have arrived within
themsel avoid the publicity, avoid the
media, avoid celebrities
and have their own enclaves.
uh closely aligned with hate is the
energy you get out of anger. You see the
energy that you get when we looked at
that brain physiology you get all kinds
of adrenaline you get to swell up with
anger and then you can uh have fantasies
of revenge and getting even getting
even. So our current world
internationally isn't it is one of
hatred and killing and getting even
and this side kills that side now they
have to get even that kills some more
people this side so then they have to
get even
though the world is going down the tubes
due to get evenness
we said it was 207 now it's 204 that's
quite a drop because 200 is a critical
level 205 is is really over the over the
edge or 207 was over the edge and 2044
is getting too close to the edge. Too
close to the edge. Too close to the edge
where we were for millennia.
Revenge then feeds hatred and anger and
uh and blows away slides and everything.
So all I want you to see because hate
you know you find yourself saying I hate
this and I hate that. On the spiritual
pathway you become self-observant. You
become self-aware
and you catch the mind saying that. Now
the reason people don't want to look at
character defects is because they
personally identify with them and that
mortifies them or affects their
self-esteem.
The ego's defects are impersonal. They
have nothing to do with who you really
are. It's a style of thinking, a style
of thinking and expressing. And it's a
verbiage and a languaging that we have
picked up from our culture. You know
what I mean? I hate the color green.
They don't really hate the color green.
That's, you know, picked that up in
kindergarten. Kindergarten is where you
learn all the hate words. I hate
pigtails. I hate this. I hate girls. I
hate boys. I hate teachers.
I hate apples. I hate applesauce. I hate
I hate Wheaties. I hate I hate vitamin
pills. I mean, all the things you hate
when you're a kid, it's a kindergarten
is full of things you hate and kids you
hate.
So, humor, as you can see, when you say,
"I hate something," you catch that that
is a style of languaging that you picked
up from kindergarten.
And uh you try to let it go by seeing
people differently.
Uh you don't have to feel guilty about
character defects because they are
characteristic of the ego. So you don't
want to fall then into self-hatred.
Uh oh, I hate myself for hating people.
Oh, I hate hating people. I hate myself
for hating. I hate people who hate
people.
So you sink into the merrygoround of
hating this and hating yourself for
hating this. And uh the only way out of
it is to transcend it. Yes. You're going
to say something. Nope. Somebody raised
their hand. Okay. They were just
praying. Okay. Lord.
Glory. Hallelujah.
All right.
Resentments. People who are in 12 12
step groups know that resentment is the
one thing that trips up more people than
anything. Uh there is no this I like the
saying there is no such thing as a
justified resentment.
Say what? That's right. Because to
accept God's will means to accept the
karmic consequences that go with
existence.
Yeah.
The karmic consequences that go with
existence. Some of it is just
protoplasmic. Protoplasmic.
I mean, this body is protoplasm. And if
you hang out with protoplasm long
enough, eventually
you see better with a magnifying glass.
The karma of
uh protoplasm.
So resentment then is uh it tends to
smolder and you have to recontextualize
it. Of course those who do the course of
miracles know that what you're asking
for is the Holy Spirit to
recontextualize it so you see it
differently. When you see it differently
you take it's taken out of time and
location and the causality that you
associate with it. When you see it
outside of time and outside of
causality, you see it's nothing but a
phenomena.
Because with advanced consciousness, all
you see is phenomena,
constant shifting of phenomena. The
world is phenomenal, logic. Uh as far as
perception goes, things always changing,
appearing to change. Uh actually,
they're just transforming into their own
the actualization of their own
potentiality.
How to let go of resentments? The
classic way of course is through
forgiveness
and um you can even get car insurance
now that includes forgiveness.
What's that company with the forgi they
forgive you when one accident? The big
black guy with a great voice.
>> All state. Yeah, he's got a great voice.
I love his voice. Every time he comes
on, you know, he's got just a
magnificent voice.
Forgiveness, you know, for accident
forgiveness. So every time he says that
I think isn't that wonderful.
So what you have to do is become
spiritually an alternator
and be willing
be willing to forgive people the
accident.
What is the accident? They said
something you don't like. They did
something you don't like. They believe
in the politician you don't like. Uh but
you're be have to be willing to be at
least up to the level of all state.
Everybody here willing to to be
forgiving of the next accident?
Anybody holding out against all state
contro?
All right. So, when you get honest with
yourself, strict honesty, this is sort
of a style of self-examination.
Strict honesty means that you confront
yourself with the juice you're getting
out of it.
feeling right and feeling righteous and
uh you're juicing the resentment. So the
basis of the ego as we said over and
over is the juice that it gets out of a
certain positionality.
You don't have to give up the
positionality.
You only have to give up the be willing
to surrender the juice that you get out
of it. And when you let go of the juice
you get out of it, then the
positionality drops of its own. If an
investment doesn't pay any interest
anymore, you don't cling to it
tenaciously. You look for someplace else
to put your money. See?
So, when resentment no longer
pays off,
no matter what ego problem you're
dealing with, you're always dealing with
the satis the narcissistic satisfaction
that is being gotten out of it.
You know the political world of today,
you see how everybody loves making else
somebody wrong. You just see the glee.
The glee is the ego juice. See, if you
can find your competitor into something
horrific,
uh people just crow with glee. Oh,
they just crow with the glee of it. They
just love it to find something wrong in
the in the opposition party. It's
hysterical. And they're like they're
like piranha. They're so eager for it.
They jump it and they overinflate it and
exaggerate it, you know, trying to juice
it for every p piece of juice. So the
only thing to let go of a positionality
is is not the positionality itself, but
the willingness to surrender the juice
that you're getting out of it.
You can put it up on on your bullet
board. What is the juice I'm getting out
of that? What is the juice? And is the
juice worth it?
Sometimes probably the juice does seem
like it's worth it, doesn't it?
Well, then you don't get enlightened.
That's it.
Can't everybody get there? I mean, yeah,
be too crowded there. All them
enlightened beings running all over the
planet at one time.
The grass would I don't know if things
would even grow with all that kind of
energy around, you know?
Uh so malice and jealousy, envy, these
all go together, don't they? Uh vanity
and these are all merely ways of
pridefulness.
And how to get over craving and greed,
wanting and desire, those are some
difficult ones.
We said the ju the juice that you get
out of the negative is why you hang on
to the negative. What about craving this
and wanting this?
though that you know you're you're happy
to the degree that you're that your
halves and meet your wants.
When you want practically nothing in the
world, you're happy all the time because
there's nothing you're lacking. Nobody
to be mad at
let go of wantingness then and letting
letting go of desires.
You you'll notice that most ambitions
and desires are not so much for the
thing itself, but for the glamour of it.
And the media have exaggerated the
glamour of everything. You watch shows
on television, they're nothing but
superficial glamour. There's absolutely
no substance to them. The people are of
no substance. They stand for nothing of
any substance. The whole thing is only
about uh transitory appearance.
Transitory appearance.
So you're a big star at a certain thing
and then if you don't match the
transitory appearance demands of the
media now you're nobody. So you never
were anybody I guess because you were
just an appearance
a sailable appearance. Yeah. So
the less you want the less you end up
needing. And then finally you realize
that it really takes nothing to make you
happy. Everything that you need comes to
you. Everything you need comes to you.
And uh either that or Walmart says it
anyway.
Well, these are Dr. Scho's shoes and
they they they're pretty this jacket was
a f present from a friend of mine.
Where'd you get your outfit?
>> Goodwill.
>> She got it at Goodwill.
We do our shopping at Goodwill.
>> That's the truth. You got it at
Goodwill.
>> You see how easy it is?
How easy it is. Back to show shoes. Get
get your clothes at Goodwill.
So, what do you need? Right.
If there's no dis disparity between what
you want and what you have, then you're
happy all the time.
Unhappiness is wanting something,
desiring something that's out there
instead of seeing that what you have
already is satisfactory.
You want to improve something. Yes,
there's nothing wrong with that. That's
aesthetics, isn't it? It's aesthetics.
You comb your hair and you try to look
nice. That's aesthetics. Aesthetics.
aesthetics is you try to bring forth the
beauty of things. So to improve life to
me is to improve its beauty in certain
ways. Um you know put a new thing in
your bathroom so that it looks more
beautiful and is more handy. Uh but your
happiness doesn't depend on that. It's
more your satisfaction with the
aesthetics of life. You become more
aware of aesthetics and the intrinsic
beauty of all things and you stop
craving things and greed disappears
and wantingness disappears and
desiringness disappears because there's
an inner satisfaction with everything
just the way it is. If everything stayed
just exactly the way it is this moment,
would it be okay? Freeze.
Freeze frame. Freeze frame.
Freeze frame. Okay,
freeze frame. Any objections?
Nobody wants to change the world today.
You must have been at these lectures
before.
All the world changers.
All right. Of course, of greater
assistance is to surrender to God's will
and see that life is evolutionary. Life
is not causal. It's evolutionary. You
see it's evolution that creation and
evolution are one and the same thing.
Uh you see that everything is has an
inherent limitation. A duck cannot be a
cat. You know what I'm saying?
The willingness to surrender to what the
available options are. We're going to
finish this chart and then we'll take a
break. We're going to finish this chart
and then we'll take a break. We're going
to finish this chart.
choices depend on situations
and karmic proclivities.
Uh one of the karmic consequences,
karmic consequences is that we are as
humans stuck with the ego and the
problems that automatically go with
having an ego. So we could get a
resentment about that except we say well
that's the price of the gift of life
itself. I would rather be alive and
working on the inherent problems
intrinsic to being human uh than dead.
So to be thankful for life to see the
world as an evolving creation and to
accept that your time here is limited.
You accept the earlier in life you pick
you you accept mortality the better
because of all the psychological fears
at the bottom of all the piles is the
fear of death itself.
And when you get over that one nobody
can really do anything to you.
I know guy says I'm going to kill you.
Well it's your problem buddy.
It's his problem. It's his goddamn
problem. If he wants to kill me,
it's not my problem. It's his problem.
So, he gets that that you picture it
that it's his problem and you can walk
right through the all kinds of stuff and
I've told you some of the things I've
walked through to completely unscathed.
You pull the trigger, it's your problem.
I don't give a damn, you know,
but you got to mean that. I wouldn't try
it if you didn't mean it.
You'll say, "Oh, yeah. Let's see."
Boing. Goodbye.
Intrinsic and and hidden beneath is is
the exquisite beauty and perfection of
God's love, which expresses itself as
mercy.
And that which is merciful is probably
the mercifulness of all of life is
probably the most difficult of all
things to see. The beauty of life you
eventually see. The reflection of all of
life you eventually see.
But the mercy of all of life, that's the
hard one to see. That intrinsic to what
you see is disaster
is divine mercy. Allowing that you the
grace of undoing that negative karma
which would would have put you into hell
and you have now undone it. Thank you,
oh Lord,
for my salvation. Yeah,
through human life, we reach salvation
through the undoing of negative karma,
the adoption of positive karma. That's
one way of putting it. And therefore,
human life is an expression of divine
grace and infinite mercy.
So, we'll take a break there.
Hallelu.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
Hallelu.