The professor is back in the body.
Thank you, professor.
We will resume the lecture.
Finishing up with left brain versus right brain.
This is so fundamental.
Once you understand that, then that helps you with forgiveness.
You're forgiving somebody whose brain does not work.
If their brain worked like yours, then you could hate them, but they don't.
Okay.
Run by animal instincts.
The desire for power, megalomania, having to dominate people.
Okay.
Let's move on to perception versus essence.
The reason it's important, which we'll get to,
the other night on TV came the statement made by a very good commentator.
In the part of the world, he was on the other side of the world.
He said, in this side of the world, perception is reality.
Perception is reality.
He said, in just a couple of words, he encapsulated the entire difficulty
and the pervasive effect of the media.
Because perception, which is what he's, the world considers this to be a reality.
Opinion has equal value with fact, right?
Free speech, right?
Falsity.
Falsity, legally, has the same defense as truth.
Legally.
The Bill of Rights.
The Bill of Rights is probably unconstitutional, and they'll get rid of it, right?
That's my private little joke.
Yeah.
That's just my opinion, right?
Which is a distortion, of course.
Probably emotional and reactive, you know.
And it's also quite mental.
All right.
So perception, then, is what we see and jump to the conclusion.
It's blogger's land.
This is blogger's land over here.
Essence is acceptance, awareness, clarity.
So seeing essence is not really possible until really a relatively high level of consciousness.
It's called the opening of the third eye of the Buddhic body,
in which the third eye opens, and now what you see is essence rather than perception.
It comes as an intuitive knowingness.
Intuitive knowingness.
When you see the Trojan horse, the person with essence knows
they're not giving you a Trojan horse for nothing.
You better look inside, see?
The person in perception says, oh, look at the wonderful Trojan horse.
Look at the sheep's clothing.
But essence tells you that they're hiding behind religion.
They're not doing it because of religion.
Religion is their cover.
It's their Trojan horse, you know.
Out of that, you can get away with more.
So essence, then, is actually sort of automatic.
In the meantime, while we shift from perception to essence,
to the calibrated levels of consciousness,
we have a means now of discerning essence.
We can actually calibrate it.
And the amount of relative truth is compared to an absolute.
Things are seen to be what they are, and not as they appear.
Why?
Because they're not as they appear.
They're not as they appear.
Because the ego projects its motives upon the world, gain or loss.
It sees it as good and bad, and it projects its value and belief,
and therefore meaning, onto the world.
Therefore, the sage says, there's no point in trying to change the world you see
because the world you see doesn't even exist.
The world you see doesn't even exist.
You know, it's all perception.
And if you understand the essence of, you know,
the purpose of human existence, and then you see that the world is perfect the way it is,
optimum opportunity for karmic merit, optimum opportunity for the undoing of negative merit.
This is the optimum environment.
And that's what the Buddha meant when he said, rare it is to be born human.
Yeah, rarer still to have heard of enlightenment.
Rarest of all to have heard of it and then proceed to pursue it.
Yeah.
So the purpose of these classes is to aid and facilitate
the pursuit of the condition of enlightenment,
or transcending the ego altogether.
That is the overall purpose of the content of the lecture, I suggest.
Uh-huh.
Now, perception, then, is a projection of motivations.
It's selective, it's very personal, it's volitional,
and it's attraction and aversion.
Therefore, to constantly let go of your attractions
and your emotions,
and let go of your aversions is one very important way to transcend the ego.
So let go of your aversions and let go of being glamorized by your attractions.
We're going to talk about memes later.
Essence is witnessed, it's impersonal,
it's a revelation, it's a knowingness,
it's a recognition, and it often comes sort of intuitively.
Intuitively.
I tend to go back and retrack reason a lot.
A lot of times, a student just skips the whole thing
and intuitively says what it is.
Oh, okay.
Saves herself 13 pages of typewritten stuff to read through.
Okay, so let's move on to the next.
She goes right to the essence.
Things that influence perception are rather obvious.
What's not obvious is the...
Actually, it's now purposeful brainwashing by the media of the populace.
It is actually intentional, it is not exactly innocent.
It's quite deliberate.
The deliberate programming of the public via the media.
Even Reuters has joined into it, and so therefore, academia fell into it quite a while ago.
The progressive programming of the human mind, my only concern about it is,
is that it's going to injure the capacity of the human mind even further than it already is.
Things that...
The level of consciousness, of course, is the one we're most familiar with.
We know that where your level of consciousness is, is how you see the world.
In a divine state, you see the world as perfect because everything is perfect.
Programming is very considerable with today's world, and we'll get to some of the popular memes.
The set and the setting, the priorities, this is important, priorities.
There's a reason, you know, what I talk about in one of the books there is the processor.
The leading edge of the ego is the processor.
I don't know which book it is, but it's processing, the processor.
And this processing takes one ten-thousandth of a second.
There's reality, there's the world the way it is, you might say.
And this...
And then it's processed.
So the information, there's a one ten-thousandth of a second delay
between the sound of the music and the time you hear the music, let's put it that way.
Now, people hear different things, and I recently read a scientific paper
by a doctor named John Medina, who I have to contact and exchange information with.
And it's called intentional set, that the mind has...
He says the mind has multiple processors, which I'll agree with him,
but they subsume as one primary processor.
You give that which you value dominance.
So the mind has multiple options all the time.
But what happens is certain fields, I call them attractor fields, become more powerful,
and you then begin to experience and perceive and interpret via predominant intentional set.
So spiritual commitment is really an intentional set.
That intentional set then influences the priority of perception with experience in any profession or field.
The mature person in the field, the experienced person, has trained their perceptual set,
so they don't have to tune around the dial to find it.
Their predominant set, for instance, in the airport, the...
What do you call that difficult job?
A difficult job, controlling all the controller in the airport.
Yeah, well, he's got an intentional set that allows him to handle complexity.
Because if you and I tried to go from this bit of da-da-da, this bit of da-da-da, this bit of da-da-da, this bit of da-da-da,
you know, you would break down in no time.
They have an intentional set that gives them the whole program like that.
So spiritual intention then sets a set of priorities.
Your priorities are to see the world.
Through the eyes of forgiveness, through benevolence, through, you know, unconditional love, etc.
So spirituality is merely a setting of priorities of these intentional sets.
And after a while, it becomes habitual.
It becomes habitual.
Other perceptual influences are obvious.
Age, sex, and gender.
And the politicalization of all these things, you see.
All these things have become political now.
I'm starting a protest group, a protest thing, calling it Mother Nature.
I think that's very sexist.
I'm calling it Mother Father Nature.
I have a protest group, men's protest.
Plus, it's always pictured as negative.
You ever watch the weather news?
Mother Nature was raging.
She's got bad emotions.
Not only feminine, but she's raging all the time.
Mother Nature is raging.
So that's my protest for today.
Yeah.
So the glamour, of course, we know about.
And the seduction has also to do with the meaning.
The instinctual appeal.
So left brain, you see, is attracted by different things than right brain.
Left brain, if you remember the guys in the room, if I may be sexist for a second.
The guys in the room, fight, fight, fight.
Everybody runs from the gym.
Fight, fight, fight.
Remember that?
It's kids.
Oh, fight.
The biggest excitement of everybody.
New kid in town, there's a big fight.
Fight, fight, fight.
I know.
I used to be in those fights all the time.
I never turned down a fight.
Every time you move to a new class, there's the tough guy in the class.
Instantly comes the challenge.
I would never turn down the challenge, even though I knew I was going to lose.
I'd just scrap like hell as I could.
And I'd get beat up.
But I was one of the guys.
I never turned down a challenge just because you were going to win.
Anyway, the meaning of the glamorization of things.
Instinctual appeal.
They were appealing to my left brain animal.
Prior experience, expectation.
You see all these things that influence perception.
So when you say perception is reality, you're talking about a very unsubstantial.
Look at all the influences.
Your personal needs will exaggerate.
Things.
How it's presented.
Glamorized.
At the political viewpoint.
Sensual appeal.
It's symbolism.
How it's framed.
The degree of narcissism versus degree of spiritual commitment.
Etc.
You're going to see how narcissism is what the enemy is.
We think it's Islamic totalitarianism.
We think it's atheists and secularists.
And we think it's anti-Marx.
Whatever we might think it is.
We'll find that we only have one critter.
And when we expose him and take off his sheep's clothing,
you'll find narcissism is at the core of all of it.
Core is at the what?
For the good of your spirit, I'm going to kill you.
And then I'll go to heaven, etc.
It's all narcissism.
And it becomes elaborated in the professorial level in current academia.
All right.
Alternate viewpoints of hating people.
People get very upset because despite their best intention to be forgiving,
they still get mad and indignant, etc.
What are some other ways you can look at the situation?
We could say, well, it's sort of a sad mistake, right?
We could say it's sort of naivete.
It comes out of the passion for life.
As I said, if you never cared enough to get mad and hate somebody,
you probably haven't got enough energy to reach it.
You've got to reach enlightenment.
You've got to care enough about life, a passion for life.
You can see people easily duped and misled,
how easily they're programmed and brainwashed.
It's now done systematically.
You see that people are run by karmic propensity.
The energy fields that you inherit as you come into the body are your own,
and therefore you have certain proclivities,
certain attractions and certain aversions,
and certain agreements also,
which you've forgotten about.
Once you incarnate, you forget all that went before.
And it isn't until you leave the body that you remember.
Alright, so, karmic propensity.
Ignorance, of course, as everyone said,
and I say it's ignorance of how the ego itself is constructed.
Many mentally ill people are high up in the news.
They give lectures at universities now.
They have conspiracy theories, you know,
that whatchamacallit never happened.
The, uh, what?
Holocaust never happened, yeah.
And, you know, they're obviously delusional.
Well, when I was younger, we put them in hospitals and treated them.
We didn't appoint them as professors
and they used the taxpayer's money to entertain the troops.
Politically correct paranoid delusions.
Conspiracy theories calibrate.
Well, they're on one of the charts coming up later.
Uh, everybody I ever met who had a conspiracy theory
was suffering from a paranoid condition, you know,
and, uh, I think I told you about a couple of them years ago.
The FBI was always tapping her phone and stuff.
Uh, anyway, so people are mentally ill.
And, uh, it's amazing,
the naivete of the public about mental illness.
That always surprised me as a psychiatrist.
I would talk to somebody so deranged that, you know,
they couldn't put two sentences together.
It's so obvious they were mentally ill.
And people are treating them as though they were a normal person
and only screwed up, you know.
Uh, really, they couldn't understand.
They can't understand it.
Even now, the leaders,
practically every dictator calibrates,
uh, you know, 90 to 180 in there.
Uh, they're all suffering from grandiose megalomania.
And the condition they have
is what we used to treat with penicillin.
It was called cerebral syphilis.
And they all ended up with granite.
We had all kinds of Jesuses and Napoleons.
And, uh...
And now you can be the leader.
Leader of a great country.
And you get up there and you talk about the Holocaust.
I mean, you know, it's documented.
You can see it on television.
Of course, that may be funny because, you know,
after World War II, as a psychiatrist,
I had to interview many Holocaust survivors
because they got compensation.
Those who had been, uh, uh, injured by it,
uh, PTSD, various things.
With the government, the...
I think it was the German government,
uh, those who had been in concentration camps
were entitled to compensation.
And so I had the chance to interview many hundreds of them.
Uh, the doctor had to give a report,
uh, you know, verifying the person's experience.
So not only is it documented in the world history,
but I personally interviewed many
of them as well as their families.
Uh, thousands of people were person...
had a personal experience.
And here's a guy getting up telling you that,
uh, it's all a Jewish plot.
That's funny.
Medically ill people now run the world, you see.
Now, there's also genetic defects.
There's degrees of vulnerability.
The energy that's dominating.
Uh, most of these people are extremely infantile
and primitive.
They are actually quite atavistic.
You know, Freud postulated
two opposing primary energies.
Uh, eros versus thanatos.
Eros is the energy of life, commitment to life,
desire for life.
And thanatos is deep buried
in the depths of the unconscious.
It's the attraction to death.
The death and the glamour of death.
Every day you can watch
people climb a, uh, high mountain
where, uh, 150 people have died already.
And they can't wait to put their clompons on
and get up there where 150 people
have just died.
Including experts.
Expert guides die, right,
and left the same as everybody else.
They can't wait to get up there.
And it's like thanatos.
The flirting with death.
How fast can you make it around
a gravel road on your motorcycle?
I remember two guys betting each other
if they could make it at 90.
And of course, if you're wrong, you died.
Huh?
This is all, uh, over a bottle of beer.
You make it, I'll buy you beer.
I don't make it, you buy me a beer.
That's a good bet,
because if you lose it,
you don't have to pay them.
The attraction to death
and flirting with death.
I always warn people,
uh, don't flirt with death.
Why?
Because it's,
because it's a, a rejection
of the, um, gift of life.
It's rejecting the, uh,
and the value of the gift of life.
You don't do that with your dollar bills.
Throw them over, you know, with a parachute on them
and see if they'll make it or something.
You know what I'm saying?
But you do it with your human body
for a cheap thrill.
So you have to turn down the cheap thrill
of endangering your life, huh?
There's social coercion, uh,
of course, which is very strong in universities.
Negative emotional states.
People tend to compartmentalize.
They'll believe a whole thing,
but it's compartmentalized personalities,
personality disorders.
Narcissistic megalomania
is like the leader of Iran
and various people like that.
Then there are people
who have unrecognized psychosis,
and many of them are in the media.
The way to get above intention
is just be crazy as all get out
or say crazy things,
and you're ready while you're on TV.
And a lot of people
have an impulse disorder,
and this shows up before age three.
Unable to hold back an impulse.
It shows up in infants.
It's also the basis of psychopathic personality
who's also unable to control their impulses.
So the foolishness of putting a person away
for one deed and giving them no,
you know, short term.
Various commentators on TV
get indignant about that.
Some guy has raped a couple little kids
and all, and he gets 30 days in jail.
Yeah.
And the idea is,
well, he'll get help
if we let him out of jail.
Actually, that's the absolute truth.
I treated a lot of them,
and they were arrested
for maybe one occurrence
of pedophilia or something.
Every one of them admitted
that they had molested hundreds,
hundreds, at least once a week.
That's 50 kids a week.
Oh, you know,
over a year,
over 10 years,
500 kids, right?
Those that were honest with me
a little older said,
it's probably been a thousand stock.
Yeah, you arrest them for one,
give them 10 days in jail.
Because now he's going to get treatment.
Yeah, right.
Yeah.
The average pedophiliac is arrested
is molested hundreds and hundreds.
All right.
So they're driven by compulsion
of lack of education,
psychopathic conditions.
People are purposely misinformed.
Some are delusional.
You know,
the crazy,
the nutty professors.
Then there are subcultures now
who have become delusional,
and we'll get to them later.
Lack of spiritual evolution,
of course,
is the predominant thing.
And then there's regression
and degeneration.
What many intellectual elitists think
is evolutionary is actually degenerative,
and it's regression and degeneration,
not evolution.
Yeah?
All right.
The fact that these things influence everybody
allows for acceptance,
limitation of the human condition.
The biggest limitation is the evolution
of human consciousness itself.
You can't expect people to be,
see things at level 700
when they're still struggling to get up to 200.
You arrive at an understanding,
a tolerance,
and a patience,
a certain forbearance,
and benign.
We all say that mistakes are inevitable in life,
and the willingness to forgive ourself
instead of heaping ashes on your head
that you made a mistake.
It's inevitable.
For one thing,
the mind is,
the processor in the mind
is not that good at prioritizing.
It's,
what it prioritizes is tendencies
but not certainties.
So what you're dealing with is likelihoods.
A spiritually committed person
has the likelihood 90% of the time
they'll try to find a way
to see the person
and forgive them.
But 10% of the time
you won't succeed
and you'll hate the SOB.
In that case,
if you can't forgive them,
then you gotta forgive yourself, right?
Forgiving others doesn't work.
Then forgive yourself
because you're unable to forgive them
because of the way you see it.
And that's why you ask the Holy Spirit
for a miracle.
Please recontextualize this
so I see it in a different light.
See it in a different light.
All right.
So then we'll move on to the next thing.
We never did the great scientists
in any of the books we did.
We did a lot of,
we did scientific theories
and things like that.
But we're talking today about truth versus reason.
All right.
Reason is very respectable.
You'll notice that the great scientists
all calibrate about the same
as the great books of the western world.
So that's the domain.
The 400s is the domain of logic and reason.
Of mathematics,
of very erudite science.
Look at the great names of history.
Aristotle, Sir Francis Bacon.
David Bohm calibrates a little higher
than most of them at 505.
That's the enfolded and unfolded universe.
Niels Bohr.
You see the great names.
Copernicus, Charles Darwin.
Eddington, Thomas Edison.
Edison's 490.
Yeah.
He was a great genius.
See, people envy America.
You know what America is?
America is the product of these people here.
Thomas Edison in one discovery of electricity
created more wealth
than the whole income of other countries.
Just one invention.
Already created great wealth.
Not to mention the computer world, etc.
So the great creativity then
people envy America's great wealth.
Here's the source of its great wealth.
You know?
The inspiration of people like this.
And of course, Albert Einstein at 499.
Euclid.
Michael Faraday.
Sir Alexander Fleming.
Sigmund Freud.
Who was my great grandfather.
I already explained that.
My analyst was Lionel Lovesey,
whose analyst was Cardiner,
whose analyst was Freud.
So Freud is my great grandfather.
Psychoanalytically speaking.
Yeah.
Galen and Galileo.
Galvani.
Stephen Hawking.
Alive today.
499.
Werner Eisenberg,
who really changed the world a great deal.
Hippocrates.
Thomas Huxley.
Jenner.
The vaccination.
Otherwise, most of us in the room
wouldn't even be alive.
We all got vaccinated as kids.
Otherwise, we would have, you know,
probably not made it.
Kekul,
who got an insight into the carbon molecule
in a dream.
That was the snake swallowing its own tail.
And he got the image.
Ernst Mach.
Malthus.
James Maxwell.
Here's the great names of Sir Isaac Newton.
The Newtonian dimension is what dominates us.
The Newtonian dimension calibrates in the mid-400s,
but its inventor was at 499.
He created the differential calculus.
Sir Isaac Newton.
Now, Sir Isaac Newton,
it's a great contribution.
On the other hand,
from the viewpoint of consciousness,
it is also a limitation.
Because this is the world of causality.
This is the world of modern science.
Now, you notice,
Oot Newton,
well, science is in the mid, like, 460,
or maybe even as high as 480.
Sir Isaac Newton calibrated 499.
How is that?
He calibrated higher than his work.
Usually, a person can do that.
A person calibrates at about the same level as their work.
Interestingly,
these great scientists with these great minds,
he was intensely spiritual, religious.
Sir Isaac Newton.
So many of the great scientists
were themselves very spiritual and very religious.
So Sir Isaac Newton,
although he declared the importance of reason and logic,
himself was very spiritual.
Louis Pasteur, Max Planck,
look at all the great names of history.
Semmelweis, childbirth fever,
the infection is due to germs,
Charles Steinmetz,
Teilhard de Chardin, Pierre,
and Ludwig Wittgenstein, yeah.
So these are all in the mid 400s
to the very high 400s.
There you have erudition,
intellectual erudition.
This is where the universities used to be.
The universities used to be in this range.
The universities' academia was in the range
of the great books of the Western world.
Intellectual excellence, elegance,
the rules of logic, etc.
These are the great scientists who shaped our,
and of course they are all greatly honored,
but you see what they created.
What came out of their creation
is today's world,
and what the world envies
is the consequence of their genius
and their productivity.
Move on next, huh?
Let's see.
Okay, can we get it on?
All right.
So we just went through what is integrous,
what calibrates high,
and what has really been beneficial.
What time do we have to stop the lecture?
Huh?
All right, these are,
what the commentators are saying,
is you can't tell truth from falsehood,
and one of the reasons you can't
is because the common belief now
is that it doesn't matter,
that falsehood is just as true as truth.
That's the academic left at 180.
It represents itself as aphorism,
and we should give favoritism
to various groups, etc.
Anarchism and atheism.
So when I say
Daniel Dennett's newest book,
his idea is that
all religion and philosophy
and spirituality is fictional,
and the professors should get together
and start a revolution
to free man from this ignorance.
Uh, yeah.
So in as much as they calibrate around 85,
you can see how we're going to get liberated.
We're going to get liberated from 465
and move to 165.
All right.
Central to the decline of the universities,
and if you do the upper universities
years ago and now,
and now it makes you feel sick,
especially if you're pouring out
a lot of money for tuition,
the thinking this,
the basic thinking this of Marcuse
has infected, you know,
like the universities
and brought them all down.
And they were,
it's represented by a deconstructionism.
Uh, integrity is demonized, you see.
And they brought it down
to dialectical materialism.
The Dixie Chicks who hit the front,
the page of the New York Time,
of the Time magazine at 160.
The unjustified the means is 120.
And of course here's the real dog,
epistemologic relativism,
which we'll get to later,
in which the Pope and I agree completely
that this is the undermining
of our world as we know it.
Eugenics was popular for a while
with fascism.
Secular fascism is 80.
Theocratic fascism is even less, 50.
Islamic militant fascism is 50.
Feminist politics, about which I protested,
mother-father nature,
it emerges as mother-father God, you see.
You know, this is not an understanding
with divinity.
Divinity is non-linear, beyond gender.
Pronoun, he or she,
you're talking about biology.
You're talking about protoplasm.
God is not protoplasm
or limited to gender.
Understand?
To say he, she, God
is worse than saying he, God,
because now you've double genderized it
into some kind of a hermaphroditic bazaar.
Can you imagine a he, she, God,
two sexes fused together?
I mean, give me a break.
So, that's why sexism,
we had a lot of them in America,
in lectures before,
come up and ask about that,
why God's called he.
I said, well, ask them.
I don't know.
Ask it.
You notice in our minds,
we pray to thee, O God.
We don't pray to he, O God,
or she, O God.
Thee, O Lord, do I worship.
Thee.
Thee is a special word.
Beyond gender.
That which is non-linear
could hardly have gender,
because gender is the description
of separate and linear.
Oh, Lord.
So, free speech in the U.S.
as of June is at 180.
Free speech in the world in which I grew up
was World War II,
was 255.
You could disagree,
but you didn't vilify.
So, free speech during the Second World War,
that was the great generation.
The world they lived in,
the great generation,
is different than the world we live in.
It's important to know that.
What your parents grew up in
is not the world that you grew up in.
You can get away with that here.
Here, you would never get away with it.
In the world I grew up in,
people would not get away with
the things they say nowadays.
They'd jerk them right off the stage.
What was that Major Bo's amateur arm?
It even had a hook.
If you came out with something bizarre,
stupid or something,
the hook went out
and they pulled you off the stage.
Major Bo's, yeah.
Hate at 70.
We said,
the last slide tried to show you ways
to avoid hate.
That you should just indulge yourself
with no morality or ethics is at 180.
Iconoclasm is the destruction
of all belief system.
Leads to irresponsibility.
And you notice,
when you call a thing an ism,
it drops.
It drops.
It's one thing to be Catholic.
It's another thing to go for Catholicism.
Because then it becomes a belief system,
takes on political meanings,
and it loses its essential truth.
So libertarian,
see liberty is one thing.
Libertarianism is another thing.
You get the differentiation?
Moral equivalency is justification.
It's really two wrongs make a right.
The New York Times security breach
recently calibrated at 140.
See?
Because it was their own messianic narcissism.
For the good of the world,
we will transcend the survival
of all you peons out there.
They're going to hang with that
until somebody threatens to throw up.
The New York Times building.
And we will see them switch quick.
Nihilism is no truth to anything.
Nutty professors, et cetera, 160.
Passivism, you see,
that's an ism.
Passivism very often leads to defeat.
So it's the politicalization of peace
into an energy field
which relies on force rather than power.
The question authority bumper.
When that first appeared,
I couldn't understand what the hell that meant.
It's a bumper sticker.
There's a question authority on there.
That's part of this whole
nutty professor world.
I would respect authority
rather than question it, you see.
And I would find out for myself
by what virtue are the authority.
So calibrating levels of consciousness
gives you what is the intrinsic authority from,
what is the level from which they speak,
which doesn't depend on opinion,
doesn't depend on propaganda,
doesn't depend on brainwashing.
What is the intrinsic energy of the essence?
All right.
So philosophic theories are,
here's where academia has hit the skids.
It doesn't know it's hit the skids,
but it has badly hit the skids
if you calibrate academia
during, let's say, my generation,
and you calibrate it now.
They're not even in the same range.
So here are the sophistries
which academia tends to worship.
Chomsky, they go in,
they just think it's higher than Jesus,
and higher than,
I've had people send me that,
he's higher than Jesus,
and higher than Dalai Lama.
Here's the very famous,
which a lot of the people you see
parrot all this political garbage,
and they don't even know where it came from.
This is where it came from.
If you think it's true,
then study these people,
and Foucault, Edmund Husserl,
Kristeva, Fritz Kuhn, Jacques Lacan,
Lyotard, Herbert Marcuse.
There's the one who brought down American universities
to the level it's at.
More strongly,
if they were going to be honest,
they would come out at 135,
because if you follow their line of reasoning,
they should come out at 135,
so they're fudging to come out at 150.
Carol Popper is the philosopher
followed by a multi-billionaire
who funds every anti-American energy out there,
and this was his philosophic teacher.
Therefore, it's easy to forgive him
because he was brainwashed at 185,
and he thinks this is his truth.
Bertrand Russell, Jean Sartre, existentialists,
the whole idea that life is ridiculous.
And in our more current world,
Gore Vidal and Howard Zinn, perhaps.
Now, we'll find out in subsequent chart.
How much more time we got?
Five more minutes.
Okay.
Next chart, quick.
Current memes.
Oh, this will give you a step to get excited over lunch.
Perception is reality.
Shepard Smith said that from the Middle East.
He said,
In this world, perception is reality.
Falsehood is truth.
And I say all these professors who tell you
that falsehood is the equivalent of truth,
that's the essence of relativism,
wouldn't mind getting paid with counterfeit money then,
would they?
It wouldn't matter if their check is good
or not, because that's only a point of view.
If one man's terrorist is another man's freedom fighter,
then he doesn't mind if we pay him in bogus bills.
If there is no core reality,
if there is no such thing as truth,
if falsehood is equal to truth,
then why should they complain
if I pay them in counterfeit money?
Then you'll see them put their money where their mouth is.
No.
They do not really believe in that,
because all the nutty professors get big money for their lectures.
University of Wisconsin.
The Holocaust never happened.
Oh, yeah, right.
And so, you get big money for that.
The alliance, you know, in contrast to the ACLU,
I don't know where they went.
I was ashamed to put them up, anyway.
You can understand why the ACLU calibrates,
I don't know,
I'm sorry,
it's 60 or something now.
Its founder, George Baldwin, himself,
was a communist sympathizer and an atheist,
agnostic, etc.
And he's the one that set up the Scopes trial.
The Scopes trial was completely fallacious.
It was all manufactured.
There was no actual issue.
They manufactured it in order to get publicity,
and also get publicity for the small town at the same time.
But the founder of the ACLU,
sort of signaled where it was going to end up over time.
You can look up the books on the ACLU,
and you'll see that that's where it was founded.
It's atheistic.
It's secular.
It hates God.
It hates religion.
And it's always challenging everything.
You know, it's challenging everything.
And here's an actual one that defends freedom,
called Alliance Defense Fund.
You see it's at 480.
So you've got your choice.
You can send your donation to 180 or 480.
It's tact-deductible either way, I guess.
You can send them a bum check,
if there's no difference between reality and bad guy.
So I'm going to make a donation to the ACLU,
and of course it's going to be a bum check,
and I'm sure they won't complain,
because if falsehood is equal to truth,
then why would they complain?
Castro was very much in the news in the 90s.
So here we have one man's freedom fighter.
See, this is moral equivalence.
And this is the basis of error.
A terrorist is not the same as a freedom fighter.
A terrorist calibrates at 90, around in here.
And a freedom fighter is usually a hero.
We're going to see a picture of a real hero at the end.
At the end of this, we're going to give you a picture
of what a real hero really looks like and feels like,
so you get the essence of it.
And it is not Kei Guevara.
So it isn't so cutesy to wear 90 Energy T-shirts around.
Ha!
Look at the university you can do now.
The best they can do is the humanities at 235.
They vacated the mid-400s as a source of truth.
The best you got is 235, you know, being socially helpful.
Ideologues, as I said, calibrated 185.
Why?
Because they confused the hypothetical with the real.
An intellectual construct is not the same as reality.
Therefore, let's say,
for so-called free speech,
you know, we got 10 liners to be shot down over the Atlantic.
It shows a confusion between reality and an ideologue.
He believes that until his ass is on the line,
and then I'll tell you how quick he becomes a realist.
I saw him during the war.
They gave up all that crap in a second.
And they became very, very democratic.
I knew a guy who was a Marxist, you know, in the service.
He was an oddity.
But it's amazing, when the bullets started,
he suddenly became a great American.
Now, you'll see, here's the undermining of academia.
It's what's called intellectual narcissism.
The narcissism of thinking this
and the ability to put together something that sounds pseudo-persuasive,
such as Marcuse and the relativists.
This is intellectual narcissism.
Daniel Danette.
We should get rid of all faith, religion, etc.,
and free the people.
He sounds like Karl Marx.
Free the people.
Opium, you know, religion is the opium of the people,
is what he's saying.
And this is his own intellectual narcissism.
You see it in skepticism as well.
The skeptic says you cannot,
the human mind, you cannot arrive at truth.
And I agree with him.
They then will go on and proceed and give you a big long argument,
which they believe in,
which, of course, they have faith in that.
Well, they just got through knocking faith,
but they have faith in their own argument,
so they negate their own argument.
Intelligent design seems to me a nice way out
for the Scopes dilemma,
religion versus science.
But neither side will take it.
It's obvious, the intelligence of design,
if you've ever watched under a name,
a nature film on underwater life,
you see the incredible intelligence of the octopus
as it changes color to match, etc.
We have to quit in three minutes.
Justification is,
you see what the competition in the world is for besides oil?
Moral high ground.
This is what all the wars are about.
The moral high ground.
A whole country could stop having its citizens bombed and killed
by returning two people that they kidnapped.
Two people.
They haven't returned them yet, I don't think.
And then you can blame the other side for bombing you,
and you were the one that pushed the bomb button.
So there you got the moral high ground,
and, of course, the Middle East right now
is the moral high ground struggle capital of the world
for moral superiority.
Nasrallah, currently,
North Korean leader, his name I can't remember,
he's about 80.
One-worldism is another fantasy.
People of conscience.
Oh, how smug that is.
Oh, you're a person of conscience?
Oh, golly, gee whiz.
I'll tell you,
in the war, if you don't want to kill anybody,
you become a conscientious objector.
You don't desert the country,
become a turncoat,
and begin attacking your country.
You just stay, you don't want to kill anybody.
And then they give you a desk job.
Have you a radio operator?
You don't have to always be killing somebody.
I myself was within conscientious objector,
but I never had, you know,
was put in a position where I'd have to kill somebody.
But the guys on the ship, if I said, you know,
they had another guy on the 20-calibrand aircraft,
and if I said to him,
you know, I just ain't got an enemy to kill the guy,
even if he is a son of a bitch of a Jap,
he would have said, okay, oh, Shorty,
my name was Shorty in the service,
okay, Shorty, I'll take the 20 million,
don't bother me.
And, you know, it was an okay thing.
You didn't have to, you know,
if you said, I just can't do it.
They don't want somebody on the front line
who just can't do it.
You think they want you there?
They don't.
They said, listen, in the meantime,
we're all going to be hungry when we get through this.
How about chopping up the thing and cooking?
They got it.
You can contribute to,
you don't have to become a turncoat.
You don't have to become a traitor.
You can become,
so a person of conscience doesn't grandstand about it.
Political science is 220.
So what's running the academia now?
It used to be in the mid-400s.
It's now in 175, 185.
At its highest, it's 235.
Political science at 220.
President of Iran,
it's at 80, by the way.
I can't write his name out.
President of Iran,
does your write out his name?
You got plenty of ink in the pen.
So I just said,
President of Iran,
Social science at 240.
Sociology, 260.
Now, you notice the difference
between the Encyclopedia Britannica and Wikipedia.
Wikipedia calibrates at 280.
Encyclopedia Britannica is at 460.
When I looked up information on the history of Islam and all,
I actually really studied it quite seriously.
I used the sources of information,
things that were printed before the Cold War,
before the current era.
I want the history of Islam before current contention about it.
So I have, for instance,
written in 1911 by a student of the Vatican.
Encyclopedia Britannica as I ever printed in the late 80s.
And so I wanted information that was unprejudiced,
unslanted by current things.
So what I write up,
I write up as the history of our Islam.
In the book Truth Versus Falsehood,
I got it from sources that were,
as far as I was concerned,
uncontaminated.
There wasn't any contention at that time.
So these things are drummed into your head.
There's a channel that drums these memes into your head.
One worldism, all this stuff.
One man's terrorist is another man's freedom fighter,
comes on repetitiously,
on certain TV channels.
Over and over they repeat this.
Why do they repeat it over and over?
Why is it hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of times?
The impact in our society is that Reuters
will not report the truth of anything anymore,
because when you ask them about it,
they quote this.
This is Reuters dictum of truth telling, 185.
You can see why the,
news commentators are in despair.
You can't even trust a news release from Reuters.
It's 185 because they've already screened it
through a political distortion.
One man's fighter is a big difference
between a terrorist,
Lenin was a terrorist,
and a freedom fighter,
a freedom fighter.
So that destruction of the capacity of the human mind
to differentiate truth from falsehood
is what I'm concerned about.
That if you're brainwashed continuously enough,
you will end up injured,
and your apparatus will no longer be able to filter out
and see things that in my generation
were clear and obvious.
Now you can explain it to a young person
and they don't even see it when you explain it,
because they have been so brainwashed,
I don't even try to talk to them,
because they've been so hopelessly brainwashed,
you would have to decondition them
so they could begin to think again on their own
and respect what is logic,
and the counterfeit dollar bill
is not as good as the real one.
So we'll meet again after lunch,
and thank you so much.
Okie doke.
Well, that's enough of truth for a guy's sake.
I don't want to ruin people's lunch.
Common belief systems.
A meme is a slogan that's repeated so often
that it becomes uncritically accepted as truth
and realigns your orientation towards reality,
so it's not exactly innocent or benign.
Conscious people shouldn't be aware
of what they're being programmed with,
and if in doubt, you calibrate it,
or if you can't calibrate it, find somebody who can,
or you email us, we'll calibrate it, I'll tell you.
Because the way to God through devotion to truth
is sort of a unique,
way of expressing it, expressing it.
It stands a lot of the traditional
ecclesiastic trappings
and belief systems
and various things that go with it.
So it's really, you might say,
a way to God for the modern mind.
It's designed for the modern mind,
which is also scientific and reasonable,
and feels better if things could also be explained
in a logical form.
And by seeing that spiritual reality
as just a different paradigm,
but it's along the same scale of truth,
is really quite a big help
to that intellectual block.
So let's go back.
We're going to not lecture as long this afternoon.
We need more time for questions and answers.
And if you have questions and answers,
maybe even during the lecture,
we'll answer them if we can.
Because this is your own group and your own people,
and we're all evolving,
and we're all evolving together.
We're all in the same boat.
We're like a bunch of birds
that tend to swoop onto this planet together,
and we're all going to be swooping off together, you know?
And in that time scale,
50 years one way or the other,
it doesn't count, you know what I mean?
A few birds get to the island first,
and some get there belatedly,
but generally you can see,
because we're all here right now,
obviously we belong to some kind of
large overall grouping, you know?
I've never asked that before.
All of us here present belong to
a karmically comparable migration of birds.
Yeah, we're all a grouping, huh?
We come on the planet together,
we evolve for a while,
share a lot of stuff,
and then we go back on the other side,
and then we come back on again.
So we've all been together before.
Isn't that nice to know?
Yeah.
I thought I remembered that one guy from...
1492, I think it was.
And I've always had that intuitive knowingness,
that we come out and we somehow swoop.
Like tends to go to like, you see?
So we're all like in our essence.
And of course, some are bigger birds than other birds.
Some have better feathers and all.
Which of course is not fair, but...
Somebody's got to be called shorty.
You know what I mean?
So I volunteered.
I volunteered.
They said, we need a few more shorties
before we go back to the planet.
I said, okay, I'll be a shorty.
Yeah.
So we're all here of our own free will.
Let's make sure of that one.
Nobody's here.
We're all here of our own free will.
Okay, we're all here of our own free will,
having chosen to incarnate,
having had an option,
and having chosen what we thought was
of the greatest spiritual merit or benefit.
And therefore, we're a pretty committed group,
even on the other side.
Yes.
We're a pretty committed group,
even on the other side.
Yeah.
They're happy to hang out, you know,
in a very comfortable heavenly space.
As we said, there's a lot of areas of heaven.
And we don't hang out in lazy heaven.
That's all them lazy ones,
just hang out there, listen to music,
listen to the angels sing, you know,
having a good time.
And then there's us worker bees, you know.
The consciousness level of mankind is currently 205.
It was up to 207.
Anyway, it's at 205.
And we know who's responsible, don't we?
Well, maybe if we hate them enough,
it'll go back up again.
So, anyway, somebody out there is dragging their feet,
and we'll have to speak to them
when we find out who they are.
Except they can't spell their name.
Okay.
Where were we on these things?
93.
Oh, yes, 93.
Okay.
We have time.
Now, is there anything we brought up?
I want 93.
Okay.
Is there anything we brought up
that you have a question about?
That's useful.
There, that's a good slide.
This was the last one?
Yes.
Okay, that's memes.
I just wanted to make sure we were done with memes.
Because it's hard to be aware
that you're being programmed
when you're being programmed.
Yeah, we did perception is reality.
See, that's what triggered this slide.
When he came out and said, you know,
and this is part of the world,
perception is reality, I thought,
yo, yo.
And that's perception.
Then we have lack of intellectual integrity.
That's different.
That's not perception.
That's belief system.
What's undermining academia is not perception,
but philosophic theories, you see.
Is this the last one before the last?
Yes.
Oh, okay.
All right.
We just wanted to see,
what is the world we're looking at?
Well, to reach a more advanced level of consciousness,
you have to be aware of what the traps are.
And this is one of the current traps.
The reason this is a trap is because it's not just devoted
to somebody sitting in the back of the library
looking up some French relativistic philosopher
to report on in class.
This is part of the media barrage.
This is the media barrage that hits you
thousands of times a day, unknowingly.
So, in other words,
the idea of being brainwashed without your permission,
without your permission.
Would you like, you know, if you said to me,
would you like to be brainwashed
with something that calibrates the lesson of truth?
Most people would say no,
but they eagerly flip the switch on the TV
from one brainwash to another.
So, the purpose is merely to be aware
that this is a phenomenon,
that other generations didn't have to grow up in.
You see, the Ku Klux Klan was pretty overt.
You weren't being subtly reprogrammed.
It was very out there, very, very blatant.
And Nazism, all the things that were fallacious
in that generation, wasn't surreptitious.
The propaganda courts,
the propaganda minister of the Nazi regime
was an expert.
And...
And his directions are being followed today.
In fact, the far left actually followed his directions,
that if you repeat a lie often enough,
the mind will begin to believe that it's truth.
So, to become aware when you're being programmed,
when you hear some kind of a theme
repeated over and over again,
you know, I watch the History Channel
and the International History Channel,
and you hear some of these things repeated so often,
just be aware.
So, as you get more advanced in consciousness
and get the essence rather than the perception,
you begin to intuit when you're getting brainwashed.
You don't know what's wrong with it,
but there's something wrong with it.
It sounds good, but there's something wrong
with the way it's presented
or the way it's being utilized.
So, sometimes you can utilize
what is taken out of context as truth,
but placed in the context in which it's presented
is no longer as truth.
They're using truth to support fallacy.
This is the subtlety of how to use truth
to support fallacy, and this is one.
You could say, yes, that's true.
This all depends on the point of view,
but that's only part of the story.
By leaving out the other part of the story,
you end up just being reprogrammed.
The moral high ground, of course,
is you're looking at what Palestine
and Israel, et cetera,
you're looking at the whole Middle East.
Who's got the moral high ground?
And moral high ground is sought
because it is then deemed to be justification.
If you can get the moral high ground
and rationalize something,
then you have permission to do whatever you wish.
So, I think that's all we wanted to really say about that.
Is there any questions you have about it?
You want anything clarified here?
Anything that's unclear?
I'm trying to make it as clear as possible.
One thing I like about consciousness calibration
is everybody can understand the number, you know?
That's why I said, if you made the numbers like money,
would you pay $80 to have this guy come and, you know,
would you pay him this kind of money for an $80 lecture?
He gets $5,000.
But you went to the University of Wisconsin
paying your taxpayer money $5,000
to this paranoid, delusional guy who calibrates at 90.
Yeah, if you put it in dollars and cents,
well, no.
Then if it costs you money, no.
If it costs you money, yeah.
All right, so let's see the next one, huh?
Huh?
Next number, Maury.
Yeah, the photo, yeah.
I don't know what number that is.
All right, this was the celebration of the Tuskegee Squadron.
It was celebrated worldwide there,
not worldwide, in the country,
various places in the country a few weeks ago.
This was sent by Nancy from St. Petersburg, Florida,
from the local paper.
It was a big thing on the front paper.
And we got it through the expertise of Robert and our staff,
so that we could show it on a slide.
When I looked at it, I said, wow.
And a friend that was close to us looked at it and he says,
the first time I saw that, he says, what do you call it?
It ran up and down my spine.
What do you call those pimples?
Chills.
Chills, yes.
Chills, chills and goose pimples.
Goosebumps, yeah.
Chills and goose bumps was an instant reaction.
When I saw it, I was stunned by it.
There's something mystical, incredible about it.
This is one of the original members.
He's still alive.
They had their 50th anniversary, I think,
and most of them are dead now.
But, you know, you remember when I went on the service,
it was still racial prejudice,
and the service just assumed that black people
would take jobs such as the kitchen steward or physical.
It's just the way the military was.
I didn't particularly like it
because I grew up in an environment where no such thinking occurred,
but it seemed to be the military tradition,
so I figured, well, whatever it is, whatever it is.
And we lived with it.
But the Tuskegee Squadron, you know,
was the most perfect squadron in the war.
They never lost a single bomber.
Not one.
All black.
Never lost a single bomber.
A perfect score.
And if I was a bomber pilot, that's the squadron.
You know, I'm protecting your butt.
A score of 100%.
Yeah.
So, and the Tuskegee Squadron calibrated at 480,
which is excellence.
480 is excellence.
And this is one of the survivors.
And I looked at his face.
I said, I can't believe this face.
There's almost an angelic, mystical aura that comes out of it.
I don't know if you feel it,
but it's more than just a person.
I can't look at it now.
It makes you want to cry,
and there's something very mystical about it, yes?
I don't know if you see it or not.
There's an entrancing quality.
It's almost like an...
an incarnated angelic being or something.
There's something behind this face.
Anyway, I thought at 480,
that sort of puts the nail in prejudice against black people.
I thought, you know, as far as the military went,
that was the end of that.
Perfect score at 480.
And so there's something mystical about that gentleman.
He's still alive.
And it's still alive.
It was sent to us by Nancy
from St. Petersburg, Florida,
from the front page of the St. Petersburg newspaper.
And then a few weeks ago,
they met here in Phoenix, too,
the final...
So not many members of the original Tuskegee squadron are alive.
So the prejudice, then, against black...
other than Caucasians
is not eliminated by counter-propaganda.
It's overcome by reality.
This guy here is reality.
480, perfect score.
What more do you want?
So the reality of their essence is what wins in the end.
You automatically rise to the level of your own inner reality
without having to propagandize it by favoritism.
I think favoritism towards women and minorities
is insulting and diminishes their achievements.
I think it diminishes their stature.
I think it's insulting.
So therefore, I've never gone for preferential treatment of people.
People are equal.
They should be treated as equal.
And so here you see an equal at 480.
That's very excellent.
That's higher than the great books of the Western world, isn't it?
That's truth plus excellence.
That's really super excellent.
So that shows a transition in our society.
Not due to...
I didn't get there because there was anti-black parades, pro-black parades.
You didn't get here with parades or spiritual protest.
You got here out of the fact that essence stands...
The power of truth stands for itself.
There's something stunning about this person.
I think we still don't know what it's all about.
Perhaps some people will have some visions or dreams or intuitions about it.
I may not know what to ask that's correct.
It's sort of entrancing, wouldn't you say?
Uh-huh.
Okay.
So we'll turn him off because I can't really think and talk when he's up there.
Some kind of an angelic being is all I can...
Because of my mind, you know.
We may have all known for really great periods of time, you know.
I don't know.
Anyway, I thought we would have more...
We're going to close the lecture early and have more time for questions and answers.
But I thought before we do it, sort of like we do on the Wednesday night,
informal sessions, we might just have any spontaneous questions that arise.
Because once we start with the questions and answers, those are individual.
Anybody need a clarification, something that's not clear?
Yes.
If you calibrate at the high consciousness that you are, why do you need muscle testing?
Who said you need it?
Well, I see you do it all the time.
Oh, that's for teaching purposes.
I get the essence of a thing the minute I have the question in my head.
I know about what it is.
But that doesn't help other people.
It's for teaching purposes.
It's because you can bring it from the...
You can bring it into the physical domain.
To many people, it's the physical demonstration that convinces people.
To intuit it and know it, there's many ways of knowing it and verifying it.
And also the muscle response is not the only one.
We're working on research with the pupillary response and other physiologic responses.
I just thought it's interesting that protoplasm knew this from the beginning.
Therefore, the knowledge is buried within protoplasm itself.
And can be revealed again through its exposure through protoplasmic response.
As far as consciousness goes, a person with more advanced consciousness doesn't need that to tell essence from perception.
And thus spots the fakes from the real early in the game.
The real problem then is the narcissistic core of the ego.
Which is convinced it knows, whereas actually it doesn't know.
What it thinks...
What it confuses are beliefs as truth.
Because people believe it, therefore it's true.
Everybody thought the earth was flat.
That didn't make it true, did it?
So...
Prevailing opinion then is not a very good direction of truth.
Because 100% of people can be wrong.
Also we see the consciousness level of mankind in general has gone down two points.
Because it's a logarithmic number, that's significant.
To go from 207 to 205 means that things are not as integrous as they were just a few years ago.
Here in class we calibrated the level of consciousness of mankind many times.
We saw it go up to 207 and now we see it's declined to 205.
A combination of the factors we've been talking about in the last few slides.
And I think the corruption of the definition and capacity to recognize truth is the main thing.
Let me see if that's true.
It's due to the disruption of the capacity to recognize truth that causes the drop, resistance.
Yes, it's so.
So the arm is really a demonstration.
A confirmation.
A confirmation from another non-intellectual domain.
Her arm doesn't think.
And she doesn't think.
I just asked the question.
She doesn't think about the question.
Most of the time I don't even tell her what it is.
The way we do it at home, because she's busy doing something.
And I'll say, what I'm holding in mind calibrates over 500.
570.
575.
580.
590.
I was holding, what do you call it?
Stigmata.
I was holding stigmata in mind.
Are the stigmata real or are they fantasy?
Is it hysterical phenomena?
Everybody looks for some medical explanation.
Some reductionistic, materialistic, rational sounding reason.
Because of the intensity of devotion, it's a spontaneous phenomena.
Of course, Father Pugh and many of the number of mystics throughout history have had it.
They're spontaneous.
It's not conscious.
It's unconscious.
The devotion is so intense with the divine figure that one becomes, begins to manifest
some of the phenomena attributed to the divine figure, you see, intense divine devotion.
So, she doesn't have to think.
When I said she doesn't have to think, she doesn't know what I'm holding in mind.
I'm just saying what I'm holding in mind.
My suspicion was that it's about 570 and up.
Because it's around 570 that the so-called city's paranormal, extra-normal, super-normal
phenomena begin to appear.
And they all occur spontaneously.
I had them going for years.
And I will tell you, they are spontaneous.
Nobody's more surprised than yourself.
The phenomena occur of their own.
Not caused by anything.
It's because of the field.
The potentiality exists within the field.
And then the field, the action, the potentiality becomes an actuality through the power of
the context.
All things manifest by virtue of potential becoming actual when the energy is appropriate.
And, of course, as the Heisenberg principle shows us, intention is powerful.
Intention already influences whether a potential is going to become an actual and manifest
as an emergence within the three dilemmas.
Right?
So,
let's get started.
All right.
Well, probably, all right.
Let's get started here.
Any other questions? Yes? Go ahead, lady. Woman?
Can you elaborate and talk about the 11 days that you surrendered at the thoughts?
I'm going to have to ask him to repeat the question.
Can you elaborate on the 11 days that you surrendered at the thoughts as they arose,
on how those days went?
Can you hear what she's saying?
The 11 days that you surrendered at the thoughts as they arose, how that happened.
Anybody know what she said?
In your personal experience, you talked about you went through a period of 11 days
where you surrendered all your thoughts.
Oh, yes.
Can you elaborate on that?
There's what I call the final run.
I don't know if I put it in previous books.
I think I'm touching it in this book.
There's a final run.
You develop a certain amount of spiritual momentum.
You start doing a spiritual practice.
It becomes habitual.
Then you begin to move forward in consciousness.
Now you're seeing things from a more expanded level.
Now you see things to apply it to that you didn't see before.
Subjectively, you're aware that you can feel the energy coming up.
The commitment to reach the ultimate truth becomes overwhelming.
Everything in your life becomes second to that.
You can't interrupt the meditation.
I did an hour in the morning, hour at night for some 20 years.
Then I quit the world and would meditate really constantly for months on end.
Meditative state.
There comes what I call the final run where you turn off the television.
You don't read anything.
You don't go anywhere.
You might visit some spiritual groups.
But your spiritual practice is continuous.
Continuous.
Every thought is turned over as it arises.
So what you're trying to do in our own language here in the lectures
is realize that which is prior to the processor.
The leading edge of the ego is that little amoeba out there
that is sensing and processing everything.
The reality of the information gathered is one ten-thousandth of a second.
You hear the music one ten-thousandth of a second later.
You play it off the playback.
So the earphones you have on is hearing the music
that just happened one ten-thousandth of a second before.
You're not getting a direct reading from reality.
You're getting the relay, the modulation of it.
As the thinkingness falls away and the silence prevails,
those things that are surrendered to God become more and more profound.
More and more profound.
They come as a revelation.
And the willingness to surrender that.
And that opens for a greater revelation.
So the experiencing of the essence begins to expand.
It becomes greater and greater and greater.
Finally, you come to existence itself.
And the willingness to surrender the desire for existence.
After existence, at least in this would happen in this lifetime,
was everything that is silent.
There are no interdependencies.
There are no entities there.
People talk to entities on the other side of the long left.
There's no one there because it's completely nonlinear.
And it's almost like the essence of existence itself has been transcended.
And now you're beyond either existence versus nonexistence.
That's the one I got at age three.
Existence versus nonexistence was the conundrum of this lifetime.
And you really experience it now
at a higher level.
And I remember, I think I've told you that the knowingness came in.
Now that you are beyond all accountability, all power is yours.
Claim it.
Own it.
All power is yours.
You're not answerable to anything or anyone.
And you've let go of emotional love.
It's therefore, all power is yours came as a knowingness.
And in that state of knowingness was the silent awareness.
That all power is already mine.
So what would I want with it?
It's the reality of realization.
That which I was, was infinitely power, omnipotent, omniscient.
Beyond all time.
And what would be the gain?
But that's the Luciferic temptation.
And that's where Lucifer fell, you see.
He wanted to own the power out of pride.
It's not just the power, but the pride of the power.
So, at that way, then I denied it.
Then what the only thing left, the only thing left,
was the power of the power.
And that's the only thing left.
The only thing left.
All the content of consciousness had been resolved.
Dissolved, surrendered to God.
There was only life itself.
That was the last thing.
The self as the source of life.
And this too, oh Lord.
I realized this too, oh Lord.
This too, oh Lord.
I must surrender to Thee.
And I surrendered life itself.
And then was agony.
Agony, I will not kid you.
It was ferocious agony.
And the experience of dying.
And you go through the death agony.
And on the other side, ecstasy.
The glory of God shines forth.
It's the radiance of all existence.
You see that all of creation is divine.
And you see the radiance of divinity shining forth
out of everything that exists.
And you get used to it after a while.
But in the beginning, everything you look at
almost knocks you over with its beauty.
You see the essence of divinity shining forth.
That's the explanation.
Gloria in excelsis Deo.
Meaning, all that is, is God.
And somehow that same essence shines through
that photograph.
Because I start to go back in the state
when I look at it.
And I'm talking so that keeps me out of it.
When I stop talking and
look at it for half a minute or something
I'll quit talking and you're all frankly
on your own then.
The only reason I repeat this
because the question will arise
is two bumps.
One at 850, which is the void.
And I've tried to give people guidance on how to get across that
because there's nothing written about it hardly at all.
And there's practically nothing written about
the final doorway.
So I write about the two things to which to me
the spiritual literature
the entities who went through them
took the information with them and left.
But somehow in the aura
it was in this aura
because it came forth as a knowingness
it was not a thinkingness.
Somehow in this aura
was already the knowingness of the truth.
Let's see if that's so.
The knowingness was already within the aura.
The knowingness was in the aura.
You won't find the answer in your mind.
You can search your mind
to find that.
But the knowingness
that all fear is fallacious
that's a maxim in Zen meditation.
I belong to the first Zen institute in America
back in the 50s.
All fear is illusion.
Therefore, based on the confidence
that must have come in at a very high vibration
because I surrendered my life to that truth
and walked through that door
I will tell you it was agonizing.
But the agony is brief.
And then on the other side
of the door
is ecstasy beyond definition.
All that is
is an expression of divinity.
In that state
you see the divinity
of all that exists
and you see it shining forth
everyone who exists
just like I thought this picture
the reason I picked it out
is because I think it's easy to see
the radiance of divinity shining forth.
It's almost a mystical state
when you look at that.
I thought it was a gift to me
and I was glad to share it with everyone here.
And I want to thank Nancy from St. Augustine
for sending it to the group.
Go ahead, you were going to ask a question.
Yes, there's the physical brain.
The spirit exists as
non-material.
It's an energy field.
It's an energy field independent
of the physical.
That's why it's a karmic inheritance.
At the moment of birth, everyone already has a
calibrated level of consciousness.
So where did you get it?
Because the spirit, which is non-physical
maintains
that energy.
The reason we're all here together
is because we have a common
sort of a flock energy.
We all
are red pigeons, or whatever we are.
We sense their energy
and we're attracted to them.
So
people say, well, Christians don't believe in karma.
They do. Of course they believe in karma.
They don't call it karma.
What do you think original sin is?
What do you need a savior for?
You're born with a negative karma of man's sinfulness
and fall from grace.
Did you hear of Adam and Eve?
Did you ever hear of the apple? Did you ever hear of the viper?
I mean, sure you got karma. What the hell do you need a savior for?
Laughter
You got plenty of karma.
And after you leave this body, you got heaven, hell, or purgatory.
Christians tell me they don't believe in karma.
No, you don't believe in that term
because it comes out of a different culture.
But you certainly believe in spiritual responsibility
and destiny
and a reality that goes beyond this
particular lifetime, yes?
And I forgot what the question was.
Laughter
Alright, so independent of
once the kundalini, at level 200
the kundalini energy
begins to flow up the chakra system.
It energizes
a shift in brain physiology
to the right brain physiology.
Information is processed
differently. It bypasses the
amygdala.
Instead of responding emotionally
with cannons, fight or flight,
you release endorphins because
you begin to see and experience life as
benign and loving.
That which is benign and loving.
In the animal kingdom, it starts out
with the mother. So the motherhood
is, to me, the source of
experiential love.
The first appearance is through the maternal.
The etheric brain then
exists independently
of the physical body.
When you go out of the physical body,
you're very much who you are.
You're very much aware.
You can see and hear, experience and think.
There's a sense of identity.
And it's totally non-physical.
And you can look down at the physical body
and it's the most boring thing in the world.
You would think, gee, I'd sure miss my physical body.
You don't. In fact, you know,
in it, you're reluctant.
There's nothing attractive about it all.
Why? Because you're complete and total just the way you are.
And you can see
through all kinds of things.
And I like being there because
I don't have to take the train. I can just think there
and I'm there.
If I want to go to Alaska, I just think Alaska.
Bang. I'm in Alaska.
Because I'm in a non...
I don't have to travel.
So having a body is a drag.
You've got to haul it everywhere.
If you want to meet somebody, you think them.
And there you are.
So the etheric realm is very nice.
And anyway,
it's weightless.
It moves the minute you think.
If you think the other side of the room,
you are on the other side of the room.
There's no time delay.
As I say, you have all your faculties.
There's the sense of yourself.
The sense of self goes with you.
And the etheric body
can be seen by their clairvoyance,
of course, people who see them.
The etheric bodies
are spiritual in nature
and they've been named over the centuries.
Esoterically named.
The first one above the crown chakra
I forget.
And then beyond that is the buddhic body
and the
etnic body
and I forget the names of all of them.
I used to know all that.
Esotericism.
But anyway, the chakra system goes on
above the physical body.
There's a chakra here, another chakra here,
another chakra here.
I think the crown chakra is at the top,
but it's not.
Opening the third eye of the buddhic body
means that you get essence
rather than appearance.
The reason I like that photograph I showed
is you get the essence of that being
which is way beyond his appearance.
You know, the appearance sociologically
you'd say, well, he's a black guy to begin with
and he's a military guy to begin with.
Start labeling him and all that.
You instantly get the essence,
the purity, the innocence, the radiance
of the divinity shining forth.
So,
the etheric bodies then
have the same chakra systems.
The spiritual reality
is far more complicated
because you also have the archetypes
you've inherited within the human domain
the archetypes by Carl Jung.
Each of the archetypes
is an energy field within you
and each of those archetypes also has a chakra system.
So, as I've mentioned,
the only problem I really had with spiritual evolution
was the
solar plexus
of the spiritual knight
getting indignant over fallacy
and killing innocent children.
The knight would come up again
back in the crusades
blowing up of innocent children
would set me off with indignation.
So, I had to overcome that
and discover what it was
and surrender that to God
that morality is not up to me
and surrender morality to divinity.
Yes?
Did Lucifer fall
when Lucifer fell?
Did he also
at that point in time
if Lucifer was an archangel
did he have a reduction
in his outstanding
power level which archangels
rank at that 50%?
To tell you the truth, I'm not an expert
on those dimensions.
Because of pride, right?
It was pride
and the power of
overcoming truth
and falsehood.
So the Luciferic sells out
truth for power.
The Satanic sells out love.
So Satan is
war, horror, torture
all that kind of stuff.
The Luciferic is more
preying upon the innocence
of the college students
with that which is fallacious
and having them think that
that's a higher truth
than truths that calibrated
way much higher.
And trying to acquire
the power of
and it's done out of pride.
Because humility would tell you
that the source of truth would be God
and you wouldn't be bothered
challenging God.
I don't suppose I would want
to challenge God.
Yeah.
Give you a black eye.
There's been a lot of prayer for peace
and I have a
problem with that
because of what I've learned here.
So my question is
is there ever
a higher evolution
so that we are not
below 200?
Yeah, you're asking actually the hypothetical
and it's sort of aligned with what is the purpose
of worldly life.
And do I think that if all of us on the planet got together
and prayed for peace we would bring about peace?
I don't think so.
Because that would defeat really divine intention.
If this was meant to be
a heavenly realm
it would be.
The realms that
calibrate 600 and over
are the heavens.
Heavens are 570 and over.
540 and over, frankly.
The celestial realms.
So the celestial realms
if you calibrate at that level
when you go out of body
you are attracted to that particular realm.
As we said, there are various levels
in heaven.
The various energy fields.
And the etheric bodies of entities
as they leave are attracted to the field.
To that which you are.
And therefore
I don't know what Lucifer's problem was
to tell you the truth.
I know it's just supposed to be prideful.
The classic falls are
Satanic and Luciferic.
And they represent different energy fields.
Anything that calibrates
90 or below you could say
is Satanic to begin with.
Serial killers who kill
50 people and dismember their bodies
and eat them and God knows all
kind of thinkable are obviously coming
from other dimensions.
Other dimensions who I don't want
to talk about.
Yes?
What?
You're speaking in a soft way.
Break time.
Break who?
Break up.
One more and then we'll go.
You just mentioned the 12 steps.
How the 12 step program is the real
spiritual authentic integrity.
Yes.
And I noticed
that one of the steps is
made a conscious decision
to turn our free will over
to God as we understood him.
Our will. Didn't say free.
You know I know that one of the real
things of our western civilization
is oh I have free will
to you know create my life to be
free.
They mean his free ego.
Free ego.
So much myself could
learn how to relinquish his
free will and turn it over to God.
It's not free will.
It's will.
We chose to surrender our will to God
asking only for his will for us.
Right?
So what you're doing is
surrendering intellectual arrogance.
We
chose to surrender our will
to God asking for his
guidance. Asking only for
his will for us.
So what you're
changing your
role. You're saying
the purpose of my life is to be
a servant of God
and not the master of my fellow
men. You are trying to control
others. He has no opinion
on outside issues.
He doesn't want to convert anybody to anything.
Any more than I want to convert.
We don't want to convert anybody to anything here do we?
Anybody who needs converting better wait
outside.
I don't want to convert
nobody.
I don't want to convert anybody to anything.
One last and then we're going to
break for the realignment.
Is ascension an option
for all of us
all of our
individualized
selves
as opposed to death?
Ascension being?
Is ascension being an option? It's a karmic option
having earned it.
Ascension.
What?
Ascended being?
I don't know what the question is.
Anybody know what the question is?
Ascending.
Ascending. Everybody's ascending here
or you wouldn't be here.
We don't want any descenders here.
All descenders leave the room
immediately.
All you ascenders
reassemble. We'll do questions and answers
and God bless you for all.
There are several cars parked on Steadley Road
and they could be ticketed.
So if you're parked on the road
up here, there is handicapped
that you can infuse
in our parking lot here.
Just don't want you to get towed.
Go ahead.
Thank you for this opportunity to be here again today.
Hello Susan. Thank you.
Dr. Hawkins. Yes.
My question has to do with
what you were saying before reminding
us of the final gate
when the ego dies and that
experience. My question is
is the, prior to that
event for you,
was the ego
dying in parts
or might that happen to
someone else prior to this
complete death
of the ego?
Well it's sort of sequential.
You're not facing the final door
until you've gone through the ones that lead to the final door.
But everything else
being gone and the mind is silent
there
is nothing left to surrender to God.
You've given control,
survival, you've surrendered all of that.
And
there's nothing left to that which
you consider to be yourself
other than
you're down to everything.
You've surrendered everything to God.
There's nothing left except all of a sudden
it dawns on you, life.
Oh, alright.
And then you realize this too must be
laid down to God once life
itself, the core of what you believe is
life.
And that brings up trepidation.
And then came a knowingness
out of nowhere.
All fear is illusion.
And
the fear of many lifetimes
since the beginning of time
came up.
As I said, it was very, very strong.
Overwhelmingly powerful.
Because you're surrendering the core
of life itself
which all these lifetimes you believed
is the narcissistic core
of your ego, is the source of your life.
And now you surrender control
over your life itself to God.
As I said,
it did bring fear and terror.
But having already
known the truth,
so today I've transmitted the same
frequency to the aura of everyone here.
When the final doorway appears,
annoyingness, you won't remember from where
or what lifetime.
But the knowingness comes forth.
Without that knowingness, you couldn't make the final step.
Yeah?
Thank you.
That's fine.
It has to be a certainty,
an absolute certainty.
Absolute certainty is an energy
that can be sent only by someone
who's actually lived the reality of it.
It can't come from the intellect.
At that level, the mind
is silent, so you don't have any mind
to refer to anyway.
Transmission goes down.
It's the same transmission you get in AA,
for instance.
Your sponsor is somebody who has authority
and lived through it and done it.
And it isn't something he read in a book.
So therefore, he has
the power of the teacher
because it's based on
experience, bitter experience of him.
He learned it the hard way.
Therefore, you give him
the authority that you can
live your life without a drink,
which you don't believe is true.
Seems like one of the
things that I'm confronting
in the ego right now is
the desire for
approval and
the aversion to
disapproval or rejection.
See, approval is associated with survival.
In the tribal culture
of the wolf, the dog pack,
without the approval of the pack, you die.
So it brings up survival,
really. If you don't have
anybody else's approval,
you won't survive.
Therefore, you've got to risk
death by letting it go.
You're not afraid of dying, right?
Give that one up right now.
This minute.
I think I'm more afraid of the disapproval
than I am death.
So then the approval would be
looking for assurance,
looking for agreement.
So it's pride in a way,
isn't it?
Wanting people to like you.
So it's coming from lack.
You don't need anybody's approval at all.
And the less you want their approval,
the more you get it.
I used to belong to a very elite group.
The world didn't know what elite is.
And if you wanted the slightest thing
from any of them, you were automatically out.
You had to be completely
self-sufficient. If you're looking for
a connection, they just
got it like this.
And you didn't get elected to the club.
You can't want anything.
You have to be total and complete within yourself.
Even if you have nothing at all,
then the thing is to be content
with nothing at all.
Nothing at all is a wonderful state.
It's very hard to achieve.
Everybody has something, for God's sake.
To have nothing at all is very hard to achieve.
Try it. See how hard it is.
Everybody screams and hollers.
The family says you've gone insane.
Gave it all away, walked away from it.
He's lost his mind.
That's true.
You see, you can't come from lack.
That which you are is already complete and total.
It doesn't need anything.
It just thinks it does.
It's because it thinks it does,
that it needs it.
So the feeling you need it
is not coming from reality.
It's just coming from a belief system.
And so you have to have the courage to drop it.
And everybody may say you're stupid
and lost your mind.
That's okay.
Tell them my doctor says
that I'm perfectly fine.
It's you folks that are crazy out there.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
Thank you, Susan, for this opportunity.
I have a...
question about children.
Sometimes it's my job
to do the Sunday school at our
Religious Science Church.
And I usually sign up with the teens.
And they're a little easier for me.
But one time I had the young ones.
And as we went around the circle,
we did some kind of
affirmation and then someone brought up
and all those suffering
kids out in the world,
you know, they just brought this thing up
and I said, and they have what they need too.
Also. And then someone said,
but I know they don't,
I know they don't have what they need.
And I said from truth
that, you know, even death
it's okay, you know.
They have what they need until they don't need it.
I think I blew a lot of people's
circuits when I did that.
Maybe you have a way
that I could relate this truth
to even children
who may be seeing
or not even children but adults
or anyone who see the appearance
as the truth.
I think you will at that level though.
I won't. I just have to stop doing that.
It kind of falls on deaf ears.
Okay, okay.
I had one more thing.
I was doing some meditation
and I took my glasses
off and I wasn't thinking
about it at all. Although I do have
this ego desire to not wear these anymore.
But when I was,
I put them down at night and I went away,
went to sleep, woke up, took a shower
came back and said, where's my glasses?
I'd gone this whole length of time
and it was okay to not
wear glasses. And then I got worried
I'd lost my glasses so I went looking around.
That's where they were from. Last night they were sitting on the table
in the other room. I'd taken them off
and I said, without thinking
about wanting to heal my
eyes, I kind of experienced
what it might be like to heal my eyes
for several hours.
Because it was perfectly okay.
How can I trick myself into not being attached
to that?
It's
a very
focused kind of spiritual practice
to surrender a belief system
and to reaffirm
that my reality is
perfect.
Don't forget I had the experience
of out of body a number of times
and I remember you could see, hear
and everything was perfect.
So I realized that
you don't hear and see
through the physical body.
You do it through the etheric body.
Because I was seeing from
up there and the body was down here
and there's been
many tests of that
during surgery and all.
People could see what's on top of the
lockers and etc.
because they were up on the ceiling.
So the reality
then is the capacity
is not dependent on the physical body
and when you identify with the physical
body, then it's limited to the
physical body's restrictions.
Then you are subject to the physical
body, yeah.
So you'd have to surrender that I am not
subject to the limitations of my physical body
because my infinite self
with a capital S is not subject
to limitation.
What you are is not subject to limitation.
It's only subject to belief system, the ego.
Got it.
Thank you very much.
I'm not recommending everybody do what I did.
I was on the edge of the cliff a number of times.
I was willing to
go over it for the sake of what I was
trying to achieve. If you go over the cliff,
you go over the cliff.
Oh, goodbye.
There was that cavalier.
I have a question on
the unmanifest.
Unmanifest?
Unmanifest, yes.
You said existence arises out
of the unmanifest?
Existence arises
Well, yes.
Out of the Godhead arises
Godness. Out of Godness arises
creation. Godhead
is prior to God
God is the manifestation.
So the Godhead is the ultimate
infinite potentiality
of everythingness which then
emerges as the God
and out of that
arises creation.
It seems to me
that if the unmanifest
is the ultimate state
that
it would be non-existence
because it's
neither existent nor non-existent,
correct?
That's what you're saying.
Existence versus non-existence
calibrates around 850.
And it's
a labeling. There's
neither existence nor non-existence.
Those are all descriptive
terminologies.
Yeah, that which you are
is beyond existence or non-existence.
It's not subject to existence or non-existence.
It's that out of which
existence arises.
You don't have to worry about it yet.
Thank you.
Give me a call when you get there.