Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Um, I just wanted to say to you, Susan,
Um, I just wanted to say to you, Susan,
Um, I just wanted to say to you, Susan, that that color is spectacular on you.
that that color is spectacular on you.
that that color is spectacular on you. Oh, you're welcome.
Oh, you're welcome.
Oh, you're welcome. >> Um,
>> Um,
>> Um, >> didn't say anything about me today.
>> didn't say anything about me today.
>> didn't say anything about me today. >> I'm sorry.
>> I'm sorry.
>> I'm sorry. >> No, but I noticed that you had a light
>> No, but I noticed that you had a light
>> No, but I noticed that you had a light blue shirt and blue pants and a tin
blue shirt and blue pants and a tin
blue shirt and blue pants and a tin jacket. Um,
jacket. Um,
jacket. Um, >> go ahead.
>> go ahead.
>> go ahead. >> Okay. My question is um
>> Okay. My question is um
>> Okay. My question is um if my husband and I in my business, I've
if my husband and I in my business, I've
if my husband and I in my business, I've been calibrating. One time on one of my
been calibrating. One time on one of my
been calibrating. One time on one of my the tapes, I heard Nico mention, "Oh,
the tapes, I heard Nico mention, "Oh,
the tapes, I heard Nico mention, "Oh, I've put my workout at 8:50 now." And it
I've put my workout at 8:50 now." And it
I've put my workout at 8:50 now." And it has its own hum. So, but of course, Nico
has its own hum. So, but of course, Nico
has its own hum. So, but of course, Nico might be at 850. So, my husband and I I
might be at 850. So, my husband and I I
might be at 850. So, my husband and I I know are not near that. So, when I'm
know are not near that. So, when I'm
know are not near that. So, when I'm doing my newsletters for the month to
doing my newsletters for the month to
doing my newsletters for the month to send to my accounts, my husband and I
send to my accounts, my husband and I
send to my accounts, my husband and I test them. We calibrate them and we
test them. We calibrate them and we
test them. We calibrate them and we calibrate them until they get to 850 if
calibrate them until they get to 850 if
calibrate them until they get to 850 if there's something wrong. So my question
there's something wrong. So my question
there's something wrong. So my question is someone said to me recently that I
is someone said to me recently that I
is someone said to me recently that I couldn't um calibrate my newsletter at
couldn't um calibrate my newsletter at
couldn't um calibrate my newsletter at 850 because I'm sure I'm not 850 and my
850 because I'm sure I'm not 850 and my
850 because I'm sure I'm not 850 and my So is that possible I guess is the
So is that possible I guess is the
So is that possible I guess is the question. Can you put out you know a
question. Can you put out you know a
question. Can you put out you know a letter with the intention can it be a
letter with the intention can it be a
letter with the intention can it be a calibrating at 850 if you are not 850?
calibrating at 850 if you are not 850?
calibrating at 850 if you are not 850? >> Can you put out that which you aren't?
>> Can you put out that which you aren't?
>> Can you put out that which you aren't? No. You can only put out what you are.
No. You can only put out what you are.
No. You can only put out what you are. >> Yeah. Well information could calibrate
>> Yeah. Well information could calibrate
>> Yeah. Well information could calibrate high. Yes. You can quote the Buddha.
high. Yes. You can quote the Buddha.
high. Yes. You can quote the Buddha. Yeah, that would calibrate.
Yeah, that would calibrate.
Yeah, that would calibrate. >> Well, this would just be a newsletter
>> Well, this would just be a newsletter
>> Well, this would just be a newsletter that you're putting out monthly. So,
that you're putting out monthly. So,
that you're putting out monthly. So, >> is it put out with good intention?
>> is it put out with good intention?
>> is it put out with good intention? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Well, then why worry about it?
Now the intention the intention is uh
Now the intention the intention is uh you know I didn't cure every patient and
you know I didn't cure every patient and
you know I didn't cure every patient and uh karmically also it wasn't allowed but
uh karmically also it wasn't allowed but
uh karmically also it wasn't allowed but my intention was to do all that I could
my intention was to do all that I could
my intention was to do all that I could to relieve suffering to advance their
to relieve suffering to advance their
to relieve suffering to advance their level of consciousness
level of consciousness
level of consciousness and to surrender them to God if I
and to surrender them to God if I
and to surrender them to God if I couldn't do anything for them.
couldn't do anything for them.
couldn't do anything for them. I don't know what they calibrated at,
I don't know what they calibrated at,
I don't know what they calibrated at, you know.
you know.
you know. >> I missed Nico today and I was wondering
>> I missed Nico today and I was wondering
>> I missed Nico today and I was wondering if you would chant a few ohms with us
if you would chant a few ohms with us
if you would chant a few ohms with us today.
today.
today. >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> We have to be out here at 5.
>> We have to be out here at 5.
>> We have to be out here at 5. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Thems are nice, but
>> Thems are nice, but
>> Thems are nice, but >> thank you.
>> thank you.
>> thank you. >> Yep. That's a different uh
>> Yep. That's a different uh
>> Yep. That's a different uh >> kind of a meeting.
Okie do.
Okie do. >> There you go.
>> There you go.
>> There you go. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> We don't have time. They told us get out
>> We don't have time. They told us get out
>> We don't have time. They told us get out of here by five or it's your you know
of here by five or it's your you know
of here by five or it's your you know what.
what.
what. >> Dr. Hawkins, thank you so much for the
>> Dr. Hawkins, thank you so much for the
>> Dr. Hawkins, thank you so much for the gifts you've given us today. Um
gifts you've given us today. Um
gifts you've given us today. Um >> I'm sure I speak for all of us. I have
>> I'm sure I speak for all of us. I have
>> I'm sure I speak for all of us. I have two questions, but I'll just ask the
two questions, but I'll just ask the
two questions, but I'll just ask the more important one. Um,
more important one. Um,
more important one. Um, I have a lot of the the attributes that
I have a lot of the the attributes that
I have a lot of the the attributes that you listed on the slide like inflexible,
you listed on the slide like inflexible,
you listed on the slide like inflexible, rigid, um,
rigid, um,
rigid, um, that's not a joke. Uh,
that's not a joke. Uh,
that's not a joke. Uh, >> the time
>> the time
>> the time >> that's the time. We're okay.
>> that's the time. We're okay.
>> that's the time. We're okay. >> With with respect to mental illness,
>> With with respect to mental illness,
>> With with respect to mental illness, which is
which is
which is >> a quarter to four. So, we're okay.
>> a quarter to four. So, we're okay.
>> a quarter to four. So, we're okay. >> Which is funny because I'm a sober
>> Which is funny because I'm a sober
>> Which is funny because I'm a sober alcoholic and a drug addict and yet I
alcoholic and a drug addict and yet I
alcoholic and a drug addict and yet I have this this inflexibility, this
have this this inflexibility, this
have this this inflexibility, this judgment, these things. Do you have any
judgment, these things. Do you have any
judgment, these things. Do you have any suggestions on how I can sort of
suggestions on how I can sort of
suggestions on how I can sort of >> Yeah, you need spiritual work. Attend
>> Yeah, you need spiritual work. Attend
>> Yeah, you need spiritual work. Attend Dr. Rug's lectures.
Dr. Rug's lectures.
Dr. Rug's lectures. >> I'll see you in November. Thank you.
It said give up the juice you're getting
It said give up the juice you're getting out of that.
out of that.
out of that. >> Don't worry about giving up that. Give
>> Don't worry about giving up that. Give
>> Don't worry about giving up that. Give up the juice you get out of that and
up the juice you get out of that and
up the juice you get out of that and then it will fall away of its own. The
then it will fall away of its own. The
then it will fall away of its own. The problem is not anger, hostility, guilt
problem is not anger, hostility, guilt
problem is not anger, hostility, guilt or resentment. The problem is that all
or resentment. The problem is that all
or resentment. The problem is that all of them are juicy and you don't want to
of them are juicy and you don't want to
of them are juicy and you don't want to give them up. So look at the unconscious
give them up. So look at the unconscious
give them up. So look at the unconscious pleasure you're getting out of this.
pleasure you're getting out of this.
pleasure you're getting out of this. Yeah. And are you willing to surrender
Yeah. And are you willing to surrender
Yeah. And are you willing to surrender that to God and then it disappears of
that to God and then it disappears of
that to God and then it disappears of its own?
its own?
its own? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Hi there.
>> Hi there.
>> Hi there. >> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> I just wanted to uh I can't think of a
>> I just wanted to uh I can't think of a
>> I just wanted to uh I can't think of a question. All of them been answered. So
question. All of them been answered. So
question. All of them been answered. So I wanted to thank you for your work.
I wanted to thank you for your work.
I wanted to thank you for your work. Thanks a lot. Good. Yes.
Thanks a lot. Good. Yes.
Thanks a lot. Good. Yes. >> Give up the juice and it falls away.
>> You don't get a kick out of chopping off
>> You don't get a kick out of chopping off people's heads. You stop stop chopping
people's heads. You stop stop chopping
people's heads. You stop stop chopping them off cuz it isn't fun anymore.
I had to do it. You, too.
I had to do it. You, too. >> Well, we're all evolutionary from the
>> Well, we're all evolutionary from the
>> Well, we're all evolutionary from the era when people got pleasure out of
era when people got pleasure out of
era when people got pleasure out of every kind of negativity, right?
every kind of negativity, right?
every kind of negativity, right? wallowed in it. Yeah. Yeah.
wallowed in it. Yeah. Yeah.
wallowed in it. Yeah. Yeah. >> I'm a psychotherapist and I work with a
>> I'm a psychotherapist and I work with a
>> I'm a psychotherapist and I work with a lot of clients who are referred from
lot of clients who are referred from
lot of clients who are referred from churches to my office and there are
churches to my office and there are
churches to my office and there are moments when I want to integrate
moments when I want to integrate
moments when I want to integrate understandings around reincarnation and
understandings around reincarnation and
understandings around reincarnation and karma kind of into the body of the work
karma kind of into the body of the work
karma kind of into the body of the work that we're doing. And I'd be interested
that we're doing. And I'd be interested
that we're doing. And I'd be interested in knowing, you know, as you read the
in knowing, you know, as you read the
in knowing, you know, as you read the scriptures, in what way did Jesus ever
scriptures, in what way did Jesus ever
scriptures, in what way did Jesus ever talk about that in a way that I could
talk about that in a way that I could
talk about that in a way that I could reframe it for them?
reframe it for them?
reframe it for them? >> To begin with, Christianity says it
>> To begin with, Christianity says it
>> To begin with, Christianity says it doesn't believe in karma. And of course,
doesn't believe in karma. And of course,
doesn't believe in karma. And of course, it does. First of all, you're born with
it does. First of all, you're born with
it does. First of all, you're born with original sin. So why do you need a
original sin. So why do you need a
original sin. So why do you need a savior if you weren't born with original
savior if you weren't born with original
savior if you weren't born with original sin? Secondly, every human being is con,
sin? Secondly, every human being is con,
sin? Secondly, every human being is con, you know, condemned to ignorance.
you know, condemned to ignorance.
you know, condemned to ignorance. There's only one sin in your ignorance.
There's only one sin in your ignorance.
There's only one sin in your ignorance. And after death, you're either going to
And after death, you're either going to
And after death, you're either going to go to heaven, hell, or purgatory. So,
go to heaven, hell, or purgatory. So,
go to heaven, hell, or purgatory. So, Christianity teaches karma plenty. It
Christianity teaches karma plenty. It
Christianity teaches karma plenty. It just doesn't use the term karma.
just doesn't use the term karma.
just doesn't use the term karma. Obviously, you're going to go to heaven,
Obviously, you're going to go to heaven,
Obviously, you're going to go to heaven, hell, or some intermediate realm, you
hell, or some intermediate realm, you
hell, or some intermediate realm, you know, purgatory.
know, purgatory.
know, purgatory. And without without original sin, you
And without without original sin, you
And without without original sin, you wouldn't need a savior. So, Christianity
wouldn't need a savior. So, Christianity
wouldn't need a savior. So, Christianity is a complete expression of karmic uh
is a complete expression of karmic uh
is a complete expression of karmic uh reality. They don't use that word, you
reality. They don't use that word, you
reality. They don't use that word, you know, it's out of the eastern
know, it's out of the eastern
know, it's out of the eastern languaging, but they certainly talk
languaging, but they certainly talk
languaging, but they certainly talk about the responsibility of the spirit.
about the responsibility of the spirit.
about the responsibility of the spirit. What do you pray for? You pray for the
What do you pray for? You pray for the
What do you pray for? You pray for the spirit. So everything has to do with the
spirit. So everything has to do with the
spirit. So everything has to do with the spirit.
spirit.
spirit. Yeah. And the future of the spirit.
Yeah. And the future of the spirit.
Yeah. And the future of the spirit. Uh so all religions teach uh long-term
Uh so all religions teach uh long-term
Uh so all religions teach uh long-term spiritual
spiritual
spiritual uh dimension to one's existence.
Yeah.
Yeah. >> Okay. And reincarnation,
>> Okay. And reincarnation,
>> Okay. And reincarnation, >> that's different than karma.
>> that's different than karma.
>> that's different than karma. Reincarnation is different. And I don't
Reincarnation is different. And I don't
Reincarnation is different. And I don't know how would that be necessary to a
know how would that be necessary to a
know how would that be necessary to a psychotherapy practice unless it would
psychotherapy practice unless it would
psychotherapy practice unless it would just fit a certain explanation. You'd
just fit a certain explanation. You'd
just fit a certain explanation. You'd have to use kinesiology to verify it.
have to use kinesiology to verify it.
have to use kinesiology to verify it. And if they're into that kind of thing,
And if they're into that kind of thing,
And if they're into that kind of thing, they might see the reality of it. You
they might see the reality of it. You
they might see the reality of it. You can use past life regression. I teach
can use past life regression. I teach
can use past life regression. I teach people self hypnosis.
people self hypnosis.
people self hypnosis. You have a question about why you don't
You have a question about why you don't
You have a question about why you don't get along with horses, you know, you go
get along with horses, you know, you go
get along with horses, you know, you go back and you ask the question and wow,
back and you ask the question and wow,
back and you ask the question and wow, you'll suddenly see why you had trouble
you'll suddenly see why you had trouble
you'll suddenly see why you had trouble with horses.
with horses.
with horses. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Took horses 55 years in my life before
>> Took horses 55 years in my life before
>> Took horses 55 years in my life before they kissed me.
they kissed me.
they kissed me. I got a picture of the horse kissing me.
I got a picture of the horse kissing me.
I got a picture of the horse kissing me. Well, that was the resolution of a
Well, that was the resolution of a
Well, that was the resolution of a long-term relationship with horses. So,
long-term relationship with horses. So,
long-term relationship with horses. So, that's meaningful to me. And of course,
that's meaningful to me. And of course,
that's meaningful to me. And of course, I can go into a past life recall and see
I can go into a past life recall and see
I can go into a past life recall and see the whole thing happen. and I realized
the whole thing happen. and I realized
the whole thing happen. and I realized why it happened and you know so
why it happened and you know so
why it happened and you know so >> thank you.
>> thank you.
>> thank you. So you can pull in as much as you know
So you can pull in as much as you know
So you can pull in as much as you know except the the patients level of
except the the patients level of
except the the patients level of consciousness what they can handle you
consciousness what they can handle you
consciousness what they can handle you know and their background. Some people
know and their background. Some people
know and their background. Some people turn you know get up and leave the
turn you know get up and leave the
turn you know get up and leave the office if you mention karma.
office if you mention karma.
office if you mention karma. >> You sound like some kind of a heathen.
>> You sound like some kind of a heathen.
>> You sound like some kind of a heathen. >> One of them weirdo eastern heathen.
>> One of them weirdo eastern heathen.
>> One of them weirdo eastern heathen. >> Hello
>> Hello
>> Hello >> Buddha. Booty types.
>> Buddha. Booty types.
>> Buddha. Booty types. >> Booty types.
>> Booty types.
>> Booty types. >> Hello. Yeah. He once said that Jesus did
>> Hello. Yeah. He once said that Jesus did
>> Hello. Yeah. He once said that Jesus did not mean what we think he meant when he
not mean what we think he meant when he
not mean what we think he meant when he said turn the other cheek. What how do
said turn the other cheek. What how do
said turn the other cheek. What how do you interpret that?
you interpret that?
you interpret that? >> Uh I feel that it's misinterpreted very
>> Uh I feel that it's misinterpreted very
>> Uh I feel that it's misinterpreted very often.
often.
often. Uh he it's interpreted to mean passivity
Uh he it's interpreted to mean passivity
Uh he it's interpreted to mean passivity and I believe it meant something
and I believe it meant something
and I believe it meant something different.
different.
different. Uh
Uh
Uh it means not to return insult for
it means not to return insult for
it means not to return insult for insult. not to return, not to retaliate.
insult. not to return, not to retaliate.
insult. not to return, not to retaliate. So, but it didn't mean necessarily to me
So, but it didn't mean necessarily to me
So, but it didn't mean necessarily to me to lay down and be passive because he
to lay down and be passive because he
to lay down and be passive because he said, "I I came to bring you the sword,
said, "I I came to bring you the sword,
said, "I I came to bring you the sword, not of peace, but of truth." Did he not?
not of peace, but of truth." Did he not?
not of peace, but of truth." Did he not? Well, he he'd bring in you a sword to
Well, he he'd bring in you a sword to
Well, he he'd bring in you a sword to become a passive slacker. Slap me some
become a passive slacker. Slap me some
become a passive slacker. Slap me some more. I love it. You know, no thanks.
more. I love it. You know, no thanks.
more. I love it. You know, no thanks. I think it's a misinterpretation.
I think it's a misinterpretation.
I think it's a misinterpretation. There's more to the story about what it
There's more to the story about what it
There's more to the story about what it symbolizes. See,
symbolizes. See,
symbolizes. See, because now you're forcing the patient,
because now you're forcing the patient,
because now you're forcing the patient, the person to face the full karmic
the person to face the full karmic
the person to face the full karmic consequence of their actions. It's so
consequence of their actions. It's so
consequence of their actions. It's so it's also confrontational.
I can tell a person to keep beating and
I can tell a person to keep beating and meeting me until their guilt is so
meeting me until their guilt is so
meeting me until their guilt is so overwhelming that they have to stop.
overwhelming that they have to stop.
overwhelming that they have to stop. So, it's taken out of context and just
So, it's taken out of context and just
So, it's taken out of context and just what was meant would take some
what was meant would take some
what was meant would take some individual research about it.
individual research about it.
individual research about it. But if you calibrate passivity,
But if you calibrate passivity,
But if you calibrate passivity, uh you'll find it's very low. It's not
uh you'll find it's very low. It's not
uh you'll find it's very low. It's not a, you know, it's not above 200.
a, you know, it's not above 200.
a, you know, it's not above 200. Passivity invites aggression.
Passivity invites aggression.
Passivity invites aggression. And um I don't think it's a spirit. I
And um I don't think it's a spirit. I
And um I don't think it's a spirit. I think spiritual responsibility is a much
think spiritual responsibility is a much
think spiritual responsibility is a much higher thing to stand up for truth.
higher thing to stand up for truth.
higher thing to stand up for truth. Stand up for truth to have the courage,
Stand up for truth to have the courage,
Stand up for truth to have the courage, the conviction to stand up for truth.
the conviction to stand up for truth.
the conviction to stand up for truth. You know, takes you right over 200.
You know, takes you right over 200.
You know, takes you right over 200. So, I don't think you meant passivity,
So, I don't think you meant passivity,
So, I don't think you meant passivity, which calibrates about 180 rather than
which calibrates about 180 rather than
which calibrates about 180 rather than standing up for truth.
standing up for truth.
standing up for truth. >> Thank you. Can we please have a
>> Thank you. Can we please have a
>> Thank you. Can we please have a photograph of my husband?
photograph of my husband?
photograph of my husband? >> Yeah, whatever.
>> Yeah, whatever.
>> Yeah, whatever. Yeah.
>> Sorry.
>> Sorry. >> See, in nature, passivity invites
>> See, in nature, passivity invites
>> See, in nature, passivity invites aggression. Pacivity invites aggression.
aggression. Pacivity invites aggression.
aggression. Pacivity invites aggression. >> One more. I'm sorry. and it triggers the
>> One more. I'm sorry. and it triggers the
>> One more. I'm sorry. and it triggers the predator prey response which is
predator prey response which is
predator prey response which is biologically deeply rooted.
>> The way to get yourself attacked is to
>> The way to get yourself attacked is to run from the attacker and now he can't
run from the attacker and now he can't
run from the attacker and now he can't resist the temptation.
resist the temptation.
resist the temptation. The running rabbit pulls the wolf after
The running rabbit pulls the wolf after
The running rabbit pulls the wolf after him. Even if the wolf hadn't noticed him
him. Even if the wolf hadn't noticed him
him. Even if the wolf hadn't noticed him before, he notices him now. Uh,
before, he notices him now. Uh,
before, he notices him now. Uh, >> hi Doc. I didn't have a question. I just
>> hi Doc. I didn't have a question. I just
>> hi Doc. I didn't have a question. I just wanted to thank you for your teachings.
wanted to thank you for your teachings.
wanted to thank you for your teachings. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
See, passivity is different than
See, passivity is different than non-action. Non-action.
Non-action is something else. But
Non-action is something else. But non-action is also an internal
non-action is also an internal
non-action is also an internal discipline.
Now for non-action to occur, you have to
Now for non-action to occur, you have to be selfless.
be selfless.
be selfless. The karma of non-action.
The karma of non-action.
The karma of non-action. Selfless service is non-action.
Selfless service is non-action.
Selfless service is non-action. Yes,
Yes,
Yes, >> Dr. Hawkins. I'm wondering if the
>> Dr. Hawkins. I'm wondering if the
>> Dr. Hawkins. I'm wondering if the calibrated level that we reach in one
calibrated level that we reach in one
calibrated level that we reach in one life is the starting point for any
life is the starting point for any
life is the starting point for any future life.
future life.
future life. >> I haven't asked that because there are
>> I haven't asked that because there are
>> I haven't asked that because there are there also so-called inner planes. You
there also so-called inner planes. You
there also so-called inner planes. You might leave at one level, but you're in
might leave at one level, but you're in
might leave at one level, but you're in some other plane and reenter. I've never
some other plane and reenter. I've never
some other plane and reenter. I've never asked it. And if I ask, can I ask in
asked it. And if I ask, can I ask in
asked it. And if I ask, can I ask in front of this audience? They're probably
front of this audience? They're probably
front of this audience? They're probably going to know. Can I ask about the inner
going to know. Can I ask about the inner
going to know. Can I ask about the inner planes? You just
>> So, it would be possible to go down as
>> So, it would be possible to go down as well as go up in those inner plains.
well as go up in those inner plains.
well as go up in those inner plains. >> I don't know. As far as I know, whatever
>> I don't know. As far as I know, whatever
>> I don't know. As far as I know, whatever your calibrated level is when you leave,
your calibrated level is when you leave,
your calibrated level is when you leave, that's the dimension that you find
that's the dimension that you find
that's the dimension that you find yourself in because that's what you are.
yourself in because that's what you are.
yourself in because that's what you are. So, you are only realizing your own
So, you are only realizing your own
So, you are only realizing your own reality. You're not going to something
reality. You're not going to something
reality. You're not going to something different than that which you are.
different than that which you are.
different than that which you are. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you. I hope
Thank you. I hope
Thank you. I hope >> if you can only breathe air, you won't
>> if you can only breathe air, you won't
>> if you can only breathe air, you won't find yourself underwater. You'd find
find yourself underwater. You'd find
find yourself underwater. You'd find yourself in an air breathing
yourself in an air breathing
yourself in an air breathing dimension.
dimension.
dimension. >> This last lot is not knowable. And and I
>> This last lot is not knowable. And and I
>> This last lot is not knowable. And and I often we often get the answer that
often we often get the answer that
often we often get the answer that they're not not to mess with it.
they're not not to mess with it.
they're not not to mess with it. >> Hello.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. >> I brought you this gift.
>> I brought you this gift.
>> I brought you this gift. >> Well, thank you.
>> Well, thank you.
>> Well, thank you. >> Blessed me much. I hope it blesses you,
>> Blessed me much. I hope it blesses you,
>> Blessed me much. I hope it blesses you, too.
>> If I can get that sign. Oh, that's
>> If I can get that sign. Oh, that's >> I would love it.
>> I would love it.
>> I would love it. >> Right, honey.
>> Right, honey.
>> Right, honey. >> He has that P. He wants that signed.
>> He has that P. He wants that signed.
>> He has that P. He wants that signed. >> See? Here.
>> See? Here.
>> See? Here. >> Any anywhere you like.
>> Any anywhere you like.
>> Any anywhere you like. >> Right in this guy's new jacket.
>> Right in this guy's new jacket.
>> Right in this guy's new jacket. >> When was this taken?
>> When was this taken?
>> When was this taken? >> Uh October was the last time I was here.
>> Uh October was the last time I was here.
>> Uh October was the last time I was here. >> Thank you. I do have one question.
>> Thank you. I do have one question.
>> Thank you. I do have one question. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Uh today you were explaining as you have
>> Uh today you were explaining as you have
>> Uh today you were explaining as you have before that the revelation of St. John
before that the revelation of St. John
before that the revelation of St. John was received in a visit to an astral
was received in a visit to an astral
was received in a visit to an astral dimension
dimension
dimension and John so so I'm sorry well the book
and John so so I'm sorry well the book
and John so so I'm sorry well the book of revelation
of revelation
of revelation >> he's not called saint
>> he's not called saint
>> he's not called saint >> yes correct
>> yes correct
>> yes correct >> right John the author of the book of
>> right John the author of the book of
>> right John the author of the book of revelation yes
revelation yes
revelation yes >> is is that also true for when people see
>> is is that also true for when people see
>> is is that also true for when people see UFOs or experience ghosts
UFOs or experience ghosts
UFOs or experience ghosts >> I think so well you see there's the
>> I think so well you see there's the
>> I think so well you see there's the child's imagination so it's hard to say
child's imagination so it's hard to say
child's imagination so it's hard to say what in in individual instance it may be
what in in individual instance it may be
what in in individual instance it may be coming from. Sometimes it's astral
coming from. Sometimes it's astral
coming from. Sometimes it's astral projection, sometimes it's out of body,
projection, sometimes it's out of body,
projection, sometimes it's out of body, sometimes it's hysterical suggestions,
sometimes it's hysterical suggestions,
sometimes it's hysterical suggestions, sometimes it's hallucinations.
sometimes it's hallucinations.
sometimes it's hallucinations. And not too not too few of them were
And not too not too few of them were
And not too not too few of them were drinking also when they saw them.
>> That's another fact.
>> That's another fact. There's also posts hypnotic suggestion,
There's also posts hypnotic suggestion,
There's also posts hypnotic suggestion, you know, in a deep trance. And I tell
you know, in a deep trance. And I tell
you know, in a deep trance. And I tell him that there's UFOs out there and
him that there's UFOs out there and
him that there's UFOs out there and here's how you identify them. Next time
here's how you identify them. Next time
here's how you identify them. Next time he comes to my office, he's going to
he comes to my office, he's going to
he comes to my office, he's going to tell me they saw UFOs.
tell me they saw UFOs.
tell me they saw UFOs. So there's mass suggestion.
So there's mass suggestion.
So there's mass suggestion. When people start seeing them, everybody
When people start seeing them, everybody
When people start seeing them, everybody starts seeing them. When nobody sees
starts seeing them. When nobody sees
starts seeing them. When nobody sees them, nobody sees them. So thank you.
them, nobody sees them. So thank you.
them, nobody sees them. So thank you. misinterpretation,
misinterpretation,
misinterpretation, you know, a naive child, you know, it's
you know, a naive child, you know, it's
you know, a naive child, you know, it's not
not
not >> not out of wickedness or something.
>> not out of wickedness or something.
>> not out of wickedness or something. People just, you know, are suggestible.
People just, you know, are suggestible.
People just, you know, are suggestible. >> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you. >> That's a great photo.
>> That's a great photo.
>> That's a great photo. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. It's a beautiful photograph.
>> They have cameras that photograph
>> They have cameras that photograph nowadays.
nowadays.
nowadays. >> Can I get a picture? No,
>> Can I get a picture? No,
>> Can I get a picture? No, >> they have they have uh they have cell
>> they have they have uh they have cell
>> they have they have uh they have cell phones that take pictures.
phones that take pictures.
phones that take pictures. >> I think he's written in this.
>> I think he's written in this.
>> I think he's written in this. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Okay. Here,
>> Dr. Hawkins.
>> Dr. Hawkins. >> They have cell phones to take pictures.
>> They have cell phones to take pictures.
>> They have cell phones to take pictures. I mean, what next? What?
>> I can't get my cell phone to go on or
>> I can't get my cell phone to go on or off. I don't know how to figure out to
off. I don't know how to figure out to
off. I don't know how to figure out to get on and off switch on it.
get on and off switch on it.
get on and off switch on it. >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> it's got all these little buttons on it.
>> it's got all these little buttons on it.
>> it's got all these little buttons on it. I gave up right then and there.
I gave up right then and there.
I gave up right then and there. >> Dr. Hawkins, this was a perfect topic
>> Dr. Hawkins, this was a perfect topic
>> Dr. Hawkins, this was a perfect topic for me and also the question of the
for me and also the question of the
for me and also the question of the gentleman before me because I'm a
gentleman before me because I'm a
gentleman before me because I'm a recovering ghost investigator.
recovering ghost investigator.
recovering ghost investigator. >> Recovering.
>> Recovering.
>> Recovering. >> Oh. Oh, okay.
>> Oh. Oh, okay.
>> Oh. Oh, okay. >> Yeah. And I I've actually your book uh
>> Yeah. And I I've actually your book uh
>> Yeah. And I I've actually your book uh the one I've written all the notes in, I
the one I've written all the notes in, I
the one I've written all the notes in, I was very helpful in that work with the
was very helpful in that work with the
was very helpful in that work with the lower level astral entities.
lower level astral entities.
lower level astral entities. >> Yeah. And those I can testify those do
>> Yeah. And those I can testify those do
>> Yeah. And those I can testify those do exist and they can be very dangerous.
exist and they can be very dangerous.
exist and they can be very dangerous. >> Yes. I'm not saying they don't exist.
>> Yes. I'm not saying they don't exist.
>> Yes. I'm not saying they don't exist. Yeah. I'm just saying a geer counter is
Yeah. I'm just saying a geer counter is
Yeah. I'm just saying a geer counter is not the right instrument to look for.
not the right instrument to look for.
not the right instrument to look for. >> Right. Right. Exactly. Uh something
>> Right. Right. Exactly. Uh something
>> Right. Right. Exactly. Uh something occurred to me when you did the
occurred to me when you did the
occurred to me when you did the calibration with Susan earlier with the
calibration with Susan earlier with the
calibration with Susan earlier with the reincarnation into lower forms. Yeah. uh
reincarnation into lower forms. Yeah. uh
reincarnation into lower forms. Yeah. uh when you first did that and of course I
when you first did that and of course I
when you first did that and of course I can't remember exactly how you phrased
can't remember exactly how you phrased
can't remember exactly how you phrased it but occurred to me it might be
it but occurred to me it might be
it but occurred to me it might be possible that it came up with the yes
possible that it came up with the yes
possible that it came up with the yes answer because it may be possible for
answer because it may be possible for
answer because it may be possible for human spirits if they get low enough to
human spirits if they get low enough to
human spirits if they get low enough to incarnate into the lower astral plane
incarnate into the lower astral plane
incarnate into the lower astral plane >> other dimensions. Yeah, I didn't ask
>> other dimensions. Yeah, I didn't ask
>> other dimensions. Yeah, I didn't ask that.
that.
that. >> Yeah. Okay.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> Yeah. Okay. >> I asked it in the context of the Hindu
>> I asked it in the context of the Hindu
>> I asked it in the context of the Hindu belief
belief
belief >> that you would come back to this earth
>> that you would come back to this earth
>> that you would come back to this earth as a lesser life form.
as a lesser life form.
as a lesser life form. >> So I was contextualize it as the as held
>> So I was contextualize it as the as held
>> So I was contextualize it as the as held by the Hindu traditional religion. Yeah.
by the Hindu traditional religion. Yeah.
by the Hindu traditional religion. Yeah. >> I have Nothing against it. I think it's
>> I have Nothing against it. I think it's
>> I have Nothing against it. I think it's a good idea. If you've been a rat, you
a good idea. If you've been a rat, you
a good idea. If you've been a rat, you come back as a rat. So,
>> what's wrong with that?
>> what's wrong with that? >> That's good. That's
>> That's good. That's
>> That's good. That's >> work your way up from ratness.
>> work your way up from ratness.
>> work your way up from ratness. >> Okay. Well, thank you very much for your
>> Okay. Well, thank you very much for your
>> Okay. Well, thank you very much for your work and that's been a great help in the
work and that's been a great help in the
work and that's been a great help in the work and the research I've done. I
work and the research I've done. I
work and the research I've done. I really appreciate that.
really appreciate that.
really appreciate that. >> Yes. Very good. That's very interesting.
>> Yes. Very good. That's very interesting.
>> Yes. Very good. That's very interesting. >> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much. >> That's very interesting research. You
>> That's very interesting research. You
>> That's very interesting research. You know, Duke University did a lot in
know, Duke University did a lot in
know, Duke University did a lot in paranormal.
paranormal.
paranormal. >> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. >> It's a whole field of its own. Journal
>> It's a whole field of its own. Journal
>> It's a whole field of its own. Journal of Scientific Investigation. You read
of Scientific Investigation. You read
of Scientific Investigation. You read that one?
that one?
that one? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Thank you.
First of all, thank you for all that
First of all, thank you for all that you've done.
you've done.
you've done. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> I've been really blessed by your work.
>> I've been really blessed by your work.
>> I've been really blessed by your work. The when I first read your book, uh I I
The when I first read your book, uh I I
The when I first read your book, uh I I just instantly got a change in my life.
just instantly got a change in my life.
just instantly got a change in my life. compassion came in and judgment fell
compassion came in and judgment fell
compassion came in and judgment fell apart for myself as well as others.
apart for myself as well as others.
apart for myself as well as others. >> Other times the change comes more slowly
>> Other times the change comes more slowly
>> Other times the change comes more slowly and all of a sudden for instance
and all of a sudden for instance
and all of a sudden for instance realizing that ego isn't leading me but
realizing that ego isn't leading me but
realizing that ego isn't leading me but spirit is. Sometimes it's as though I
spirit is. Sometimes it's as though I
spirit is. Sometimes it's as though I look up and I realize something's going
look up and I realize something's going
look up and I realize something's going to happen but ego could not have told me
to happen but ego could not have told me
to happen but ego could not have told me and the spirit just said see it's me.
and the spirit just said see it's me.
and the spirit just said see it's me. I'm working with you. Other times I have
I'm working with you. Other times I have
I'm working with you. Other times I have to really struggle. Today I got
to really struggle. Today I got
to really struggle. Today I got something that I hadn't even realized
something that I hadn't even realized
something that I hadn't even realized and that is I hold on to some adolescent
and that is I hold on to some adolescent
and that is I hold on to some adolescent kind of behavior and I realize that that
kind of behavior and I realize that that
kind of behavior and I realize that that barrier seems to draw my own children's
barrier seems to draw my own children's
barrier seems to draw my own children's interaction with me to be negative
interaction with me to be negative
interaction with me to be negative and we we kind of dance around.
and we we kind of dance around.
and we we kind of dance around. >> You become a fellow adolescent with your
>> You become a fellow adolescent with your
>> You become a fellow adolescent with your own adolescent.
own adolescent.
own adolescent. >> It seems that way you know um and I
>> It seems that way you know um and I
>> It seems that way you know um and I didn't recognize it. I didn't
didn't recognize it. I didn't
didn't recognize it. I didn't >> pull up the adolescent in you.
>> pull up the adolescent in you.
>> pull up the adolescent in you. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> they do. And And so
>> they do. And And so
>> they do. And And so >> rebellion or what?
>> rebellion or what?
>> rebellion or what? >> Rebellion.
>> Rebellion.
>> Rebellion. >> Oh. Huh.
>> Oh. Huh.
>> Oh. Huh. >> In me. I mean, I can feel it coming up.
>> In me. I mean, I can feel it coming up.
>> In me. I mean, I can feel it coming up. And we just kind of do this dance. And
And we just kind of do this dance. And
And we just kind of do this dance. And until today, I couldn't name it or
until today, I couldn't name it or
until today, I couldn't name it or understand it or see where the juice
understand it or see where the juice
understand it or see where the juice was.
was.
was. >> And I'm wondering if it's in me, am I
>> And I'm wondering if it's in me, am I
>> And I'm wondering if it's in me, am I drawing it to me to get it?
drawing it to me to get it?
drawing it to me to get it? >> I don't know. What do you say about
>> I don't know. What do you say about
>> I don't know. What do you say about them? I mean, you tell them they're
them? I mean, you tell them they're
them? I mean, you tell them they're being rebellious and they're being
being rebellious and they're being
being rebellious and they're being rebellious.
rebellious.
rebellious. >> No, no, no. It's it's more other things.
>> No, no, no. It's it's more other things.
>> No, no, no. It's it's more other things. I mean, it's like political arguments
I mean, it's like political arguments
I mean, it's like political arguments and we get in these silly arguments and
and we get in these silly arguments and
and we get in these silly arguments and I think I need to be right.
I think I need to be right.
I think I need to be right. >> I didn't realize that before. I thought
>> I didn't realize that before. I thought
>> I didn't realize that before. I thought they thought they needed to be right,
they thought they needed to be right,
they thought they needed to be right, but I'm thinking I do. And then they
but I'm thinking I do. And then they
but I'm thinking I do. And then they they get it from me.
they get it from me.
they get it from me. >> Well, you can present an alternative
>> Well, you can present an alternative
>> Well, you can present an alternative viewpoint and don't claim it as yours.
viewpoint and don't claim it as yours.
viewpoint and don't claim it as yours. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> That that's what you've heard,
>> That that's what you've heard,
>> That that's what you've heard, >> you know. uh I've heard. The Buddha
>> you know. uh I've heard. The Buddha
>> you know. uh I've heard. The Buddha often did that. He says, "I have heard.
often did that. He says, "I have heard.
often did that. He says, "I have heard. I have heard." And then he presents an
I have heard." And then he presents an
I have heard." And then he presents an alternate way of looking at it. Doesn't
alternate way of looking at it. Doesn't
alternate way of looking at it. Doesn't mean you should accept it. Doesn't mean
mean you should accept it. Doesn't mean
mean you should accept it. Doesn't mean it's my reality,
it's my reality,
it's my reality, but it's presenting an alternate view.
but it's presenting an alternate view.
but it's presenting an alternate view. They don't have to agree with it right
They don't have to agree with it right
They don't have to agree with it right then and there either,
then and there either,
then and there either, you know?
you know?
you know? >> And that's part of just my letting go of
>> And that's part of just my letting go of
>> And that's part of just my letting go of the juice of it, the payoff.
the juice of it, the payoff.
the juice of it, the payoff. >> Huh? And then I let go of the payoff of
>> Huh? And then I let go of the payoff of
>> Huh? And then I let go of the payoff of it all by just saying there's an
it all by just saying there's an
it all by just saying there's an alternative point of view and letting it
alternative point of view and letting it
alternative point of view and letting it go.
go.
go. >> Yeah. That's what I would do.
>> Yeah. That's what I would do.
>> Yeah. That's what I would do. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yes. Many people would say and then you
>> Yes. Many people would say and then you
>> Yes. Many people would say and then you give the other way, you know.
give the other way, you know.
give the other way, you know. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> U I I think education helps so many
>> U I I think education helps so many
>> U I I think education helps so many things because you know we had a chance
things because you know we had a chance
things because you know we had a chance to be debaters, debating teams, debate
to be debaters, debating teams, debate
to be debaters, debating teams, debate club, and you didn't know what your
club, and you didn't know what your
club, and you didn't know what your position was going to be till you pulled
position was going to be till you pulled
position was going to be till you pulled it out of a hat.
it out of a hat.
it out of a hat. >> That's right. And then you began to see
>> That's right. And then you began to see
>> That's right. And then you began to see that you know you can corral
that you know you can corral
that you know you can corral argumentation in the support of
argumentation in the support of
argumentation in the support of anything.
anything.
anything. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yes. That's true.
>> Yes. That's true.
>> Yes. That's true. >> And then that makes you more
>> And then that makes you more
>> And then that makes you more sophisticated and you don't identify
sophisticated and you don't identify
sophisticated and you don't identify with the view then you see that
with the view then you see that
with the view then you see that alternate views is a sophisticated level
alternate views is a sophisticated level
alternate views is a sophisticated level of intellectual.
of intellectual.
of intellectual. >> Yeah. So you want a term to be more uh
>> Yeah. So you want a term to be more uh
>> Yeah. So you want a term to be more uh more advanced intellectually then
more advanced intellectually then
more advanced intellectually then and uh philosophic
and uh philosophic
and uh philosophic encourage the reading of philosophy
encourage the reading of philosophy
encourage the reading of philosophy >> instead of a narrow spectrum.
>> instead of a narrow spectrum.
>> instead of a narrow spectrum. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Right and wrong, good and bad.
>> Right and wrong, good and bad.
>> Right and wrong, good and bad. >> Yeah. You can't really just get right
>> Yeah. You can't really just get right
>> Yeah. You can't really just get right and wrong, good and bad. And also if you
and wrong, good and bad. And also if you
and wrong, good and bad. And also if you see the philosophic position behind the
see the philosophic position behind the
see the philosophic position behind the argument, then you can start addressing
argument, then you can start addressing
argument, then you can start addressing it from the impersonal level of
it from the impersonal level of
it from the impersonal level of philosophic theory, you know.
philosophic theory, you know.
philosophic theory, you know. That's what I do with relativism.
That's what I do with relativism.
That's what I do with relativism. >> Okay?
>> Okay?
>> Okay? >> I just look at the philosophic theory,
>> I just look at the philosophic theory,
>> I just look at the philosophic theory, put it together, and see if it proves
put it together, and see if it proves
put it together, and see if it proves out. And of course, it it collapses of
out. And of course, it it collapses of
out. And of course, it it collapses of its own weight because it's based upon
its own weight because it's based upon
its own weight because it's based upon nothing. But I don't have to attack it.
nothing. But I don't have to attack it.
nothing. But I don't have to attack it. I just, you know, take pull it out to
I just, you know, take pull it out to
I just, you know, take pull it out to its extreme.
its extreme.
its extreme. >> Just reveal it.
>> Just reveal it.
>> Just reveal it. >> I mean, if all, you know, if all
>> I mean, if all, you know, if all
>> I mean, if all, you know, if all positions are facious, then you're
positions are facious, then you're
positions are facious, then you're supporting relativism is obviously
supporting relativism is obviously
supporting relativism is obviously facious, is it not? If all argumentation
facious, is it not? If all argumentation
facious, is it not? If all argumentation is stupid, then everything you're saying
is stupid, then everything you're saying
is stupid, then everything you're saying today is a waste of time. You know what
today is a waste of time. You know what
today is a waste of time. You know what I mean? If there isn't a morality, then
I mean? If there isn't a morality, then
I mean? If there isn't a morality, then why get so moralistic about relativism?
why get so moralistic about relativism?
why get so moralistic about relativism? >> So, in other words, the same as the
>> So, in other words, the same as the
>> So, in other words, the same as the skeptic, you know, the skeptic says you
skeptic, you know, the skeptic says you
skeptic, you know, the skeptic says you can't believe anything the human mind
can't believe anything the human mind
can't believe anything the human mind says except what he says,
says except what he says,
says except what he says, in which case it's the truth. Right? So,
in which case it's the truth. Right? So,
in which case it's the truth. Right? So, the skeptic is not skeptic of all about
the skeptic is not skeptic of all about
the skeptic is not skeptic of all about his own skepticism. So, he's stupid and
his own skepticism. So, he's stupid and
his own skepticism. So, he's stupid and he's hung by his own petard. So I try to
he's hung by his own petard. So I try to
he's hung by his own petard. So I try to hang him up with his own petard.
hang him up with his own petard.
hang him up with his own petard. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> If there's no truth in argumentation,
>> If there's no truth in argumentation,
>> If there's no truth in argumentation, then you've just wasted 10 minutes of my
then you've just wasted 10 minutes of my
then you've just wasted 10 minutes of my time because your argumentation is
time because your argumentation is
time because your argumentation is stupid also. You know what I mean?
>> Can I have a picture taken?
>> Can I have a picture taken? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Thank you. Well, thank you.
>> Thank you. Well, thank you.
>> Thank you. Well, thank you. >> My daughter says, "Don't argue with him.
>> My daughter says, "Don't argue with him.
>> My daughter says, "Don't argue with him. You'll never win."
Well, the human mind is convinced that
Well, the human mind is convinced that its view of the world is the real one. E
its view of the world is the real one. E
its view of the world is the real one. E and the skeptic thinks that you know
and the skeptic thinks that you know
and the skeptic thinks that you know skepticism is the way to truth
if the human mind is unable to arrive at
if the human mind is unable to arrive at truth and skepticism itself is a total
truth and skepticism itself is a total
truth and skepticism itself is a total waste of time.
waste of time.
waste of time. Yep.
Hi, D.
Hi, D. >> Yeah. What's up?
>> Well, I just wanted to tell you that
>> Well, I just wanted to tell you that you've done it twice now. Uh
you've done it twice now. Uh
you've done it twice now. Uh >> oh.
>> oh.
>> oh. >> Uh
>> Uh
>> Uh >> oh.
>> oh.
>> oh. >> I um was getting along just marvelous,
>> I um was getting along just marvelous,
>> I um was getting along just marvelous, shuffling along, getting into this old
shuffling along, getting into this old
shuffling along, getting into this old age thing. I had little old ladies
age thing. I had little old ladies
age thing. I had little old ladies opening the door for me and I was loving
opening the door for me and I was loving
opening the door for me and I was loving this. How did you do, man? Too much,
this. How did you do, man? Too much,
this. How did you do, man? Too much, >> man. Oh, it was marvelous. Absolutely
>> man. Oh, it was marvelous. Absolutely
>> man. Oh, it was marvelous. Absolutely marvelous. And then I got your CD on old
marvelous. And then I got your CD on old
marvelous. And then I got your CD on old age
age
age and the whole thing went out the window.
and the whole thing went out the window.
and the whole thing went out the window. The only thing that bothers me if I go
The only thing that bothers me if I go
The only thing that bothers me if I go back the way I was, my wife is going to
back the way I was, my wife is going to
back the way I was, my wife is going to divorce me.
divorce me.
divorce me. So somewhere I have to give something
So somewhere I have to give something
So somewhere I have to give something up.
up.
up. and uh move on.
>> Yeah. The young man.
>> Yeah. The young man. >> Yeah. Because age is such a powerful
>> Yeah. Because age is such a powerful
>> Yeah. Because age is such a powerful program
program
program >> from beginning to end, you know.
>> from beginning to end, you know.
>> from beginning to end, you know. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And we see it all through life. And
>> And we see it all through life. And
>> And we see it all through life. And that's what it is. That, you know, it
that's what it is. That, you know, it
that's what it is. That, you know, it isn't a thought form. It's it's like
isn't a thought form. It's it's like
isn't a thought form. It's it's like that's what it looks like. That's what
that's what it looks like. That's what
that's what it looks like. That's what it looks like. That's what it looks
it looks like. That's what it looks
it looks like. That's what it looks like.
like.
like. >> Yeah. So in life you say we're in middle
>> Yeah. So in life you say we're in middle
>> Yeah. So in life you say we're in middle age now. So now we have this and we have
age now. So now we have this and we have
age now. So now we have this and we have this and by god we do have this and uh
this and by god we do have this and uh
this and by god we do have this and uh maybe it's just natural maybe it is
maybe it's just natural maybe it is
maybe it's just natural maybe it is natural you know a lot of these things
natural you know a lot of these things
natural you know a lot of these things >> it seems like
>> it seems like
>> it seems like >> yeah it seems
>> yeah it seems
>> yeah it seems >> and why avoid them.
>> and why avoid them.
>> and why avoid them. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah. If you get forgetful and
>> Yeah. If you get forgetful and
>> Yeah. If you get forgetful and >> rickety so you get forgetful and rickety
>> rickety so you get forgetful and rickety
>> rickety so you get forgetful and rickety so what's the big deal?
so what's the big deal?
so what's the big deal? >> Why resist? You know what I mean?
>> Why resist? You know what I mean?
>> Why resist? You know what I mean? Yeah, I understand that. I'm looking at
Yeah, I understand that. I'm looking at
Yeah, I understand that. I'm looking at that.
that.
that. >> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. >> Yeah. And I'm giving it all up.
>> Yeah. And I'm giving it all up.
>> Yeah. And I'm giving it all up. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yeah. I'm not going back where I
>> Yeah. I'm not going back where I
>> Yeah. I'm not going back where I >> have one real question.
>> have one real question.
>> have one real question. >> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. >> For a friend of mine.
>> For a friend of mine.
>> For a friend of mine. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Not for myself.
>> Not for myself.
>> Not for myself. >> He's been recently diagnosed and he
>> He's been recently diagnosed and he
>> He's been recently diagnosed and he couldn't be here because this just
couldn't be here because this just
couldn't be here because this just happened.
happened.
happened. >> Oh.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. >> He comes to your classes when he can.
>> He comes to your classes when he can.
>> He comes to your classes when he can. >> Yeah. He's been recently diagnosed with
>> Yeah. He's been recently diagnosed with
>> Yeah. He's been recently diagnosed with prostate cancer.
prostate cancer.
prostate cancer. >> Very early stage with a high PSA.
>> Very early stage with a high PSA.
>> Very early stage with a high PSA. >> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. >> And he's trying to address it. He has
>> And he's trying to address it. He has
>> And he's trying to address it. He has your CDs on health and these things.
your CDs on health and these things.
your CDs on health and these things. >> So, he's trying to address it with that
>> So, he's trying to address it with that
>> So, he's trying to address it with that >> and natural cures,
>> and natural cures,
>> and natural cures, >> right? He came up with this as a product
>> right? He came up with this as a product
>> right? He came up with this as a product of a natural that helps the process.
of a natural that helps the process.
of a natural that helps the process. >> Oh yeah.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Oh yeah. >> And some friends of his have had
>> And some friends of his have had
>> And some friends of his have had positive results.
positive results.
positive results. >> He asked if you would calibrate that on
>> He asked if you would calibrate that on
>> He asked if you would calibrate that on his behalf for him
his behalf for him
his behalf for him >> if if you can do that.
>> if if you can do that.
>> if if you can do that. >> What is it?
>> What is it?
>> What is it? >> It's an herbal.
>> It's an herbal.
>> It's an herbal. >> Well, this is a brand name, but I don't
>> Well, this is a brand name, but I don't
>> Well, this is a brand name, but I don't say what it is.
say what it is.
say what it is. >> It's on there. It's such fine print you
>> It's on there. It's such fine print you
>> It's on there. It's such fine print you have to use a magnifying glass. Now
have to use a magnifying glass. Now
have to use a magnifying glass. Now >> your question is is this beneficial to
>> your question is is this beneficial to
>> your question is is this beneficial to prostate problems
prostate problems
prostate problems >> for him
>> for him
>> for him >> specifically?
>> specifically?
>> specifically? >> Let's ask in general. His name is Mike.
>> Let's ask in general. His name is Mike.
>> Let's ask in general. His name is Mike. >> Well, we Okay. Um
>> Well, we Okay. Um
>> Well, we Okay. Um we have permission to ask this. This is
we have permission to ask this. This is
we have permission to ask this. This is beneficial to prostate problems. Says
beneficial to prostate problems. Says
beneficial to prostate problems. Says it's beneficial. It would be beneficial
it's beneficial. It would be beneficial
it's beneficial. It would be beneficial to his prostate problems. Resist. Well,
to his prostate problems. Resist. Well,
to his prostate problems. Resist. Well, good news.
good news.
good news. >> Got it.
>> Got it.
>> Got it. >> Good news.
>> Good news.
>> Good news. No, no, we're not talking about cure.
No, no, we're not talking about cure.
No, no, we're not talking about cure. >> It's just beneficial. You know,
>> It's just beneficial. You know,
>> It's just beneficial. You know, >> it's beneficial.
>> it's beneficial.
>> it's beneficial. >> There's some other stuff they recommend
>> There's some other stuff they recommend
>> There's some other stuff they recommend for it and I always forget the name of
for it and I always forget the name of
for it and I always forget the name of it. I got a bottle of it home, but I
it. I got a bottle of it home, but I
it. I got a bottle of it home, but I never get around to opening it. But
never get around to opening it. But
never get around to opening it. But >> something that's good for it, you know.
>> something that's good for it, you know.
>> something that's good for it, you know. >> I heard another product called
>> I heard another product called
>> I heard another product called glutathione.
>> Another nothing other thing.
>> Another nothing other thing. >> Anyway, I I believe everything is
>> Anyway, I I believe everything is
>> Anyway, I I believe everything is physical, mental, and spiritual.
physical, mental, and spiritual.
physical, mental, and spiritual. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> So, you cancel the thought form. I'm an
>> So, you cancel the thought form. I'm an
>> So, you cancel the thought form. I'm an infinite being. I'm not subject to that.
infinite being. I'm not subject to that.
infinite being. I'm not subject to that. That's a belief system, you see. At the
That's a belief system, you see. At the
That's a belief system, you see. At the same time, you take whatever you need,
same time, you take whatever you need,
same time, you take whatever you need, flowmax, so you can go to the bathroom
flowmax, so you can go to the bathroom
flowmax, so you can go to the bathroom whereas you couldn't before, and you
whereas you couldn't before, and you
whereas you couldn't before, and you pray about it. So, you do physical,
pray about it. So, you do physical,
pray about it. So, you do physical, mental, and spiritual on everything.
mental, and spiritual on everything.
mental, and spiritual on everything. >> Everything's physical, mental, and
>> Everything's physical, mental, and
>> Everything's physical, mental, and spiritual. Just because you're doing the
spiritual. Just because you're doing the
spiritual. Just because you're doing the course of miracles don't mean you can't
course of miracles don't mean you can't
course of miracles don't mean you can't take an aspirin for a headache. You know
take an aspirin for a headache. You know
take an aspirin for a headache. You know what I mean?
what I mean?
what I mean? >> Everything's physical, mental, and
>> Everything's physical, mental, and
>> Everything's physical, mental, and spiritual. And I believe it should be
spiritual. And I believe it should be
spiritual. And I believe it should be approached on all three simultaneously.
approached on all three simultaneously.
approached on all three simultaneously. in in my practice uh back east and out
in in my practice uh back east and out
in in my practice uh back east and out here, I always put, you know, all all
here, I always put, you know, all all
here, I always put, you know, all all all all them together, physical, mental,
all all them together, physical, mental,
all all them together, physical, mental, spiritual, nutritional, acupuncture,
spiritual, nutritional, acupuncture,
spiritual, nutritional, acupuncture, whatever would help,
whatever would help,
whatever would help, >> whatever,
>> whatever,
>> whatever, >> vitamins, highdose vitamins.
>> vitamins, highdose vitamins.
>> vitamins, highdose vitamins. >> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I appreciate that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I appreciate that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I appreciate that. Thank you very,
Thank you very,
Thank you very, >> you know, I I've had all those myself.
>> you know, I I've had all those myself.
>> you know, I I've had all those myself. Acupuncture was a big help when my back
Acupuncture was a big help when my back
Acupuncture was a big help when my back collapsed and
collapsed and
collapsed and vertebrae cursed.
But I ain't one thing, it's another,
But I ain't one thing, it's another, right?
right?
right? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> I want to thank you both again.
>> I want to thank you both again.
>> I want to thank you both again. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> For what you meant in our life and for
>> For what you meant in our life and for
>> For what you meant in our life and for everybody else. My question is you
everybody else. My question is you
everybody else. My question is you mentioned again today that the Buddha
mentioned again today that the Buddha
mentioned again today that the Buddha felt like he was beset by demons.
felt like he was beset by demons.
felt like he was beset by demons. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Did he ever see how he transcended it?
>> Did he ever see how he transcended it?
>> Did he ever see how he transcended it? >> He became fully enlightened in the end.
>> He became fully enlightened in the end.
>> He became fully enlightened in the end. See, but as a book guy, you know,
See, but as a book guy, you know,
See, but as a book guy, you know, transcending levels also I think in
transcending levels also I think in
transcending levels also I think in devotional non-duality. I described the
devotional non-duality. I described the
devotional non-duality. I described the levels from about 800 on. From about 800
levels from about 800 on. From about 800
levels from about 800 on. From about 800 on, uh, you can be beset by all kinds of
on, uh, you can be beset by all kinds of
on, uh, you can be beset by all kinds of aches and pains and strange comingings
aches and pains and strange comingings
aches and pains and strange comingings and goings and demons, etc.
and goings and demons, etc.
and goings and demons, etc. That which gains that which has its
That which gains that which has its
That which gains that which has its total gain from falsehood. If you come
total gain from falsehood. If you come
total gain from falsehood. If you come from truth, you are its ultimate enemy.
from truth, you are its ultimate enemy.
from truth, you are its ultimate enemy. So you look like the enemy and it will
So you look like the enemy and it will
So you look like the enemy and it will attack you from every angle. It can look
attack you from every angle. It can look
attack you from every angle. It can look for every So these spiritual
for every So these spiritual
for every So these spiritual teachers who typically around in the
teachers who typically around in the
teachers who typically around in the 570s or so tend to fall. They become
570s or so tend to fall. They become
570s or so tend to fall. They become world famous and a lot of followers etc.
world famous and a lot of followers etc.
world famous and a lot of followers etc. Next thing you read they're into
Next thing you read they're into
Next thing you read they're into childhood seduction, sexual seduction,
childhood seduction, sexual seduction,
childhood seduction, sexual seduction, extortion of money, every kind of
extortion of money, every kind of
extortion of money, every kind of finagling.
finagling.
finagling. It's like the spirit. It's like the the
It's like the spirit. It's like the the
It's like the spirit. It's like the the little demons look for where there's a
little demons look for where there's a
little demons look for where there's a in your armor. They try a little
in your armor. They try a little
in your armor. They try a little flattery. Oh,
flattery. Oh,
flattery. Oh, >> he liked that title, didn't he?
>> he liked that title, didn't he?
>> he liked that title, didn't he? He that girl winked at him and said,
He that girl winked at him and said,
He that girl winked at him and said, "Boy, I'd love to be with you, honey."
"Boy, I'd love to be with you, honey."
"Boy, I'd love to be with you, honey." And he says, "Well, you know, all
And he says, "Well, you know, all
And he says, "Well, you know, all everything is spiritual. Sex is
everything is spiritual. Sex is
everything is spiritual. Sex is spiritual, so let's do it for God." You
spiritual, so let's do it for God." You
spiritual, so let's do it for God." You know what I mean? You can rationalize
know what I mean? You can rationalize
know what I mean? You can rationalize anything. You know, and it's done by
anything. You know, and it's done by
anything. You know, and it's done by gurus. And there's ladies who've been
gurus. And there's ladies who've been
gurus. And there's ladies who've been around and been to bed with a lot of
around and been to bed with a lot of
around and been to bed with a lot of gurus and they've written books about
gurus and they've written books about
gurus and they've written books about it. You know, I've got books at home,
it. You know, I've got books at home,
it. You know, I've got books at home, the various gurus and the the tactics.
the various gurus and the the tactics.
the various gurus and the the tactics. So the seduction of the innocent I feel
So the seduction of the innocent I feel
So the seduction of the innocent I feel it's the fault of the spiritual teacher
it's the fault of the spiritual teacher
it's the fault of the spiritual teacher who did not know that it's his
who did not know that it's his
who did not know that it's his responsibility to warn students of where
responsibility to warn students of where
responsibility to warn students of where the weak sides are. Everybody thinks
the weak sides are. Everybody thinks
the weak sides are. Everybody thinks well I'm going to become spiritual and
well I'm going to become spiritual and
well I'm going to become spiritual and everything's going to be just beautiful
everything's going to be just beautiful
everything's going to be just beautiful and angels and flowers and perfume.
and angels and flowers and perfume.
and angels and flowers and perfume. No, you're going to pull up that which
No, you're going to pull up that which
No, you're going to pull up that which is antitheical to purity. You're going
is antitheical to purity. You're going
is antitheical to purity. You're going to pull up its opposite.
to pull up its opposite.
to pull up its opposite. you know the attempts at seducing you
you know the attempts at seducing you
you know the attempts at seducing you and attacking you there with vanity. So
and attacking you there with vanity. So
and attacking you there with vanity. So the spiritual ego is one of them. See
the spiritual ego is one of them. See
the spiritual ego is one of them. See spiritual ego uh and thinking that
spiritual ego uh and thinking that
spiritual ego uh and thinking that you're more than what you are you know
you're more than what you are you know
you're more than what you are you know because the students see you that way
because the students see you that way
because the students see you that way that way doesn't mean that's what you
that way doesn't mean that's what you
that way doesn't mean that's what you are buddy you're just a beginner. You
are buddy you're just a beginner. You
are buddy you're just a beginner. You realize that enlightenment in this realm
realize that enlightenment in this realm
realize that enlightenment in this realm is kindergarten when you're in the room
is kindergarten when you're in the room
is kindergarten when you're in the room the next one. So anybody who calibrates
the next one. So anybody who calibrates
the next one. So anybody who calibrates at 850 is moving fine in kindergarten.
at 850 is moving fine in kindergarten.
at 850 is moving fine in kindergarten. And I remind them this is kindergarten.
And I remind them this is kindergarten.
And I remind them this is kindergarten. There are realms where it starts at
There are realms where it starts at
There are realms where it starts at couple thousand and you aren't even hit
couple thousand and you aren't even hit
couple thousand and you aren't even hit a thousand yet. So
a thousand yet. So
a thousand yet. So >> we're still in kindergarten.
>> we're still in kindergarten.
>> we're still in kindergarten. >> To get humility back into the you know
>> To get humility back into the you know
>> To get humility back into the you know the knock over the spiritual ego each
the knock over the spiritual ego each
the knock over the spiritual ego each one of us you know even to very high
one of us you know even to very high
one of us you know even to very high levels is only a servant of God and the
levels is only a servant of God and the
levels is only a servant of God and the archangels are so far beyond us you
archangels are so far beyond us you
archangels are so far beyond us you know.
know.
know. So keeping those spiritual principles
So keeping those spiritual principles
So keeping those spiritual principles safeguards the student
safeguards the student
safeguards the student >> and just surrendering everything to God
>> and just surrendering everything to God
>> and just surrendering everything to God no matter what
no matter what
no matter what >> that which uh makes us living off
>> that which uh makes us living off
>> that which uh makes us living off falsehood certainly does not like
falsehood certainly does not like
falsehood certainly does not like integrity
integrity
integrity doesn't like truth because its whole
doesn't like truth because its whole
doesn't like truth because its whole power base is based on falsehood
power base is based on falsehood
power base is based on falsehood so why should it like truth
Thank you.
Thank you. >> Mhm.
>> That's true.
>> That's true. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Think I'm looking for you. Looking for a
>> Think I'm looking for you. Looking for a
>> Think I'm looking for you. Looking for a where they can get you.
where they can get you.
where they can get you. >> Hello, D.
>> Hello, D.
>> Hello, D. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Hi. I think you might have touched this
>> Hi. I think you might have touched this
>> Hi. I think you might have touched this probably often, but um I was wondering
probably often, but um I was wondering
probably often, but um I was wondering if you could give some tips on
if you could give some tips on
if you could give some tips on surrendering the payoff and uh just one
surrendering the payoff and uh just one
surrendering the payoff and uh just one practice that I use is self inquiry. I
practice that I use is self inquiry. I
practice that I use is self inquiry. I constantly um contemplate, you know, my
constantly um contemplate, you know, my
constantly um contemplate, you know, my being and watch just constantly watching
being and watch just constantly watching
being and watch just constantly watching the mind do its thing.
the mind do its thing.
the mind do its thing. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And um
>> And um
>> And um >> surrendering the payoff. Um
>> surrendering the payoff. Um
>> surrendering the payoff. Um I just wonder if you could give some
I just wonder if you could give some
I just wonder if you could give some tips on
tips on
tips on >> the payoff of negativity,
>> the payoff of negativity,
>> the payoff of negativity, >> right? See, in other words, every
>> right? See, in other words, every
>> right? See, in other words, every negative feeling is held in place by a
negative feeling is held in place by a
negative feeling is held in place by a payoff.
payoff.
payoff. So, you look at what the payoff is. You
So, you look at what the payoff is. You
So, you look at what the payoff is. You don't have to get rid of hatred. You
don't have to get rid of hatred. You
don't have to get rid of hatred. You just look at what is the payoff of the
just look at what is the payoff of the
just look at what is the payoff of the hatred. And then don't ask yourself, am
hatred. And then don't ask yourself, am
hatred. And then don't ask yourself, am I willing to give up hatred? Ask
I willing to give up hatred? Ask
I willing to give up hatred? Ask yourself, am I willing to give up the
yourself, am I willing to give up the
yourself, am I willing to give up the payoff of that, the feeling of revenge,
payoff of that, the feeling of revenge,
payoff of that, the feeling of revenge, the glee of it, you know? So once you
the glee of it, you know? So once you
the glee of it, you know? So once you give up the payoff payoff then the thing
give up the payoff payoff then the thing
give up the payoff payoff then the thing tends to relinquish of its own and of
tends to relinquish of its own and of
tends to relinquish of its own and of course then the next step comes up. So
course then the next step comes up. So
course then the next step comes up. So you won't run out of suffering.
Get off pride then the anger comes up
Get off pride then the anger comes up then the then the grief comes up then
then the then the grief comes up then
then the then the grief comes up then the remorse comes up then the self- aure
the remorse comes up then the self- aure
the remorse comes up then the self- aure comes up.
comes up.
comes up. So each thing unccors a stack and you
So each thing unccors a stack and you
So each thing unccors a stack and you work through the stack. But the whole
work through the stack. But the whole
work through the stack. But the whole stack is held in place by some projected
stack is held in place by some projected
stack is held in place by some projected value. But the real value to the
value. But the real value to the
value. But the real value to the narcissistic core of the ego is that it
narcissistic core of the ego is that it
narcissistic core of the ego is that it feeds off it. Without the feed without
feeds off it. Without the feed without
feeds off it. Without the feed without the payoff of negativity, people would
the payoff of negativity, people would
the payoff of negativity, people would instantly give it up.
instantly give it up.
instantly give it up. So something must be keeping it there.
So something must be keeping it there.
So something must be keeping it there. >> And you say, what is keeping it there?
>> And you say, what is keeping it there?
>> And you say, what is keeping it there? Can it be that I actually feel good to
Can it be that I actually feel good to
Can it be that I actually feel good to watch that so have a sword put right
watch that so have a sword put right
watch that so have a sword put right through him? Yes, he he deserved it.
So that's what you look for. What's the
So that's what you look for. What's the secret payoff?
secret payoff?
secret payoff? >> It's a secret narcissistic payoff
>> It's a secret narcissistic payoff
>> It's a secret narcissistic payoff because people are ashamed of it. So
because people are ashamed of it. So
because people are ashamed of it. So they don't want to admit that they're
they don't want to admit that they're
they don't want to admit that they're enjoying that.
enjoying that.
enjoying that. They're enjoying all the grief and
They're enjoying all the grief and
They're enjoying all the grief and celebrity status of it and the attention
celebrity status of it and the attention
celebrity status of it and the attention they're getting.
they're getting.
they're getting. >> Oh yeah.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Oh yeah. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> They give it up, it tends to disappear.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Hello. Um my question actually was quite
>> Hello. Um my question actually was quite
>> Hello. Um my question actually was quite similar to the fellow just before me.
similar to the fellow just before me.
similar to the fellow just before me. Uh giving up the juice. Um, in one of
Uh giving up the juice. Um, in one of
Uh giving up the juice. Um, in one of your books, I believe it was I, you
your books, I believe it was I, you
your books, I believe it was I, you mentioned um, giving up the ego in one
mentioned um, giving up the ego in one
mentioned um, giving up the ego in one fell swoop
fell swoop
fell swoop instead of maybe looking at all the
instead of maybe looking at all the
instead of maybe looking at all the individual little things. I guess that's
individual little things. I guess that's
individual little things. I guess that's the same as giving up the juice. Is it?
the same as giving up the juice. Is it?
the same as giving up the juice. Is it? >> No. Giving up the juice is giving up
>> No. Giving up the juice is giving up
>> No. Giving up the juice is giving up specific negative feelings and
specific negative feelings and
specific negative feelings and viewpoints. Yeah.
>> Okay. Is that similar to surrendering
>> Okay. Is that similar to surrendering one's life to God in every moment?
one's life to God in every moment?
one's life to God in every moment? as we go along
as we go along
as we go along >> because errors are going to come up. I
>> because errors are going to come up. I
>> because errors are going to come up. I know
know
know >> but uh just to keep going and and not
>> but uh just to keep going and and not
>> but uh just to keep going and and not >> constantly surrendering to God. So when
>> constantly surrendering to God. So when
>> constantly surrendering to God. So when you finally get
you finally get
you finally get >> I don't think I've ever written about or
>> I don't think I've ever written about or
>> I don't think I've ever written about or talked about the group. There's going to
talked about the group. There's going to
talked about the group. There's going to there'll come a time when I call it the
there'll come a time when I call it the
there'll come a time when I call it the final run. Suddenly
final run. Suddenly
final run. Suddenly the you're like desperate to read the
the you're like desperate to read the
the you're like desperate to read the truth and you're willing to drop
truth and you're willing to drop
truth and you're willing to drop everything in this world. walk away from
everything in this world. walk away from
everything in this world. walk away from all of it. Titles, money, positions,
all of it. Titles, money, positions,
all of it. Titles, money, positions, houses, servants, everything
houses, servants, everything
houses, servants, everything because you like know this is going to
because you like know this is going to
because you like know this is going to be the final run. On the final run,
be the final run. On the final run,
be the final run. On the final run, every second you're releasing,
every second you're releasing,
every second you're releasing, surrendering, releasing, surrendering
surrendering, releasing, surrendering
surrendering, releasing, surrendering every second. And you do make very rapid
every second. And you do make very rapid
every second. And you do make very rapid progress. You forget the body's even
progress. You forget the body's even
progress. You forget the body's even there. And I remember living all by
there. And I remember living all by
there. And I remember living all by myself doing that. And there was
myself doing that. And there was
myself doing that. And there was somebody in the mirror. It scared me. I
somebody in the mirror. It scared me. I
somebody in the mirror. It scared me. I looked and there was somebody in the
looked and there was somebody in the
looked and there was somebody in the house for God's sake.
house for God's sake.
house for God's sake. Me.
Me.
Me. Another time I w walk walked through a
Another time I w walk walked through a
Another time I w walk walked through a wall. I have to walk through the wall.
wall. I have to walk through the wall.
wall. I have to walk through the wall. You know, and you're a third guy. You
You know, and you're a third guy. You
You know, and you're a third guy. You walk through walls. I walk through the
walk through walls. I walk through the
walk through walls. I walk through the wall and bang, my whole face got I
wall and bang, my whole face got I
wall and bang, my whole face got I bashed myself up against the solid wall.
bashed myself up against the solid wall.
bashed myself up against the solid wall. You know what I'm saying? It just
You know what I'm saying? It just
You know what I'm saying? It just transit transcended any identification
transit transcended any identification
transit transcended any identification with the physical body. You say it's
with the physical body. You say it's
with the physical body. You say it's Thursday and the last time you ate
Thursday and the last time you ate
Thursday and the last time you ate anything was Monday or Tuesday. You
anything was Monday or Tuesday. You
anything was Monday or Tuesday. You know, you look inside, there's one apple
know, you look inside, there's one apple
know, you look inside, there's one apple and two diet Pepsis and a piece of
and two diet Pepsis and a piece of
and two diet Pepsis and a piece of cheese and you haven't eaten this week.
cheese and you haven't eaten this week.
cheese and you haven't eaten this week. That's sort of, you know, in other
That's sort of, you know, in other
That's sort of, you know, in other words, you're you're on a drive and this
words, you're you're on a drive and this
words, you're you're on a drive and this drive will take you very far. And if you
drive will take you very far. And if you
drive will take you very far. And if you get a drive like that, go with it. Go
get a drive like that, go with it. Go
get a drive like that, go with it. Go with it. Go with it.
with it. Go with it.
with it. Go with it. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> The world will see you've gone mad.
>> The world will see you've gone mad.
>> The world will see you've gone mad. Good.
You've gone mad. The world hasn't said
You've gone mad. The world hasn't said you haven't gone mad. going for an
you haven't gone mad. going for an
you haven't gone mad. going for an interview if you
interview if you
interview if you >> cuz in the world's view you're going
>> cuz in the world's view you're going
>> cuz in the world's view you're going you're going
you're going
you're going >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Um
>> Um
>> Um I'm working with a guy that's in
I'm working with a guy that's in
I'm working with a guy that's in recovery right now and uh I'm trying to
recovery right now and uh I'm trying to
recovery right now and uh I'm trying to help him you know and uh he's like into
help him you know and uh he's like into
help him you know and uh he's like into some of the things that you were showing
some of the things that you were showing
some of the things that you were showing on the slide today that you know aren't
on the slide today that you know aren't
on the slide today that you know aren't really that productive and spiritual
really that productive and spiritual
really that productive and spiritual progress. And sometimes I feel like I
progress. And sometimes I feel like I
progress. And sometimes I feel like I want to tell them about it, you know,
want to tell them about it, you know,
want to tell them about it, you know, but then I feel that that's like uh
but then I feel that that's like uh
but then I feel that that's like uh pride or some sort of positionality.
pride or some sort of positionality.
pride or some sort of positionality. >> You can tell them what you've heard.
>> You can tell them what you've heard.
>> You can tell them what you've heard. >> I've heard, you know, the Buddha said, I
>> I've heard, you know, the Buddha said, I
>> I've heard, you know, the Buddha said, I have heard. I've heard.
have heard. I've heard.
have heard. I've heard. >> So you can quote, "I have heard from,
>> So you can quote, "I have heard from,
>> So you can quote, "I have heard from, you know, pretty advanced spiritual
you know, pretty advanced spiritual
you know, pretty advanced spiritual teacher
teacher
teacher >> that that this can have a very delarious
>> that that this can have a very delarious
>> that that this can have a very delarious effect as pleasant and exciting and fun
effect as pleasant and exciting and fun
effect as pleasant and exciting and fun as it can be." I have heard. Now it's up
as it can be." I have heard. Now it's up
as it can be." I have heard. Now it's up to him, his karmic uh preparedness for
to him, his karmic uh preparedness for
to him, his karmic uh preparedness for listening to you. Yes.
listening to you. Yes.
listening to you. Yes. >> Okay. Thanks.
>> Okay. Thanks.
>> Okay. Thanks. >> At a certain point, you'll do anything
>> At a certain point, you'll do anything
>> At a certain point, you'll do anything uh that you hear that is spiritually
uh that you hear that is spiritually
uh that you hear that is spiritually beneficial and you'll drop anything that
beneficial and you'll drop anything that
beneficial and you'll drop anything that you think is spiritually negative. And
you think is spiritually negative. And
you think is spiritually negative. And very often the news comes to you because
very often the news comes to you because
very often the news comes to you because you're innocent by somebody more
you're innocent by somebody more
you're innocent by somebody more advanced, somebody more advanced.
advanced, somebody more advanced.
advanced, somebody more advanced. You know, like I once had a person who
You know, like I once had a person who
You know, like I once had a person who could see auras tell me that such and
could see auras tell me that such and
could see auras tell me that such and such a teacher, no energy around the
such a teacher, no energy around the
such a teacher, no energy around the heart chakra. See, so that was
heart chakra. See, so that was
heart chakra. See, so that was information, but I was ready to listen
information, but I was ready to listen
information, but I was ready to listen to it. So, uh, I say, "Oh, huh. What do
to it. So, uh, I say, "Oh, huh. What do
to it. So, uh, I say, "Oh, huh. What do you mean about that?" See, so you can
you mean about that?" See, so you can
you mean about that?" See, so you can carry the information and it's not up to
carry the information and it's not up to
carry the information and it's not up to you to do anything, but to karmically
you to do anything, but to karmically
you to do anything, but to karmically responsible, I would like to know that I
responsible, I would like to know that I
responsible, I would like to know that I shared that information. So, it's his
shared that information. So, it's his
shared that information. So, it's his option. No.
option. No.
option. No. >> So, we carry the message and not the
>> So, we carry the message and not the
>> So, we carry the message and not the person. See, we carry the message. It's
person. See, we carry the message. It's
person. See, we carry the message. It's not up to us whether they do so, but
not up to us whether they do so, but
not up to us whether they do so, but it's our obligation as spiritually
it's our obligation as spiritually
it's our obligation as spiritually evolved to carry the message whenever we
evolved to carry the message whenever we
evolved to carry the message whenever we can
can
can >> at the level of the person's capacity
>> at the level of the person's capacity
>> at the level of the person's capacity and willingness to hear it. See?
and willingness to hear it. See?
and willingness to hear it. See? >> Yeah.
>> Good question.
>> Good question. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah.
>> Hello. Yes.
>> Hello. Yes. Uh my question is about uh the duality
Uh my question is about uh the duality
Uh my question is about uh the duality of good and evil.
of good and evil.
of good and evil. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Um
>> Um
>> Um >> back home I have a friend that teaches a
>> back home I have a friend that teaches a
>> back home I have a friend that teaches a class and he teaches on the art of war
class and he teaches on the art of war
class and he teaches on the art of war and uh kind of puts it as a spiritual
and uh kind of puts it as a spiritual
and uh kind of puts it as a spiritual battle that we're in.
battle that we're in.
battle that we're in. >> The art of war the calibrates the 350
>> The art of war the calibrates the 350
>> The art of war the calibrates the 350 the ancient Chinese text leotu
the ancient Chinese text leotu
the ancient Chinese text leotu I would assume you got some of the ideas
I would assume you got some of the ideas
I would assume you got some of the ideas from that but it's mainly centered
from that but it's mainly centered
from that but it's mainly centered around the ego
around the ego
around the ego that we're fighting or yourself. It's a
that we're fighting or yourself. It's a
that we're fighting or yourself. It's a class to alcoholics and addicts.
class to alcoholics and addicts.
class to alcoholics and addicts. >> Yeah. Oh, I see. Okay.
>> Yeah. Oh, I see. Okay.
>> Yeah. Oh, I see. Okay. >> But I have a problem with the whole war
>> But I have a problem with the whole war
>> But I have a problem with the whole war because I think of the duality of good
because I think of the duality of good
because I think of the duality of good and evil. Am I fighting a war? I'm on
and evil. Am I fighting a war? I'm on
and evil. Am I fighting a war? I'm on the good side of love trying to fight
the good side of love trying to fight
the good side of love trying to fight this war.
this war.
this war. >> What war
>> What war
>> What war >> exactly? I just But then I'm trying to
>> exactly? I just But then I'm trying to
>> exactly? I just But then I'm trying to think of you say that there's spirits
think of you say that there's spirits
think of you say that there's spirits out there that are trying to attack you
out there that are trying to attack you
out there that are trying to attack you when you rise in levels of
when you rise in levels of
when you rise in levels of consciousness.
consciousness.
consciousness. >> But you don't have to call it war.
>> But you don't have to call it war.
>> But you don't have to call it war. And so the other side,
And so the other side,
And so the other side, >> they're just being themselves. They
>> they're just being themselves. They
>> they're just being themselves. They ain't at war with you.
ain't at war with you.
ain't at war with you. >> Okay. So there would be no necessary
>> Okay. So there would be no necessary
>> Okay. So there would be no necessary to look at it as a war.
to look at it as a war.
to look at it as a war. >> No. No. I wouldn't contextualize it as a
>> No. No. I wouldn't contextualize it as a
>> No. No. I wouldn't contextualize it as a war.
war.
war. >> What would it be contextualized as?
>> What would it be contextualized as?
>> What would it be contextualized as? >> Uh the way nature responds at certain
>> Uh the way nature responds at certain
>> Uh the way nature responds at certain levels.
levels.
levels. It's uh natural to certain segments of
It's uh natural to certain segments of
It's uh natural to certain segments of the populace
the populace
the populace uh to rise up against that which does
uh to rise up against that which does
uh to rise up against that which does not agree with it. That's all.
not agree with it. That's all.
not agree with it. That's all. The ego want is always looking for
The ego want is always looking for
The ego want is always looking for agreement. So the ego, an enemy is
agreement. So the ego, an enemy is
agreement. So the ego, an enemy is somebody that doesn't agree with you.
somebody that doesn't agree with you.
somebody that doesn't agree with you. Yeah. It's not a matter of war. War is a
Yeah. It's not a matter of war. War is a
Yeah. It's not a matter of war. War is a projection of a contextualization.
projection of a contextualization.
projection of a contextualization. You you might say in nature you see the
You you might say in nature you see the
You you might say in nature you see the struggle for dominance all the time.
struggle for dominance all the time.
struggle for dominance all the time. Dominance, dominance where their
Dominance, dominance where their
Dominance, dominance where their prevailing view should be dominant.
prevailing view should be dominant.
prevailing view should be dominant. That's really an animal instinct, isn't
That's really an animal instinct, isn't
That's really an animal instinct, isn't it? I mean, who cares if other people
it? I mean, who cares if other people
it? I mean, who cares if other people agree with yours the way you see it?
agree with yours the way you see it?
agree with yours the way you see it? >> Who cares?
>> Who cares?
>> Who cares? >> So, in the defenselessness, I think of
>> So, in the defenselessness, I think of
>> So, in the defenselessness, I think of the course or
the course or
the course or >> just in defenselessness of love, you
>> just in defenselessness of love, you
>> just in defenselessness of love, you don't have to engage in an active battle
don't have to engage in an active battle
don't have to engage in an active battle with your ego.
with your ego.
with your ego. >> You know, the you know, the wisdom of
>> You know, the you know, the wisdom of
>> You know, the you know, the wisdom of the Dao is uh Teoism, you know, as it's
the Dao is uh Teoism, you know, as it's
the Dao is uh Teoism, you know, as it's pronounced English. You've been with the
pronounced English. You've been with the
pronounced English. You've been with the read. So, let it go by with its
read. So, let it go by with its
read. So, let it go by with its viewpoint.
viewpoint.
viewpoint. I don't have to oppose communism. I can
I don't have to oppose communism. I can
I don't have to oppose communism. I can just say, you know, if I calibrated it
just say, you know, if I calibrated it
just say, you know, if I calibrated it so much, I see its demonstration in the
so much, I see its demonstration in the
so much, I see its demonstration in the world stage. And uh to me, it's not
world stage. And uh to me, it's not
world stage. And uh to me, it's not appealing to watch 100 million people
appealing to watch 100 million people
appealing to watch 100 million people starve to death. Not appealing.
starve to death. Not appealing.
starve to death. Not appealing. Despite his little red book, I don't
Despite his little red book, I don't
Despite his little red book, I don't have to be his enemy. I don't have to
have to be his enemy. I don't have to
have to be his enemy. I don't have to conquer him, but I certainly am not
conquer him, but I certainly am not
conquer him, but I certainly am not overwhelmed by his wisdom. Chairman Mayo
overwhelmed by his wisdom. Chairman Mayo
overwhelmed by his wisdom. Chairman Mayo and and his ilk. So in recovery in
and and his ilk. So in recovery in
and and his ilk. So in recovery in helping others what I mean that's not
helping others what I mean that's not
helping others what I mean that's not fighting a battle that's I mean you're
fighting a battle that's I mean you're
fighting a battle that's I mean you're but
but
but >> no because of in recovery you're sharing
>> no because of in recovery you're sharing
>> no because of in recovery you're sharing the truth without taking any position it
the truth without taking any position it
the truth without taking any position it has no opinion on outside matters
has no opinion on outside matters
has no opinion on outside matters >> right but the disease of addiction
>> right but the disease of addiction
>> right but the disease of addiction sometimes seems as though it's an enemy
sometimes seems as though it's an enemy
sometimes seems as though it's an enemy that's
that's
that's against
against
against >> an enemy that's a contextualization
>> an enemy that's a contextualization
>> an enemy that's a contextualization >> okay
>> okay
>> okay >> it's a spiritual opportunity
>> it's a spiritual opportunity
>> it's a spiritual opportunity addiction is one of fastest routes to to
addiction is one of fastest routes to to
addiction is one of fastest routes to to God. I mean, it's one of the fastest
God. I mean, it's one of the fastest
God. I mean, it's one of the fastest spiritual pathways.
spiritual pathways.
spiritual pathways. You see, because addiction is such a
You see, because addiction is such a
You see, because addiction is such a narrow line, you can't turn around. You
narrow line, you can't turn around. You
narrow line, you can't turn around. You can only go straight ahead or die. So,
can only go straight ahead or die. So,
can only go straight ahead or die. So, either surrender or die. That makes it
either surrender or die. That makes it
either surrender or die. That makes it easy, don't you?
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> I'll tell I don't care which way it is
>> I'll tell I don't care which way it is
>> I'll tell I don't care which way it is with you. You go to meetings or die.
with you. You go to meetings or die.
with you. You go to meetings or die. What do I care?
What do I care?
What do I care? Convulsion. Your convulsion is not mine.
Convulsion. Your convulsion is not mine.
Convulsion. Your convulsion is not mine. I'm just trying to see over the duality
I'm just trying to see over the duality
I'm just trying to see over the duality of good and evil.
of good and evil.
of good and evil. >> Yeah, I understand what you're saying.
>> Yeah, I understand what you're saying.
>> Yeah, I understand what you're saying. Yeah. Look at it instead of opposite,
Yeah. Look at it instead of opposite,
Yeah. Look at it instead of opposite, look at look at it as
look at look at it as
look at look at it as side by sides, you know.
side by sides, you know.
side by sides, you know. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Our positions on a thermometer, you
>> Our positions on a thermometer, you
>> Our positions on a thermometer, you know, this is right and this is wrong.
know, this is right and this is wrong.
know, this is right and this is wrong. It's more like where where is it in
It's more like where where is it in
It's more like where where is it in between depending on the viewpoint. It's
between depending on the viewpoint. It's
between depending on the viewpoint. It's a subtle question.
a subtle question.
a subtle question. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> And it's a difficult one. Difficult.
>> And it's a difficult one. Difficult.
>> And it's a difficult one. Difficult. >> Thank you. Problem of good and evil, of
>> Thank you. Problem of good and evil, of
>> Thank you. Problem of good and evil, of course, has been around since Genesis,
course, has been around since Genesis,
course, has been around since Genesis, right?
right?
right? >> And the tree.
>> And the tree.
>> And the tree. >> Serpent in the tree. Serpent played on
>> Serpent in the tree. Serpent played on
>> Serpent in the tree. Serpent played on E's childhood naive and innocence.
E's childhood naive and innocence.
E's childhood naive and innocence. >> Okay, we'll just move faster. What do
>> Okay, we'll just move faster. What do
>> Okay, we'll just move faster. What do you want to know?
you want to know?
you want to know? >> I don't really have a question to ask of
>> I don't really have a question to ask of
>> I don't really have a question to ask of you. I just brought a gift and I guess
you. I just brought a gift and I guess
you. I just brought a gift and I guess it's a twofold gift because it was a
it's a twofold gift because it was a
it's a twofold gift because it was a thank you gift.
thank you gift.
thank you gift. >> Thank you. and just to a happy birthday
>> Thank you. and just to a happy birthday
>> Thank you. and just to a happy birthday gift.
gift.
gift. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> And u of angels that I made and they're
>> And u of angels that I made and they're
>> And u of angels that I made and they're made out of
made out of
made out of >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Isn't that cute?
>> Isn't that cute?
>> Isn't that cute? >> This is the first time we've been here
>> This is the first time we've been here
>> This is the first time we've been here physically, but my husband has I think
physically, but my husband has I think
physically, but my husband has I think every one of your capes and uh out
every one of your capes and uh out
every one of your capes and uh out there. So,
there. So,
there. So, >> I'm so glad you're here.
>> I'm so glad you're here.
>> I'm so glad you're here. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you for the gifts.
>> Thank you for the gifts.
>> Thank you for the gifts. >> You're welcome.
>> You're welcome.
>> You're welcome. >> There is one question that I'd like to
>> There is one question that I'd like to
>> There is one question that I'd like to ask of Susan.
ask of Susan.
ask of Susan. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Because the kinesiology resonates with
>> Because the kinesiology resonates with
>> Because the kinesiology resonates with my husband.
my husband.
my husband. >> Uhhuh. And so when I do it and he
>> Uhhuh. And so when I do it and he
>> Uhhuh. And so when I do it and he doesn't necessarily get the answer that
doesn't necessarily get the answer that
doesn't necessarily get the answer that he wants,
he wants,
he wants, um, is it because that my resistance or
um, is it because that my resistance or
um, is it because that my resistance or if I'm not So I guess with the way you
if I'm not So I guess with the way you
if I'm not So I guess with the way you do with your arm or whatever of how the
do with your arm or whatever of how the
do with your arm or whatever of how the resistance is, how do you know when
resistance is, how do you know when
resistance is, how do you know when there's a yes or a no?
there's a yes or a no?
there's a yes or a no? >> You you can't have a vested interest in
>> You you can't have a vested interest in
>> You you can't have a vested interest in the answer and still get a right answer.
the answer and still get a right answer.
the answer and still get a right answer. >> You can't care. You you have to be
>> You can't care. You you have to be
>> You can't care. You you have to be devoted to truth above gain. See, and
devoted to truth above gain. See, and
devoted to truth above gain. See, and one gain is being right. So
one gain is being right. So
one gain is being right. So you have to relinquish
you have to relinquish
you have to relinquish uh
uh
uh wanting to control the answer. And I'll
wanting to control the answer. And I'll
wanting to control the answer. And I'll tell you in return you get a gift that
tell you in return you get a gift that
tell you in return you get a gift that is greater than that which you
is greater than that which you
is greater than that which you relinquished.
relinquished.
relinquished. >> Because if you say am I willing to
>> Because if you say am I willing to
>> Because if you say am I willing to relinquish control of this answer?
relinquish control of this answer?
relinquish control of this answer? uh you feel for momentarily that you
uh you feel for momentarily that you
uh you feel for momentarily that you lost and then on the way to the bathroom
lost and then on the way to the bathroom
lost and then on the way to the bathroom sudden you got man I just saw the door
sudden you got man I just saw the door
sudden you got man I just saw the door that that opened so you're letting go
that that opened so you're letting go
that that opened so you're letting go positionality
positionality
positionality and it's replaced by essence and out of
and it's replaced by essence and out of
and it's replaced by essence and out of essence you see oh my god I'm good thing
essence you see oh my god I'm good thing
essence you see oh my god I'm good thing I didn't go that way
I didn't go that way
I didn't go that way >> thank you
>> thank you
>> thank you >> and Ron stock didn't do too good after
>> and Ron stock didn't do too good after
>> and Ron stock didn't do too good after all
>> I I guess WorldCom wasn't the best
>> I I guess WorldCom wasn't the best investment after all, huh?
investment after all, huh?
investment after all, huh? >> Hello.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> I'll try and make it as concise as
>> I'll try and make it as concise as
>> I'll try and make it as concise as possible. Um, a few years ago, I was
possible. Um, a few years ago, I was
possible. Um, a few years ago, I was walking down an avenue in Manhattan and
walking down an avenue in Manhattan and
walking down an avenue in Manhattan and all of a sudden, every face, every
all of a sudden, every face, every
all of a sudden, every face, every person became lovable, even the
person became lovable, even the
person became lovable, even the sidewalk.
sidewalk.
sidewalk. >> Wonderful. It had it lasted for you know
>> Wonderful. It had it lasted for you know
>> Wonderful. It had it lasted for you know a few moments but then wow
a few moments but then wow
a few moments but then wow >> an intense fear came over me of
>> an intense fear came over me of
>> an intense fear came over me of >> like agonizing that the eye was
>> like agonizing that the eye was
>> like agonizing that the eye was disappearing like there questions that
disappearing like there questions that
disappearing like there questions that popped into my mind would who would love
popped into my mind would who would love
popped into my mind would who would love my friends and family how would I
my friends and family how would I
my friends and family how would I function
function
function >> and um
>> and um
>> and um >> it was it was like a non-verbal choice I
>> it was it was like a non-verbal choice I
>> it was it was like a non-verbal choice I could give up an the eye and stay there
could give up an the eye and stay there
could give up an the eye and stay there in this state
in this state
in this state >> yes
>> yes
>> yes >> or
>> or
>> or >> you got a glimpse
>> you got a glimpse
>> you got a glimpse >> and I but I I couldn't do it then.
>> and I but I I couldn't do it then.
>> and I but I I couldn't do it then. >> Okay. Because you weren't prepared. But
>> Okay. Because you weren't prepared. But
>> Okay. Because you weren't prepared. But now you know that it's going to recur
now you know that it's going to recur
now you know that it's going to recur for sure.
for sure.
for sure. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> So you got a premature glimpse.
>> So you got a premature glimpse.
>> So you got a premature glimpse. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> So that you can adjust your life that
>> So that you can adjust your life that
>> So that you can adjust your life that when it becomes dominant, you walk, you
when it becomes dominant, you walk, you
when it becomes dominant, you walk, you know, I walked away from everything.
know, I walked away from everything.
know, I walked away from everything. Everything. Everything this world has to
Everything. Everything this world has to
Everything. Everything this world has to offer.
offer.
offer. >> Money, titles, wealth, state, home
>> Money, titles, wealth, state, home
>> Money, titles, wealth, state, home titles,
titles,
titles, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> Walked away.
>> Walked away.
>> Walked away. >> Yeah. But I was prepared to do that.
>> Yeah. But I was prepared to do that.
>> Yeah. But I was prepared to do that. Mhm.
Mhm.
Mhm. >> Because I saw what was coming and I
>> Because I saw what was coming and I
>> Because I saw what was coming and I thought,
thought,
thought, >> see what what what's coming is so far
>> see what what what's coming is so far
>> see what what what's coming is so far beyond all that the world has to offer
beyond all that the world has to offer
beyond all that the world has to offer >> that it's easy to let go. People say,
>> that it's easy to let go. People say,
>> that it's easy to let go. People say, "Well, it must have been difficult to
"Well, it must have been difficult to
"Well, it must have been difficult to let go of all that compared to what you
let go of all that compared to what you
let go of all that compared to what you saw." Okay. I can remember one time 12
saw." Okay. I can remember one time 12
saw." Okay. I can remember one time 12 people being at dinner. I looked at him
people being at dinner. I looked at him
people being at dinner. I looked at him all of a sudden all of them turned into
all of a sudden all of them turned into
all of a sudden all of them turned into Jesus Christ. I like saw the Jesus
Jesus Christ. I like saw the Jesus
Jesus Christ. I like saw the Jesus Christ. I saw the Christ in all of them.
Christ. I saw the Christ in all of them.
Christ. I saw the Christ in all of them. Literally saw the Christ shine forth in
Literally saw the Christ shine forth in
Literally saw the Christ shine forth in all of them. Mhm.
all of them. Mhm.
all of them. Mhm. >> It's time to adjust your life when that
>> It's time to adjust your life when that
>> It's time to adjust your life when that happens.
>> I guess so.
>> I guess so. >> But you have a glimpse and that's more
>> But you have a glimpse and that's more
>> But you have a glimpse and that's more than
than
than >> you got a glimpse and that warns you.
>> you got a glimpse and that warns you.
>> you got a glimpse and that warns you. >> But that's what's coming. That is what's
>> But that's what's coming. That is what's
>> But that's what's coming. That is what's coming. You see the reality, the essence
coming. You see the reality, the essence
coming. You see the reality, the essence of divinity of all of existence.
of divinity of all of existence.
of divinity of all of existence. >> Right. I I guess and just a followup to
>> Right. I I guess and just a followup to
>> Right. I I guess and just a followup to that after you cross the final doorway,
that after you cross the final doorway,
that after you cross the final doorway, is there any individual aspect left that
is there any individual aspect left that
is there any individual aspect left that was like a secondary fear that came up?
was like a secondary fear that came up?
was like a secondary fear that came up? Even if I left the eye, would there be
Even if I left the eye, would there be
Even if I left the eye, would there be anything like an individual awareness?
anything like an individual awareness?
anything like an individual awareness? >> It's none of your business.
>> It's none of your business.
>> It's none of your business. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Would it really matter?
>> Would it really matter?
>> Would it really matter? >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. What happens is the the dimension of
What happens is the the dimension of
What happens is the the dimension of existence changes.
existence changes.
existence changes. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> The dimension changes in which there's
>> The dimension changes in which there's
>> The dimension changes in which there's no longer a personal locus. It's like
no longer a personal locus. It's like
no longer a personal locus. It's like the truck is running itself.
the truck is running itself.
the truck is running itself. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> Because
>> Because
>> Because it the truck is built that way, but
it the truck is built that way, but
it the truck is built that way, but there's nobody at the wheel.
there's nobody at the wheel.
there's nobody at the wheel. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You witness the truck running down the
>> You witness the truck running down the
>> You witness the truck running down the highway the way it's supposed to go, but
highway the way it's supposed to go, but
highway the way it's supposed to go, but there's no personal self. Everything is
there's no personal self. Everything is
there's no personal self. Everything is happening autonomously and spontaneous
happening autonomously and spontaneous
happening autonomously and spontaneous of its own because what you're seeing is
of its own because what you're seeing is
of its own because what you're seeing is a potentiality uh eventuating into an
a potentiality uh eventuating into an
a potentiality uh eventuating into an actuality. Such as you're coming up here
actuality. Such as you're coming up here
actuality. Such as you're coming up here was a potentiality. Now it's an
was a potentiality. Now it's an
was a potentiality. Now it's an actuality. There's no cause of it. Yeah.
actuality. There's no cause of it. Yeah.
actuality. There's no cause of it. Yeah. >> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. >> But your energy, my energy pull pulled
>> But your energy, my energy pull pulled
>> But your energy, my energy pull pulled each other together just like that at
each other together just like that at
each other together just like that at that moment, but it's doing it of its
that moment, but it's doing it of its
that moment, but it's doing it of its own.
own.
own. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. You're doing well.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Hi. I have no question. I just have
>> Hi. I have no question. I just have
>> Hi. I have no question. I just have Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. >> I can't hear you.
>> I can't hear you.
>> I can't hear you. >> It's okay.
>> It's okay.
>> It's okay. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> You heard me.
>> You heard me.
>> You heard me. >> What' you say?
>> What' you say?
>> What' you say? >> Oh, you didn't hear me. I said I have no
>> Oh, you didn't hear me. I said I have no
>> Oh, you didn't hear me. I said I have no questions. I just
questions. I just
questions. I just >> Oh, you have no questions.
>> Oh, you have no questions.
>> Oh, you have no questions. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> God bless.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. >> Thank you. Thank you. Her
>> Thank you. Thank you. Her
>> Thank you. Thank you. Her question was, "What'll he say if I have
question was, "What'll he say if I have
question was, "What'll he say if I have no questions?" So, I answered it.
no questions?" So, I answered it.
no questions?" So, I answered it. >> Yep. Hi.
>> Yep. Hi.
>> Yep. Hi. >> Hi. Hi.
>> Hi. Hi.
>> Hi. Hi. >> Can you uh explain to me about angels
>> Can you uh explain to me about angels
>> Can you uh explain to me about angels and what they are?
and what they are?
and what they are? >> I'm not an expert on angels. No.
>> I'm not an expert on angels. No.
>> I'm not an expert on angels. No. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> I just haven't had time to check it out.
>> I just haven't had time to check it out.
>> I just haven't had time to check it out. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> I know something about archangels that
>> I know something about archangels that
>> I know something about archangels that they calibrate, you know, 50,000
they calibrate, you know, 50,000
they calibrate, you know, 50,000 and uh the angelic memories I have Yes,
and uh the angelic memories I have Yes,
and uh the angelic memories I have Yes, that it's a reality
that it's a reality
that it's a reality >> and an experiential reality.
>> and an experiential reality.
>> and an experiential reality. And um I have a memory of greeting
And um I have a memory of greeting
And um I have a memory of greeting people as they came across in a state of
people as they came across in a state of
people as they came across in a state of shock just hit by a bus. They're coming
shock just hit by a bus. They're coming
shock just hit by a bus. They're coming across to a different dimension
across to a different dimension
across to a different dimension and through the love that shone forth
and through the love that shone forth
and through the love that shone forth that eliminated their fear.
that eliminated their fear.
that eliminated their fear. I have a memory of that, you know, an
I have a memory of that, you know, an
I have a memory of that, you know, an angelic kind of experience. Yeah.
Okay, thank you.
Okay, thank you. >> And I know angels have come to me in
>> And I know angels have come to me in
>> And I know angels have come to me in physical bodies. In fact, I even
physical bodies. In fact, I even
physical bodies. In fact, I even calibrated whether I'm an angel and said
calibrated whether I'm an angel and said
calibrated whether I'm an angel and said yes.
yes.
yes. >> And they do.
>> And they do.
>> And they do. >> The most ridiculous impossibility
>> The most ridiculous impossibility
>> The most ridiculous impossibility and then along would come just the
and then along would come just the
and then along would come just the person who didn't even know you were
person who didn't even know you were
person who didn't even know you were there hundreds of miles away
there hundreds of miles away
there hundreds of miles away and just happened to come up at a moment
and just happened to come up at a moment
and just happened to come up at a moment of crisis. You know, you say, "Well,
of crisis. You know, you say, "Well,
of crisis. You know, you say, "Well, that's accidental." Well, the chances
that's accidental." Well, the chances
that's accidental." Well, the chances would be one in one 100 million. And
would be one in one 100 million. And
would be one in one 100 million. And then it happens over and over and over
then it happens over and over and over
then it happens over and over and over again. Then you realize why people do
again. Then you realize why people do
again. Then you realize why people do the course of miracles. They call a
the course of miracles. They call a
the course of miracles. They call a course of miracles.
Unpredictable, unlikely, statistically
Unpredictable, unlikely, statistically impossible, but there it is.
impossible, but there it is.
impossible, but there it is. >> Yeah. Uhhuh.
My friend asked me friend asked me to
My friend asked me friend asked me to give this to you.
give this to you.
give this to you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. >> So
>> So
>> So >> my question is you talked about Muhammad
>> my question is you talked about Muhammad
>> my question is you talked about Muhammad when he was transcribing the Quran. He
when he was transcribing the Quran. He
when he was transcribing the Quran. He was at 720 or something like that.
was at 720 or something like that.
was at 720 or something like that. >> He was around 700. Yeah.
>> He was around 700. Yeah.
>> He was around 700. Yeah. >> And then you said he had temporal lobe
>> And then you said he had temporal lobe
>> And then you said he had temporal lobe epilepsy.
epilepsy.
epilepsy. >> That's a probable explanation. Yeah.
>> That's a probable explanation. Yeah.
>> That's a probable explanation. Yeah. >> Because I was wondering if that's like a
>> Because I was wondering if that's like a
>> Because I was wondering if that's like a physical mental disease. How it seems
physical mental disease. How it seems
physical mental disease. How it seems like they' be a lot less powerful than
like they' be a lot less powerful than
like they' be a lot less powerful than his state. So how could that have
his state. So how could that have
his state. So how could that have dragged him down? Well, it has to do
dragged him down? Well, it has to do
dragged him down? Well, it has to do with karma. It has to do with maybe some
with karma. It has to do with maybe some
with karma. It has to do with maybe some entities that don't like anybody else
entities that don't like anybody else
entities that don't like anybody else getting up to 700.
getting up to 700.
getting up to 700. But um temporal lobe epilepsy is also
But um temporal lobe epilepsy is also
But um temporal lobe epilepsy is also often associated with religiosity and
often associated with religiosity and
often associated with religiosity and religious illusions. Even
religious illusions. Even
religious illusions. Even uh anyway, he
uh anyway, he
uh anyway, he his experience is very different than
his experience is very different than
his experience is very different than anything I've had because there's never
anything I've had because there's never
anything I've had because there's never been an other. He felt he was getting
been an other. He felt he was getting
been an other. He felt he was getting dictation from an archangel. I've never
dictation from an archangel. I've never
dictation from an archangel. I've never f felt that any knowingness was coming
f felt that any knowingness was coming
f felt that any knowingness was coming from any other entity you know guide or
from any other entity you know guide or
from any other entity you know guide or entity.
entity.
entity. Uh and at that point he was calibrated
Uh and at that point he was calibrated
Uh and at that point he was calibrated well and three years later he crashed
well and three years later he crashed
well and three years later he crashed down extremely low and I I clinically
down extremely low and I I clinically
down extremely low and I I clinically suspected that temporal lobe epilepsy
suspected that temporal lobe epilepsy
suspected that temporal lobe epilepsy had triggered it. It created a
had triggered it. It created a
had triggered it. It created a vulnerability and in that vulnerability
vulnerability and in that vulnerability
vulnerability and in that vulnerability he was taken over by other entities. The
he was taken over by other entities. The
he was taken over by other entities. The same thing happens with people that are
same thing happens with people that are
same thing happens with people that are in good condition in a state of
in good condition in a state of
in good condition in a state of intoxication. You're now vulnerable to
intoxication. You're now vulnerable to
intoxication. You're now vulnerable to lower astral possession.
lower astral possession.
lower astral possession. A lot of people become quite demonic.
A lot of people become quite demonic.
A lot of people become quite demonic. And u
And u
And u so what happened to him was was a
so what happened to him was was a
so what happened to him was was a tragedy. Of course the cost to the world
tragedy. Of course the cost to the world
tragedy. Of course the cost to the world has been enormous because
has been enormous because
has been enormous because in in all those centuries since it's
in in all those centuries since it's
in in all those centuries since it's been one continuous war and the number
been one continuous war and the number
been one continuous war and the number of people who have died as a result of
of people who have died as a result of
of people who have died as a result of that is in the hundreds of millions. And
that is in the hundreds of millions. And
that is in the hundreds of millions. And the teachings that come out of Wahhabism
the teachings that come out of Wahhabism
the teachings that come out of Wahhabism calibrated at 90. Wahab calibrated
calibrated at 90. Wahab calibrated
calibrated at 90. Wahab calibrated himself was at 30.
himself was at 30.
himself was at 30. >> Oh, he was a person.
>> Oh, he was a person.
>> Oh, he was a person. >> Wahab was 30.
>> Wahab was 30.
>> Wahab was 30. So Wahab at 30 reinterpreted the
So Wahab at 30 reinterpreted the
So Wahab at 30 reinterpreted the teachings of Muhammad and came out with
teachings of Muhammad and came out with
teachings of Muhammad and came out with Wahhabism which is the backbone of
Wahhabism which is the backbone of
Wahhabism which is the backbone of al-Qaeda and all the rest. You see? So
al-Qaeda and all the rest. You see? So
al-Qaeda and all the rest. You see? So it's one of the great tragedies of uh
it's one of the great tragedies of uh
it's one of the great tragedies of uh human evolution.
Might
Might >> say it's a battle for dominion of this
>> say it's a battle for dominion of this
>> say it's a battle for dominion of this planet.
planet.
planet. He was a threat to that dominion. So
He was a threat to that dominion. So
He was a threat to that dominion. So they they caught him where he was
they they caught him where he was
they they caught him where he was vulnerable.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> First of all, I'd like to thank you for
>> First of all, I'd like to thank you for
>> First of all, I'd like to thank you for these tools and um
these tools and um
these tools and um >> yeah,
>> yeah,
>> yeah, >> Dr. Hawkins
>> Dr. Hawkins
>> Dr. Hawkins and um it's helped pull out some of
and um it's helped pull out some of
and um it's helped pull out some of those that I had in the closet too and
those that I had in the closet too and
those that I had in the closet too and hone them and start using them again.
hone them and start using them again.
hone them and start using them again. And I really appreciate this. And um I
And I really appreciate this. And um I
And I really appreciate this. And um I do have a question
do have a question
do have a question as as the the intellectual um does a
as as the the intellectual um does a
as as the the intellectual um does a person's
person's
person's educational background limit you as far
educational background limit you as far
educational background limit you as far as what you can achieve in the as far as
as what you can achieve in the as far as
as what you can achieve in the as far as >> in what word? Spiritual work.
>> in what word? Spiritual work.
>> in what word? Spiritual work. >> In spiritual work. Yes.
>> In spiritual work. Yes.
>> In spiritual work. Yes. >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> No. In fact, sometimes uh education gets
>> No. In fact, sometimes uh education gets
>> No. In fact, sometimes uh education gets in the way.
in the way.
in the way. to
to
to you know the teaching of brother uh
>> the practice of the presence of God
>> the practice of the presence of God >> is it just a little book
>> is it just a little book
>> is it just a little book the practice of the presence of God
the practice of the presence of God
the practice of the presence of God >> brother
>> brother
>> brother >> father what
>> father what
>> father what >> brother Lawrence
>> brother Lawrence
>> brother Lawrence >> brother
>> brother
>> brother >> yes
>> yes
>> yes >> brother
>> brother
>> brother >> yes the practice of the presence of god
>> yes the practice of the presence of god
>> yes the practice of the presence of god uh means that you know you could maybe
uh means that you know you could maybe
uh means that you know you could maybe finish third grade and still get it and
finish third grade and still get it and
finish third grade and still get it and uh you know the the the genuiness of his
uh you know the the the genuiness of his
uh you know the the the genuiness of his devotion and attention to it and all you
devotion and attention to it and all you
devotion and attention to it and all you know it's very uh it's a quite great
know it's very uh it's a quite great
know it's very uh it's a quite great classic.
classic.
classic. No, you don't even have to go past third
No, you don't even have to go past third
No, you don't even have to go past third grade, but you'd have to have somebody
grade, but you'd have to have somebody
grade, but you'd have to have somebody read it to you.
>> Well, thank you very much.
>> Well, thank you very much. >> The practice of the presence of God.
>> The practice of the presence of God.
>> The practice of the presence of God. Yes, brother Lawrence sits over the head
Yes, brother Lawrence sits over the head
Yes, brother Lawrence sits over the head of my bed.
of my bed.
of my bed. >> Okay. Thank you. Yeah,
>> Okay. Thank you. Yeah,
>> Okay. Thank you. Yeah, that's simplicity.
that's simplicity.
that's simplicity. Simplicity.
Simplicity.
Simplicity. >> Hey, Doc.
>> Hey, Doc.
>> Hey, Doc. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> I love you, Doc. And and I and I
>> I love you, Doc. And and I and I
>> I love you, Doc. And and I and I appreciate your work.
appreciate your work.
appreciate your work. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> You already signed my book.
>> You already signed my book.
>> You already signed my book. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> I wonder if you could give raise the
>> I wonder if you could give raise the
>> I wonder if you could give raise the consciousness level of everyone here. um
consciousness level of everyone here. um
consciousness level of everyone here. um just with a prayer maybe or a word and
just with a prayer maybe or a word and
just with a prayer maybe or a word and just just let us have a a little bit of
just just let us have a a little bit of
just just let us have a a little bit of what you have.
>> No,
>> No, >> I tried.
>> I tried.
>> I tried. >> I don't want to share.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> You bet. We'll take care of it.
>> You bet. We'll take care of it.
>> You bet. We'll take care of it. We do every meeting.
We do every meeting.
We do every meeting. >> It's my high joy of the day.
>> It's my high joy of the day.
>> It's my high joy of the day. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah. Hi.
>> My question is on the origin of evil. Do
>> My question is on the origin of evil. Do they arise out of the within the
they arise out of the within the
they arise out of the within the ultimate context potentiality of God?
ultimate context potentiality of God?
ultimate context potentiality of God? >> Does is God the uh creator of evil?
We're talking about different universes
We're talking about different universes now.
now.
now. There are different universes and this
There are different universes and this
There are different universes and this universe we talk about during these
universe we talk about during these
universe we talk about during these lectures and all pertains to this
lectures and all pertains to this
lectures and all pertains to this universe. It does not pertain to other
universe. It does not pertain to other
universe. It does not pertain to other dimensions.
dimensions.
dimensions. >> The human assumes that his dimension and
>> The human assumes that his dimension and
>> The human assumes that his dimension and the god that goes with his dimension and
the god that goes with his dimension and
the god that goes with his dimension and the religion and all explains
the religion and all explains
the religion and all explains everything. The universe has been going
everything. The universe has been going
everything. The universe has been going going on forever. It's increasing at the
going on forever. It's increasing at the
going on forever. It's increasing at the speed of light.
speed of light.
speed of light. So this little putsy planet here stuck
So this little putsy planet here stuck
So this little putsy planet here stuck in the middle of nowhere like the
in the middle of nowhere like the
in the middle of nowhere like the outhouse of civilization here doesn't
outhouse of civilization here doesn't
outhouse of civilization here doesn't include the explanation of all of
include the explanation of all of
include the explanation of all of creation. So I wouldn't over burden
creation. So I wouldn't over burden
creation. So I wouldn't over burden religion or spirituality to answer.
religion or spirituality to answer.
religion or spirituality to answer. I don't expect it to be omnisient.
I don't expect it to be omnisient.
I don't expect it to be omnisient. Omniscience is a quality of divinity. We
Omniscience is a quality of divinity. We
Omniscience is a quality of divinity. We don't need it. We don't need
don't need it. We don't need
don't need it. We don't need omniscience. to the reason I guess the
omniscience. to the reason I guess the
omniscience. to the reason I guess the reason I asked the question is that um
reason I asked the question is that um
reason I asked the question is that um they're saying that all like God is the
they're saying that all like God is the
they're saying that all like God is the source of all creation.
source of all creation.
source of all creation. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Then is God also the source of the
>> Then is God also the source of the
>> Then is God also the source of the possibility of evil?
possibility of evil?
possibility of evil? >> I don't know.
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know. Evil is a human term projected on that
Evil is a human term projected on that
Evil is a human term projected on that which denies the reality of God.
which denies the reality of God.
which denies the reality of God. >> Not necessarily opposed but denies it.
>> Not necessarily opposed but denies it.
>> Not necessarily opposed but denies it. So I don't want to think in terms of
So I don't want to think in terms of
So I don't want to think in terms of opposites.
opposites.
opposites. There's light and then there's no light
There's light and then there's no light
There's light and then there's no light and then we call it darkness. But
and then we call it darkness. But
and then we call it darkness. But darkness is not the opp the the enemy of
darkness is not the opp the the enemy of
darkness is not the opp the the enemy of light. There's not a war between dark
light. There's not a war between dark
light. There's not a war between dark and light.
and light.
and light. >> Yeah. I was thinking like how inclusive
>> Yeah. I was thinking like how inclusive
>> Yeah. I was thinking like how inclusive is God is it? But embrace all
is God is it? But embrace all
is God is it? But embrace all possibilities. that that which refuses
possibilities. that that which refuses
possibilities. that that which refuses or rejects the radiance of divinity
or rejects the radiance of divinity
or rejects the radiance of divinity um posthumously finds a different realm
um posthumously finds a different realm
um posthumously finds a different realm in which to evolve. You know, we don't
in which to evolve. You know, we don't
in which to evolve. You know, we don't have to worry about that.
have to worry about that.
have to worry about that. >> Okay. So, it's beyond concern for
>> Okay. So, it's beyond concern for
>> Okay. So, it's beyond concern for spiritual
spiritual
spiritual >> more an intellectual wonderment.
>> more an intellectual wonderment.
>> more an intellectual wonderment. Sometimes when we ask the kinesiology
Sometimes when we ask the kinesiology
Sometimes when we ask the kinesiology when we get off into
when we get off into
when we get off into uh uh wonderments like that, we often
uh uh wonderments like that, we often
uh uh wonderments like that, we often get a no.
get a no.
get a no. And the reason is what God's saying is
And the reason is what God's saying is
And the reason is what God's saying is you don't need it. Don't distract
you don't need it. Don't distract
you don't need it. Don't distract yourself. That's a whole different
yourself. That's a whole different
yourself. That's a whole different dimension. Do that some other lifetime.
dimension. Do that some other lifetime.
dimension. Do that some other lifetime. Wait until you're in some celestial
Wait until you're in some celestial
Wait until you're in some celestial realm and all the guys up there do that.
realm and all the guys up there do that.
realm and all the guys up there do that. See, but
See, but
See, but for you in this lifetime, it's not
for you in this lifetime, it's not
for you in this lifetime, it's not necessary to know that. So with
necessary to know that. So with
necessary to know that. So with humility, a lot of times we get to know
humility, a lot of times we get to know
humility, a lot of times we get to know and I'm satisfied with that. What he's
and I'm satisfied with that. What he's
and I'm satisfied with that. What he's God is saying is don't go there. I mean,
God is saying is don't go there. I mean,
God is saying is don't go there. I mean, leave it alone.
leave it alone.
leave it alone. >> It's a whole thing in itself. See, it
>> It's a whole thing in itself. See, it
>> It's a whole thing in itself. See, it could take a whole lifetime to resolve
could take a whole lifetime to resolve
could take a whole lifetime to resolve what you're asking here and you're going
what you're asking here and you're going
what you're asking here and you're going to open Pandora's box. Don't mess with
to open Pandora's box. Don't mess with
to open Pandora's box. Don't mess with it at this time.
it at this time.
it at this time. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> So, you know, and maybe you're not
>> So, you know, and maybe you're not
>> So, you know, and maybe you're not prepared for the answer. So, I always
prepared for the answer. So, I always
prepared for the answer. So, I always use kinesiology. Should we go there? A
use kinesiology. Should we go there? A
use kinesiology. Should we go there? A lot of times she'll get no, don't go
lot of times she'll get no, don't go
lot of times she'll get no, don't go there now.
there now.
there now. >> I see.
>> I see.
>> I see. >> Isn't that you can't go there somewhere
>> Isn't that you can't go there somewhere
>> Isn't that you can't go there somewhere or that it isn't legitimate, but now is
or that it isn't legitimate, but now is
or that it isn't legitimate, but now is not the time or the place.
not the time or the place.
not the time or the place. >> I see. Thank you.
>> I see. Thank you.
>> I see. Thank you. >> Also like to thank you very much because
>> Also like to thank you very much because
>> Also like to thank you very much because um of the all the all the benefit and
um of the all the all the benefit and
um of the all the all the benefit and teachings. Yes. able to expose to and
teachings. Yes. able to expose to and
teachings. Yes. able to expose to and I'll be going back to Hong Kong where I
I'll be going back to Hong Kong where I
I'll be going back to Hong Kong where I originally from about next month.
originally from about next month.
originally from about next month. >> Oh, wonderful.
>> Oh, wonderful.
>> Oh, wonderful. >> And I'd like to take this chance to
>> And I'd like to take this chance to
>> And I'd like to take this chance to Thank you very much.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> He's going to start a study group in
>> He's going to start a study group in
>> He's going to start a study group in Hong Kong.
>> So, he's going to start he's going to
>> So, he's going to start he's going to start a study group in Hong Kong.
>> I've never been to Hong Kong. I was to
>> I've never been to Hong Kong. I was to Shanghai.
Shanghai.
Shanghai. Uh, I never got to Hong Kong. No,
Uh, I never got to Hong Kong. No,
Uh, I never got to Hong Kong. No, it's quite a startling city when you
it's quite a startling city when you
it's quite a startling city when you look at it. Looks like New York City.
look at it. Looks like New York City.
look at it. Looks like New York City. Incredible.
Incredible.
Incredible. >> Hong Kong.
>> Hong Kong.
>> Hong Kong. >> Hello, doctor.
>> Hello, doctor.
>> Hello, doctor. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Uh, no questions.
>> Uh, no questions.
>> Uh, no questions. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Um, I'm from a study group here in
>> Um, I'm from a study group here in
>> Um, I'm from a study group here in Houston. Not here in Houston, but
Houston. Not here in Houston, but
Houston. Not here in Houston, but >> and just wanted to thank you for showing
>> and just wanted to thank you for showing
>> and just wanted to thank you for showing me the path.
me the path.
me the path. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> For signing all of our books. Thank you
>> For signing all of our books. Thank you
>> For signing all of our books. Thank you for be part being a part of a study
for be part being a part of a study
for be part being a part of a study group.
group.
group. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> That's how AA started out you know uh it
>> That's how AA started out you know uh it
>> That's how AA started out you know uh it was the first group and then they wrote
was the first group and then they wrote
was the first group and then they wrote they wrote down the 12 steps and
they wrote down the 12 steps and
they wrote down the 12 steps and eventually 12 traditions and other
eventually 12 traditions and other
eventually 12 traditions and other people just repeated them. Little groups
people just repeated them. Little groups
people just repeated them. Little groups popped up here hopped up there popped up
popped up here hopped up there popped up
popped up here hopped up there popped up there and now they're by the millions
there and now they're by the millions
there and now they're by the millions you know it just grassroots.
you know it just grassroots.
you know it just grassroots. >> Well the group in Houston is definitely
>> Well the group in Houston is definitely
>> Well the group in Houston is definitely growing.
growing.
growing. >> I love that. Yes. Beautiful.
>> I love that. Yes. Beautiful.
>> I love that. Yes. Beautiful. >> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much. >> When you got to speak there at the Unity
>> When you got to speak there at the Unity
>> When you got to speak there at the Unity Church in Houston
Church in Houston
Church in Houston >> Oh yes. So yes,
>> Oh yes. So yes,
>> Oh yes. So yes, >> it's a wonderful place.
>> it's a wonderful place.
>> it's a wonderful place. >> Thank you.
>> Have to watch it for all this time.
>> Have to watch it for all this time. >> Yeah, we have 15 minutes.
>> Yeah, we have 15 minutes.
>> Yeah, we have 15 minutes. >> Yes. Uh
>> Yes. Uh
>> Yes. Uh >> hi.
>> hi.
>> hi. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> I have a follow-up question to an
>> I have a follow-up question to an
>> I have a follow-up question to an earlier question.
earlier question.
earlier question. >> Um and it's about once we understand
>> Um and it's about once we understand
>> Um and it's about once we understand about attachments and that we are
about attachments and that we are
about attachments and that we are addicted to attachments. Mhm.
addicted to attachments. Mhm.
addicted to attachments. Mhm. >> Once we understand that,
>> Once we understand that,
>> Once we understand that, >> how do we then do that?
>> how do we then do that?
>> how do we then do that? >> They're difficult.
>> They're difficult.
>> They're difficult. Difficult. The attachment is difficult.
Difficult. The attachment is difficult.
Difficult. The attachment is difficult. Uh and uh it sometimes takes a lot of
Uh and uh it sometimes takes a lot of
Uh and uh it sometimes takes a lot of work to undo it. An attachment
work to undo it. An attachment
work to undo it. An attachment uh what is it that is appealing to you
uh what is it that is appealing to you
uh what is it that is appealing to you and and is it the child uh the
and and is it the child uh the
and and is it the child uh the adolescent the adult? Who is it is
adolescent the adult? Who is it is
adolescent the adult? Who is it is appealing to for one thing? For
appealing to for one thing? For
appealing to for one thing? For instance, I love kitties. Who is that
instance, I love kitties. Who is that
instance, I love kitties. Who is that appealing to? My kid just loves kitties,
appealing to? My kid just loves kitties,
appealing to? My kid just loves kitties, you know, the kid in me. See, so if a
you know, the kid in me. See, so if a
you know, the kid in me. See, so if a kitty gets run over, you know, the child
kitty gets run over, you know, the child
kitty gets run over, you know, the child in me is going to go into grief, right?
in me is going to go into grief, right?
in me is going to go into grief, right? >> The adult in me says, "Need another cat
>> The adult in me says, "Need another cat
>> The adult in me says, "Need another cat like a hole in the head right now."
So you could look at you know um games
So you could look at you know um games people play I think was interesting
people play I think was interesting
people play I think was interesting because the delineation of the child the
because the delineation of the child the
because the delineation of the child the adolescent adult in ourselves you know
adolescent adult in ourselves you know
adolescent adult in ourselves you know and see which identification is it
and see which identification is it
and see which identification is it that's having the problem that's helpful
that's having the problem that's helpful
that's having the problem that's helpful so all you can learn about it from
so all you can learn about it from
so all you can learn about it from various dimensions tends to loosen it
various dimensions tends to loosen it
various dimensions tends to loosen it you know what I'm saying
you know what I'm saying
you know what I'm saying >> we then say uh I surrender this to God
>> we then say uh I surrender this to God
>> we then say uh I surrender this to God is something we say we think we feel
is something we say we think we feel
is something we say we think we feel How do we actually surrender something?
How do we actually surrender something?
How do we actually surrender something? >> Oh yes. Okay. So you pray for God to uh
>> Oh yes. Okay. So you pray for God to uh
>> Oh yes. Okay. So you pray for God to uh relieve you of it. Uh that you want what
relieve you of it. Uh that you want what
relieve you of it. Uh that you want what you do is you substitute love for
you do is you substitute love for
you do is you substitute love for attachment.
attachment.
attachment. So you can love everything without
So you can love everything without
So you can love everything without necessarily being attached. Attached is
necessarily being attached. Attached is
necessarily being attached. Attached is wanting to control it. And uh love is
wanting to control it. And uh love is
wanting to control it. And uh love is letting it be free. So the energy in
letting it be free. So the energy in
letting it be free. So the energy in attachment in love is
attachment in love is
attachment in love is u the willingness to control it.
u the willingness to control it.
u the willingness to control it. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. >> If you love it, then nothing can
>> If you love it, then nothing can
>> If you love it, then nothing can interrupt the love. Attachment is
interrupt the love. Attachment is
interrupt the love. Attachment is something different.
something different.
something different. >> But thank you, sir.
>> But thank you, sir.
>> But thank you, sir. >> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. Uhhuh. There's more to that question. I mean,
There's more to that question. I mean,
There's more to that question. I mean, you're talking about a couple years of
you're talking about a couple years of
you're talking about a couple years of therapy. Really, you know,
therapy. Really, you know,
therapy. Really, you know, attachment is really such a proclivity
attachment is really such a proclivity
attachment is really such a proclivity of the human mind that takes a lot of
of the human mind that takes a lot of
of the human mind that takes a lot of work to not get attached to.
work to not get attached to.
work to not get attached to. >> Yep.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. >> Dr. Hawkins,
>> Dr. Hawkins,
>> Dr. Hawkins, >> I'm attached to nonattachment. You know
>> I'm attached to nonattachment. You know
>> I'm attached to nonattachment. You know what I'm saying?
what I'm saying?
what I'm saying? >> We have a we have a study group in a
>> We have a we have a study group in a
>> We have a we have a study group in a little town. We have a study group in a
little town. We have a study group in a
little town. We have a study group in a little town north of Fort Worth, Texas.
little town north of Fort Worth, Texas.
little town north of Fort Worth, Texas. >> And all of us want to want to know how
>> And all of us want to want to know how
>> And all of us want to want to know how much we appreciate you. We are not the
much we appreciate you. We are not the
much we appreciate you. We are not the same people
same people
same people >> and we've been doing this for a couple
>> and we've been doing this for a couple
>> and we've been doing this for a couple of years now. So, thank you so much.
of years now. So, thank you so much.
of years now. So, thank you so much. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> Yes. We spoken a couple places in Texas,
>> Yes. We spoken a couple places in Texas,
>> Yes. We spoken a couple places in Texas, didn't we? I've been to Austin to hear
didn't we? I've been to Austin to hear
didn't we? I've been to Austin to hear you and Houston and Unity Village and
you and Houston and Unity Village and
you and Houston and Unity Village and Kansas City.
Kansas City.
Kansas City. >> Oh yeah.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Oh yeah. >> Contribution to the planet.
>> Contribution to the planet.
>> Contribution to the planet. >> Thank you so much. Thank you.
>> I never realized how big Texas was. So I
>> I never realized how big Texas was. So I remember driving across the panhandle.
remember driving across the panhandle.
remember driving across the panhandle. Oh my god. Today is just And this is
Oh my god. Today is just And this is
Oh my god. Today is just And this is just the panhandle.
just the panhandle.
just the panhandle. Panhandle. Oh. Yeah. Hello. My
Panhandle. Oh. Yeah. Hello. My
Panhandle. Oh. Yeah. Hello. My >> ocean. It's so flat. You can see the
>> ocean. It's so flat. You can see the
>> ocean. It's so flat. You can see the ocean.
ocean.
ocean. >> My question is how does one find
>> My question is how does one find
>> My question is how does one find selfacceptance and acceptance for others
selfacceptance and acceptance for others
selfacceptance and acceptance for others and who they are?
and who they are?
and who they are? >> Acceptance
>> Acceptance
>> Acceptance means letting go criticalness
means letting go criticalness
means letting go criticalness means you realizing the difference
means you realizing the difference
means you realizing the difference between perception and essence.
between perception and essence.
between perception and essence. Uh maybe what you don't like is the way
Uh maybe what you don't like is the way
Uh maybe what you don't like is the way you're perceiving them. Perceptions are
you're perceiving them. Perceptions are
you're perceiving them. Perceptions are all projections out there. So
all projections out there. So
all projections out there. So um it's how you perceive of the perceive
um it's how you perceive of the perceive
um it's how you perceive of the perceive them and then how you contextualize that
them and then how you contextualize that
them and then how you contextualize that >> and it applies to myself like the way I
>> and it applies to myself like the way I
>> and it applies to myself like the way I perceive myself and
perceive myself and
perceive myself and >> Yes. Mhm.
>> Yes. Mhm.
>> Yes. Mhm. >> And how how do I it's I find it so hard
>> And how how do I it's I find it so hard
>> And how how do I it's I find it so hard >> you have to be willing to be um we put
>> you have to be willing to be um we put
>> you have to be willing to be um we put up virtues today. I said, you know, the
up virtues today. I said, you know, the
up virtues today. I said, you know, the world I grew up in, that was you have to
world I grew up in, that was you have to
world I grew up in, that was you have to be willing to be a good neighbor to
be willing to be a good neighbor to
be willing to be a good neighbor to yourself, to be cordial, to be polite to
yourself, to be cordial, to be polite to
yourself, to be cordial, to be polite to yourself, to be considerate, to be
yourself, to be considerate, to be
yourself, to be considerate, to be decent. I would just take the page of uh
decent. I would just take the page of uh
decent. I would just take the page of uh the virtues and apply them to yourself.
the virtues and apply them to yourself.
the virtues and apply them to yourself. Are you kind to yourself and kind to
Are you kind to yourself and kind to
Are you kind to yourself and kind to others? You know, are you appreciative?
others? You know, are you appreciative?
others? You know, are you appreciative? Are you hospitable?
Are you hospitable?
Are you hospitable? Are you fair with yourself? I mean, you
Are you fair with yourself? I mean, you
Are you fair with yourself? I mean, you know, just be a decent person with
know, just be a decent person with
know, just be a decent person with yourself.
yourself.
yourself. Are you going to give the guy a break?
Are you going to give the guy a break?
Are you going to give the guy a break? Let him off the hook. You know what I'm
Let him off the hook. You know what I'm
Let him off the hook. You know what I'm saying?
saying?
saying? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> To be goodnatured with yourself is is
>> To be goodnatured with yourself is is
>> To be goodnatured with yourself is is simple. You don't have to have something
simple. You don't have to have something
simple. You don't have to have something irriodite sounding, but benevolent.
irriodite sounding, but benevolent.
irriodite sounding, but benevolent. Benevolent. What? Out of respect for the
Benevolent. What? Out of respect for the
Benevolent. What? Out of respect for the gift of life. The gift of life is gift
gift of life. The gift of life is gift
gift of life. The gift of life is gift of divinity. out of respect for the gift
of divinity. out of respect for the gift
of divinity. out of respect for the gift of life itself. You now
of life itself. You now
of life itself. You now uh have the responsibility to treat it
uh have the responsibility to treat it
uh have the responsibility to treat it as a great gift.
as a great gift.
as a great gift. I always say worry about stewardship.
I always say worry about stewardship.
I always say worry about stewardship. What is your responsibility in return
What is your responsibility in return
What is your responsibility in return for the gift of life?
for the gift of life?
for the gift of life? I think to respect it to be be
I think to respect it to be be
I think to respect it to be be benevolent towards it the same as you
benevolent towards it the same as you
benevolent towards it the same as you would the little black beetle lying
would the little black beetle lying
would the little black beetle lying upside down in the alley. You know, you
upside down in the alley. You know, you
upside down in the alley. You know, you can be that kind to yourself, can you
can be that kind to yourself, can you
can be that kind to yourself, can you not? Yeah. And stop beating on yourself
not? Yeah. And stop beating on yourself
not? Yeah. And stop beating on yourself for making errors because errors are,
for making errors because errors are,
for making errors because errors are, you know, uh it's impossible to avoid
you know, uh it's impossible to avoid
you know, uh it's impossible to avoid errors. You know, the only people who
errors. You know, the only people who
errors. You know, the only people who don't make errors are people who don't
don't make errors are people who don't
don't make errors are people who don't do anything.
My favorite philosopher, columnist, a
My favorite philosopher, columnist, a black columnist.
black columnist.
black columnist. What's his name? Professor. Oh, he's
What's his name? Professor. Oh, he's
What's his name? Professor. Oh, he's wonderful. Yesterday his column was he
wonderful. Yesterday his column was he
wonderful. Yesterday his column was he has like thoughts passing thoughts on
has like thoughts passing thoughts on
has like thoughts passing thoughts on everything. When you have achieved 90%
everything. When you have achieved 90%
everything. When you have achieved 90% of a goal, think twice about the next
of a goal, think twice about the next
of a goal, think twice about the next 10%.
10%.
10%. Anybody read that yesterday? Who is
Anybody read that yesterday? Who is
Anybody read that yesterday? Who is that? Anyway,
that? Anyway,
that? Anyway, yeah,
yeah,
yeah, >> thank you.
>> thank you.
>> thank you. >> I think that's great. You achieve 90%
>> I think that's great. You achieve 90%
>> I think that's great. You achieve 90% think think carefully about the last
think think carefully about the last
think think carefully about the last 10%. I think that's wisdom.
10%. I think that's wisdom.
10%. I think that's wisdom. >> Thank you very much.
What's the name of that editorial?
What's the name of that editorial? >> I know you told me his name.
>> I know you told me his name.
>> I know you told me his name. >> He's so terrific. I don't I can't think
>> He's so terrific. I don't I can't think
>> He's so terrific. I don't I can't think of at the moment. Yeah,
of at the moment. Yeah,
of at the moment. Yeah, >> you told me his name.
>> you told me his name.
>> you told me his name. >> Calibrates at 480, by the way. Yeah.
>> Calibrates at 480, by the way. Yeah.
>> Calibrates at 480, by the way. Yeah. >> Dr. Hawkins, it's nice to see you again.
>> Dr. Hawkins, it's nice to see you again.
>> Dr. Hawkins, it's nice to see you again. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Um
>> Um
>> Um I met you in San Francisco.
I met you in San Francisco.
I met you in San Francisco. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Three years ago.
>> Three years ago.
>> Three years ago. >> And um your book changed my life.
>> And um your book changed my life.
>> And um your book changed my life. >> Yes. And I came from from addiction and
>> Yes. And I came from from addiction and
>> Yes. And I came from from addiction and hadn't read a book in 10 years and
hadn't read a book in 10 years and
hadn't read a book in 10 years and wasn't capable of comprehending a book.
wasn't capable of comprehending a book.
wasn't capable of comprehending a book. >> And I learned how to read by reading
>> And I learned how to read by reading
>> And I learned how to read by reading that book.
that book.
that book. >> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> Um,
>> Um,
>> Um, and the last time that I came up, we
and the last time that I came up, we
and the last time that I came up, we were running really short on time. And
were running really short on time. And
were running really short on time. And so I got a little signature here at the
so I got a little signature here at the
so I got a little signature here at the date.
date.
date. >> Um, but when I looked into your eyes, I
>> Um, but when I looked into your eyes, I
>> Um, but when I looked into your eyes, I was afraid. I I felt love, but my own
was afraid. I I felt love, but my own
was afraid. I I felt love, but my own ego um was afraid. afraid afraid of
ego um was afraid. afraid afraid of
ego um was afraid. afraid afraid of love.
love.
love. >> Afraid of everything.
>> Afraid of everything.
>> Afraid of everything. >> Oh, everything.
>> Oh, everything.
>> Oh, everything. >> Yeah. Good for you.
>> Yeah. Good for you.
>> Yeah. Good for you. >> And so, uh,
>> And so, uh,
>> And so, uh, >> it's best to start out being afraid of
>> it's best to start out being afraid of
>> it's best to start out being afraid of everything.
everything.
everything. >> That way, you're not going to be blind
>> That way, you're not going to be blind
>> That way, you're not going to be blind and be in denial.
and be in denial.
and be in denial. Start out at the bottom rung and work
Start out at the bottom rung and work
Start out at the bottom rung and work your way up. Yeah.
When you get to death, then all of it
When you get to death, then all of it disappears.
disappears.
disappears. And when you let go of all your fears,
And when you let go of all your fears,
And when you let go of all your fears, the last buried fear is one of death.
the last buried fear is one of death.
the last buried fear is one of death. Everything we fear is death. All of them
Everything we fear is death. All of them
Everything we fear is death. All of them when you finally let it all go is going
when you finally let it all go is going
when you finally let it all go is going to be death. And when you let go of the
to be death. And when you let go of the
to be death. And when you let go of the fear of death, then you're free of fear.
fear of death, then you're free of fear.
fear of death, then you're free of fear. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> And I was going to ask you um a
>> And I was going to ask you um a
>> And I was going to ask you um a question. I don't know if it's
question. I don't know if it's
question. I don't know if it's appropriate,
appropriate,
appropriate, >> right? But uh I work 12step program and
>> right? But uh I work 12step program and
>> right? But uh I work 12step program and uh I couldn't think of a better sponsor
uh I couldn't think of a better sponsor
uh I couldn't think of a better sponsor than you. So I thought uh that that on
than you. So I thought uh that that on
than you. So I thought uh that that on our spiritual level
our spiritual level
our spiritual level >> Yeah, you got it.
>> Yeah, you got it.
>> Yeah, you got it. >> If you'd be there.
>> If you'd be there.
>> If you'd be there. >> Yeah, you got it.
>> Yeah, you got it.
>> Yeah, you got it. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> And I got the energy from Bill.
>> And I got the energy from Bill.
>> And I got the energy from Bill. >> Right on.
The edit the editorial writer is Thomas
The edit the editorial writer is Thomas Soul. Thomas Saul Thomas comes up with
Soul. Thomas Saul Thomas comes up with
Soul. Thomas Saul Thomas comes up with incredible wisdom periodically. You
incredible wisdom periodically. You
incredible wisdom periodically. You know, that knocked me out.
>> There's one of those camera phones you
>> There's one of those camera phones you were talking about.
>> I'm hitting. Okay.
>> I'm hitting. Okay. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well, you go to the next life, you know.
Well, you go to the next life, you know.
Well, you go to the next life, you know. >> I'm not sure.
>> I'm not sure.
>> I'm not sure. >> We'll get it to work.
>> We'll get it to work.
>> We'll get it to work. >> Yeah. Okay. Hey, Nick, come on up. In
>> Yeah. Okay. Hey, Nick, come on up. In
>> Yeah. Okay. Hey, Nick, come on up. In the meantime, you might we can keep
the meantime, you might we can keep
the meantime, you might we can keep moving.
moving.
moving. >> Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. Well, just first of all, I want to
>> Yeah. Well, just first of all, I want to express my gratitude
express my gratitude
express my gratitude >> to you and to Susan for all the work and
>> to you and to Susan for all the work and
>> to you and to Susan for all the work and for all the teachings. It has been very,
for all the teachings. It has been very,
for all the teachings. It has been very, very helpful to me.
very helpful to me.
very helpful to me. >> One more time.
>> One more time.
>> One more time. >> Yeah. You don't have to get out of the
>> Yeah. You don't have to get out of the
>> Yeah. You don't have to get out of the way. They can go around me. All right.
way. They can go around me. All right.
way. They can go around me. All right. Then go around me.
Then go around me.
Then go around me. Do it.
Did it do it?
Did it do it? >> I think so.
>> I think so.
>> I think so. >> We'll just ignore them. We'll just
>> We'll just ignore them. We'll just
>> We'll just ignore them. We'll just continue. No problem.
continue. No problem.
continue. No problem. >> That's their problem.
>> That's their problem.
>> That's their problem. >> Just say thank you again for all your
>> Just say thank you again for all your
>> Just say thank you again for all your work and all your teachings.
work and all your teachings.
work and all your teachings. >> Um my question has basically to do with
>> Um my question has basically to do with
>> Um my question has basically to do with the uh levels of teaching of
the uh levels of teaching of
the uh levels of teaching of Christianity before and after the
Christianity before and after the
Christianity before and after the council of Nika.
council of Nika.
council of Nika. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Okay. After reading power versus force,
>> Okay. After reading power versus force,
>> Okay. After reading power versus force, at least my impression was that the
at least my impression was that the
at least my impression was that the levels of teaching of Christianity
levels of teaching of Christianity
levels of teaching of Christianity dropped because of the debate that was
dropped because of the debate that was
dropped because of the debate that was going on and they made a decision and
going on and they made a decision and
going on and they made a decision and Constantine was the one who because
Constantine was the one who because
Constantine was the one who because apparently for political reasons they
apparently for political reasons they
apparently for political reasons they declared that, you know, Jesus was just
declared that, you know, Jesus was just
declared that, you know, Jesus was just I mean he was divine in nature and and
I mean he was divine in nature and and
I mean he was divine in nature and and he was the only son of God and and I
he was the only son of God and and I
he was the only son of God and and I just got the impression that the that
just got the impression that the that
just got the impression that the that the nis creed was born or created I mean
the nis creed was born or created I mean
the nis creed was born or created I mean it was created in that time and for me
it was created in that time and for me
it was created in that time and for me it like a dualistic notion of God being
it like a dualistic notion of God being
it like a dualistic notion of God being in a place in a certain time manifested.
in a place in a certain time manifested.
in a place in a certain time manifested. Of course, it still manifests as
Of course, it still manifests as
Of course, it still manifests as consciousness as Christ consciousness.
consciousness as Christ consciousness.
consciousness as Christ consciousness. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> But what really is is troubling me is
>> But what really is is troubling me is
>> But what really is is troubling me is after reading truth versus falsehood,
after reading truth versus falsehood,
after reading truth versus falsehood, the level I truth of the nis creed is 97
the level I truth of the nis creed is 97
the level I truth of the nis creed is 97 something. So I just there's something
something. So I just there's something
something. So I just there's something that I'm not getting there or something
that I'm not getting there or something
that I'm not getting there or something that I don't understand.
that I don't understand.
that I don't understand. >> No, that's not the level of the nine
>> No, that's not the level of the nine
>> No, that's not the level of the nine creed. No,
creed. No,
creed. No, >> see the council of Na,
>> see the council of Na,
>> see the council of Na, they they voted on what should be in the
they they voted on what should be in the
they they voted on what should be in the Bible, what should not be in the Bible.
Bible, what should not be in the Bible.
Bible, what should not be in the Bible. You had the
You had the
You had the u
u
u >> but there was a vote uh declaring if
>> but there was a vote uh declaring if
>> but there was a vote uh declaring if Jesus was just a man or or
Jesus was just a man or or
Jesus was just a man or or >> No, I didn't I didn't take the council
>> No, I didn't I didn't take the council
>> No, I didn't I didn't take the council of Nika part. I just said what was the
of Nika part. I just said what was the
of Nika part. I just said what was the level of Christianity prior to and after
level of Christianity prior to and after
level of Christianity prior to and after to the whole the whole it's a whole
to the whole the whole it's a whole
to the whole the whole it's a whole study of uh religious history to study
study of uh religious history to study
study of uh religious history to study all what went on around the time of the
all what went on around the time of the
all what went on around the time of the council of Nika in the various schools
council of Nika in the various schools
council of Nika in the various schools and you know
and you know
and you know uh
uh
uh therefore
therefore
therefore I'm not attributing it to anything
I'm not attributing it to anything
I'm not attributing it to anything specifically however at the time they
specifically however at the time they
specifically however at the time they did vote on the books to be included in
did vote on the books to be included in
did vote on the books to be included in the Bible did they Huh. And they
the Bible did they Huh. And they
the Bible did they Huh. And they included
included
included >> the Old Testament and the book of
>> the Old Testament and the book of
>> the Old Testament and the book of Romans.
Romans.
Romans. >> Yes. They included the Old Testament in
>> Yes. They included the Old Testament in
>> Yes. They included the Old Testament in all the negativities that are in there.
all the negativities that are in there.
all the negativities that are in there. They also included uh Revelations which
They also included uh Revelations which
They also included uh Revelations which calibrates about 70. That brought the
calibrates about 70. That brought the
calibrates about 70. That brought the whole thing the whole thing down, did it
whole thing the whole thing down, did it
whole thing the whole thing down, did it not?
not?
not? >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> They just left it alone the way it was
>> They just left it alone the way it was
>> They just left it alone the way it was the way in the original first century
the way in the original first century
the way in the original first century caliber around 900. It was the teaching
caliber around 900. It was the teaching
caliber around 900. It was the teaching of the apostles.
of the apostles.
of the apostles. But then how that's heard by people
But then how that's heard by people
But then how that's heard by people interpreted later uh brings it down. But
interpreted later uh brings it down. But
interpreted later uh brings it down. But that's typical of any spiritual
that's typical of any spiritual
that's typical of any spiritual teaching.
teaching.
teaching. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> How the human ego he hears it and what
>> How the human ego he hears it and what
>> How the human ego he hears it and what it what it means. It doesn't know what
it what it means. It doesn't know what
it what it means. It doesn't know what it means because it's not that evolved.
it means because it's not that evolved.
it means because it's not that evolved. >> Okay. Just real quick, how's the
>> Okay. Just real quick, how's the
>> Okay. Just real quick, how's the translation of the eye of eye of the eye
translation of the eye of eye of the eye
translation of the eye of eye of the eye in Spanish going? Because
in Spanish going? Because
in Spanish going? Because >> in Spanish?
>> in Spanish?
>> in Spanish? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Uh I don't know. Um,
>> Uh I don't know. Um,
>> Uh I don't know. Um, >> all the books are translated into all
>> all the books are translated into all
>> all the books are translated into all the world's languages and they're all at
the world's languages and they're all at
the world's languages and they're all at some level
some level
some level translated in the out but um I don't
translated in the out but um I don't
translated in the out but um I don't know where it's at at this point,
know where it's at at this point,
know where it's at at this point, >> but it's on the program.
>> but it's on the program.
>> but it's on the program. >> We hope so.
>> We hope so.
>> We hope so. >> All the books are in the process of
>> All the books are in the process of
>> All the books are in the process of being translated by every country and
being translated by every country and
being translated by every country and >> um what happens in in foreign
>> um what happens in in foreign
>> um what happens in in foreign publications what they do is um one
publications what they do is um one
publications what they do is um one publisher will bid on the right to have
publisher will bid on the right to have
publisher will bid on the right to have that book and then we don't hear back
that book and then we don't hear back
that book and then we don't hear back from them. We don't know whether it's
from them. We don't know whether it's
from them. We don't know whether it's being translated or what. So, we're kind
being translated or what. So, we're kind
being translated or what. So, we're kind of in limbo for like a year sometimes
of in limbo for like a year sometimes
of in limbo for like a year sometimes until we hear back from saying yes, it's
until we hear back from saying yes, it's
until we hear back from saying yes, it's completed. So,
completed. So,
completed. So, >> I can't answer where we are on that at
>> I can't answer where we are on that at
>> I can't answer where we are on that at this point.
this point.
this point. >> Thank you very much. We have books in
>> Thank you very much. We have books in
>> Thank you very much. We have books in languages I never even heard of.
>> What was the one that was uh Bali? No,
>> What was the one that was uh Bali? No, it wasn't Bali. It was uh some weird.
it wasn't Bali. It was uh some weird.
it wasn't Bali. It was uh some weird. >> Anyway, it's very interesting. Oh,
>> Anyway, it's very interesting. Oh,
>> Anyway, it's very interesting. Oh, >> there's interest in somebody's devices.
>> It's a pleasure to be here.
>> It's a pleasure to be here. >> You bet. You bet. You bet. You bet.
>> You bet. You bet. You bet. You bet.
>> You bet. You bet. You bet. You bet. >> He's got a camera that works.
>> He's got a camera that works.
>> He's got a camera that works. >> It's got to wait for the flash to
>> It's got to wait for the flash to
>> It's got to wait for the flash to starting it.
starting it.
starting it. >> Uhoh.
>> Uhoh.
>> Uhoh. >> Charge the flash.
>> Charge the flash.
>> Charge the flash. >> We're almost there.
>> We're almost there.
>> We're almost there. >> All these new fangle gadgets, I tell
>> All these new fangle gadgets, I tell
>> All these new fangle gadgets, I tell you. I don't know.
you. I don't know.
you. I don't know. >> You get them from Walgreens. You You
>> You get them from Walgreens. You You
>> You get them from Walgreens. You You throw them back in the basket. They give
throw them back in the basket. They give
throw them back in the basket. They give you back the picture. That's the end of
you back the picture. That's the end of
you back the picture. That's the end of the story, you know. Oh,
the story, you know. Oh,
the story, you know. Oh, >> there we go.
>> there we go.
>> there we go. >> Uh oh. Quit filming. Okay.
>> Uh oh. Quit filming. Okay.
>> Uh oh. Quit filming. Okay. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> Thank you. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Thank you. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Thank you. Yeah. Yeah. >> Um
>> Um
>> Um >> Dr. Hawkins, this is an honor and a
>> Dr. Hawkins, this is an honor and a
>> Dr. Hawkins, this is an honor and a privilege and I just on behalf of the
privilege and I just on behalf of the
privilege and I just on behalf of the whole group, thanks so much for
whole group, thanks so much for
whole group, thanks so much for everything you've done in your entire
everything you've done in your entire
everything you've done in your entire lifetime. I am in a synopsis. I I'm an
lifetime. I am in a synopsis. I I'm an
lifetime. I am in a synopsis. I I'm an avid reader. I've finished reading all
avid reader. I've finished reading all
avid reader. I've finished reading all of your books.
of your books.
of your books. >> Bam. Bam.
>> Bam. Bam.
>> Bam. Bam. >> And
>> And
>> And >> Oh, boy. That's good. Now, here's the
>> Oh, boy. That's good. Now, here's the
>> Oh, boy. That's good. Now, here's the thing. The the principle that really
thing. The the principle that really
thing. The the principle that really hits home to me the most is the
hits home to me the most is the
hits home to me the most is the principle of positionalities and
principle of positionalities and
principle of positionalities and attachments. And those are the creation
attachments. And those are the creation
attachments. And those are the creation of the ego.
of the ego.
of the ego. >> Am I right?
>> Am I right?
>> Am I right? >> Projections. Yeah.
>> Projections. Yeah.
>> Projections. Yeah. >> Right. So,
>> Right. So,
>> Right. So, >> see, when he was asking about
>> see, when he was asking about
>> see, when he was asking about attachments before, I didn't have a
attachments before, I didn't have a
attachments before, I didn't have a chance to think about it a second and
chance to think about it a second and
chance to think about it a second and after I thought about a second. What
after I thought about a second. What
after I thought about a second. What you're attached to is the value that you
you're attached to is the value that you
you're attached to is the value that you have projected onto something.
have projected onto something.
have projected onto something. And uh so my answer now is complete.
And uh so my answer now is complete.
And uh so my answer now is complete. You know, you think you're attached to
You know, you think you're attached to
You know, you think you're attached to that. No, it's the value. You're
that. No, it's the value. You're
that. No, it's the value. You're attached to what you've projected onto
attached to what you've projected onto
attached to what you've projected onto it. You've glamorized it by the energy
it. You've glamorized it by the energy
it. You've glamorized it by the energy of like Alice Bailey says,
of like Alice Bailey says,
of like Alice Bailey says, >> right? Okay. So, here's my question.
>> right? Okay. So, here's my question.
>> right? Okay. So, here's my question. >> You've enhanced its value by your own
>> You've enhanced its value by your own
>> You've enhanced its value by your own projection. Yeah. I can live without
projection. Yeah. I can live without
projection. Yeah. I can live without another cat. See, but if I go into
another cat. See, but if I go into
another cat. See, but if I go into depression, if something happens to one
depression, if something happens to one
depression, if something happens to one of these kittens, and that's a
of these kittens, and that's a
of these kittens, and that's a detachment. See? So I'm I'm really
detachment. See? So I'm I'm really
detachment. See? So I'm I'm really trying to evolve spiritually. But I do
trying to evolve spiritually. But I do
trying to evolve spiritually. But I do know that for me personally, my big
know that for me personally, my big
know that for me personally, my big stumbling block, my obstacle is the ego.
stumbling block, my obstacle is the ego.
stumbling block, my obstacle is the ego. And the ego's got a huge amount of fear.
And the ego's got a huge amount of fear.
And the ego's got a huge amount of fear. And the ego says, I will not let go. I
And the ego says, I will not let go. I
And the ego says, I will not let go. I am in command. So I if you could please
am in command. So I if you could please
am in command. So I if you could please tell me what is a technique for me to
tell me what is a technique for me to
tell me what is a technique for me to let the ego relax and let go of fear.
let the ego relax and let go of fear.
let the ego relax and let go of fear. You can't just let go of the ego as
You can't just let go of the ego as
You can't just let go of the ego as though it's a piece of ice, an ice cube
though it's a piece of ice, an ice cube
though it's a piece of ice, an ice cube or something. You know, it's a
or something. You know, it's a
or something. You know, it's a complexity that's evolved since the
complexity that's evolved since the
complexity that's evolved since the beginning of time. We show you how the
beginning of time. We show you how the
beginning of time. We show you how the ego began with the amoeba and the
ego began with the amoeba and the
ego began with the amoeba and the protozoa. We mouse up through the and
protozoa. We mouse up through the and
protozoa. We mouse up through the and that's multiple identifications. Inside
that's multiple identifications. Inside
that's multiple identifications. Inside of the human you, there's an animal you.
of the human you, there's an animal you.
of the human you, there's an animal you. >> Right.
>> Right.
>> Right. >> Right. Under appropriate conditions, you
>> Right. Under appropriate conditions, you
>> Right. Under appropriate conditions, you come out swinging. Right. Your animal's
come out swinging. Right. Your animal's
come out swinging. Right. Your animal's going to come right up.
going to come right up.
going to come right up. >> Right.
>> Right.
>> Right. >> So, there's all kinds of aspects of it.
>> So, there's all kinds of aspects of it.
>> So, there's all kinds of aspects of it. And it really takes uh really years of
And it really takes uh really years of
And it really takes uh really years of uh looking at yourself, introspection,
uh looking at yourself, introspection,
uh looking at yourself, introspection, surrendering what comes up, asking God
surrendering what comes up, asking God
surrendering what comes up, asking God uh to be help uh picking up spiritual
uh to be help uh picking up spiritual
uh to be help uh picking up spiritual energy groups like this that give you
energy groups like this that give you
energy groups like this that give you the power to handle it. And of course,
the power to handle it. And of course,
the power to handle it. And of course, you're doing the right thing by first of
you're doing the right thing by first of
you're doing the right thing by first of all bringing in as much information as
all bringing in as much information as
all bringing in as much information as you can bring into yourself,
you can bring into yourself,
you can bring into yourself, >> right? And then as the stuff comes up,
>> right? And then as the stuff comes up,
>> right? And then as the stuff comes up, it should trigger a relationship to what
it should trigger a relationship to what
it should trigger a relationship to what you've read and how it would apply, you
you've read and how it would apply, you
you've read and how it would apply, you know.
know.
know. >> And then I'm there's no way I'm even
>> And then I'm there's no way I'm even
>> And then I'm there's no way I'm even near 800. But when you were at that
near 800. But when you were at that
near 800. But when you were at that threshold of fear, what technique did
threshold of fear, what technique did
threshold of fear, what technique did you use to go break through that fear?
you use to go break through that fear?
you use to go break through that fear? >> Trust.
>> Trust.
>> Trust. >> Trust.
>> Trust. >> Trust. See, so that's why the spiritual
>> Trust. See, so that's why the spiritual
>> Trust. See, so that's why the spiritual teacher has to be somebody who has the
teacher has to be somebody who has the
teacher has to be somebody who has the power of having done it. The aura of the
power of having done it. The aura of the
power of having done it. The aura of the teacher is what it is because of having
teacher is what it is because of having
teacher is what it is because of having done it. See, not having read it. So I
done it. See, not having read it. So I
done it. See, not having read it. So I had in my aura already the knowingness.
had in my aura already the knowingness.
had in my aura already the knowingness. All fear is illusion. Surrender it. So
All fear is illusion. Surrender it. So
All fear is illusion. Surrender it. So the fear of death which came up and it
the fear of death which came up and it
the fear of death which came up and it was strong. I going to get you. It came
was strong. I going to get you. It came
was strong. I going to get you. It came up like terror of death. The
up like terror of death. The
up like terror of death. The knowingness, there was just a
knowingness, there was just a
knowingness, there was just a knowingness there. No voice, no other,
knowingness there. No voice, no other,
knowingness there. No voice, no other, no archangel, you know, no archangel
no archangel, you know, no archangel
no archangel, you know, no archangel Gabriel, nobody out there. There was
Gabriel, nobody out there. There was
Gabriel, nobody out there. There was just the the knowingness coming out of
just the the knowingness coming out of
just the the knowingness coming out of the vibrational energy of the aura.
the vibrational energy of the aura.
the vibrational energy of the aura. All fear is illusion. Surrender it no
All fear is illusion. Surrender it no
All fear is illusion. Surrender it no matter what. And I surrendered my life
matter what. And I surrendered my life
matter what. And I surrendered my life and the fear came up like terror. And
and the fear came up like terror. And
and the fear came up like terror. And then
Okay.
Okay. >> Thank you. Now you have that energy
>> Thank you. Now you have that energy
>> Thank you. Now you have that energy yourself forever.
yourself forever.
yourself forever. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> That's the truth.
>> That's the truth.
>> That's the truth. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> That's Is that it?
>> That's Is that it?
>> That's Is that it? >> Oh,
>> Oh,
>> Oh, >> wowy.
>> wowy.
>> wowy. >> One more.
>> One more.
>> One more. >> Come on up.
>> Come on up.
>> Come on up. >> That's it.
>> That's it.
>> That's it. >> We have one more and then that's
>> We have one more and then that's
>> We have one more and then that's >> All right. Oh, boy.
>> All right. Oh, boy.
>> All right. Oh, boy. >> The big guy here.
>> The big guy here.
>> The big guy here. >> Happy birthday to you.
>> Happy birthday to you.
>> Happy birthday to you. >> Yeah. Thank you. Uh, did humans
>> Yeah. Thank you. Uh, did humans
>> Yeah. Thank you. Uh, did humans originate on the planet Earth?
originate on the planet Earth?
originate on the planet Earth? >> I don't know.
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Is there a timeline to it?
>> Is there a timeline to it?
>> Is there a timeline to it? >> I haven't tracked it out.
>> I haven't tracked it out.
>> I haven't tracked it out. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Uh,
>> Uh,
>> Uh, all I know is from what I've done done
all I know is from what I've done done
all I know is from what I've done done so far,
so far,
so far, >> is that life has evolved into higher and
>> is that life has evolved into higher and
>> is that life has evolved into higher and higher life forms.
higher life forms.
higher life forms. >> And, you know, human the human homo
>> And, you know, human the human homo
>> And, you know, human the human homo sapien didn't arrive, you know, began to
sapien didn't arrive, you know, began to
sapien didn't arrive, you know, began to emerge. What was it 600,000 years ago or
emerge. What was it 600,000 years ago or
emerge. What was it 600,000 years ago or something?
something?
something? >> Yeah. Yeah. And it was a different
>> Yeah. Yeah. And it was a different
>> Yeah. Yeah. And it was a different offshoot than Neanderthal. The
offshoot than Neanderthal. The
offshoot than Neanderthal. The Neanderthal man and then these various
Neanderthal man and then these various
Neanderthal man and then these various jokers coming off the beam.
jokers coming off the beam.
jokers coming off the beam. But we have our own specific lineage.
But we have our own specific lineage.
But we have our own specific lineage. See?
See?
See? >> And was
>> And was
>> And was >> so it's evolutionary to me. Creation is
>> so it's evolutionary to me. Creation is
>> so it's evolutionary to me. Creation is evolutionary.
evolutionary.
evolutionary. So God's will is that this life form
So God's will is that this life form
So God's will is that this life form evolve. You see this is the potentiality
evolve. You see this is the potentiality
evolve. You see this is the potentiality of evolution. And we become more and
of evolution. And we become more and
of evolution. And we become more and more spiritually evolved as we evolve,
more spiritually evolved as we evolve,
more spiritually evolved as we evolve, you know. So
you know. So
you know. So in that way it seems to me is as though
in that way it seems to me is as though
in that way it seems to me is as though you've earned karmic credit.
you've earned karmic credit.
you've earned karmic credit. >> Let's say the minute you're you're born
>> Let's say the minute you're you're born
>> Let's say the minute you're you're born uh somebody goes bum bum and you're
uh somebody goes bum bum and you're
uh somebody goes bum bum and you're enlightened. H
now what is your authority in the
now what is your authority in the universe after that? You didn't earn it.
universe after that? You didn't earn it.
universe after that? You didn't earn it. It wasn't really yours. It was a
It wasn't really yours. It was a
It wasn't really yours. It was a imposition.
imposition.
imposition. >> Right?
>> Right?
>> Right? >> You remember asking for it? No. Because
>> You remember asking for it? No. Because
>> You remember asking for it? No. Because there wasn't anybody that evolved to ask
there wasn't anybody that evolved to ask
there wasn't anybody that evolved to ask for it, was there?
for it, was there?
for it, was there? So it seems to me like potentiality
So it seems to me like potentiality
So it seems to me like potentiality uh is is divine
uh is is divine
uh is is divine intention that we become the awareness
intention that we become the awareness
intention that we become the awareness of of truth of that which we are because
of of truth of that which we are because
of of truth of that which we are because we have been it all.
we have been it all.
we have been it all. >> It's almost like a godly experience that
>> It's almost like a godly experience that
>> It's almost like a godly experience that and like recapitulating
and like recapitulating
and like recapitulating the evolution of divinity almost is it
the evolution of divinity almost is it
the evolution of divinity almost is it not so?
not so?
not so? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Yeah. So
>> Yeah. So
>> Yeah. So >> because God's lonely and wanted panels
>> because God's lonely and wanted panels
>> because God's lonely and wanted panels to hand, you know what it's like. I
to hand, you know what it's like. I
to hand, you know what it's like. I mean, you know what I mean? If you
mean, you know what I mean? If you
mean, you know what I mean? If you haven't been everything in the universe
haven't been everything in the universe
haven't been everything in the universe and evolved to this level,
and evolved to this level,
and evolved to this level, >> you're not going to make anybody to be
>> you're not going to make anybody to be
>> you're not going to make anybody to be with. So God wanted a pal. So he got
with. So God wanted a pal. So he got
with. So God wanted a pal. So he got he's got us all growing like kittens in
he's got us all growing like kittens in
he's got us all growing like kittens in his garden, you know.
his garden, you know.
his garden, you know. >> So when humans became humans,
>> So when humans became humans,
>> So when humans became humans, >> huh? Yeah.
>> huh? Yeah.
>> huh? Yeah. >> When humans became humans, was there an
>> When humans became humans, was there an
>> When humans became humans, was there an event for that or was that just a
event for that or was that just a
event for that or was that just a progression of
progression of
progression of >> No, energy became that energy. energy of
>> No, energy became that energy. energy of
>> No, energy became that energy. energy of consciousness began. Yeah. So within
consciousness began. Yeah. So within
consciousness began. Yeah. So within consciousness is omni potentiality
consciousness is omni potentiality
consciousness is omni potentiality >> then. So it wasn't individual becoming
>> then. So it wasn't individual becoming
>> then. So it wasn't individual becoming individual. It was the energy of of
individual. It was the energy of of
individual. It was the energy of of consciousness itself.
consciousness itself.
consciousness itself. Light the light of God to me is
Light the light of God to me is
Light the light of God to me is consciousness
consciousness
consciousness >> of of infinite omniresence and infinite
>> of of infinite omniresence and infinite
>> of of infinite omniresence and infinite power. And when the the energy field of
power. And when the the energy field of
power. And when the the energy field of consciousness encounters matter out of
consciousness encounters matter out of
consciousness encounters matter out of that arises life. See, because only life
that arises life. See, because only life
that arises life. See, because only life can only arise out of life. There can be
can only arise out of life. There can be
can only arise out of life. There can be no extinguishing of life. The law of the
no extinguishing of life. The law of the
no extinguishing of life. The law of the conservation of life is that life cannot
conservation of life is that life cannot
conservation of life is that life cannot be extinguished. The law of conservation
be extinguished. The law of conservation
be extinguished. The law of conservation of matter of energy. And it's funny that
of matter of energy. And it's funny that
of matter of energy. And it's funny that man never noticed the law of the
man never noticed the law of the
man never noticed the law of the conservation of life. It's impossible to
conservation of life. It's impossible to
conservation of life. It's impossible to destroy life. Why? Life is nonlinear. So
destroy life. Why? Life is nonlinear. So
destroy life. Why? Life is nonlinear. So what would you destroy it with? A
what would you destroy it with? A
what would you destroy it with? A hatchet. A hatchet is linear.
hatchet. A hatchet is linear.
hatchet. A hatchet is linear. >> What would destroy life? There's nothing
>> What would destroy life? There's nothing
>> What would destroy life? There's nothing that has the capacity to destroy life.
that has the capacity to destroy life.
that has the capacity to destroy life. Therefore, life is eternal. Therefore,
Therefore, life is eternal. Therefore,
Therefore, life is eternal. Therefore, the fear of death. When you let go of
the fear of death. When you let go of
the fear of death. When you let go of the fear of death, you see, the door
the fear of death, you see, the door
the fear of death, you see, the door opens to eternity.
opens to eternity.
opens to eternity. That which always was, which always will
That which always was, which always will
That which always was, which always will be, is not different than that which you
be, is not different than that which you
be, is not different than that which you are. That came into me in the snowbank
are. That came into me in the snowbank
are. That came into me in the snowbank beyond all time, beyond all conditions.
beyond all time, beyond all conditions.
beyond all time, beyond all conditions. That which you are has always been and
That which you are has always been and
That which you are has always been and will always be. That's a knowingness.
will always be. That's a knowingness.
will always be. That's a knowingness. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. >> And that's the truth.
>> And that's the truth.
>> And that's the truth. >> Okay, that's it.
>> Okay, that's it.
>> Okay, that's it. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> And what I just said is the absolute
>> And what I just said is the absolute
>> And what I just said is the absolute truth at the level of 1,00.
I thank you so much.
I thank you so much. As you know, you are my blessing. You
As you know, you are my blessing. You
As you know, you are my blessing. You are my blessing. You are my gift from
are my blessing. You are my gift from
are my blessing. You are my gift from God. God says, "I love you." And here
God. God says, "I love you." And here
God. God says, "I love you." And here you are.
you are.
you are. Anybody's um greatest ambition come
Anybody's um greatest ambition come
Anybody's um greatest ambition come true. to be surrounded by so much love,
true. to be surrounded by so much love,
true. to be surrounded by so much love, to be blessed by you all, to be blessed
to be blessed by you all, to be blessed
to be blessed by you all, to be blessed by your presence and uh is with
by your presence and uh is with
by your presence and uh is with gratitude that I bid you. I thank you
gratitude that I bid you. I thank you
gratitude that I bid you. I thank you for being with me today. God bless you
for being with me today. God bless you
for being with me today. God bless you all.