soul.
two
two more.
Thank
Thank you.
>> Yes,
>> Dr.
>> Dr. Hawkins.
>> Dr. Hawkins. Um,
>> Dr. Hawkins. Um, you
>> Dr. Hawkins. Um, you said
>> Dr. Hawkins. Um, you said everything
>> Dr. Hawkins. Um, you said everything is
happening
happening spontaneously.
>> Everything
>> Everything happens
>> Everything happens autonomously
>> of
>> of its
>> Everything happens autonomously
>> of its own
>> of
>> of its
>> of its own.
>> of its own. Um,
>> potentiality
>> potentiality emerging
>> of its own. Um,
>> potentiality emerging as
>> potentiality emerging as actuality
as
as a
as a consequence
as a consequence of
as a consequence of intention.
>> So,
>> So, isn't
as a consequence of intention.
>> So, isn't isn't
>> So, isn't isn't intention,
as a consequence of intention.
>> So, isn't isn't intention, dedication,
devotion,
devotion, and
devotion, and faith
devotion, and faith happening
devotion, and faith happening on
devotion, and faith happening on its
own?
>> Isn't
>> Isn't what
>> isn't
>> isn't like
>> Isn't what
>> isn't like intention,
>> isn't like intention, dedication,
devotion,
devotion, and
devotion, and faith
devotion, and faith happening
devotion, and faith happening on
devotion, and faith happening on its
own?
own? Yes.
>> But
>> But then
>> But then but
>> But then but then
>> But then but then you
>> But then but then you say
>> But then but then you say that
>> But then but then you say that u
>> the
>> the likelihood
>> But then but then you say that u
>> the likelihood is
>> the likelihood is uh
>> But then but then you say that u
>> the likelihood is uh the
>> the likelihood is uh the likelihood
>> But then but then you say that u
>> the likelihood is uh the likelihood you
see
instead
instead of
see
instead of determination
instead of determination or
see
instead of determination or causality
what
what you're
what you're dealing
what you're dealing with
what you're dealing with is
what you're dealing with is likelihoods
likelihood.
likelihood. So
what you're dealing with is likelihoods
likelihood. So the
likelihood. So the height
what you're dealing with is likelihoods
likelihood. So the height the
likelihood. So the height the likelihood
of
of the
of the thing
of the thing manifesting
is
is increased
of the thing manifesting
is increased by
is increased by intention
of the thing manifesting
is increased by intention and
commitment.
commitment. Yes.
commitment. Yes. But
commitment. Yes. But not
commitment. Yes. But not caused
commitment. Yes. But not caused by
commitment. Yes. But not caused by it,
you
you know.
So
So then
So then um
So then um I'm
So then um I'm maybe
So then um I'm maybe confused
So then um I'm maybe confused about
intention.
intention. It
So then um I'm maybe confused about
intention. It seems
intention. It seems like
So then um I'm maybe confused about
intention. It seems like if
intention. It seems like if everything's
happening
happening on
happening on its
happening on its own,
>> what's
>> what's your
happening on its own,
>> what's your intention
>> what's your intention coming
happening on its own,
>> what's your intention coming up
>> what's your intention coming up here
now?
>> To
>> To clarify
now?
>> To clarify this
>> To clarify this doubt.
>> What
>> to
>> to clarify
>> What
>> to clarify this
>> to clarify this doubt.
>> What
>> What is
>> What is the
>> What is the doubt?
>> What is the doubt? Whether
>> What is the doubt? Whether anything
>> What is the doubt? Whether anything is
happening
happening spontaneously
>> What is the doubt? Whether anything is
happening spontaneously or
happening spontaneously or is
>> What is the doubt? Whether anything is
happening spontaneously or is it
>> if
>> if everything
>> if everything is
>> if everything is happening
spontaneously?
>> Yes.
>> Then
>> Then why
>> Yes.
>> Then why have
>> Then why have intention?
>> Yes.
>> Then why have intention? Why
>> Then why have intention? Why have
>> Yes.
>> Then why have intention? Why have all
this?
this? It's
this? It's happening
this? It's happening on
this? It's happening on its
this? It's happening on its own,
this? It's happening on its own, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. But
this? It's happening on its own, right?
>> Yeah. But it's
>> Yeah. But it's happening
this? It's happening on its own, right?
>> Yeah. But it's happening on
>> Yeah. But it's happening on its
this? It's happening on its own, right?
>> Yeah. But it's happening on its own
>> Yeah. But it's happening on its own when
local
local conditions
local conditions permit.
One
One of
local conditions permit.
One of the
One of the one
local conditions permit.
One of the one of
One of the one of the
local conditions permit.
One of the one of the local
One of the one of the local conditions
is
is intention.
is intention. I
is intention. I see.
is intention. I see. Yeah.
One
One of
is intention. I see. Yeah.
One of the
One of the local
is intention. I see. Yeah.
One of the local conditions
One of the local conditions is
is intention. I see. Yeah.
One of the local conditions is that
One of the local conditions is that that
saying
saying yes
saying yes be
saying yes be there.
saying yes be there. So
saying yes be there. So the
saying yes be there. So the thing
doesn't
doesn't tip
saying yes be there. So the thing
doesn't tip till
doesn't tip till somebody
saying yes be there. So the thing
doesn't tip till somebody says
doesn't tip till somebody says yes.
saying yes be there. So the thing
doesn't tip till somebody says yes. And
that
that was
that was what
that was what tipped
that was what tipped it.
>> Okay.
>> So
>> So me
>> So me being
>> So me being here
>> So me being here is
>> So me being here is my
>> So me being here is my intention.
It's
It's a
>> So me being here is my intention.
It's a spontaneously
It's a spontaneously happening.
>> So me being here is my intention.
It's a spontaneously happening. Yes.
As
As a
As a consequence
As a consequence of
As a consequence of your
As a consequence of your intention,
As a consequence of your intention, it's
spontaneous.
spontaneous. You
As a consequence of your intention, it's
spontaneous. You see,
spontaneous. You see, you're
As a consequence of your intention, it's
spontaneous. You see, you're you're
trying
trying to
trying to get
trying to get unhooked
trying to get unhooked from
trying to get unhooked from the
limitation
limitation of
trying to get unhooked from the
limitation of causality
because
because you
because you desire
because you desire it
because you desire it or
because you desire it or intended
because you desire it or intended and
then
then it
because you desire it or intended and
then it happens.
then it happens. You
because you desire it or intended and
then it happens. You think
then it happens. You think there's
because you desire it or intended and
then it happens. You think there's a
causal
causal connection.
causal connection. They're
causal connection. They're not
causal connection. They're not they're
not
not connected
because
because you
because you can
because you can also
because you can also not
because you can also not be
because you can also not be here
because you can also not be here just
because you can also not be here just as
easily.
uh
uh your
uh your decision
uh your decision then
uh your decision then pulls
uh your decision then pulls in
uh your decision then pulls in the
uh your decision then pulls in the field
and
and the
uh your decision then pulls in the field
and the field
and the field intensifies
uh your decision then pulls in the field
and the field intensifies the
likelihood.
likelihood. This
likelihood. This is
likelihood. This is mathematically
likelihood. This is mathematically true
in
in quantum
likelihood. This is mathematically true
in quantum mechanics,
in quantum mechanics, you
likelihood. This is mathematically true
in quantum mechanics, you know.
Okay.
Okay. The
Okay. The more
Okay. The more a
Okay. The more a thing
Okay. The more a thing happens,
Okay. The more a thing happens, the
Okay. The more a thing happens, the more
it's
it's likely
Okay. The more a thing happens, the more
it's likely to
it's likely to happen.
Okay. The more a thing happens, the more
it's likely to happen. What's
it's likely to happen. What's that
called?
called? There's
called? There's a
called? There's a principle.
Um
Um well,
called? There's a principle.
Um well, I'm
Um well, I'm not
called? There's a principle.
Um well, I'm not into
Um well, I'm not into my
called? There's a principle.
Um well, I'm not into my left
Um well, I'm not into my left brain
right
right now.
right now. There's
right now. There's a
right now. There's a principle
right now. There's a principle that
right now. There's a principle that the
greater
greater a
right now. There's a principle that the
greater a thing
greater a thing happens,
right now. There's a principle that the
greater a thing happens, the
greater a thing happens, the more
right now. There's a principle that the
greater a thing happens, the more likely
it
it is
it is to
it is to happen.
it is to happen. It's
it is to happen. It's called
it is to happen. It's called the
something
something or
it is to happen. It's called the
something or the
something or the principle.
Is
Is it
Is it the
Is it the Heisenberg
Is it the Heisenberg principle?
>> Yeah.
>> Talking
>> Talking about
>> Talking about the
>> Talking about the Heisenberg
>> Talking about the Heisenberg or
>> Heisenberg?
>> No,
>> No, no,
>> No, no, the
>> No, no, the Heisenberg.
>> That's
>> That's not
>> that's
>> that's a
>> that's a principle.
>> It's
>> It's another
>> that's a principle.
>> It's another thing.
>> No,
>> No, there's
>> No, there's a
>> No, there's a there's
>> No, there's a there's a
>> No, there's a there's a observation
>> in
>> in quantum
>> No, there's a there's a observation
>> in quantum mechanics.
>> in quantum mechanics. What's
>> No, there's a there's a observation
>> in quantum mechanics. What's the
>> in quantum mechanics. What's the word
for
for it?
>> I
>> I can't
for it?
>> I can't think
>> I can't think of
for it?
>> I can't think of the
>> I can't think of the name
for it?
>> I can't think of the name for
>> I can't think of the name for it.
for it?
>> I can't think of the name for it. Uh
>> I can't think of the name for it. Uh the
the
the zero.
the zero. No,
the zero. No, not
the zero. No, not zero.
the zero. No, not zero. The
the zero. No, not zero. The something
>> is
>> is principle
>> equator.
>> equator. No,
>> the
>> the more
>> equator. No,
>> the more often
>> the more often a
>> equator. No,
>> the more often a selection
>> the more often a selection is
>> equator. No,
>> the more often a selection is made,
>> the more often a selection is made, the
more
more likely
more likely it's
more likely it's going
more likely it's going to
more likely it's going to be
more likely it's going to be made
more likely it's going to be made in
more likely it's going to be made in the
future.
>> No,
>> No, it's
>> No, it's got
>> No, it's got a
>> No, it's got a it's
>> No, it's got a it's got
>> No, it's got a it's got a
>> No, it's got a it's got a proper
>> No, it's got a it's got a proper title
in
in the
>> No, it's got a it's got a proper title
in the quantum
in the quantum mechanics.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Anyway,
>> Anyway, you'll
>> Anyway, you'll find
>> Anyway, you'll find it.
>> Okay.
>> Can
>> Can I
>> Can I take
>> Can I take a
>> Can I take a picture
>> Can I take a picture with
>> Can I take a picture with you?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> You
>> You you
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> You you can
>> You you can look
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> You you can look up
>> You you can look up what's
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> You you can look up what's his
>> You you can look up what's his name
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> You you can look up what's his name on
the
the internet.
the internet. Uh
>> Howard
>> Howard St.
the internet. Uh
>> Howard St. Step
>> I'm
>> I'm not
>> I'm not very
>> I'm not very left
>> I'm not very left brain
>> I'm not very left brain today.
>> I'm not very left brain today. This
>> I'm not very left brain today. This is
>> I'm not very left brain today. This is a
bad
bad day
>> I'm not very left brain today. This is a
bad day to
bad day to ask
>> I'm not very left brain today. This is a
bad day to ask me
bad day to ask me specifics.
>> Henry.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Out
>> Henry.
>> Yeah. Out of
>> Yeah. Out of Berkeley.
>> Henry.
>> Sherry.
>> Henry
>> Henry stab.
>> Henry stab. Stap.
>> Okay.
>> I
>> I think
>> I think it's
>> I think it's a
>> I think it's a Anyway,
>> I think it's a Anyway, it's
>> I think it's a Anyway, it's a
>> I think it's a Anyway, it's a commonly
known
known word
>> I think it's a Anyway, it's a commonly
known word that
known word that the
>> I think it's a Anyway, it's a commonly
known word that the more
known word that the more often
>> I think it's a Anyway, it's a commonly
known word that the more often you
select
select a
select a make
select a make a
select a make a certain
select a make a certain selection,
select a make a certain selection, the
greater
greater the
select a make a certain selection, the
greater the likelihood
greater the likelihood that
select a make a certain selection, the
greater the likelihood that selection
will
will continue.
will continue. That's
will continue. That's why
will continue. That's why we're
will continue. That's why we're here.
Men
Men and
will continue. That's why we're here.
Men and women
Men and women were
will continue. That's why we're here.
Men and women were at
Men and women were at that
will continue. That's why we're here.
Men and women were at that for
centuries.
Yeah.
Yeah. The
centuries.
Yeah. The more
Yeah. The more likely
centuries.
Yeah. The more likely one
Yeah. The more likely one phenomena
happens,
happens, the
happens, the greater
happens, the greater the
happens, the greater the stat
statistical
statistical likelihood
happens, the greater the stat
statistical likelihood that
statistical likelihood that it
happens, the greater the stat
statistical likelihood that it will
recur.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Okay.
recur.
>> Okay. Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you.
>> It's
>> It's not
>> It's not by
>> It's not by causality.
>> It's not by causality. It's
>> It's not by causality. It's by
>> It's not by causality. It's by the
>> It's not by causality. It's by the shift
of
of the
>> It's not by causality. It's by the shift
of the field.
It's
It's not
It's not the
It's not the Xeno
It's not the Xeno effect.
It's not the Xeno effect. I
It's not the Xeno effect. I think
It's not the Xeno effect. I think Xeno
effect.
>> No,
>> No, it's
>> No, it's I
>> No, it's I think
>> No, it's I think it's
>> No, it's I think it's X.
>> No, it's I think it's X. Xeno
>> No, it's I think it's X. Xeno effect.
>> Yeah.
>> Anybody
>> Anybody got
>> Anybody got a
>> Anybody got a diction?
>> It
>> It is.
>> Anybody got a diction?
>> It is. I
>> It is. I think
>> Anybody got a diction?
>> It is. I think it's
>> It is. I think it's called
>> Anybody got a diction?
>> It is. I think it's called the
>> It is. I think it's called the Xeno
effect.
>> I'm
>> I'm not
effect.
>> I'm not an
>> I'm not an expert
effect.
>> I'm not an expert in
>> I'm not an expert in quantum
effect.
>> I'm not an expert in quantum mechanics.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you
>> Oh, you have a
>> Oh, you have a flash
>> Oh, you have a flash on
>> Oh, you have a flash on your
>> Oh, you have a flash on your finger.
You
You have
>> Oh, you have a flash on your finger.
You have to
You have to put
>> Oh, you have a flash on your finger.
You have to put a
You have to put a quarter
>> Oh, you have a flash on your finger.
You have to put a quarter in.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, I
>> Yeah, I think
>> Yeah, I think it's
>> Yeah, I think it's xeno
>> Yeah, I think it's xeno effect.
Xeno
Xeno Xeno.
>> Yes.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. This
>> Yes.
>> Hello. This is
>> Hello. This is uh
>> Yes.
>> Hello. This is uh the
>> Hello. This is uh the first
>> Yes.
>> Hello. This is uh the first time
>> Hello. This is uh the first time I'm
meeting
meeting you
meeting you personally
meeting you personally and
meeting you personally and it's
meeting you personally and it's very
meeting you personally and it's very big
for
for me.
I've
I've been
I've been aware
I've been aware of
I've been aware of you
I've been aware of you for
I've been aware of you for three
I've been aware of you for three years
and
and I
I've been aware of you for three years
and I wrote
and I wrote to
I've been aware of you for three years
and I wrote to you
and I wrote to you about
I've been aware of you for three years
and I wrote to you about a
and I wrote to you about a small
community
community in
community in BC
that
that gathers
community in BC
that gathers around
that gathers around your
community in BC
that gathers around your uh
that gathers around your uh work
community in BC
that gathers around your uh work 108
mile.
>> Yeah.
>> And
>> And uh
>> And uh just
>> And uh just love
>> And uh just love from
>> And uh just love from all
>> And uh just love from all of
>> And uh just love from all of them.
>> And uh just love from all of them. Uh
four
four of
>> And uh just love from all of them. Uh
four of us
four of us are
>> And uh just love from all of them. Uh
four of us are here
four of us are here today.
>> And uh just love from all of them. Uh
four of us are here today. So
four of us are here today. So actually
one,
one, two,
one, two, seven
one, two, seven of
one, two, seven of us
one, two, seven of us are
one, two, seven of us are here
one, two, seven of us are here today.
>> Wow.
>> Wow. Wow.
one, two, seven of us are here today.
>> Wow. Wow. Huh.
I
I want
I want to
I want to thank
I want to thank you
I want to thank you for
recontextualizing
um
um the
um the spiritual
um the spiritual rape
um the spiritual rape experience
um the spiritual rape experience of
um the spiritual rape experience of this
morning.
morning. I
um the spiritual rape experience of this
morning. I I've
morning. I I've had
um the spiritual rape experience of this
morning. I I've had perhaps
morning. I I've had perhaps two
experiences
experiences of
experiences of that.
>> The
>> The first
experiences of that.
>> The first one
>> The first one leaving
experiences of that.
>> The first one leaving me
>> in
>> in a
>> in a near-death
>> in a near-death state
>> and
>> and I
>> in a near-death state
>> and I connected
>> and I connected with
>> in a near-death state
>> and I connected with a
>> and I connected with a white
>> in a near-death state
>> and I connected with a white brotherhood
at
at that
at that time.
>> Oh
>> Oh yes.
>> And
>> And I
>> And I actually
>> And I actually connected
>> And I actually connected it
>> And I actually connected it seemed
almost
almost behind
>> And I actually connected it seemed
almost behind the
almost behind the white
>> And I actually connected it seemed
almost behind the white brotherhood.
almost behind the white brotherhood. The
influence
influence was
influence was so
influence was so huge
influence was so huge and
influence was so huge and so
experientially
experientially changing
um
um seemed
um seemed like
um seemed like archangel
um seemed like archangel substance
um seemed like archangel substance and
>> the
>> the white
um seemed like archangel substance and
>> the white brotherhood
>> the white brotherhood is a
um seemed like archangel substance and
>> the white brotherhood is a celestial
realm.
>> Yes.
>> Mhm.
>> And
>> And the
>> Mhm.
>> And the presence
>> And the presence um
>> Mhm.
>> And the presence um of
>> And the presence um of it
>> Mhm.
>> And the presence um of it was
>> And the presence um of it was as
>> Mhm.
>> And the presence um of it was as I
>> And the presence um of it was as I say
>> really
>> really helpful.
>> really helpful. And
>> in
>> in the
>> really helpful. And
>> in the second
>> in the second experience
>> really helpful. And
>> in the second experience I
>> in the second experience I had
>> really helpful. And
>> in the second experience I had is
>> in the second experience I had is how
>> really helpful. And
>> in the second experience I had is how I
met
met you.
met you. the
met you. the second
met you. the second experience
met you. the second experience of
met you. the second experience of uh
met you. the second experience of uh say
spiritual
spiritual devastation
met you. the second experience of uh say
spiritual devastation is
spiritual devastation is is
met you. the second experience of uh say
spiritual devastation is is how
spiritual devastation is is how I
met you. the second experience of uh say
spiritual devastation is is how I met
you.
you. So
you. So thank
you. So thank you
you. So thank you for
you. So thank you for that.
>> I'm
>> I'm very
you. So thank you for that.
>> I'm very glad.
>> Um
>> Um in
>> Um in the
>> Um in the book
>> Um in the book map
>> Um in the book map which
>> Um in the book map which u
>> Um in the book map which u map
>> map
>> that
>> that the
>> that the white
>> that the white brotherhood
>> that the white brotherhood was
>> that the white brotherhood was um
>> that the white brotherhood was um played
out.
out. It
>> that the white brotherhood was um played
out. It was
out. It was supposedly
>> that the white brotherhood was um played
out. It was supposedly the
out. It was supposedly the white
brotherhood
brotherhood was
brotherhood was described
brotherhood was described in
brotherhood was described in map
>> oh
>> map.
>> map. They
>> map. They speak
>> map. They speak about
>> map. They speak about um
>> map. They speak about um something
called
called mayazm.
>> They
>> They talk
>> They talk about
>> mayism.
>> mayism. They
>> They talk about
>> mayism. They explain
>> mayism. They explain something.
>> They talk about
>> mayism. They explain something. We
>> mayism. They explain something. We don't
we're
we're not
we're not familiar.
>> Go
>> Go ahead.
we're not familiar.
>> Go ahead. Go
>> Go ahead. Go ahead.
we're not familiar.
>> Go ahead. Go ahead. Go
>> Go ahead. Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Yeah.
>> Well,
>> Well, um
>> Yeah.
>> Well, um myism
>> Well, um myism it
>> Yeah.
>> Well, um myism it would
>> Well, um myism it would seem
>> Yeah.
>> Well, um myism it would seem has
>> Well, um myism it would seem has has
much
much the
much the same
much the same implication
much the same implication as
much the same implication as um
much the same implication as um say
karmic
um
um predisposition.
>> Yeah.
>> So
>> So I
>> So I I
>> So I I was
>> So I I was I
>> So I I was I was
>> So I I was I was simply
>> So I I was I was simply going
>> So I I was I was simply going to
>> So I I was I was simply going to ask
>> So I I was I was simply going to ask you
if
if there
>> So I I was I was simply going to ask you
if there was
if there was a
>> So I I was I was simply going to ask you
if there was a relationship
if there was a relationship to
>> So I I was I was simply going to ask you
if there was a relationship to mayazism
and
and karma.
and karma. I'm
and karma. I'm not
and karma. I'm not familiar
and karma. I'm not familiar with
and karma. I'm not familiar with the
tech
tech technical
and karma. I'm not familiar with the
tech technical term
tech technical term myasma
and karma. I'm not familiar with the
tech technical term myasma as
tech technical term myasma as it's
and karma. I'm not familiar with the
tech technical term myasma as it's used
there.
>> In
>> In traditional
there.
>> In traditional medicine,
>> In traditional medicine, myasms
there.
>> In traditional medicine, myasms were
the
the influence
the influence of
the influence of the
the influence of the environment,
>> you
>> you know,
the influence of the environment,
>> you know, the
>> you know, the influence
the influence of the environment,
>> you know, the influence to
>> you know, the influence to close
the influence of the environment,
>> you know, the influence to close the
window
window at
window at night,
window at night, not
window at night, not to
window at night, not to let
window at night, not to let the
window at night, not to let the night
myasm
myasm come
window at night, not to let the night
myasm come in.
myasm come in. You
window at night, not to let the night
myasm come in. You see?
>> So,
>> So, it's
>> So, it's sort
>> So, it's sort of
>> So, it's sort of a
>> So, it's sort of a diffuse
>> So, it's sort of a diffuse energy
>> So, it's sort of a diffuse energy myasm
in
in a
>> So, it's sort of a diffuse energy myasm
in a general
in a general generic
>> So, it's sort of a diffuse energy myasm
in a general generic kind
in a general generic kind of
>> So, it's sort of a diffuse energy myasm
in a general generic kind of a
in a general generic kind of a saying.
I'm
I'm not
I'm not familiar
I'm not familiar as
I'm not familiar as a
I'm not familiar as a technical
I'm not familiar as a technical term.
And
And and
I'm not familiar as a technical term.
And and with
And and with genetics
I'm not familiar as a technical term.
And and with genetics as
And and with genetics as well,
I'm not familiar as a technical term.
And and with genetics as well, are
And and with genetics as well, are are
genetics
genetics also
genetics also what
genetics also what you
genetics also what you would
genetics also what you would consider
part
part of
genetics also what you would consider
part of the
part of the karmic
genetics also what you would consider
part of the karmic uh
part of the karmic uh potentiality
genetics also what you would consider
part of the karmic uh potentiality of
part of the karmic uh potentiality of a
person?
>> Yeah,
that's
that's the
that's the mechanics
that's the mechanics of
that's the mechanics of it.
>> The
>> The the
that's the mechanics of it.
>> The the mechanics
>> The the mechanics of
that's the mechanics of it.
>> The the mechanics of it
>> The the mechanics of it finds
that's the mechanics of it.
>> The the mechanics of it finds uh
>> The the mechanics of it finds uh genetic
expression.
Yeah.
Yeah. But
expression.
Yeah. But that's
Yeah. But that's the
expression.
Yeah. But that's the consequence
Yeah. But that's the consequence of
expression.
Yeah. But that's the consequence of the
karma.
karma. That's
karma. That's the
karma. That's the consequence,
you
you know,
karma. That's the consequence,
you know, to
you know, to to
karma. That's the consequence,
you know, to to be
you know, to to be born
karma. That's the consequence,
you know, to to be born a
you know, to to be born a human
karma. That's the consequence,
you know, to to be born a human is
already,
already, as
already, as the
already, as the Buddha
already, as the Buddha said,
already, as the Buddha said, one
already, as the Buddha said, one of
already, as the Buddha said, one of the
greatest
greatest of
already, as the Buddha said, one of the
greatest of all
marvels
marvels in
marvels in the
marvels in the universe.
To
>> be
>> be born
>> be born a
>> be born a human
>> be born a human is
>> be born a human is extremely
>> be born a human is extremely extremely
rare.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Can
>> Thank you. Can I
>> Thank you. Can I have
>> Thank you. Can I have my
>> Thank you. Can I have my picture
>> Thank you. Can I have my picture taken
with
with you,
>> Thank you. Can I have my picture taken
with you, too?
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. To
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. To be
>> Yeah. To be born
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. To be born a
>> Yeah. To be born a human
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. To be born a human is
>> Yeah. To be born a human is already
the
the consequence
the consequence of
the consequence of incredible
the consequence of incredible good
karma.
To
To have
To have heard
To have heard of
To have heard of enlightenment
To have heard of enlightenment is
To have heard of enlightenment is even
more
more incredible.
Most
Most incredible
Most incredible all
Most incredible all of
Most incredible all of all
Most incredible all of all is
Most incredible all of all is to
Most incredible all of all is to have
heard
heard of
Most incredible all of all is to have
heard of it
heard of it and
Most incredible all of all is to have
heard of it and to
heard of it and to pursue
Most incredible all of all is to have
heard of it and to pursue it.
That
That is
That is the
That is the most
That is the most rare
That is the most rare of
That is the most rare of all.
That is the most rare of all. Therefore,
we
we have
That is the most rare of all. Therefore,
we have the
we have the most
That is the most rare of all. Therefore,
we have the most rare
we have the most rare of
That is the most rare of all. Therefore,
we have the most rare of all
we have the most rare of all people
That is the most rare of all. Therefore,
we have the most rare of all people on
the
the planet
the planet in
the planet in this
the planet in this room
the planet in this room today.
Yep.
>> Mhm.
>> All
>> All fear
>> Mhm.
>> All fear is
>> All fear is illusion
>> Mhm.
>> All fear is illusion right
>> now.
>> now. We
>> now. We got
>> now. We got you.
>> now. We got you. You're
>> now. We got you. You're in
>> now. We got you. You're in the
>> now. We got you. You're in the hot
>> now. We got you. You're in the hot seat.
>> You're
>> You're going
>> now. We got you. You're in the hot seat.
>> You're going to
>> You're going to appear
>> now. We got you. You're in the hot seat.
>> You're going to appear like
>> You're going to appear like an
>> now. We got you. You're in the hot seat.
>> You're going to appear like an idiot
>> You're going to appear like an idiot and
then
then die.
then die. Is
then die. Is that
then die. Is that all
then die. Is that all you
then die. Is that all you worry
then die. Is that all you worry about?
It's
It's about
then die. Is that all you worry about?
It's about it.
>> So,
>> So, don't
>> So, don't worry.
>> So, don't worry. We're
>> So, don't worry. We're nothing
>> So, don't worry. We're nothing in
>> So, don't worry. We're nothing in the
series
series to
>> So, don't worry. We're nothing in the
series to begin
series to begin with.
>> So, don't worry. We're nothing in the
series to begin with. Right.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> All
>> All right.
>> I
>> I just
>> I just wanted
>> I just wanted to
>> I just wanted to first
>> I just wanted to first of
>> I just wanted to first of all,
>> I just wanted to first of all, thank
>> I just wanted to first of all, thank you
very
very much.
>> I just wanted to first of all, thank you
very much. Your
very much. Your work
>> I just wanted to first of all, thank you
very much. Your work has
very much. Your work has meant
>> so
>> so much
>> so much to
>> so much to me
>> so much to me personally.
>> And
>> And uh
>> so much to me personally.
>> And uh I
>> And uh I did
>> so much to me personally.
>> And uh I did have
>> And uh I did have one
>> so much to me personally.
>> And uh I did have one question
>> And uh I did have one question on
>> so much to me personally.
>> And uh I did have one question on the
differences
differences between
differences between uh
differences between uh luciferic
differences between uh luciferic and
satanic
satanic temptation,
>> how
>> how they
>> how they relate.
>> Two
>> Two different
>> how they relate.
>> Two different types
>> Two different types of
>> how they relate.
>> Two different types of energy.
>> Two different types of energy. The
luciferic
luciferic is
luciferic is what
luciferic is what turns
luciferic is what turns people
luciferic is what turns people into
um
they
they turn
they turn things
they turn things into
they turn things into the
they turn things into the opposite
like
like killing
they turn things into the opposite
like killing a
like killing a busload
they turn things into the opposite
like killing a busload of
like killing a busload of children
they turn things into the opposite
like killing a busload of children will
please
please God
please God because
please God because it's
please God because it's a
please God because it's a it's
please God because it's a it's a
please God because it's a it's a great
good
good you
please God because it's a it's a great
good you know
so
so turning
so turning things
so turning things into
so turning things into their
so turning things into their opposite
uh
uh supporting
so turning things into their opposite
uh supporting that
uh supporting that which
so turning things into their opposite
uh supporting that which is
uh supporting that which is making
so turning things into their opposite
uh supporting that which is making it
integrous
integrous to
integrous to support
integrous to support non-
integrous to support non- integrity
that's
that's political
integrous to support non- integrity
that's political warp
that's political warp of
integrous to support non- integrity
that's political warp of the
that's political warp of the current
culture
take
take that
culture
take that which
take that which is
culture
take that which is non-
take that which is non- integrous
culture
take that which is non- integrous and
try
try to
try to make
try to make non-integrity
try to make non-integrity integrous
try to make non-integrity integrous and
feel
feel superior
try to make non-integrity integrous and
feel superior about
feel superior about it
try to make non-integrity integrous and
feel superior about it at
feel superior about it at the
try to make non-integrity integrous and
feel superior about it at the same
feel superior about it at the same time.
>> And
>> And that
>> And that that's
>> And that that's luciferic.
>> That's
>> That's lucifer.
>> And that that's luciferic.
>> That's lucifer. Satanic
>> That's lucifer. Satanic is
>> And that that's luciferic.
>> That's lucifer. Satanic is cruelty,
anger,
anger, war,
anger, war, rage,
anger, war, rage, torture.
And
And the
anger, war, rage, torture.
And the most
And the most dangerous
anger, war, rage, torture.
And the most dangerous of
And the most dangerous of all
anger, war, rage, torture.
And the most dangerous of all cultures,
you
you see
you see both
you see both the
you see both the luciferic
you see both the luciferic and
you see both the luciferic and the
satanic.
world
world leaders
world leaders right
world leaders right now
world leaders right now who
world leaders right now who demonstrate
both
both the
world leaders right now who demonstrate
both the satanic
both the satanic we
world leaders right now who demonstrate
both the satanic we will
both the satanic we will blow
world leaders right now who demonstrate
both the satanic we will blow you
both the satanic we will blow you all
world leaders right now who demonstrate
both the satanic we will blow you all up
and
and the
and the inversion
and the inversion of
and the inversion of the
and the inversion of the luciferic
seeing
seeing evil
and the inversion of the luciferic
seeing evil is
seeing evil is good
and the inversion of the luciferic
seeing evil is good and
seeing evil is good and good
and the inversion of the luciferic
seeing evil is good and good is
seeing evil is good and good is evil
dangerous
dangerous combo
>> thanks
>> thanks doc
>> thank
>> thank you
>> can
>> can I
>> thank you
>> can I get
>> can I get a
>> thank you
>> can I get a picture
>> sure
like
like taking
>> sure
like taking the
like taking the naivity
>> sure
like taking the naivity of
like taking the naivity of children
>> sure
like taking the naivity of children and
teaching
teaching them
teaching them to
teaching them to become
teaching them to become gunfather.
You
You see
teaching them to become gunfather.
You see what
You see what I'm
teaching them to become gunfather.
You see what I'm saying?
You see what I'm saying? Remember
teaching them to become gunfather.
You see what I'm saying? Remember the
Hitler
Hitler youth
Hitler youth in
Hitler youth in their
Hitler youth in their innocent
Hitler youth in their innocent and
Hitler youth in their innocent and trust
like
like a
Hitler youth in their innocent and trust
like a bunch
like a bunch of
Hitler youth in their innocent and trust
like a bunch of boy
like a bunch of boy scouts
Hitler youth in their innocent and trust
like a bunch of boy scouts going
like a bunch of boy scouts going in
Hitler youth in their innocent and trust
like a bunch of boy scouts going in the
camp.
camp. They
camp. They salute
camp. They salute the
camp. They salute the fear
camp. They salute the fear out
camp. They salute the fear out of
camp. They salute the fear out of their
innocence,
innocence, out
camp. They salute the fear out of their
innocence, out of
innocence, out of their
camp. They salute the fear out of their
innocence, out of their trust,
innocence, out of their trust, out
camp. They salute the fear out of their
innocence, out of their trust, out of
their
their goodness
their goodness is
their goodness is what
their goodness is what they
their goodness is what they do.
their goodness is what they do. They
their goodness is what they do. They did
that.
that. Then
their goodness is what they do. They did
that. Then he
that. Then he twisted
their goodness is what they do. They did
that. Then he twisted that
that. Then he twisted that around
their goodness is what they do. They did
that. Then he twisted that around for
that. Then he twisted that around for a
luciferic
luciferic and
luciferic and a
luciferic and a satanic
luciferic and a satanic purpose.
Woe
Woe to
luciferic and a satanic purpose.
Woe to those
Woe to those who
luciferic and a satanic purpose.
Woe to those who what
Woe to those who what the
luciferic and a satanic purpose.
Woe to those who what the children
Woe to those who what the children said
Jesus.
Jesus. Woe
Jesus. Woe unto
Jesus. Woe unto those
Jesus. Woe unto those who
Jesus. Woe unto those who want
Jesus. Woe unto those who want the
children.
Huh?
Huh? Do
Huh? Do you
Huh? Do you remember
>> to
>> to what?
>> I'm
>> I'm sorry.
>> I'm sorry. I
>> I'm sorry. I was
>> I'm sorry. I was waiting
>> I'm sorry. I was waiting for
>> I'm sorry. I was waiting for his
question.
question. What?
>> Anybody
>> Anybody go
>> Anybody go to
>> Anybody go to Sunday
>> Anybody go to Sunday school?
>> Anybody go to Sunday school? Woe.
Woe
Woe unto
>> Anybody go to Sunday school? Woe.
Woe unto those
Woe unto those who
>> Anybody go to Sunday school? Woe.
Woe unto those who what
Woe unto those who what the
>> Anybody go to Sunday school? Woe.
Woe unto those who what the children
said
said Jesus
said Jesus Christ.
What's
What's the
said Jesus Christ.
What's the missing
What's the missing word?
>> Rape.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, I
>> Rape.
>> Yeah, I guess
>> Yeah, I guess so.
>> Rape.
>> Yeah, I guess so. My
>> Yeah, I guess so. My question
>> Rape.
>> Yeah, I guess so. My question is
>> Yeah, I guess so. My question is about
this
this pesky
this pesky ego
this pesky ego thing.
this pesky ego thing. Where
this pesky ego thing. Where is
this pesky ego thing. Where is the
this pesky ego thing. Where is the off
switch?
switch? because
this pesky ego thing. Where is the off
switch? because I
switch? because I have
this pesky ego thing. Where is the off
switch? because I have I
switch? because I have I don't
this pesky ego thing. Where is the off
switch? because I have I don't know
switch? because I have I don't know I
went
went I
went I was
went I was listening
went I was listening to
went I was listening to some
went I was listening to some old
went I was listening to some old I
went I was listening to some old I was
listening
listening to
went I was listening to some old I was
listening to some
listening to some old
went I was listening to some old I was
listening to some old uh
listening to some old uh lectures
went I was listening to some old I was
listening to some old uh lectures and
the
the question
the question was
the question was you
the question was you know
the question was you know people
the question was you know people are
the question was you know people are on
a
a path
the question was you know people are on
a path for
a path for 20
the question was you know people are on
a path for 20 years
a path for 20 years and
the question was you know people are on
a path for 20 years and they
a path for 20 years and they don't
the question was you know people are on
a path for 20 years and they don't move
forward
forward one
forward one point
forward one point and
forward one point and the
forward one point and the realization
that
that you
forward one point and the realization
that you had
that you had shared
forward one point and the realization
that you had shared was
that you had shared was it's
forward one point and the realization
that you had shared was it's the
that you had shared was it's the ego's
reluctance
reluctance to
reluctance to give
reluctance to give complete
reluctance to give complete sovereignty
to
to the
reluctance to give complete sovereignty
to the Lord
to the Lord and
reluctance to give complete sovereignty
to the Lord and I
to the Lord and I sense
reluctance to give complete sovereignty
to the Lord and I sense that
to the Lord and I sense that and
reluctance to give complete sovereignty
to the Lord and I sense that and life
was
was good
>> and
>> and then
was good
>> and then it's
>> and then it's come
was good
>> and then it's come back
>> and then it's come back full
was good
>> and then it's come back full force
>> and then it's come back full force and
>> well
>> well it's
>> well it's it's
>> well it's it's because
>> well it's it's because you
>> well it's it's because you have
>> well it's it's because you have to
>> well it's it's because you have to do
>> well it's it's because you have to do it
constantly
constantly you
>> well it's it's because you have to do it
constantly you see
constantly you see spiritual
>> well it's it's because you have to do it
constantly you see spiritual evolution
is
is not
is not a
is not a linear
is not a linear a
is not a linear a measurable
is not a linear a measurable uh
is not a linear a measurable uh logical
phenomena.
phenomena. You
is not a linear a measurable uh logical
phenomena. You get
phenomena. You get absolutely
is not a linear a measurable uh logical
phenomena. You get absolutely nowhere
for
for 20
for 20 years
for 20 years and
for 20 years and suddenly
for 20 years and suddenly there
for 20 years and suddenly there it
for 20 years and suddenly there it is.
>> Yeah.
>> You
>> You say
>> You say I'm
>> You say I'm not
>> You say I'm not getting
>> You say I'm not getting anywhere.
>> Well,
>> Well, I'll
>> You say I'm not getting anywhere.
>> Well, I'll tell
>> Well, I'll tell you
>> You say I'm not getting anywhere.
>> Well, I'll tell you one
>> Well, I'll tell you one place
>> You say I'm not getting anywhere.
>> Well, I'll tell you one place you're
getting.
getting. You're
getting. You're getting
getting. You're getting disgusted.
getting. You're getting disgusted. It's
been
been 20
getting. You're getting disgusted. It's
been 20 years
been 20 years and
getting. You're getting disgusted. It's
been 20 years and nothing
been 20 years and nothing has
getting. You're getting disgusted. It's
been 20 years and nothing has happened.
>> That
>> That weakens
>> That weakens the
>> That weakens the resistance
>> That weakens the resistance right
>> That weakens the resistance right there.
See?
>> Well,
>> Well, I
>> Well, I mean,
>> Well, I mean, I
>> Well, I mean, I feel
>> Well, I mean, I feel like
>> Well, I mean, I feel like I've
>> Well, I mean, I feel like I've been
growing
growing exponentially
>> Well, I mean, I feel like I've been
growing exponentially since
growing exponentially since being
>> Well, I mean, I feel like I've been
growing exponentially since being on
growing exponentially since being on the
path,
path, but
>> it's
>> it's like
path, but
>> it's like relentless.
>> it's like relentless. Like
path, but
>> it's like relentless. Like I
>> it's like relentless. Like I pray
ceaselessly.
ceaselessly. I'm
ceaselessly. I'm on
ceaselessly. I'm on the
ceaselessly. I'm on the course
ceaselessly. I'm on the course of
miracles.
miracles. I
ceaselessly. I'm on the course of
miracles. I listen
miracles. I listen to
ceaselessly. I'm on the course of
miracles. I listen to lectures
miracles. I listen to lectures all
ceaselessly. I'm on the course of
miracles. I listen to lectures all the
time.
time. But
time. But it's
time. But it's so
time. But it's so loud
time. But it's so loud I
time. But it's so loud I can't
time. But it's so loud I can't hear
time. But it's so loud I can't hear the
silence.
>> The
>> The doingness
>> The doingness of
>> The doingness of this
>> The doingness of this very
>> The doingness of this very is
>> The doingness of this very is the
>> The doingness of this very is the doing
this.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, the
>> Yeah, the doing
>> Yeah, the doing this.
>> There's
>> There's nothing
>> Yeah, the doing this.
>> There's nothing wrong
>> There's nothing wrong with
>> Yeah, the doing this.
>> There's nothing wrong with the
>> There's nothing wrong with the doing
this
this for
this for a
this for a period
this for a period of
this for a period of time
this for a period of time and
this for a period of time and then
this for a period of time and then then
there'll
there'll come
this for a period of time and then then
there'll come up
there'll come up a
this for a period of time and then then
there'll come up a period
there'll come up a period of
this for a period of time and then then
there'll come up a period of not
there'll come up a period of not doing
this
that
that not
this
that not doing
that not doing is
this
that not doing is also
that not doing is also a
this
that not doing is also a way
that not doing is also a way of
this
that not doing is also a way of subtly
doing
doing and
doing and getting
doing and getting away
doing and getting away with
doing and getting away with it.
You
You guys
doing and getting away with it.
You guys are
You guys are the
doing and getting away with it.
You guys are the greatest.
>> I
>> I want
>> I want you
>> I want you to
>> I want you to practice
>> I want you to practice not
>> I want you to practice not doing
>> I want you to practice not doing this
all
all together.
>> Okay.
>> No
>> No more
>> Okay.
>> No more doing
>> No more doing anything.
>> Let
>> Let God
>> Let God do
>> Let God do it.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Let God do it.
>> Yeah. And I
>> Yeah. And I I
>> Let God do it.
>> Yeah. And I I I
>> Yeah. And I I I know
>> Let God do it.
>> Yeah. And I I I know that's
>> Yeah. And I I I know that's what
>> Let God do it.
>> Yeah. And I I I know that's what it's
been.
been. It's
been. It's just
been. It's just such
been. It's just such a
been. It's just such a reluctance
been. It's just such a reluctance to
>> let
>> let it
been. It's just such a reluctance to
>> let it go.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I
>> Yeah. I will.
>> So
>> So it's
>> Yeah. I will.
>> So it's So
>> So it's So it's
>> Yeah. I will.
>> So it's So it's not
>> So it's So it's not spiritual.
>> Yeah. I will.
>> So it's So it's not spiritual. It's
control.
control. Control.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> Might
>> Might not
>> Okay.
>> Might not h
>> Might not h may
>> Okay.
>> Might not h may not
>> Might not h may not happen
>> Okay.
>> Might not h may not happen until
>> Might not h may not happen until one
second
second before
second before you
second before you leave
second before you leave the
second before you leave the planet.
second before you leave the planet. Just
as
as the
second before you leave the planet. Just
as the bomb
as the bomb goes
second before you leave the planet. Just
as the bomb goes off,
as the bomb goes off, you
second before you leave the planet. Just
as the bomb goes off, you get
as the bomb goes off, you get Thank
second before you leave the planet. Just
as the bomb goes off, you get Thank you,
Lord.
>> My
>> My life
Lord.
>> My life was
>> My life was a
Lord.
>> My life was a success.
>> I
>> I can
>> I can live
>> I can live with
>> I can live with that.
>> My
>> My life
>> I can live with that.
>> My life was
>> My life was a
>> I can live with that.
>> My life was a success.
>> And
>> And then
>> And then um
>> And then um mini
>> And then um mini question,
>> And then um mini question, is
>> And then um mini question, is it
possible
possible due
>> And then um mini question, is it
possible due to
possible due to the
>> And then um mini question, is it
possible due to the current
possible due to the current state
>> And then um mini question, is it
possible due to the current state of
world
world affairs
world affairs for
world affairs for the
world affairs for the man
world affairs for the man the
consciousness
consciousness of
world affairs for the man the
consciousness of mankind
consciousness of mankind to
world affairs for the man the
consciousness of mankind to drop
consciousness of mankind to drop below
200?
200? Again,
>> I
>> I don't
200? Again,
>> I don't know
>> I don't know hypothetically.
>> Hypothetically,
>> Hypothetically, I
>> Hypothetically, I don't
>> Hypothetically, I don't know.
>> Hypothetically, I don't know. Well,
>> Hypothetically, I don't know. Well, is
there
there a
>> Hypothetically, I don't know. Well, is
there a particular
>> because
>> because the
>> because the collect
>> because the collect the
>> because the collect the collective
>> because the collect the collective tends
to
to boy
>> because the collect the collective tends
to boy up
to boy up the
>> because the collect the collective tends
to boy up the totality.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know.
>> Okay.
Well,
Well, thank
Well, thank you
Well, thank you guys.
>> Good
>> Good question.
>> You're
>> You're the
>> You're the best.
>> Yeah.
>> Less
>> Less than
>> Less than 200
>> Less than 200 is
>> uh
>> uh man
>> Less than 200 is
>> uh man evolved
>> uh man evolved past
>> Less than 200 is
>> uh man evolved past that.
>> uh man evolved past that. Remember
>> Less than 200 is
>> uh man evolved past that. Remember in
1987?
>> Yeah.
>> All
>> All right.
>> All right. So,
>> All right. So, that's
>> All right. So, that's not
>> All right. So, that's not so
>> All right. So, that's not so long
>> All right. So, that's not so long ago.
So,
So, it's
>> All right. So, that's not so long ago.
So, it's not
So, it's not too
>> All right. So, that's not so long ago.
So, it's not too unbelievable
So, it's not too unbelievable that
>> All right. So, that's not so long ago.
So, it's not too unbelievable that man
could
could back
could back down
could back down again
could back down again below
could back down again below 200,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
Yeah,
Yeah, good.
>> Well,
>> Well, I'm
>> Well, I'm not
>> Well, I'm not going
>> Well, I'm not going to
>> Well, I'm not going to worry
>> Well, I'm not going to worry about
>> Well, I'm not going to worry about it
because
because it's
>> Well, I'm not going to worry about it
because it's not
because it's not my
>> Well, I'm not going to worry about it
because it's not my problem.
>> No,
>> No, God's
>> No, God's problem.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Hitting
>> Hitting bottom
>> Hitting bottom is
>> Hitting bottom is hitting
>> Hitting bottom is hitting bottom
>> Hitting bottom is hitting bottom and
whatever
whatever it
>> Hitting bottom is hitting bottom and
whatever it takes
whatever it takes is
>> Hitting bottom is hitting bottom and
whatever it takes is whatever
whatever it takes is whatever it
>> Hitting bottom is hitting bottom and
whatever it takes is whatever it takes.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. Um,
>> Hi. Um, I'm
>> Hi. Um, I'm a
>> Hi. Um, I'm a musician
>> Hi. Um, I'm a musician and
>> Hi. Um, I'm a musician and I
>> Hi. Um, I'm a musician and I uh
>> Hi. Um, I'm a musician and I uh I
>> Hi. Um, I'm a musician and I uh I I
>> Hi. Um, I'm a musician and I uh I I make
music
music and
>> Hi. Um, I'm a musician and I uh I I make
music and I
music and I have
>> Hi. Um, I'm a musician and I uh I I make
music and I have fans
music and I have fans and
>> Hi. Um, I'm a musician and I uh I I make
music and I have fans and I
music and I have fans and I play
concerts
concerts and
concerts and stuff.
>> That's
>> That's where
concerts and stuff.
>> That's where I
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. I'm
>> Oh, yeah. I'm not
>> Oh, yeah. I'm not I'm
>> Oh, yeah. I'm not I'm not
>> Oh, yeah. I'm not I'm not a
>> Oh, yeah. I'm not I'm not a famous
musician.
musician. Oh.
But
But anyway,
But anyway, uh
>> generally
>> generally a
But anyway, uh
>> generally a lot
>> generally a lot of
But anyway, uh
>> generally a lot of time
>> generally a lot of time places
But anyway, uh
>> generally a lot of time places I
>> generally a lot of time places I play
it,
it, I
it, I don't
it, I don't think
it, I don't think calibrate
it, I don't think calibrate above
it, I don't think calibrate above 200
it, I don't think calibrate above 200 or
maybe
>> right
>> down
>> down and
>> right
>> down and dirty.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Yeah. And uh
>> Yeah. And uh I
>> Yeah. And uh I usually
>> Yeah. And uh I usually just
>> Yeah. And uh I usually just go
>> Yeah. And uh I usually just go in,
>> Yeah. And uh I usually just go in, do
>> Yeah. And uh I usually just go in, do my
thing,
thing, and
>> Yeah. And uh I usually just go in, do my
thing, and leave.
>> Right.
>> However,
>> However, you
>> Right.
>> However, you know,
>> However, you know, I
>> Right.
>> However, you know, I feel
>> However, you know, I feel kind
>> Right.
>> However, you know, I feel kind of
>> However, you know, I feel kind of an
obligation
obligation to
um
talk
talk to
talk to people
talk to people somewhat
talk to people somewhat if
talk to people somewhat if they,
talk to people somewhat if they, you
know,
know, if
talk to people somewhat if they, you
know, if they
know, if they like
talk to people somewhat if they, you
know, if they like my
know, if they like my music,
talk to people somewhat if they, you
know, if they like my music, I
know, if they like my music, I feel
>> gratitude
>> gratitude for
>> gratitude for them
>> gratitude for them liking
>> gratitude for them liking it.
>> True.
>> True. But
>> gratitude for them liking it.
>> True. But in
>> True. But in the
>> gratitude for them liking it.
>> True. But in the same
>> True. But in the same way
>> gratitude for them liking it.
>> True. But in the same way they
>> True. But in the same way they kind
>> gratitude for them liking it.
>> True. But in the same way they kind of
like
like really
like really glamorize
like really glamorize me
like really glamorize me and
like really glamorize me and then
sometimes
sometimes I
like really glamorize me and then
sometimes I let
sometimes I let it
like really glamorize me and then
sometimes I let it get
sometimes I let it get to
like really glamorize me and then
sometimes I let it get to my
sometimes I let it get to my head.
>> Right.
>> I'm
>> I'm just
>> Right.
>> I'm just curious
>> I'm just curious if
>> Right.
>> I'm just curious if you
>> I'm just curious if you have
>> Right.
>> I'm just curious if you have any
>> being
>> being a
>> being a star,
>> being a star, you
>> being a star, you know,
>> being a star, you know, and
>> being a star, you know, and uh
>> stardom
>> stardom and
>> being a star, you know, and uh
>> stardom and it's
>> stardom and it's it's
>> being a star, you know, and uh
>> stardom and it's it's a
>> stardom and it's it's a uh
>> being a star, you know, and uh
>> stardom and it's it's a uh it's
difficult
difficult to
difficult to not
difficult to not get
difficult to not get inflated
difficult to not get inflated by
difficult to not get inflated by the
agilation.
>> Mhm.
>> And
>> And um
>> Mhm.
>> And um I
>> And um I experienced
>> Mhm.
>> And um I experienced it.
>> And um I experienced it. I
>> Mhm.
>> And um I experienced it. I completely
understood
understood it
understood it one
understood it one time.
understood it one time. I
understood it one time. I was
understood it one time. I was on
understood it one time. I was on some
uh
uh program,
understood it one time. I was on some
uh program, Barbara
uh program, Barbara Wallers
understood it one time. I was on some
uh program, Barbara Wallers or
uh program, Barbara Wallers or some
understood it one time. I was on some
uh program, Barbara Wallers or some big
program
program and
program and you
program and you I
program and you I drove
program and you I drove into
program and you I drove into the
program and you I drove into the city,
parked
parked in
program and you I drove into the city,
parked in a
parked in a parking
program and you I drove into the city,
parked in a parking garage,
parked in a parking garage, went
program and you I drove into the city,
parked in a parking garage, went up
parked in a parking garage, went up in
whatchamacallit
whatchamacallit city
whatchamacallit city there
whatchamacallit city there and
whatchamacallit city there and I
whatchamacallit city there and I don't
know
know ABC,
whatchamacallit city there and I don't
know ABC, NBC,
know ABC, NBC, whatever
whatchamacallit city there and I don't
know ABC, NBC, whatever it
know ABC, NBC, whatever it was.
whatchamacallit city there and I don't
know ABC, NBC, whatever it was. Anyway,
the
the the
the the studio
the the studio was
the the studio was huge.
the the studio was huge. I
the the studio was huge. I mean,
the the studio was huge. I mean, it
covers
covers a
the the studio was huge. I mean, it
covers a half
covers a half acre
the the studio was huge. I mean, it
covers a half acre and
covers a half acre and there's
the the studio was huge. I mean, it
covers a half acre and there's booms
everywhere
everywhere and
everywhere and all
everywhere and all kinds
everywhere and all kinds of
everywhere and all kinds of stuff
everywhere and all kinds of stuff and
millions
millions of
everywhere and all kinds of stuff and
millions of people,
millions of people, lights
everywhere and all kinds of stuff and
millions of people, lights everywhere.
So
So then
So then you
So then you go
So then you go into
So then you go into makeup
So then you go into makeup and
So then you go into makeup and they
everybody
everybody hovers
So then you go into makeup and they
everybody hovers over
everybody hovers over you
So then you go into makeup and they
everybody hovers over you and
everybody hovers over you and everybody
introduces
introduces you
introduces you and
introduces you and you're
introduces you and you're Mr.
introduces you and you're Mr. Somebody.
Then
Then yeah,
introduces you and you're Mr. Somebody.
Then yeah, you're
Then yeah, you're all
introduces you and you're Mr. Somebody.
Then yeah, you're all made
Then yeah, you're all made up
introduces you and you're Mr. Somebody.
Then yeah, you're all made up and
Then yeah, you're all made up and now
the
the great
the great moment
the great moment arrives.
the great moment arrives. You
the great moment arrives. You get
the great moment arrives. You get up
there
there and
the great moment arrives. You get up
there and it
there and it seems
the great moment arrives. You get up
there and it seems like
there and it seems like about
the great moment arrives. You get up
there and it seems like about a
there and it seems like about a second
and
and a
and a half
and a half later,
you
you know,
70 million
70 million people
70 million people watching
70 million people watching you
70 million people watching you and
suddenly
suddenly the
70 million people watching you and
suddenly the interview
suddenly the interview is
70 million people watching you and
suddenly the interview is over.
suddenly the interview is over. Then
70 million people watching you and
suddenly the interview is over. Then the
program
program comes
program comes to
program comes to an
program comes to an end.
program comes to an end. All
program comes to an end. All the
program comes to an end. All the cle
lights
lights go
program comes to an end. All the cle
lights go out,
lights go out, everybody
program comes to an end. All the cle
lights go out, everybody disappears.
>> Yeah.
>> You
>> You find
>> Yeah.
>> You find yourself
>> You find yourself all
>> Yeah.
>> You find yourself all alone
>> You find yourself all alone in
>> Yeah.
>> You find yourself all alone in this
giant
giant jungle.
giant jungle. And
giant jungle. And there's
giant jungle. And there's a
giant jungle. And there's a guy
giant jungle. And there's a guy pushing
a
a broom.
giant jungle. And there's a guy pushing
a broom. I
a broom. I said,
giant jungle. And there's a guy pushing
a broom. I said, "Where
a broom. I said, "Where the
giant jungle. And there's a guy pushing
a broom. I said, "Where the hell's
a broom. I said, "Where the hell's the
men's
men's room?
men's room? And
men's room? And how
men's room? And how do
men's room? And how do you
men's room? And how do you get
men's room? And how do you get out
men's room? And how do you get out of
here
here to
men's room? And how do you get out of
here to get
here to get to
men's room? And how do you get out of
here to get to the
here to get to the street
from
from being
from being the
from being the center
from being the center of
from being the center of focus
from being the center of focus of
from being the center of focus of 70
million
million people
from being the center of focus of 70
million people and
million people and I
from being the center of focus of 70
million people and I was
million people and I was on
from being the center of focus of 70
million people and I was on her
million people and I was on her program
a
a couple
a couple times
a couple times plus
a couple times plus other
a couple times plus other programs
a couple times plus other programs and
a couple times plus other programs and I
noticed
noticed the
a couple times plus other programs and I
noticed the same
noticed the same thing."
a couple times plus other programs and I
noticed the same thing." And
noticed the same thing." And when
a couple times plus other programs and I
noticed the same thing." And when I
noticed the same thing." And when I got
off
off the
off the elevator
off the elevator at
off the elevator at the
off the elevator at the bottom
off the elevator at the bottom and
off the elevator at the bottom and stood
up
up onto
off the elevator at the bottom and stood
up onto the
up onto the street,
off the elevator at the bottom and stood
up onto the street, there
up onto the street, there was
off the elevator at the bottom and stood
up onto the street, there was like
up onto the street, there was like a
dropping
dropping feeling
dropping feeling from
dropping feeling from the
dropping feeling from the high
dropping feeling from the high the
dropping feeling from the high the drop.
And
And I
dropping feeling from the high the drop.
And I said,
And I said, "Now
dropping feeling from the high the drop.
And I said, "Now I
And I said, "Now I understand
dropping feeling from the high the drop.
And I said, "Now I understand why
And I said, "Now I understand why people
in
in the
in the entertainment
in the entertainment business
in the entertainment business do
in the entertainment business do drugs.
It's
It's almost
in the entertainment business do drugs.
It's almost intolerable
It's almost intolerable that
in the entertainment business do drugs.
It's almost intolerable that down
It's almost intolerable that down from
being
being from
being from that
being from that enormous
being from that enormous high,
being from that enormous high, that
crash.
>> So
>> So if
>> So if you're
>> So if you're into
>> So if you're into drugs,
>> So if you're into drugs, you
>> So if you're into drugs, you do
>> So if you're into drugs, you do some
meth,
meth, you
>> So if you're into drugs, you do some
meth, you get
meth, you get stoned,
>> So if you're into drugs, you do some
meth, you get stoned, you
meth, you get stoned, you do
>> So if you're into drugs, you do some
meth, you get stoned, you do something,
a
a party
a party to
a party to keep
a party to keep that
a party to keep that high
a party to keep that high going."
a party to keep that high going." So
a party to keep that high going." So I
could
could see
a party to keep that high going." So I
could see how
could see how musicians
a party to keep that high going." So I
could see how musicians and
could see how musicians and entertainers
and
and all
and all get
and all get into
and all get into that
and all get into that world
>> because
>> because from
and all get into that world
>> because from being
>> because from being the
and all get into that world
>> because from being the center
>> because from being the center of
agilation
agilation to
agilation to being
agilation to being a
agilation to being a nobody
agilation to being a nobody walking
anonymously
anonymously down
agilation to being a nobody walking
anonymously down the
anonymously down the street,
agilation to being a nobody walking
anonymously down the street, it's
anonymously down the street, it's quite
a
a crash.
a crash. And
a crash. And I
a crash. And I had
a crash. And I had sympathy
a crash. And I had sympathy for
a crash. And I had sympathy for him.
a crash. And I had sympathy for him. I
said,
said, "Uh
a crash. And I had sympathy for him. I
said, "Uh oh,
said, "Uh oh, I
a crash. And I had sympathy for him. I
said, "Uh oh, I see
said, "Uh oh, I see you.
a crash. And I had sympathy for him. I
said, "Uh oh, I see you. I
said, "Uh oh, I see you. I that's
a crash. And I had sympathy for him. I
said, "Uh oh, I see you. I that's not
tolerable."
>> So,
>> So, um
tolerable."
>> So, um like
>> So, um like does
tolerable."
>> So, um like does gratitude
>> So, um like does gratitude just
tolerable."
>> So, um like does gratitude just standing
in
in a
in a state
in a state of
in a state of gratitude
in a state of gratitude for
in a state of gratitude for the
in a state of gratitude for the gift
that
that God
in a state of gratitude for the gift
that God has
that God has given
in a state of gratitude for the gift
that God has given me.
>> That's
>> That's what
>> That's what you
>> That's what you do.
>> That's
>> That's good
>> That's what you do.
>> That's good enough
>> That's good enough to
>> That's what you do.
>> That's good enough to keep
>> That's good enough to keep away
>> That's what you do.
>> That's good enough to keep away from
>> and
>> and ask
>> and ask God
>> and ask God for
>> and ask God for protection
>> and ask God for protection from
>> and ask God for protection from the
seduction
seduction of
>> and ask God for protection from the
seduction of the
seduction of the temptate,
>> and ask God for protection from the
seduction of the temptate, the
seduction of the temptate, the seduction
of
>> the
>> the seduction
of
>> the seduction of
>> the seduction of the
of
>> the seduction of the high
>> the seduction of the high of
of
>> the seduction of the high of the
attention.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> Mhm.
I
I thought
>> Mhm.
I thought you
I thought you had
>> Mhm.
I thought you had some
I thought you had some babies
>> Mhm.
I thought you had some babies here.
>> You
>> You know,
>> You know, I
>> You know, I don't
>> You know, I don't know how
>> You know, I don't know how MC
>> You know, I don't know how MC Jagger
survived.
survived. Is
>> You know, I don't know how MC Jagger
survived. Is he
survived. Is he still
>> You know, I don't know how MC Jagger
survived. Is he still up
survived. Is he still up there?
>> You know, I don't know how MC Jagger
survived. Is he still up there? You
think,
>> I
>> I know,
>> how
>> how come
>> how come it
>> how come it hasn't
>> how come it hasn't killed
>> how come it hasn't killed him
>> how come it hasn't killed him yet?
>> how come it hasn't killed him yet? You
know,
>> hello.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um,
>> hello.
>> Yeah. Um, I
>> Yeah. Um, I had
>> hello.
>> Yeah. Um, I had a
>> Yeah. Um, I had a wonderful
>> hello.
>> Yeah. Um, I had a wonderful day
>> Yeah. Um, I had a wonderful day here
>> hello.
>> Yeah. Um, I had a wonderful day here and
I
I was
I was on
I was on a
I was on a fabulous
I was on a fabulous high
I was on a fabulous high and
I was on a fabulous high and everything
just
just was
I was on a fabulous high and everything
just was funny
just was funny and
I was on a fabulous high and everything
just was funny and I
just was funny and I was
I was on a fabulous high and everything
just was funny and I was flowing
just was funny and I was flowing and
then
then you
then you got
then you got to
then you got to the
then you got to the word
then you got to the word poverty
and
and my
then you got to the word poverty
and my whole
and my whole body
then you got to the word poverty
and my whole body just
and my whole body just clenched
then you got to the word poverty
and my whole body just clenched and
and my whole body just clenched and I'm
wondering
wondering what
wondering what the
wondering what the definition
wondering what the definition of
wondering what the definition of poverty
is.
>> Whatever
>> Whatever you
>> Whatever you made
>> Whatever you made it
>> Whatever you made it to
>> Whatever you made it to be.
>> Whatever you made it to be. I
>> Whatever you made it to be. I don't
>> I
>> I think
>> Whatever you made it to be. I don't
>> I think it
>> I think it is.
>> Whatever you made it to be. I don't
>> I think it is. I
>> I think it is. I don't
>> Whatever you made it to be. I don't
>> I think it is. I don't know
>> I think it is. I don't know if
>> Whatever you made it to be. I don't
>> I think it is. I don't know if I'm
making
making the
making the idea
>> most
>> most people
making the idea
>> most people think
>> most people think of
making the idea
>> most people think of it
>> most people think of it monetarily,
making the idea
>> most people think of it monetarily, you
know,
know, having
know, having no
know, having no money.
know, having no money. Yeah,
know, having no money. Yeah, that's
scary
>> because
>> because true
>> because true poverty
>> because true poverty would
>> because true poverty would be
>> because true poverty would be devoid
>> because true poverty would be devoid of
assets.
assets. Devoid
>> because true poverty would be devoid of
assets. Devoid of
assets. Devoid of assets.
>> That
>> That would
>> That would be
>> That would be true
>> That would be true poverty.
>> That would be true poverty. Inner
poverty.
poverty. Most
>> That would be true poverty. Inner
poverty. Most people
poverty. Most people think
>> That would be true poverty. Inner
poverty. Most people think of
poverty. Most people think of poverty
>> That would be true poverty. Inner
poverty. Most people think of poverty as
having
having no
having no money,
having no money, being
having no money, being flat
having no money, being flat broke.
having no money, being flat broke. You
know,
>> that's
>> that's what
>> that's what I
>> that's what I think
>> that's what I think of
>> that's what I think of it
>> that's what I think of it as.
>> that's what I think of it as. Is
>> that's what I think of it as. Is that
what
what you're
>> that's what I think of it as. Is that
what you're talking
what you're talking about?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Flat
>> Yeah. Flat broke.
>> Yeah. Flat broke. Yeah.
>> That
>> That I
>> Yeah. Flat broke. Yeah.
>> That I should
>> That I should be
>> Yeah. Flat broke. Yeah.
>> That I should be flat
>> That I should be flat broke
>> Yeah. Flat broke. Yeah.
>> That I should be flat broke and
therefore
therefore I'll
therefore I'll be
therefore I'll be peaceful.
>> No,
>> No, I
therefore I'll be peaceful.
>> No, I didn't
>> No, I didn't say
therefore I'll be peaceful.
>> No, I didn't say that.
>> I
>> I know,
>> I know, but
>> I know, but my
>> I know, but my mind's
>> I know, but my mind's saying
>> I know, but my mind's saying that.
>> I know, but my mind's saying that. So,
>> I know, but my mind's saying that. So, I
needed
needed some
>> I know, but my mind's saying that. So, I
needed some clarity.
needed some clarity. Would
>> I know, but my mind's saying that. So, I
needed some clarity. Would that
needed some clarity. Would that be
>> I know, but my mind's saying that. So, I
needed some clarity. Would that be okay?
He
He know
>> life
>> life is
He know
>> life is okay
>> life is okay if
He know
>> life is okay if you
>> life is okay if you have
He know
>> life is okay if you have money
>> life is okay if you have money and
He know
>> life is okay if you have money and it's
okay
okay if
okay if you
okay if you don't
okay if you don't have
okay if you don't have money.
>> Okay.
>> And
>> And one
>> And one of
>> And one of the
>> And one of the reasons
>> And one of the reasons for
>> And one of the reasons for poverty
>> And one of the reasons for poverty is
>> And one of the reasons for poverty is to
discover
discover that
>> you
>> you can't
>> you can't just
>> you can't just do
>> you can't just do it
>> you can't just do it allesely.
>> Uhhuh.
>> You
>> You got
>> You got to
>> You got to walk
>> You got to walk out
>> You got to walk out of
>> You got to walk out of the
>> You got to walk out of the house
>> You got to walk out of the house and
have
have no
>> You got to walk out of the house and
have no money.
>> You've
>> You've got
>> You've got a
>> You've got a what
>> You've got a what now?
>> I'M
>> I'M REALLY
>> You've got a what now?
>> I'M REALLY STUCK.
>> I'M REALLY STUCK. I
>> You've got a what now?
>> I'M REALLY STUCK. I JUST
>> I'M REALLY STUCK. I JUST HAVE
>> You've got a what now?
>> I'M REALLY STUCK. I JUST HAVE TO
>> I'M REALLY STUCK. I JUST HAVE TO BE
HONEST.
>> You've
>> You've got
HONEST.
>> You've got like
>> You've got like how
HONEST.
>> You've got like how much
>> You've got like how much time?
HONEST.
>> You've got like how much time? In
>> You've got like how much time? In order
to
to not
to not have
to not have any
to not have any money,
to not have any money, you
to not have any money, you have
to not have any money, you have to
to not have any money, you have to be
to not have any money, you have to be in
a
a situation
to not have any money, you have to be in
a situation where
a situation where you
to not have any money, you have to be in
a situation where you don't
a situation where you don't have
to not have any money, you have to be in
a situation where you don't have any
money.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I
money.
>> Okay. I have
>> Okay. I have been
money.
>> Okay. I have been without
>> Okay. I have been without money
money.
>> Okay. I have been without money before.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And it
>> Yes.
>> And it wasn't
>> And it wasn't as
>> Yes.
>> And it wasn't as comfortable
>> And it wasn't as comfortable as
>> Yes.
>> And it wasn't as comfortable as it
>> And it wasn't as comfortable as it is
when
when I
when I have
when I have money.
>> Well,
>> Well, yeah,
when I have money.
>> Well, yeah, it's
>> Well, yeah, it's comfort,
when I have money.
>> Well, yeah, it's comfort, you
>> Well, yeah, it's comfort, you know.
when I have money.
>> Well, yeah, it's comfort, you know. Mhm.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So,
>> Yeah. So, I
>> Yeah. So, I feel
>> Yeah. So, I feel that
>> Yeah. So, I feel that having
>> Yeah. So, I feel that having money
>> Yeah. So, I feel that having money in
>> Yeah. So, I feel that having money in my
life
life is
>> Yeah. So, I feel that having money in my
life is much
life is much more
>> Yeah. So, I feel that having money in my
life is much more comfortable.
life is much more comfortable. But
>> Yeah. So, I feel that having money in my
life is much more comfortable. But is
that
that an
that an ego?
>> No.
>> No,
>> No, that's
>> No, that's just
>> No, that's just comfort.
>> No, that's just comfort. That's
>> No, that's just comfort. That's just
Yeah,
Yeah, you
>> No, that's just comfort. That's just
Yeah, you discover
Yeah, you discover that
>> No, that's just comfort. That's just
Yeah, you discover that it's
Yeah, you discover that it's not
magical.
magical. Doesn't
magical. Doesn't cure
magical. Doesn't cure anything.
>> Correct.
>> Correct. But
magical. Doesn't cure anything.
>> Correct. But it
>> Correct. But it is
magical. Doesn't cure anything.
>> Correct. But it is more
>> Correct. But it is more comfort.
>> I
>> I agree
>> I agree with
>> I agree with that.
>> I agree with that. That
>> I agree with that. That it
>> I agree with that. That it is
>> I agree with that. That it is more
comfortable.
comfortable. Therefore,
>> I agree with that. That it is more
comfortable. Therefore, it's
comfortable. Therefore, it's not
>> I agree with that. That it is more
comfortable. Therefore, it's not really
a
a ego
a ego gratification
>> to
>> to have
a ego gratification
>> to have it
>> to have it or
a ego gratification
>> to have it or even
>> to have it or even somebody
a ego gratification
>> to have it or even somebody replace
>> to have it or even somebody replace the
flat
flat on
flat on your
flat on your car
flat on your car than
flat on your car than do
flat on your car than do it
flat on your car than do it yourself.
Yeah,
Yeah, it's
flat on your car than do it yourself.
Yeah, it's a
Yeah, it's a lot
flat on your car than do it yourself.
Yeah, it's a lot easier.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> Okay. So,
>> Okay. So, as
>> Okay. Okay.
>> Okay. So, as long
>> Okay. So, as long as
>> Okay. Okay.
>> Okay. So, as long as I
>> Okay. So, as long as I understand
>> Okay. Okay.
>> Okay. So, as long as I understand that's
not
not really
not really an
not really an ego
not really an ego drive
not really an ego drive to
not really an ego drive to necessarily
have
have that
not really an ego drive to necessarily
have that comfort.
have that comfort. Okay.
not really an ego drive to necessarily
have that comfort. Okay. Um
have that comfort. Okay. Um the
not really an ego drive to necessarily
have that comfort. Okay. Um the other
thing
thing is
thing is I
thing is I was
thing is I was wondering
thing is I was wondering if
thing is I was wondering if you
thing is I was wondering if you could
hold
hold a
thing is I was wondering if you could
hold a vision
hold a vision for
thing is I was wondering if you could
hold a vision for me
hold a vision for me and
thing is I was wondering if you could
hold a vision for me and my
practitioners
practitioners to
practitioners to allow
practitioners to allow us
practitioners to allow us to
practitioners to allow us to be
practitioners to allow us to be able
practitioners to allow us to be able to
have
have um
practitioners to allow us to be able to
have um consistent
have um consistent results
practitioners to allow us to be able to
have um consistent results with
kinesiology.
kinesiology. Oh,
>> it's
>> it's not
kinesiology. Oh,
>> it's not for
>> it's not for everybody.
>> It
>> It has
>> It has to
>> It has to be
>> It has to be all
>> It has to be all across
>> It has to be all across the
>> It has to be all across the board.
>> It has to be all across the board. Well,
two
two of
>> It has to be all across the board. Well,
two of them
two of them are
>> It has to be all across the board. Well,
two of them are chiropractors
two of them are chiropractors that
>> It has to be all across the board. Well,
two of them are chiropractors that are
both
both um
>> first
>> first of
both um
>> first of all,
>> first of all, everybody
both um
>> first of all, everybody has
>> first of all, everybody has to
both um
>> first of all, everybody has to be
>> first of all, everybody has to be over
200.
200. Secondly,
200. Secondly, their
200. Secondly, their intention
200. Secondly, their intention has
200. Secondly, their intention has to
200. Secondly, their intention has to be
integrous.
>> Okay?
>> And
>> And the
>> Okay?
>> And the intensity
>> And the intensity the
>> Okay?
>> And the intensity the the
>> And the intensity the the question
>> Okay?
>> And the intensity the the question you
can't
can't have
can't have any
can't have any stake
can't have any stake in
can't have any stake in the
can't have any stake in the outcome.
>> Okay?
>> Then
>> Then you
>> Then you have
>> Then you have to
>> Then you have to make
>> Then you have to make sure
>> Then you have to make sure that
>> Then you have to make sure that you're
not
not blown
>> Then you have to make sure that you're
not blown out
not blown out by
>> Then you have to make sure that you're
not blown out by something
not blown out by something else.
>> Then you have to make sure that you're
not blown out by something else. So
not blown out by something else. So you
go
through
>> the
>> the thymus.
>> the thymus. Okay.
>> Through
>> Through the
>> the thymus. Okay.
>> Through the thyic
>> Through the thyic thumb.
>> the thymus. Okay.
>> Through the thyic thumb. Okay.
>> Through the thyic thumb. Okay. Uh
>> the thymus. Okay.
>> Through the thyic thumb. Okay. Uh then
you
you ask
you ask to
you ask to you
you ask to you can
you ask to you can ask
you ask to you can ask have
you ask to you can ask have somebody
else
else ask
you ask to you can ask have somebody
else ask am
else ask am I
you ask to you can ask have somebody
else ask am I karmically
else ask am I karmically permitted
you ask to you can ask have somebody
else ask am I karmically permitted to
else ask am I karmically permitted to to
utilize
utilize it
utilize it and
utilize it and about
utilize it and about 10%
utilize it and about 10% of
utilize it and about 10% of people
utilize it and about 10% of people you
get
get karmically
utilize it and about 10% of people you
get karmically no
>> oh
>> their
>> their violation
>> oh
>> their violation of
>> their violation of truth
>> oh
>> their violation of truth has
>> their violation of truth has been
>> oh
>> their violation of truth has been so
severe
severe in
severe in lifetimes
>> that
>> that there
severe in lifetimes
>> that there this
>> that there this is
severe in lifetimes
>> that there this is not
>> that there this is not a
severe in lifetimes
>> that there this is not a gift
>> that there this is not a gift in
severe in lifetimes
>> that there this is not a gift in this
lifetime
lifetime yet
lifetime yet you
lifetime yet you got
lifetime yet you got to
lifetime yet you got to earn
lifetime yet you got to earn it
lifetime yet you got to earn it back
lifetime yet you got to earn it back so
you
you you
lifetime yet you got to earn it back so
you you check
you you check out
lifetime yet you got to earn it back so
you you check out the
you you check out the various
lifetime yet you got to earn it back so
you you check out the various things
you you check out the various things uh
you
you know
you know and
you know and not
you know and not everybody
you know and not everybody has
you know and not everybody has that
capacity
capacity just
you know and not everybody has that
capacity just like
capacity just like not
you know and not everybody has that
capacity just like not everybody
capacity just like not everybody can
ride
ride a
ride a bicycle
ride a bicycle you
ride a bicycle you know
ride a bicycle you know they
ride a bicycle you know they just
ride a bicycle you know they just lack
the
the balance
ride a bicycle you know they just lack
the balance or
the balance or something
>> well
>> well two
>> well two of
>> well two of them
>> well two of them are
>> well two of them are ky
>> well two of them are ky chiropractors
who
who who've
>> well two of them are ky chiropractors
who who've gone
who who've gone to
>> well two of them are ky chiropractors
who who've gone to applied
who who've gone to applied kinesiology
and
and use
and use it
and use it every
and use it every day
and use it every day in
and use it every day in their
and use it every day in their work.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And um
>> And um so
>> And um so I
>> And um so I felt
>> I
>> I feel
>> And um so I felt
>> I feel like
>> I feel like the
>> And um so I felt
>> I feel like the integrity
>> I feel like the integrity is
>> And um so I felt
>> I feel like the integrity is there.
Yeah.
>> But
>> But we
Yeah.
>> But we seem
>> But we seem to
Yeah.
>> But we seem to like
>> But we seem to like for
Yeah.
>> But we seem to like for instance
>> But we seem to like for instance if
Yeah.
>> But we seem to like for instance if we
take
take your
take your your
take your your calibrations
take your your calibrations and
take your your calibrations and we
take your your calibrations and we all
test
test multiple
take your your calibrations and we all
test multiple different
test multiple different ways.
>> They're
>> They're all
>> They're all across
>> They're all across the
>> What's
>> What's the
>> They're all across the
>> What's the intention?
>> The
>> The intention
>> The intention is
>> The intention is that
>> The intention is that we
>> The intention is that we can
>> The intention is that we can um
>> The intention is that we can um have
>> The intention is that we can um have a
consistency
consistency so
>> The intention is that we can um have a
consistency so we
consistency so we can
>> The intention is that we can um have a
consistency so we can use
consistency so we can use kinesiology
>> The intention is that we can um have a
consistency so we can use kinesiology in
our
our practices
our practices to
our practices to help
our practices to help people.
our practices to help people. But
our practices to help people. But if
there's
there's not
our practices to help people. But if
there's not a
there's not a consistency,
our practices to help people. But if
there's not a consistency, I
there's not a consistency, I feel
our practices to help people. But if
there's not a consistency, I feel like
we're
we're either
we're either using
we're either using it
we're either using it and
we're either using it and not
we're either using it and not in
integrity.
>> You
>> You may
>> You may not
>> You may not be,
>> You may not be, you
>> You may not be, you know,
>> You may not be, you know, gifted
>> You may not be, you know, gifted in
>> You may not be, you know, gifted in that
area.
area. I
>> You may not be, you know, gifted in that
area. I mean,
area. I mean, some
>> You may not be, you know, gifted in that
area. I mean, some people
area. I mean, some people are
>> You may not be, you know, gifted in that
area. I mean, some people are good
area. I mean, some people are good at,
>> you
>> you know,
>> you know, I
>> you know, I built
>> you know, I built the
>> you know, I built the largest
>> you know, I built the largest practice
in
in United
>> you know, I built the largest practice
in United States
in United States using
>> you know, I built the largest practice
in United States using alternative
in United States using alternative forms
of
of medicine,
of medicine, of
of medicine, of which
of medicine, of which kinesiology
of medicine, of which kinesiology was
one
>> was
>> was one,
>> but
>> but I
>> was one,
>> but I wasn't
>> but I wasn't a
>> was one,
>> but I wasn't a kinesiologist,
>> but I wasn't a kinesiologist, nor
>> was one,
>> but I wasn't a kinesiologist, nor am
>> but I wasn't a kinesiologist, nor am I
now.
now. So,
>> okay.
>> It's
>> It's only
>> It's only an
>> It's only an additional
>> It's only an additional tool
>> It's only an additional tool that
>> It's only an additional tool that I
>> It's only an additional tool that I use
to
to cooperate
>> It's only an additional tool that I use
to cooperate other
to cooperate other things.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. In
>> Okay. In my
>> Okay. In my own
>> Okay. In my own personal
>> Okay. In my own personal life,
>> Okay. In my own personal life, it's
>> Okay. In my own personal life, it's been
very
very useful.
>> Okay. In my own personal life, it's been
very useful. I
very useful. I can
>> Okay. In my own personal life, it's been
very useful. I can treat
very useful. I can treat and
>> Okay. In my own personal life, it's been
very useful. I can treat and diagnose
anything.
anything. You
anything. You know,
anything. You know, how
anything. You know, how much
anything. You know, how much something
or
or the
anything. You know, how much something
or the dose
or the dose should
anything. You know, how much something
or the dose should I
or the dose should I take
anything. You know, how much something
or the dose should I take or
or the dose should I take or nothing?
>> Yeah.
>> So,
>> So, I
>> Yeah.
>> So, I don't
>> So, I don't know
>> Yeah.
>> So, I don't know what
>> So, I don't know what to
>> Yeah.
>> So, I don't know what to tell
>> So, I don't know what to tell you
>> Yeah.
>> So, I don't know what to tell you about
it.
it. I'd
it. I'd have
it. I'd have to
it. I'd have to be
it. I'd have to be a
it. I'd have to be a long
it. I'd have to be a long conversation
why
why some
it. I'd have to be a long conversation
why some people
why some people may
it. I'd have to be a long conversation
why some people may be
why some people may be destined
it. I'd have to be a long conversation
why some people may be destined for
why some people may be destined for it
or
or gifted
or gifted for
or gifted for it
>> or
>> or why
or gifted for it
>> or why would
>> or why would they
or gifted for it
>> or why would they want
>> or why would they want to
or gifted for it
>> or why would they want to learn
>> or why would they want to learn it?
Well,
Well, practical
Well, practical reasons
Well, practical reasons for
Well, practical reasons for helping
patients.
patients. Yes,
Well, practical reasons for helping
patients. Yes, that's
patients. Yes, that's certainly
Well, practical reasons for helping
patients. Yes, that's certainly an
integrous
integrous reason.
>> Well,
>> Well, I
integrous reason.
>> Well, I think
>> Well, I think you
integrous reason.
>> Well, I think you might
>> Well, I think you might have
integrous reason.
>> Well, I think you might have answered
>> Well, I think you might have answered it
when
when you
when you said
when you said asked
when you said asked the
when you said asked the question,
when you said asked the question, is
when you said asked the question, is it
karmically
karmically suited
when you said asked the question, is it
karmically suited for
karmically suited for this
when you said asked the question, is it
karmically suited for this lifetime?
Maybe
Maybe that's
Maybe that's what
Maybe that's what we
Maybe that's what we have
>> something
>> something like
Maybe that's what we have
>> something like 10%
>> something like 10% of
Maybe that's what we have
>> something like 10% of people
>> something like 10% of people you'll
Maybe that's what we have
>> something like 10% of people you'll get
a
a no.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
a no.
>> Oh, okay. Well,
>> Oh, okay. Well, I'll
a no.
>> Oh, okay. Well, I'll start
>> Oh, okay. Well, I'll start with
a no.
>> Oh, okay. Well, I'll start with that.
>> Well,
>> Well, in
>> Well, in like
>> Well, in like patients,
>> Well, in like patients, if
>> Well, in like patients, if you're
>> Well, in like patients, if you're using
it
it to
>> Well, in like patients, if you're using
it to diagnose
it to diagnose a
>> Well, in like patients, if you're using
it to diagnose a patient,
it to diagnose a patient, you
>> Well, in like patients, if you're using
it to diagnose a patient, you have
it to diagnose a patient, you have to
>> Well, in like patients, if you're using
it to diagnose a patient, you have to be
karmically
karmically permitted
karmically permitted to
karmically permitted to do
karmically permitted to do that.
>> Correct.
>> Correct. Okay.
karmically permitted to do that.
>> Correct. Okay. Okay.
>> Correct. Okay. Okay. Well,
karmically permitted to do that.
>> Correct. Okay. Okay. Well, let
>> Correct. Okay. Okay. Well, let me
karmically permitted to do that.
>> Correct. Okay. Okay. Well, let me start
with
with that.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
with that.
>> Thank you. Okay.
>> I
>> I appreciate
>> I appreciate it.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, I
>> I appreciate it.
>> Yeah, I know.
>> And
>> And I'm
>> And I'm glad
>> And I'm glad I
>> And I'm glad I get
>> And I'm glad I get to
>> And I'm glad I get to keep
>> And I'm glad I get to keep money.
>> If
>> If I
>> And I'm glad I get to keep money.
>> If I had
>> If I had if
>> And I'm glad I get to keep money.
>> If I had if I
>> If I had if I had
>> And I'm glad I get to keep money.
>> If I had if I had time,
>> If I had if I had time, I'd
>> And I'm glad I get to keep money.
>> If I had if I had time, I'd work
>> If I had if I had time, I'd work with
you
you on
you on it.
>> The
>> The clinical
you on it.
>> The clinical application
>> The clinical application of
you on it.
>> The clinical application of kinesiology
is
is interesting.
Hi.
>> But
>> But you
>> But you can
>> But you can make
>> But you can make diagnosis
>> But you can make diagnosis that
>> But you can make diagnosis that nobody
else
else can
>> But you can make diagnosis that nobody
else can make.
else can make. I'll
>> But you can make diagnosis that nobody
else can make. I'll tell
else can make. I'll tell you
>> But you can make diagnosis that nobody
else can make. I'll tell you that.
>> There's
>> There's another
>> There's another resident
>> There's another resident of
>> There's another resident of Wisconsin
who's
who's had
>> There's another resident of Wisconsin
who's had the
who's had the opportunity
>> There's another resident of Wisconsin
who's had the opportunity to
who's had the opportunity to speak
>> There's another resident of Wisconsin
who's had the opportunity to speak to
you
you this
you this afternoon.
you this afternoon. I
you this afternoon. I want
you this afternoon. I want to
you this afternoon. I want to thank
you this afternoon. I want to thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Although
>> Although I
>> Although I think
>> Although I think I
>> Although I think I have
>> Although I think I have enough
>> Although I think I have enough furniture
already.
>> You
>> You don't
>> You don't want
>> You don't want the
>> You don't want the duct
>> You don't want the duct tape?
>> No.
>> No. Thank
>> You don't want the duct tape?
>> No. Thank you.
>> No. Thank you. I
>> You don't want the duct tape?
>> No. Thank you. I guess
>> No. Thank you. I guess my
>> You don't want the duct tape?
>> No. Thank you. I guess my question
concerns
concerns a
concerns a level
concerns a level of
concerns a level of anxiety
concerns a level of anxiety I
concerns a level of anxiety I feel
towards
towards being
concerns a level of anxiety I feel
towards being able
towards being able to
concerns a level of anxiety I feel
towards being able to provide
towards being able to provide for
concerns a level of anxiety I feel
towards being able to provide for my
family
>> and
>> and my
family
>> and my wife
>> and my wife and
family
>> and my wife and children.
>> and my wife and children. M
>> uh
>> uh you
>> uh you know
>> uh you know what
>> uh you know what responsibility
>> uh you know what responsibility is
>> uh you know what responsibility is there
as
as a
>> uh you know what responsibility is there
as a parent
as a parent and
>> uh you know what responsibility is there
as a parent and when
as a parent and when are
>> uh you know what responsibility is there
as a parent and when are you
as a parent and when are you allowed
>> uh you know what responsibility is there
as a parent and when are you allowed to
relinquish
relinquish that
relinquish that to
relinquish that to pursue
relinquish that to pursue spiritual
objectives?
objectives? Is
relinquish that to pursue spiritual
objectives? Is there
objectives? Is there such
relinquish that to pursue spiritual
objectives? Is there such a
objectives? Is there such a thing
relinquish that to pursue spiritual
objectives? Is there such a thing as
relinquishing
relinquishing that
relinquishing that responsibility
relinquishing that responsibility at
some
some point
relinquishing that responsibility at
some point in
some point in your
relinquishing that responsibility at
some point in your life?
>> Not
>> Not unless
>> Not unless it
>> Not unless it becomes
>> Not unless it becomes compelling.
We'd
We'd have
>> Not unless it becomes compelling.
We'd have to
We'd have to delay
>> Not unless it becomes compelling.
We'd have to delay it
We'd have to delay it perhaps.
>> Not unless it becomes compelling.
We'd have to delay it perhaps. Uh
because
because obligation
um
um is
because obligation
um is also
um is also to
because obligation
um is also to the
um is also to the commitments
because obligation
um is also to the commitments you've
already
already made
already made to
already made to see
already made to see to
already made to see to it
already made to see to it that
already made to see to it that they're
handled
handled and
already made to see to it that they're
handled and then
handled and then you
already made to see to it that they're
handled and then you can
handled and then you can move
already made to see to it that they're
handled and then you can move on
>> regressively.
>> regressively. And
>> regressively. And besides
>> regressively. And besides there
shouldn't
shouldn't be
>> regressively. And besides there
shouldn't be any
shouldn't be any interference
>> regressively. And besides there
shouldn't be any interference in
shouldn't be any interference in being
>> regressively. And besides there
shouldn't be any interference in being a
parent
parent and
parent and a
parent and a working
parent and a working person
parent and a working person and
spiritual
uh
uh work
uh work and
uh work and commitment
uh work and commitment because
uh work and commitment because you
uh work and commitment because you can
do
do it
uh work and commitment because you can
do it no
do it no matter
uh work and commitment because you can
do it no matter what
do it no matter what you're
uh work and commitment because you can
do it no matter what you're doing.
>> All
>> All right.
>> All right. Thank
>> All right. Thank you
>> All right. Thank you very
>> All right. Thank you very much.
Yes.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. Not
>> Hi. Not not
>> Hi. Not not coming
>> Hi. Not not coming to
>> Hi. Not not coming to Montreal
>> Hi. Not not coming to Montreal soon.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yes.
>> You're
>> You're from
>> Yes.
>> You're from Montreal?
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Yes.
So,
So, I
>> Okay. Yes.
So, I have
So, I have a
>> Okay. Yes.
So, I have a couple
So, I have a couple of
>> Okay. Yes.
So, I have a couple of question.
Uh
Uh I'm
Uh I'm glad
Uh I'm glad to
Uh I'm glad to have
Uh I'm glad to have here
Uh I'm glad to have here about
Uh I'm glad to have here about the
adulation
adulation because
Uh I'm glad to have here about the
adulation because I
adulation because I had
Uh I'm glad to have here about the
adulation because I had I
adulation because I had I had
Uh I'm glad to have here about the
adulation because I had I had a
adulation because I had I had a company
before
before with
before with 75
before with 75 employee
before with 75 employee and
before with 75 employee and I
before with 75 employee and I was
before with 75 employee and I was a
before with 75 employee and I was a head
of
of in
before with 75 employee and I was a head
of in my
of in my area
before with 75 employee and I was a head
of in my area of
of in my area of spiritual
before with 75 employee and I was a head
of in my area of spiritual teaching
of in my area of spiritual teaching and
I
I when
I when I
take
take the
I when I
take the decision
take the decision to
I when I
take the decision to leave
take the decision to leave or
I when I
take the decision to leave or and
take the decision to leave or and sell
the
the company
the company I
the company I felt
the company I felt the
the company I felt the loss
the company I felt the loss and
the company I felt the loss and I
the company I felt the loss and I see
the company I felt the loss and I see I
I
I recognize
the company I felt the loss and I see I
I recognize today
I recognize today that
the company I felt the loss and I see I
I recognize today that it's
I recognize today that it's like
the company I felt the loss and I see I
I recognize today that it's like an
addiction
>> when
>> when people
addiction
>> when people look
>> when people look at
addiction
>> when people look at you
>> when people look at you as
addiction
>> when people look at you as the
>> when people look at you as the the
addiction
>> when people look at you as the the boss
or
or the
or the one
or the one who
or the one who is
or the one who is leading
or the one who is leading them.
or the one who is leading them. You
or the one who is leading them. You can
be
be very
or the one who is leading them. You can
be very much
be very much addicted
or the one who is leading them. You can
be very much addicted to
be very much addicted to that.
So
it's
it's just
So
it's just a
it's just a comment
So
it's just a comment from
it's just a comment from my
So
it's just a comment from my own
it's just a comment from my own uh
observation.
observation. Yes.
>> From
>> From your
observation. Yes.
>> From your research
from
from the
from the people
from the people that
from the people that you
from the people that you uh
from the people that you uh read
from the people that you uh read about
the
the biography,
do
do you
do you have
do you have some
do you have some books
do you have some books or
do you have some books or some
do you have some books or some people
who
who talk
do you have some books or some people
who talk about
who talk about the
do you have some books or some people
who talk about the transition
who talk about the transition to
do you have some books or some people
who talk about the transition to the
who talk about the transition to the 600
level?
level? Because
level? Because in
level? Because in this
level? Because in this book
level? Because in this book you
level? Because in this book you you
level? Because in this book you you talk
about
about the
level? Because in this book you you talk
about the dark
about the dark knight
level? Because in this book you you talk
about the dark knight of
about the dark knight of the
level? Because in this book you you talk
about the dark knight of the of
about the dark knight of the of the
level? Because in this book you you talk
about the dark knight of the of the soul
or
or Diego.
or Diego. But
or Diego. But did
or Diego. But did you
or Diego. But did you find
or Diego. But did you find some
interesting
interesting book
or Diego. But did you find some
interesting book like
interesting book like Gandhi
Centilla
Centilla or
Centilla or someone?
Centilla or someone? Uh
>> no
>> no that
Centilla or someone? Uh
>> no that you
>> I
>> I list
>> I list in
>> I list in on
>> I list in on the
>> I list in on the chapter
>> I list in on the chapter on
>> I list in on the chapter on the
>> I list in on the chapter on the 600s
>> I list in on the chapter on the 600s I
list
list I
>> I list in on the chapter on the 600s I
list I think
list I think uh
>> I list in on the chapter on the 600s I
list I think uh authors
list I think uh authors of
>> I list in on the chapter on the 600s I
list I think uh authors of reference.
list I think uh authors of reference. Is
it
it this
it this book
it this book or
it this book or the
it this book or the next
it this book or the next book?
>> Yes.
>> The
>> The devotional
>> The devotional on
>> The devotional on deval.
>> The devotional on deval. No
transcending.
>> All right.
>> All right. Okay.
>> All right. Okay. So
>> All right. Okay. So then
>> All right. Okay. So then the
>> All right. Okay. So then the chapter
>> All right. Okay. So then the chapter on
the
the 600s
>> All right. Okay. So then the chapter on
the 600s I
the 600s I would
>> All right. Okay. So then the chapter on
the 600s I would have
the 600s I would have some
>> All right. Okay. So then the chapter on
the 600s I would have some well-known
authors
authors in
authors in the
authors in the 600
authors in the 600 listed
authors in the 600 listed there
authors in the 600 listed there in
authors in the 600 listed there in the
chapter.
>> Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> So
>> So we
>> So we can
>> So we can recognize
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Sure.
>> what
>> what they
>> what they went
>> what they went through
>> what they went through in
>> what they went through in some
>> what they went through in some of
>> what they went through in some of their
books.
>> Many
>> Many tell
>> Many tell their
>> Many tell their story.
>> Many tell their story. Yes.
>> Many tell their story. Yes. Many
>> Many tell their story. Yes. Many tell
their
their story.
>> Many tell their story. Yes. Many tell
their story. Yes.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> In
>> In the
>> In the spiritual
>> In the spiritual teaching
>> In the spiritual teaching I
>> In the spiritual teaching I was
>> In the spiritual teaching I was before
>> In the spiritual teaching I was before I
was
was using
>> In the spiritual teaching I was before I
was using the
was using the sound
>> In the spiritual teaching I was before I
was using the sound you
was using the sound you like
>> In the spiritual teaching I was before I
was using the sound you like that.
>> Yes.
>> You.
>> It
>> Yes.
>> It was
>> It was with
>> Yes.
>> It was with this
>> It was with this teaching.
>> Yes.
>> It was with this teaching. I
>> It was with this teaching. I read
>> Yes.
>> It was with this teaching. I read a
>> It was with this teaching. I read a book
also
also from
also from Sufism
also from Sufism mysticism
also from Sufism mysticism of
also from Sufism mysticism of sound.
Yeah.
Yeah. Network
also from Sufism mysticism of sound.
Yeah. Network very
Yeah. Network very credible
also from Sufism mysticism of sound.
Yeah. Network very credible sound.
Yeah. Network very credible sound. Did
you
you ever
you ever calibrate
you ever calibrate that
you ever calibrate that sound?
>> I
>> I think
you ever calibrate that sound?
>> I think I've
>> I think I've done
you ever calibrate that sound?
>> I think I've done it.
>> I think I've done it. Uh
you ever calibrate that sound?
>> I think I've done it. Uh it's
>> I think I've done it. Uh it's called
you ever calibrate that sound?
>> I think I've done it. Uh it's called the
sound
sound uh
sound uh the
sound uh the hell
sound uh the hell is
sound uh the hell is it
sound uh the hell is it called
sound uh the hell is it called now?
sound uh the hell is it called now? The
sound
sound uh
I
I know
I know what
I know what you're
I know what you're referring
I know what you're referring to.
I know what you're referring to. There's
um
um American
I know what you're referring to. There's
um American groups
um American groups based
I know what you're referring to. There's
um American groups based on
um American groups based on the
I know what you're referring to. There's
um American groups based on the same
>> uh
>> uh car
>> technology.
>> technology. Huh?
>> Aken
>> Aken car.
>> Aken car. Yeah.
>> Aken car. Yeah. So
>> Aken car.
>> Aken car. Yeah. So what
>> Aken car. Yeah. So what is
>> Aken car.
>> Aken car. Yeah. So what is the
>> Aken car. Yeah. So what is the question?
>> Did
>> Did you
>> Did you ever
>> Did you ever calibrate
>> Did you ever calibrate this
>> Did you ever calibrate this sound?
>> Did you ever calibrate this sound? You
>> you
>> okay?
>> okay? You
>> you
>> okay? You we
>> okay? You we have
>> you
>> okay? You we have permission
>> okay? You we have permission is
>> you
>> okay? You we have permission is over
>> okay? You we have permission is over 200
resist
300 resist
300 resist 400
resist
300 resist 400 resist.
300 resist 400 resist. 800
resist
300 resist 400 resist. 800 resist.
600 resist.
500 resist.
500 resist. 510,
600 resist.
500 resist. 510, 520,
500 resist. 510, 520, 530,
525,
5,
5, it's
525,
5, it's about
5, it's about 520.
525,
5, it's about 520. That's
5, it's about 520. That's because
525,
5, it's about 520. That's because of
5, it's about 520. That's because of the
intention.
intention. You
intention. You see?
>> Okay.
>> In
>> In other
>> In other words,
>> In other words, like
>> In other words, like genulection
>> In other words, like genulection or
folding
folding your
>> In other words, like genulection or
folding your hands
folding your hands or
>> In other words, like genulection or
folding your hands or uh
folding your hands or uh the
>> In other words, like genulection or
folding your hands or uh the prayer
prayer
prayer wheel,
prayer wheel, the
prayer wheel, the intention
prayer wheel, the intention is
prayer wheel, the intention is what
gives
gives it.
prayer wheel, the intention is what
gives it. I
gives it. I don't
prayer wheel, the intention is what
gives it. I don't think
gives it. I don't think the
prayer wheel, the intention is what
gives it. I don't think the thing
gives it. I don't think the thing in
prayer wheel, the intention is what
gives it. I don't think the thing in and
of
of itself
of itself had
of itself had calibrates
of itself had calibrates anything.
>> Okay.
>> What
>> What about
>> What about the
>> What about the home?
>> M
>> M is
>> What about the home?
>> M is something
>> M is something different.
>> What about the home?
>> M is something different. Okay,
>> that's
>> that's about
>> that's about 700.
>> that's about 700. Yeah,
>> that's about 700. Yeah, it
>> it
>> it doesn't
>> that's about 700. Yeah, it
>> it doesn't depend
>> it doesn't depend about
>> that's about 700. Yeah, it
>> it doesn't depend about the
>> it doesn't depend about the intention.
>> It's
>> It's a
>> It's a field
>> It's a field of
>> It's a field of its
>> It's a field of its own.
>> Um
>> Um is
>> It's a field of its own.
>> Um is like
>> Um is like a
>> It's a field of its own.
>> Um is like a it's
>> Um is like a it's it's
>> It's a field of its own.
>> Um is like a it's it's ancient.
>> Um is like a it's it's ancient. It's
>> It's a field of its own.
>> Um is like a it's it's ancient. It's an
ancient
>> one
>> one comes
ancient
>> one comes from
>> one comes from ancient.
>> Okay.
>> While
>> While you
would
would not
Okay.
Okay. So
>> you
>> you follow
>> you follow what
>> you follow what I'm
>> you follow what I'm saying
>> you follow what I'm saying but
>> you follow what I'm saying but the
intention
intention behind
>> you follow what I'm saying but the
intention behind it
intention behind it is
>> you follow what I'm saying but the
intention behind it is the
intention behind it is the key.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So
>> Okay. So he's
>> Okay. So he's he
>> Okay. So he's he told
>> Okay. So he's he told that
>> Okay. So he's he told that the
>> Okay. So he's he told that the U
>> Okay. So he's he told that the U was
>> Okay. So he's he told that the U was at
this
this level
>> Okay. So he's he told that the U was at
this level 525
this level 525 because
>> Okay. So he's he told that the U was at
this level 525 because of
this level 525 because of the
>> Okay. So he's he told that the U was at
this level 525 because of the of
this level 525 because of the of the
intention
intention mainly.
>> In
>> In other
intention mainly.
>> In other words,
>> In other words, if
intention mainly.
>> In other words, if you
>> In other words, if you were
intention mainly.
>> In other words, if you were if
>> In other words, if you were if you
intention mainly.
>> In other words, if you were if you were
meditating
meditating okay
meditating okay and
meditating okay and you
behind
behind that
meditating okay and you
behind that okay
behind that okay he's
meditating okay and you
behind that okay he's not
behind that okay he's not leaving
because
because of
because of me.
because of me. Oh,
because of me. Oh, no.
He
He had
because of me. Oh, no.
He had he
He had he has
because of me. Oh, no.
He had he has to
He had he has to take
because of me. Oh, no.
He had he has to take a
He had he has to take a medication
because of me. Oh, no.
He had he has to take a medication for
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> Oh, okay. Okay.
>> So,
>> So, uh
>> thank
>> thank you
>> thank you very
>> thank you very much
>> thank you very much for
>> thank you very much for your
>> thank you very much for your time
>> thank you very much for your time and
your
your Susan
>> thank you very much for your time and
your Susan too.
>> Yes,
I
I remember
>> Yes,
I remember the
I remember the four
>> Yes,
I remember the four o'
>> Hello.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Um,
I
I can't
I can't believe
I can't believe I'm
I can't believe I'm actually
I can't believe I'm actually meeting
somebody
somebody that's
I can't believe I'm actually meeting
somebody that's enlightened.
somebody that's enlightened. I
I can't believe I'm actually meeting
somebody that's enlightened. I can't
believe
believe I
believe I get
believe I get to
believe I get to do
believe I get to do this
believe I get to do this in
believe I get to do this in this
lifetime.
>> Isn't
>> Isn't it
>> Isn't it fun?
>> It's
>> It's It's
>> Isn't it fun?
>> It's It's the
>> It's It's the most
>> Isn't it fun?
>> It's It's the most exciting
>> It's It's the most exciting day
>> Isn't it fun?
>> It's It's the most exciting day of
>> It's It's the most exciting day of my
life.
life. As
life. As lame
life. As lame as
life. As lame as that
life. As lame as that might
life. As lame as that might sound,
life. As lame as that might sound, it
is.
is. I'm
life. As lame as that might sound, it
is. I'm just
is. I'm just so
life. As lame as that might sound, it
is. I'm just so excited.
is. I'm just so excited. Um,
life. As lame as that might sound, it
is. I'm just so excited. Um, I
is. I'm just so excited. Um, I have
life. As lame as that might sound, it
is. I'm just so excited. Um, I have two
questions.
questions. one
questions. one is
questions. one is um
questions. one is um in
questions. one is um in this
questions. one is um in this book
questions. one is um in this book where
you're
you're talking
questions. one is um in this book where
you're talking about
you're talking about the
questions. one is um in this book where
you're talking about the below
you're talking about the below the
questions. one is um in this book where
you're talking about the below the 200s
and
and about
and about the
and about the emotions
and about the emotions uh
and about the emotions uh I
and about the emotions uh I was
and about the emotions uh I was wanting
to
to know
and about the emotions uh I was wanting
to know if
to know if it
and about the emotions uh I was wanting
to know if it would
to know if it would be
and about the emotions uh I was wanting
to know if it would be all
to know if it would be all right
and about the emotions uh I was wanting
to know if it would be all right if
to know if it would be all right if I
wanted
wanted to
wanted to put
wanted to put that
wanted to put that into
wanted to put that into some
wanted to put that into some classes
wanted to put that into some classes for
my
my clients
>> good
>> good be
>> good be okay
>> yeah
>> yeah the
>> good be okay
>> yeah the energy
>> yeah the energy what
>> good be okay
>> yeah the energy what they
>> yeah the energy what they you
>> good be okay
>> yeah the energy what they you know
because
because people
because people should
because people should know
because people should know the
because people should know the more
because people should know the more you
know
know about
because people should know the more you
know about it
know about it the
because people should know the more you
know about it the less
know about it the less of
because people should know the more you
know about it the less of a
know about it the less of a hold
because people should know the more you
know about it the less of a hold it
know about it the less of a hold it has
on
on you
>> okay
>> and
>> and then
>> and then also
>> and then also um
>> and then also um where
>> and then also um where I
>> and then also um where I work
>> and then also um where I work uh
>> and then also um where I work uh there's
a
a woman
>> and then also um where I work uh there's
a woman that
a woman that um
uh
has
has the
uh
has the gift
has the gift of
uh
has the gift of discernment.
has the gift of discernment. So
uh
has the gift of discernment. So she
has the gift of discernment. So she says
and
and um
>> she
>> she has
and um
>> she has what?
>> The
>> The gift
>> The gift of
>> The gift of discernment.
>> So
>> So she
>> The gift of discernment.
>> So she says,
>> "Oh,
>> "Oh, the
>> "Oh, the gift
>> "Oh, the gift of
>> "Oh, the gift of discernment."
>> Yes,
>> Yes, sir.
>> "Oh, the gift of discernment."
>> Yes, sir. Okay.
>> I
>> I could
>> I could use
>> I could use the
>> I could use the vulgarity
>> I could use the vulgarity to
>> I could use the vulgarity to explain
>> I could use the vulgarity to explain it,
but
but I
>> I could use the vulgarity to explain it,
but I won't.
>> Okay.
>> You
>> You know
>> Okay.
>> You know what
>> You know what you
>> Okay.
>> You know what you know
>> You know what you know from
>> Okay.
>> You know what you know from hot
>> You know what you know from hot rock.
Yes.
Anyway,
Anyway, um
Yes.
Anyway, um it's
Anyway, um it's it
Yes.
Anyway, um it's it see
Anyway, um it's it see it
Yes.
Anyway, um it's it see it seems
Anyway, um it's it see it seems to
Yes.
Anyway, um it's it see it seems to me
that
that she
that she calibrates
that she calibrates at
that she calibrates at the
that she calibrates at the level
that she calibrates at the level of
pride
and
and so
and so I'm
and so I'm confused
>> likely
>> and
>> and I'm
>> and I'm also
>> and I'm also confused
>> and I'm also confused that
>> and I'm also confused that when
>> and I'm also confused that when she
>> and I'm also confused that when she sees
things
things they
>> and I'm also confused that when she sees
things they she
things they she has
>> and I'm also confused that when she sees
things they she has to
things they she has to interpret
>> and I'm also confused that when she sees
things they she has to interpret them
like
like people
like people with
like people with mental
like people with mental illness
like people with mental illness are
supposedly
supposedly have
like people with mental illness are
supposedly have a
supposedly have a polka
like people with mental illness are
supposedly have a polka dot
supposedly have a polka dot hat
like people with mental illness are
supposedly have a polka dot hat on
supposedly have a polka dot hat on their
head
>> and
>> and it's
head
>> and it's quite
>> and it's quite confusing.
>> Well,
>> Well, I
>> Well, I wasn't
>> Well, I wasn't paying
>> Well, I wasn't paying attention
>> Well, I wasn't paying attention then.
It's
It's your
>> Well, I wasn't paying attention then.
It's your own
It's your own game.
>> Well, I wasn't paying attention then.
It's your own game. you
It's your own game. you know,
>> Well, I wasn't paying attention then.
It's your own game. you know, she
It's your own game. you know, she plays.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I
>> Okay. I I
>> Okay. I I thought
>> Okay. I I thought so,
>> Okay. I I thought so, but
>> Okay. I I thought so, but um
>> Okay. I I thought so, but um she
>> Okay. I I thought so, but um she when
she
she does
>> Okay. I I thought so, but um she when
she does it,
she does it, she
>> Okay. I I thought so, but um she when
she does it, she asks
she does it, she asks Jesus.
>> Okay. I I thought so, but um she when
she does it, she asks Jesus. And
she does it, she asks Jesus. And so,
>> yeah,
>> I
>> I I
>> yeah,
>> I I really
>> I I really get
>> yeah,
>> I I really get confused
>> I I really get confused about
>> yeah,
>> I I really get confused about that.
>> It's
>> It's not
>> It's not really
>> It's not really important,
>> It's not really important, you
>> It's not really important, you know,
>> It's not really important, you know, in
a
a way.
>> Okay.
>> There's
>> There's all
>> Okay.
>> There's all kinds
>> There's all kinds of
>> Okay.
>> There's all kinds of people
>> There's all kinds of people that
>> Okay.
>> There's all kinds of people that fool
around
around with
around with various
around with various energies.
around with various energies. They
around with various energies. They get
into
into very
around with various energies. They get
into very strange
into very strange places
>> and
>> and have
>> and have strange
>> and have strange experiences
>> and
>> and and
>> and have strange experiences
>> and and that's
>> and and that's why
>> and have strange experiences
>> and and that's why I
>> and and that's why I explained
>> and have strange experiences
>> and and that's why I explained to
>> and and that's why I explained to people
don't
don't go
don't go there
don't go there unless
don't go there unless you're
don't go there unless you're gifted.
don't go there unless you're gifted. You
see?
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> Okay. Yeah. I
>> Okay. Yeah. I never
>> Okay. Yeah. I never wanted
>> Okay. Yeah. I never wanted to
>> Okay. Yeah. I never wanted to go
>> Okay. Yeah. I never wanted to go there.
>> Also,
>> Also, I
>> Okay. Yeah. I never wanted to go there.
>> Also, I have
>> Also, I have another
>> Okay. Yeah. I never wanted to go there.
>> Also, I have another question.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um,
I
I need
>> Yeah. Um,
I need a
I need a teacher
>> Yeah. Um,
I need a teacher and
I need a teacher and um,
>> Yeah. Um,
I need a teacher and um, are
I need a teacher and um, are there
>> Yeah. Um,
I need a teacher and um, are there any
in
in the
in the United
in the United You
in the United You said
in the United You said there's
in the United You said there's 12
in the United You said there's 12 people
that
that are
in the United You said there's 12 people
that are enlightened
that are enlightened in
in the United You said there's 12 people
that are enlightened in the
that are enlightened in the world
in the United You said there's 12 people
that are enlightened in the world and
that are enlightened in the world and I
don't
don't know
don't know how
don't know how to
don't know how to find
don't know how to find a
don't know how to find a teacher.
>> Who's
>> Who's outside?
>> I
>> I know
>> I know you're
>> I know you're a
>> I know you're a teacher
>> I know you're a teacher and
>> outside
>> outside of
>> I know you're a teacher and
>> outside of Glendale.
>> outside of Glendale. I
>> I know you're a teacher and
>> outside of Glendale. I heard
>> outside of Glendale. I heard of
>> I know you're a teacher and
>> outside of Glendale. I heard of one
there.
>> Where
>> Where do
there.
>> Where do you
>> Where do you live?
>> I
>> I live
>> I live in
>> I live in Sacramento
>> I live in Sacramento and
>> I live in Sacramento and I
>> I live in Sacramento and I was
>> I live in Sacramento and I was seriously
thinking
thinking of
>> I live in Sacramento and I was seriously
thinking of moving
thinking of moving here
>> I live in Sacramento and I was seriously
thinking of moving here just
thinking of moving here just so
>> I live in Sacramento and I was seriously
thinking of moving here just so I
thinking of moving here just so I could
go
go to
go to your
go to your little
go to your little groups.
go to your little groups. Well,
go to your little groups. Well, the
California
California groups
go to your little groups. Well, the
California groups are
California groups are uh
go to your little groups. Well, the
California groups are uh some
California groups are uh some of
go to your little groups. Well, the
California groups are uh some of them
are
are centered
are centered out
are centered out of
are centered out of uh
are centered out of uh um
I'm
I'm not
are centered out of uh um
I'm not too
I'm not too uh
are centered out of uh um
I'm not too uh left
I'm not too uh left brain
are centered out of uh um
I'm not too uh left brain for
>> uh
>> uh in
>> uh in California
>> unity
>> unity out
>> uh in California
>> unity out of
>> unity out of unity
>> uh in California
>> unity out of unity churches
>> unity out of unity churches and
>> I
>> I could
>> I could find
>> I could find some
>> I could find some people
>> I could find some people there
>> I could find some people there that
>> um
>> I
>> I think
>> I think there's
>> I think there's a
>> I think there's a unity
>> I think there's a unity uh
>> I think there's a unity uh there's
>> I think there's a unity uh there's a
discussion
discussion group
>> I think there's a unity uh there's a
discussion group on
discussion group on this
>> I think there's a unity uh there's a
discussion group on this work
discussion group on this work at
>> I think there's a unity uh there's a
discussion group on this work at uh
unity
unity of
unity of we
unity of we were
unity of we were there
unity of we were there unity
unity of we were there unity of
>> Marian
several
several unity
several unity churches
several unity churches there
several unity churches there are
several unity churches there are the
locus
locus of
several unity churches there are the
locus of discussion
locus of discussion groups
several unity churches there are the
locus of discussion groups you
locus of discussion groups you can
several unity churches there are the
locus of discussion groups you can check
around.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
around.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> The
>> The one
>> The one that
>> The one that sent
>> The one that sent us
>> The one that sent us the
>> The one that sent us the teaching
>> The one that sent us the teaching man
>> The one that sent us the teaching man uh
>> this
>> this lady
>> The one that sent us the teaching man uh
>> this lady right
>> this lady right here
>> The one that sent us the teaching man uh
>> this lady right here runs
>> this lady right here runs a
>> The one that sent us the teaching man uh
>> this lady right here runs a runs
>> this lady right here runs a runs our
>> The one that sent us the teaching man uh
>> this lady right here runs a runs our uh
website
website for
website for our
website for our um
website for our um um
website for our um um discussion
website for our um um discussion groups
online
online so
website for our um um discussion groups
online so she
online so she can
website for our um um discussion groups
online so she can give
online so she can give you
website for our um um discussion groups
online so she can give you information.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, great.
>> To
>> To send
>> Okay, great.
>> To send us
>> To send us the
>> Okay, great.
>> To send us the uh
>> To send us the uh teaching
>> Okay, great.
>> To send us the uh teaching manual
>> To send us the uh teaching manual for
this
this work.
>> Marge
>> Marge Brit.
>> Marge Brit. Where
>> Marge Brit. Where was
>> Marge Brit. Where was that?
>> Marge Brit. Where was that? Unity
>> Marge Brit. Where was that? Unity of
>> that
>> that was
>> Marge Brit. Where was that? Unity of
>> that was Tusken.
>> that was Tusken. Tustin.
>> Unity
>> Unity of
>> Unity of Tustin.
>> Unity of Tustin. Yes.
>> Unity of Tustin. Yes. Yes.
>> But
>> But she's
>> Unity of Tustin. Yes. Yes.
>> But she's no
>> But she's no longer
>> Unity of Tustin. Yes. Yes.
>> But she's no longer there.
>> But she's no longer there. She's
>> Unity of Tustin. Yes. Yes.
>> But she's no longer there. She's at
>> But she's no longer there. She's at the
She's
She's at
She's at Unity
She's at Unity in
She's at Unity in uh
She's at Unity in uh Kansas
She's at Unity in uh Kansas City
She's at Unity in uh Kansas City now.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
She's at Unity in uh Kansas City now.
>> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see. Okay.
>> Okay.
>> They've
>> They've moved
>> Okay.
>> They've moved her.
>> So,
>> okay.
>> okay. Thank
>> So,
>> okay. Thank you.
>> Anyway,
>> online
>> online groups
>> Anyway,
>> online groups are
>> online groups are good.
>> Anyway,
>> online groups are good. If
>> online groups are good. If any
>> Anyway,
>> online groups are good. If any of
>> online groups are good. If any of you
are
are looking
are looking for
are looking for some
are looking for some kind
are looking for some kind of
are looking for some kind of connection
with
with uh
are looking for some kind of connection
with uh other
with uh other people
are looking for some kind of connection
with uh other people that
with uh other people that uh
are looking for some kind of connection
with uh other people that uh are
interested
interested in
interested in the
interested in the work,
interested in the work, the
interested in the work, the online
groups
groups are
interested in the work, the online
groups are good.
groups are good. um
interested in the work, the online
groups are good. um you
groups are good. um you can
interested in the work, the online
groups are good. um you can go
groups are good. um you can go there
interested in the work, the online
groups are good. um you can go there and
um
um connect
um connect with
um connect with other
um connect with other people
um connect with other people that
um connect with other people that are
doing
doing the
um connect with other people that are
doing the same
doing the same uh
um connect with other people that are
doing the same uh and
doing the same uh and have
um connect with other people that are
doing the same uh and have the
doing the same uh and have the same
questions
questions and
questions and some
questions and some of
questions and some of them
questions and some of them can
questions and some of them can answer
and
and some
questions and some of them can answer
and some of
and some of them
questions and some of them can answer
and some of them can't
and some of them can't and
questions and some of them can answer
and some of them can't and if
and some of them can't and if they
questions and some of them can answer
and some of them can't and if they can't
then
then they
then they come
then they come to
then they come to us
then they come to us and
then they come to us and we
then they come to us and we answer
then they come to us and we answer them.
So
So the
then they come to us and we answer them.
So the online
So the online groups
then they come to us and we answer them.
So the online groups are
So the online groups are very
then they come to us and we answer them.
So the online groups are very very
So the online groups are very very good.
>> What
>> What website?
>> Um
>> Um there's
>> What website?
>> Um there's several
>> Um there's several different
>> What website?
>> Um there's several different ones
>> Um there's several different ones if
>> What website?
>> Um there's several different ones if you
want
want to
want to check.
>> Huh?
>> Project
>> Project consciousness.org
>> Project consciousness.org or
>> Project consciousness.org or is
>> Project consciousness.org or is um
someone
someone where
>> Project consciousness.org or is um
someone where we
someone where we have
>> Project consciousness.org or is um
someone where we have already
someone where we have already done
>> Project consciousness.org or is um
someone where we have already done a
someone where we have already done a lot
of
of special
of special calibrations
of special calibrations for
of special calibrations for him.
of special calibrations for him. That's
Scott.
>> And
>> And then
>> And then this
>> And then this lady
>> And then this lady right
>> And then this lady right here,
>> And then this lady right here, stand
>> And then this lady right here, stand up,
>> Alison
I
don't
don't Okay.
>> Right.
>> Right. But
>> Right. But I
>> Right. But I mean
>> Right. But I mean if
>> Right. But I mean if you
>> Right. But I mean if you want
>> Right. But I mean if you want a
connection
connection with
>> Right. But I mean if you want a
connection with other
connection with other groups
>> Right. But I mean if you want a
connection with other groups that
connection with other groups that you
want
want to
want to that
want to that she
want to that she handles
want to that she handles the
want to that she handles the groups.
want to that she handles the groups. If
you
you want
want to that she handles the groups. If
you want connection
you want connection with
want to that she handles the groups. If
you want connection with the
you want connection with the groups,
>> stand
>> stand up
>> stand up just
>> stand up just for
>> stand up just for a
>> stand up just for a sec.
>> stand up just for a sec. Alison
>> stand up just for a sec. Alison Wilson
>> uh
>> uh she
>> stand up just for a sec. Alison Wilson
>> uh she has
>> uh she has uh
>> stand up just for a sec. Alison Wilson
>> uh she has uh she
>> uh she has uh she has
>> stand up just for a sec. Alison Wilson
>> uh she has uh she has the
>> uh she has uh she has the connections
with
with all
with all other
with all other groups
with all other groups that
with all other groups that might
with all other groups that might be
close
close to
with all other groups that might be
close to your
close to your areas
with all other groups that might be
close to your areas and
close to your areas and that
with all other groups that might be
close to your areas and that sort
close to your areas and that sort of
thing
thing if
thing if you
thing if you have
thing if you have any
thing if you have any questions.
thing if you have any questions. So
>> I
>> I just
thing if you have any questions. So
>> I just wanted
>> I just wanted to
thing if you have any questions. So
>> I just wanted to say
>> I just wanted to say hi
thing if you have any questions. So
>> I just wanted to say hi teacher.
>> Hi
>> hi
>> hi Susan.
>> Um
>> Um my
>> Um my question
>> Um my question has
>> Um my question has to
>> Um my question has to do
>> Um my question has to do with
>> Um my question has to do with a
>> Um my question has to do with a course
in
in miracles.
>> Um my question has to do with a course
in miracles. I
in miracles. I started
>> Um my question has to do with a course
in miracles. I started reading
in miracles. I started reading a
>> Um my question has to do with a course
in miracles. I started reading a course
in
in miracles
in miracles in
in miracles in the
in miracles in the text
in miracles in the text uh
in miracles in the text uh part
in miracles in the text uh part of
in miracles in the text uh part of it
and
and got
in miracles in the text uh part of it
and got about
and got about 140
in miracles in the text uh part of it
and got about 140 something
and got about 140 something pages.
in miracles in the text uh part of it
and got about 140 something pages. Was
never
never really
never really able
never really able to
never really able to get
never really able to get my
never really able to get my teeth
never really able to get my teeth into
it.
it. you
never really able to get my teeth into
it. you know,
it. you know, I
never really able to get my teeth into
it. you know, I could
it. you know, I could read
never really able to get my teeth into
it. you know, I could read a
it. you know, I could read a few
never really able to get my teeth into
it. you know, I could read a few pages
at
at a
at a time.
at a time. I
at a time. I just
at a time. I just couldn't
at a time. I just couldn't quite
at a time. I just couldn't quite get
with
with it.
at a time. I just couldn't quite get
with it. And
with it. And I've
at a time. I just couldn't quite get
with it. And I've heard
with it. And I've heard you
at a time. I just couldn't quite get
with it. And I've heard you comment
with it. And I've heard you comment that
you
you thought
you thought that
you thought that the
you thought that the text
you thought that the text possibly
you thought that the text possibly came
from
from a
you thought that the text possibly came
from a different
from a different source
you thought that the text possibly came
from a different source on
from a different source on the
you thought that the text possibly came
from a different source on the workbook.
>> Well,
>> Well, I
>> Well, I I
>> Well, I I think
>> Well, I I think the
>> Well, I I think the workbook
>> Well, I I think the workbook is
>> Well, I I think the workbook is is
>> Well, I I think the workbook is is it
calibrates
calibrates higher,
>> Well, I I think the workbook is is it
calibrates higher, is
calibrates higher, is a
>> Well, I I think the workbook is is it
calibrates higher, is a lot
calibrates higher, is a lot easier?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Yeah. And my
>> Yeah. And my question
>> Yeah. And my question is,
>> Yeah. And my question is, should
>> Yeah. And my question is, should I
>> Yeah. And my question is, should I just
go
go straight
>> Yeah. And my question is, should I just
go straight to
go straight to the
>> Yeah. And my question is, should I just
go straight to the workbook
go straight to the workbook and
>> Yeah. And my question is, should I just
go straight to the workbook and bypass
the
the text
the text or
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I
the text or
>> Yeah. I would
>> Yeah. I would I
the text or
>> Yeah. I would I always
>> Yeah. I would I always advise
the text or
>> Yeah. I would I always advise people
>> Yeah. I would I always advise people do
the
the workbook
the workbook every
the workbook every day
the workbook every day and
the workbook every day and don't
the workbook every day and don't worry
about
about it.
>> Don't
>> Don't worry
>> Don't worry about
>> Don't worry about reading
>> Don't worry about reading the
>> Don't worry about reading the text.
Okay,
Okay, that's
>> Don't worry about reading the text.
Okay, that's it.
Okay, that's it. And
>> Don't worry about reading the text.
Okay, that's it. And and
Okay, that's it. And and a
>> Don't worry about reading the text.
Okay, that's it. And and a and
Okay, that's it. And and a and a
>> Don't worry about reading the text.
Okay, that's it. And and a and a quick
pick.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, quick
pick.
>> Oh, quick pick.
>> And
>> And a
>> And a quick
>> And a quick pick.
>> And a quick pick. Here,
>> And a quick pick. Here, honey.
>> And a quick pick. Here, honey. Sit
>> quick.
>> What
>> What the
>> Is
>> Is that
>> What the
>> Is that one
>> Is that one of
>> What the
>> Is that one of those
>> Is that one of those phones?
>> Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> We
>> We got
>> We got a
>> We got a picture
>> We got a picture taken
>> We got a picture taken by
>> We got a picture taken by a
>> We got a picture taken by a phone.
David,
>> that
>> that phone.
>> that phone. That
>> that phone. That was
>> that phone. That was a
>> that phone. That was a phone.
>> that phone. That was a phone. He
>> that phone. That was a phone. He just
had
had a
>> that phone. That was a phone. He just
had a picture
had a picture taken
>> that phone. That was a phone. He just
had a picture taken by
had a picture taken by a
>> that phone. That was a phone. He just
had a picture taken by a phone.
>> Okay.
>> Picture
>> Picture taken
>> Okay.
>> Picture taken by
>> Picture taken by a
>> Okay.
>> Picture taken by a phone.
>> Yes.
>> Doctor,
>> Doctor, I
>> Yes.
>> Doctor, I was
>> Doctor, I was um
>> Yes.
>> Doctor, I was um been
>> Doctor, I was um been trying
>> Yes.
>> Doctor, I was um been trying to
>> Doctor, I was um been trying to get
>> Yes.
>> Doctor, I was um been trying to get a
little
little bit
little bit better
little bit better understanding
little bit better understanding of
little bit better understanding of the
term
term karma.
little bit better understanding of the
term karma. Yes.
>> And
>> And is
>> And is karma
>> And is karma really
>> And is karma really simply
>> And is karma really simply that
>> And is karma really simply that we
>> And is karma really simply that we reap
what
what we
>> And is karma really simply that we reap
what we sow?
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, that's
>> Yeah, that's the
>> Yeah, that's the simplest
>> Yeah, that's the simplest explanation.
>> That's
>> That's the
>> Yeah, that's the simplest explanation.
>> That's the simplest.
>> Is
>> Is it
>> Is it possible
>> you
>> you go
>> Is it possible
>> you go this
>> you go this backs
>> Is it possible
>> you go this backs to
>> you go this backs to you?
>> Is it possible
>> you go this backs to you? Yeah.
>> Is
>> Is it
>> Is it possible
>> Is it possible to
>> Is it possible to undo
>> Is it possible to undo negative
>> Is it possible to undo negative karma?
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, of
>> Is it possible to undo negative karma?
>> Yeah, of course.
>> Yeah, of course. Otherwise,
>> Is it possible to undo negative karma?
>> Yeah, of course. Otherwise, we'd
>> Yeah, of course. Otherwise, we'd all
>> Is it possible to undo negative karma?
>> Yeah, of course. Otherwise, we'd all be
for,
for, you
for, you know,
for, you know, how
for, you know, how do
for, you know, how do we
for, you know, how do we do
for, you know, how do we do that
for, you know, how do we do that gone
for?
>> Is
>> Is there
>> Is there a
>> Is there a process?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you
>> Is there a process?
>> Oh, you would
>> Oh, you would just
>> Is there a process?
>> Oh, you would just live
>> Oh, you would just live a
>> Is there a process?
>> Oh, you would just live a spiritually
oriented
oriented life
oriented life and
oriented life and do
oriented life and do the
oriented life and do the best
oriented life and do the best you
oriented life and do the best you can.
That
That undo
oriented life and do the best you can.
That undo negative
That undo negative karma.
>> Live
>> Live your
>> Live your life
>> Live your life like
>> Live your life like a
>> Live your life like a prayer.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. be
>> Live your life like a prayer.
>> Yeah. be as
>> Yeah. be as forgiving.
>> Live your life like a prayer.
>> Yeah. be as forgiving. See
>> Yeah. be as forgiving. See the
sacredness
sacredness and
sacredness and beauty
sacredness and beauty of
sacredness and beauty of all
sacredness and beauty of all of
sacredness and beauty of all of life,
reverence,
reverence, life
sacredness and beauty of all of life,
reverence, life and
reverence, life and all
sacredness and beauty of all of life,
reverence, life and all of
reverence, life and all of its
expressions
and
and that
expressions
and that undoes
and that undoes it.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Selfless
>> Selfless service.
>> Thank you.
>> Selfless service. Those
>> Selfless service. Those are
>> Thank you.
>> Selfless service. Those are all
>> Selfless service. Those are all the
yoga,
meditation,
meditation, selfless
yoga,
meditation, selfless service,
meditation, selfless service, prayer,
devotion.
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
devotion.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you
>> Thank you. Thank you for
>> Thank you. Thank you for coming.
>> Mhm.
Mr.
Mr. Hawkins,
Mr. Hawkins, I
Mr. Hawkins, I feel
Mr. Hawkins, I feel a
Mr. Hawkins, I feel a deep
Mr. Hawkins, I feel a deep gratitude
Mr. Hawkins, I feel a deep gratitude for
the
the tremendous
Mr. Hawkins, I feel a deep gratitude for
the tremendous contribution
the tremendous contribution you
Mr. Hawkins, I feel a deep gratitude for
the tremendous contribution you have
given
given me.
>> Yes,
>> your
>> your enlightenment
has
has opened
>> your enlightenment
has opened and
has opened and increased
>> your enlightenment
has opened and increased my
has opened and increased my conscience
and
and energies
and energies of
and energies of certain
and energies of certain levels
and energies of certain levels that
levels
levels that
and energies of certain levels that
levels that I
levels that I wouldn't
and energies of certain levels that
levels that I wouldn't imagine
levels that I wouldn't imagine exists.
But
But because
But because the
But because the search
But because the search is
But because the search is not
But because the search is not over,
I'm
I'm still
But because the search is not over,
I'm still looking
I'm still looking finding
But because the search is not over,
I'm still looking finding and
I'm still looking finding and I've
But because the search is not over,
I'm still looking finding and I've been
reading
reading about
reading about Braa
reading about Braa and
reading about Braa and I've
reading about Braa and I've been
reading about Braa and I've been in
reading about Braa and I've been in his
at
at his
reading about Braa and I've been in his
at his school
and
and I
and I would
and I would like
>> what
>> what do
and I would like
>> what do you
>> what do you want
and I would like
>> what do you want from
>> what do you want from her?
>> What
>> What I
>> What I want
>> What I want is
>> What I want is to
>> What I want is to calibrate
>> What I want is to calibrate because
>> What I want is to calibrate because that
this
this entity
>> what
>> what are
>> what are you
>> what are you looking
>> what are you looking for
>> what are you looking for in
>> what are you looking for in that
person's
person's teaching?
Well,
Well, as
Well, as your
Well, as your knowledge
Well, as your knowledge has
Well, as your knowledge has a
Well, as your knowledge has a lot
Well, as your knowledge has a lot of
impact
impact in
Well, as your knowledge has a lot of
impact in my
impact in my life
Well, as your knowledge has a lot of
impact in my life all
impact in my life all his
Well, as your knowledge has a lot of
impact in my life all his his
impact in my life all his his knowledge
and
and because
and because he's
and because he's very
and because he's very very
and because he's very very new
and because he's very very new what
and because he's very very new what all
his
his because
and because he's very very new what all
his because he
his because he has
and because he's very very new what all
his because he has he's
his because he has he's an
and because he's very very new what all
his because he has he's an entity
his because he has he's an entity that
is
is channeling
is channeling through
is channeling through a
is channeling through a person.
is channeling through a person. So
is channeling through a person. So it's
something
something that
is channeling through a person. So it's
something that was
something that was really
is channeling through a person. So it's
something that was really in
something that was really in my
is channeling through a person. So it's
something that was really in my life.
>> I've
>> I've always
>> I've always said
>> I've always said to
>> I've always said to um
>> I've always said to um uh
>> I've always said to um uh don't
>> I've always said to um uh don't trust
any
any teacher
>> I've always said to um uh don't trust
any teacher unless
any teacher unless they're
>> I've always said to um uh don't trust
any teacher unless they're in
any teacher unless they're in a
>> I've always said to um uh don't trust
any teacher unless they're in a physical
body
>> and
>> or
>> or were
>> or were taught
>> or were taught in
>> or were taught in a
>> or were taught in a physical
>> or were taught in a physical body.
That's
That's a
>> or were taught in a physical body.
That's a generalized
That's a generalized teaching.
>> or were taught in a physical body.
That's a generalized teaching. have
nothing
nothing to
nothing to do
nothing to do with
nothing to do with the
nothing to do with the specifics
nothing to do with the specifics of
nothing to do with the specifics of what
you
you asked.
>> Well,
>> if
>> if you
>> Well,
>> if you can't
>> if you can't see
>> Well,
>> if you can't see them
>> if you can't see them or
>> Well,
>> if you can't see them or speak
>> if you can't see them or speak to
>> Well,
>> if you can't see them or speak to them,
>> I
>> I would
>> I would like
>> I would like to
>> I would like to I
>> I would like to I would
>> I would like to I would like
>> I would like to I would like to
>> I would like to I would like to be
>> like
>> like you
>> I would like to I would like to be
>> like you like
>> like you like the
>> I would like to I would like to be
>> like you like the glamour
>> like you like the glamour of
>> I would like to I would like to be
>> like you like the glamour of the
>> like you like the glamour of the magic
of
of it.
>> I
>> I would
of it.
>> I would like
>> I would like you
of it.
>> I would like you calibrate
>> I would like you calibrate his
of it.
>> I would like you calibrate his teaching
as
as you
as you do
as you do with
as you do with Buddha
as you do with Buddha or
as you do with Buddha or you
as you do with Buddha or you do
as you do with Buddha or you do with
Madrid.
Madrid. I
as you do with Buddha or you do with
Madrid. I would
Madrid. I would like
as you do with Buddha or you do with
Madrid. I would like be
Can
Can you
Can you calibrate
Can you calibrate me
Can you calibrate me that
Can you calibrate me that for
Can you calibrate me that for me?
>> No.
>> Is
>> Is this
>> Is this entity
>> Is this entity on
>> Is this entity on this
>> Is this entity on this in
>> Is this entity on this in this
>> Is this entity on this in this world?
>> No.
>> No. Well,
>> No. Well, the
>> No. Well, the knowledge
>> No. Well, the knowledge of
>> No. Well, the knowledge of JC
>> No. Well, the knowledge of JC Knights,
>> he's
>> Where
>> Where does
>> Where does the
>> Where does the entity
>> Where does the entity live
>> Where does the entity live that
>> Where does the entity live that speaks?
>> Excuse
>> Excuse me.
>> Where
>> Where is
>> Where is the
>> Where is the entity?
>> Where is the entity? The
>> Where is the entity? The teacher.
>> Where is the entity? The teacher. Where
is
is the
>> Where is the entity? The teacher. Where
is the teacher?
>> Where
>> Where is
>> Where is Rona
>> Where is Rona live?
>> Where
>> Where is
>> Where is Rona live?
>> Where is the
>> Where is the teacher?
>> Um,
>> Um, I
>> Um, I don't
>> Um, I don't know.
>> Um, I don't know. That's
>> Um, I don't know. That's it.
>> That's
>> That's uh
>> Um, I don't know. That's it.
>> That's uh You
>> That's uh You don't
>> Um, I don't know. That's it.
>> That's uh You don't know.
>> That's uh You don't know. Krishna
>> and
>> and if
>> and if Buddha
>> and if Buddha or
>> and if Buddha or Krishna
>> and if Buddha or Krishna have
>> and if Buddha or Krishna have not,
>> they're
>> they're not
>> and if Buddha or Krishna have not,
>> they're not the
>> they're not the same
>> and if Buddha or Krishna have not,
>> they're not the same dimension.
Okay,
>> they're
>> they're the
Okay,
>> they're the great
>> they're the great avatars
Okay,
>> they're the great avatars that
>> they're the great avatars that have
contextualized
contextualized the
contextualized the significance
contextualized the significance of
contextualized the significance of human
life
life for
contextualized the significance of human
life for thousands
life for thousands of
contextualized the significance of human
life for thousands of years.
You
You can't
You can't put
You can't put them
You can't put them in
You can't put them in the
You can't put them in the same
You can't put them in the same basket.
You
You understand
>> some
>> some certain
>> some certain but
>> some certain but I
>> some certain but I don't
>> some certain but I don't understand
>> some certain but I don't understand why
cannot
cannot you
>> some certain but I don't understand why
cannot you calibrate
cannot you calibrate the
>> some certain but I don't understand why
cannot you calibrate the books
cannot you calibrate the books or
>> some certain but I don't understand why
cannot you calibrate the books or JC
knives
knives their
knives their their
knives their their knowledge
knives their their knowledge or
knives their their knowledge or what
their
their philosophies
knives their their knowledge or what
their philosophies why
their philosophies why can't
knives their their knowledge or what
their philosophies why can't you
calibrate
calibrate that
>> I
>> I don't
calibrate that
>> I don't know
>> I don't know I'm
calibrate that
>> I don't know I'm I'm
>> I don't know I'm I'm not
calibrate that
>> I don't know I'm I'm not I'm
>> I don't know I'm I'm not I'm not
calibrate that
>> I don't know I'm I'm not I'm not trying
to
to to
>> you're
>> you're attracted
to to
>> you're attracted you're
>> you're attracted you're attracted
to to
>> you're attracted you're attracted to
>> you're attracted you're attracted to it
is
is that
is that correct
>> it's
>> it's something
is that correct
>> it's something new
>> it's something new and
>> yes
>> yes why
>> yes why are
>> yes why are you
>> yes why are you so
>> yes why are you so attracted
>> yes why are you so attracted to
>> yes why are you so attracted to it
>> because
>> you
>> you have
>> you have to
>> you have to ask
>> you have to ask what
>> you have to ask what is
>> you have to ask what is my
>> you have to ask what is my motive
>> you have to ask what is my motive and
what
what I'm
>> you have to ask what is my motive and
what I'm what
what I'm what I'm
>> very
>> very attracted
>> very attracted to
>> very attracted to you
>> very attracted to you also
>> very attracted to you also to
>> very attracted to you also to your
knowledge
also
>> let's
>> let's see
I
I have
I have counseledled
I have counseledled against
I have counseledled against channeling
>> and
>> and I
I have counseledled against channeling
>> and I continue
>> and I continue to
I have counseledled against channeling
>> and I continue to do
>> and I continue to do so
>> okay
>> that's
>> that's a
>> okay
>> that's a generic
>> that's a generic answer
>> I
>> I think
>> I think I
>> I think I mentioned
>> I think I mentioned during
>> I think I mentioned during the
lecture
Then
Then an
Then an entity
Then an entity on
Then an entity on the
Then an entity on the other
Then an entity on the other side
Then an entity on the other side that's
been
been there
Then an entity on the other side that's
been there for
been there for thousands
Then an entity on the other side that's
been there for thousands of
been there for thousands of years
Then an entity on the other side that's
been there for thousands of years is
hooked
hooked on
hooked on where
hooked on where it's
hooked on where it's at.
hooked on where it's at. It's
hooked on where it's at. It's not
evolving.
The
The same
The same place
The same place they
The same place they were
The same place they were during
Mesopotamia,
Mesopotamia, they
The same place they were during
Mesopotamia, they are
Mesopotamia, they are still
The same place they were during
Mesopotamia, they are still reading
palms
palms in
palms in this
palms in this lifetime
palms in this lifetime and
palms in this lifetime and reading
palms in this lifetime and reading tea
leaves
leaves and
palms in this lifetime and reading tea
leaves and all
leaves and all the
palms in this lifetime and reading tea
leaves and all the rest
leaves and all the rest that
palms in this lifetime and reading tea
leaves and all the rest that goes
leaves and all the rest that goes with
it.
it. It's
it. It's not
it. It's not a
it. It's not a it's
it. It's not a it's not
it. It's not a it's not an
it. It's not a it's not an evolutionary
pathway
and
and you
and you form
and you form an
and you form an attachment
and you form an attachment a
and you form an attachment a dependent
attachment
and
and the
and the magicalness
and the magicalness of
and the magicalness of it
and the magicalness of it all.
>> I
>> I would
and the magicalness of it all.
>> I would say
>> I would say to
and the magicalness of it all.
>> I would say to avoid
>> I would say to avoid channeling
and the magicalness of it all.
>> I would say to avoid channeling period
as
as a
as a general
as a general measure.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
as a general measure.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Let's
>> Let's see
>> Let's see the
>> Let's see the advice
>> Let's see the advice just
>> Let's see the advice just given
>> Let's see the advice just given was
correct.
correct. resist.
You're
You're glamorized
You're glamorized already
You're glamorized already by
You're glamorized already by it.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> All right.
>> That
>> That was
>> All right.
>> That was a
>> That was a tough
>> All right.
>> That was a tough one.
>> That
>> That was
>> That was a
>> That was a tough
>> That was a tough one.
>> Hi.
>> Mhm.
>> I
>> I gave
>> Mhm.
>> I gave your
>> I gave your book
>> Mhm.
>> I gave your book Powers
>> I gave your book Powers is
>> Mhm.
>> I gave your book Powers is Force
>> I gave your book Powers is Force to
President
President of
President of Mexico
President of Mexico about
President of Mexico about 3,
President of Mexico about 3, four
President of Mexico about 3, four weeks
ago.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Thank
>> Yeah. Thank you.
and
and to
>> Yeah. Thank you.
and to his
and to his chief
>> Yeah. Thank you.
and to his chief of
and to his chief of staff
>> Yeah. Thank you.
and to his chief of staff and
and to his chief of staff and to
>> Yeah. Thank you.
and to his chief of staff and to two
and to his chief of staff and to two of
the
the three
the three candidates
the three candidates to
the three candidates to be
the three candidates to be the
the three candidates to be the next
president
president of
the three candidates to be the next
president of Mexico.
president of Mexico. So
>> I'm
>> I'm praying
>> I'm praying for
>> I'm praying for a
>> I'm praying for a miracle.
>> Yeah.
>> That
>> That they
>> That they read
>> That they read it
>> That they read it is
>> That they read it is going
>> That they read it is going to
>> That they read it is going to be
>> That they read it is going to be the
>> That they read it is going to be the the
challenge.
challenge. If
>> That they read it is going to be the the
challenge. If they
challenge. If they read
>> That they read it is going to be the the
challenge. If they read it,
challenge. If they read it, I
>> That they read it is going to be the the
challenge. If they read it, I know
challenge. If they read it, I know what
the
the outcome
the outcome is
the outcome is going
the outcome is going to
the outcome is going to be.
the outcome is going to be. If
the outcome is going to be. If they
the outcome is going to be. If they read
it,
it, it's
the outcome is going to be. If they read
it, it's going
it, it's going to
the outcome is going to be. If they read
it, it's going to be
it, it's going to be a
the outcome is going to be. If they read
it, it's going to be a challenge.
it, it's going to be a challenge. My
question
question is
question is sort
question is sort of
question is sort of um
question is sort of um weird.
question is sort of um weird. It's
question is sort of um weird. It's about
ascension.
>> By
>> By what?
>> Ascension.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, ascension.
>> Ascension.
>> Oh, ascension. Yes.
>> You
>> You could
>> You could tell
>> You could tell me
>> You could tell me something
>> You could tell me something about
Ascension
Ascension of
>> You could tell me something about
Ascension of who?
>> Of
>> Of me.
>> Of me. Of
>> Of me. Of course.
>> Eventually.
>> Eventually. Why
>> Of me. Of course.
>> Eventually. Why not?
>> Eventually. Why not? You
>> Of me. Of course.
>> Eventually. Why not? You got
>> Eventually. Why not? You got to
>> Of me. Of course.
>> Eventually. Why not? You got to start
practicing,
practicing, right?
>> He's
>> He's cute.
>> The
>> The process
>> The process of
>> The process of ascension.
>> You're
>> You're talking
>> The process of ascension.
>> You're talking about
>> You're talking about the
>> The process of ascension.
>> You're talking about the spirit
>> You're talking about the spirit leaving
the
the body.
the body. Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Transcending.
>> Uh,
>> Uh, the
>> Uh, the spirit
>> Uh, the spirit leaves
>> Uh, the spirit leaves the
>> Uh, the spirit leaves the body.
Hopefully,
Hopefully, it
>> Uh, the spirit leaves the body.
Hopefully, it transcends.
Let's
Let's hopefully
Let's hopefully it
Let's hopefully it goes
Let's hopefully it goes in
Let's hopefully it goes in the
Let's hopefully it goes in the other
direction.
direction. Yeah.
What
What you're
What you're talking
What you're talking about
What you're talking about is
transcending
transcending the
What you're talking about is
transcending the physicality,
transcending the physicality, leaving
the
the body.
the body. Yeah.
the body. Yeah. The
the body. Yeah. The spirit
the body. Yeah. The spirit leaves
the body. Yeah. The spirit leaves the
body
body and
the body. Yeah. The spirit leaves the
body and gravitates
body and gravitates to
the body. Yeah. The spirit leaves the
body and gravitates to that
body and gravitates to that which
the body. Yeah. The spirit leaves the
body and gravitates to that which it
body and gravitates to that which it is.
It
It gravitates
It gravitates to
It gravitates to the
It gravitates to the celestial
It gravitates to the celestial realm
It gravitates to the celestial realm or
to
to the
It gravitates to the celestial realm or
to the other
to the other realms
based
based on
based on what
based on what it
based on what it is
that
that because
based on what it is
that because when
that because when like
based on what it is
that because when like goes
that because when like goes to
based on what it is
that because when like goes to like.
that because when like goes to like. So
one
one is
one is attracted
one is attracted to
one is attracted to this
one is attracted to this because
one is attracted to this because that's
what
what you
one is attracted to this because that's
what you are
and
and one
and one is
and one is attracted
and one is attracted to
and one is attracted to this
and one is attracted to this because
that
that is
and one is attracted to this because
that is what
that is what you
and one is attracted to this because
that is what you have
that is what you have become.
and one is attracted to this because
that is what you have become. So
that is what you have become. So you
only
only go
only go to
only go to that
only go to that which
only go to that which you
only go to that which you are.
only go to that which you are. Therefore
there's
there's nothing
only go to that which you are. Therefore
there's nothing to
there's nothing to fear
only go to that which you are. Therefore
there's nothing to fear because
there's nothing to fear because all
you're
you're going
you're going to
you're going to encounter
you're going to encounter is
you're going to encounter is a
reflection
reflection of
you're going to encounter is a
reflection of yourself
reflection of yourself back
you're going to encounter is a
reflection of yourself back again.
person
person down
person down here
person down here is
person down here is not
person down here is not going
person down here is not going to
person down here is not going to be
attracted
attracted by
person down here is not going to be
attracted by a
attracted by a celestial
person down here is not going to be
attracted by a celestial realm
and
and a
and a person
and a person from
and a person from you
and a person from you know
and a person from you know a
and a person from you know a celestial
level
level of
and a person from you know a celestial
level of consciousness
level of consciousness is
and a person from you know a celestial
level of consciousness is going
level of consciousness is going to
and a person from you know a celestial
level of consciousness is going to be
repulsed
repulsed by
repulsed by anything
repulsed by anything lower.
repulsed by anything lower. So
repulsed by anything lower. So each
repulsed by anything lower. So each one
goes
goes to
repulsed by anything lower. So each one
goes to that
goes to that which
repulsed by anything lower. So each one
goes to that which he's
goes to that which he's attuned
repulsed by anything lower. So each one
goes to that which he's attuned to
attracted
attracted to.
You
You go
attracted to.
You go to
You go to that
attracted to.
You go to that which
You go to that which you
attracted to.
You go to that which you already
You go to that which you already are.
So
So there's
So there's no
So there's no sense
So there's no sense in
So there's no sense in in
So there's no sense in in in
attempting
attempting it
So there's no sense in in in
attempting it per
attempting it per se
So there's no sense in in in
attempting it per se or
attempting it per se or there's
So there's no sense in in in
attempting it per se or there's no
process
process to
process to you
process to you you
process to you you are
process to you you are where
process to you you are where you're
supposed
supposed to
process to you you are where you're
supposed to be
supposed to be and
process to you you are where you're
supposed to be and that's
supposed to be and that's it.
>> No
>> No process
>> No process though
>> No process though what
>> no
>> no process
>> No process though what
>> no process in
>> no process in what
>> No process though what
>> no process in what now?
>> The
>> The the
>> The the process
>> The the process of
>> The the process of of
>> The the process of of ascension
>> The the process of of ascension itself
does
does it
>> The the process of of ascension itself
does it does
does it does it
>> The the process of of ascension itself
does it does it make
does it does it make any
>> The the process of of ascension itself
does it does it make any sense
does it does it make any sense or
>> The the process of of ascension itself
does it does it make any sense or or
does it does it make any sense or or is
that
that something
that something more
that something more theoretical?
>> Don't
>> Don't worry
that something more theoretical?
>> Don't worry about
>> Don't worry about the
that something more theoretical?
>> Don't worry about the process
>> Don't worry about the process of
ascension.
>> Okay.
>> The
>> The spirit
>> The spirit leaves
>> The spirit leaves the
>> The spirit leaves the body.
the
the energy
>> The spirit leaves the body.
the energy field,
the energy field, the
>> The spirit leaves the body.
the energy field, the atheric
the energy field, the atheric field.
>> The spirit leaves the body.
the energy field, the atheric field. If
you're
you're over
you're over 200,
you're over 200, you
you're over 200, you have
you're over 200, you have an
you're over 200, you have an individual
karmaic
field
field and
field and you
field and you automatically
field and you automatically gravitate
field and you automatically gravitate to
the
the realm
field and you automatically gravitate to
the realm that
the realm that is
field and you automatically gravitate to
the realm that is what
the realm that is what you
field and you automatically gravitate to
the realm that is what you are.
So
So the
So the answer
So the answer to
So the answer to which
So the answer to which one
So the answer to which one has
the
the answer
So the answer to which one has
the answer we
the answer we got
So the answer to which one has
the answer we got is
the answer we got is that
So the answer to which one has
the answer we got is that there's
multiple
multiple regions
multiple regions to
multiple regions to heaven.
multiple regions to heaven. There
multiple regions to heaven. There isn't
just
just one
multiple regions to heaven. There isn't
just one heaven
just one heaven and
multiple regions to heaven. There isn't
just one heaven and this
just one heaven and this group's
multiple regions to heaven. There isn't
just one heaven and this group's got
control
control of
control of heaven.
There
There are
control of heaven.
There are whole
There are whole regions.
control of heaven.
There are whole regions. Don't
There are whole regions. Don't forget
the
the possibility
the possibility is
the possibility is infinite
the possibility is infinite within
the possibility is infinite within the
possibility
possibility of
the possibility is infinite within the
possibility of infinity.
There
There are
There are numerous
There are numerous what
There are numerous what I
There are numerous what I would
There are numerous what I would call
like
like neighborhoods.
And
And the
And the group
And the group on
And the group on on
And the group on on this
And the group on on this planet
And the group on on this planet is
And the group on on this planet is the
is
is the
And the group on on this planet is the
is the way
is the way to
And the group on on this planet is the
is the way to that
is the way to that particular
And the group on on this planet is the
is the way to that particular part
is the way to that particular part of
heaven.
heaven. So
heaven. So if
heaven. So if you
heaven. So if you got
heaven. So if you got to
heaven. So if you got to have
heaven. So if you got to have 13
heaven. So if you got to have 13 wives
to
to get
heaven. So if you got to have 13 wives
to get to
to get to this
heaven. So if you got to have 13 wives
to get to this heaven,
to get to this heaven, then
heaven. So if you got to have 13 wives
to get to this heaven, then they
to get to this heaven, then they control
that.
that. You
that. You prove
that. You prove this
that. You prove this group,
that. You prove this group, you
that. You prove this group, you get
that. You prove this group, you get to
that
that group
that. You prove this group, you get to
that group there.
that group there. If
that. You prove this group, you get to
that group there. If you
that group there. If you think
that. You prove this group, you get to
that group there. If you think celibacy
is
is the
is the only
is the only way
is the only way to
is the only way to heaven,
is the only way to heaven, then
is the only way to heaven, then you
is the only way to heaven, then you you
get
get to
is the only way to heaven, then you you
get to the
get to the celibate
is the only way to heaven, then you you
get to the celibate levels
get to the celibate levels of
is the only way to heaven, then you you
get to the celibate levels of you
get to the celibate levels of you know
what
what I'm
what I'm saying?
So
So each
what I'm saying?
So each one
So each one they
what I'm saying?
So each one they claim
So each one they claim to
what I'm saying?
So each one they claim to have
So each one they claim to have the
what I'm saying?
So each one they claim to have the only
truth
truth and
truth and you
truth and you know
truth and you know the
truth and you know the the
truth and you know the the they're
truth and you know the the they're the
gatekeepers
gatekeepers to
truth and you know the the they're the
gatekeepers to heaven.
gatekeepers to heaven. They're
truth and you know the the they're the
gatekeepers to heaven. They're partially
true.
true. They're
true. They're gatekeepers
true. They're gatekeepers to
true. They're gatekeepers to their
portion
portion of
true. They're gatekeepers to their
portion of heaven,
but
but not
but not to
but not to heaven
but not to heaven itself.
Many
my
my father's
my father's house
my father's house has
my father's house has many
my father's house has many mansions
my father's house has many mansions and
the
the mansions
my father's house has many mansions and
the mansions had
the mansions had many
my father's house has many mansions and
the mansions had many rooms.
Yeah.
Somebody
Somebody I
Yeah.
Somebody I knew
Somebody I knew who
Yeah.
Somebody I knew who was
Somebody I knew who was world
Yeah.
Somebody I knew who was world famous
Somebody I knew who was world famous was
close
close to
close to death
close to death and
close to death and that's
close to death and that's why
close to death and that's why I
close to death and that's why I was
around
around him
close to death and that's why I was
around him a
around him a lot.
close to death and that's why I was
around him a lot. And
around him a lot. And he
close to death and that's why I was
around him a lot. And he would
around him a lot. And he would drift
close to death and that's why I was
around him a lot. And he would drift in
and
and out
and out and
and out and when
and out and when he
and out and when he would
and out and when he would drift
and out and when he would drift out
and out and when he would drift out he
would
would visit
and out and when he would drift out he
would visit these
would visit these celestial
and out and when he would drift out he
would visit these celestial realms
would visit these celestial realms and
he
he would
he would come
he would come back
he would come back and
he would come back and he'd
he would come back and he'd say
he would come back and he'd say there
are
are many
he would come back and he'd say there
are many many
are many many places
he would come back and he'd say there
are many many places and
are many many places and he
he would come back and he'd say there
are many many places and he would
are many many places and he would visit
he'd
he'd sort
he'd sort of
he'd sort of go
he'd sort of go out
he'd sort of go out and
he'd sort of go out and You
he'd sort of go out and You know,
he'd sort of go out and You know, he
would
would visit
he'd sort of go out and You know, he
would visit various
would visit various realms.
he'd sort of go out and You know, he
would visit various realms. He
would visit various realms. He got
he'd sort of go out and You know, he
would visit various realms. He got to
visit
visit the
visit the various
visit the various mansions.
visit the various mansions. You
visit the various mansions. You see,
a
a man
visit the various mansions. You see,
a man of
a man of great
visit the various mansions. You see,
a man of great integrity
a man of great integrity who
visit the various mansions. You see,
a man of great integrity who profoundly
affected
affected the
affected the entire
affected the entire world.
He
He affected
the
the entire
the entire world.
the entire world. Man
the entire world. Man of
the entire world. Man of great
integrity.
integrity. You
the entire world. Man of great
integrity. You he
integrity. You he said
the entire world. Man of great
integrity. You he said he
integrity. You he said he visited
the entire world. Man of great
integrity. You he said he visited the
various
various mansions,
various mansions, various
various mansions, various realms.
>> I'd
>> I'd like
various mansions, various realms.
>> I'd like to
>> I'd like to see
various mansions, various realms.
>> I'd like to see some
>> I'd like to see some other
various mansions, various realms.
>> I'd like to see some other mansions.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you. you.
>> We
>> We have
>> Thank you. Thank you. you.
>> We have to
>> We have to move
>> Thank you. Thank you. you.
>> We have to move along
>> We have to move along now
>> Thank you. Thank you. you.
>> We have to move along now quicker.
>> Well,
>> Well, it's
>> Well, it's it's
>> Well, it's it's only
>> we're
>> we're getting
>> Well, it's it's only
>> we're getting long
>> we're getting long questions.
>> We're
>> We're okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you so
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much. So
>> Thank you so much. So beautiful.
>> Thank you so much. So beautiful. Hello,
Dr.
>> Yes.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. My
>> Yes.
>> Hello. My question
>> Hello. My question is
>> Yes.
>> Hello. My question is regarding
>> Hello. My question is regarding the
void.
void. You
void. You have
void. You have mentioned
void. You have mentioned in
void. You have mentioned in the
void. You have mentioned in the past
that
that sometimes
void. You have mentioned in the past
that sometimes people
that sometimes people get
void. You have mentioned in the past
that sometimes people get or
that sometimes people get or we
void. You have mentioned in the past
that sometimes people get or we get
stuck
stuck in
stuck in the
stuck in the void
stuck in the void in
stuck in the void in the
stuck in the void in the abyss
stuck in the void in the abyss of
stuck in the void in the abyss of the
stuck in the void in the abyss of the of
the
the void.
stuck in the void in the abyss of the of
the void. My
the void. My question
stuck in the void in the abyss of the of
the void. My question to
the void. My question to you
stuck in the void in the abyss of the of
the void. My question to you is,
the void. My question to you is, is
stuck in the void in the abyss of the of
the void. My question to you is, is it
one's
one's character
one's character slashintention
that
that saves
one's character slashintention
that saves them
that saves them from
one's character slashintention
that saves them from that
that saves them from that positionality
once
once the
once the void
once the void is
around
that
that soul?
>> I'll
>> I'll make
that soul?
>> I'll make clear
the
the experience
the experience of
the experience of the
the experience of the void
the experience of the void is
the experience of the void is the
consequence
consequence of
the experience of the void is the
consequence of the
consequence of the pathway
the experience of the void is the
consequence of the pathway of
consequence of the pathway of negation.
Not
Not this,
Not this, not
Not this, not that,
Not this, not that, not
Not this, not that, not this,
Not this, not that, not this, not
Not this, not that, not this, not that.
Um
Um instead
Not this, not that, not this, not that.
Um instead of
Um instead of saying
Not this, not that, not this, not that.
Um instead of saying yes
Um instead of saying yes this
Not this, not that, not this, not that.
Um instead of saying yes this it
Um instead of saying yes this it says
Not this, not that, not this, not that.
Um instead of saying yes this it says no
not
not that.
The
The purpose
not that.
The purpose of
The purpose of negation
not that.
The purpose of negation is
The purpose of negation is to
not that.
The purpose of negation is to let
The purpose of negation is to let go
attachment
attachment to
attachment to the
attachment to the linear
attachment to the linear that
attachment to the linear that which
attachment to the linear that which is
temporary
temporary and
attachment to the linear that which is
temporary and temporal.
temporary and temporal. So
attachment to the linear that which is
temporary and temporal. So the
temporary and temporal. So the intention
is
is is
is is great
is is great but
is is great but what
is is great but what it
is is great but what it forgets
is is great but what it forgets is
underneath
underneath the
is is great but what it forgets is
underneath the linear.
underneath the linear. Underneath
is is great but what it forgets is
underneath the linear. Underneath the
circumscribed
circumscribed is
circumscribed is the
circumscribed is the nonlinear.
The
The source
circumscribed is the nonlinear.
The source of
The source of existence
circumscribed is the nonlinear.
The source of existence of
The source of existence of the
circumscribed is the nonlinear.
The source of existence of the linear
The source of existence of the linear is
the
the nonlinear.
the nonlinear. So
the nonlinear. So within
the nonlinear. So within the
the nonlinear. So within the non
the nonlinear. So within the non within
the
the linear
the nonlinear. So within the non within
the linear is
the linear is the
the nonlinear. So within the non within
the linear is the nonlinear.
So
So you
So you can
So you can negate
So you can negate attachment
So you can negate attachment to
So you can negate attachment to the
linear.
linear. Um
but
but that's
but that's not
but that's not the
but that's not the entire
but that's not the entire game
but that's not the entire game because
it
it all
but that's not the entire game because
it all comes
it all comes out
but that's not the entire game because
it all comes out of
it all comes out of the
but that's not the entire game because
it all comes out of the nonlinear.
Um
Um how
Um how to
Um how to express
Um how to express it
Um how to express it better?
Uh
uh
uh using
uh using devotion
uh using devotion will
uh using devotion will bypass
uh using devotion will bypass the
uh using devotion will bypass the the
void
void because
uh using devotion will bypass the the
void because the
void because the void
uh using devotion will bypass the the
void because the void is
void because the void is absent
uh using devotion will bypass the the
void because the void is absent of
void because the void is absent of love.
It's
It's stunning.
It's stunning. it.
It's stunning. it. I
It's stunning. it. I don't
It's stunning. it. I don't want
It's stunning. it. I don't want to
It's stunning. it. I don't want to put
it
it down.
It's stunning. it. I don't want to put
it down. It's
it down. It's very
It's stunning. it. I don't want to put
it down. It's very very
it down. It's very very profound.
It's stunning. it. I don't want to put
it down. It's very very profound. I
mean,
mean, it
mean, it is
mean, it is staggering.
mean, it is staggering. It
mean, it is staggering. It is
transformative.
Everything
Everything is
Everything is happening
Everything is happening spontaneously.
Everything
Everything everything
Everything is happening spontaneously.
Everything everything is
Everything everything is one.
Everything is happening spontaneously.
Everything everything is one. Uh
Everything everything is one. Uh you're
outside
outside of
outside of time,
outside of time, dimension,
outside of time, dimension, etc.
But
But it's
outside of time, dimension, etc.
But it's devoid
But it's devoid of
outside of time, dimension, etc.
But it's devoid of that
But it's devoid of that certain
outside of time, dimension, etc.
But it's devoid of that certain energy.
It
It would
It would be
It would be like
It would be like a
It would be like a room
It would be like a room that's
It would be like a room that's chilly
and
and cold
It would be like a room that's chilly
and cold and
and cold and vacant
It would be like a room that's chilly
and cold and vacant rather
and cold and vacant rather than
It would be like a room that's chilly
and cold and vacant rather than one
that's
that's full
that's full of
that's full of warmth.
that's full of warmth. Huh?
So,
So, so
that's full of warmth. Huh?
So, so if
So, so if you
that's full of warmth. Huh?
So, so if you get
So, so if you get to
that's full of warmth. Huh?
So, so if you get to a
So, so if you get to a state
that's full of warmth. Huh?
So, so if you get to a state of
So, so if you get to a state of uh
nothingness
nothingness and
there's
there's warmth
nothingness and
there's warmth that
there's warmth that is
nothingness and
there's warmth that is absent,
there's warmth that is absent, then
nothingness and
there's warmth that is absent, then you
can
can refuse
can refuse it
can refuse it and
can refuse it and ask
can refuse it and ask almighty
can refuse it and ask almighty God
can refuse it and ask almighty God to
help
help you
can refuse it and ask almighty God to
help you back
help you back out
can refuse it and ask almighty God to
help you back out because
help you back out because it
can refuse it and ask almighty God to
help you back out because it is
help you back out because it is your
love
love that
love that I
love that I seek,
love that I seek, oh
love that I seek, oh Lord.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you,
>> Thank you. Thank you, sir.
>> The
>> The love
>> Thank you. Thank you, sir.
>> The love of
>> The love of God
>> Thank you. Thank you, sir.
>> The love of God dissolves
>> The love of God dissolves the
>> Thank you. Thank you, sir.
>> The love of God dissolves the attachment
to
to the
to the linear.
to the linear. You
to the linear. You see
to the linear. You see that's
to the linear. You see that's the
to the linear. You see that's the divine
pathway
pathway through
to the linear. You see that's the divine
pathway through devotion.
pathway through devotion. Then
>> you
>> you mentioned
>> you mentioned today
>> you mentioned today um
>> you mentioned today um that
>> you mentioned today um that you
>> you mentioned today um that you had
>> you mentioned today um that you had one
thought
thought that
>> you mentioned today um that you had one
thought that you
thought that you hung
>> you mentioned today um that you had one
thought that you hung on
thought that you hung on to.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And was
>> Yes.
>> And was that
>> And was that thought
>> Yes.
>> And was that thought backed
>> And was that thought backed up
>> Yes.
>> And was that thought backed up by
>> And was that thought backed up by the
>> Yes.
>> And was that thought backed up by the by
your
your personal
your personal intention?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, there
your personal intention?
>> Oh, there was
>> Oh, there was nothing
your personal intention?
>> Oh, there was nothing left
>> Oh, there was nothing left in
your personal intention?
>> Oh, there was nothing left in the
>> Oh, there was nothing left in the in
your personal intention?
>> Oh, there was nothing left in the in the
nothingness.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So
>> if
>> if you
>> if you were
>> if you were in
>> if you were in an
>> if you were in an infinite
>> if you were in an infinite space
>> if you were in an infinite space of
infinite
infinite nothingness
>> if you were in an infinite space of
infinite nothingness and
infinite nothingness and you
>> if you were in an infinite space of
infinite nothingness and you saw
infinite nothingness and you saw one
sparrow,
sparrow, wow,
sparrow, wow, you'd
sparrow, wow, you'd head
sparrow, wow, you'd head for
sparrow, wow, you'd head for that
sparrow.
>> Come
>> Come here,
>> Come here, pal.
I
I get
>> Come here, pal.
I get out
I get out of
>> Come here, pal.
I get out of here.
>> And
>> And may
>> And may I
>> And may I also
>> And may I also have
>> And may I also have my
>> And may I also have my photo
>> And may I also have my photo taken?
>> And may I also have my photo taken? And
I
I have
>> And may I also have my photo taken? And
I have a
I have a real
>> And may I also have my photo taken? And
I have a real quick
I have a real quick one.
>> And may I also have my photo taken? And
I have a real quick one. It's
I have a real quick one. It's an
>> And may I also have my photo taken? And
I have a real quick one. It's an inatic.
>> What
>> What is
>> What is it?
>> Quick
>> Quick one.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, one
>> Oh, one of
>> Oh, one of these
>> Oh, one of these machines.
>> These
>> These are
>> Oh, one of these machines.
>> These are magical
>> These are magical picture
>> Oh, one of these machines.
>> These are magical picture machines.
It's
It's a
It's a magical
It's a magical picture
It's a magical picture machine.
It's a magical picture machine. You
It's a magical picture machine. You push
the
the button
It's a magical picture machine. You push
the button and
the button and it
It's a magical picture machine. You push
the button and it takes
the button and it takes your
It's a magical picture machine. You push
the button and it takes your picture.
It's
It's incredible.
I
I don't
It's incredible.
I don't think
I don't think they
It's incredible.
I don't think they sell,
I don't think they sell, but
it's
it's a
it's a toy.
Yeah.
>> A
>> A gentleman,
>> A gentleman, I
>> A gentleman, I was
>> A gentleman, I was asking
>> A gentleman, I was asking earlier
>> A gentleman, I was asking earlier about
contemplation.
I
I just
I just want
I just want to
I just want to hear
I just want to hear more
I just want to hear more about
I just want to hear more about that.
I just want to hear more about that. I
loved
loved your
I just want to hear more about that. I
loved your story
loved your story about
I just want to hear more about that. I
loved your story about catching
loved your story about catching the
alien
alien chicken
alien chicken and
alien chicken and the
alien chicken and the central
alien chicken and the central focus
alien chicken and the central focus and
the
the idea
alien chicken and the central focus and
the idea of
the idea of being
alien chicken and the central focus and
the idea of being connected
the idea of being connected with
alien chicken and the central focus and
the idea of being connected with the
self
self and
self and the
self and the peripheral
self and the peripheral focus.
self and the peripheral focus. But
self and the peripheral focus. But I
lead
lead a
self and the peripheral focus. But I
lead a active
lead a active business
self and the peripheral focus. But I
lead a active business life.
lead a active business life. It
self and the peripheral focus. But I
lead a active business life. It seems
virtually
virtually impossible
virtually impossible to
virtually impossible to do.
virtually impossible to do. I
virtually impossible to do. I mean,
virtually impossible to do. I mean, I
could
could see
virtually impossible to do. I mean, I
could see myself
could see myself maybe
virtually impossible to do. I mean, I
could see myself maybe central
could see myself maybe central focus
when
when I'm
when I'm working
when I'm working on
when I'm working on a,
when I'm working on a, you
when I'm working on a, you know,
paperwork
paperwork and
when I'm working on a, you know,
paperwork and maybe
paperwork and maybe peripheral
when I'm working on a, you know,
paperwork and maybe peripheral focus,
but
but I'm
but I'm afraid
but I'm afraid I'll
but I'm afraid I'll trip
but I'm afraid I'll trip over
but I'm afraid I'll trip over something
and
and kill
but I'm afraid I'll trip over something
and kill myself.
and kill myself. So
but I'm afraid I'll trip over something
and kill myself. So I
and kill myself. So I just
but I'm afraid I'll trip over something
and kill myself. So I just wanted
and kill myself. So I just wanted a
little
little more
little more encouragement
little more encouragement or
little more encouragement or practical
advice
advice about
little more encouragement or practical
advice about how
advice about how to
little more encouragement or practical
advice about how to do
advice about how to do that
>> to
>> to be
>> to be constantly
>> to be constantly aware
>> to be constantly aware of
>> to be constantly aware of the
>> to be constantly aware of the field.
Constantly
Constantly aware
>> to be constantly aware of the field.
Constantly aware of
Constantly aware of the
>> to be constantly aware of the field.
Constantly aware of the field.
Constantly
Constantly aware
Constantly aware of
Constantly aware of the
Constantly aware of the field
Constantly aware of the field and
Constantly aware of the field and not
just
just the
Constantly aware of the field and not
just the content
just the content of
Constantly aware of the field and not
just the content of the
just the content of the field.
Um
Um to
Um to really
Um to really and
Um to really and to
Um to really and to be
Um to really and to be aware
Um to really and to be aware of
Um to really and to be aware of your
Um to really and to be aware of your own
existence.
Be
Be aware
Be aware of
Be aware of existence
Be aware of existence as
Be aware of existence as such
because
because that
Be aware of existence as such
because that will
because that will lead
Be aware of existence as such
because that will lead you
because that will lead you to
Be aware of existence as such
because that will lead you to the
because that will lead you to the source
of
of your
of your existence
to
to the
of your existence
to the self
to the self with
of your existence
to the self with the
to the self with the capital
of your existence
to the self with the capital S
to the self with the capital S which
of your existence
to the self with the capital S which is
the
the source
the source of
the source of your
the source of your existence
the source of your existence which
the source of your existence which the
ego
ego takes
the source of your existence which the
ego takes credit
ego takes credit for
the source of your existence which the
ego takes credit for and
ego takes credit for and claims
the source of your existence which the
ego takes credit for and claims for
itself.
So
So by
itself.
So by holding
So by holding on
itself.
So by holding on to
So by holding on to the
itself.
So by holding on to the field
So by holding on to the field eagle's
ego
ego specialty
ego specialty is
ego specialty is the
ego specialty is the content
ego specialty is the content of
ego specialty is the content of the
field.
field. By
ego specialty is the content of the
field. By holding
field. By holding on
ego specialty is the content of the
field. By holding on to
field. By holding on to the
ego specialty is the content of the
field. By holding on to the field,
field. By holding on to the field, you
deenergize
uh
uh the
deenergize
uh the linear
fixations
fixations of
fixations of the
fixations of the ego.
Let's
Let's say
fixations of the ego.
Let's say you're
Let's say you're driving
fixations of the ego.
Let's say you're driving for
Let's say you're driving for money.
fixations of the ego.
Let's say you're driving for money. You
see
a
a contemplative
see
a contemplative lifestyle.
a contemplative lifestyle. You're
see
a contemplative lifestyle. You're saying
the
the money
the money for
the money for what?
I'm
I'm wanting
the money for what?
I'm wanting money.
I'm wanting money. What
the money for what?
I'm wanting money. What am
I'm wanting money. What am I
the money for what?
I'm wanting money. What am I wanting
money
money for?
money for? And
money for? And then
money for? And then it
money for? And then it comes
money for? And then it comes to
money for? And then it comes to you.
money for? And then it comes to you. All
the
the things
money for? And then it comes to you. All
the things you're
the things you're wanting
money for? And then it comes to you. All
the things you're wanting money
the things you're wanting money for.
money for? And then it comes to you. All
the things you're wanting money for. and
grants
grants you
grants you the
grants you the illusions
grants you the illusions of
grants you the illusions of all
grants you the illusions of all those
things
things pass
grants you the illusions of all those
things pass away
things pass away the
grants you the illusions of all those
things pass away the because
things pass away the because people
grants you the illusions of all those
things pass away the because people look
at
at the
at the things
at the things they
at the things they desire
at the things they desire as
at the things they desire as magic.
at the things they desire as magic. If
at the things they desire as magic. If I
was
was only
at the things they desire as magic. If I
was only better
was only better looking,
at the things they desire as magic. If I
was only better looking, if
was only better looking, if I
at the things they desire as magic. If I
was only better looking, if I was
famous,
famous, if
famous, if I
famous, if I had
famous, if I had all
famous, if I had all kinds
famous, if I had all kinds of
famous, if I had all kinds of money
famous, if I had all kinds of money and
how
how wondrous
famous, if I had all kinds of money and
how wondrous that's
how wondrous that's going
famous, if I had all kinds of money and
how wondrous that's going to
how wondrous that's going to make
famous, if I had all kinds of money and
how wondrous that's going to make your
life
life except
life except millionaires
life except millionaires commit
life except millionaires commit suicide
all
all the
life except millionaires commit suicide
all the time.
all the time. I
life except millionaires commit suicide
all the time. I used
all the time. I used to
life except millionaires commit suicide
all the time. I used to live
all the time. I used to live on
millionaire
millionaire zero
millionaire zero back
millionaire zero back east.
Suicide,
Suicide, alcohol,
millionaire zero back east.
Suicide, alcohol, same
Suicide, alcohol, same as
millionaire zero back east.
Suicide, alcohol, same as anybody
Suicide, alcohol, same as anybody else.
Okay.
Okay. Can
Okay. Can I
Okay. Can I ask
Okay. Can I ask one
Okay. Can I ask one other
Okay. Can I ask one other question?
Okay. Can I ask one other question? Um,
you
you talk
Okay. Can I ask one other question? Um,
you talk about
you talk about in
Okay. Can I ask one other question? Um,
you talk about in your
you talk about in your books
Okay. Can I ask one other question? Um,
you talk about in your books about
you talk about in your books about the
importance
importance of
importance of the
importance of the teacher.
importance of the teacher. I
importance of the teacher. I read
importance of the teacher. I read your
books
books avidly
importance of the teacher. I read your
books avidly and
books avidly and I
importance of the teacher. I read your
books avidly and I consider
books avidly and I consider you
importance of the teacher. I read your
books avidly and I consider you my
teacher.
teacher. Is
teacher. Is that
teacher. Is that appropriate?
teacher. Is that appropriate? And
teacher. Is that appropriate? And is
your
your field
teacher. Is that appropriate? And is
your field am
your field am I
teacher. Is that appropriate? And is
your field am I getting
your field am I getting the
teacher. Is that appropriate? And is
your field am I getting the feel
your field am I getting the feel that
teacher. Is that appropriate? And is
your field am I getting the feel that I
need
need or
need or the
>> If
>> If you're
need or the
>> If you're saying
>> If you're saying that
need or the
>> If you're saying that I'm
>> If you're saying that I'm the
need or the
>> If you're saying that I'm the I'm
>> If you're saying that I'm the I'm your
teacher,
teacher, then
teacher, then I'm
teacher, then I'm your
teacher, then I'm your teacher
teacher, then I'm your teacher now.
teacher, then I'm your teacher now. I
have
have a
teacher, then I'm your teacher now. I
have a responsibility
have a responsibility to
teacher, then I'm your teacher now. I
have a responsibility to you
have a responsibility to you to
teacher, then I'm your teacher now. I
have a responsibility to you to be
have a responsibility to you to be the
best
best teacher
best teacher I
best teacher I can.
>> Well,
>> Well, you're
best teacher I can.
>> Well, you're pretty
>> Well, you're pretty terrific
best teacher I can.
>> Well, you're pretty terrific in
>> Well, you're pretty terrific in my
obligation.
I
I am
obligation.
I am I
I am I feel
obligation.
I am I feel obliged
I am I feel obliged to
obligation.
I am I feel obliged to you,
I am I feel obliged to you, you
obligation.
I am I feel obliged to you, you see,
>> but
>> but I
>> but I I
>> but I I do
>> but I I do that
>> but I I do that because
>> but I I do that because I
>> but I I do that because I acknowledge
>> but I I do that because I acknowledge my
responsibility,
responsibility, the
>> but I I do that because I acknowledge my
responsibility, the stewardship
responsibility, the stewardship of
>> but I I do that because I acknowledge my
responsibility, the stewardship of my
gifts
gifts for
gifts for the
gifts for the good
gifts for the good of
gifts for the good of my
gifts for the good of my students
gifts for the good of my students and
and
and those
gifts for the good of my students and
and those that
and those that that
gifts for the good of my students and
and those that that touch
and those that that touch their
gifts for the good of my students and
and those that that touch their lives,
you
you know,
you know, in
you know, in return
you know, in return for
you know, in return for the
you know, in return for the gift
you know, in return for the gift from
God.
God. See,
because
because the
because the the
because the the realization
because the the realization was
because the the realization was a
because the the realization was a gift.
But
But am
because the the realization was a gift.
But am I
But am I getting
because the the realization was a gift.
But am I getting you
But am I getting you talk
because the the realization was a gift.
But am I getting you talk a
But am I getting you talk a lot
because the the realization was a gift.
But am I getting you talk a lot about
the
the field
the field and
the field and the
the field and the aura
the field and the aura and
the field and the aura and I'm
the field and the aura and I'm getting
that
that through
the field and the aura and I'm getting
that through your
that through your books
the field and the aura and I'm getting
that through your books or
that through your books or do
the field and the aura and I'm getting
that through your books or do I
that through your books or do I need
the field and the aura and I'm getting
that through your books or do I need to
>> You
>> You just
>> You just got
>> You just got it
>> You just got it from
>> You just got it from sitting
>> You just got it from sitting here.
>> You just got it from sitting here. The
aura
aura energy
>> You just got it from sitting here. The
aura energy of
aura energy of the
>> You just got it from sitting here. The
aura energy of the aura.
aura energy of the aura. If
>> You just got it from sitting here. The
aura energy of the aura. If you
aura energy of the aura. If you say
>> You just got it from sitting here. The
aura energy of the aura. If you say I'm
your
your teacher
your teacher and
your teacher and then
your teacher and then you
your teacher and then you meet
your teacher and then you meet the
your teacher and then you meet the guy,
you
you got
your teacher and then you meet the guy,
you got it.
>> That's
>> That's probably
>> That's probably why
>> That's probably why I'm
>> That's probably why I'm here.
>> That's probably why I'm here. I
>> I
>> I think
>> That's probably why I'm here. I
>> I think I
>> I think I got
>> That's probably why I'm here. I
>> I think I got it
>> I think I got it thousands
>> That's probably why I'm here. I
>> I think I got it thousands of
>> I think I got it thousands of years
>> That's probably why I'm here. I
>> I think I got it thousands of years ago.
Many
Many years
Many years ago.
Many years ago. Yeah.
Many years ago. Yeah. Long
Many years ago. Yeah. Long time.
Many years ago. Yeah. Long time. Many
lifetimes
lifetimes ago.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> The
>> The teacher
>> Thank you.
>> The teacher I
>> The teacher I picked
>> Thank you.
>> The teacher I picked up
>> The teacher I picked up his
>> Thank you.
>> The teacher I picked up his door
>> The teacher I picked up his door at
>> Thank you.
>> The teacher I picked up his door at that
time.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. It's
>> Thank you. It's been
>> Thank you. It's been available
>> Thank you. It's been available to
mankind
mankind since,
>> Thank you. It's been available to
mankind since, you
mankind since, you know,
>> Thank you. It's been available to
mankind since, you know, 5,000
mankind since, you know, 5,000 BC,
>> Thank you. It's been available to
mankind since, you know, 5,000 BC, 7,000
BC.
That
That energy.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> What?
>> What? I
>> What? I I
>> What? I I was
>> What? I I was looking
>> What? I I was looking for
>> What? I I was looking for the
>> What? I I was looking for the word
>> What? I I was looking for the word the
rig
rig vita
>> What? I I was looking for the word the
rig vita today
rig vita today and
>> What? I I was looking for the word the
rig vita today and I
rig vita today and I couldn't
>> What? I I was looking for the word the
rig vita today and I couldn't get
rig vita today and I couldn't get the
word
word rig.
>> Hello.
>> It's
>> It's 900
>> It's 900 rig.
>> Nice
>> Nice to
>> It's 900 rig.
>> Nice to see
>> Nice to see you
>> It's 900 rig.
>> Nice to see you both.
>> Yes.
>> Um
>> Um I
>> Yes.
>> Um I wanted
>> Um I wanted to
>> Yes.
>> Um I wanted to clarify
>> Um I wanted to clarify something
>> Yes.
>> Um I wanted to clarify something that
>> Um I wanted to clarify something that I
heard
heard on
heard on one
heard on one of
heard on one of your
heard on one of your tapes.
heard on one of your tapes. Um
heard on one of your tapes. Um I
heard on one of your tapes. Um I think
you
you said
heard on one of your tapes. Um I think
you said when
you said when um
heard on one of your tapes. Um I think
you said when um people
you said when um people overcome
alcoholism
they
they automatically
alcoholism
they automatically go
they automatically go to
alcoholism
they automatically go to 540.
they automatically go to 540. Is
alcoholism
they automatically go to 540. Is that
correct
correct or
correct or did
correct or did I
correct or did I misunderstand?
>> You
>> You didn't
correct or did I misunderstand?
>> You didn't say
>> You didn't say automatically.
correct or did I misunderstand?
>> You didn't say automatically. No.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I
>> Okay. I mean
>> Okay. I mean I
>> Okay. I mean I did.
>> Okay. I mean I did. Everyone
>> Okay. I mean I did. Everyone laughed
>> Okay. I mean I did. Everyone laughed and
then
then there
>> Okay. I mean I did. Everyone laughed and
then there was
then there was other
>> Okay. I mean I did. Everyone laughed and
then there was other comments
then there was other comments and
>> Okay. I mean I did. Everyone laughed and
then there was other comments and I
never
never could.
>> The
>> The energy
never could.
>> The energy field
>> The energy field of
never could.
>> The energy field of Alcoholics
>> The energy field of Alcoholics Anonymous
>> the
>> the field
>> the field of
>> the field of AA
>> the field of AA is
>> the field of AA is 540.
>> the field of AA is 540. That's
>> the field of AA is 540. That's the
>> the field of AA is 540. That's the level
of
of unconditional
>> the field of AA is 540. That's the level
of unconditional love,
>> right?
>> Guy
>> Guy has
>> right?
>> Guy has a
>> Guy has a slip.
>> right?
>> Guy has a slip. He
>> Guy has a slip. He goes
>> right?
>> Guy has a slip. He goes out
>> Guy has a slip. He goes out shoots
>> right?
>> Guy has a slip. He goes out shoots three
people.
people. runs
people. runs over
people. runs over eight
people. runs over eight children,
crashes
crashes his
people. runs over eight children,
crashes his car,
crashes his car, burns
people. runs over eight children,
crashes his car, burns down
crashes his car, burns down his
building,
building, goes
building, goes to
building, goes to a
building, goes to a meeting,
building, goes to a meeting, they
building, goes to a meeting, they say,
"George,
"George, we're
building, goes to a meeting, they say,
"George, we're sure
"George, we're sure glad
building, goes to a meeting, they say,
"George, we're sure glad to
"George, we're sure glad to see
building, goes to a meeting, they say,
"George, we're sure glad to see you
back."
back." That's
back." That's the
back." That's the only
back." That's the only comments
back." That's the only comments you're
going
going to
back." That's the only comments you're
going to get.
>> So,
>> So, the
>> So, the act
>> So, the act of
>> So, the act of actually
>> So, the act of actually overcoming
alcoholism
alcoholism is
>> So, the act of actually overcoming
alcoholism is still
alcoholism is still separate
>> So, the act of actually overcoming
alcoholism is still separate from
alcoholism is still separate from that.
>> No,
>> No, it's
>> No, it's a
>> No, it's a consequence
>> No, it's a consequence of
>> No, it's a consequence of it.
>> No, it's a consequence of it. As
>> No, it's a consequence of it. As a
consequence
consequence of
>> No, it's a consequence of it. As a
consequence of working
consequence of working a
>> No, it's a consequence of it. As a
consequence of working a program
consequence of working a program that
calibrates
calibrates so
calibrates so high,
calibrates so high, uh,
calibrates so high, uh, one
calibrates so high, uh, one when
calibrates so high, uh, one when he's
eventually
eventually healed
calibrates so high, uh, one when he's
eventually healed of
eventually healed of the
calibrates so high, uh, one when he's
eventually healed of the disorder.
eventually healed of the disorder. Yeah.
Yep.
>> And
>> And when
Yep.
>> And when you've
>> And when you've healed
Yep.
>> And when you've healed that,
>> And when you've healed that, does
Yep.
>> And when you've healed that, does that
take
take you
take you to
take you to a
take you to a different
take you to a different place
calibration
calibration wise
take you to a different place
calibration wise or
calibration wise or does
take you to a different place
calibration wise or does the
calibration wise or does the one
take you to a different place
calibration wise or does the one have
nothing
nothing to
nothing to do
nothing to do with
nothing to do with the
nothing to do with the other?
>> I
>> I don't
nothing to do with the other?
>> I don't understand
>> I don't understand the
nothing to do with the other?
>> I don't understand the question.
>> She's
>> She's trying
>> She's trying to
>> She's trying to if
>> She's trying to if you
>> She's trying to if you overcome
alcoholism,
alcoholism, she's
>> She's trying to if you overcome
alcoholism, she's trying
alcoholism, she's trying to
>> She's trying to if you overcome
alcoholism, she's trying to say
alcoholism, she's trying to say is
>> She's trying to if you overcome
alcoholism, she's trying to say is what
do
do you
do you calibrate?
do you calibrate? If
do you calibrate? If you
do you calibrate? If you overcome
alcoholism,
alcoholism, do
do you calibrate? If you overcome
alcoholism, do you
alcoholism, do you go
do you calibrate? If you overcome
alcoholism, do you go up
alcoholism, do you go up in
do you calibrate? If you overcome
alcoholism, do you go up in calibration?
>> Well,
>> Well, of
>> Well, of course.
From
From the
>> Well, of course.
From the bottom
From the bottom of
>> Well, of course.
From the bottom of the
From the bottom of the barrel,
>> Well, of course.
From the bottom of the barrel, you
From the bottom of the barrel, you go
up.
up. Yes.
up. Yes. Yes.
bounce
bounce off
up. Yes. Yes.
bounce off the
bounce off the bottom.
That's
That's the
That's the only
That's the only way
That's the only way a
That's the only way a lot
That's the only way a lot of
That's the only way a lot of people
That's the only way a lot of people can
get
get to
That's the only way a lot of people can
get to the
get to the top.
That's the only way a lot of people can
get to the top. The
get to the top. The crash
That's the only way a lot of people can
get to the top. The crash has
get to the top. The crash has to
That's the only way a lot of people can
get to the top. The crash has to be
get to the top. The crash has to be so
severe,
severe, so
severe, so confronted,
severe, so confronted, so
severe, so confronted, so overwhelming,
because
because that's
severe, so confronted, so overwhelming,
because that's what
because that's what it
severe, so confronted, so overwhelming,
because that's what it takes
because that's what it takes to
severe, so confronted, so overwhelming,
because that's what it takes to beat
because that's what it takes to beat the
ego.
ego. That's
ego. That's what
ego. That's what the
ego. That's what the world's
ego. That's what the world's facing
today.
today. Is
ego. That's what the world's facing
today. Is it
today. Is it going
ego. That's what the world's facing
today. Is it going to
today. Is it going to precipitate
hitting
hitting bottom
hitting bottom for
hitting bottom for everyone
hitting bottom for everyone to
hitting bottom for everyone to turn
hitting bottom for everyone to turn to
integrity
integrity and
hitting bottom for everyone to turn to
integrity and truth,
integrity and truth, forgiveness,
hitting bottom for everyone to turn to
integrity and truth, forgiveness, and
love
love and
love and integrity?
love and integrity? I
love and integrity? I don't
love and integrity? I don't know.
love and integrity? I don't know. They
might
might choose
love and integrity? I don't know. They
might choose it.
When
When you
When you face
When you face nuclear
When you face nuclear annihilation,
When you face nuclear annihilation, it's
amazing
how
how you
how you could
how you could change
how you could change your
how you could change your view
how you could change your view of
things.
>> Mhm.
>> So,
>> So, who
>> Mhm.
>> So, who knows
>> So, who knows what
>> Mhm.
>> So, who knows what the
>> So, who knows what the world
>> Mhm.
>> So, who knows what the world is
>> So, who knows what the world is going
>> Mhm.
>> So, who knows what the world is going to
bring
bring up
bring up in
bring up in itself
bring up in itself to
bring up in itself to make
bring up in itself to make a
bring up in itself to make a turnaround.
You
You see,
bring up in itself to make a turnaround.
You see, who
You see, who knows?
bring up in itself to make a turnaround.
You see, who knows? So,
You see, who knows? So, therefore,
bring up in itself to make a turnaround.
You see, who knows? So, therefore, the
advice
advice is
advice is to
advice is to surrender
advice is to surrender the
advice is to surrender the world
advice is to surrender the world to
advice is to surrender the world to God
because
because God's
advice is to surrender the world to God
because God's ways
because God's ways are
advice is to surrender the world to God
because God's ways are beyond
because God's ways are beyond man's
understanding.
understanding. Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
Yes.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> What
>> What is
>> What is the
>> What is the question?
>> You're
>> You're the
>> What is the question?
>> You're the question.
>> No,
>> No, she
>> No, she says,
>> No, she says, "What
>> No, she says, "What is
>> No, she says, "What is the
>> No, she says, "What is the question?"
>> What
>> What is
>> No, she says, "What is the question?"
>> What is the
>> What is the question?
>> You
>> You are
>> You are the
>> You are the question.
>> Not
>> Not the
>> You are the question.
>> Not the answer
>> Not the answer you
>> You are the question.
>> Not the answer you wanted.
>> No.
>> And
>> And I
>> No.
>> And I don't
>> And I don't know
>> No.
>> And I don't know what
>> And I don't know what to
>> No.
>> And I don't know what to do
>> And I don't know what to do with
>> No.
>> And I don't know what to do with it.
So,
So, what
So, what is
So, what is she
So, what is she asking
So, what is she asking today?
>> She
>> She says,
So, what is she asking today?
>> She says, "What
>> She says, "What is
So, what is she asking today?
>> She says, "What is the
>> She says, "What is the question?"
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yes.
>> Oh, yes. Actually,
>> Oh, yes. Actually, you
>> Oh, yes. Actually, you are.
You
You are
>> Oh, yes. Actually, you are.
You are the
You are the question.
>> Okay.
That's
That's all
>> Okay.
That's all you're
That's all you're going
>> Okay.
That's all you're going to
That's all you're going to give
>> Okay.
That's all you're going to give me.
>> You're
>> You're walking
>> You're walking question
>> You're walking question mark.
What
What you
>> You're walking question mark.
What you asking?
What you asking? You
>> You're walking question mark.
What you asking? You just
What you asking? You just got
nonverbally
>> at
>> at the
nonverbally
>> at the same
>> at the same time.
>> Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> I
>> I know
>> I know what
>> I know what you're
>> I know what you're asking.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Mhm.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Hi,
>> Hi, Dr.
>> Thank you.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Um
>> y
>> my
>> my question
>> y
>> my question is
>> my question is um
>> y
>> my question is um if
>> my question is um if we're
>> y
>> my question is um if we're all
>> my question is um if we're all born
>> y
>> my question is um if we're all born with
a
a certain
a certain level
a certain level of
a certain level of consciousness
>> are
>> are we
a certain level of consciousness
>> are we also
>> are we also born
a certain level of consciousness
>> are we also born with
>> are we also born with a
a certain level of consciousness
>> are we also born with a certain
>> are we also born with a certain life
purpose
purpose or
purpose or task
purpose or task to
purpose or task to accomplish
purpose or task to accomplish or
purpose or task to accomplish or some
kind
kind of
purpose or task to accomplish or some
kind of contribution?
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know
>> I don't know that
>> I don't know that uh
>> I don't know that uh necessarily
karmically
karmically one
>> I don't know that uh necessarily
karmically one of
karmically one of may
>> I don't know that uh necessarily
karmically one of may probably
karmically one of may probably inherited
a
a pattern
a pattern and
a pattern and may
a pattern and may have
a pattern and may have already
a pattern and may have already committed
to
to that
a pattern and may have already committed
to that pattern.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, you
>> Yeah, you may
>> Yeah, you may have
>> Yeah, you may have already
>> Yeah, you may have already um
>> Yeah, you may have already um it's
>> Yeah, you may have already um it's not
predestination
but
but it's
but it's like
but it's like an
but it's like an agreement.
It's
It's like
but it's like an agreement.
It's like an
It's like an agreement
but it's like an agreement.
It's like an agreement with
It's like an agreement with yourself,
but it's like an agreement.
It's like an agreement with yourself, a
commitment
that
that I
commitment
that I would
that I would like
commitment
that I would like to
that I would like to return
commitment
that I would like to return because
that I would like to return because I
can
can see
can see now
what
what I
can see now
what I want
what I want to
can see now
what I want to transcend.
>> And
>> And so
>> And so you
>> And so you become
>> And so you become a
>> And so you become a nurse,
>> And so you become a nurse, let's
>> And so you become a nurse, let's say,
and
and and
>> And so you become a nurse, let's say,
and and help
and and help the
>> And so you become a nurse, let's say,
and and help the sick
and and help the sick and
>> And so you become a nurse, let's say,
and and help the sick and suffering
instead
instead of
instead of making
instead of making people
instead of making people sick.
instead of making people sick. You
instead of making people sick. You see?
>> Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Is
>> Okay. Is there
>> Okay. Is there some
>> Okay. Is there some way
>> Okay. Is there some way that
>> Okay. Is there some way that you
>> Okay. Is there some way that you would
know
know that
>> Okay. Is there some way that you would
know that or
>> uh
>> uh you
>> uh you you're
>> uh you you're sort
>> uh you you're sort of
>> uh you you're sort of intuitive.
>> uh you you're sort of intuitive. You
>> uh you you're sort of intuitive. You can
tell
tell by
>> uh you you're sort of intuitive. You can
tell by the
tell by the things
>> uh you you're sort of intuitive. You can
tell by the things that
tell by the things that attract
>> uh you you're sort of intuitive. You can
tell by the things that attract you
tell by the things that attract you in
your
your life.
>> Okay,
>> there
>> there is
>> there is certain
>> there is certain things
>> there is certain things as
>> there is certain things as past
>> there is certain things as past life
recall,
recall, but
>> there is certain things as past life
recall, but I
recall, but I never
>> there is certain things as past life
recall, but I never did
recall, but I never did past
>> there is certain things as past life
recall, but I never did past life
recall, but I never did past life recall
in
in order
in order to
in order to remember
in order to remember an
in order to remember an inner
in order to remember an inner decision.
It
It was
in order to remember an inner decision.
It was more
It was more a
in order to remember an inner decision.
It was more a phenomena
It was more a phenomena that
in order to remember an inner decision.
It was more a phenomena that I
It was more a phenomena that I wanted
in order to remember an inner decision.
It was more a phenomena that I wanted to
confirm
confirm was
confirm was an
confirm was an actual
confirm was an actual phenomena.
Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> Wasn't
>> Wasn't there
>> Okay.
>> Wasn't there something?
>> Wasn't there something? Nope.
>> I
>> I already
>> I already got
>> I already got it
>> I already got it signed.
>> I already got it signed. Thank
>> I already got it signed. Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> I already got it signed. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Yes.
>> I
>> I I'm
Yes.
>> I I'm really
>> I I'm really nervous,
Yes.
>> I I'm really nervous, too.
>> Yeah.
>> And
>> And I
>> Yeah.
>> And I hope
>> And I hope I
>> Yeah.
>> And I hope I can
>> And I hope I can talk.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you're
>> Oh, you're not
>> Oh, you're not nervous
>> Oh, you're not nervous enough.
>> Oh, you're not nervous enough. Get
>> Oh, you're not nervous enough. Get more
nervous.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, I'll
>> Okay, I'll try.
>> More
>> More nervous.
>> Okay, I'll try.
>> More nervous. You're
>> More nervous. You're not
>> Okay, I'll try.
>> More nervous. You're not nervous
>> More nervous. You're not nervous enough.
Harder.
Harder. More
Harder. More nervous.
Harder. More nervous. Come
Harder. More nervous. Come on.
>> I
>> I think
Harder. More nervous. Come on.
>> I think I
>> I think I can
Harder. More nervous. Come on.
>> I think I can get
>> I think I can get more
Harder. More nervous. Come on.
>> I think I can get more sort
>> I think I can get more sort of
Harder. More nervous. Come on.
>> I think I can get more sort of a
>> I think I can get more sort of a weaky
nervous.
nervous. I
nervous. I want
nervous. I want to
nervous. I want to see
nervous. I want to see real
nervous. I want to see real nervousness.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, it's
nervous. I want to see real nervousness.
>> Yeah, it's pretty
>> Yeah, it's pretty shaky.
nervous. I want to see real nervousness.
>> Yeah, it's pretty shaky. All
>> Yeah, it's pretty shaky. All right.
nervous. I want to see real nervousness.
>> Yeah, it's pretty shaky. All right. Go
ahead.
>> I
>> I guess
ahead.
>> I guess my
>> I guess my question
ahead.
>> I guess my question was
>> I guess my question was the
ahead.
>> I guess my question was the same
>> I guess my question was the same is
ahead.
>> I guess my question was the same is that
fellows
fellows about
fellows about the
fellows about the teacher
>> about
>> about um
fellows about the teacher
>> about um if
>> about um if it's
fellows about the teacher
>> about um if it's important
>> about um if it's important to
fellows about the teacher
>> about um if it's important to have
>> a
>> a because
>> a because I've
>> a because I've been
>> a because I've been really
>> a because I've been really attracted
>> a because I've been really attracted to
your
your teachings
>> a because I've been really attracted to
your teachings and
your teachings and well
>> a because I've been really attracted to
your teachings and well and
your teachings and well and have
>> a because I've been really attracted to
your teachings and well and have been
reading
reading and
reading and listening.
reading and listening. Is
reading and listening. Is it
reading and listening. Is it important
that
that you
reading and listening. Is it important
that you have
that you have a
reading and listening. Is it important
that you have a teacher
that you have a teacher in
reading and listening. Is it important
that you have a teacher in the
that you have a teacher in the physical
that
that you're
that you're connected
that you're connected to
that you're connected to or
that you're connected to or can
that you're connected to or can talk
that you're connected to or can talk to
or
or is
that you're connected to or can talk to
or is it
or is it okay
that you're connected to or can talk to
or is it okay to
or is it okay to do
that you're connected to or can talk to
or is it okay to do the
>> be
>> be um
>> be um uh
>> be um uh a
>> be um uh a luxury?
>> be um uh a luxury? Yeah.
>> be um uh a luxury? Yeah. Uh
a
a lot
>> be um uh a luxury? Yeah. Uh
a lot of
a lot of people,
>> be um uh a luxury? Yeah. Uh
a lot of people, you
a lot of people, you know,
>> be um uh a luxury? Yeah. Uh
a lot of people, you know, Jesus
a lot of people, you know, Jesus Christ
is
is their
is their teacher
is their teacher and
is their teacher and is
still
still around
is their teacher and is
still around asking
still around asking questions.
is their teacher and is
still around asking questions. You
still around asking questions. You know,
uh
uh you
uh you know,
uh you know, what
uh you know, what your
uh you know, what your commitment
uh you know, what your commitment does
is
is sort
uh you know, what your commitment does
is sort of
is sort of pull
uh you know, what your commitment does
is sort of pull in
is sort of pull in a
uh you know, what your commitment does
is sort of pull in a knowingness.
It
It sort
It sort of
It sort of accesses
It sort of accesses a
It sort of accesses a certain
It sort of accesses a certain etheric
realm
realm uh
It sort of accesses a certain etheric
realm uh which
realm uh which uh
It sort of accesses a certain etheric
realm uh which uh then
realm uh which uh then comes
It sort of accesses a certain etheric
realm uh which uh then comes back
realm uh which uh then comes back to
It sort of accesses a certain etheric
realm uh which uh then comes back to you
sort
sort of
sort of as
sort of as a
sort of as a revelation.
The
The revelation
sort of as a revelation.
The revelation is
The revelation is merely
sort of as a revelation.
The revelation is merely a
The revelation is merely a return
sort of as a revelation.
The revelation is merely a return of
your
your commitment.
Resist.
Resist. Oh
your commitment.
Resist. Oh yes,
that's
that's an
that's an intuitive
that's an intuitive knowingness
that's an intuitive knowingness that
just
just answered
that's an intuitive knowingness that
just answered you.
just answered you. See
that's an intuitive knowingness that
just answered you. See the
just answered you. See the that
that's an intuitive knowingness that
just answered you. See the that to
just answered you. See the that to which
you
you pray
you pray that
you pray that that
you pray that that which
you pray that that which you
you pray that that which you hold
you pray that that which you hold dear
uh
uh the
you pray that that which you hold dear
uh the energy
uh the energy of
you pray that that which you hold dear
uh the energy of that
uh the energy of that then
you pray that that which you hold dear
uh the energy of that then becomes
available
available and
available and comes
available and comes back
available and comes back to
available and comes back to you
available and comes back to you like
available and comes back to you like the
ripple
ripple of
available and comes back to you like the
ripple of a
ripple of a pool
available and comes back to you like the
ripple of a pool comes
ripple of a pool comes back
available and comes back to you like the
ripple of a pool comes back to
ripple of a pool comes back to you.
available and comes back to you like the
ripple of a pool comes back to you. You
see?
>> No,
>> No, I
see?
>> No, I don't
>> No, I don't see.
Well,
Well, that's
Well, that's the
Well, that's the way
Well, that's the way it
Well, that's the way it is.
>> Okay.
>> So,
>> So, it's
>> So, it's okay
>> So, it's okay then
>> So, it's okay then for
>> So, it's okay then for you
>> So, it's okay then for you for
>> So, it's okay then for you for me
>> So, it's okay then for you for me to
>> So, it's okay then for you for me to say
ask
ask for
>> So, it's okay then for you for me to say
ask for you
ask for you to
>> So, it's okay then for you for me to say
ask for you to be
ask for you to be my
>> So, it's okay then for you for me to say
ask for you to be my teacher
ask for you to be my teacher and
>> you
>> you can
>> you can be
>> you can be any.
>> you can be any. Yes,
>> you can be any. Yes, you
>> you can be any. Yes, you can
>> you can be any. Yes, you can pick.
>> you can be any. Yes, you can pick. You
are
are free
>> you can be any. Yes, you can pick. You
are free to
are free to select
>> you can be any. Yes, you can pick. You
are free to select the
are free to select the wisdom
>> you can be any. Yes, you can pick. You
are free to select the wisdom of
are free to select the wisdom of any
teacher.
teacher. Okay.
>> Let's
>> Let's ask
teacher. Okay.
>> Let's ask if
>> Let's ask if it's
teacher. Okay.
>> Let's ask if it's karmically
>> Let's ask if it's karmically permitted.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Wait
>> Okay. Wait a
>> Okay. Wait a second.
>> Okay. Wait a second. I
>> Okay. Wait a second. I got
>> Okay. Wait a second. I got to
>> was
>> was asking
>> Okay. Wait a second. I got to
>> was asking what
>> was asking what she's
>> Okay. Wait a second. I got to
>> was asking what she's asking
>> was asking what she's asking is
karmically
karmically permitted.
karmically permitted. What
karmically permitted. What she's
karmically permitted. What she's uh
asking
asking is
karmically permitted. What she's uh
asking is answerable.
Uh
Uh and
Uh and it
Uh and it should
Uh and it should be
Uh and it should be the
Uh and it should be the affirmative.
Okay.
Okay. I'm
Uh and it should be the affirmative.
Okay. I'm your
Okay. I'm your teacher.
Uh and it should be the affirmative.
Okay. I'm your teacher. Oh
Okay. I'm your teacher. Oh boy.
>> Then
>> Then can
>> Then can I
>> Then can I ask
>> Then can I ask a
>> Then can I ask a real
>> Then can I ask a real simple
>> Then can I ask a real simple one?
>> Then can I ask a real simple one? Go
ahead.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I
>> Yeah. I think
>> Yeah. I think a
>> Yeah. I think a funny
>> Yeah. I think a funny one
>> Yeah. I think a funny one because
>> Yeah. I think a funny one because you
said
said this
>> Yeah. I think a funny one because you
said this morning,
said this morning, you
>> Yeah. I think a funny one because you
said this morning, you know,
said this morning, you know, when
>> Yeah. I think a funny one because you
said this morning, you know, when you
have
have sore
have sore feet,
have sore feet, you
have sore feet, you know,
have sore feet, you know, and
have sore feet, you know, and the
have sore feet, you know, and the older
you
you get,
have sore feet, you know, and the older
you get, the
you get, the more
have sore feet, you know, and the older
you get, the more little
you get, the more little things
have sore feet, you know, and the older
you get, the more little things like
that
that come
that come up.
that come up. Like
that come up. Like you
that come up. Like you can
that come up. Like you can ignore
that come up. Like you can ignore it
that come up. Like you can ignore it or
do
do you
that come up. Like you can ignore it or
do you need
do you need to
that come up. Like you can ignore it or
do you need to like
do you need to like process
that come up. Like you can ignore it or
do you need to like process it?
do you need to like process it? It's
that come up. Like you can ignore it or
do you need to like process it? It's I'd
be
be processing
be processing all
be processing all day.
be processing all day. It
be processing all day. It seems
be processing all day. It seems like,
you
you know,
be processing all day. It seems like,
you know, cuz
you know, cuz so
be processing all day. It seems like,
you know, cuz so many
you know, cuz so many things
be processing all day. It seems like,
you know, cuz so many things come
you know, cuz so many things come up,
you
you know,
you know, hot
you know, hot flashes,
you know, hot flashes, sore
you know, hot flashes, sore feet,
you know, hot flashes, sore feet, all
that
that stuff.
But
But you
But you eventually
But you eventually let
But you eventually let go
But you eventually let go of
But you eventually let go of you
But you eventually let go of you of
clinging
clinging to
But you eventually let go of you of
clinging to any
clinging to any second.
But you eventually let go of you of
clinging to any second. See
clinging to any second. See when
But you eventually let go of you of
clinging to any second. See when your
life
life becomes
life becomes contemplative.
>> You
>> You don't
life becomes contemplative.
>> You don't cling
>> You don't cling to
life becomes contemplative.
>> You don't cling to anything.
>> You don't cling to anything. You
life becomes contemplative.
>> You don't cling to anything. You don't
cling
cling to
cling to things.
cling to things. Oh,
cling to things. Oh, these
cling to things. Oh, these followers
cling to things. Oh, these followers are
beautiful.
beautiful. I
cling to things. Oh, these followers are
beautiful. I don't
beautiful. I don't want
cling to things. Oh, these followers are
beautiful. I don't want them
beautiful. I don't want them to
cling to things. Oh, these followers are
beautiful. I don't want them to fade.
beautiful. I don't want them to fade. I
don't
don't want
don't want them
don't want them anywhere
don't want them anywhere to
don't want them anywhere to take
don't want them anywhere to take it.
don't want them anywhere to take it. You
stop
stop clinging
don't want them anywhere to take it. You
stop clinging to
stop clinging to things.
don't want them anywhere to take it. You
stop clinging to things. Stop
stop clinging to things. Stop clinging
to
to things
to things because
to things because when
to things because when you
to things because when you let
to things because when you let go
clinging,
clinging, you
to things because when you let go
clinging, you you
clinging, you you create
to things because when you let go
clinging, you you create the
clinging, you you create the space
to things because when you let go
clinging, you you create the space for
the
the next
the next delight
the next delight to
the next delight to come
the next delight to come in
the next delight to come in light.
the next delight to come in light. So
life
life doesn't
the next delight to come in light. So
life doesn't go
life doesn't go from
the next delight to come in light. So
life doesn't go from miserable
life doesn't go from miserable to
the next delight to come in light. So
life doesn't go from miserable to good
and
and then
and then back
and then back to
and then back to miserable.
and then back to miserable. It
and then back to miserable. It goes
and then back to miserable. It goes from
good
good to
and then back to miserable. It goes from
good to great
good to great to
and then back to miserable. It goes from
good to great to wonderful
good to great to wonderful to
wonderfuler
wonderfuler to
wonderfuler to wonderfuler
wonderfuler to wonderfuler to
wonderfuler to wonderfuler to wonderful.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
wonderfuler to wonderfuler to wonderful.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. Okay.
And
And then
And then you
And then you die.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh
>> Oh yeah.
>> Oh yeah. Then
>> Oh yeah. Then you
>> Oh yeah. Then you die.
>> Oh yeah. Then you die. We
>> Oh yeah. Then you die. We both
>> Oh yeah. Then you die. We both laugh.
>> It
>> It is
>> Oh yeah. Then you die. We both laugh.
>> It is funny,
>> It is funny, isn't
>> Oh yeah. Then you die. We both laugh.
>> It is funny, isn't it?
>> Hi.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I
>> Hi.
>> Yeah. I came
>> Yeah. I came from
>> Hi.
>> Yeah. I came from Japan
>> Yeah. I came from Japan to
>> Hi.
>> Yeah. I came from Japan to uh
>> Yeah. I came from Japan to uh to
>> Hi.
>> Yeah. I came from Japan to uh to ask
these
these questions
these questions uh
these questions uh with
these questions uh with my
these questions uh with my poor
these questions uh with my poor English.
I'm
I'm sorry.
these questions uh with my poor English.
I'm sorry. Uh
it's
it's fine.
>> In
>> In my
it's fine.
>> In my life,
>> In my life, I
it's fine.
>> In my life, I want
>> In my life, I want to
it's fine.
>> In my life, I want to make
>> In my life, I want to make uh
it's fine.
>> In my life, I want to make uh great
consulting
consulting company
consulting company that
consulting company that calibrates
higher
higher than
consulting company that calibrates
higher than Mckenz
higher than Mckenz and
consulting company that calibrates
higher than Mckenz and greater
higher than Mckenz and greater than
Boston
Boston Consulting
Boston Consulting Company.
create
create a
Boston Consulting Company.
create a company
create a company that
Boston Consulting Company.
create a company that calibrates
create a company that calibrates higher
>> than
>> than um
>> than um other
>> than um other I
>> than um other I can't
>> than um other I can't remember
>> than um other I can't remember what
>> than um other I can't remember what he
said
said but
>> than um other I can't remember what he
said but other
said but other companies
>> oh
>> oh you
>> oh you want
>> oh you want your
>> oh you want your company
>> oh you want your company to
>> oh you want your company to calibrate
>> oh you want your company to calibrate as
high
high as
>> oh you want your company to calibrate as
high as possible
high as possible right
>> is
>> is that
>> is that correct
>> yes
>> yes you
>> is that correct
>> yes you do
>> yes you do that
>> is that correct
>> yes you do that with
>> yes you do that with um
>> is that correct
>> yes you do that with um uh
>> yes you do that with um uh make
>> is that correct
>> yes you do that with um uh make it
>> yes you do that with um uh make it like
a
a family
>> everybody's
>> everybody's committed
a family
>> everybody's committed to
>> everybody's committed to each
a family
>> everybody's committed to each other
everybody's
everybody's committed
everybody's committed to
everybody's committed to the
everybody's committed to the integrity
of
of the
everybody's committed to the integrity
of the product
of the product and
everybody's committed to the integrity
of the product and its
of the product and its presentation
>> everybody's
>> everybody's uh
>> everybody's uh committed
>> everybody's uh committed to
>> everybody's uh committed to honesty
>> yes
>> uh
>> uh to
>> uh to being
>> uh to being of
>> uh to being of service
>> uh to being of service to
>> uh to being of service to the
>> uh to being of service to the world
>> uh to being of service to the world Yes.
>> Uh
>> Uh to
>> uh to being of service to the world Yes.
>> Uh to the
>> Uh to the share
>> uh to being of service to the world Yes.
>> Uh to the share of
>> Uh to the share of the
>> uh to being of service to the world Yes.
>> Uh to the share of the best
>> Uh to the share of the best intelligence
that
that you
that you can
that you can gather.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Thank
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> We
>> We do
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> We do interesting
>> We do interesting things
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> We do interesting things like
>> We do interesting things like uh
calibrating
calibrating uh
calibrating uh TV
calibrating uh TV commercials.
>> Commercial.
>> Commercial. Yes.
>> You
>> You know,
>> You know, some
>> You know, some TV
>> You know, some TV commercials
>> You know, some TV commercials lose
>> You know, some TV commercials lose so
much
much money
>> You know, some TV commercials lose so
much money for
much money for the
>> You know, some TV commercials lose so
much money for the company.
much money for the company. You
>> You know, some TV commercials lose so
much money for the company. You wonder
how
how it
how it survives
how it survives it.
how it survives it. It's
how it survives it. It's commercials.
They're
They're so
how it survives it. It's commercials.
They're so awful.
They're so awful. And
how it survives it. It's commercials.
They're so awful. And others
They're so awful. And others have
how it survives it. It's commercials.
They're so awful. And others have a
delight.
delight. Others
delight. Others have
delight. Others have delight.
delight. Others have delight. So
delight. Others have delight. So you
delight. Others have delight. So you see
the
the application
delight. Others have delight. So you see
the application in
the application in a
delight. Others have delight. So you see
the application in a practical
the application in a practical way.
delight. Others have delight. So you see
the application in a practical way. Yes.
Commercials
Commercials that
Commercials that uh
Commercials that uh uh
Commercials that uh uh are
Commercials that uh uh are objectionable
lose
lose customers.
Commercials that uh uh are objectionable
lose customers. Yeah.
lose customers. Yeah. So
Commercials that uh uh are objectionable
lose customers. Yeah. So you
lose customers. Yeah. So you can
Commercials that uh uh are objectionable
lose customers. Yeah. So you can you
know
know you
know you can
know you can use
know you can use it
know you can use it in
know you can use it in what
know you can use it in what way?
know you can use it in what way? To
match
match your
know you can use it in what way? To
match your product
match your product to
know you can use it in what way? To
match your product to your
match your product to your purchaser.
Let's
Let's say
>> how
>> how does
Let's say
>> how does this
>> how does this product
Let's say
>> how does this product best
>> how does this product best meet
Let's say
>> how does this product best meet their
needs?
needs? You
needs? You know
needs? You know what
needs? You know what kind
needs? You know what kind of
advertising?
advertising? What
needs? You know what kind of
advertising? What kind
advertising? What kind of
needs? You know what kind of
advertising? What kind of people
advertising? What kind of people should
we
we have
we have with
we have with the
we have with the company?
we have with the company? Yeah.
Thank
Thank you.
>> Yeah,
>> proactive
>> proactive applications.
>> Yeah,
>> proactive applications. Yes,
>> we
>> we got
>> we got the
>> we got the questions
>> we got the questions done
>> we got the questions done quickly.
>> Hi.
>> Uh
>> Uh I
>> Hi.
>> Uh I was
>> Uh I was uh
>> Hi.
>> Uh I was uh uh
>> Uh I was uh uh I
>> Hi.
>> Uh I was uh uh I was
>> Uh I was uh uh I was brought
>> Hi.
>> Uh I was uh uh I was brought up
>> Uh I was uh uh I was brought up a
fundamentalist
fundamentalist Christian
fundamentalist Christian and
fundamentalist Christian and I've
fundamentalist Christian and I've uh
fundamentalist Christian and I've uh I
found
found it
fundamentalist Christian and I've uh I
found it a
found it a bit
fundamentalist Christian and I've uh I
found it a bit hard
found it a bit hard to
fundamentalist Christian and I've uh I
found it a bit hard to shake
found it a bit hard to shake uh
fundamentalist Christian and I've uh I
found it a bit hard to shake uh at
times.
times. Uh
times. Uh there
times. Uh there is
times. Uh there is the
times. Uh there is the pernitious
times. Uh there is the pernitious fear
of
of God
times. Uh there is the pernitious fear
of God uh
of God uh that
times. Uh there is the pernitious fear
of God uh that sticks
of God uh that sticks and
times. Uh there is the pernitious fear
of God uh that sticks and uh
of God uh that sticks and uh it
times. Uh there is the pernitious fear
of God uh that sticks and uh it does
of God uh that sticks and uh it does not
thus
thus far
thus far it
thus far it has
thus far it has evaded
thus far it has evaded attempts
thus far it has evaded attempts uh
thus far it has evaded attempts uh to
>> to
>> to be
thus far it has evaded attempts uh to
>> to be taken
>> to be taken care
thus far it has evaded attempts uh to
>> to be taken care of
>> to be taken care of with
thus far it has evaded attempts uh to
>> to be taken care of with either
psychological
psychological or
psychological or spiritual
psychological or spiritual means.
>> Uh
>> Uh biological
psychological or spiritual means.
>> Uh biological doesn't
>> Uh biological doesn't seem
psychological or spiritual means.
>> Uh biological doesn't seem appropriate.
>> What
>> What do
>> What do I
>> What do I do?
>> So
>> So it's
>> What do I do?
>> So it's like
>> So it's like a
>> What do I do?
>> So it's like a fear
>> So it's like a fear of
>> What do I do?
>> So it's like a fear of God.
>> Yeah.
>> Fear
>> Fear of
>> Yeah.
>> Fear of God's
>> Fear of God's what?
>> Yeah.
>> Fear of God's what? Anger,
>> wrath,
>> wrath, hell.
>> wrath, hell. Wrath
>> wrath, hell. Wrath for
>> wrath, hell. Wrath for for
>> wrath, hell. Wrath for for committing
sins.
>> Uh
>> Uh screwing
>> Uh screwing up,
>> Uh screwing up, doing
>> Uh screwing up, doing wrong,
>> committing
>> committing sins,
>> Uh screwing up, doing wrong,
>> committing sins, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And
>> And what's
>> And what's what
>> And what's what would
>> And what's what would he
>> And what's what would he do
>> And what's what would he do to
>> And what's what would he do to you?
>> Uh
>> Uh probably
>> And what's what would he do to you?
>> Uh probably the
>> Uh probably the hell
>> And what's what would he do to you?
>> Uh probably the hell thing,
>> Uh probably the hell thing, I
>> And what's what would he do to you?
>> Uh probably the hell thing, I think,
>> Uh probably the hell thing, I think, is
that's
that's a
that's a rough
that's a rough one.
>> So
>> So So
that's a rough one.
>> So So what
>> So So what are
that's a rough one.
>> So So what are you
>> So So what are you going
that's a rough one.
>> So So what are you going to
>> So So what are you going to do
that's a rough one.
>> So So what are you going to do to
>> So So what are you going to do to make
him
him do
him do the
him do the hell
him do the hell thing?
>> Uh
>> Uh well,
him do the hell thing?
>> Uh well, sometimes
>> Uh well, sometimes I'm
him do the hell thing?
>> Uh well, sometimes I'm afraid
>> Uh well, sometimes I'm afraid that
him do the hell thing?
>> Uh well, sometimes I'm afraid that I
already
already did
already did it.
already did it. Yeah.
>> And
>> And then
already did it. Yeah.
>> And then he's
>> And then he's just
already did it. Yeah.
>> And then he's just kind
>> And then he's just kind of
already did it. Yeah.
>> And then he's just kind of waiting
>> And then he's just kind of waiting on
me,
me, you
me, you know.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. That's
>> Yes. That's the
>> Yes. That's the anthrop
>> Yes. That's the anthrop anthropomorphic
image
image of
>> Yes. That's the anthrop anthropomorphic
image of God.
>> Yeah.
>> That
>> That God
>> Yeah.
>> That God is
>> That God is just
>> Yeah.
>> That God is just a
>> That God is just a magnified
>> Yeah.
>> That God is just a magnified human
>> That God is just a magnified human ego
projected
projected up
projected up there
projected up there somewhere.
projected up there somewhere. Prone
projected up there somewhere. Prone to
jealousy,
jealousy, anger,
projected up there somewhere. Prone to
jealousy, anger, revenge,
intolerance.
Uh,
not
not as
not as kind
not as kind as
not as kind as my
not as kind as my own
not as kind as my own grandmother.
Less
Less kind
not as kind as my own grandmother.
Less kind than
Less kind than my
not as kind as my own grandmother.
Less kind than my grandmother.
Less kind than my grandmother. You
really
really think
really think he's
really think he's so?
>> Would
>> Would that
really think he's so?
>> Would that be
>> Would that be called
really think he's so?
>> Would that be called God
>> Would that be called God or
really think he's so?
>> Would that be called God or would
>> Would that be called God or would that
be?
be? Oh,
be? Oh, I
be? Oh, I guess
be? Oh, I guess you
be? Oh, I guess you see
be? Oh, I guess you see is
be? Oh, I guess you see is some
be? Oh, I guess you see is some kind
be? Oh, I guess you see is some kind of
a
a God
be? Oh, I guess you see is some kind of
a God image,
a God image, God
be? Oh, I guess you see is some kind of
a God image, God belief
a God image, God belief system,
which
which is
which is anthropomorphic.
which is anthropomorphic. It
which is anthropomorphic. It takes
which is anthropomorphic. It takes the
downside
downside of
which is anthropomorphic. It takes the
downside of human
downside of human consciousness
which is anthropomorphic. It takes the
downside of human consciousness and
projects
projects it
projects it onto
projects it onto deity.
How
How could
projects it onto deity.
How could anybody
How could anybody be
projects it onto deity.
How could anybody be God
How could anybody be God and
projects it onto deity.
How could anybody be God and be
How could anybody be God and be so
incomplete
incomplete that
incomplete that he
incomplete that he was
incomplete that he was prone
incomplete that he was prone to
jealousy?
jealousy? He
incomplete that he was prone to
jealousy? He wouldn't
jealousy? He wouldn't be
incomplete that he was prone to
jealousy? He wouldn't be God.
jealousy? He wouldn't be God. He'd
incomplete that he was prone to
jealousy? He wouldn't be God. He'd be
jealousy? He wouldn't be God. He'd be an
astral
astral entity.
An
An astral
astral entity.
An astral entity
An astral entity that
astral entity.
An astral entity that calls
An astral entity that calls itself
astral entity.
An astral entity that calls itself God.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, that
>> Yeah, that that
>> Yeah, that that would
>> Yeah, that that would make
>> Yeah, that that would make more
>> Yeah, that that would make more sense.
>> Yeah.
For
For God
>> Yeah.
For God to
For God to be
>> Yeah.
For God to be God,
For God to be God, he
>> Yeah.
For God to be God, he would
For God to be God, he would have
>> Yeah.
For God to be God, he would have to
For God to be God, he would have to be
divine.
Dei
Dei divinity
divine.
Dei divinity means
Dei divinity means unconditional
divine.
Dei divinity means unconditional love.
Unconditional
Unconditional love
Unconditional love instantly
Unconditional love instantly sees
Unconditional love instantly sees the
limitation
limitation of
Unconditional love instantly sees the
limitation of human
limitation of human consciousness.
It
It would
It would be
It would be like
It would be like punishing
It would be like punishing a
It would be like punishing a baby
It would be like punishing a baby for
being
being infantile.
Therefore,
Therefore, he
Therefore, he would
Therefore, he would be
Therefore, he would be a
Therefore, he would be a sadist.
Therefore, he would be a sadist. What
you're
you're picturing
Therefore, he would be a sadist. What
you're picturing is
you're picturing is really
Therefore, he would be a sadist. What
you're picturing is really a
you're picturing is really a sadist
Therefore, he would be a sadist. What
you're picturing is really a sadist who
is
is punitive
is punitive towards
is punitive towards his
is punitive towards his own
is punitive towards his own creation.
God
God created
is punitive towards his own creation.
God created man
God created man in
is punitive towards his own creation.
God created man in his
God created man in his own
is punitive towards his own creation.
God created man in his own image
God created man in his own image and
is punitive towards his own creation.
God created man in his own image and now
he's
he's going
he's going to
he's going to condemn
he's going to condemn him
he's going to condemn him to
he's going to condemn him to hell
he's going to condemn him to hell for
being
being in
he's going to condemn him to hell for
being in his
being in his own
he's going to condemn him to hell for
being in his own image.
If
If you're
If you're created
If you're created by
If you're created by God,
If you're created by God, how
If you're created by God, how can
If you're created by God, how can you
hate
hate his
If you're created by God, how can you
hate his own
hate his own creation?
Or
Or is
Or is that
Or is that a
Or is that a distorted
Or is that a distorted picture
Or is that a distorted picture of
Or is that a distorted picture of God
based
based on
Or is that a distorted picture of God
based on fear?
You
You can
You can get
You can get a
You can get a lot
You can get a lot of
You can get a lot of mileage
You can get a lot of mileage out
You can get a lot of mileage out of
selling
selling the
You can get a lot of mileage out of
selling the fear
selling the fear image
You can get a lot of mileage out of
selling the fear image of
selling the fear image of God.
You can get a lot of mileage out of
selling the fear image of God. A
selling the fear image of God. A lot
You can get a lot of mileage out of
selling the fear image of God. A lot of
mileage.
lots
lots of
mileage.
lots of followers
lots of followers and
mileage.
lots of followers and lots
lots of followers and lots of
mileage.
lots of followers and lots of bucks
lots of followers and lots of bucks and
lots
lots of
lots of time
lots of time on
lots of time on TV
lots of time on TV in
lots of time on TV in giant
amphitheaters.
amphitheaters. You
lots of time on TV in giant
amphitheaters. You can
amphitheaters. You can shout
lots of time on TV in giant
amphitheaters. You can shout the
amphitheaters. You can shout the evils
of
of sin,
big
big bucks.
>> So,
>> So, so
>> So, so there
>> So, so there is
>> So, so there is um
>> So, so there is um intellectually
>> So, so there is um intellectually I
>> So, so there is um intellectually I feel
like
like I
>> So, so there is um intellectually I feel
like I grasp
like I grasp what
>> So, so there is um intellectually I feel
like I grasp what you're
like I grasp what you're saying
>> So, so there is um intellectually I feel
like I grasp what you're saying and
sometimes
sometimes it
sometimes it feels
sometimes it feels like
sometimes it feels like maybe
emotionally
>> you
>> you pray
>> you pray about
>> you pray about it
>> you pray about it and
>> you pray about it and ask
>> you pray about it and ask God
>> you pray about it and ask God for
>> you pray about it and ask God for help.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. You
>> you pray about it and ask God for help.
>> Okay. You may
>> Okay. You may you
>> you pray about it and ask God for help.
>> Okay. You may you may
>> Okay. You may you may have
>> you pray about it and ask God for help.
>> Okay. You may you may have been
>> Okay. You may you may have been one
>> you pray about it and ask God for help.
>> Okay. You may you may have been one of
them
them hell
them hell hell
them hell hell and
them hell hell and brimstone
them hell hell and brimstone creatures
in
in another
them hell hell and brimstone creatures
in another lifetime.
>> Maybe
>> Maybe you
>> Maybe you terrified
>> Maybe you terrified a
>> Maybe you terrified a lot
>> Maybe you terrified a lot of
>> Maybe you terrified a lot of people.
>> Maybe you terrified a lot of people. Now
you
you got
>> Maybe you terrified a lot of people. Now
you got to
you got to see
>> Maybe you terrified a lot of people. Now
you got to see what
you got to see what it's
>> Maybe you terrified a lot of people. Now
you got to see what it's like.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, I
>> Yeah, I think
>> Yeah, I think it's
>> Yeah, I think it's very
>> Yeah, I think it's very close
>> Yeah, I think it's very close to
>> Yeah, I think it's very close to the
truth.
truth. Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Hell
>> Hell and
>> Thank you.
>> Hell and brimstone.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> And
>> And if
>> Thank you.
>> And if I'm
>> And if I'm wrong,
>> Thank you.
>> And if I'm wrong, you
>> And if I'm wrong, you just
>> Thank you.
>> And if I'm wrong, you just fry
>> And if I'm wrong, you just fry in
>> Thank you.
>> And if I'm wrong, you just fry in hell.
What
What the
What the hell?
>> Thank
>> Thank you
What the hell?
>> Thank you so
>> Thank you so much.
I
I don't
I don't know
I don't know why
I don't know why when
I don't know why when I
I don't know why when I ask
I don't know why when I ask questions
I don't know why when I ask questions of
you
you anymore.
>> I
>> I wanted
>> I wanted to
>> I wanted to ask
>> I wanted to ask about
>> I wanted to ask about the
>> I wanted to ask about the early
Christian
Christian church.
>> I wanted to ask about the early
Christian church. I
Christian church. I was
>> I wanted to ask about the early
Christian church. I was became
Christian church. I was became more
interested
interested in
interested in after
interested in after you
interested in after you said
interested in after you said the
calibration
calibration dropped
interested in after you said the
calibration dropped after
calibration dropped after the
interested in after you said the
calibration dropped after the nine
council.
>> Yes.
>> But
>> But it
>> But it seemed
>> But it seemed like
>> But it seemed like they
>> But it seemed like they were
>> But it seemed like they were out
rounding
rounding up
>> But it seemed like they were out
rounding up converts
rounding up converts back
>> But it seemed like they were out
rounding up converts back then.
and
uh
uh they're
and
uh they're pretty
uh they're pretty high
and
uh they're pretty high calibration
to
to be
to be doing
to be doing that.
to be doing that. Um
to be doing that. Um what
to be doing that. Um what I
to be doing that. Um what I hear
to be doing that. Um what I hear from
you
you now,
to be doing that. Um what I hear from
you now, they're
you now, they're not
to be doing that. Um what I hear from
you now, they're not um
you now, they're not um it's
to be doing that. Um what I hear from
you now, they're not um it's the
opposite.
opposite. I
opposite. I we're
opposite. I we're not
opposite. I we're not going
opposite. I we're not going out
opposite. I we're not going out rounding
up
up converts.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't get
>> I don't get what
>> I don't get what your
>> I don't get what your question
>> I don't get what your question is.
>> He
>> He said
>> I don't get what your question is.
>> He said that
>> He said that the
>> I don't get what your question is.
>> He said that the Christian
>> He said that the Christian uh
>> I don't get what your question is.
>> He said that the Christian uh faith
>> He said that the Christian uh faith uh
after
>> it
>> it dropped
after
>> it dropped its
>> it dropped its caliber
after
>> it dropped its caliber level
>> it dropped its caliber level dropped
after
after the
after the council
after the council of
after the council of Nika.
after the council of Nika. That's
correct.
correct. So
after the council of Nika. That's
correct. So what
correct. So what has
after the council of Nika. That's
correct. So what has that
correct. So what has that got
after the council of Nika. That's
correct. So what has that got to
correct. So what has that got to do
after the council of Nika. That's
correct. So what has that got to do with
the
the question?
the question? So
the question? So before
the question? So before that
they
they at
the question? So before that
they at a
they at a high
the question? So before that
they at a high calibration
they at a high calibration they
the question? So before that
they at a high calibration they were
still
still trying
still trying to
still trying to convert
still trying to convert people.
>> They
>> They were
still trying to convert people.
>> They were the
>> They were the apostles.
still trying to convert people.
>> They were the apostles. The
>> They were the apostles. The twel
apostles.
apostles. Is
apostles. Is that
apostles. Is that what
apostles. Is that what you're
apostles. Is that what you're talking
about?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. The
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. The 12
>> Yeah. The 12 apostles
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. The 12 apostles tried
>> Yeah. The 12 apostles tried to
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. The 12 apostles tried to spread
the
the word.
>> Uh
>> Uh yes.
the word.
>> Uh yes. And
>> Uh yes. And then
the word.
>> Uh yes. And then what?
>> Spreading
>> Spreading the
>> Spreading the word.
>> The
>> The council
>> Spreading the word.
>> The council of
>> The council of Na
>> Spreading the word.
>> The council of Na had
>> The council of Na had nothing
>> Spreading the word.
>> The council of Na had nothing to
>> The council of Na had nothing to do
>> Spreading the word.
>> The council of Na had nothing to do with
the
the apostles
the apostles or
>> I
>> I know
the apostles or
>> I know spreading
>> I know spreading the
the apostles or
>> I know spreading the word.
>> I know spreading the word. It
the apostles or
>> I know spreading the word. It was
different.
>> The
>> The calibration
before
before the
before the council.
before the council. Yes.
>> They
>> They weren't
before the council. Yes.
>> They weren't just
>> They weren't just spreading
before the council. Yes.
>> They weren't just spreading the
>> They weren't just spreading the word.
They
They were
They were converting
They were converting people.
>> Yes.
>> How
>> How do
>> How do you
>> How do you convert
>> How do you convert people?
>> Are
>> Are they
>> How do you convert people?
>> Are they threatening
>> Are they threatening to
>> How do you convert people?
>> Are they threatening to burn
>> Are they threatening to burn them
>> How do you convert people?
>> Are they threatening to burn them at
>> Are they threatening to burn them at the
stake?
>> No,
>> No, they
stake?
>> No, they were
>> No, they were being
stake?
>> No, they were being burned.
>> No, they were being burned. I
>> Okay.
>> I
>> I think
>> Okay.
>> I think it's
>> I think it's the
>> Okay.
>> I think it's the other
>> I think it's the other way
>> Okay.
>> I think it's the other way around.
>> I think it's the other way around. Yeah.
Now,
Now, the
Now, the council
Now, the council of
Now, the council of Nika
Now, the council of Nika introduced
Now, the council of Nika introduced many
concepts
concepts that
Now, the council of Nika introduced many
concepts that calibrated
concepts that calibrated low.
Now, the council of Nika introduced many
concepts that calibrated low. the
concepts that calibrated low. the in
Now, the council of Nika introduced many
concepts that calibrated low. the in the
New
New Testament
New Testament revelations
New Testament revelations the
New Testament revelations the book
New Testament revelations the book of
revelations
revelations calibrates
New Testament revelations the book of
revelations calibrates about
revelations calibrates about 70
New Testament revelations the book of
revelations calibrates about 70 or
revelations calibrates about 70 or 80
New Testament revelations the book of
revelations calibrates about 70 or 80 or
90 or
90 or something
90 or something that
90 or something that brought
90 or something that brought down
90 or something that brought down the
whole
whole New
90 or something that brought down the
whole New Testament
whole New Testament because
90 or something that brought down the
whole New Testament because if
whole New Testament because if you
remove
remove that
remove that the
remove that the calibrated
remove that the calibrated level
remove that the calibrated level of
remove that the calibrated level of the
whole
whole New
remove that the calibrated level of the
whole New Testament
whole New Testament skyrockets
the
the vision
the vision of
the vision of John
the vision of John which
the vision of John which is
the vision of John which is an
the vision of John which is an old
the vision of John which is an old lower
astral
astral domain
the vision of John which is an old lower
astral domain not
astral domain not not
the vision of John which is an old lower
astral domain not not peculiar
astral domain not not peculiar to
the vision of John which is an old lower
astral domain not not peculiar to John
by
by the
by the way
by the way in
by the way in fact
by the way in fact there
by the way in fact there was
by the way in fact there was a
by the way in fact there was a spiritual
teacher
teacher in
by the way in fact there was a spiritual
teacher in Sedona
teacher in Sedona who
by the way in fact there was a spiritual
teacher in Sedona who I
teacher in Sedona who I knew
by the way in fact there was a spiritual
teacher in Sedona who I knew extremely
well
well that
well that had
well that had visited
well that had visited the
well that had visited the same
well that had visited the same astral
realm
realm in
well that had visited the same astral
realm in In
realm in In fact,
well that had visited the same astral
realm in In fact, every
realm in In fact, every generation
well that had visited the same astral
realm in In fact, every generation a
couple
couple of
couple of people
couple of people visit
couple of people visit that
couple of people visit that astral
couple of people visit that astral realm
and
and report
couple of people visit that astral realm
and report it.
and report it. Now,
couple of people visit that astral realm
and report it. Now, they're
and report it. Now, they're not
couple of people visit that astral realm
and report it. Now, they're not lying
because
because it's
because it's experiential
because it's experiential just
because it's experiential just like
because it's experiential just like uh
uh
uh spirit
because it's experiential just like uh
uh spirit possession
uh spirit possession uh
extraterrestrials.
The
The spirit
extraterrestrials.
The spirit leaves
The spirit leaves the
extraterrestrials.
The spirit leaves the body
The spirit leaves the body and
extraterrestrials.
The spirit leaves the body and they
experience
experience that
experience that domain.
experience that domain. When
experience that domain. When they
experience that domain. When they come
back,
back, they're
experience that domain. When they come
back, they're very
back, they're very convincing
experience that domain. When they come
back, they're very convincing because
they
they did
they did experience
they did experience it
they did experience it in
they did experience it in a
they did experience it in a lower
they did experience it in a lower astral
domain.
teacher
teacher I
teacher I knew
teacher I knew very
teacher I knew very well
draw
draw a
teacher I knew very well
draw a lot
draw a lot of
teacher I knew very well
draw a lot of people
draw a lot of people out
they're
they're going to
they're going to avoid
they're going to avoid the
they're going to avoid the great
catastrophe
catastrophe California
they're going to avoid the great
catastrophe California is
catastrophe California is going
they're going to avoid the great
catastrophe California is going to
catastrophe California is going to fall
into
into the
into the ocean
into the ocean Phoenix
into the ocean Phoenix is
into the ocean Phoenix is going
into the ocean Phoenix is going to
become
become a
into the ocean Phoenix is going to
become a seapport
earthquakes
earthquakes famine
earthquakes famine disaster
earthquakes famine disaster roving
earthquakes famine disaster roving bands
of
of starving
earthquakes famine disaster roving bands
of starving savages
of starving savages therefore
earthquakes famine disaster roving bands
of starving savages therefore we'll
of starving savages therefore we'll have
to
to have
to have a
to have a survival
to have a survival community
to have a survival community and
to have a survival community and live
underground
underground that's
to have a survival community and live
underground that's routine
That's
That's your
That's your nickel
That's your nickel and
That's your nickel and dime
That's your nickel and dime vision.
That's
That's what
That's your nickel and dime vision.
That's what brought
That's what brought down
That's your nickel and dime vision.
That's what brought down the
That's what brought down the New
Testament.
Testament. The
Testament. The book.
Testament. The book. That
Testament. The book. That book.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> That's
>> That's why
>> That's why it's
>> That's why it's important
>> That's why it's important to
>> That's why it's important to be
>> That's why it's important to be able
>> That's why it's important to be able to
tell
tell truth
>> That's why it's important to be able to
tell truth from
tell truth from falsehood.
>> Yes.
>> They
>> They could
>> Yes.
>> They could calibrate
>> They could calibrate things
>> Yes.
>> They could calibrate things at
>> They could calibrate things at the
>> Yes.
>> They could calibrate things at the time
of
of the
of the New
of the New Testament.
of the New Testament. I'm
of the New Testament. I'm sure
of the New Testament. I'm sure they
wouldn't
wouldn't have
of the New Testament. I'm sure they
wouldn't have included
wouldn't have included the
of the New Testament. I'm sure they
wouldn't have included the book
wouldn't have included the book of
of the New Testament. I'm sure they
wouldn't have included the book of John.
John
John himself
John himself calibrated
John himself calibrated about
John himself calibrated about 70.
John himself calibrated about 70. And
the
the book
John himself calibrated about 70. And
the book the
the book the New
John himself calibrated about 70. And
the book the New Testament,
the book the New Testament, that
John himself calibrated about 70. And
the book the New Testament, that book
the book the New Testament, that book in
the
the New
the New Testament
the New Testament calibrated
the New Testament calibrated about
the New Testament calibrated about 70.
Remove
Remove that
the New Testament calibrated about 70.
Remove that from
Remove that from the
the New Testament calibrated about 70.
Remove that from the New
Remove that from the New Testament.
Whole
Whole thing
Whole thing shoots
based
based on
Whole thing shoots
based on fear,
based on fear, retaliation,
catastrophe.
You
You don't
catastrophe.
You don't need
You don't need a
catastrophe.
You don't need a holy
You don't need a holy book
catastrophe.
You don't need a holy book to
You don't need a holy book to tell
catastrophe.
You don't need a holy book to tell you
all
all that.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Good.
>> Did
>> Did I
>> Did I answer?
>> Did I answer? I
>> Did I answer? I hope
>> Did I answer? I hope so.
>> We
>> We have
>> Did I answer? I hope so.
>> We have two
>> We have two more.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, I'm
>> Yes, I'm just
>> Yes, I'm just about
>> Yes, I'm just about the
>> Yes, I'm just about the end.
>> Yes.
first.
first. Thank
first. Thank you.
first. Thank you. Um,
first. Thank you. Um, my
first. Thank you. Um, my question
first. Thank you. Um, my question is
first. Thank you. Um, my question is the
Zohar
Zohar I
first. Thank you. Um, my question is the
Zohar I believe
Zohar I believe you
first. Thank you. Um, my question is the
Zohar I believe you calibrate
Zohar I believe you calibrate quite
high.
>> Yes.
>> I
>> I also
>> I also was
>> I also was under
>> I also was under the
>> I also was under the belief
>> I also was under the belief that
>> I also was under the belief that that
was
was a
>> I also was under the belief that that
was a chneled.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know
>> I don't know anything
>> I don't know anything about
>> I don't know anything about it.
>> Pardon
>> Pardon me.
>> I
>> I I
>> I I don't
>> I I don't tend
>> I I don't tend to
>> I I don't tend to tell
>> I I don't tend to tell you
>> I I don't tend to tell you anything
about
about it.
>> So,
>> So, you
>> So, you don't
>> So, you don't know
>> So, you don't know if
>> So, you don't know if the
>> So, you don't know if the Zohar
>> So, you don't know if the Zohar was
channelneled?
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know
>> I don't know anything
>> I don't know anything about
>> I don't know anything about it.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. But
>> I don't know anything about it.
>> Okay. But I
>> Okay. But I thought
>> I don't know anything about it.
>> Okay. But I thought in
>> Okay. But I thought in your
>> I don't know anything about it.
>> Okay. But I thought in your book
>> Okay. But I thought in your book though,
you've
you've calibrated
you've calibrated it
you've calibrated it rather
you've calibrated it rather highly.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. That's
you've calibrated it rather highly.
>> Yes. That's what
>> Yes. That's what the
you've calibrated it rather highly.
>> Yes. That's what the Zohar
>> Yes. That's what the Zohar is.
>> The
>> The Zohar
>> The Zohar is.
>> I
>> I don't
>> The Zohar is.
>> I don't know
>> I don't know anything
>> The Zohar is.
>> I don't know anything about
>> I don't know anything about the
>> The Zohar is.
>> I don't know anything about the Zohar.
>> I don't know anything about the Zohar. I
learn
learn what
learn what it
learn what it calibrated.
learn what it calibrated. You
learn what it calibrated. You show
learn what it calibrated. You show me
learn what it calibrated. You show me an
image,
image, I
learn what it calibrated. You show me an
image, I calibrate
image, I calibrate it.
learn what it calibrated. You show me an
image, I calibrate it. I
image, I calibrate it. I see
learn what it calibrated. You show me an
image, I calibrate it. I see what
image, I calibrate it. I see what the
calibration
calibration is.
calibration is. I
calibration is. I don't
calibration is. I don't know
calibration is. I don't know the
calibration is. I don't know the story,
what
what his
calibration is. I don't know the story,
what his name
what his name is,
calibration is. I don't know the story,
what his name is, where
what his name is, where he
calibration is. I don't know the story,
what his name is, where he grew
what his name is, where he grew up.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So,
>> Okay. So, in
>> Okay. So, in other
>> Okay. So, in other words,
>> Okay. So, in other words, although
>> Okay. So, in other words, although it
was
was a
>> Okay. So, in other words, although it
was a channel
was a channel book,
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know
>> I don't know anything
>> I don't know anything about
>> I don't know anything about channel
whether
whether it's
>> I don't know anything about channel
whether it's a
whether it's a channel
>> I don't know anything about channel
whether it's a channel book.
>> You
>> You you
>> You you statement.
>> You you statement. I
>> You you statement. I don't
>> You you statement. I don't know
>> You you statement. I don't know any
>> You you statement. I don't know any such
truth.
truth. Where
>> You you statement. I don't know any such
truth. Where do
truth. Where do you
>> You you statement. I don't know any such
truth. Where do you tell
truth. Where do you tell me?
>> You you statement. I don't know any such
truth. Where do you tell me? Where
truth. Where do you tell me? Where do
you
you find
you find that?
you find that? It
you find that? It says
you find that? It says in
you find that? It says in the
you find that? It says in the front
you find that? It says in the front this
is
is a
you find that? It says in the front this
is a channel
is a channel book.
you find that? It says in the front this
is a channel book. What
is a channel book. What does
you find that? It says in the front this
is a channel book. What does it
is a channel book. What does it say?
>> Uh
>> Uh I
>> Uh I heard
>> Uh I heard it.
>> Uh I heard it. I
>> Uh I heard it. I can't
>> Uh I heard it. I can't really
>> Uh I heard it. I can't really say
>> Uh I heard it. I can't really say where.
You
You heard
>> Uh I heard it. I can't really say where.
You heard it,
You heard it, you
>> Uh I heard it. I can't really say where.
You heard it, you know,
You heard it, you know, from
>> Uh I heard it. I can't really say where.
You heard it, you know, from in
You heard it, you know, from in a
careless
careless fashion.
careless fashion. You
careless fashion. You better
careless fashion. You better research
it.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, I
>> Okay, I will
>> Okay, I will research
>> Okay, I will research it.
>> Thank
>> Thank you,
>> Maya.
>> Now,
>> Now, you
>> Maya.
>> Now, you want
>> Now, you want a
>> Maya.
>> Now, you want a hug
>> Now, you want a hug on
>> Maya.
>> Now, you want a hug on top
>> Now, you want a hug on top of
>> Maya.
>> Now, you want a hug on top of that?
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> What
>> What happened?
>> Okay.
>> There.
>> Hold
>> Hold it.
>> Hold it. Hold
>> Hold it. Hold it.
>> Hold it. Hold it. Hold
>> Hold it. Hold it. Hold it
>> Hold it. Hold it. Hold it down.
>> Okie
>> Okie do.
>> Hold it. Hold it. Hold it down.
>> Okie do. Thank
>> Okie do. Thank you.
>> There
>> There are
>> There are many
>> There are many sources
>> There are many sources of
>> There are many sources of teaching.
>> There are many sources of teaching. You
see,
see, you
>> There are many sources of teaching. You
see, you have
see, you have to
>> There are many sources of teaching. You
see, you have to find
see, you have to find out
>> There are many sources of teaching. You
see, you have to find out what
see, you have to find out what is
>> There are many sources of teaching. You
see, you have to find out what is the
intention.
intention. The
intention. The intention
intention. The intention of
intention. The intention of our
intention. The intention of our lessons,
our
our classes,
intention. The intention of our lessons,
our classes, our
our classes, our our
intention. The intention of our lessons,
our classes, our our studies,
our classes, our our studies, our
lectures
lectures etc.
lectures etc. Is
lectures etc. Is it
lectures etc. Is it like
lectures etc. Is it like frankly
lectures etc. Is it like frankly that
lectures etc. Is it like frankly that is
the
the purpose?
>> And
>> And therefore
>> And therefore you
>> And therefore you have
>> And therefore you have to
>> And therefore you have to contextualize
in
in everything
>> And therefore you have to contextualize
in everything in
in everything in terms
>> And therefore you have to contextualize
in everything in terms of
in everything in terms of that
>> And therefore you have to contextualize
in everything in terms of that purpose.
Whether
Whether the
Whether the purpose
Whether the purpose of
Whether the purpose of the
Whether the purpose of the Zohor
Whether the purpose of the Zohor is
Whether the purpose of the Zohor is to
give
give you
Whether the purpose of the Zohor is to
give you high
give you high uh
Whether the purpose of the Zohor is to
give you high uh high
give you high uh high spiritual
understandings
understandings or
understandings or is
understandings or is it
understandings or is it to
understandings or is it to reach
enlightenment?
enlightenment? There
understandings or is it to reach
enlightenment? There are
enlightenment? There are two
understandings or is it to reach
enlightenment? There are two different
goals.
goals. You
goals. You understand?
>> Hello.
>> Hello. Um
>> I'm
>> I'm very
>> I'm very thankful
>> I'm very thankful to
>> I'm very thankful to be
>> I'm very thankful to be here.
>> I'm very thankful to be here. Um
>> I'm very thankful to be here. Um Susan
and
and Dr.
>> I'm very thankful to be here. Um Susan
and Dr. um
and Dr. um three
>> I'm very thankful to be here. Um Susan
and Dr. um three years
and Dr. um three years ago
>> I'm very thankful to be here. Um Susan
and Dr. um three years ago I
and Dr. um three years ago I made
>> I'm very thankful to be here. Um Susan
and Dr. um three years ago I made a
musical
musical CD
musical CD and
musical CD and that
musical CD and that an
musical CD and that an uncle
musical CD and that an uncle had
musical CD and that an uncle had called
a
a like
musical CD and that an uncle had called
a like a
a like a dark
musical CD and that an uncle had called
a like a dark night
a like a dark night of
musical CD and that an uncle had called
a like a dark night of the
a like a dark night of the soul
musical CD and that an uncle had called
a like a dark night of the soul CD.
a like a dark night of the soul CD. And
um
um I
um I just
um I just made
um I just made another
um I just made another one
um I just made another one this
um I just made another one this uh
um I just made another one this uh just
recently
recently kind
um I just made another one this uh just
recently kind of
recently kind of for
um I just made another one this uh just
recently kind of for my
recently kind of for my family.
um I just made another one this uh just
recently kind of for my family. And
recently kind of for my family. And this
one
one uh
one uh is
one uh is labeled
one uh is labeled more
one uh is labeled more inspirational.
And
And after
one uh is labeled more inspirational.
And after the
And after the the
one uh is labeled more inspirational.
And after the the last
And after the the last CD
one uh is labeled more inspirational.
And after the the last CD that
And after the the last CD that was
one uh is labeled more inspirational.
And after the the last CD that was kind
of
of my
of my uncle
of my uncle had
of my uncle had classified
of my uncle had classified a
of my uncle had classified a dark
of my uncle had classified a dark night
of
of soul.
of my uncle had classified a dark night
of soul. It's
of soul. It's kind
of my uncle had classified a dark night
of soul. It's kind of
of soul. It's kind of a
of my uncle had classified a dark night
of soul. It's kind of a very
of soul. It's kind of a very dark
of my uncle had classified a dark night
of soul. It's kind of a very dark CD.
of soul. It's kind of a very dark CD. I
had
had stumbled
had stumbled came
had stumbled came upon
had stumbled came upon your
had stumbled came upon your teachings
and
and uh
had stumbled came upon your teachings
and uh had
and uh had a
had stumbled came upon your teachings
and uh had a profound
and uh had a profound impact
had stumbled came upon your teachings
and uh had a profound impact on
and uh had a profound impact on my
had stumbled came upon your teachings
and uh had a profound impact on my life
and
and uh
and uh I
and uh I just
and uh I just wanted
and uh I just wanted to
and uh I just wanted to give
and uh I just wanted to give this
and uh I just wanted to give this to
and uh I just wanted to give this to you
guys
guys for
and uh I just wanted to give this to you
guys for whatever
guys for whatever reason.
and uh I just wanted to give this to you
guys for whatever reason. My
guys for whatever reason. My heart
really
really wants
really wants to
really wants to give
really wants to give it
really wants to give it to
really wants to give it to you
really wants to give it to you guys.
>> On
>> On the
really wants to give it to you guys.
>> On the upside.
>> This
>> This is
>> This is on
>> This is on the
>> This is on the upside,
>> This is on the upside, baby.
>> Yeah.
Don't
Don't worry.
Don't worry. Yeah.
Don't worry. Yeah. So,
Don't worry. Yeah. So, thanks
Don't worry. Yeah. So, thanks so
Don't worry. Yeah. So, thanks so much.
Oh,
Oh, good.
Don't worry. Yeah. So, thanks so much.
Oh, good. Upbeat.
Oh, good. Upbeat. Good
Don't worry. Yeah. So, thanks so much.
Oh, good. Upbeat. Good for
Oh, good. Upbeat. Good for you,
Don't worry. Yeah. So, thanks so much.
Oh, good. Upbeat. Good for you, man.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thanks
>> Thank you. Thanks so
>> Thank you. Thanks so much.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thanks so much.
>> Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thanks so much.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank you
>> Thank you. Thanks so much.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank you for
sharing
sharing that.
>> Nothing
>> Nothing wrong
sharing that.
>> Nothing wrong with
>> Nothing wrong with the
sharing that.
>> Nothing wrong with the downside
>> Nothing wrong with the downside of
getting
getting trapped
getting trapped getting
getting trapped getting trapped
getting trapped getting trapped there.
Yeah.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. Uh
>> Hi. Uh I
>> Hi. Uh I just
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted to
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted to say
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted to say first
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted to say first off,
thank
thank you
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted to say first off,
thank you so
thank you so much
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted to say first off,
thank you so much for
thank you so much for your
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted to say first off,
thank you so much for your teachings
thank you so much for your teachings and
for
for very
for very nervous.
for very nervous. Um
for very nervous. Um you
for very nervous. Um you have
for very nervous. Um you have a
for very nervous. Um you have a great
gift
gift of
for very nervous. Um you have a great
gift of words
gift of words and
for very nervous. Um you have a great
gift of words and ideas
gift of words and ideas and
for very nervous. Um you have a great
gift of words and ideas and thank
gift of words and ideas and thank you
for
for staying
for staying and
for staying and sharing
for staying and sharing it
for staying and sharing it with
for staying and sharing it with us.
Okay,
the
the question
the question becomes
um
I
I have
I have uh
I have uh this
I have uh this is
I have uh this is this
I have uh this is this is
I have uh this is this is very
emotional.
>> I
>> I know.
>> I know. I
>> I know. I know.
>> I know. I know. It's
>> I know. I know. It's okay.
>> Um
it's
it's not
it's not even
it's not even an
it's not even an emotional
it's not even an emotional question.
it's not even an emotional question. My
goodness.
goodness. Um
it's not even an emotional question. My
goodness. Um I
goodness. Um I have
it's not even an emotional question. My
goodness. Um I have friends
goodness. Um I have friends and
it's not even an emotional question. My
goodness. Um I have friends and family
who
who are
who are um
who are um who
who are um who very
who are um who very strong
who are um who very strong in
who are um who very strong in their
belief
belief in
who are um who very strong in their
belief in their
belief in their religion.
who are um who very strong in their
belief in their religion. And
belief in their religion. And when
who are um who very strong in their
belief in their religion. And when you
talk
talk to
talk to them,
talk to them, their
talk to them, their religion
talk to them, their religion and
talk to them, their religion and their
beliefs
beliefs are
talk to them, their religion and their
beliefs are so
beliefs are so totally
talk to them, their religion and their
beliefs are so totally different
beliefs are so totally different from
what
what I
what I believe.
>> Yeah.
>> Don't
>> Don't bring
>> Don't bring up
>> Don't bring up religion.
>> Don't bring up religion. Yeah.
>> Not
>> Not about
>> Don't bring up religion. Yeah.
>> Not about the
>> Not about the weather.
>> The
>> The Olympics
>> The Olympics are
>> The Olympics are on
>> The Olympics are on now.
>> The Olympics are on now. You
>> The Olympics are on now. You know,
>> um
>> um my
>> The Olympics are on now. You know,
>> um my question
>> um my question to
>> The Olympics are on now. You know,
>> um my question to you
>> um my question to you is
do
do where
do where so
do where so they
do where so they believe
do where so they believe in
do where so they believe in a
do where so they believe in a heaven
do where so they believe in a heaven and
and
and and
do where so they believe in a heaven and
and and another
and and another thing
do where so they believe in a heaven and
and and another thing that
and and another thing that is
do where so they believe in a heaven and
and and another thing that is beyond
this
this that
this that is
this that is different
this that is different from
this that is different from what
this that is different from what I
this that is different from what I do.
>> Y
>> so
>> so will
>> so will their
>> so will their heaven
>> so will their heaven be
>> so will their heaven be what
>> so will their heaven be what their
intention
intention is
>> so will their heaven be what their
intention is what
intention is what they
>> so will their heaven be what their
intention is what they believe
intention is what they believe and
>> so will their heaven be what their
intention is what they believe and will
it
it be
it be different
it be different from
it be different from what
it be different from what I
it be different from what I believe?
Well,
Well, the
it be different from what I believe?
Well, the only
Well, the only thing
it be different from what I believe?
Well, the only thing I
Well, the only thing I haven't
it be different from what I believe?
Well, the only thing I haven't spent
Well, the only thing I haven't spent a
lot
lot of
lot of time,
lot of time, you
lot of time, you know,
lot of time, you know, but
lot of time, you know, but it's
sufficient
sufficient time
lot of time, you know, but it's
sufficient time that
that
that which
that which you
that which you are
that which you are determines
that which you are determines where
that which you are determines where you
will
will be
that which you are determines where you
will be huh
will be huh by
that which you are determines where you
will be huh by your
will be huh by your commitment,
that which you are determines where you
will be huh by your commitment, by
will be huh by your commitment, by your
practices,
practices, etc.
You
You could
practices, etc.
You could also
You could also in
practices, etc.
You could also in your
You could also in your own
practices, etc.
You could also in your own spiritual
beliefs
beliefs be
beliefs be quite
beliefs be quite liberal
beliefs be quite liberal in
beliefs be quite liberal in which
beliefs be quite liberal in which case
you
you could
beliefs be quite liberal in which case
you could visit
you could visit lots
beliefs be quite liberal in which case
you could visit lots of
you could visit lots of neighborhoods.
That's
That's right.
That's right. That's
That's right. That's correct.
Oh,
>> thank
>> thank you.
>> You
>> You could
>> thank you.
>> You could hang
>> You could hang out
>> thank you.
>> You could hang out in
>> You could hang out in various
neighborhoods.
>> You
>> You could
neighborhoods.
>> You could do
>> You could do it
neighborhoods.
>> You could do it any
>> Well,
>> Well, but
>> Well, but you
>> Well, but you can
>> Well, but you can find
>> Well, but you can find love
>> Well, but you can find love and
forgiveness
forgiveness and
>> Well, but you can find love and
forgiveness and beauty
forgiveness and beauty and
>> Well, but you can find love and
forgiveness and beauty and charm
forgiveness and beauty and charm and
>> so
>> unconditional
>> unconditional love
>> so
>> unconditional love uh
>> unconditional love uh in
>> so
>> unconditional love uh in anything
>> unconditional love uh in anything that
would
would be
would be called
would be called celestial.
would be called celestial. Celestial
itself
itself is
would be called celestial. Celestial
itself is 600
itself is 600 and
would be called celestial. Celestial
itself is 600 and over
itself is 600 and over at
would be called celestial. Celestial
itself is 600 and over at least
itself is 600 and over at least 540
would be called celestial. Celestial
itself is 600 and over at least 540 and
over.
over. So
over. So the
over. So the heavenly
over. So the heavenly realms
over. So the heavenly realms there's
going
going to
over. So the heavenly realms there's
going to be
going to be a
over. So the heavenly realms there's
going to be a certain
going to be a certain similarity,
over. So the heavenly realms there's
going to be a certain similarity, you
know.
>> Yeah.
>> Well,
>> Well, so
>> Well, so they
>> Well, so they seem
>> Well, so they seem very
>> Well, so they seem very integrous.
>> Well, so they seem very integrous. So
Mhm.
>> They
>> They they
>> They they are
>> and
>> and it
>> They they are
>> and it doesn't
>> and it doesn't matter,
>> They they are
>> and it doesn't matter, right?
>> Purity
>> Purity of
>> Purity of devotion
>> Purity of devotion and
>> Purity of devotion and commitment
>> Purity of devotion and commitment and
all
all and
>> Purity of devotion and commitment and
all and that
all and that that
>> Purity of devotion and commitment and
all and that that counts
all and that that counts takes
>> Purity of devotion and commitment and
all and that that counts takes you
places.
>> That's
>> That's what's
places.
>> That's what's important
>> and
>> and that's
>> and that's what's
>> and that's what's important.
>> Marvelous.
>> Yep.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Yep.
>> Thank you so
>> Thank you so much.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know if
>> I don't know if they
>> I don't know if they got
>> I don't know if they got McDonald's
there,
there, but
that's
that's that's
that's that's it.
>> Okay.
>> Dear
>> Dear God,
>> Dear God, do
>> Dear God, do we
>> Dear God, do we give
>> Dear God, do we give thanks
>> Dear God, do we give thanks for
>> Dear God, do we give thanks for thy
>> Dear God, do we give thanks for thy thy
presence,
presence, O
>> Dear God, do we give thanks for thy thy
presence, O Lord?
presence, O Lord? Uh
as
as I
as I always
as I always say
as I always say uh
as I always say uh you
as I always say uh you are
as I always say uh you are God's
as I always say uh you are God's gift
as I always say uh you are God's gift to
me.
me. Uh
as I always say uh you are God's gift to
me. Uh you
me. Uh you are
as I always say uh you are God's gift to
me. Uh you are all
me. Uh you are all my
as I always say uh you are God's gift to
me. Uh you are all my God's
me. Uh you are all my God's gift
as I always say uh you are God's gift to
me. Uh you are all my God's gift to
me. Uh you are all my God's gift to me
and
and I
and I do
and I do uh
and I do uh by
and I do uh by declaration
and I do uh by declaration commit
and I do uh by declaration commit myself
to
to you
and I do uh by declaration commit myself
to you in
to you in return.
and I do uh by declaration commit myself
to you in return. Amen.
>> Amen.
Yeah.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.