My question is, is there a difference between God, or the Creator, and the true self?
And if so, or is there a difference in quality?
The capital S is the radiance of God as experienced, you know, in the human domain, yeah.
So it's sort of like the emanation of God?
Mm-hmm.
And also, when you were talking about earlier that the dilemma of human, of being here is
whether we're going to worship the narcissistic core, the ego, or God.
Yes, that's the dilemma.
Is it the true self that's deciding between those two options?
It's the true self that attracts you to seeking the truth in the first place, yeah.
The ego separates off as an individual, which is not the absolute truth.
So the self is not satisfied with that until you transcend that illusion.
Well, it keeps you on the path.
Yeah, I felt it kind of.
The gravity of God pulls all your little molecules.
Is this for a dozen people here, or what is this?
Yep.
Well, I really appreciate being able to come here.
I've never expressed my gratitude for this.
It's the whole experience, the people here, and it's been a great source of inspiration.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Hello.
I want to thank you also.
I've been coming quite a bit this year, and I want to thank you, Susan,
for your devotion to truth and to Dr. Hawkins.
It's beautiful to see.
And Dr. Hawkins, I want to thank you.
I was introduced to your teachings in about March of last year,
and I had been struggling with being an honest person, being more honest,
and your teachings have given me the courage to be more honest and live more honestly.
And as I've been...
As I've been practicing, this year I recognized this little whining, bawling child within me.
And I've been practicing the Zen thing of just recognizing the childishness when it comes up
and trying not to judge it and allow it to go through its process.
But I have started recently becoming really paranoid when the childishness comes.
And being paranoid that, oh, who saw that, oh, you know, did somebody see me be childish
or is somebody picking up on my childishness?
And how do I handle that paranoia?
Well, you do it like a parent would with a child.
You can parent the child within yourself, see, and say, yes, I hear you and I understand how you see that.
But now we have to give that up and see it as an adult sees it, you know?
So it's the adult in my mind talking to the child?
Yes.
And the child in the mind?
That's so.
They're different archetypes.
The adult, the parent, and the child are different archetypes in the Jungian sense of archetypes.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
I appreciate you both.
Well, I talk about that in weight reduction.
See, in weight reduction, I always say, put a label on your refrigerator that says adults only.
Because the minute you sit down to eat, the child comes.
I saw that in a dignified businessman in a cafeteria.
He sits down, and here's a dignified businessman.
And as he starts to look at his tray, you can see the child come up in him.
The child came up.
It was very comical.
So the adult in you says, I'm going to watch my calories.
The minute you open the refrigerator, the child comes up.
The adult disappears.
After the child has indulged himself, then the parent comes up in you and says, how could you have been so stupid?
You just ate 300 calories, idiot.
So once you see that's the interplay between those archetypes within the unconscious, and make them conscious.
So you put a sign on your refrigerator that says, adults only.
Adults only.
Yes.
First, thank you for all your work.
It's been very helpful.
I mean, so helpful.
Thank you.
My question is about directing attention through visualization of goals, as you pointed out.
Can it be called conscious creation?
That would be pushing it a little.
And any idea of what is the calibration of doing the visualization of goals?
Because what I'm saying is the ego can really...
grasp it like, now I have a way to...
Well, you have to select, you know, you have to look over what the goal is.
That's the time to look at it.
Because once you start giving it energy, then it's going to tend to materialize.
So you have to choose what you think is worth putting the energy in.
Let's say you want to live in a certain kind of house.
What you do is you picture the house and you picture the setting, and you just hold that in mind.
Okay.
And when you do that, it tends to materialize.
So, you know, if you picture yourself being the chief of evil, I guess you'd have to, you know, question yourself,
is that a good thing to hold in mind, you know?
There is no cause of anything as it in this world.
But as I put my attention on it, it tends to...
Materialize, yes.
Because it's depending on context.
See, the idea of cause is within content.
There's a this doing a that causing a that.
There's another way things can happen.
Under the most optimal conditions, the seed tends to flourish, huh?
So you provide the optimal conditions.
And under the optimal conditions, you tend to manifest that which you're envisioning.
So envisioning does have an effect on outcome, but it does not cause an effect.
Thank you.
It plays a part, see?
Things are really propensities.
Propensities.
For propensity to actualize depends on local conditions as well as general conditions, huh?
Thank you.
Hi.
I'm hoping you can explain this.
It seems like every time I come here or I get a new insight or a glimpse of something higher,
I get just something will happen in the external world and I just get flattened.
And is this a coincidence?
How does that work?
Every time you seem to be pulling ahead, you fall behind?
Is that it?
Yes.
This last month was just the whole month.
Well, we all said that periods, you know, you work through some negative karma, you come out into a nice positive place.
That now gives permission for the next stack to come up.
That's why.
Spiritual progression is not a straight line.
So when you're riding over your karma, you're feeling good.
But that now gives, the self takes advantage of that and now brings up the next stack.
Then you feel like you're going down.
You're not actually going down.
You now have the strength to handle the next stack.
It does not feel that way.
You must say, thank you God for allowing me to handle the next stack.
But I have had some experiences out of that.
Where I have prayed and felt something higher just lift me.
The prayer wasn't to change the circumstance.
The prayer was, help me see it differently.
That's right.
And so I think the first time that I ever prayed that way, something did happen.
So you might say, spiritual progression comes in waves.
Where you feel like you're above it and then suddenly that brings up the worst.
I made great progress before I hit hell.
Oh no.
Thank you, I think.
See now you have the strength to handle the worst of all possible.
So it's really God's confirmation of his confidence in your ability.
That you can handle this now.
Before it would have destroyed you.
So there's also another premise.
You're never given more than you can handle.
You feel like you can't.
But it doesn't mean that you can't.
I've heard that before but I didn't know if that was a true statement or just.
Yes, I think it's a true statement.
You're never given more than you can handle.
Yeah, but you think you can.
Right.
You think you can but that's an illusion, you know.
Okay, thank you.
It's because you think you can't that you didn't handle it before.
You say, oh I can't handle that.
That's right.
The person you were at that time couldn't have handled that.
But the person you are now.
With conviction, determination and some spiritual experience under your belt.
You know, can handle it.
So it's a vote of confidence.
Thank you very much.
You can even handle chewing gum after a while.
Dr. Hawkins, first of all I want to thank you very much for your work.
Thank you.
Life has definitely changed for the better.
But now I have a question that.
Probably needs some recontextualization so I'll try to read it out.
In the new book you mention that seriously committed devotees end up with challenges such as.
The seriously committed devotees end up with challenges such as surrendering attachments to people.
Possessions, lifestyles, concepts such as obligation and responsibilities.
Yes.
I feel that in my life I have a responsibility and obligation to my family.
My child and my business.
And I would like for you to help me recontextualize that.
What is your conflict between the two?
I feel like I'm pulled.
How are you pulled? I don't get it.
In business are you tempted to be dishonest?
No, not that.
Are you tempted to provide the best for the people you love?
Sure.
So what is the conflict?
I feel that in business that I can't take decisions.
You can't what?
Clear decisions.
You can't make clear decisions in business.
Do you have a partner or a consultant?
No.
Do you have anybody you confide in?
Well yeah, I have some people I can talk to.
Well you confide in them and of course you see what we do is we often use the arm.
We ask is this in the highest good?
You know, we get invited to speak all kinds of places.
The first thing we do is say, you know, this is integrous, this will serve the highest good.
Then we'll ask, would this work in our life right now?
See, that's something different.
It may be a good thing but you may get that the timing is not right.
Is there a time that you, I think what I'm leading to is, is there a time that you give up everything?
Oh, he's worried about giving up everything.
Yeah.
And his family.
Well, there comes a time when it's not a decision, it's what happens.
I see.
You can raise your family and continue your business by your family.
Yeah.
Your business while your family's growing and then still.
Right.
And then you become spiritual.
There comes a time that it's overwhelming and overpowering.
And you don't have to make a decision, you just can't go there anymore.
Okay.
Thank you.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Hi.
I feel so grateful and blessed to be here.
And I wanted to thank you for making yourself available to all of us.
Thank you.
And my question is, I wonder if you could elaborate a little on how to surrender your
sexuality to God.
I can't hear you.
Surrender your sexuality to God.
She wants to know how you surrender your sexuality to God.
Oh, you mean sexual drive?
Yes.
How can, how do you turn it over to God so it serves that?
You begin to see that it's autonomous, that it's innate to animal life, that you're an
animal.
And you stop resisting it.
Yeah.
You ask God to recontextualize it to you so that you see what it is.
Is it an embrace of love and closeness and expressed in the physical manner?
Is it just desire, craving or lust, you see?
So, is it coming out of the heart or is it coming out of a lower chakra?
So, you try to raise the energy of it as much as you can.
And then you just see that it's innate to biologic life, you see.
If it's a dominant, like an addiction, that's a different problem, a different problem.
Then I would seek like a 12-step program over sexual addiction, that's a different thing.
So, you have to ask yourself, is it within the normal range, you know?
Is it ruling your life?
Is it causing pain and suffering to yourself or others?
It's an addiction when it's causing pain and suffering to yourself and others, you see.
It also has to do with breathing up some of the energy from the lower chakras to higher
chakras.
And maybe some yoga exercises where you picture the energy running up from the lower chakra
up through into the heart, let's say, or up into the third eye, you know, or the crown.
You can do some yoga exercises like that, you see.
I can't see if that's writing or not.
Is that writing?
Yes?
Okay.
Age takes care of it anyway.
Promise?
You're still obsessed with sex at 90, you better call my office.
Hi, Doc, I just wanted to say thank you for answering my last question.
I don't know if it was your answer or being up here, but I was able to see my issue in
a whole new light, so thank you for that.
And my question has to do with the ego and revelation.
I find myself praying for understanding in situations, and sometimes it seems like something
comes in.
Where it's completely changed and I see it in a whole new light.
It's recontextualized, I guess.
And then within a second, less than a second, the ego comes in and says, well, you don't
really know anything that isn't valid and negates this very powerful, I don't know if
answer is the right word, but whatever has just come in.
So what do I do about that?
Oh, you go back to the reflection and continue to reflect on it until it becomes reconfirmed.
If it's true, it becomes reconfirmed.
And it leaves no doubt in the mind and the ego just sort of backs up.
You get a certain understanding, then the ego returns and recaps it the way it was.
So you just keep praying and consciously recall the different way you saw it.
You ask the Holy Spirit for a miracle to recontextualize it so you can see it again in a different
light.
Okay.
Thanks.
If it's true, it'll come back.
It'll come back as a revelation again.
But sometimes they're evanescent in the beginning.
Hello, doctor.
My question is from the parents of a one-week-old baby.
The baby was born a week ago with advanced leukemia.
And the doctor is doing transfusions and they said that if they keep him for at least
a week, he'll recover.
Is that true?
Yes.
For at least a month, they will give him chemotherapy.
But even then, there's not much chance of recovery.
Yes.
So the mother would like to know or...
Should you take heroic measures when they're going to be futile in the end is what you're
asking, right?
Well, whether we could ask through kinesiology if the baby, whose name is Trevor, would
rather stay in the hospital and be subjected to all the medical treatments or whether he
would want to go home with the family.
A baby isn't going to think of that.
That's an adult's kind of thought.
That's what the mother would like to know.
I suppose that's what...
Don't imagine that the baby thinks like an adult.
Well, the soul, the spirit certainly knows.
The soul doesn't think.
Well, the soul is embodied right now.
It's not a thinking body, right?
It's a one-week-old infant.
That's true.
Yeah.
I guess it would be the responsibility of the parents.
I mean, what would the...
I mean, I think that's a good question.
I think that's a good question.
I mean, what would be the will of the entity?
The entity wouldn't have been born and a baby due to die within weeks if it was otherwise,
would it?
No, I guess he wouldn't know.
I guess it already made his choice.
He wouldn't know that.
To be born, to de-die, to undo some kind of karma, and to be reborn again in a different
state, that would be the will of the parents.
I know.
circumstances would be my guess of it let's see we have permission to ask
about it my contextualization of it is correct
resist and wouldn't have chosen that body otherwise it old karma karmically
at all you know what an infant so the decision to bring him home or to leave
him is up strictly up to the mother and the parents it would seem to be so
prognosis is zero correct well it's a little bit more than zero but not what
is point one you gonna subject the child all kinds of pain and discomfort
on the hope on the thin hope that it might survive and if it does it's gonna
be a sick child that survives even yet right it's an ethical problem really
you're saying it's an ethnic problem so what's the will of the entity itself
we just did the best we could get out of it
it's already chosen the best possible karmic circumstances for its own
evolution
the entities
are the best the reality there's everything around us the evolution of
already chosen you just that's the answer I intuit and that I get with you
know so the parents should feel that no the chair you're asking about the
infant I know but the choice right now is bring him home or leave him in the
hospital that's the parents decision I can't help you without that's what I
mean it's up to them yeah you know it's often with serious illness there's such
a decision is made you know in this case you the adults have to make it for the
infant so we already got what best we could about the will of the infant thank
you sometimes people would rather live with whatever the consequences are
they go through what would purportedly be of assistance to it you know thank you
I had grave disease they said we should take out the thyroid I said no they said
we should use radiation and
radiation and I said no and I'm still here it's a difficult question thank you
so much what I think what could be going on is not wanting the weight of the
moral responsibility of making the decision it's a difficult decision to
make
it's titled as I only have arms for you I thought you'd appreciate the cleverness
yes my question is how do different levels above 200 interact with each other
in relationships and is it advantageous to be close to the same calibration or
is it more about alignment karmic roles and the essence yes I was the question
out of the various levels above each other
they interact based on that they don't have to match because very often the
the purpose of the relationship is to resolve the very issues that arise so it
doesn't have to be you don't have to both be you know concordant it can be
quite disparate and beneficial to each other for the very same reason you know
thank you there were the prisons of a serious intellectual it may not be the
best thing to marry another's
serious intellectual I mean never get off the couch you spend the rest of your
life reading a book
I need somebody to jostle you and say you know let's do something else
thank you thank you
actually I can't see that that's actually showing up that's right
yeah thank you I'm very grateful
yeah hi I've discovered through some acute powers of observation
that I'm a clutterer
you can always cut this out of the film yes and well I've missed some great
clutterers in my life yes cause me a lot of pain and I'm in a 12-step group now
there are two anonymous and I've acquired in three or four books and I'm
learning that there's a
clinical aspects to this clinical diagnostic aspects to it that's why I'm
just early in my study of it and I'm improving but I'd like to hear your
comments about it well my best wishes to you I want my money back I think it's
childhood rebellion your mother says put all your toys away okay some of us
neatly line up our toys I put them away and lined them up neatly so they were
all exactly exactly the same and then you could be the other way and forget
when she gets home from the store the toys are still laying there so it's how
much you wanted your parents approval and how much you know support they gave
you in it well my mother wasn't was a clutter as well oh she was a player and
I don't putters badly when I'm
living in the city I'm living in the city I'm living in the city I'm living in
the city I'm living with a woman it's not so bad actually I'm alone now I
think it's a age too okay yeah see because you either choose to please your
mother by being neat or you choose to oppose her so it has to do with the
relationship to authority the power of authority I think you find some
authority and the way to get rid of that is you become the authority okay you
become the authority whose order it is to clear up this mess
okay that makes extra sense fantastic thank you Allisonे
Hi. I want to express my gratitude also because I've been a student for about
five years I've never come up and asked a question because they seem to always be
answered however I'm in a little predicament now and I never thought I'd
make a decision this early on and kept focus only on my mother making
ulation north and south business and you don't show up nobody ever showed up
and said you know take the tym and come here I will tell you something but you
have to keep on going whether or not you age south and it just hands down you
have a bad attitude and you know you know how structure probably pretending now
however I'm in a little predicament now I mean like I've been coming over and said
and she's the youngest, I'm the oldest of five and she's the youngest
and she's very dear to me and it seems harmless
but I just can't get a read on it at all and I don't know if it's a
spiritual trap, and this is her name by the way in case we need it
and I don't know if it's a spiritual trap or if
it's a gift or how do I, do I even assist her?
There's psychic abilities which are emerged spontaneously
clairvoyance and various things may emerge
spontaneously, you know, so sometimes it tends to have a genetic
component, very often the mother is psychic and the daughter has become psychic
and it doesn't mean that it's an evil thing, you see
but you have to keep it within, it's how you contextualize
it and how you hold it, if you say this is what I hear
this is what I hear, they're saying to me, talking about the spirit realm
I would calibrate the energy
that we're just being listened to
I've tried that and I've asked other people to help me do that
I get various responses or answers and I think, you know, for myself I have a
a love for her, so
I was wondering if we could calibrate her
and I just have her name right here
The entity?
Either side, either side
First my sister though
I don't have permission to do that now
Okay, you don't
She would have to be the one to ask me
Okay
So do I just let it unfold?
You don't have to intervene
Okay
Sometimes people become clairvoyant for periods of time
Clairvoyant, yeah, yeah
And then it diminishes
It happened to me
One time, well it was back when they were doing the space shuttle
and they knew they were going to send the teacher up
Yeah
Well I knew that space shuttle was going to blow up
Now who do you tell that you know that this is going to happen
Right
But I knew it just by
Annoying
Just this clear annoyingness that I knew this
and I was so frustrated because there was nothing you could do about it
So, but then I've never had another strong premonition like that ever again
So it's just one of those things that it comes and it goes and you don't know
But it's not, you don't think it's a spiritual trap
like for my family or for myself or for my sister
Is she advising other people in channeling?
With them asking, it's just basically in my family right now
It's not like she's not on a stage somewhere
But she's helping some of my other family members come through some very difficult things
Well if you, you know, by their fruits you shall know them
Yeah
And it seems innocent enough by the fruits that I can see
It's a gift and it calibrates over 200
I guess I'd appreciate the gift
Okay
Not glamorize it, that's all
I really love you both and your teaching
And it's really changed my life so much
Thank you very much
It's very difficult especially when someone's so close to you
Yeah and I'd say it often runs in families also
Very commonly the mother and the daughter become psychic
And they're born with it
Well my mother's
They don't like go to a school to learn it
They just thought
It just comes, right
They just have it, yeah
Right
Well thank you so much
Hi
I want to thank you for this book
This is a, it's difficult to put into words
The way you have been able to dissect an experience
And put it into something that is meaningful for us
And I want to thank you for that
Thank you
I have a question
If I can get it out
In here you talk about the experiencer, observer
Yeah
And that on a practical level one can become non-attached
To the point of being able to observe
Even when they're involved in doing something else
Yes that, yes
My
That's sort of like what we were talking about during the lecture
Mindfulness
You know you're the witness of the witnessing you might say
Right
Yeah
That's consciousness that's doing that
Conscious
Well consciousness is a more diffuse field than witnessing
Consciousness becomes consciously aware that the process of witnessing
Is the phenomenon of witnessing is occurring
And then it tends to identify with consciousness rather than the witnessing
And it sees that witnessing is just an autonomous function of consciousness
And it's not a person that's witnessing
Right
Witnessing is witnessing as a consequence of the quality of consciousness
So you let go identifying with the witness observer
Anyway when you get to that point you're moving along
Letting go identifying with the witness observer
Yeah
Well what I find happens in me
I can do that if I'm not involved in something
But if I then start to work
Intentionality yeah
Or get involved in my work
It's hard to do when you're running a lead
Yeah well
Or dangerous tools or yeah you have to be very careful
But I tend to find myself
Waking up two or three hours later
And remember what I was going to do for that two or three hours
And it's already gone by
In which case I obviously was not detached
And watching what was happening so
Well that's no that's alright when those gaps occur like that
You just stop tracking it
And it just happens you know
You go into autonomous
And you realize a couple of hours have gone by
But that's a pretty free state already
When you're not trying to control it
Yeah
Just letting it happen of its own
Okay alright
Thank you very much
That's moving along already
Well that's thank you
Alright
Hi doctor hi Susan
Recently I was I was waiting for the results of a test that I had taken
And I realized that I had a pretty strong
Preference for the outcome of that test that I wanted
And then I realized that
I really had no clue what was the highest good in terms of the outcome
So I just surrendered it and let it go the way it wanted to go
And I was wondering if you could say a little bit about
When you talk about surrender to God
Does that mean that it's the highest good for us to surrender
Every choice every possibility
Every potential option we face to God
Or are there times when it is in fact
For the highest good for us to have
A strong feeling and preference
And ask for a specific outcome to occur
Well the only outcome
That I think it makes sense to ask for
Is to become aware of God's will in the matter
To ask the Holy Spirit to recontextualize it so that
You know you see the answer for yourself
To reframe it you might say
You can use the arm and ask you know
Which way serves the highest good
What outcome would serve the highest good
You could also surrender trying to control it
Because you don't know what's for the highest good
And to not get it could be for the highest good
You know what I'm saying
So other than using the arm like we do
And asking you know if it's for the highest good
Sometimes what you'll get is that
It doesn't matter either way
Because what counted was your intention in the first place
So which whether you play croquet or tennis
Is irrelevant see
And on you know so called deeper or meatier matters
You know suppose a loved one was in the hospital
Having diagnostic work done to determine whether
You know they were going to be around much longer or not
Is it are we in any way abdicating some responsibility
As a family member let's say
In not praying for their health
Or is it actually in truly surrendering to God
Is it best just to say God
Oh Lord you know what needs to happen
It's not a sin to ask you know
To express your wish in the matter
But you know you want to pray for the highest good
Naturally
So simply to rather than stating a specific preference
Simply to say whatever is in the highest good
Oh Lord that's what my intention is
Well trying to specify in spiritual language
Is called outlining
I'm praying for God's will in this matter
And that I should win you know
Outline is telling God how you want it
Right and God doesn't need any help from us
Well God gets bombarded with advice all day long
What serves the highest good I don't know
We always assume that winning
Winning serves the highest good
Exactly
But not necessarily so
Because there's certain things you can only learn through defeat
Yeah
And therefore defeat means success to the self with a capital S
Right
Even though it's viewed as failure
Like yeah
To the self with a small s
Like the child with leukemia you know
Maybe only a few months of existence this time
Who knows
Could be for the highest good
But that already served it
So if it was just paying off a lifetime
You know why hang around after you've paid off a lifetime
You already paid that one off
What's next
Thank you very much
Thanks Susan
I think the intention
The intensity of your intention
That you ask for God's will in the matter
And you ask for the humility to be grateful and acceptance
Of the expression of that will whatever it might be
Hi teacher
Hi
Hi Susan
I was wondering if you could help me
I was curious about the origins of the third step prayer in AA
If you knew the origins or the authorship of that
Is it biblically based or did Bill do it
Most of this came from the Oxford groups
You know
And Roland had relapsed after he saw Carl Jung
And he went back
Carl Jung said alas and alack
Neither my science nor my art can help you
But from time to time
There has been reported of miraculous recoveries
Of people who threw themselves intently into spiritual groups wholeheartedly
Roland went back downhearted and discouraged
And he discovered the Oxford groups
The Oxford groups I think didn't
Instead of twelve steps I think they only had five or six
But the basic ones of AA
My question was really if the origins of the third step prayer
That they use in Alcoholics Anonymous
Like what
The prayer of the one that's in chapter five
Where it's God I offer myself to thee to build with me
And do with me as I will
That's a way of expressing it
Third step is you surrender yourself to God's will
Right
I was just wondering if you knew who might have
Did Bill write that himself
If you had any idea about that
Isn't that one of the Oxford groups steps
Well I would imagine it originates from there
I was just wondering that specific prayer that's in the big book
You know if that was a biblical based thing or
I don't know
All I know is that it originated primarily from the Oxford groups
And then it was tailored for application to alcoholism
I was curious because you know we use
We use the prayer of Saint Francis
Yeah
In AA but I've never heard it said
Who actually wrote that short third step prayer
Yeah
I can't give you the historical background on it
I don't know
Okay thank you
The third step is really intrinsic to all high spiritual teachings
Throughout history no matter who it is
Whether it's the Buddha or Krishna
She painted it
Oh wow
We have so many talented people here
Thank you
You're welcome
I'm back to the question of the soul
The soul and the highest self
Are the same thing, is that correct?
Higher what?
The soul and the higher self are the same thing
Yes
And the soul has
Lots of people do this type of work
And they say things like well I had to learn that
And my argument is that the soul doesn't have to learn anything
It's nothing
The capitalist soul self doesn't have to learn anything
But the smalls?
But the smalls
The small self
Yes
Has to learn a lot
The small self which is the ego?
Mm-hmm
Okay
What does the ego have to learn?
No I'm serious because I thought
It has to learn humility, reverence for God
Wouldn't that just be surrender?
Surrender of willfulness
Huh?
Isn't that just surrender?
It has to surrender its self-servingness
Its own selfishness
Mm-hmm
And its alignment with the linear and
To align with the non-linear dimension
Yeah
Mm-hmm
Thank you
I think
Through devotion, selfless service, devotion
Goodwill towards all of life
The willingness to be loving no matter what
That doesn't though come from the ego
Doesn't that come from the higher self?
Yes well I'm telling you how to overcome the lower self yes
Yeah
Thank you
When the change occurs
It's quite obvious what the ego, small ego was
Yes
Yeah
Are you still confused?
Well that's okay I'll work on it and see you next year
I know you're a little
Your intention will carry you through don't worry about it
Thank you
It's a very complex subject when you tack it first in your mind you know
Well see I teach a course in miracles at home
And my argument that I make to the people
They will say oh I had to learn that I had to learn that
Oh oh
And what I say to them is that what's really important
Is that you remember who you are
And that's where you put your focus
If you can remember who you or what you are
If you can remember what you are
Then that sort of just takes care of all that other stuff
That the ego likes to think you have to learn and figure out
That's a shortcut yes
It gains momentum with familiarity
So the more I say that the more people will be able to
The more you yourself
Do that
Realize the truth of it
They don't have to tell anybody anymore
You just be that to them
Instructions are good in the beginning
After a while they dissolve into the way you have become
Yes
I got that one
Okay
Gotcha
Thank you
You've become the student
You're not studying out of your students
You are the student
And therefore you bring forth answers to your questions
Yes
You can't do anything about hot flashes can you
I'm having one you couldn't do anything about them
What's your suggestion
Fifty percent of the women out there need help
There's a million cures for hot flashes out there
I haven't found one
Oh you haven't looked hard enough
There are a lot of good answers to hot flashes
You got just one good one
We'd have to sit down in a session you see
Okay
Okay because it's partly a belief system
Everything is physical mental and spiritual
It is a belief system
So you do what hormonally you have to do
You do what physically you have to do
You let go in the belief system that you're subject to them
And you pray at the same time
So if you're doing physical mental and spiritual
The rest is just a matter of patience
It'll disappear
I like that
When you get old and gray they'll be gone
Don't worry
Thank you
I really don't have a question
I've been coming to your lectures for quite a while
And I just wanted to express
That you've been such a wonderful part of my journey
Thank you
I love you
And just express my gratitude
Thank you
I had many questions along the time
Never had enough guts to get up here
But interestingly enough I noticed that eventually
They just lost their importance
Yes that's what happens
It's awesome
As you go to talk to the teacher
And suddenly they dissolve
And you realize it isn't a problem
And that was the answer you were seeking
Yeah
So I just wanted to be here closer to you
Thank you so much
Thank you
Hello
So I work with people in the context of psychotherapy and healing and so forth
So I have my theoretical orientation
Psychology and spirituality
And I feel very much drawn to this
And coming here as well
But they don't 100% kind of match
Especially with calibrations sometimes
What I think might help is
If you'd be willing to calibrate the work that I do
With people
Do you think you can't?
I don't know
We could
But you're talking about multi-faceted
So what facet are you talking about?
Well, oh, hmm, I don't know
I mean can't you just do it as a whole?
As a hole in the wall?
Do it as a hole in the wall
We're calibrated so we're 20
We have to ask permission
Okay
I give permission
We have permission
We're calibrated so we're 20
We're 200
That's what's important
Okay
Hmm
I see
So right
Because I don't calibrate myself
Because of that I just don't care
But I still had wanted to do that
But I see what you're saying
Oh yeah
Well it's not an academic approach
Right
It's a clinical approach
Yeah
So what you want is something probably in the high 300s around there
Uh-huh
Yeah
Wait, what's academic?
I missed that
Is your approach to patients academic?
No, it's primarily spiritual
But I present myself
It's clinical and spiritual
Yeah
So
But I mean I use the Jungian stuff
It's eclectic I dare say
Composite
Using the dirty word
Yeah, yeah
You know that
Yeah
In other words it's not strict medical, medical practice
No, I call
Because that's the 400s
I call it consciousness psychotherapy
Okay
And I pick that because that's my sense is really whatever they're coming for and however we work
If we don't create some greater awareness
Oh, I see
We're just moving things around
Yeah, yeah
We're not really doing a permanent
So you're trying to recontextualize things
Yeah
Yeah, okay
Right
So anyway
Oh, that's very good, very good
It's sophisticated
Uh-huh
Anyway, thank you very much
Yep
What counts is that it's over 200
That's okay
Yeah
That's good
It's integrous, so
That's a wide latitude
Uh-huh
It's beautiful
I thought I'd given it to you for once now
Oh, that's gorgeous
It's actually
It's the most precious thing
Yeah
So it goes to you
Thank you
Hi, Docs
Good to see you again
All right
I love you both very much
And I'm very grateful to be here
I've been in the area two weeks
And it's been pretty amazing
I moved here from Maui
Oh, you did?
I left
So if you guys are still gonna go
I know people there
I have nice condos on the beach
So let me know
My question has to do with intention and karma
A lot of the mindset of, you know
Whatever you intend
And hold it in mind
And all of that stuff
And it seems like to a certain point
That's great
You know, it's like
I've been holding certain things in mind for years
And, you know, it just seems like
It's a karmic thing
Like it hasn't come
It's not gonna come
Or maybe I'm just not waiting long enough
Or maybe I'm not
You know, what's the relationship?
I mean, I've watched the intention video several times
And I, you know, I'm pretty much
You're trying to make something happen with intention
Yeah
Trying to control it
Because you're complaining that it hasn't happened
So therefore you're trying to control it and make it happen
If you let go of wanting to make it happen
Intention is not a tool
To try to force karmic
Cosmic forces, you know what I mean?
Intention is only an influence
It's a contextual field
Then within that
Propensities will manifest or not manifest
So you're responsible for the effort
But not the result
Yes?
Yes
So
So whatever the result is, it's fine
Yes
For it not to happen, that's fine
Okay
It could be the death of you
Well, I've already said
Oh Lord, let me be present
You know, assassination
Thank you God
So
It gets rid of that one
I guess it's
I guess the
Well, there's a lot of the intentionality stuff around abundance and this
Around what?
Abundance
You know
Are you good?
If you hold this and that and that
I mean, I'm not attached to the abundance thing
But it wouldn't mind having a little improvement
Like a job right now would be great
Just because I want to, you know, live up to my responsibilities
Which are still my debts
What are you frustrated about?
I don't get it
You want a job?
Well, yes, I'd like a job
I'm almost there
You know, the newspaper here has about six pages of jobs
Yeah, every day
You can walk down any street and have a job within ten minutes flat
So not having a job is not really something you need to pray about
Just need something to go get
No, no, no
I know that will come
One will come that will suffice
Yeah, when you walk around the corner
You gotta walk around the corner to get a job
I've been driving all over to get a job
Every single store in Sedona has a sign of wanting
Yeah
So how can you not get a job?
It must take some real
Well, it's
Adopt for this
I mean, I'm looking
I'm, I'm
No, it's
I don't want just any job
Oh, any job
I want a job that's gonna provide for me
I need a job that's gonna provide for me
Okay
You know, the job will come
I'm not
It'll come
Alright, so that's not really the problem
No, I'm just trying to
Something more long-term you've been holding in mind, right?
Um, I guess it's
I'm just trying to understand the, the role that karma plays in intention
If one holds an intention, does that intention come about because of your karma?
Because of the karmic pattern that you hold
Well, it won't manifest
If there's some karmic blockage
No, it won't manifest
Okay
So, okay
So, basically
So, you're responsible for the effort, not the result
Right
You're still trying to control the result
Is what you're telling me over and over
I've been doing this and what I wanted hasn't happened yet
Okay
So, I'm still attached to the outcome
Why don't you give up what it is you want to happen
And just use a decent amount of effort and what comes up, comes up
And so, it's let go of the attachment to the outcome
Yeah
Okay
So
That's just holding it up
I mean, pretty much
What I hold in mind or intend is oneness with God
And, and then other things in the world, you know, things you'd like, like maybe your
relationship
Well, why don't you just hold your your happiness in mind
And then whatever it takes to make you happy
We'll follow them
Instead of trying to outline how that happiness should come about
A certain salary
A certain location
A certain neighborhood
A certain car
A certain person
If I was God, I'd just get fatigued, you know
What do you want?
You want to be happy or what?
Oh yeah, I want to be happy
Why don't you just hold that in mind
Why don't you just hold thatonia
just hold that
that you feel satisfied, fulfilled, and happy.
Without even, like, well, without visualizing, without...
Visualizing is adding another true sense worth.
It's not going to change.
Yeah, but you talked about visualizing on that lit.
Yes, yes.
So what's, I'm not understanding that.
Visualize happiness.
Well, potentiality, see?
Visualizing increases the potentiality of a likelihood.
You know, quantum mechanics.
Right.
All right.
Holding a certain thing in mind,
tends to statistically increase the likelihood of that happening.
It doesn't control it, because it's still non...
I can't think of the right mathematical term.
It's not non-deterministic.
You're looking at prayer and intention, all that is deterministic.
All you're influencing is likelihoods.
You're increasing the likelihood of a certain realm manifesting,
but you're not going to control it or make it happen.
I would be more general.
You know, you're being too specific.
Why don't you picture yourself?
Being satisfied, happy, and fulfilled.
And then let God fill in how that's to come about,
because you obviously don't know, or you wouldn't be complaining.
That's perfect.
Of course.
Okay.
I think, so just basically visualize happiness.
There, feel.
What do you want for your life?
I mean, don't you know?
Well, that's always been a hard thing.
You don't know that you want to be happy?
Oh, my God.
No, no, no, no.
No, no.
I know I want to be happy.
Oh.
You haven't made that point at all.
It's the details.
It's the...
What are you getting at?
I want this, this, and this to be happy.
Well, I guess it's like...
You're outlining.
Well, it's kind of that thing like you say,
if I get this, then I'll be happy kind of thing.
Right.
So you have to elevate your level of consciousness and the whole thing.
And be...
Just go for the generic happy.
You ask God, you want to fulfill God's will for you.
I ask that all the time.
Ask God for your knowledge of his will for me and the power to carry it out, see?
And to fulfill my potential and to serve God and myself and mankind all at the same time.
The power to carry it out.
And then go out and around the corner and get a job.
I'll bring broccoli.
I'm going to bring broccoli to the next lecture.
What does broccoli say all the time, Susie?
Go to work.
Get a job.
Thank you.
There is one right around the corner.
There you go.
All right.
Thank you.
One time I took a job.
You know, I used to have trouble.
In the summertime, I'd have to find a short-term job, see?
And by fall, they had me in executive training for 20th Century Fox.
And I was looking for a summer job.
Hopefully, that'll be the case for me soon.
Thank you.
That's what I'm saying.
I started out as an usher, so you don't know.
You would be saying, oh, I don't want to work as an usher.
But by the end of the summer, I was in executive training for 20th Century Fox.
We sold more buttered popcorn than any theater in the chain.
Thank you.
Today has been fabulous.
My question is also on intentionality.
I experienced about three weeks ago, I was a little bit late to work,
and I have quite a long commute.
And as I was driving, it just came to me to put out an intention that I'm there on time, safe,
and without any interference, because a lot of times there's trucks.
And I got, it's an hour and 15 minutes to work,
so I got to a place where all of a sudden the cars were backed up.
And at that moment, there was an old farm road to the right.
I just took it.
I had no idea where it was going.
And I followed it, and I came around a corner,
and there were a lot of other cars.
And there was a wave to me from the school where I was,
and I just followed it in.
There were fatalities in the accident,
and one of the clerks was calling all the rooms
to make sure the teachers were there.
And I said, you won't believe this,
but I put out an intention, not knowing there was an accident,
and all these things happened.
And she said, Sue,
I prayed this morning that I would see God at work somewhere on this campus,
and it's already happened to you.
And I realized that intentionality,
intentionality, intentionality, intentionality, intentionality, intentionality, intentionality, intentionality.
Intention.
In that moment, it seemed that I didn't have that intention,
that there was some power.
When we do have an intention,
is it ours or is it Spirit with a capital S leading us to our next greater good,
knowing where that is?
It doesn't matter.
So over 200 when we have the etheric brain,
it doesn't, it's just accept whatever comes?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Because it's automatically going to align with the higher power field.
And if it's permissible to happen,
the likelihood will increase that it happens.
If it's not permissible,
then it won't have any effect.
Okay.
Not having it happen is okay, too.
Right.
See?
Well, that would be, I just had never,
it just came to me, this stunning beauty of this moment,
that I could not have accounted for.
What's the intention, the likelihood?
And that's mathematically so, also, quantum mechanics.
Thank you.
Next lecture we have is on, is the miraculous real.
In November?
Yeah, the next one.
December.
Oh, in December.
I'm not coming to that.
I'm coming to November.
Well, you can't have a miracle then.
Until next year.
I'll be back for the miracle.
Thank you so much.
You already had a miracle.
I have miracles every day.
Yeah, miracles, see, people don't recognize them.
But that's for the miraculous,
where your intention brings about the manifestation
of a different likelihood.
It was stunning for me.
That moment was stunning.
I just, I was in awe, because when I was praying,
it was, just get me to daub on time.
Yes.
Not the thought.
And this was special.
Okay.
Thank you.
Great.
Yes.
I've struggled with a lot of things.
I've struggled with a lot of recurrent depression
and anxiety throughout this life.
And I've successfully treated the symptoms of it
on physical and mental levels.
Good, good.
But I'm wondering, in order to resolve it,
do I need to, is it necessary to get to a karmic origin
of it in some specific way?
It may, I'm not talking about, now karma is like,
an experience that reduplicates,
that's a different kind.
Karmically, you could say the evolution
of your consciousness is such that it gets tripped up
at certain points for reasons you don't know yet.
But you ask God, you know, to reveal to you,
you know, what, is there a greater meaning to this
than I'm supposed to be seeing?
And then it either reveals itself or it doesn't.
See, there's no timing in these things.
You're going to be depressed for eight or ten years.
Suddenly it goes away.
And in that same instant that it goes away,
you also get the karmic experience of it,
the karmic background of it, yeah?
So you can't tell because it isn't a linear sequence
that makes sense necessarily.
You know, you might be 60 years old,
and one day you're sitting out in the hammock
and all of a sudden you say,
oh, God, I see that.
Out of the blue.
Mysterious in a way.
The non-linear, see?
The linear mind tries to make sense of the non-linear,
you can't.
Retrospectively, you can say,
aha, but anticipatorily,
you can't really predict it.
Doesn't unravel in any kind of predictable, logical way.
Yeah?
Thanks.
I'm glad you got rid of the symptoms,
so that's sane and logical.
Hi, Susan.
Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
I'm telling you, I'm compelled to tell you
just how giddy I am
about this because I was so excited
when I first read your first book.
I was like, I mean,
although I had to have a dictionary on one side
and the book on the other.
You're smart.
But you have changed my life profoundly.
And I mean, it's been so exciting.
I mean, and speaking of surrendering
and such like that,
I have worked very hard on those and it works.
I have, I don't have no stress.
I have, I mean, I will live my life.
And I'm just, my family thinks I'm .
But I haven't.
Flippy doodle, eh?
Yeah, exactly.
But I wanted to tell you how much,
what an impact you've had on me.
I mean, you coming back from your journey
and bringing with you all this insight
and all this valuable information
is just unbelievable.
I mean, I.
If I've got just another second,
how I heard about you,
because I want to,
I want to give,
let the audience hear how I really,
but I happened to be mowing the lawn.
I came in the house and there was Wayne Dyer on TV.
And the only thing I heard out of his mouth was,
we all have an appointment with infinity.
Don't we all?
And he says,
why don't you make an appointment with infinity today?
And I'm telling you.
So instead of being stressful and dying,
I figured I was just going to make an appointment
with infinity today and surrender all that stuff
and then just be,
just enjoy my life.
Just go.
Yeah, just go.
Go with the flow.
Zingo.
Anyway, I hope you can see the excitement in me
because I love you, man.
And you just go on your way.
Thank you, man.
Thank you.
I love you, man.
And you get the spiritual.
When you get the spiritual wheel going,
I can't really go.
That's a tough act to follow.
Thank you.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins, for everything.
My question is coming from the eight-year-old
that lives inside of me.
It's very trivial compared to everybody else's question.
I'm wondering,
when you first moved to Sedona,
you calibrated it, I'm sure, the energy.
And has it changed?
I haven't calibrated it.
You haven't?
No.
Why not?
I don't know.
Nobody ever asked me to.
Nobody asked you to?
No.
Why?
Do you think it's changed?
I don't know.
I've been here seven years.
I see a lot of changes,
but I don't feel the energy shifting that much.
Yeah, apparently.
And maybe it hasn't.
Well, maybe it hasn't.
I don't know if it's even pertinent.
We have permission to ask about Sedona.
No.
My eight-year-old child is very disappointed.
Well, it's because you're a child.
It's a child.
I'm very disappointed.
Well, it's because spiritual groups
have such a powerful energy
Right.
that, you know,
you'd have to differentiate, you know?
Right.
Like a group that's aligned with enlightenment,
you know?
It's a very powerful group.
Yeah.
So, would you include them
as part or parcel of,
are they residents of your,
you know,
so you,
I don't know how we'd diagnose it,
you know?
Well, thank you.
Anyway,
it's a place that is charitable
to spiritually oriented people.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Good word.
We never did child races,
I don't know,
you know,
there was the vortexes and all of that.
I don't know either.
We never got around to it.
Thank you.
I don't think we should do that,
at all.
I've been a member
of a 12 step group
for many years.
And,
which has helped me
with my work
sobriety alcohol being the problem at the time yeah and what's happened since
then is I've developed chronic pain and I'm frightened about taking medication
for it can it ever be justified or is it a spiritually or it depends what you
think for it to relieve the pain yeah what I mean the what is very important
yeah what is the question well we're about just the pain you mean it's
physical pain not not as far as I know
it's been diagnosed as problems in the pelvic area following them a difficult
obstetric career a difficult time with cesarean sections and things like that
you
so she's having physical pain in the pelvic area yeah which her doctors want
to put on some sort of medication oh well you're afraid you're afraid of
losing your sobriety exactly all right so it depends on what the pain
medication is some pain medications are addictive have an addictive potential
and others don't if you're sick with ibuprofen aspirin things like that they
have no addictive propensity if you get into coding the addict and you could get
to like in the coding yes so you could try acupuncture
acupuncture acupuncture is excellent for things like that great and so
acupuncture plus non-addictive pain relievers self-hypnosis is a variety I
was that I had good experience with acupuncture frankly with a variety of
pretty bad ones too okay thank you he had a collapse vertebrae so I mean that's
all I had a number of illnesses they responded very well I can puncture so
I'm just telling you that it's safe so non-addictive analgesics plus acupuncture
maybe self hypnosis there's a variety of techniques you know okay thank you
alternate alternative medicine yeah okay thank you very much herbs alternative
medicine I just have a question regarding spirituality and love for a
woman and kids does it get is it is it possible to get to a point where you can
You cannot love a woman, have a family, to pursue your own spirituality.
I'm not hearing him.
He's asking about love of a woman. Is it possible to get to a point where you don't?
You cannot love a woman and be spiritual at the same time.
No, no, they're not antithetical at all.
The more you love, the more you can love.
So you love God, you love your fellow beings, you love life.
The more you can love, the more you do love.
The more conditional it becomes.
So loving that starts life in all of its expressions is the way you end up, by removing the blocks to life.
Okay, then I guess the second part would be why all of the avatars were not married, for example.
Like Christ and Buddha and so on.
Maybe they didn't like women.
I don't know.
They were born, don't forget, in different eras.
And also different parts of the world.
So the spiritual tradition of the spiritual teacher is one thing in India, it's another thing in Buddhism, it's another thing in the Hebrew culture.
But Jesus Christ was born incarnated, you know, was already, the presence of divinity was very strong at a very young age, you know.
And so why each one occurred in that way is hard to say.
It would take some research, you know.
I'd need half an hour and some meditative time to ask the reason for that.
Thank you.
They were the only volunteers around, maybe, you know.
Somebody else said, what?
Come into life and not get married and have kids?
The heck with that.
Hello.
Hello, Susan.
I came for the first time.
I came because I had friends who had been here and I've heard about you and I looked at some books.
I don't think I read one completely.
I looked at a tape and I listened to an audio cassette.
But I had no idea what the presence of the teacher.
I have three points.
There's blue in two of them.
I know.
But.
You can laugh if you like.
Yeah.
But that the presence of the teacher would bring.
That's your potential.
That's you.
First to realize.
Yeah, yeah.
That all is as well.
There is a peace that passes the understanding.
And I don't have to know why.
And when the mind clears up.
When it's able to think clearly.
It's okay.
You can't think right now.
Well.
He's thinking but he can't say it.
I can't say it.
It's just when the mind clear, thinks clearly, it is such a joy.
To do one thing and then the next and then the next.
And to have the timelessness.
You wish every human could feel that at least.
And the last gift was that it's.
That one could die and it's perfectly okay.
And I didn't want to die in the last month without coming back and saying thank you.
It isn't dying.
It's leaving the ego to the old self.
Right.
Yeah.
It's not dying.
It's being reborn.
Yes.
So.
Don't have to grieve it.
Right.
And it.
And it's place is something of greater dimension, you know.
Right.
And with it comes joy.
And an overwhelming joy.
And sometimes people lose control.
Right.
And sometimes people can't stop crying for months.
Yes.
It's hard to think about it without getting emotional.
I didn't think this would happen because I thought I had cried enough.
It's common in monasteries.
Kind of common in spiritual communities.
And sometimes people cry for a couple of years.
I don't want that.
No.
You can cry for 20 minutes.
But tears of joy.
Yes.
You know what?
The spiritual, the saints tell you that they went through periods where they cried for
some years.
And then in spiritual communities it's common.
Right.
And I remember going through the phase.
I would be in an airport.
And a couple would be sitting there waiting for a plane.
And they would look at each other.
And I got the love.
And I would begin to cry.
Any exposure to love I would cry.
A mother with her puppy, you know.
Right.
And any kind of expression of love.
And I would start to cry.
Cry.
Dr. Hawkins is like
the life makes perfect sense
everything that happened
up to now
however sad or everything
it makes perfect sense
it falls into place
and there are no words to thank you
very good you just did
do you have a question?
I have no idea what it was
a long time ago
one lady asked what do you do
and you said get a box of Kleenex
I would have some if I didn't spill coffee
in my car
let me see if I can remember
the question
in the picture too
in the process
of surrendering
all things
to God's will
my life has changed
in great measure
a lot of things have been surrendered
but in that process
very linear decisions come up
and
I surrender the decisions
as completely as possible
and want
divine will
above all else
and I try to use self-kinesiology
and I can't get accurate responses
and I've tried using other people
and the answer that we usually get is that
karmically I have to figure it out for myself
laughter
you're on your own baby
that's tough
and so I guess my question is about discernment
how do you know
when what you feel in your gut
is for the highest good
you don't have to worry about
being the highest good all the time
that's only a way of phrasing the question
don't worry about it
you see
spiritual commitment already takes care of it
if you say to God
I trust in your guidance
and I ask for the expression of your will
to the best of my capacity
to understand
and then let it go
it's his problem
that's what God's sort of there for
don't blow your stuff on me
laughter
I'm sorry about that
you see you do the best thing you can
and then you let go of it
that's all
I said to a guy one time
I said look either we blow up or we don't
and he says you're right
I took care of it
we didn't worry about it after that
laughter
you let go of it in an instant
you say either it's going to be that way or not that way
in that instant you surrender it to God
and then you forget about it
whatever happens is whatever happens
okay
thank you
thank you so much
and then you say dear God thank you for showing me
what a very bad mistake is like
laughter
I have to remind you guys
because you sit here and then you go to pieces
and then I have to remind you
laughter
oh God
oh geez
I would have to do this right
bypass her
she's just taking a photo
laughter
he's with her
oh he's with her
I thought she was the lady we just talked to
laughter
I thought we just talked to her
oh God
laughter
okay he has a question
you end up being non-linear
thank you
thank you doctor
thank you so much
all this work that you've done
and I'm just being introduced to it
this is
just thank you
thank you very much
laughter
I have a question
is it speak next to the telephone
yeah come on up here
don't be afraid of these
they can't hear you
laughter
okay
and it's a simple question
but I don't know if it's been answered or asked before
you know people smile
you know children
adults
and there's polite smiles
and then there's sometimes there's smiles
a lot of times actually
there's smiles that you feel that go right to the heart
can that be calibrated
can that smile
sure
do you know what is
do you know what the level is
has it been calibrated
well it depends on the person
and the occasion
you know a smile like you said means different things in different circumstances
so
some people smile just because they're glad to be alive
and they have an upbeat attitude
but is that
there is
I mean for myself I know I absolutely feel it
in my heart
either coming to me or even leaving me
when I give smiles out
can that be calibrated then I guess a lot of times
and I guess on my behalf
I'm not sure what you mean but
smiling is a way of showing your appreciation for life
and your joy at your own existence
that you want to share with others
so a smile lights up other people
and lights up the world
so you're being of service to others you see
I guess what I was thinking about
you know the dog
a love of the dog
and then when he's wagging his tail
it's a little bit more
at 500
it does a smile
from the heart
like that
oh yes
yes
yeah of course it would sure
okay
yep
you know I can hear wagging your tail
you know
so
okay
so it's over 500
we don't have a tail
so we have to smile
you know a dog can't smile
but he's got a tail
we purr a lot though
thank you
and once again thank you so much
for sharing
sharing your
sharing yourself
with the
world
is a gift to the world
just
yeah
hi
what's up doc
that's a good one
give me a slug of that pepsi
they should give me free pepsi right
for giving it air time
I was wondering if you can
I have been doing work
on specialness
on the need to be special
lately
and I was hoping
you could provide some feedback
with that
because I have
well it's just
the specialness is
you know
feeling unique
and
giving the ego
a boost
the ego
hates to be
nothing
and nobody
and if you learn
to
to delight
in being
nothing
and nobody
then you've got it beat
anonymity
I learned
the value
of being nobody
right
in my early life
thanks
in boot camp
you had to run around
a mile
in the dark
10 below zero
in January
in Great Lakes
so they would
you know
it's still dark out
5 am
10 below zero
and I'm not the athletic
and joyful type
so I'd wait
until the whole crowd
was around
and they had
metal lockers
so I would open
this locker behind me
and I would sneak
into the locker
and close the door
and I would hear them
coming back
into the room
you know
and I would
emerge
and mix
with the crowd
again
I got away
with that
for a month
and one day
the guy in charge
caught me
so I had to do
two laps around
I'm probably
going to be
another crier
so that's ok
yeah
what
I said
I'm probably
going to be
another crier
oh I didn't say that
no
I just wanted
to say
thank you
for
all of your love
and support
and how much
it means
to me
and
I had a question
and I don't know
if I can
get it out
but I'll try it
I've been here
almost two years
and
I must have
brought a lot
of karma
everybody's
got a lot
of karma
baby
but
you know
I've been here
almost two years
and
but
you know
in the spiritual
community
stuff gets
at me
as if
I'm the cause
of everything
and
you're
what's your position
with it
well
I'm the minister
over the
all right
so you have
an authoritative
position
you know
that authority
always gets blamed
I know that
that's your job
to take the blame
I
you're right
yeah
I guess the thing is
I think I'm doing
a really good job
of it
and I'm like
I'm surrendering
and I'm surrendering
and I'm handling
it really well
and then sometimes
just some little thing
somebody will say
or do
and it's like
this whole other
bunch of stuff
comes up
yeah
oh yeah
uh huh
yeah but you're
on the front line
I know
yeah you're
on the front line
yeah
all right
you know
well you've already
reached perfections
you don't have to
worry about that
which is a good thing
pleasing everybody
else
that's something
so I'm just
all I guess
I was wanting
is
you know
it's like
it's kind of
it's kind of weird
it's like
they're in this space
actually right now
of evaluating
whether they want
to give me
another contract
or not
which is
you know
what I know
is it's all
surrendered
and it's all
okay
but what I end up
doing
sometimes
and
and where I want
to get unhooked
and where I feel
like it's my
stuff
is when they start
giving me stuff
about if I just
be different
here
or if I just be
a little different
there
or if I just
this
and
and I start
getting
hooked into it
trying to
do it
I realize
I'm getting pulled off
and I have to
come back
so
you mean
trying to comply
with criticism
with the board
yeah
what do they know
they think
they know a lot
oh
okay
and
and they're basically
you know
I know
it's all
okay
I guess
all I wanted to do
is I wanted
to come up
and say
you know
it's all surrendered
and I know
it's hard to take though
but it's hard to take
yeah
because despite
yourself
the ego's involved
and what people think
of you
and their attitude
and all
so you have to decide
what is my role
what am I really
supposed to be doing
am I supposed
to share
that which I learned
in my
ministerial education
am I supposed
to share myself
to the
best perfection
that I'm able
to express it
am I supposed
to be helpful
to energize
a spiritual community
by leadership
and by your role
and if that doesn't
please them
nobody can please them
ain't nobody
gonna please them
right
yeah
because people
have fixed ideas
maybe of what
they want
you know
and if you don't
fit that
fix in their head
you know
but then
that
the place
I get
caught
I guess
yeah
where I really
get in there
is it's like
okay
my responsibility
is to be
their
spiritual
teacher
take picture
of yourself
as a leader
right
and let them
learn on their own
okay
that sounds
good
okay
it's very
difficult
to
it's very
difficult
for me
to be spiritual
all the time
when you
when you're
I mean
you're dealing
in an office
and you're dealing
with workers
with people
and multi personalities
and they're all
dealing with all
their stuff
right
so all you can do
is say
here's what I expect
from you
and the rest
of the stuff
you're gonna have
to deal with
on your own
but it's very
difficult with a
minister
because you're
dealing with a board
with all the other
stuff that goes
along with it
and you're dealing
with clergy
to
you know
to comply
with everybody
you can't
clean it up
I know
but I think
as a focus
of spiritual
energy
that's
you serve
a very good job
as a focus
of spiritual
energy
and whether
the people
agree or not
with the style
or things you say
or something
there
that's relevant
you know
you can discuss
it with them
and
they're not
gonna do better
than that
they're not
gonna do better
than that
and if it comes
from the heart
that's what's important
right
so if
genuineness
and commitment
isn't enough
they better
go hire
somebody
out there
yeah
they're gonna
have the same
problems
with anybody
out there
yeah
because it's
very hard
to find
somebody who has
you know
the energy
that pulls
a congregation
together
you know
I think
they're very joyful
the ones that I've witnessed
so I don't know
what anybody's complaint
could be
okay
so just
keep doing
what I'm doing
is what I'm hearing
you just do
the best you can
and try to please people
and come to a compromise
and say I understand
what you mean
and
we'll look at it
and discuss it
you know
see how we can
please you
and you know
we have to be
out of here
at what
five
ten
okay
we'll make it
hi
hello Susan
I just recently
just
discovered in myself
almost a fear of
a fear of love
actually
yes what
a fear of love
yeah
oh god
that's a smart guy
it sounds funny
I never thought
you know
something like that
would come up
but
like
let's say I'm
sitting around
almost blissful
with friends
like very beautiful
situation
suddenly
just
even two days ago
I walked into the bathroom
and all of a sudden
I saw this
almost like
it wasn't even me
just this fear thought
of like
wow
you shouldn't be feeling
all that
or experiencing that
almost like a pull back
from that
like
I don't know
like I
like it was
I shouldn't be allowed
to experience
that
it doesn't seem
like something
that would ever
come up within myself
but it
just happens to be there
well that's
you know
that's being judgmental
and you have to
you know
surrender judgmentalism
to god
you don't know
what you're
karmically
entitled to
by now
I wouldn't worry about it
besides
all those spiritual things
tend to be
evanescent
as you're walking along
you can go from
a state of high joy
and then suddenly
into a
like a depression
you know
yeah
then you say
well the depression
is okay
but not the high joy
you know
you can't say it
that way either
it's
that's why spiritual work
is difficult
because it's not
a smooth line
yeah
it's not linear
it's not really
explicable
in terms of reason
and
you know
causality
it's just sort of
on quirks
of its own
so
you ask for the grace
to ride with it
I pray for the wisdom
and the
tolerance
to
you know
experience through
in my own
spiritual evolution
that's all you're
asking for
is what you're
actually entitled to
by virtue
of your existence
excellent
thank you
it's uneven
there's periods
of doubt
periods of great
expansion
periods of elation
periods of despair
yeah
it's a rocky road
it's so hard
to be
anybody makes it
it's true
you have to have
a cheerleader
you know
that keeps you going
through the thick
and the thin
yep
thank you
good coach
hello
I want to
thank you
and with love
and gratitude
for your being
grateful
for being here
I have two questions
about the etheric brain
yes
when the
etheric brain
gets connected
is that when we commit
unto the oh lord
is that
the connection
no
the etheric brain
according to our research
emerges
at consciousness
level 200
it just emerges
but that's the field
it emerges
it now becomes
a radiance
an energy
I liken it
best to
electricity
going through a wire
creates a magnetic
field around it
so like our
field as a person
the etheric
yes
in other words
it's an energy body
it's not an anatomical body
right
an energy body
and
the etheric body
is powerful enough
that
like a
like a magnetic field
if you put a wire
in a magnetic field
electricity
will start to run
and that's how you get
the neuronal action
that is the correct
explanation
is this
aha
well
this is for the new book
neurophysiology
huh
so
would you say
that
when
when we are in the field
it's like we're
like with the quantum
we're a particle
when we're below
like 200
like in quantum physics
I'm not that familiar
with the analogy
but we are
below 200
the instinctual brain
dominates
above 200
you develop
an etheric body
and
the capacity
to see things
differently
is that
energized
by faith
and love
yes indeed
oh very much so
oh yes
that's the
okay
thank you
that's very much so
hello Dr. Higgins
yes
hello Susan
thank you very much
for your material
today
it was a lot of
for me
so I especially appreciate
the video
so I can go watch it again
to
learn more of those practices
uh
but my inner
little child
I was raised by
uh
two mothers
one which was
both of them very
100% Irish
and both of them
very tough disciplinarians
uh
believed in physical
strong physical punishment
I'm not getting
what he said
he was raised by
two mothers
both of them
strict discipline
yeah
okay
and uh
strong physical punishment
okay yeah
okay
and and then my mother
was also good
good then
at shame
and abandonment
yeah
and including
pulling my older sister away
so I could really be shamed
yeah
now um
I mean I've
dealt with that
in lots of ways
but it's all coming up again
in my life now
in a big way
and I'm attracting people
like that into my life
and my child
really wants to know
directly from you
and what's the question
he's um
it seems like people
are coming into his life
recently with those
same shame
and disciplinarian
uh
they're coming into his life
abused child
and abused
and so his child in him
wants to deal with this
but he doesn't know
how to quite
how to deal with it
people come into his life
that are similar
to the
the abusive parents
he had
I don't get the question
no
uh
that have
recently
a bunch of people
abused child
children
very severely abused children
they were abused children
yes
oh they were
all right
so what is the question
what do I do about myself
to take care of myself
so that I can be balanced
in dealing with them
and also deal with myself
how does the fact
that they were an abused child
interfere with your relationship
with them
are these relatives
no no
these people
that work
I'm working with them
because since they're abused
I go try to help them
I mean I
you know
don't help
they didn't hire you
as a therapist
did they
see there's
what do you mean by help them
there's fixers
and non-fixers
I'm a fixer
yeah
don't
fix them
so
how would you fix them
what am I
a kid
screaming like crazy
you have to just
back off
and say
that's their karma
don't fix it
how would you
how would you help them with it
share your experience
strength and hope
yeah
and then also
send them to alternative techniques
of getting
different kinds of
uh
alternative therapy
well you can certainly
find techniques
that you've heard of
that have been beneficial
to others
but I think
other than carrying the message
I wouldn't try to carry
the patient
I would carry the message
that is up to them
that you've heard
that people who did
so and so
have found great benefit
I would share my experience
strength and hope
but I wouldn't try
to carry them
now what do I do
is that my own inner child
is screaming
for
that this abuse
is around
and he
and he's screaming
like crazy
screaming about what
uh
abuse
abusive parents
he's a fix it
he wants to fix him
he wants to fit
help
it's a complex
uh
you need to
sit down
talk with a psychotherapist
about this
I can't do it right
right now
in this amount of time
in front of the audience
I really have to know more
about it
the fact that you
have suffered
damage
from a certain thing
have you found
how to recover
from that damage
I thought I had
I thought mostly I had
all right
so you share with these people
what you've discovered
it's up to them
isn't that correct
I thought so
I think that'd be
the end of your task
wouldn't it
you're not
you haven't been hired
as their therapist
have you
no
so your function
don't overplay
your function
is to share
the communication
strength
hope
and faith
in what you've experienced
with others
and then you leave
the result up to God
see
yeah
you
you carry the message
but not the person
but I've heard
that people
have had this experience
I've had that experience
this is what
I found helpful
other people
found helpful
and you encourage them
to take whatever steps
they need
to recover
from the
you know
narcissistic injury
etc
okay
yeah
you have to protect
that child
within you too
yeah
you encourage them
by your own success
of the thing
okay
that's all you gotta do
thank you
so Stephanie
I'm watching
eight minutes
just finish up
seven minutes
we've got a strike
in seven minutes
all right
yes
no question
just
just wanna thank you
what
I have no question
oh
no question
she just wants to
to get your energy
oh
hi thanks
thank you
yes
okay
give me a hand
God bless you
thank you
I have a question
about karma
karma
yeah
and
is karma
real
and part of our truth
or is it something
we fall back on
because we don't
understand
the truth
of reality
is karma real
yeah
you're here
aren't you
yeah
but
I guess
that's very real
I
believe
I believe
in the essence
otherwise you wouldn't have it
yes
other wise
the whole universe
is nothing but
chance
right
accidental chance
that's mechanistic reductionism
materialism
that everything is just
a chemical accident
I
I thought I heard you saying
in one of your audio visuals
that karma
karma doesn't exist
I think I heard that somewhere
I thought you were saying
that
I didn't say that
I'm not sure
maybe
that's why I'm trying to clarify
yeah i guess i i want to do any kind of past life recall you'll find the karma
funny does exist yeah i think part of my ego doesn't really want to buy into
and feel well you don't have to believe in it just forget it let god worry about it
yeah okay that's cool that's easy enough cool karma yeah
thank you yeah
oh yes i just want to thank you for everything thank you so much
hold on yes
thank you and we have one last question thank you yes no we're done no one more okay
and then we we finished up just on time by golly that's intention right
all right
that's intention for real
thank you so much uh my question is um what do you do when you're attacked by demons and you know it
what you do when you're attacked by demons is in your in what specific way are you attacked by them
um it's a feeling or what well i can get pain severe pain um or i can get severe emotional
disturbance yes um and i know it's not
me okay so you can reject them uh you can pray uh for the one in you that is attracting
demons you can forgive yourself for having played with them yeah you played with demons you just
yeah you play with demons uh that's why people tell people don't there's certain avenues don't
even go there don't even go there bible says don't go there don't go there because you can't
play with them they are been around longer than you and you say oh i'm not going to play with them
well, I can go in there and be untouched.
I never saw anybody go in there and be untouched.
Even the Buddha was beset, correct?
Okay.
So whatever demons you've set up over all your lifetimes
will now come to seek you out for that weakness.
All right, so you intuit what is the weakness they're looking at
and pray for the one in you that's attracting them
and pray for God to repel them.
And there are many esoteric prayers
and various things like that you can do to repel them, yeah?
Okay.
Thank you very much.
I tell people, do not play with demons.
Do not play with demons.
Why should you not play with demons?
Because they're demonic.
That's why.
They like to torture people.
Dear God, we give thanks for this
and very grateful for this meeting of all of us together.
What a joyful group of people.
They are...
They're like playmates.
And we get great joy out of each other's company.
And we pray that we may be of service to thee, O Lord, as a group.
Not only as individuals, but as a group.
We ask for the knowledge of thy will for us
and the power to carry it out.
Glory be to thee, O Lord.
Amen.
Thank you so much.
It was joyful, as usual.
And they ask me such tough questions.
It's not fair.