So
heal.
I not see anything.
>> I am not here yet.
>> You love it anyway.
>> No, dude. No, no, no.
I'll see you later.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Okay. There now.
>> Where are we going? Oh, yes.
>> Okay, I'm here now.
>> Oh, I am here.
>> God bless you.
God bless you, everyone.
>> That's a nice shirt. I'm going to steal
that shirt.
>> How are you guys? God bless you all. God
bless you.
>> Hello, Dr.
>> Thank you.
Thank you so much.
>> It's for eternity. Closing
to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
>> Bless you.
>> Yes.
Ah,
God bless you all.
>> Hi.
>> Thank you.
>> Some know why I touch them and some
don't.
Hi sweetheart.
>> Thank you.
>> God bless you.
>> Look at this Christmas hat. Is there
something else?
Ah. Hi.
We'll see you tomorrow morning.
>> Yes.
>> Yes, ma'am.
>> Sorry.
>> Do you ever eat there?
>> Yes.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah.
>> Ah, look who's here now.
Oh, the ladies and the gentlemen.
There's the gentleman here. The ladies,
you get a second one.
You got a second one, too.
>> Look here, John. Yeah.
Gloria and Excelsius Dio.
To thee, O Lord, do we surrender our
lives this day and ever more.
Anybody disagree?
What was that noise I heard? A sucking
sound.
Okay, so we can sit down. Tell me how
many are new people are there here
today. New
I can't see. Not many.
Okay. Cuz we may reverse the way we
usually do it in that case. Those brakes
are very bright. My eyes I don't know. I
can't see the thing. Are they supposed
to be that bright?
>> Help. Help. Are they supposed to be that
bright?
Help. Help. Help. Help.
>> They are.
>> Okay.
>> I can't see anything anyway. No.
>> What's there to see? Just
Everybody you love. That's all.
Well, uh there's not many new people.
So,
generally generally we start from
scratch. We start with the scale and and
just briefly sketch how it all came
about for people that are new. Those who
have been here many times, they've heard
it. So, I thought we'll start with where
we usually end up, which is the subject
of today.
Well, it was because some people like to
see the lectures on videotape and
therefore we start from the beginning
and uh but they'll have to get an
earlier one. All right. So, we're going
to start
we're going to start I didn't uh
>> quue you into what I was going to do.
I'm going to start with the last three.
We're going to start with the end
the last three which I can't read. Oh
well anyway.
Okay.
No other. So we're going to start with
um
here it is on the list here. Here. Here.
We're going to start with
97.
We'll do 97, 98, and 99. Okay.
So, we've done almost 100 slides. Whoa.
Boy. Oh, boy.
All right. Today's lecture is is on the
miraculous.
the miraculous and uh
it's a very interesting subject and I
wish I'd had more time to spend on it.
I'm going to spend more time in the
future
uh because today's world we don't think
of the miraculous as a reality. We think
of it as something that happened
centuries ago and it was so u incredibly
unusual that it changed the course of
history and
so people don't think of the miraculous
in terms of everyday life their own life
in that of others unless you're doing a
course of miracles in which case you are
thinking about it
and asking for a miracle all the time.
The first miracle is that you're asking
for a miracle, you already got one.
So the miraculous
is
usually held in mind somewhere in the
past. And of course when it did occur in
the past, it did change human history.
The great miracles of uh of the past
totally changed the history of the
world, especially the history of the
western world. And so therefore, when we
re review just how that came about,
we found out that people under 200 do
not experience the miraculous, do not
witness it, and do not experience it.
And you notice all the skeptics who
calibrate below 200, poo poo the
miraculous,
of course, because they've never
witnessed it, never experienced it, is
not a reality. So it sounds like a
dreaming dreamer's fantasy.
The miraculous, as we'll find out, is
relatively common place.
Almost everybody in this room has
already experienced uh the miraculous
resist. Almost everybody in this room,
in fact, everybody in this room has
boy.
I didn't want one of them to sneak in.
Thank you, Lord.
We're safe from the unholy.
ungodly.
Well, therefore, it has something to do
with karmic merit.
And people will say, well, yes, but what
about people who are uh deep in the pits
of of hell and horror, negativity
and experienced a transformative
miracle.
They didn't experience the miracle when
they were below 200. What happened is
they were way below 200 and in dis in
despair they they prayed fervently to
God. Oh God please help me. They
instantly jumped above 200 and when you
and therefore they were over 200 when
they experienced the miraculous.
I had to clear that up about the emperor
Constantine
uh which we'll get to. Of course, the
miracle that he experienced in the year
changed all of human history forever.
Quite a So, the miraculous then can be
have a stunning impact. So, we'll put
that back on and I'll start with
uh I just wanted us to be aware that the
miraculous is common place but
unobserved and not recognized. H
we we always talk at the in these uh
lectures about
transcending the the level of the
intellect which sees everything in terms
of causality of this causing it that
with a time dimension and
the energies of force.
The other downside of that is that gives
you the same picture of God. God started
someplace and is going to end someplace
and God is experiencing time etc. The
miraculous occurs outside of time and it
is not a consequence of causality.
There isn't a this causing a that.
All things see all things
happen or see all phenomena occur as a
consequence of potentiality becoming
actuality as in the process is one of
emergence
because you picture things you witness
them sequentially.
You think that sequence is out in the
universe. There is no sequence in the
universe.
There's no sequence in the universe.
The sequence is in the observer. The
phenomena are not occurring
sequentially. The witnessing is
occurring sequentially as as the thing
emerges like like this. You do a stop
stop stop stop and you think those are
all stages
but it's actually all just one action.
All right?
Because everything
emerges from potentiality into
actuality.
It does so when conditions are
appropriate.
So the seed does not
the seed does not become a seedling in
the middle of winter. So because the
local conditions however its potential
lays there all winter long. The
potential of some
um what do they call them? Century
plants may lay underground for a hundred
years and then suddenly the right
conditions it emerges. So the
potentiality is is within and it waits
to be actualized and local conditions
are favorable.
One of the local conditions that is very
very powerful because of the Heisenberg
principle is prayer and supplication.
In this particular lifetime from the
lowest pits of hell
to suddenly the infinite presence
all came about as a consequence of a
profound supplication.
If there is a God, I ask him to help me.
And then a 180
from the endless pits of endless
suffering and agony, foreverness of
hell, suddenly the dazzling brilliance
of the source of existence itself shone
forth. The ice
transformed everything to this day.
So the miraculous is not the not the
result of causation
as as therefore there's no person
causing a miracle.
There's no person that does miracles.
People advertise that they're miracle
workers.
You should always calibrate them.
The miraculous we've observed all around
the world and myself many a time. It's
always a phenomena that
you don't even get until it's happened.
You witness it
because of a certain energy and because
of the supplication on the part of the
person
and because of karmic appropriateness.
The phenomena that would seem
scientifically unlikely happen and they
happen relatively often not not
infrequent but ra relatively frequent.
So the mechanics of it is that the
potentiality is there. Uh karmic
propensity is one of the local
conditions. The en prevailing energy
field is one of the local conditions and
prayer. Praying of course increases
the power of the context which is uh the
spiritual energy. So in the presence of
a high spiritual energy,
a likelihood becomes an actuality.
It's like the apple is waiting to fall
from the tree. And when a certain energy
walks by the tree, it drops.
But that which walked by the tree
doesn't cause the apple to drop. You
understand? It just precipitates a
potentiality
by virtue of the power of the energy.
From the viewpoint of linear causality,
it's of course not explicable
and therefore
even all the most famous miracles of
history are poo pooed by a certain
percentage of the population routinely.
The difficulty is because the cynic and
the skeptic etc. um does not understand
context and doesn't understand the
nonlinear.
The pedestrian mind is only concerned
with the linear, provable, factual,
material and thinks in terms of a
limited causality. It doesn't understand
context
because the same one statement in this
context is true in this context is
false. Therefore, context is profoundly
important and you ignore it at your own
peril.
the unexpected occurrence from the
viewpoint of linear causality.
Now, the mind believes that and because
it believes that it it misses about 99%
of the miraculous that's occurring
around them. Let's see. The average mind
misses about 99% resist. Misses 100%
resist.
Misses 99%.
And miraculous is happening all around
you and and you're not even noticing it.
and you're busy saying you don't believe
in miracles and they're all happening
all around you in one way or another.
Uh
so it isn't that they're rare,
it's that people are not uh conscious of
them as a present reality or potential
reality seeing rarity due to limitation
of the observer. It isn't that miracles
are rare. It's that people who are
capable of witnessing them are rare.
Even when it's in front of their eye,
they can't see it. You know, I used to
watch that sometimes and it was just
delirious.
And it's in fact a lot of people will go
temporarily unconscious.
And u there was a period of my time when
the miraculous was was continuous and
rather dazzling. And I would watch a
person witnessing it and they would
actually
bl uh go unconscious for a split second
and not not see it. They actually
couldn't see it. It was really strange.
Yeah.
Uh
so if you believe that miracles are rare
and not pass possible and only happen in
the presence of angels and great saints,
but you probably won't witness any.
Well, you won't be aware that you're
witnessing them. All right?
They are also facilitated by favorable
karmic propensity
as is the witnessing of them. uh the
apple doesn't fall from the tree until
it's reached a certain state of
ripeness.
So the whole purpose of spiritual
evolution is to transcend from the Lord
to the higher levels of consciousness.
And as you do, the miraculous becomes
more and more frequent. And I don't even
see the miraculous anymore.
I stopped seeing them years ago
because they weren't the miraculous.
there just every day.
It's the way the world is. The way the
world is is once you see emergence of
potentiality into actuality.
Uh
once you see that everything is
happening autonomously of its own then
you no longer differentiate the
miraculous from the non-miraculous
because for this hand to move up in the
air and try to express something
nonverbally
is already out. You know it's happening
on its own. I didn't ask it to do it. I
didn't write it up ahead of time. Now,
at soon so time, I will have the right
hand go to this way. The fingers will go
out. You see, it all happens
autonomously and spontaneously.
So, you might say all of life in all of
its aspects is on one level of reality
the miraculous
human existence itself. you might say.
Of course, the greatest miracles of all
time, the now we'll get into historical
miracles.
Um because the average person can't
witness
doesn't observe that which is
extraordinary because it's not within
their realm of reality.
They're only observed when they become
very very
uh pronounced
and
for the audience for the participants
then Jesus 33 miracles which we've asked
before we'll ask him again make sure he
didn't change his mind in the meantime
we have permission to ask this
uh the 33 documented miracles of Jesus
were indeed miraculous exist.
So they did indeed exist. And why were
they so dramatic?
Because otherwise people wouldn't get
it. Unless you do something, unless
something occurs dramatically, the
witness doesn't get it. The fact that
the bus that would have killed you just
veered off one split second before
doesn't seem you know it seems lucky. So
the average mind dismisses the
miraculous as lucky fortuitous
and doesn't see that it is the operation
of the potentiality becoming actual when
appropriate conditions. Huh. The 33
miracles then are of course the average
person is un uh you know unaware of
enlightened or advanced states
and in today's world that's extremely
so. It was so in the days of Jesus as
well. And therefore
the presence of divinity within a
teacher
uh was not recognized until they did
something theatrical.
See, you can be enlightened and be
speaking great truths that will change
mankind. But it isn't until you turn
water into wine that every that people
say, "Oh,
so the 33 miracles were of course uh
dramatic and called attention to his
divinity and and therefore he became
famous Because
the average unsophisticated mind doesn't
understand what the presence of God
within a teacher means. And so they wait
for something spectacular.
When something spectacular occurs, then
they are convinced. Either that or they
get spooked out.
They get spooked.
Yeah.
So we won't
have these flowers turn into birds and
fl away this morning because people
might think that we have something up
our sleeve.
There's, you know, the debunkers. I love
debunkers. You see them on TV and they
can think up the most incredible
engineering mechanical explanations for
anything that would happen. So it
doesn't any good do any good for these
to turn into birds because the debunker
will get on TV program within a month or
two and show you how he can manipulate
these lights and make these look like
birds. So you you know the the need to
to uh to deny the nonlinear. It's so
interesting.
uh in our own time and of course
throughout history the stigmata
have been a subject of discussion
and query and the Vatican cat you know
cataloges them and they go through quite
a whole thing to make sure it's a
stigmata
um stigmata that were recently endorsed
by the let's do the stigmata that were
re recently endorsed by the Vatican They
were indeed stigmata resist. Yes, the
church is extremely careful
and uh goes through a great deal of
effort
uh to doc document the stigmata. So how
does stigmata come about? They come
about by virtue of intense adoration
and identification.
Intense identification and adoration of
Jesus Christ can bring bleeding
nail marks in your hand. And they do
indeed bleed.
They are indeed there.
They are not artificial
because the identification is so
powerful and strong and psychossematic
conditions
uh appropriate and with karmic principle
with certain karmic
uh entitlement the these stigmata
actually
the stigmata are very often used as a s
a sign of saintthood and the stigmata
tend to occur I would think from about
570 and up. You don't have to get up
there. You know the stigmata occur from
570 and up. Yes. Which is the level of
saintthood. So the Catholic Church is
right.
Uh
they're right. The stigmata occurred at
about that level of consciousness which
is exactly the same level as saintthood.
And therefore consciousness celebration
we document that it is actual truthful
and the church is correct.
This canonized the saints were these
were canonized in 2006
and the those that were canonized by the
pope in 2006
were indeed saints resist.
So we just want to document that there
is you saintthood is a reality. Stigmata
are sometimes a consequence of that
expression of that reality
that uh you can validate it
scientifically.
And the great care that the Vatican puts
into canonizing saints is because they
do not want to take any chance of of a
error.
How did these things come about? Well,
Young had a con had an interesting
concept called synthesia.
That phenomena
will tend to pull together into what I
would call an energy field
that is not accidental. That is, it's
the composite of all all that has been
added to it over the centuries.
Synesthesia
uh has to do with time and location.
People think it's lucky that that they
were all just there at that time. I
would have drowned, but there was a
sailboat and there was two people on it.
I would have drowned, but but there was
this sailboat there and I got saved.
So, well, the sailboat had the whole sea
to be on. Why did why was it within a
couple hundred feet of a drowning
sailor?
So that has to do with young would call
it synchronicity,
synthesia, synchronicity that those
things are not by accident. Of course,
first we're students of energy fields
and we see that an energy field
uh then tends to dominate the phenomena
within that energy field.
One of the most u was Jesus Christ
changed all of history and and and the
miracles helped establish uh who he
really was.
So his miracles changed the course of
history. Of course
that was 2006 years ago.
AD.
A ad a okay 2006 years ago
in the year 312 now the history of the
Roman Empire is extremely interesting
and its correlation with religious
history is extremely interesting the
emperor Constantine
I forget what year he was born but
anyway
uh Constantine was an emperor
and uh Constantine for some reason
sought
sought direction from God. He was facing
a great enemy, I think his
brother-in-law with a great army for the
control of Rome. And um Constantine
calibrated at 195 in those days.
When confronted with uh dealing with
this issue, Constantine suddenly went
into a state of devotion
and he prayed to God for a sign.
He was at 195.
But then when he prayed to God
for a sign, he entreated God with great
sincerity.
he automatically jumped to 245.
So it wasn't
his prior state. It was in his new state
that summoned forth
a sign. So Constantine
when he looked up in the sky, he saw a
light in the form of a cross and it was
a sign from God.
So he put together the two Greek.
He put together the letters kai and row
which became the symbol which was put on
the shields of of his
soldiers and the message was that this
would give him great power and
Constantine then defeated
his brother-in-law
and became the great emperor
of all time.
So Constantine
uh declared Christianity to be the
official church of the Roman Empire.
At the same time he was tolerant of
non-Christian churches and did not
banish them or anything but he
established that Christianity
and of course the Roman Empire is what
became Western civilization. All of
Europe, all of Europe, America, the
entire Western world emerged out of that
decision of Constantine.
Quite a powerful miracle.
And Constantine did indeed see a
miraculous sign from God in the sky.
Resist.
He did indeed.
Well, the debunkers hate miracles. So,
if you look look up Constantine and the
internet, what do you call that machine
the system there? Uh, a debunker will
get in there and say, well, he claimed
that. However,
uh skeptics affirmed that then they
named three planets were in such an
alignment that that's really what he saw
except it was daylight. You don't see
planets and daylights.
So, but that you know it's just amazing
how the mind stretches to try and cancel
any recognition of the reality of
divinity or nonlinear reality.
these three planets. He saw the three
planets and that's what he saw. Wasn't a
miracle at all.
Except they forget it was daytime when
he saw them. So
anyway, they did put that insignia on
the Roman shield. It's very famous one
with a loop around. And the Roman
legions were indeed formidable. The
Roman legions were indeed informable.
Formidable. the most powerful country in
the world then which has come down to
the present time is America
and America is in consequence then of
the Judo Christian legacy and really the
decision of Constantine in the year 312.
Uh
the other other miracles are as I say
they're not recognized and They don't
seem to occur until you become aware
that they are not only a possibility but
a probability
and eventually you realize that it is a
certainty.
People who take a course do the course
of miracles are far more aware of the
presence of the miraculous and how to
how what to do in order to let's say
facilitate the likelihood of their
emergence. How many people here have
done the course? Yeah. Okay. So, you all
know what we're talking about.
And the likelihood then is that when you
can take when you change how you see a
thing, then you see it how it really is.
And how it really is is miraculous.
You don't see the miraculous until you
start to become aware of it. And
therefore, you don't ask to have a
certain thing done. you you ask for a
change of how you're seeing it. And when
you see it differently, you see that it
wasn't that way to begin with. So the
person who was bad doesn't suddenly
become nice. You just see the intrinsic
um
niceness of the basic personality that
was obscured by some passing ripple.
The clinical experience of a course of
miracle. So,
you know, we started groups here in
Sedona. In fact, I was the one that
brought brought it to Sedona. They
didn't have the books or anything and we
started it at Unity Church and they gave
a sermon and
we had the company deliver the books and
uh I knew uh the printer of it and I
knew Helen and Bill and
and Steinbergs and um so we had it and I
remember we had over 100 people jammed
up jammed the church that day and we
ended up with I think four groups or six
groups I forget family uh out of the
original people and those groups went
for many years and some are still going.
Some of the groups we started then and
we had Jerry Jolski come and lectured to
us at uh what was the old theater there.
We had a full house 300 people filled up
the movie theater standing room only to
see Jerry and the whole story of the
miraculous and of course his book Love
is living without fear. So
the miraculous has now become uh much
you know well known amongst spiritually
oriented people. Uh to the lay people in
the world it is still a ooh ooh ooh kind
of a thing and uh spooky spooky and
scary. Yeah. Uh or very unlikely they
say a miracle. Yeah. Sure. Uhhuh.
As I say, I've watched I get to some of
the miraculous that occurred around me
and I would watch people witness it. It
was more fun watching the people witness
it than the miraculous experience.
So the miraculous is a consequence of
level of consciousness.
You don't see it below level 200. And as
your consciousness goes higher and
higher, especially in the 500s, in the
400s, you're still dominated
considerably by reason. But reason would
tell you if the miraculous has been
documented by many witnesses throughout
history, it's very, very, you know, it's
probably a likelihood. But that would
still be reason.
But as you get into the 500s, you get
into faith and love and that tends to
precipitate a deeper understanding and
awareness and you begin to experience
the presence of the miraculous as a na
as a natural.
So the miraculous is both experienced
and witnessed consequent to a level of
consciousness.
So a person who's below 200, how in the
world did they get above?
Well, by intention. by intention
because
uh
because the emperor Constantine was at
195.
He was at 195. So how come a great
miracle occurred at 195? As I explained,
he was at 195. Then he said, "Oh God, I
I prayed to you for a sign."
Bang. People have been praying for a
sign ever since.
But you'll when you examine it, you'll
find that's attempted control. You're
trying to outline. Telling God what to
do is called outlining. And u you tell
God not only what you want to happen,
but how and when. My sister-in-law will
recover from her gallb attack and her
daughter will marry that nice guy and he
will quit smoking marijuana. You know,
most of us, the average mind gives God a
great many directions and help
giving God advice what needs to be done.
Uh, you know, and of course, world
things, the wars and all, both sides are
praying to God to win the war. How's
that in World War II? How's that? Here
we are all praying to win the war and
all the Germans are praying to win the
war.
You know what I mean?
Oh golly. Germany was very heavily both
Lutheran and Catholic.
The Germans are praying for victory and
the Americans are praying for victory.
And here's both sides praying for
victory. And I used to think I wonder
how that's all going to come out. Both
sides are winning praying for victory.
We'll get to the cities later. U 12step
groups. Of course, uh,
the miraculous is common place in every
day.
There's a skeptic that wrote
something very negative about the
miraculous and
consciousness, all kind of thing.
And uh I will say to the person like
that, do you know that there's like I
don't know how many three million
members of Alcoholics Anonymous right
now? There's over a million recovered
alcoholics walking all over the globe.
Let's see. There's over a million. You
don't have to get up all the time.
There's over a million recovered
alcoholics.
Two million,
one and a half million. One and 3/4
million. That's close enough.
a million and a half hopeless victims of
a progressive deteriorating disease that
eventually causes brain damage and
hallucinations and convulsions
and you die with a wet brain. I remember
at autopsy we take off the top of the
skull
with a little saw and and you could
smell alcohol in the whole room from the
person's brain.
a hopeless progressive condition lead to
progressive insanity, grandm convulsions
and finally get put away with a wet
brain. A completely hopeless condition.
There was never hardly ever very just
once in a while in history it would
occur and it would occur only if the
person threw themsel devotedly into some
kind of a spiritual organization.
And that's what Carl Young told Roland
who was a hopeless alcoholic and Roland
saw Carl Young and Young
uh he was in pretty good shape. Came
back to America.
But then Roland got drunk again and came
back to see Carl Young.
And young, thank God for his honesty,
said, "Alas, there are some things that
neither my neither my art, my art or my
science can help you.
Neither my art nor science.
However, it has occurred occasionally
throughout history. It has been recorded
that people have recovered from this
grave and hopeless aggressive disease
who threw themselves wholeheartedly into
religious or spiritual programs.
And Roland, who was an atheist at the
time, I suppose, went back dejectedly,
but he sought out the Oxford groups. in
the Oxford groups
followed certain steps which are the
basic steps of AA or the 12step recovery
group and Roland recovered and that then
it got transmitted to EIE
and EIE told Bill
Wilson.
Bill Wilson was a skeptic and an atheist
and he said, "Okay, I haven't got any
time for all that God business. Go
away." But things got worse and he was
in and out of town's hospital in New
York City and his wife Lois was in
despair. The doctor said prepare for his
death.
Well, then Bill did listen to him and
changed his mind. And uh
he took a great leap and Bill prayed to
God and then the miraculous happened.
The drum lit up.
>> Resist.
That was a miracle that changed the life
of millions of people worldwide. and the
12step groups out of them emerged all
the other 12step groups, recovery groups
and group therapy itself came out of uh
AA. So that's one of the most powerful
spiritual organizations in our culture
because it's silent. It's invisible
and it merely influences all of society
by virtue of its energy and not by
virtue of buildings or edififices
or rich and famous people. You don't see
any TV ads for AA. You don't see any
billboards
and uh because of anonymity at the level
of press etc. You don't see them getting
up and uh
saying I'm so and so.
So the very famous 12step groups then so
I have to say to the skeptic who in the
skeptics dictionary who poo faith how do
you explain the recovery of one and a
half million people
alive today all given up as hopeless and
incurable. So the power of faith then is
sufficient to precipitate the
miraculous. It doesn't cause it.
Powerful spiritual energy is context.
And within that context, then likelihood
becomes actuality.
If it's karmically propitious,
karmically propitious.
So lower mind at calibrated low. This is
the skeptic's mind at 155.
Uh has an intrinsic limitation.
very intrinsic limitation
and therefore there's no point in being
angry at them or anything. It's just
that they cannot see it. There are some
unfortunates who are born with a
limitation. And the fifth fifth chapter
of the book Alcoholics Anonymous
states there are those unfortunates who
apparently have been born with an
incapacity to be honest with themsel and
others. They cannot help it. They were
born that way.
Let's see.
They were born that way. They just Yes.
They came into this lifetime at a very
low energy calibration level and they're
here more or less in the uh kindergarten
and just learning the very first things
about being honest and truthful and
trying to be nice to people. There are
people who to whom that is quite
foreign.
Okay. So
the skeptic then we can expect if we
talk about miracles, you're going to
trot out every skeptic and they will get
very busy and create marvelous machines
that can imitate a miracle and by if you
can do it by machinery therefore the
reality couldn't have happened because
you can see I can make it look like it.
And you see them on TV every once in a
while. They all have the same attitude.
I can tell the minute they come on the
screen
where their head is at and what they're
about. You know, they put together
elaborate laboratory equipment and
lighting and electronic controls and all
and make it sizzle like well, you see, I
can make it sizzle like that. So, it
couldn't, you know, so it could it
couldn't have sizzled in the sky. It's
all right. So, that's the limitation of
lower mind.
unfortunates who were born that way.
They're still at an early level of
evolution really and they deserve
sympathy. Sympathy rather than to revile
them. Okay.
Oh,
miraculous is consequent to the level of
consciousness of the observer
of the observer. So the w the phenomena
are witnessed. They've happened all you
know as I say in our travels they happen
many a time. We're in some foreign
country with some group that we're
speaking with or for and um they will
bring somebody over and sit them right
across from the table from you and uh
I'm wondering why did they bring that
person then? And then all of a sudden I
see
and I say, "Oh,
I see what it was." Now
I because I don't think in terms of
miracles. I just the phenomena that are
occurring are all miraculous. So I don't
separate it out that this is miraculous
and that is not. You see, but apparently
in that energy with the right karmic
preparation, the group brings her here
and now this side of her brain which was
numb and couldn't work works and
everything. It's just uh it's consequent
to the level of consciousness of the
observer.
The miraculous is a constant creation
and evolution. creation as evolution.
The presence of of creation is
continuously present and the form that
the form that it takes the form the
creation takes is evolutionary from the
viewpoint of the witness.
The witness thinks that it's out there
as evolutionary.
So divinity,
divinity when it expresses itself in
this dimension
becomes
evolutionary.
Of course, we used to always start out
these lectures recapitulating the
evolution of consciousness to give it
just an overall context so that it
becomes obvious. But it's quite obvious
that
consciousness itself and its expression
is evolutionary from lower to higher and
higher forms.
And finally you get the preffrontal
cortex.
Then you're in trouble.
Now you can think. God help the world.
Now
you can think. So when you give an
animal when you give some the
intelligent human who calibrates below
200 you give them a prefrontal cortex
gray matter with which to think
he's now a very dangerous animal
energized by wickedness and now with the
knowhow of how to put it into nuclear
physics or whatever form it can be put
in. So
miraculous the miraculous is constant.
So if creation then if creation takes
the form of evolution
evolution is the constant emergence of
potentiality
into actuality.
Therefore
all of creation is continuously
miraculous.
You live as a consequence of the
miraculous and the presence of the
miraculous.
And at a certain level of consciousness,
you become aware that the miraculous is
a constant. It's not an infrequent. It's
not rare. It's not something you
separate from real life. It is real
life.
To watch this emerge.
We've got a beautiful bulb of some kind
of flower bulb at home. And every day I
look at it and every day it gets bigger
and bigger and bigger and now it's just
splendiferous.
What's the name of that crazy big bulb
we got?
>> Yeah. Well, it's just splendifferous.
It goes from just a dump dopey looking
bulb and then every day gets more
interesting and then finally it's just
wow
Christmas time.
I just think they're just wonderful.
So you see the miraculous of the
Amorillis. Amarillis.
Amarillis, my honey.
That's my Amorelas.
I fell in love with Amorillis. I just
had to sing that beautiful flower song.
You are so pretty in the window.
If I was God, I'd wear an amilis over my
ear and every day
it gets bigger and bigger. They say,
"All right, so the miraculous is an
intrinsic quality. It's statistical
likelihood is what hangs people up. And
the other thing that holds them up is
being literal and linear.
Um,
people in this room would not even be
alive today were it not for the
miraculous in their lives. You just
everyone here is alive because of the
miraculous in your lives. You may think
of some stunning incident. It sounds
good to your grandmother, but
it's the car that almost hit you in the
road and didn't.
I'll just witness
I'm going to recall a memory of the You
don't have to jump up that. But I'm
holding in mind was miraculous. Yes. All
right. I was going down 89A. I used to
go over the Mingus Mountain for about 12
years cuz there was a girl's recovery
house there
and they didn't have any doctors. So I
went over.
Come to think of it,
my not going over the cliff that time
was miraculous. Was just my god, I came
so close 5,000 ft down.
It's just a torturous road. It was snow
on it. And you come around the side and
anyway, I didn't go inside.
Well, I forgot what I was talking about
now.
>> H
>> and personally. All right. So, the
miraculous is a phenomena that's
witnessed and not caused.
So, there's nobody Nobody who causes
miracles.
Therefore, it's doesn't make sense to
run down to South America to see the God
man who performs miracles all the time.
They go down there by the thousands
because there is no person
uh causing a miracle. It they're
phenomena that happen of their own. It's
impersonal.
So healings are really a lot of times we
think healings are spontaneous but
they're really the consequence of your
level of consciousness.
They're the consequence of the effect of
prayer which we can get into later. So
the miraculous is abused by promoters
for fame and money and India the holy
men of India the classic ones they have
it down so expert
the skeptics caught is what I'm thinking
about they finally caught it on
photograph how he was performing the
miracle
I guess it was all over the internet
anyway the holy men of India are experts
many of them are are experts at
simulating the miraculous
and don't underrate the expertise.
It's been perfected over thousands of
years. And when you read meet a real
uh miracle performing holy man, uh
it's entrancing. You're sure you're sure
you just saw the real thing, you know?
youth jury. You just saw the real thing.
Uh very great expertise. No person is
performing the miracles.
Um
we'll go to the Heisenberg principle and
then I'll give you some of my own
personal experiences. Contribution of
the Heisenberg principle of course makes
the whole thing scientifically
possible. the power of intention.
It wasn't really until quantum mechanics
and the Heisenberg principle
that there was a crossover between the
linear and the non nonlinear domain.
And now we see the power of intention.
So everyone
hoping for and praying for
uh someone's recovery increases the
likelihood of that occurrence. Does not
cause it, does not determine it.
And if it is karmically not the right
time, it's not going to happen.
Why? Because every event is synchronized
with everything else in creation.
And you're healing from something might
disrupt something else. You know, say,
"Oh, dear God, please don't let me die
from so and so." Question is, why not?
You'd rather be crushed by a truck,
maybe.
All right. Because everything in the
universe is intertwined with everything
else.
What some people are doing is praying
intensely to try and change that
synchronicity.
But you see, if this thumb doesn't turn,
then the hand can't open. Therefore,
what you're praying for would be the
antithesis of the design of creation
altogether. You're asking for something
that would not be fortuitous.
healings for instance
what is served by suffering well one
thing it undo does a lot of bad karma
doesn't it I mean that the last pope
held up the dignity of suffering
he did not give us a consciousness
explanation for it but sort of intuitive
we got that it's a propitiation for sin
and because of his stature he was to
some degree
taking on the propitiation of the sin
and suffering of others to the greatest
degree he could at his level of
consciousness. So
uh
the willingness to surrender to whatever
the consequence may be
seems paradoxical.
You say, "Well, if I give up wanting
that person to recover or wanting myself
to recover, then how would I recover?"
Yeah.
Because you surrender it to the will of
God and then the karmic propensities, it
will manifest in a certain way or it
will not manifest.
All right. Subjective witnessing. Oh,
well, we'll get to that last. What time
is it now?
We have 15 more minutes.
>> 15 more minutes. Okay. All right.
>> Okay. Uh well, you know, I was a
physician. I still am practiced for 50
years and uh so healing versus treating
to me is quite a interesting subject.
And we're going to have a special uh
restorative medicine conference here.
They're going to come here to Sedona and
I'm going to speak one morning in fact,
next October. And um I'll be speaking
more about that particularly
uh
in in this this experience. I I uh
had a chance to experience many things
in both the medical and the non-medical
uh fields
uh experientially.
So we give uh testimony
uh to the miracles that we have
witnessed and experienced within our own
life. As we say, everyone here is alive
because of a miracle.
Because of many miracles in the doubt,
it's just that you have not recognized
them.
So I'll just give you an obvious
example. I was going down 89A about 65
miles an hour. those days it wasn't four
lane, it was only two lane
and uh it was early in the morning,
you know, 10 to 7:30, everybody's coming
to work. So all the heavy traffic is
coming up from Cottonwood. So as I'm
going south, I'm in the right hand lane
and the left hand lane was solid cars
all the way down.
In my lane, there was nobody
this lane all to myself
and the other lane was jammed.
All of a sudden, this thing we're going
65 70. All of a sudden, the car pulled
out. Uh I'd say a quarter mile down,
pulled into my lane, coming straight at
me. There only two cars in this lane
now. I'm going south 70. He's coming
north. 65 or so. And as he gets closer
and closer, I figure, oh, he's going to
pull in the line any minute now. And I'm
watching. He gets closer and closer and
I can see he can't get in the line.
Nobody's going to let him in. He tries
to pull the right. Nobody's going to let
him in. And we were headed for a
head-on.
65. He was going 65 or 70. And so was I.
So two cars head on at 70°. It would
have made us splash, I'll tell you.
So I prepared to go and I just
surrendered the whole situation to God.
And
all of a sudden, this oncoming car
pulled off was pulled off the highway
onto the side and sort of tipped over
like this semi in the ditch, you know.
And uh so I drove on. I looked in the
rearview mirror and that guy stayed
there a little long time off the side of
the road.
He did not just quickly recover and go
back into traffic. I look good going
couple of minutes down the thing I could
still see way back he was still
recovering.
All right. So now the person would say
uh what would the average mind think of
that incident?
Huh? Lucky. Hey lucky. How are you?
Lucky you pulled over at the last
minute.
Actually, it was just it was the
emergence of the miraculous.
It was the emergence of the miraculous.
He should have hit me. You know, say he
had no way to get off. And uh this way
you turn your car over. So,
how he managed to get half off and half
on and not turned his car over. So
if you look back over your life then and
recall many of the close close close
calls and in my life a lot of close
calls a lot of close calls. Piece of
shrapnel missed my jugular vein by it
just ticked the skin boom stuck in the
in the bulkhead
exploding mine. And uh funny this
jugular vein must have some karma. I'll
have to ask about it. Uh
this you say this karma this jelly vein
does have a karma to it. Yeah, I guess I
can guess what it is. What I'm guessing
is correct. Okay. All right. Anyway,
then one time I was on a on a ward with
very psychotic patients and some guy, it
wasn't my patient, uh, just came out of
nowhere. And, um, he what he done is
broken a spoon, scraped it on the
cement, made it into a very sharp shiv,
you know. Anyway, he was over here, my
patient. I'm here talking to him, and I
turn this way, and the guy swings at me
with a shiv, and just nick right above
the juggler vein.
repeated episodes over your jugular
vein.
Probably best to go to church and say
your prayer of the night.
But this is how you pick up karmic
patterns. This is how you know I'm just
showing you how you pick up a karmic
pattern. You begin to sense is this just
accident that something is always just
nearly missing your chain
and then you pick up that in some
lifetime
what I'm holding in mind uh
was a fact. Yes. In fact almost remember
it. Yeah. Well served him right anyway.
So, I just thought I'd give you some
common place commonplace examples.
Commonplace examples. And I've also told
you how I did, you know, I've had
surgery without anesthesia and was
lifted into miraculous realms.
Uh, which brings up angels. We've never
talked about angels. Why? because the
subject is so abused. I hate to even
bring up the subject.
Um
during this surgery, that which lifted
me out of the body was the angelic.
Yeah.
So when I went through surgery for
instance uh without anesthesia and I
just kept surrendering every instant to
God let go resisting
uh the pain which was frankly
excruciating and just kept letting go
resisting it and all of a sudden I was
like lifted up by an infinite softness
and I knew it was angels. The one has
does have uh guardian angels. I wasn't
going to talk about that today.
We have permission to do this one.
Everyone does have a guardian angel.
Wow.
I always thought they were
ladies fantasies. Ladies like angels.
Guys don't talk about angels much.
It ain't really a guy thing. You know
what I mean?
Mhall is made up of warriors. You know
what I mean? On the other side, there's
a warrior spirit, you know, with a
Viking hat on and oh,
Berian proportions.
Women have very nice little angels
who whisper pleasant, wonderful things
to them.
Well, could be true.
No, the the angelic forces were
infinitely they're always the same.
Infinitely powerful and simultaneously
infinitely gentle.
And when I first experienced their
presence
in a snowbank as a boy, as a boy, uh the
field, the field that replaced that
which had been my personal self had the
same infinite power
and infinite softness
and gentleness.
Divinity and the great angels
are infinitely powerful. You don't want
to mess with them
at the same time like a powder puff,
exquisitly soft and infinitely powerful,
not to be denied.
And yet you melt in the softness of the
presence which is the presence of pure
love.
And by that sign, you know
when you've reached a good place
through spiritual work that you're not
in the void of nothingness because the
presence of God is exquisite and makes
it hard to function and walk until you
get used to it.
Uh is that enough on that?
>> We have five more minutes.
>> Oh, I have five more minutes. Okay. All
right. So then there's there's periods
of time. You see spiritual evolution is
bumpy and jumpy. It just just not linear
and nice.
You go through horrible periods 12 years
of agony and misery and suffering and
suddenly the good fairy smiles on you
and your life is just transformed and
you think what did I do?
Uh it's like uh all the karmic patterns
are undone and when you get above your
negative karma you go into a good space
and the greatest space
the greatest spaces uh in my lifetime.
Although during the war there was you
know like this like a thing not going
off or next to you and blowing you off.
Was that miraculous? Let's see if that
was miraculous. that the that mind uh
didn't go off because of the miraculous
resist. Okay.
So anyway, I wouldn't be telling you
about it. So
that was when I told you about it. It
was it almost went off. And this kid
looks at me. He I was a kid. He was a
kid. We're both 17 or 18, whatever. And
he said, "Well, what if it blows up?"
And I said, "So then we die." So he
said, "Oh."
So the energy field
was such it actually put him in a state
of peace. So I said you so we die. So
then he went yeah
fear and terror replaced by uh neutral
when this is surrender to God. Huh?
Uh
so the miraculous occurs throughout our
life apparently starting from
consciousness level 200
and then becoming quite powerful and
very obvious in the 500s the so-called
cities which are the famous field of the
miraculous calibrates around 570 and
from 570 calibration level 570 up to 600
the miraculous become
first uh
sporadic then they become more and more
continuous and finally quite profound
and finally almost continuous
but I thought we should take a break and
we'll get into that later. Uh people who
I've consciously experienced a miracle.
Good for you.
people who were lying.
Liars. How many liars
without the miraculous? You wouldn't be
here to say you've never experienced the
miraculous. And we already calibrated
that before the class. All right. So
realizing that they are common,
familiar, that they're normal, that
they're part of evolution, that they're
part of the evolution of your
consciousness, that they're they're
automatic consequence to your own
spiritual development increases your
awareness of the phenomena. And as your
awareness increases, the the frequency
naturally seems to increase. It's only
just that you're noticing them now all
the time. All right. So we will take a
break for how long?
>> Um about 15 minutes.
>> 15 minutes. 14 and a half minutes. Yeah.
Yeah.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu