dancing because the powerpoint is working again as you can see spirituality is a very serious
business no laughing in church ah well there we are i forget where we were yes okay the less you
want the less you want the happier you are and when i first came to sedona i had practically
nothing and it was fine i bought a cot in the dime store and i had a box and a candlestick
and what else do you need that was it
and i bought all my clothes at goodwill so i mean what do you need money for so
the less you want you're happy all the time because you're not craving anything so the
letting go of wants if you say you want something
what do you want what you want is the glamour of the satisfaction uh primarily uh uh the
necessities are something else uh there's the needs and then there's the wants so happiness
is the fulfillment of your needs and letting go of the wants and the more wants you let go of the
the fewer the needs eventually you have to eat every once in a while or people complain because
you fall over
you
and things like that but you know you you really need very little so happiness to me is the
fulfillment of your needs uh that you have a place to sleep and enough so uh the basic needs then
as an animal your basic animal needs huh so letting go that gets rid of greed craving craving
greed and wantingness and desiringness and because
these things lead to envy see if you crave that then you envy those that have it in the
that leads to jealousy that leads to malice hating them and attacking them and that makes you feel
unconsciously guilty and worthless so you hate yourself and your anger at everything and that's
the downward spiral the downward spiral starts with wanting things and being attached to things
uh
so you're willing to surrender whatever god wants for you at this particular time of your life
uh there was times actually when i didn't have what to eat i used to swipe it from the hospital
and take it home because i had no money and i had no food so you more or less had to and i apologized
to god for it i depended on god's mercy as a medical student i didn't have it so
so you do need the basic needs uh
all right so let's go to the next thing you know the next thing uh we started with the education
and choosing teachers choosing a pathway and then devotion to that pathway choose holy company
is a classic dictum and of course this is what we do here uh you choose holy company why because
there's an energy to the it's not necessarily the only thing that's going to happen to you it's not
necessarily physically being there but to be aligned with it to be aligned with the group because
you share the group energy the group energy of a spiritual group is quite powerful it actually
affects the world and affects the consciousness level of all of mankind the group this group here
has a very positive effect on the consciousness level of all of mankind all of mankind resist
this group here affects the consciousness level of
all of mankind all of mankind is being affected why because logarithmically as consciousness level
goes up it becomes more and more powerful if you took off i did the statistics for the book i'm
working on now if you take off the top 100 people in the world the consciousness level or let's say
in the united states uh the consciousness level drops precipitously if you take off the top
thousand it drops below 200. so the people at the top are the people who are at the top of the world
rather holding up the world frankly they were really what's holding up the world and if you
eliminate the top thousand people in the country or the top thousand people in the world the world
would dissolve into disaster very very rapidly instead of slinking slowly into it
by the time it goes we'll have all left anyway we'll be in a better better safer place
all right choosing holy company then means to avoid that which is non-integrous don't hang out
with anything that calibrates below 200 and as i say people say well they went there and they
came back unscathed that's what they think because after they leave i got to clear their energy out
of my aura they didn't come back unscathed they didn't those demonic forces have been
there for longer than you've ever existed and they're smarter than you do you think negative
entities the demons that beset the buddha you think you're smarter than they are anybody here
think you're smarter than the demons oh thank god demons are smarter than you they've been counting
people for thousands of years on the other side thousands of years in fact they're saying exactly
the same thing the very fact that you're consulting them tells them right away that you want to be
special
they got you hooked right off the bat master buha
on the other side tells you you should be good to your grandmother okay
oh dear and once i was psychic and she you know when you're exploring all that she said
your grandmother said to be sure and eat your greens that's probably what she did say
you practice socrates view everybody wants to be a good christian or a good whatever and
socrates says that you have to be a good christian to forgive it's artificial to forgive and you're
pretending to yourself if you still see them the same way socrates says that man intrinsically is
incapable of discerning perception from essence and that he always chooses the good once you see
that everybody is choosing what they picture and believe to be the good whether it's blowing up a
bunch of americans for allah or whatever it is you can forgive them it doesn't mean you have to hang
out with them but you can understand you can understand their viewpoint if they think killing
up killing infidels is serving allah then your death is uh so you can see how they picture it
i don't have to agree with them i don't have to agree with them but socrates helps us understand
jesus people feel guilty if they are condemning others
you feel guilty because jesus says to forgive you see so then you feel religious guilt so the way
out of the guilt about not going along with what jesus prescribed is to view it as socrates viewed
it socrates then unhooks you from that because you can see that everyone is choosing what they
consider to be the good at the time because they can't tell perception from essence we can tell you
what they're pursuing calibrates at 90. i think it calibrates at 900 but it's at 90. see because
others are programmed and of course this programming is purposeful continuous and in today's
electronic world it's become an art you can look up on the internet how to brainwash people that's
described and the political blog bloggerizer use it all the time the first thing is to say
something totally outrageous
extreme compared to which the real messages went across will see and seem mild got that
they say all pedophiles should get an honorary room from the government and be subsidized that
sounds so crazy and outrageous that then when you come down to a halfway well they should be
interested then you accept this so the first thing is all in shock you shock people with an outrageous
bizarre statement
bush arranged 9 11 or something america america arranged 9 11 something
all right then so after you this is a purposeful a purposeful brainwashing technique if you study
brainwashing techniques the first thing to do is to make an extreme outrageous bizarre statement
subsequent to which they are benumbed and you can program them quite easily yeah you'll see that's the way you can program them quite easily
yeah you'll see that's the way you can program them quite easily
see that's how it's done as you as you get more
sophisticated about watching the media so you see other people as being programmed and of course we're
aware how people are programmed um there's a new program on cnn news i like a lot uh anyway he's
running the way people in other cultures are being programmed the children are being taught the uh
that thing about the elders of zion uh which is calibrated 90.
and it was behind the whole nazi movement and it was henry ford's anti-semitism
the protocol of the elders of zion which i mentioned in a number of my books calabrese on 90
and it's like hate to the extreme and it was the whole basis of the nazi
uh movement etc and that's currently being taught to the children in these foreign countries
who don't have anything else to compare it to they think it's valid history and of course the
whole thing is a fiction from french history and some people are saying it's true and it's just all fiction
satire so you see they're being programmed of course that's also why
they're dangerous because so you can't also be Pollyanna and say well they
don't know any better therefore I'll turn my back yeah you can't be Pollyanna
either that's being stupid you become aware of how they are programmed I'm not
Pollyanna about a rattlesnake you know and a rattlesnake is only being
a rattlesnake and I don't have anything against them except I'm not going to
hang out where you can bite me because it's tedious going to the hospital and
all that deal so being spiritual doesn't mean being stupid some people carry it
to a Pollyanna stupidity you know these people are safe they're all okay yes
except they have a bomb in their pocket and they do intend to blow you up that
does change a little bit
yeah
I always got a kick out of the shoe bomb and the shoe bomber was such a wild
crazy-looking guy you know he is on a plane with a bomb under his shoe and he's
letting it with a match letting it with a match oh god so now we all take our
shoes off in the airport what is it 1.5 million people a day fly you have to
take their shoes off that's three million shoes flying all around because of this one dumb kid
ah so he's programmed so we can laugh at him and say gee kid I hope better next
time but alright so our spirituality is a commitment and you can use
visualization and you can use a technique which is used in sports you
can run a trial run do a trial run of how you would like to do it and visualize
that so
Do a trial run on how you want to see it happen.
You can practice any sport, laying in bed.
You practice every single move.
It's now being done also in business.
You practice every move mentally,
and then when the event comes up in the external world,
you're already familiar with the pathway
because you've created the neuronal circuits.
You can do the same thing.
Picture yourself as being forgiving.
Instead of trying to fight the resentment you've got now,
picture yourself in a really great state of consciousness
in which you say, oh, the heck with it.
How could a person like that know any better?
No schooling, no education, no mommy, no daddy, no nothing, you know?
So picture yourself as capable of that which you wish for yourself.
That which you wish for yourself.
That which you wish for yourself is to live your life
in a way in which you're constantly experiencing
the beauty and the perfection of all things,
and in which you maintain a sense of goodwill
towards all of life.
That which does not have goodwill towards all of life,
Jesus Christ said, don't encounter them, but avoid them.
So don't encounter them, but avoid them.
Because even though they may be benign,
they can still kill you.
I mean, that is if you want to stay alive, avoid them.
You make a declaration.
You make a declaration to yourself and to God
to live by a commitment,
and that this is your goal,
to be loving towards all of life,
to be grateful for all of life.
So instead of resenting what you don't have,
gratitude for what you do have.
Gratitude for what you do have.
You can still see out of one eye,
so what do you need two for, you know what I'm saying?
The hell with binocular vision.
You know what I mean?
Anytime you do what you can about it,
and you're satisfied with the progress.
If it gets better, it gets better,
and if it doesn't, it doesn't.
So what can you do about that?
Now there's something that attention set is interesting.
It's a new kind of a term.
It comes from neurophysiology.
I forget the author's name now.
It's in the book I'm working on currently.
By declaration and by commitment,
you neurologically set up an attention set of priority.
Priority of attention set, you see?
Because options are coming forth.
You have like cascades of levels of options.
Cascades of levels of options.
What is the likelihood of you're making this choice
rather than this choice?
This brings up the whole question of free will.
Because by intention set,
the advanced physics of it,
is the oftener you make this choice,
the greater the chance of success,
the greater mathematically the likelihood
that you will make it again.
In everyday lingo, we call it character formation
and habit formation.
Neurologically, you actually set up preferences
of priorities of dominations of attention.
So it's called attention set.
So by declaration and commitment to a spiritual goal
and to a spiritual way of life,
you prioritize choices.
You prioritize choices.
Having done that,
it's less likely that you will choose to hate this guy
and it's more likely you will try to understand him
and forgive him.
Okay?
So attention set, then.
It's like you're setting your compass to be sensitive.
So choice is then free will.
How does free will come about?
There's all kinds of loony linear arguments about free will
that doesn't exist, et cetera.
It ignores the fact that preference sets up a likelihood
and advanced theoretical physics,
and that's what we're doing.
And it's the same thing with quantum mechanics.
There's a name for it in the name,
I forget it at the moment.
But the more often you choose a certain sporadic event,
the more likely that will not be sporadic,
the more likely it will begin to reach.
It's called the Zeno effect, I think, something like that.
That may be incorrect.
It's okay to make a mistake, you know what I'm saying?
Benevolence towards self and others.
You know, I get the,
I get the blogger things, too, you know?
Ooh, I'm paid so-and-so, you said so-and-so,
and so-and-so, and so-and-so.
Yeah, they gotcha, I gotcha, I gotcha, I gotcha.
Oh, you got me.
Benevolence, that is the way of the human ego.
So how do you look at nasty bloggers with benevolence?
Attention set is the old-fashioned term for that
out of Eastern traditions is mindfulness.
What does mindfulness mean?
It means that at all times, there's some,
some aspect of, some aspect that is self-reflective
and watching yourself and mindful
so that you know when you're off course.
You find yourself hating somebody, I hate that so-and-so,
and some aspect of mindfulness brings to your attention
that you're wandering off the path.
So mindfulness is merely a constant self-awareness,
self-criticalness of where you are,
like where we are in time.
How much time do I have?
Okay, good.
All right, so in order to accomplish these things,
then it's helpful to surrender
because you can pull out big blocks
and get rid of all kinds of problems.
You see that the opposite of truth is not falsehood.
The opposite of truth is really narcissism.
It's really narcissism that's the opposite of truth
because how does falsehood arise?
It comes from worshiping the wonderful me.
Having me at the center of the stage
is the whole difficulty.
You know, the ego juices every positionality
to get what it can for wonderful, wonderful me.
All right, so renunciation,
there's the pathway of renunciation.
Renunciation is a lifestyle.
You can leave the world and join an ashram
and lead a devoted lifestyle.
Renunciation, to me, is a lifestyle.
To me, it's internal.
It's not renouncing the world.
It's renouncing the ego's attachment
and gains from the world.
And yeah, I think you have to be more evolved
to be a renunciate and remain in the world
than to withdraw from the world
because the world is always challenging.
The world is always tempting you to go out there
with a positionality and to renounce positionalities,
to be detached from the world means
to renounce all positionalities.
Therefore, a thing is what it is.
This snake, if he bites you, will kill you.
You don't have any position about it.
You don't make any claims about it.
It just is.
I avoid making any claims, if possible,
except that I avoid making claims.
The intention is to reflect essence.
That's the intention, to reflect essence.
And you can make a commitment, with all your heart, to it.
You can make a commitment without making a claim.
And the funniest one is when somebody accused me
of purposely committing a falsehood.
And I said, yes, I've written all these books
and given a zillion lectures all over the world
on how to tell truth from falsehood,
and now I'm going to get in front of the audience
and make a false claim.
I had to tell the real from the bogus,
and now I'm going to sell them bogus diamonds, right?
Oh, God, anyway.
It doesn't mean you can't make an error.
Of course you can make an error.
So fearfulness, emotionalism, and the drama.
So what we watch all the time is people juicing the drama
out of victimhood.
Oh, my God, isn't that sickening, you know?
Every tragedy has somebody out there on the TV land
juicing it and giving it a political twist
one way or the other.
Tragedy comes into everyone's life, everyone.
Somebody lost one member of the family.
Good luck.
I've lost them all.
Emotionalism and the drama of victimhood.
All right, so you see how it plays into the narcissism,
and so you see narcissistic indulgence.
You can't live by the opinions of others,
but you should respect them.
I respect the opinions of others.
It means I don't have to agree with them,
nor do I have to detract from them,
but as a teacher, I do have to point out
what is the downside of that.
If you're a couple of degrees off-compass,
that's not much in the short run,
but as the miles go by, a couple of degrees off the compass,
you're gonna end up in a different port
than the one you're headed for.
So mindfulness, then, is just watching your compass
to say, am I still on course?
Competitiveness, our society thrives on that, of course,
because you can win,
and that's a big gain, and especially by being right.
And being right makes you feel very important.
And because you're right and you're important,
therefore, you wish to control others and change them,
because you are special.
Well, children now are taught to express themself.
When I was young, I was taught not to express yourself.
My mother would say,
if I had taken my sister in the streetcar,
and I was the dutiful, obsessive-compulsive,
mindful in this one, and she was more wild, you know?
So she'd run up and down the streetcar thing,
and I would sit in my seat and pretend I didn't know her,
that I wasn't with her.
I'd just pretend I didn't even know who she was.
Too embarrassed.
So the idea of changing others,
I don't think you can change others.
I think you can tell them how you see it,
and then it's up to them,
because you can't control them.
So letting go, wanting to control other people,
or change them, or make them different than they are,
of course, is doomed to defeat.
And of course, good luck across the world,
now trying to change others and control them,
because we're right, because we're important,
and thereby we'll gain and win.
And it's,
better, I can see, yeah, that's right, uh-huh.
Yeah, in a couple thousand years, maybe, huh?
Control others, change others.
And being special.
So all this kind of gain is to become special.
Specialness in relationships,
specialness in positions, titles, possessions.
Lurking in the background is constant thinkingness.
Constant thinkingness, and of course,
when we talked about meditation,
and contemplation, but especially meditation,
the difficulty is how to get beyond thinkingness.
And you do that when you notice that underneath
all the noise and the talk and the verbalization
that's going on in the mind,
there is an infinite stillness and silence.
Instead of just watching the waves on the top of the ocean,
wake up and realize that the ocean
goes down another thousand feet.
Down there, there aren't any waves, okay.
So once you sense the infinite, profound silence,
underneath thinkingness, you can learn how to live there.
That's the contemplative lifestyle,
is to live in the infinite silence.
Without the infinite silence, you wouldn't be able
to know what you were thinking,
nor could you even hear my voice.
It's because of the infinite silence,
which is present in everybody in this room right now.
Everybody's mind right here is 99% silent.
1% is listening to this voice and maybe thinking about it.
It's better not to think about it.
don't think about this voice you could hear it with 1% of your mind but 99% of
you is not listening to me 99% of you are not paying attention to what's being
said at all it's just existing and being present and sensing itself as existence
it has an inner knowingness of existence and then the existence about the
whatness the whatness is irrelevant if I switch the subject suddenly you won't
care really no you know because it hasn't really changed anything that
which you are repeats the same that which is still silent the presence
within is untouched by the linear because it's nonlinear so you learn to
identify with that underneath the thinkingness and you let go of the idea
of a personal independent self that is causing things you can let go of the
idea of causation altogether as an illusion it's a very egotistical
illusion and then it's projected into the world because you think in terms of
cause-effects
you think in terms of cause-effects
causality you see causality out there that's just your own ego projecting
itself into the world there's no causality out there each
thing is becoming what it is nothing is causing it become that it's happening
because it has the potential to express itself like that that's what you're
doing right yes it's expressing itself as it
autonomously expresses itself the personal self doesn't have
everything to do with it. What do I care whether the hand goes that way or this way? I don't have
any stake in it, do I? No gain, no pain. It can do whatever it likes. Sometimes it's funny.
I don't have anything to do with it. If you look at your own ego that way, you can become
compassionate about it. It just goes off like a little winged thing doing whatever it does.
You can have compassion towards your own ego and stop seeing it as an enemy.
What I disagree with in The Course in Miracles in the textbook, and the reason it calibrates
lower than the workbook, is the textbook is introducing a different voice. It's not the
same voice as the workbook. This other voice then sees the ego as an enemy, talks out rants
and rages and so on. Yes, that's correct in a certain way, but it sets up a duality
with the ego as your enemy. The ego is not your enemy. The ego is a little wild little dog,
and all you have to do is make it friendly.
It's not house trained.
So, what you do is you adopt your ego like a pet.
Your little pet gets angry, it gets jealous.
You say, oh.
You're jealous. He's got a bigger, nicer, newer car.
She's got more diamonds.
They live in a bigger house.
You got a higher salary.
Better title.
More handsome.
Good looking. Athletic. Yes.
Think of all the things you can be jealous about.
You shouldn't be more jealous than you are.
It's just you're too dumb to realize all the things that they are ahead of you.
You don't even know they're ahead of you.
You've got more kids than you.
He can jump higher.
There's all kinds of stuff you're missing that you could really be jealous about.
The same with being special.
Okay.
So, you see the purpose of a sense of humor.
As you begin to take the ego with a sense of humor.
Because it's the little animal.
As we've traced the evolution of the ego from the beginning of time.
It's interested in survival.
It's interested in territorial gain.
When you listen to the world leaders right now, you don't know if they're talking about dogs or wolves.
What are they talking about?
We're going to expand our territory and take over your territory.
And kill this tribe so that our tribe.
Can have your territory.
Which is wolf talk, isn't it?
What does that calibrate about?
70? 80?
That's the level of a primitive animal.
I'll spray my scent here.
This is my hunting range.
I'm the president of Iran.
Israel will die.
It's hysterical.
That's left brain animal.
You see what?
Below 200.
Now, if you're going to try and convince people.
To convince them about benevolence, forgiveness.
What about forgiveness and benevolence?
Right.
Okay.
Thinkingness.
Necessary.
These are the necessities.
To put in the necessary effort.
We said mindfulness.
Mindfulness means being willing to put forth the energy to be watchful of yourself.
And know when you're off course.
It's the willingness to spot your defects of character.
And the willingness to change them.
Admit them.
Admit your.
One of the 12 steps is willing to admit your shortcomings.
And ask God for help to overcome them.
Didn't say we ignore our shortcomings.
Or made a big deal out of them.
It just said we noticed it.
That we always take more cookies than anybody else at the table.
You don't have to go into a guilt spasm about that.
So that does take some effort.
To be watchful of yourself.
And see areas where you can improve.
You do this out of gratitude to God for your creation.
The same reason.
When you look at the great cathedrals in Europe.
And you realize.
A man spent an entire lifetime.
Carving this one pulpit let's say.
One entire lifetime was spent.
Why?
Because his devotion to God.
His thankfulness for his own creation.
Expresses itself.
In this expressive way.
It's his worship of God that he expresses.
Through excellence.
For God he does the most painstaking excellence possible.
When you look at the great windows.
In the great cathedrals.
There was one cathedral.
That they want to clean this window.
To take down this stained glass window.
And clean it.
Costs 1.5 million dollars.
Costs a couple million dollars.
To take down these giant stained glass windows.
Take them all apart.
Clean them.
Reassemble them.
Put them back up.
One and a half million dollars.
I was going to put ten in the plate.
And I thought.
What good is ten against a million?
How is that going to help?
Is he going to buy a Kleenex.
To blow his nose while he's doing it?
The enormity of man's effort.
To express his devotion.
To God.
Is staggering when you see it.
And it is a great spiritual experience.
When you visit the great cathedrals.
The Washington National Cathedral is the same.
Or when you visit a place like in Sedona.
Chapel of the Holy Cross.
Knocked me out first time I saw it.
And I spent many a night all night there.
All by myself.
In those days.
They left the candles lighted at night.
They let the music run at night.
And they did not lock the doors.
So you could go into the Chapel of the Holy Cross.
After all the tourists had leave.
After dinner.
And there'd be no one there.
You had the whole chapel to yourself.
All night long.
It was fantastic.
In the meantime.
In the background.
There was this beautiful music.
And the flickering candles.
And the silence.
It was stunning.
I haven't calibrated that chapel recently.
But it was.
And there I had some ecstatic experiences.
I went into the state of ecstasy.
Existing.
Beyond ecstasy.
This too has to be surrendered to the old Lord.
So as exquisite as it is.
You surrender the ecstasy.
And then when the ecstasy.
When you've surrendered that to the old Lord.
It's replaced by an infinite peace that is beyond ecstasy.
The selfless service.
Is of course.
A great way.
And an actual way.
And it's very, done in America, America is the most beneficent, is the most, what do you call it, philanthropic nation on earth.
It's the most philanthropic nation on earth, in fact, probably of all of time.
There are many other countries on the other side of the world that don't give anything to any humanitarian effort.
And we outdo the whole world.
America puts out more than all the rest of the nations of the world, the UN, all the members of the UN put together don't equal what America, philanthropic givingness of America.
So those who say, you're going to be little America, I say, yeah, who else is looking after Asia and Africa, et cetera.
America gives more than all the rest of the nations in the UN put together.
All of them, all 188 don't match what America puts out.
So.
So selfless service, then, is time honored.
Inner honesty, that has to do with mindfulness.
Taking your personal inventory.
So part of one's prayers at the end of the day can be taking one's inner inventory, not in order to feel guilt, because guilt is a self-indulgence.
Guilt is narcissistic.
Did you ever realize that?
Did you get that?
How guilty is that?
You know?
Guilt is narcissistic.
Don't wallow in it.
And, you know, it's just me, me, oh, how guilty I am.
It's the big me again.
The big, guilt is the big me.
So you have to be willing to let go of guilt.
Inner honesty.
Responsibility is part of mindfulness.
Part of mindfulness is with inner honesty.
At least once a day, you take an inner inventory.
Mindfulness, you have an inner inventory going all the time.
The minute you're somewhat off, you already feel that you're off.
As you're taking responsibility for your own consciousness, the inner silence is what we talked about before, below all the thinkingness, below all this thinkingness, and all the glamour and conflict, is an inner silence, and as you evolve, you identify that that is who you are, and the inner silence then begins to manifest as a radiance, like a light coming up inside of yourself, a silent light that illuminates.
This is illumination.
It has.
It has no linear content.
It's just an illumination.
So the higher states of consciousness are called illumination because the subjective experience is that of a light coming forth from within oneself, and you realize that you're experiencing yourself with a capital S.
There's an alignment with peace instead of drama, how people live off drama instead of peace, and will reject peace at any cost in order to keep the drama going because the ego feeds off drama.
Yeah.
And in the silence, you realize that witnessing and observing is going on all the time.
So the mindfulness, the mindfulness is partly and eventually becomes the impersonal witness observer.
The observer and the witness notices those things without being necessarily termed the personal I.
You know, it's not exactly the personal I, and this is the easiest position towards enlightenment.
It's to withdraw from the arena, the movie, the drama, ask yourself, how do I know what's going on in the movie in my mind?
And it's because you're witnessing and observing it.
Then you can let go the identification with the content of consciousness and realize that that's which I call I.
Right now, we all sit here and say, what is the real I?
Well, something is aware.
You're aware of the talking that's going on here, the lecture, lecturing the people around you.
There's an awareness going on.
And if you don't have the time and energy to comment, it's cannot comment on it so much the better.
You're just like a contemplative style.
You're aware of it.
You're aware of everybody in the room.
You're aware that he's talking.
Part of your mind is getting what is being said.
Part of your mind is just ignoring it.
Part of your.
So what's happening?
Actually, it's not thinking you can think later, but not now.
You don't have time to think now because the witness observer is automatic.
The easiest way to enlightenment is to withdraw from identifying with the content of consciousness and realize, how do I even know what's going on in consciousness because of the witness observer?
So you withdraw from the content to the witness observer, and that takes you right in eventually to consciousness itself.
All of this is a non positionality.
And a non attachment due to surrendering opinions, non positionality, what I got, how much longer five minutes?
Yeah, you don't give me more than five.
I'll kill you.
Okay, she says, so you kill me.
All right, then positionality, not attachment.
We talked about the pathway of negation, not attachment.
Renunciation means to stop being attached to looking.
For gain, looking for payoff, et cetera, from all these linear positionalities, it negates, negates the reality of such things.
And of course, the Buddha taught that originally, you know, all is transitory.
And if you become attached to that, which is transitory, you will bring about suffering and pain.
The way out of suffering is to is to non attachment, to let go your attachment to the delinear.
We've already spoken that that can take you to the.
Void that the essence of the presence of divinity is a love of a very profound, very profound nature.
It dominates every other aspect.
The omniscience, the power is all obvious, but it's the quality of divine love that is impossible to miss.
That is the ultimate state.
Everything is silent.
And what radiates forth is not different than that which you are.
Is a love of.
Infinite strength and quality.
When it willing to surrender all the positionalities and what takes you through all of this is faith and confidence, patience and confidence that what I'm telling you today is true.
Let's see if what I was saying is true.
What I said today calibrates over 800, 850, 870, 865, 870.
What was said calibrates at 865.
Same thing.
So that's part of mindfulness.
If you're teaching, you say, what level am I teaching?
What is the level of class?
Am I sequencing the presentation of the material in the most beneficial way?
And mindfulness is watching that all the time.
So although he's up here talking and gesticulating and verbalizing.
The silent part of the mind is what is watching all the time and giving a certain compass steer back, sort of compass steer back, whether you're online.
And then to share with the audience what the validity of the material is, we calibrate it.
The reason we calibrate it is to really document and confirm, confirm.
The intuitive knowingness of everybody in the audience knows truth when it hears it, so we're not fooling anybody.
But to put it in linear terminology, what was the calibration again?
I forget.
Anyway, whatever that level is.
It was 850.
Oh, whatever that level is.
Okay, yeah, we got as far as the void.
Yeah, that's right.
And then, well, we could leave everybody in the void until the next lecture.
I'll tell you one thing about the void, you don't have any problems there.
Why?
Because there isn't anybody there.
Nor is there any place to be.
If you don't exist and there isn't any place to exist, you're free of problems.
That's why at age three or three and a half, whenever I came back in this body, I was not
pleased.
Prior to that, I lived in oblivion, the nothingness, which is completely beyond all anxiety or
suffering, et cetera.
The being with the nothingness of the void, to suddenly find that you exist again was
not a happy moment.
Not happy.
That took years to accommodate, the acceptance of existence and what existence really is,
but, and what it is that exists, you see, and you realize that it is only awareness,
it is only awareness.
The expression of divinity as the consciousness, infinite consciousness, infinite power of
awareness itself.
So did you say we have to stop now?
She said we have to stop now.
This afternoon, I thought we'll spend a little more time.
I have to fix you, it's something, we're having technical problems today, I'm sorry.
All right, there we go.
Thank you.
And did I finish the second slide?
Yes.
Yeah, I did.
Okay.
All right, so we're going to come back this afternoon and I'm going to finish a little
bit more on the subject that we're talking about, the subject that we're talking about.
And then we're going to spend a little more time on questions and dialogue, and people
like dialogue, you get a chance to say what's really.
So out of the whole lecture and all, there's still something that you want clarified, or
you want further, or are you seeing it differently?
Well, you think he's dead wrong.
I'm not telling him he's dead wrong.
I don't mind being dead wrong, you know what I mean?
It's sort of fun.
Nuisance is, you always have to tell the truth and everything, you know what I'm saying?
Be fun to sell a, tell a big fat one.
A big fat lie.
So we'll see you again after lunch.
You can put up the last slide if you like.
Uh-huh.
Okay, thank you.
Thank you.
Bye.
Bye-bye.
Well, today we're going to move a little faster because we have to be out of here,
they have a big event here tonight.
So we're going to start the questions and answers, you know, the, the dialogue earlier.
So we'll make the lecture shorter.
And so we'll have more time for questions and answers because each question really
brings up a whole subject, you know.
You know what I mean?
One question you could speak on, you know for the next couple of hours.
So each one opens up, you know, a whole subject for discussion.
So has anybody got any subjects they want handled?
We've got half an hour.
Hands.
I can't see anybody.
There's somebody there waving.
You pick out somebody.
I can't see them.
Okay, what is it?
Speak.
Okay, surrender.
Yes, that is the how-to of surrender.
Hmm, relinquishment.
It means learning how to become yin.
How to surrender means to submit to God's will.
It means to stop resisting.
It's a technique that each energy or thought as you rise, you surrender to it.
How do you surrender?
That's sort of strange, isn't it?
Did you ever float?
Well, there's swimming.
And then there's floating.
And so you float with no struggle.
You stop struggling.
If you constantly surrender, what you're surrendering is the leading edge of the experiencer.
We said the ego rises through evolution for life to survive.
It doesn't have any source of energy within itself.
It has to sense what is edible and not edible.
A little amoeba.
If it eats the wrong thing,
he will stop being an amoeba.
He'll be an ex-amoeba.
So one of the first things he has to learn is truth from falsehood.
So truth from falsehood is intrinsic.
In fact, the newest research is that it's intrinsic to the mammalian kingdom.
It is hardwired.
If you make the right choice, you survive and prosper.
And if you make the wrong choice, you get eliminated.
So it's not moralistic, but to be correct and not correct,
that which constantly chooses,
incorrectness no longer survives.
So truth from falsehood is innate biologically,
anatomically, and neurophysiologically.
Without it, you can't live.
What was the question?
Oh, surrender.
It's the Beatles' song, Let It Be.
Well, all right, Let It Be, it calibrates extremely high.
I remember when it came out,
Let It Be, the Stones quickly countered with Let It Bleed.
Didn't they?
Well, if you calibrate Let It Be compared to Let It Bleed,
let's see what the Beatles saw.
Let It Be, we have permission to do Let It Be.
Let It Be is over 480, 500, 499, 500, 499, 49,
Let It Be, Let It Be.
So the Beatles were quite erudite, and they went their individual ways.
And the Stones hung together.
It's a...
like a team you know a team survival team so surrendering means to relinquish
to God's will and it's the actually when you think of it is the easiest thing in
the world to do and that's why it's so difficult to let go resisting to become
very yin you know as I say you know yang is like so in yin is like so to allow to
allow is in his surrender thy will O Lord not mine if God's will is that it
heals then it heals if God's will is for it not to heal it won't heal so you can
only do so much and within a certain level
and the
rest of
of
Rest is up to divine providence, which a more sophisticated person discerns as karmic trends,
and therefore what you think is a negative experience may well be the undoing of negative
karma.
And I've given you some personal examples of going through surgery without anesthesia,
and during the middle of it recall the exact experience in a previous lifetime that brought
forth this karmic consequence, and so you accept then that God's grace is expressing
itself as allowing you to recover spiritually from the damage that you did to yourself.
People in hell do not have that option, that's why you don't want to go there.
Here we have the option by good actions to undo the consequences of bad actions.
We see it expressed.
You know, in sizable portions of the population, sizable, you know, sizable, great numbers
of people did horrendous things for many, many centuries, thousands of years.
Great hordes of people did horrible things, did they not?
And now we see horrible things happening, you know, to great hordes of people.
And mankind's been at war 93% of the time.
The other 7%, I never did get a chance to find out what he was up to.
No good of some kind, no doubt.
It wasn't war, but it was probably something else just as bad, right?
So the evolution of mankind has been.
So out of gratitude for the willingness to surrender then is the willingness to worship
God by virtue of the expression of creation.
That every phenomena is an expression of the unfolding of creation.
And therefore, to surrender to it is, you know, the old saying, the reed that resists
the stream breaks, and the reed that bends with the stream.
So you follow the Wu way, you follow the way of the wisdom, and you bend with it.
So if the regime is totalitarian, you blend with the totalitarianism.
You know?
Yeah.
So whatever the regime is, you blend with it, and then you look for a way that you might
shift your balance in what you think is a more favorable direction.
Surrendering is extremely easy.
So if you can float in the water, anybody here doesn't know how to float?
There probably are.
Come on, liars, speak up.
All right, yeah, I know.
How to float.
How to just go with the wind.
And allow yourself to be passive, passive, passive participant, and then surrender.
So recovery from any illnesses requires surrendering your will to God, taking a moral inventory,
asking for God's help, and the willingness to surrender that which is habitually injurious
or painful to yourself or others, yes?
Is that sufficient?
And there's exercises.
And passivity.
You ever do these exercises where you have three people, person in the middle, there's
a person behind them, and you push them over, and he has to allow himself to be caught by
the other person?
So that's a good practice to do.
If you can't figure out how to surrender, you need two people, that's all.
And somebody pushes you this way, and the other person catches you.
And to allow yourself to be thrown about like a midget.
Midgets don't mind.
Yeah.
They don't mind.
It's just the viewers think it's insulting to midgets.
Midgets don't feel that way at all.
It must be fun just to be thrown around.
Imagine flying through the air and people are catching you.
I mean, it would be hilarious.
Anybody else got anything else they want?
We'll hear some other things.
But let's have a vote for whatever subject you might like finished.
I'd like for you to explain how we can do self-vocation and self-referencing.
I mean, I think it's a great question.
I think it's a great question.
I don't think it's a great question.
I'm going for it.
I'm not sure what the question is.
Yeah.
No, it doesn't really sound like conflict.
Does it?
Yeah.
Belinda?
Yeah, how is it?
Just getting to the heart of it.
Hi.
Good to be here.
Great.
I'mINTERPOSINGいて Gordon.
Roberto Garcia Saldana.
Hello.
I'm youаетrabandobillia.
Oh.
Hi.
Will you come to the exercise on the wall?
Sure.
Ok.
Koban?
OK.
J lassen.
LOL.
Well many of these things are non-verbal.
As I said the contemplative lifestyle is one in which you see instead of acquiring knowledge
you can retreat and allow for revelation.
The major experiences of my life are all revelations.
They were preceded by let's say some great anguish within the ego, the mind, etc.
But the experiences were all extremely yin.
It was all a matter of standing back and allowing that which is magnificent to reveal itself.
None of it was acquisition.
There was no going from here to there or from this space to that space.
The willingness to let go of thinkingness, well that has to do with letting go of opinionation
and you don't need it.
You don't need an opinion on anything.
I remember a friend of mine in recovery and he said,
it suddenly dawned on me I don't have to have an opinion on everything.
I said, wow, what a relief, you don't have to have an opinion on everything.
In fact you don't have to have an opinion at all, you become the witness observer.
The witness observer just observes how it is.
This survives, this doesn't survive.
.
The leaves turn brown, the leaves fall off and acquiescence to God's will is nearly witnessing
the unfoldment of evolution as creation.
Creation and evolution are one and the same thing and therefore allowing spontaneity.
Everything is becoming the actuality of that which it is.
What anything means, what does anything mean?
Anything you can say about.
What a thing means is idiotic.
.
What a thing means is what it is.
Why do you have to talk about it?
What is the meaning of this?
It's spoken.
It speaks again.
.
The fact that I use it for that doesn't mean that's what it means.
It means what it means to me, see?
So, what a thing means is identical with it's existence.
This is a very advanced, a very advanced, a very advanced technique.
.
insight, a very advanced
philosophic, epistemological
knowingness, which is beyond
verbalization. It's really an awareness
that
everything is being what it is
and its expression of its reality
is its meaning.
Look at the lovely curve
to the pattern. Look at the lovely
color of the green. Everything
is stunningly, perfectly
exactly what it is. It couldn't be
better than what it is. How could
it be better than what it is?
You know what I'm saying? Put pebbles
on it and have it make music or what?
The perfect curve,
the perfect expression of it.
The room is just
perfect the way it is, is it not?
My shoes are perfect the way they are.
My pants are perfect.
My jacket's perfect. Everything's perfect
the way it is.
You don't see as well.
That's perfectly
what it is. Perfectly what it is
is a
diminution
of
diminution of
being able to see out of one eye.
So?
So what?
Like accepting
you have two ears, one nose, I mean
protoplasm
gets older. Should it
be that way? You see how
nonsensical it is to ask the question.
What does it mean?
It doesn't mean anything. It just
is what it is.
Protoplasm is meant
to arise from
that which arises, turns back to dust,
does it not?
So what else?
Resignation. Resignation is the closest
thing I could get to it, yeah?
Dr. Hawkins, you say that
to be a witness to positionality,
how do I differentiate that
from perception?
Yes.
That is called my mind-melting charm,
mind-do.
Yes.
Okay, so letting go of the valuing
of opinions. See, the ego gets
a lot of food out of it, out of having an opinion
about everything. If you're willing to
relinquish the juice out of
having an opinion and stop having
opinions, then you're content to
witness.
You witness the beauty
of all creation.
So you retreat from the
thinker, the experiencer,
you withdraw to
that aspect of consciousness
called witness. You're the
witness observer.
I witness this
curvaceous thing here.
I don't have to have an opinion.
You see, I don't have to tell you that I think it's aesthetically
pleasing. I don't have to tell you that
I like the color green.
All that's unnecessary. That's just
conversation.
In reality, you just look at it
and you see it, but there's no comment.
You don't look at every
tree and stop and say, boy,
that is a nice tree and write a whole
essay on it. Then you go to the next
tree and write an essay on that one. Then you see
the mountain, you write an essay, and then you write an essay
on the road, and then you're...
You can't write an essay on everything, so don't you
see how the pomposity of the
narcissism of the ego has
to express an opinion about
everything? That's the disaster
of the
giggledom
empire. What is that? Gang people.
The talk-up
electronic world.
What do they call those things? Bloggers.
Bloggers. Bloggerism.
The blog site
is the world of the ego.
Nobody asks any of those people to put
an effing thing up there.
What's the name of their website? It's called
Me.
Wonderful Me.
Oh, beautiful, wonderful me.
This is what I think.
The whole world
waits with bated breath.
What does Morgenstein Schnuckenbarger
think about the
president of Iran?
I don't care what he thinks about the president of Iran.
The president of Iran
doesn't care what he thinks about the president of Iran.
He doesn't care what he thinks about the president of Iran.
Neither. Other than being wonderful.
Do I think
it's awful you should think you're wonderful?
No. It's wonderful that you think you're wonderful.
The only way you can hit bottom.
So you eventually relinquish
opinionation and commentary
because you see it's irrelevant.
You're in the middle
of a giant, you know,
magnificent woods and everything is still
and silent. Nothing needs
your commentary.
The tree doesn't need you to say,
oh, what a beautiful tree.
The tree says,
what an idiot.
What a beautiful
tree.
Oh, what a beautiful
human.
Nothing needs your
commentary.
And when you see
how superficial, how
irrelevant it is,
you don't quit it because it's wrong.
You just see that it's worthless.
It has no value.
And that it's a disturbance.
So that you're preoccupied
with opinionation running across your mind.
And then you don't
notice that the mind is really primarily
silent. You see?
Silent.
Out of nowhere comes a hand.
I didn't cause it to do that.
I didn't ask it to do that.
It's just suddenly a hand appears from nowhere
and adjusts your microphone.
You see how wonderful the world is?
It's just perfect. Everything is concordant.
Everything interacts with complete perfection.
As you relinquish
opinionation about everything,
the perfection of all.
So what you...
The perfection of
all that exists shines forth.
In one stunning instant,
you see the absolute perfection
of all that exists.
Shortly behind
seeing the perfection,
you see the beauty of all that exists.
And then the divinity
of that which exists
shines forth as the essence
of existence itself.
Which is
like overwhelming.
And if there were
any remaining thoughts, they disappear.
It's
what reveals itself
can only be described
as a wonderment.
A wonderment of immense dimension.
It's like you've been
looking at it your whole lifetime
and never realized what it was.
What it is.
And suddenly, it's like the door is
open and the essence
of that which it is shines forth.
And the mind is silent
thereafter.
There's nothing that can be said.
A wonderment.
A whole shipload of passengers
went into a wonderment.
We were going up.
The inside channel
hadn't been away in three years.
I went to the Alaska Inland
whatchamacallit
Inland Tour.
So, we come to
a place called something arm.
Tracy's Arm, yes.
Anyway,
all around you are these incredible mountains
and the mystical
clouds.
The clouds there just stay there.
They stay there. A cloud just stays there like this.
And this whole
huge
ship stopped.
It's stopped right in the middle.
And it slowly let itself go around
like this because all the passengers
were like struck with awe.
It's like the incredible beauty
of it finally got through
and the mind stopped thinking.
And everybody went into like a mystical state.
We calibrated that view
on Tracy's arm.
There's 635, I think, you know.
Well, I don't think over 600 is
none of your bliss.
So, here's a whole ship with, I don't know,
a thousand people on it.
And everybody suddenly gets still.
And this giant ship slowly, slowly, slowly goes around.
And everybody goes into a state of wonderment
at the incredible beauty.
And they probably wouldn't have done so
except for the wisdom of the captain who stopped it.
He was like, the captain was saying to you,
look at the beautiful scene.
He was French.
And he had a...
At the end of everything.
And now we will stop at the ship
and we will stay here for a few moments.
And you can see the beautiful view.
And there it was, like God's creation,
the divinity of all that's shown forth.
It's shown forth at 635,
which is pretty very high
for just a physical expression.
So, yes.
That was the question.
Dr. Hawkins, I understand how you can consciously
envision about what you see.
But what I was referring to,
the innate coloring that we have
when we see a world through our own colored classes
that are determined by our upbringing,
by our culture.
Yes.
That's a matter of sophistication
to transcend the current belief systems.
Or to not identify with them.
Not take a position about them.
You can say, I think that's correct.
And they say, are you willing to die for that?
No, thank you.
Now, what if America
was still a colony of Great Britain?
So what?
What if it was?
What if this was still a British dominion?
So?
Would the subway stop?
Would you stop going to work?
People stop populating?
Having children?
I mean, what if the Revolutionary War
had never happened?
So we'd be British citizens.
You'd have pounds instead of dollars.
Life wouldn't change hardly at all, would it?
No great deal, would it?
It satisfies our egotism that we're independent
of the British Empire.
But it doesn't really matter.
In fact, the only thing wrong with the British Empire
is you got carried away with craziness
George III.
Yeah.
It isn't that there was a British Empire.
It was that it was abusive of its power.
Abusive, exploitive.
Had George III been a, you know,
like the Dalai Lama,
we probably never would have revolted, right?
So let everything be.
So all the things that we die for,
even when you recontextualize history,
you say, well, what if it had been otherwise?
And probably nothing at all
if it had been otherwise, you see.
Nothing at all.
Yeah?
Any other thing you want covered
and then we'll finish up any lecture material.
Yes?
I'm curious if you could tell me about the soul.
Does that come directly from God
or is it that the soul needs to evolve
and that's why some...
Well, I'll give you my understanding of it.
That which is, you know, not separated from God.
But because of its nature,
the arising of the ego
and the identification with that,
you're asking about the soul,
which is eternal.
All right.
So the soul is nonlinear itself intrinsically.
But I understand within the nonlinear
are energy fields that we call karmic
that are set up in the infinite field of consciousness itself
as vibrational patterns.
You know, with consciousness research,
you're not limited to time, location or distance.
But was is now.
There is no separation in time.
There is no separation in place.
All of reality is equally present
at every single point within space,
within creation.
All that has ever existed
in all of its expressions
throughout all of time,
everywhere in the universe,
exists at every single point.
Resist.
Got it?
All that has ever existed
in all of its expressions,
anywhere in time or space,
is existent right now
and available everywhere in space.
Therefore, we can,
with kinesiologic research,
calibrate everything Napoleon said
and thought, felt,
all through his campaigns.
How Napoleon felt
before he entered the Great Pyramid
and what he thought and felt
after he left the Great Pyramid.
And I meditated in the Great Pyramid
myself all night long.
When Napoleon thought and felt
in the transformation,
his realization
that he was going to be defeated,
anyway, arose as he walked out
of the Great Pyramid.
So we can ask about that now.
If we want to know anything about Napoleon,
we can get every detail
of every instant leading up to that.
What he thought, what he felt,
how it was resolved,
what his karma was about that, etc.
You know, you remember Napoleon
calibrated around 440 or something.
And then when he crowned himself Emperor,
when he crowned himself Emperor,
he dropped from 440 to, I forget,
190 or something.
So he was,
when he met the Duke of Wellington,
Napoleon was counting on his previous power
at 440.
And he was a great, you know,
one of the greatest generals that ever lived.
Napoleon was extremely brilliant.
But when he crowned himself Emperor,
then he fell from 440 to,
I forget what he was at the end.
And so when he met the Duke of Wellington,
he calibrated much less than the Duke of Wellington.
The Duke of Wellington at the time was 420.
And I think Napoleon had dropped to 170 or something.
So how could Napoleon have dropped so dramatically?
Because all the leaders,
all the emperors, etc.
were crowned by the Vatican,
by the Pope,
by virtue of the Lord Jesus Christ,
through his representative on earth, the Pope.
So to allow yourself to be crowned by the Pope
was in a way acknowledging your subservience to God.
Via the symbolism of the church and the Pope.
But it's really acknowledging the sovereignty of God.
By the sovereignty of God,
you become the ruler of men.
So when Napoleon crowned himself,
he was rejecting divinity as the source of authority.
And crowned himself the same as Nero had done.
And he crashed like Nero did.
So when he met the Duke of Wellington,
Napoleon was shocked because he was depending
on his old expertise at calibration 440.
And instead he'd lost it.
So he now was at calibrated less than the Duke of Wellington.
And of course Napoleon, when he invaded Russia,
made the fatal mistake of grandiosity.
And Hitler, who was a student of Napoleon,
for the exactly same reason,
turned around and made the identical mistake
to invade Russia in the winter.
.
Grandiosity.
To think you can have a war on two fronts
and invade Russia in the winter.
You could say,
how could a man as brilliant as Napoleon be so stupid?
Because he had negated the source of his power
as not God, but his own ego.
So therefore,
the opposite of divinity
is the narcissistic core of the ego,
which we call the devil.
Because when it expresses itself,
it's pretty unsavory
in its mode of expression.
But the opposite of God
is the narcissistic core of the ego,
which claims sovereignty on its own.
It claims sovereignty.
If it doesn't claim innate sovereignty,
it claims the authorization of sovereignty.
So in the name of God,
the worst and most horrendous things happen in our world.
Because once you say it's in the name of God,
now there's no limits.
.
And the narcissistic core of the ego is sovereign.
So whether you're going to worship
the narcissistic core of the ego or divinity
is really what life is all about
in its various expressions.
Yes?
I know you didn't ask me that.
But yes, in the back.
Dr. Hawkins, regarding something that you wrote about
in Truth vs. Falsehood,
is it true that there is no such thing
as extraterrestrial physical life?
Extraterrestrials?
I mean, you know, in terms of, like,
UFO-type of extraterrestrials?
Well, let's ask it now.
Yeah, but he's talking about something different.
Extraterrestrials, as represented in the literary world,
are fictitious.
I have, okay.
We have permission to ask about extraterrestrials.
Extraterrestrials.
All right.
They are the product of imagination.
Resist.
All right.
Extraterrestrials, as pictured,
are imaginary.
Resist.
There are, however, entities living in other galaxies
and celestial systems.
Resist.
Yeah, yeah.
So extraterrestrial meaning from our planet
or extraterrestrial meaning, you know,
ooh-la-la kind of extraterrestrials.
Resist.
Yeah.
And they're not visitors from other planets and all.
We don't have any in Sedona.
We don't allow them within the city limits.
They've got five minutes.
Yes.
Then we're going to go to the questions and answers.
Could you speak on sexuality within the context
of spiritual enlightenment?
Sexuality and enlightenment?
Within the context.
Oh, yes.
That has to do with the mammalian,
with our genetic origin, you know, and evolution.
Because of the mammalian kingdom,
the chromosomal patterns are necessary
for the continuation of life.
As far as the origination of it within consciousness itself,
the yin and yang of the universe,
is of course expressed best in the eastern tradition
of yin and yang as merely the directions of energies.
The directions of energies.
And they look at it as impersonally.
You know, it's impersonal.
It becomes sexualized in the mammalian animal life kingdom,
insects and other things.
What is the purpose of it?
I have no idea.
Getting married and having kids, I guess.
What's the purpose of it?
The fulfillment of the human potential.
I can't tell you the reason,
because it has to do with divinity
as the source of the origination of mankind and humankind.
The Garden of Eden supposedly was non-linear paradise.
Non-linear paradise.
People say they don't, you know,
Christianity doesn't believe in karma.
Of course they do.
What do you think original sin is all about?
You read Genesis,
and in the Garden of non-linear paradise,
temptation came in the form of curiosity,
and the curiosity, the innate curiosity of the child
fell for the invitation of the snake
to eat of the tree of good and evil,
the bush of good and evil,
and therefore fell from non-linear paradise
to linear humanness.
Humanness.
And so what was the problem?
Was it disobedience?
I see it more the innate innocence within the child.
The snake says,
eat of me,
and the child in the person said,
okay.
That was, you know,
it was in a woman person,
but it has nothing to do with gender.
Because people eat of the tree of good and evil all day long.
There's channels on television that specialize in that.
Television is specialized in it.
You can eat at the apple of evil hour after hour.
They specialize in evil and brag about it.
Don't they?
They brag about how evil they are,
and they're proud of it.
And as freedom of expression,
evil now has equal time with goodness,
just as falsehood has equal time with truth.
You see, if you're going to,
there's a fallacious statement,
and I've emphasized every question.
Of course, there's no,
that's idiotic on the surface of it.
If you're going to argue with falsehood,
what is left,
I mean, if you're going to argue with truth,
what is left for you?
Falsehood, correct?
So fair and balanced means you will have truth,
and now we will have falsehood.
And they will be given equal time and equal validity,
so that we're fair and balanced.
So when falsehood has equal validity,
gets equal time and equal play and equal emphasis as truth,
then you have the fall and decline of a great empire,
which you're seeing in America currently.
What you're witnessing is the fall and decline
of the great empire.
All great empires have come and gone.
So we saw the crest of this great empire,
and now we see its decline for the same reason,
when ethics and morality
and the difference between good and evil
are blurred,
so that they are of equal credence and equal,
and the courts,
the Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals
will guarantee evil legal status everywhere.
Then you see the fall and the decline of the great empire.
You know, historians say
that democracy lasts about two to three hundred years,
and then because, frankly,
because the people below 200
have an equal vote to the people above 200
and out-populate them,
eventually,
the great empire,
whether it's Egypt or Greece or Italy,
Italian Empire, Rome,
all the great empires come and go.
We see Europe on the decline.
You see?
So what is the meaning of all that?
It's the multiple expressions of potentiality,
and of course,
the more energy this has,
the more energy this has to have to bring it down.
So if you have considerable powerful integrity,
it takes some very powerful negativity to destroy it.
And so we're seeing the powerful negativity arise,
and you see the decline of the calibration level of America
and of the world in general.
So I think I agree with the people.
There are a number of writers
who write about the fall and decline
of the West currently,
and I think they're probably correct.
So?
So what about it?
All things arise and all things fall.
All protoplasm arises and all protoplasm returns to dust.
But you could say what happens then
is when a thing goes down,
it then triggers a reaction that brings it back up again.
So let's say consciousness arose here,
went down here,
this causes a reaction and now it rebounds to ever higher.
So I would say the calamity that arises
from negating the value of truth
will be so calamitous
that truth will regain respectability.
You see?
And people will say,
hey, without truth you can't survive.
And truth will come back with a big bang, you know.
So, all right.
So now we're going to do what?
We're going to take a break?
Yes.
All right.
So I hope that answers, you know,
just sort of general questions.
I'm just giving you my understanding.
I don't claim omniscience.