attractive. Hate is very popular in today's world and guilt is also very
popular. That's the whole idea of blame is that you punish other people with guilt.
Guilt mongers. So guilt-mongering is very popular in the media. As soon as
something happens, who should we blame? And the lawyers congregate because who
should we blame means who should we sue. So you gotta have a, you gotta have a
villain. We'll move on to shame then and guilt. Guilt and hate. The attraction is,
you know, hard to beat and people become addicted to hatred, addicted to hatred. I
can put an ad in the Sedona newspaper, Saturday morning at 10 there will be a
demonstration in so-and-so's parking lot. That's all it says, 10 o'clock. There will
be a lot of people there. There will be a demonstration at 10 o'clock in the
parking lot.
Batch's parking lot. Hundreds of people show up. Doesn't even say about what. There
will be a demonstration, a protest demonstration, 10 o'clock. Hundreds of
people show up and have examined it and the same people go to anti-everything.
They love protests, marches, and riots, throwing stuff at the rocks of the
police. You get hooked on it, you get hooked on it. The addiction to the
excitement. Okay, let's move on. The dualities of apathy, apathy,
anti-rebellion, and violent crimes. What do you see as your most important
condition?
So, you could say, well people, there is no payoff to that. Yes, there is. It's, it
sort of feels good to feel hopeless and overwhelmed and life is too much. Life is
just too much. Feels good to say. Life is too much, isn't it? You think about it. Life
very difficult. It's a very difficult trip. And you've got the body to take care of along
the way. It's difficult enough without this thing, you know. Things are going wrong with
it, you know. The pacemaker stops, your heart suddenly flutters and you feel faint. I mean,
God knows what it's going to do, you know. Whoever asked us to do that, I don't remember
asking to do that. All right, we'll move on out of apathy. The guy says, I don't know,
I don't have the energy to move out of apathy. First of all, it's an excuse. It's an excuse.
It's an excuse. And that's what, what's his name, that black comedian? What's his name?
Cosby, yeah. He won't let him use it as an excuse. He says, you sunk low enough for God's
sake. Take responsibility. Get off the self-indulgence of this excuse and move your butt,
you know.
And I've,
I've,
I think he's doing a great job like a cheerleader. So people need a coach and he's just being
a coach to a certain group of people who need a coach. They need a coach. They're not doing
well without a coach. They're stuck in where they're at. Okay, move up. Yep. Grief, people
would say, well, grief is inevitable. Everybody goes through grief in their life. Starts out
in early childhood and grief is recurrent and inevitable. Some people know how to handle
grief.
And they don't fight it. They just experience it out. And they experience it out. So one
way to transcend these things is to stop resisting them and experience them out. Experience them
out. How do you experience a thing out? You let, you experience it out by letting go resisting
it. And just tell yourself, I'm going to experience this out. I'm going to experience it out.
That okay? Everybody vote for that? Experience it out. That's a, that's...
Why not? Because that way
you get rid of it. So you get
a temporary discomfort, but a
long-term gain. If you
don't experience it out, 30 years later
you're grieving the same thing. So we know
people, you know, who are
grieving a loss that happened like
25 or 30 years ago, and they're still
pumping it for all it's worth, you know.
That was 30 years ago, man, like, you know.
Let's move on,
you know. All right. The attraction,
they cling to it and, you know,
keep trying to juice it for
narcissistic gain. So
you see how the bottom of all these
stuck positions is a narcissistic
gain. It's always a narcissistic
gain. So you don't
have to surrender all these
multiple things. You
only have to surrender
narcissistic gain, and
that eliminates all of them.
All of them disappear.
I remember points in my own
spiritual evolution where letting
go a key thing and suddenly
they all disappeared.
They all disappeared.
Why? Because they were all hooked into
narcissistic gain.
Okay, we'll move on.
Narcissistic gain doesn't
care, you know, you see it in the
messianic
megalomania.
Narcissistic gain doesn't
care if you kill
10 million of your countrymen
and your entire family.
Can you believe that?
That's routine.
That's
routine to kill all your fellow
countrymen. Kill them by the
millions. That's
routine. Therefore,
that gives you respect for the
narcissistic ego.
The narcissistic ego will kill
you, everybody it knows, its
entire family, and exterminate
not only all of your countrymen,
but the human race.
The narcissistic ego
takes glee
in plotting the bomb,
the ultimate dirty bomb that
will eliminate the possibility
of all human life.
You think that's a fact?
That's a fact. Let's see if
such a consciousness is playing the very thing
right now. There is a consciousness
whose name I will not mention
that is playing that very thing right
as we speak. Resist.
Yes? Do you think being
nice to that person will
help? Okay, we'll
move on next. Okay.
Duality is a fear.
We say certainly fear can't have any
side. Yeah, it does. It has a lot
of, all that adrenaline,
all that excitement, all the
exaggerated importance of
various things. Move to the next one.
We'll move on.
That's enough fear for now. I'm scared
to death of the whole thing.
Desire.
Give me more, give me more, give me more.
I've got to have more. I've got to control
it. I've got to force it.
So we all know desire.
We all know desire. Move on to the
next. TV specializes in
desire. Advertising
does. Anger, of course.
You know, the world
specializes in righteous anger,
especially righteous anger.
It loves righteous anger because you
can be right, you can puff up
and you get all that
narcissistic swelling,
you know, being bigger than what you
really are. The ego's illusion
that thinks that if it swells, it's more
important. No, it's not more
important. It's just swollen.
Move on.
And pride. This is pride we were
talking about. Vanity and pride
makes you feel superior.
So this is a superior
elitism, you know.
Politically elite, politically elites.
They like
to be superior and it's fashionable.
And you get to be right
and you get to be better than other people
and you get to be special. You get to be noticed,
you get to be mentioned on TV
and you think it gives you status, at least
in the small, and makes you very important.
And the payoff
is very
difficult to get
off it because you would have to accept
humility.
And the narcissistic ego
would rather die than be humble.
Rather die than be humble.
Rather die than say
I don't know. And of course
we know that spiritual evolution
is really based on humility.
Why? Because so much of spiritual
understanding comes in the form of a
revelation. It's not the acquisition
of new information.
But putting that information to work
and then you step back
and as you're walking along not thinking about
anything, it spontaneously
comes to you.
One time as you're walking by the beetle
it spontaneously comes to you.
Oh, what the heck.
Give him a break. That wasn't
logical. It's not something you read in a book.
It's what you have become. A certain
caringness about life
in all of its forms.
Next one. After pride
pride
What does that say?
I don't know what it says.
Skip it because I can't read it.
If I can't read it it can't be
important.
Yeah, these
are confirmation of
spiritual reality.
The confirmation of spiritual reality.
If you've tested with kinesiology
you will get these answers.
God, divinity, Allah, by whatever
name, the Buddha.
These are all characteristics of divinity.
Now here's where it makes a
difference. You see, at 855,
we have to move
from nothingness
to allness.
The omnipotence, omnipresence,
omniscience, these
are all confirmable. You see that
nothingness is 850. That's where
I started. 850.
Nothingness. Nothingness
is a great place, frankly,
other than allness.
This side of allness, nothingness
is fine.
There's nobody to be concerned about
anything. It's infinitely
marvelous. That's the void.
Okay, seeing into one's self-nature.
This is around
800 here.
And the reality of witness-observer,
you see, is a good
place that anybody can start. Anybody
can, by a little contemplation
and observation,
get to realize
that witnessing and observing is not
something that there's a personal you doing.
The personal you
is not doing that.
Consciousness is doing that.
Yes?
So we confirm
divinity. We confirm
all these names
and ways of holding divinity.
Allah, Shiva, Krishna,
Brahma, Vishnu, Durga,
Asvara, Rama,
God of Moses and Abraham.
All of them infinity.
The Christ, Christ Consciousness,
Purusha,
the Self with a capital S, the Atman.
Yes.
And we calibrate and confirm
the reality of these things here.
The angels and the archangels.
And I said the archangel,
once an archangel thought of me,
once an archangel had a passing
notice. It was like
being hit by lightning.
Calibrates at 50,000.
I would say, here's this
you know,
archangel cruising by and he hears this
prayer. I was in the pits of hell.
The very pits of hell.
The pits of hell are worse.
Than I've ever read, described.
Although, Dante comes close to it.
Out of the pits of hell.
This prayer arose.
And there was a response.
And the response was from an energy field of 50,000.
No wonder.
The vibration is still going in.
So, so it goes on from there on up to infinity.
When you think that this universe is an expression
of divinity, the universe is expanding
at the speed of light.
New universes are being created at the speed of light.
With no limitation, with no end beyond time.
That's just, your mind can't even stretch it, can it?
Universes beyond these universes every second are
stretching on into infinity forever.
At the speed of light.
A little silly to defy God, wouldn't it?
We'll move on.
Okay, John the Baptist, this just confirms the spiritual realities and St. Paul, Tarsus, et cetera.
The fall of Muhammad, of course, is what the world is experiencing the consequence of.
Three years after he dictated the Quran, his consciousness suddenly dropped.
Well, it's characteristic of many advanced spiritual teachers, pathetic.
But they get knocked off one after another.
You'll see a teacher calibrates at 580, 590, and then suddenly they're 160 and you read about them on the internet.
So, there's a vulnerability, I think, that the forces which are not happy with truth,
the world being dominated by truth and integrity, look for some chink in the armor.
Look for some chink in the armor.
Therefore, what I try to teach is the chinks that they, that are looked for at the various levels.
And I think students...
I think what happened to these teachers is their teacher did not forewarn them about
what the weaknesses are at the various level.
And so, I try to tell people, when you get into the 500s, when you get into the 400s,
you think you're smart.
So, the intellectual pride and the spiritual ego really starts to kick in in the 400s.
In the 500s, you become very...
The energy field of love is attractive to others.
It's very attractive.
And the pitfall there is seduction, seduction, and maybe half a dozen world-famous avatars
and teachers and they fell right there.
Spiritual, you know, sexual seduction of devotees, etc., exploitation of them.
And then the power to exploit, the exploitive teacher who starts to control people's personal
lives, etc.
So, each level then has its own downside.
Okay?
And the list of living as well as dead spiritual teachers who were in a great place and crashed
is really disconcerting.
And I don't like to put it up.
I did it one time.
The next thing I knew it was on the Internet.
I didn't put it up for the Internet.
I put it up for students in the class.
But anyway, the safety that we have in the world today is that we can calibrate the level
of teachers, and therefore, I think that's very valuable.
And I wouldn't study a teacher...
Okay.
I don't care who they are, unless I calibrated them to begin with, you know?
You're going to put your hands, your life, and your spirit, and your soul in the hands
of somebody who you don't even know who they are?
Right?
Why?
Because they're famous and they've got a million followers?
I know spiritual teachers with millions of followers.
They think they're the walking reincarnation of Christ and they calibrate 195, you know?
People give up everything and follow them.
So we have, at last, a way to keep that from happening again.
Move on.
Next.
We've got just a few more for lunch.
Is our thing working?
Yeah.
So we already did this one.
We did this one?
Oh, we did the Gospels.
Well, of course, the current Gnostic thing is the Gospel of Judas, which was rejected
at the time it was written as being heretical.
Just as the Gnostics were.
The Gnostics themselves were heretical and somewhat aberrant in their teachings.
So we can...
You notice many things are extremely high.
So I think these are wonderful things to read.
So the previous list, we had the Integrist teachers.
These are Integrist writings, writings, the Rig Veda, the Rubbiot.
These are all things that we can easily put our hands on and they're accessible.
So a spiritual student today has many advantages.
You've got verification of teachers and verification of scriptures and writings, which the world
has never had before.
The world has never had before.
Therefore, when we say the chances of becoming enlightened in today's world, I'll reconfirm
this again for the audience, is over a thousand times what it was in the past.
Resist.
The chances of people in this audience becoming enlightened are over a thousand times what
it was even one generation ago.
Yeah.
Even 50 years ago.
Thank the Zohar.
Thank the Yoga Sutras of Padañjala.
Thank all these people here.
Okay.
So very interesting, is it not?
We'll go on one more time.
See, we said Wang Po's teachings, yeah, okay.
So we'll move on.
We've got one more slide to go.
This is the verses of the Old Testament.
You can't...
You see...
It's hard to calibrate a scripture, because they are very variable, as you know.
Scriptures are written over hundreds of years, many generations, many contributors.
What ended up in the Bible, you know, was by vote, and then the scribes, even as they're
writing it down, put in their own interpretations, changed the word here and there, et cetera.
So you can't really do the whole thing at once.
It's a composite.
It's many books.
So what you can do is calibrate the percentage they calibrate.
This is the Old Testament.
There are only 10 verses that calibrate exactly to 1,000, 0.2% calibrate over 800.
Isn't that an interesting study you can go through and see what percentage of the...
Now, here we do the same thing with the Koran, you know?
And so people say, well, that's in the Koran.
What's in the Koran?
Anything...
Anything in the Koran...
It can be from the lowest to the highest.
If you're talking about Surah 9-5, that's the sword verse.
When you meet the infidel, cut his head off.
That's a religion of peace.
They're trying to tell me it's a religion of peace.
Read verse 30, Surah 34.4 in the Koran, and tell me if it's a religion of peace.
Kill every infidel.
That's the Koran.
The way you glorify God is by killing every infidel.
Cut his head off.
They didn't say slowly in the Koran.
That's a new addition.
Invented creative addition.
All right, so we have a whole different way now of understanding religion, what to put
our faith in.
The fact that it's in the Koran or in the Bible doesn't mean anything.
We'll move on.
Last one.
Places of spiritual interest.
I think that is in truth versus falsehood.
And I think that's...
I think that's...
And I think that's a very interesting list.
I mean, that was a fun list to do.
All the famous places around the world.
Some of these I've been to.
But to be able to calibrate a cathedral, calibrate Stonehenge.
Stonehenge is at $5.99.
I don't know why, but it is.
It's just a bunch of stones.
Bunch of big rocks.
How does it get to be $5.99?
Okay.
Can we break for lunch now?
She says we break for lunch.
Can we resume at what time?
We'll resume at 2 o'clock.
We're breaking for lunch and we're resuming at 2 o'clock.
And I thank you for your attentiveness.
Now this afternoon, this afternoon we'll do the new slides that we did, a run through
the whole thing.
This afternoon we'll do the new slides, okay?
Perception versus essence.
Spoiled rotten.
That's my problem.
Spoiled rotten with a group like this.
Where were we?
Somebody probably knows where we were.
Janice?
Seventy-one?
Seventy-nine.
Okay.
So we want to get to the new slides.
So spiritual experiences, oh, thank you.
All right.
So if we calibrate them, Der Gapuja Festival, is it 480?
Passover?
485?
Christian Communion?
Wow, 700.
Yes, I knew that years ago when they blessed the host.
That's 700.
Huh?
Wow.
Enlightenment is really 600 and over.
You know, Satchitananda, that's 600 and over.
And there's not many people around because of that.
No, I didn't mean it that way.
Some people are always asking me, how many people are there?
I don't know.
Some people are always asking me, how many people are on the planet, you know, 600 and
over?
So we've counted them over and over and over again.
It's because at this level, about 50% of the people leave, and it's hard to explain why,
but you have permission to leave, and it's really sort of an option.
All right.
So enlightenment is really the levels from 600 and up.
Satori, very often in meditations, around 585.
The near-death experience, 520, and, of course, the ultimate states are 1,000.
I like the Amazing Grace hymn, you should, at 575.
Christmas itself is at 675.
Let those who wish to demolish Christmas beware.
They will arouse my ire and my wrath.
In the name of the Prince of Peace, I'm going to blow them up.
Smudge.
Smudging.
Isn't that fun?
Smudging is at 520.
So it's more than just a sweat lodge ceremony, about which most of us here in Arizona are
quite respectful, 560, Ramadan and Hanukkah, Hanukkah, and, okay, so we can forget the
gunas.
You don't need any gunas today.
You need any gunas today?
No, thanks.
We'll move on.
So spiritual progress.
Spiritual practices.
I thought we did this already.
No, we didn't.
Devotional acts are all as a group, 540.
Devotional burning of incense, all these things, genuflection are 540.
The golden rule is at 405, which is above Mexican and Chinese fortune cookies.
.
Ha!
You can move from fortune cookies to the golden rule.
Kneeling to prayer, you see anything that indicates devotional supplication to the Lord
is at 540, saying the rosary.
They're all about the same.
Isn't that interesting?
So, okay, turning prayer wheels.
Okay, so we'll walk in the labyrinth.
Now, we're going to go through, I don't want to go through the levels of consciousness again,
but I think we should just briefly mention them, because I want to get to the farther ones.
This is covered in Transcending Levels of Consciousness, where each level is taken
and what characterizes it, what character traits, see?
At the level of courage, you want to look.
You want to learn and grow.
So to become spiritually aware, you have to have intention and curiosity.
You have to stop blaming and be concerned about others.
And this is the most important, I think, honesty and integrity.
And being steadfast.
People say, what does it take?
It means stick to it, stick to it.
Even when it seems like you're getting nowhere, just keep doing it.
And stop worrying about arriving somewhere.
If I keep doing this, I will reach that, or do, become that.
That's, you see, doing it for some kind of a reward, and you've got to do it for no reward.
Maybe be a good guy for nothing.
You're a good guy and nobody likes you.
There's a lot of people in our culture, you're a good guy, you'd be, they'd throw you out.
Give them their money back.
Throw this guy out.
Okay, next is, after courage, of course, is neutral, which is very comfortable.
It's okay if it goes this way, and it's okay if it goes that way.
Neutral, it's okay if you find the button, and it's okay if you go without a button.
I wasn't able to convince her of that this morning.
Okay for you to say, but it wasn't your button.
All right.
Neutral, it's easy going.
It's very comfortable.
It's not fired up with ambition.
But neutral people are very comfortable.
They're agreeable, okay.
You want to go this way?
Fine with me.
You want a cheeseburger?
Good.
You want a fish burger?
It's okay.
It's all right.
Okay.
Easy to be with.
And, you see, they're safe to be with, and that's why they're attractive people, and they're comfortable, comfortable people at neutral.
What's the next one above that?
They're cordial, and they have a good sense of humor.
Above neutral, what's after neutral?
Willingness.
Oh, there we are.
Yes.
Well, we're up to the fortune cookie.
To be helpful, to be positive, goodwill towards life.
So I think goodwill to life is a very powerful tool.
We didn't calibrate it, but I think goodwill to all of life is a very powerful tool.
It's a very positive asset, and we'll move on, okay?
Reason, of course, we're very familiar with.
That's the world of today, the world of science, technology, the world of education, and the Newtonian level.
Okay.
Science.
We don't need any introduction to science.
At 500, then what happens is we begin to change paradigm.
We move from the linear, definable.
Okay.
From logic, from the dialectic of logic.
And at 500, you leave logic.
There's nothing logical to love.
There's nothing logical.
You've left logic.
You can't prove it.
You can't destroy it.
In other words, now you're in a different dimension.
And this is why theology and science and consciousness, you see conferences on consciousness and spirituality
and consciousness, rather consciousness and science.
When you see science and consciousness or science and religion or science and theology,
it always calibrates around 440.
I don't know.
It never seems to get much past that.
And what they don't get is that love, spiritual reality, is a different paradigm.
You can't measure, look for ghosts with a Geiger counter.
You know what I'm saying?
You can't measure ghosts with a Geiger counter.
It's just the wrong tool.
The intellect is not the tool to investigate spiritual reality.
Spiritual reality is subjective.
It's subjective.
It's not objective.
It's non-linear.
You can't prove that somebody loves somebody, and yet they'll give up their life for love.
It's very powerful.
Love is inclusive, of course.
It's cordial.
It's uplifting.
And it has an innate goodness to itself.
So people in a spiritual evolution reach a point.
They reach a point of sort of a sweet goodness, sort of a sweetness to their life.
Yeah.
Sort of cordial towards life itself.
So we'll move on.
Yeah.
Unconditional love at 540.
0.4% of the people.
This is characteristic of healing groups.
It becomes saintly.
The miraculous begins to occur because the Kundalini energy now gets quite strong.
In the 540s.
There is a sensitivity to beauty, which becomes even more almost rapturous.
And beauty can become overwhelming.
And you can look at two people sitting and waiting for a plane in an airport.
They look at each other with a loving look, and it just makes you cry.
Beauty makes you cry.
Okay.
We'll move.
Level 600.
These are the levels of illumination.
And it's an inner.
It's a radiant state.
It emanates from within.
It has no form.
It doesn't say anything.
There's nobody talking to you in it.
It's a blissful state is the classic term for it.
It's not really quite right either.
Bliss.
It's a state of absolute fulfillment.
And the presence of love.
It's infinite peace.
It's rather unmistakable.
It's just beyond ecstasy.
You go into joy.
Then you go into ecstasy.
And if you surrender ecstasy to God, then this replaces it.
So we'll move on.
All right.
Self-realization.
The famous, the best known, of course, are Nisargadatta Maharaj.
And the Ramana Maharshi, et cetera.
And the 700s.
Nonduality.
And this is where the self, it is dissolved into the self with a capital S.
And the grace of the Guru becomes sought because they begin to radiate an energy from 700 and up.
They radiate an energy which you pick up in your aura.
And that becomes then.
The potential becomes actually possible once there's the vibration.
The vibration is necessary because it's a nonlinear dimension.
It's a nonlinear dimension.
And therefore to have heard about it, known about it, or read about it doesn't do you any good.
And because you have to have the energy, the frequency, the vibration.
These are the states of samadhi.
We say they're awakened, enlightened, transcendent states.
The sage, the teacher.
Devoid of needs and witnesses.
And we say they've become sanctified, Mother Teresa.
Okay, next.
Devoid of needs.
So one reason those levels are peaceful is because there's nothing you really want.
In fact, the only time you say you want something is because other people are not happy unless you say you want something.
So you make up something that's plausible and then they're happy.
Okay, I want a pickle.
Okay, now they're happy.
So you sacrifice the truth a little bit.
Yes, I do want a pound of gold.
Yes, I do.
Yes, okay.
Now they're happy.
Okay.
Full enlightenment then has these peculiar characteristics.
Consciousness is not different than that which you are.
We said level 850, we've already spoken quite a bit about that.
And it's really a subject in and of itself.
How to transcend the void, which I've written about several times.
Because I don't want any students of mine to land in the void and stay there for a lifetime after a lifetime.
Yeah.
And they say, Dave, you didn't tell them about the void?
Nope.
Then I'll get it, you know what I mean?
I don't want to get it from upstairs.
So I'm on record.
How to transcend the void.
I don't want anybody stuck there.
Yes, because you can go into the void.
You can leave this lifetime in the void and come back in and go back out again.
And no memory of any lifetimes in between because you're in the void.
So there weren't any.
Which saves you a lot of bother in a way.
All right.
Awareness is intrinsic to consciousness.
So when you realize, when you become identified, no longer the witness, the watcher, the observer,
that which is consciousness and that which you are are one and the same thing.
What goes with consciousness is awareness.
But awareness is also an aspect of consciousness and it's not personal.
It's not personal.
So when a spiritual teacher is speaking from what's classically called the Purusha,
they're talking from the self with a capital S, which has no personal identity.
There is no person speaking.
Also, a teacher doesn't hear anything from anybody.
Doesn't have conversations.
Doesn't speak with other forces.
Now this will probably conflict with some religious teachings.
But in my own experience, there's never been an other.
There is no other who speaks to you.
There's no need for an other to speak to you.
Because what is being spoken about is what you are.
An ant doesn't need somebody to tell him you're an ant, you know.
What it is, is self-revealing.
So the Purusha is the self of the teacher, which speaks only from its own knowingness from within.
It doesn't have any external with which it communicates.
It doesn't channel some entity.
It doesn't channel an archangel.
It doesn't channel anything.
It is what it is.
Complete and total.
That which is already is complete and total.
It radiates out its completeness and its totality as a radiance, as a knowingness.
Self-fulfilling knowingness.
That which speaks and that which is spoken of are identical.
There is no separation.
It's non-dualistic, yeah?
So those are the levels of 850 and up.
So this oneness, anyway, these are just words, anyway.
Yeah.
Sounds good, anyway.
I'm trying.
It's easier, it's easier to be it than it is to describe it.
I mean, of course, you all understand what it is because we all share it every time we get together.
Yeah.
Okay, next.
Yes, these are all true.
Inevitable.
Non-volitional.
That's right.
It's non-verbal.
You verbalize it in order to communicate.
And that which verbalizes it, I always call it the persona.
It's sort of an aspect of energy that is called up when there's a purpose for communication.
And it speaks autonomously and spontaneously.
So you don't have to think about what to say because there's nobody saying it.
The speakingness is already its own speakingness.
The speakingness is fulfilled already.
It's the speakingness that is speaking, which is hard to understand in ordinary predicate and subject languaging in English, you see.
But the speakingness is what is speaking, is all you can say about it.
And people either get it or they don't, you know.
Just like lovingness is loving, you know.
It isn't a dualistic thing.
The lovingness is its own expression.
It's the expression of what it is, you know.
So we'll move on because we have to get to where we're going.
We made obligations as spiritual teachers, which nobody's ever done before.
I think it's about time, a couple of thousand years too late if you ask me,
that the person should be willing to make a declaration of responsibility about their integrity,
about their obligation, the stewardship of their knowledge, the moral and ethical conduct with students,
which is outrageous all over the planet.
The refusal to exploit people's, any aspect of other people.
The commitment to explanation.
To provide, maintain availability, to be the steward of the availability of the teachings, you know.
Some didn't get written down for a hundred years.
And by the time they got written down, they had wandered far from the original truth.
A good teacher, you know, dissuades people from becoming teachers.
They become dependent.
And likes to see autonomous study groups, which we have them all over the world.
Acknowledges the source of the knowingness.
There's no person doing it.
Therefore, there's no personal credit because there's no person to take credit or claim.
I mean, who would take credit or claim unless they thought there was some separate person there
to whom adulation was due, you know what I mean?
It's comical.
Anyway.
No, so there's no personal credit.
So therefore, the student owes you nothing at all.
And if they stay awake, great.
And if they don't, who cares?
It's not necessary to stay awake.
There's nobody to feel offended if you snore.
Who's gonna say, oh, you're snoring all through the lecture.
So we'll move on.
Obligation of spiritual teacher.
Provide a means of verification of the truth.
So you don't have to take somebody's word for it.
And you don't have to push people's credibility.
Teachers should be devoted and explain the difference between spiritual and personal love.
Because those that we mentioned, the pitfalls in the 500s.
In the 500s, you're putting out, high 500s, you're putting out a pretty powerful energy.
I remember going through that and people of the opposite sex would just come over to you and solicit you off the blue.
Knock on your door or your office.
And say, this is gonna sound crazy, but I'd like to go to bed with you.
So anyway.
If you're forewarned, you see, because they're confusing spiritual love with personal love.
It's not personal, you know.
It's that you radiate that kind of a magnetism.
And they feel in your presence a sense of love.
Because they're picking up the energy field.
And it's activating it in them.
But it's not personal.
So for an inexperienced teacher will be easily flattered and easily seduced.
And there's a lot of books about, you know, the various gurus who've been seduced by various spiritual students.
And you avoid mystification.
People mumble jumbo in order to sound wise.
And that's just, that's a type of seduction.
You know, jab her away in Sanskrit or something and do weird things.
That's to hypnotize everybody into thinking you're the great swami.
Oh, look, it levitates all by itself.
And look at the smoke coming out of my fingers.
And beautiful robes.
Give me a break, will you?
So that's not spirituality.
That's theatrics.
It's called theatrics.
You learn it in drama school.
Drama school.
By the magical soul.
By the magical so-and-so ring.
It shows them.
They're always meditating.
It's always a slim blonde lady.
And she's always meditating on the front of the magazine.
Very slick and seductive, you know.
Buy Rama shampoo.
All right.
The teacher should be unguarded and open.
Not defensive.
Try to provide some historical correlation.
He should be approachable.
And maintain a simplicity of his own personal life.
Whether that's pomposity, glamorization, or theatrical displays.
He should be transparent.
Completely transparent.
Who you are should be completely and totally transparent.
There's nothing you need to guard or protect against or try to hide.
That which you are is clearly transparent and obvious.
Yes.
Oh.
And we'll move on.
Thank you.
And we'll move on next.
Okay.
Now we're getting to the subject for today.
Well, I didn't want us to get stuck in it.
So I made sure we just have.
All right.
Retrograde falsification of memory.
We said that perception has to do with linear content.
Essence has to do with field.
But how you perceive the content is a consequence of the field.
It's a consequence of set and setting.
And the conditions.
Do you remember during the psychedelic era?
An LSD trip.
What kind of experience you had was considerably determined by the set and the setting.
By your intention, your expectation.
The more beautiful and spiritual the setting, the greater the likelihood of a spiritual LSD experience.
And that was before it was used by the public.
And sort of desecrated.
But in the beginning, it was considered almost a sacrament.
You remember the doors of perception by Aldous Huxley.
And I knew the Hollywood Hospital in Vancouver.
I forget his name now.
The doctor that ran it.
Anyway, they had about a 50% recovery rate with alcoholics.
They would give them a LSD plus mescaline.
Blindfold them.
And then have a guide be with them.
And they went in.
And they went in an inner journey.
And they had a 50% recovery rate.
Pretty good.
A similar thing was done in South America with mescaline.
A group met once a week.
Took mescaline together.
The next week they met and discussed their inner spiritual experience.
The next week they took mescaline together.
And they also had about a 50% recovery rate.
So in the beginning, it was the doors of perception.
It was considered psychedelics were a way to like envision God in the reality.
And it wasn't to get high at all.
It was to open the doors.
And people would prepare for months of meditation and fasting and become vegetarians.
And then pick a wonderful guide to be with.
And it was a very mystical experience.
So everything becomes partly the experience as a result of your intention.
So perception then tends to be judgmental.
Whereas essence is accepting.
Perception obviously is a projection in contrast to an awareness.
Therefore, perception is obviously up to opinion.
Whereas essence is impersonal.
When we calibrate something, we don't have any personal investment in the answer.
You know, I don't care whether something calibrates at 600 or 250 or something.
I'm trying to verify my own intuitive grasp of what its essence is.
So you intuitively grasp the Chinese fortune cookie fortune.
You know, it seems to have a characteristic goodness to it.
Characteristic goodness.
So then to verify it, you calibrate it.
So the purpose of calibrating then is to verify whether your capacity to discern essence
is correct or not.
Correct or not.
I felt America had gone down in calibrated level.
So we did it this morning.
And, of course, America is still not as high as Singapore.
You understand Singapore is the, calibrates the highest of any country.
Singapore.
What is Singapore right now?
Do you remember?
I don't remember what Singapore is.
We have permission.
You don't have to get up any.
Singapore, we have permission.
It's over 425.
430.
428.
429.
So Singapore is higher than the United States.
Interesting, eh?
You're doing drugs in Singapore.
You get to do them for 24 hours.
And then they hang you.
Get stoned on Saturday, die on Sunday.
They got a simple prob to solve it.
They solve it right away.
So that's how it works.
right away but it was a benign dictatorship we asked was oligarchy the
highest the democracy is high not as high as the oligarchy but a benign a
benign dictator oligarchy so Singapore is unique in that a person had absolute
power who was infinitely benign benign imagine that who can think of a benign
dictator I found that out from from Brock I said to Brock one day you think
with all these dictators can't one of them just be benign can't there be a
benign dictator without him to kill everybody and slave them take their
money you know Brock's told me about Singapore and he'd been there what life
was like there if you drop trash on this street you get a $50 fine right then put
gum on you and then the street you they find you right there
you
so everything's clean neat dependable they don't have criminals wandering all
over there's their solution to the criminal problem I don't know if it
would appeal to everyone but it certainly works all right so perception
then is a projection of a pinyin which is usually a distortion and contrast to
clarity you see because essence has to do with that which is pristine
and detached and not emotional and embroiled. Perception tends to be
reactive, as everybody watches television knows that, and essence is not
involved in the outcome. It doesn't care what the outcome is. This perception sees
gain or loss. It's either going to be a profit or helpless, and essence merely
sees everything is as it is, and this is hard to get other people to explain, you
know that everything is as it is. It sounds like a dumb sentence except that
it's the extent of really enlightenment, is to see that what it means is what it
is. You want to know what the meaning of this is? This is its meaning. What it is is
its meaning. Anything else is a projection. When you say it's a this or
that you just made that up and projected it onto it. In and of itself
itself, it is not this or that. It's only what it is. It's neither a pointer, nor a
piece of wire, nor a piece of junk. No. Neither is it useful or not useful. Those are all
things you make up in your head. That's how the belief in Newtonian causality comes about.
You see this become this, and then right away your head makes up a reason for that. Oh,
it caused it. Well, as I told you last time, recent neuroscience shows, it's already happened
by the time the neurons, to move it, make it happen, become activated. Intention is
coming out of the etheric body, and the thing has already happened by the time you decide
that you're going to do it. It's already happened. I already told you I discovered that when
I was like 16 or 17 or something. A rabbit ran in front of the car, and the foot instantly
break the car.
And I caught my ego claiming credit for that. I caught it thinking I put the brake on to
save the rabbit's life. No. The brake was on when it, it had already happened. I caught
it. It's one ten-thousandth of a second. It takes one ten-thousandth of a second for the
experiencer to move from the phenomena to the subjective readout. So reality is happening
like the actual reality.
The activity in the world, in the readout, what you're getting through your ego, is like
the old tape recorder, the tape monitor. So the ego is your tape monitor, which is one
ten-thousandth of a second after the reality has happened. So perception is one ten-thousandth
of a second behind what is. And it's a shock when that, that's, when the monitoring stops,
and the awareness and the experiencing are simultaneous. And that's what gives the highest
level their extraordinary quality. Because when the door opens up, you're paralyzed,
you're knocked out by the brilliance and the radiance of divinity as all that exists. All
that exists is divinity. The radiance of the divinity shines forth with such a stunning
beauty that you're immobile.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
You're not able to function, think, and from that moment on, all has changed, all changed.
All right, so perception that is mental, the isness of things is something you intuit without thinking about it.
The reason that contemplation is so useful, and I recommend it as a spiritual style,
is because contemplation is a lifestyle, it's a way of being with reality.
It's a way of being open.
Meditation, as I've said before, it serves a purpose, but it takes you out of the world.
Being contemplative, you're always in, you might say, a meditative state about everything all the time.
You don't give any more attention to this than you do to that.
I don't give any attention, more attention to the left side of the aisle than the right side of the aisle.
Nor do I give either side of the aisle greater attention.
And then being aware of the walls in the room, or of the light coming in from above,
or the color of the rug, the green, et cetera.
In other words, the totality is equally valued, you might say, equally experienced at all times,
within which phenomena are occurring, yeah, within which.
Within which perception, it doesn't that perception stops, but because it's modified by essence,
it has a different quality.
It has a different value.
Perception makes distinctions, and essence is the allness and the oneness of things.
Perception, therefore, is motivated and is selective.
It's very personal.
Essence is witnessed, it's the totality, it's impersonal.
It registers, but it does so passively.
You don't seek it out.
You're not trying to.
You're not trying to accept it.
You're not trying to experience the silence of the woods as you walk through the woods.
You're not straining to hear the silence, right?
And yet the silence is one of the most profound aspects.
And in the silence, then the sound of a twig becomes highly meaningful.
Not every twig sounds the same.
You hear a twig snap, and you hear a twig snap, and suddenly when you hear this twig snap,
you whirl because that's the sound of a bear.
Those were not the sound of a bear.
How did you know this is the sound of a bear?
You didn't.
You'd never experienced the sound of a bear behind you before.
But there's a knowingness of the field that somehow that twig snap is different somehow
than the other twig snaps.
The other twig snaps have a certain benignness.
This one had a loud crunch to it that something inside your animal,
ancient animal knows that that's the sound of a binging.
And you whirl around, and it is the bear.
Now, you didn't know the bear was there.
Why did you whirl on this one?
So there was a prior knowingness there on a subliminal level.
Is that so?
Yeah.
Meaning, therefore, is a projection.
This is only concerned with things being that they are.
Perception is, therefore, motivated.
Essence is witnessed.
This is selective.
This is impersonal.
This is want, don't want.
And this is merely observation.
And, you know, the memory is filed according to feeling states.
Research shows that memories, it's the feeling associated with the memory
that selects where these flowers are filed.
And this memory bank are filed under pretty.
They're filed under pleasant, good, smell good.
There's an affective tone to all memories.
And the memory banks are filed according to affective tone.
Isn't that interesting?
Not linear content like dogs and cats, but the cozy, the dog and cat is cozy lovingness,
pet, friend kind of feeling.
In that file, you find the cozy, cuddly, happy, waggy.
And there's where dog and kitty are.
It's not filed under domestic animal.
Domestic animal.
Yeah.
So the memory file.
Interesting is shaded by affect.
Here you think about a thing and here you know it.
So there's no thinking about what could be said.
For instance, right now, speaking this here.
This speaking this here, you can't think about it.
Where would you get the time to think about it?
You can't think about it.
You either have to know it and you speak.
So the knowingness speaks because it does it right now.
Here you'd have to think about it, which is a whole different deal, you know, thinking about it.
This would require evaluation and this you're just to recognize the purity of it.
This is processed and therefore somewhat contaminated.
Perception is very, very programmable.
And when you hear people make comments about politics, what they're usually pulling
out is a blog site and a bunch of memes.
They're just like parrots.
They've been parrot, parrots, yeah?
And they think that's their opinion.
And it's got nothing to do with their opinion.
It's just a program that they picked up, either, you know, subliminally or not.
Quarter of?
We're okay?
We'll move to the next one.
All right.
Perceptual influences.
The level of consciousness obviously determines considerably because your dedication
to truth makes you very aware that the media are programming you all the time.
And you hold back belief because you know
there's going to be more to the story.
And those who have lived long enough know that sometimes 20 or 25 years,
the stories of what really happened in World War II are still being revealed.
It's still being revealed.
There were things that are still coming out.
So you hold back judgment because the whole story obviously is not out yet.
Not out yet.
And the level of consciousness then has to do, you might say,
somewhat with sophistication in a certain way.
Perception.
Perception is therefore programmable, conditioned, depends again on set and setting and priority.
And whether people like it or not, age, sex, and gender play a big role, a very big role.
And you hear people protest that.
You're fooling yourself.
Of course, the age is going to determine how you evaluate that.
Men see certain things as more fun than women do, and vice versa.
Gender certainly has a big effect.
If I walk down the street, I'll notice a new dress in the storefront, and she notices them.
Why?
Because dresses don't interest me, you know?
I don't wear them.
Obviously, gender plays a role in how you perceived it.
You know, Fifth Avenue is either fun.
Gucci's and all those stores are either fun or not fun.
You know, I think they're boring.
Once you've got a good set of shoes, I don't know where you want to go there.
I don't know what you're going to wear there for, but anyway.
Anyway, just to be very smart, you know, people like to hang out there.
All right, so your education, the culture which you come from, your emotional set, the
media play, the propaganda, the hype, the glamorization, the status symbols that become
associated with that, you know, your label.
And I don't know, it's a person wearing a label or a label wearing a person sometimes.
You see a label walking down the street, and there's a person and a person attached to
it, you know?
So that is all very seductive, and it has a very personal meaning.
Not that it's wrong, but to see that that's what it is.
Some things have an instinctual appeal, and your prior experience and exposure will certainly
determine your expectation and how you interpret it.
And of course, your political viewpoint will skew it one way or the other.
Many things don't have a specific meaning in themself, but they're very powerful because
they have become a symbol.
The emotional projections onto a symbol become very, very powerful.
And there again, they're in the memory file according to, and they're framed according
to specific meanings.
How you frame a thing will very profoundly alter how you interpret it.
What do we mean by how you frame it?
The same situation, when looked at differently, from a different perspective, now seems different.
That of course is the course of miracles.
The course of miracles is really a course in reframing, reframing.
You take it out of the immediate present, instead of projecting your own ego onto it,
you turn it over to the Holy Spirit.
What you mean is you allow God to give it a greater context, and in a greater context,
it means something totally different, you know?
You saw him as a terrible, frightening enemy.
And now in a greater context, you see what he is, driven by something, and obviously
a teacher of yours, and et cetera.
So therefore, the way a thing is framed, and one way to heal things is to merely reframe
them.
And I used to do a lot of that in therapy when I did psychiatry for many years, is I
would just reframe it, and then say, now, if you looked at it this way, then how would
it look?
Oh, well, if I held it that way, then it would look differently.
Okay.
So that's what the Holy Spirit does.
When you surrender it, you allow the field to reframe it, and now when it's reframed,
taken out of context, out of time, and out of the concept of causality, it's totally
different.
So your level of spiritual evolution will determine your opinions and intentions.
We'll go to the next slide, and I think we have only one left after this, correct?
Huh?
Is this the last one, or is the second the last?
No.
This is it.
Yeah.
This is it?
Oh.
How to get off hate, you know, alternate viewpoints.
People are upset with hate.
They feel guilty about it, and yet they see things as hateful and evil, and at the same
time, they feel guilty, and they hate themselves for hating.
They feel guilty about hating.
There's the idea that evil is in the past.
There's the idea that evil is in the present.
There's the idea that death is in the past.
There's the idea that it's in the eye of the beholder.
That's a hard one, because if you calibrate things, it's not just in the eye of the beholder.
It can be just in the eye of the beholder.
On the other hand, it cannot even be in the eye of the beholder and be out there.
All right.
So there's different ways of looking at all the horrible people that have been in your
life and who deserve to die.
Slow and painfully.
Slowly, slowly.
Hehehe.
they've earned every turn of the screw
so first give yourself a gleeful chance
to torture them
call them all kinds of horrible names
and get over it
now if you don't hate somebody
you don't hate them enough, that's your problem
I want you to hate them more
they are awful, they stink
they're awful
you just gotta hate them a lot harder
a lot harder, a lot harder
and then you'll see that what they're suffering from
could be viewed as a sad mistake
I'm sorry you ran across my new lawn with your truck
that was a sad mistake
you don't have to kill them after all
first get killing them out of your blood
and get it over with
have a good time, chop them to small pieces
burn them at the stake
you don't have to kill them
all right you can see that it
we can say that that's a sad mistake
the history of world war two
one sad mistake after another
you see reruns of world war two
you know
and the other side he was visiting his wife on D-day
and the great general that was supposed to defend Germany
Raoul, yeah, it was his wife's birthday
it was his wife's birthday
the day he was needed more than any other day in the entire world
he was visiting his wife's birthday
oh god, yeah
he could say a naive error
on the other hand didn't it come out of his passion for life
it came out of his love for his wife, did it not?
yeah
we can see people as duped and misled
we can see that they're programmed and brainwashed
you can certainly see that
in islamic terrorism
in fact they systematically brainwashed them
in fact they even admit that they brainwashed them
you can see other people's behaviors as some kind of a karmic propensity
of which they really have no conscious memory
you can see it of course as Christ's ignorance
I commonly see distinct character traits of mentally ill psychopathic personalities
due to a genetic defect
I understand the serial killer cannot
there was the most gruesome one I've heard in years
just about a week ago
and what this guy was going to do with this little girl
I don't want to hear about it
you know what I mean
about as bad as you can get
what does that calibrate?
it's probably around 10
10 or 15
pathetic, some kind of a karmic propensity
based on ignorance
and the person is obviously mentally ill
you know, mentally ill
alright, so there's a genetic defect in the psychopathic criminal personality
you know, the criminality is diagnosable by age 3
the genetic propensity to criminality is diagnosed by age 3
the psychologist puts a candy there
says I'm going to leave for a minute
I'll be back in one minute
if you don't touch it, I'll give you five
the normal child can withstand for one minute
psychologist comes out, one minute later
it's still there
you reward the child
the psychopathic personality by age 3
cannot do it for one minute
psychologist walks out
instead of getting five pieces of candy
cannot tolerate one minute of frustration
that's already diagnosable by age 3
and there's a congenital defect in the prefrontal cortex
the gray matter is actually thinner
the inability to control one's behavior
alright, so you can say there's a genetic defect
obviously this person who has planned this most gruesome of all crimes
which, you know, was on the TV last week
and doesn't bear description
obviously has a genetic defect
alright, so we could say the person was vulnerable
they were duped
they were dominated by some energy
like a person we were talking about at lunch
who had many years sober
and then got a gambling addiction
and thought he could make up his mind not to gamble
he could go into a casino and not gamble
but if you've ever been walked through a casino
there's a very distinct energy to a casino
and every time I walk through them I usually do so briskly
there's an energy pulling like this
it's a seductive energy
and so he lost it
and now the last phone call I got from him
he's lost everything, everything
house, family, wife, everything
wiped out
didn't lose his sobriety but
so that's energy dominated
that energy field hits you in the solar plexus
and you're a goner, alright
alternate viewpoints is that they're not evil but infantile
that they're very primitive
very atavistic meaning very primitive
and you know Freud's theory in
in the depth of the id
the depth of the id
the id is the most
the pits in the unconscious
is what you know
Freud postulated eros
eros, love, the energy of life
he also postulated
to explain other inexplicable behavior
thanatos, the energy of death
let's see if there is such a thing
we have permission to do this right now
within Freud's id is thanatos
and thanatos is an operating energy
there's this
I don't like the answer but it says yes
that within the id there's also the attraction to death
the attraction to death
to play with death
to challenge death
to flirt with death
skydiving
you know all the things where you flirt with death
and the thrill is seeing how close you can get to the candle and not get burned
and of course as we said from non-linear dynamics
you can get close to the candle only so many times and then bang
gotcha
bang, gotcha
in non-linear dynamics you cannot predict
you can do a four
four gainer many times
and then one day
somebody says
what about your mother's birthday
that's it
the foot slips and goodbye
so there's an attraction to death itself
isn't that weird
thanatos counterbalanced by eros
alternative viewpoints is that the people are socially coerced
many people behave in certain ways because their society
has a profound influence
negative emotional storm
people snapped
let's do snapped
you want to do snapped
we got time to do snapped
we got permission to do snapped
snapped calibrates to 90
snapped is about 95
calibration level 95
the emotional storm is such
negative emotional storm
and they say what happened he snapped
I always loved that diagnosis
snapped
there's another explanation
the compartmentalized personality
this is very common in informants whistleblowers
people like we recently in the CIA
intelligence departments
the Manhattan project
turncoats
espionage agents have compartmentalized personalities
sometimes they know about the other personality
sometimes they do not
and in the book truth versus false
would we diagnose several of them
they are quite famous
quite famous
famous, the expert group and etc. had some compartmentalized personalities. Some
people well-known in the public had a Jacqueline High personality, a
personality disorder. Then you have narcissistic megalomania. I don't think
people like these crazy dictators have any control. I don't think they have any
possibility of control. All 300 million have to die. They don't have any control
over that. Okay, so let them die. We will prepare an atomic bomb that will now
kill all of life. It will kill all of human life forever. I don't think they
can control that. Psychosis, you might call it a psychosis. Impulse disorder,
psychopathy, just plain ignorance. Driven compulsion, intoxication, intoxication.
They're misinformed. They're delusional. See, instead of hating them, you can see
that they're ill. You can see they're a member of a subculture. There's a lack of
spiritual evolution. There's regression and degeneration. All right.
And how do you handle it? With acceptance. You accept that all these factors, you
have compassion for them. You understand that this person has no capacity to do
other than, be other than that which they are. It doesn't mean you have to
become their victim. The fault of the far left is because of this, now you need to
become their victim. No, you need to know this and not become their victim. Because
you feel sorry for them,
it doesn't mean you have to allow them to run over you with a tractor. Yeah. Acceptance
and self-compassion doesn't mean passivity, to willingly assist that which is destructive
through understanding, tolerance, patience, forbearance, and because you yourself have
become benign, these alternate ways of looking at it are welcome because you're very glad
to be rid of hatred and anger.
It's very unpleasant to hate anything, is it not? You don't like yourself for hating
it. There's a certain narcissistic juice you get out of it. But overall if you're always
spiritually committed, you don't feel good about the fact that you hate something,
you don't go around모 AND ANNOUNCING ALL YOUR HATREDS, YOU KNOW, FOR ADMIRATION BY SOCIETY
OR YOUR FAMILY, YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING? We always look at them as some kind of a defect,
and we ask God to help us get over our hatred.
ZACH DENISON SAID, YOU CAN'T AFFORD THIS. OR YOU CAN'T AFFORD THIS. IF YOU CAN'T HAVE
IT, I CAN'T MAKE IT. ZACH DENISON SAID, WHAT IF YOU CAN'T PUT IT IN YOUR MOUTH? IT'S A POTENTIAL
hatred. And the way, at least my own experience has been, is that the Holy Spirit reframes
it, reframes it. And now when it's reframed, you see it differently. And you feel compassion
for the person, and you see them, they're fulfilling their own karmic potentiality.
That's what they're doing. And of course, in the language of the Course, they become
your teacher. They become your teacher. So the hateful ones are then secretly your teacher.
Why? Because now you're forced to see them differently. A sad mistake. I like sad mistakes.
That's pretty good. You look back on your own life, anything that happened, you can
say, well, that was a sad mistake. Eventually you reach the point where choosing to get
born again was a sad mistake. But anyway, here we are.
Anyway, I think that does. Is that 89, sweetheart? Okay. So we've run through most of 89 slides,
which covers an incredible amount of territory, a huge, staggering amount of information.
And even assimilating small bits of it, it already begins to change how you see the world,
how you react, how you see the world changes, as a consequence of which you react differently
to the world. And because you react differently to the world, because you react differently
to the world, you love yourself more. And because you love yourself more, you can be
more benign towards the world. And because you're more benign towards the world, the
world treats you more benignly. And you can see that it's a self-fulfillment of your own
potential. So we'll meet again later, after a short break. What time do we have to be
back? What?
3 o'clock, which is now.
We take a break from 2.45 to 3, which we just blew, because I lost track of time.
Well, why don't we be back in 15 minutes, which is 25 after, just so you know.
Right.
Doc, if you don't mind, if you want just your book signed, please line up on the right side.
Oh, okay.
And if you wanted to ask Dr. Hawkins a question, please line up on the left side.
There is a cut-off point to the lining up, because we have a short amount of time, and
we'll see you in 15.
I forgot to tell you, essence is timeless. Time doesn't mean anything. I don't know
what happened to time.
Somebody stole my time. They stole my time, and I don't know what they did with it.