We
We are
If that annoys you, you're in the wrong
If that annoys you, you're in the wrong lecture.
Well, this morning we're going to do it
Well, this morning we're going to do it differently. We always start at the end
differently. We always start at the end
differently. We always start at the end and work back to the beginning.
and work back to the beginning.
and work back to the beginning. And um and so I thought we'd do the same
And um and so I thought we'd do the same
And um and so I thought we'd do the same thing this morning.
How many people are new? We always have
How many people are new? We always have to find out how many are new. Oh my
to find out how many are new. Oh my
to find out how many are new. Oh my goodness. Okay. All right. So, for the
goodness. Okay. All right. So, for the
goodness. Okay. All right. So, for the new people, we uh run through the whole
new people, we uh run through the whole
new people, we uh run through the whole presentation. I mean, for the new
presentation. I mean, for the new
presentation. I mean, for the new people, yes, we run through the whole
people, yes, we run through the whole
people, yes, we run through the whole presentation. And for those that are not
presentation. And for those that are not
presentation. And for those that are not new, we always say something uh
new, we always say something uh
new, we always say something uh different and uh noteworthy.
different and uh noteworthy.
different and uh noteworthy. And in fact,
You can't get to heaven without a few
You can't get to heaven without a few laughs. I guarantee it. You know.
All right. So, I thought this morning we
All right. So, I thought this morning we would start out, you know, I'm working
would start out, you know, I'm working
would start out, you know, I'm working on three books right now. One of the
on three books right now. One of the
on three books right now. One of the books is a collection of all the slides.
books is a collection of all the slides.
books is a collection of all the slides. We'll have like a hundred slides and
We'll have like a hundred slides and
We'll have like a hundred slides and then you know you flip the book over and
then you know you flip the book over and
then you know you flip the book over and then there's a page of explanation or
then there's a page of explanation or
then there's a page of explanation or two of explanation so that you can like
two of explanation so that you can like
two of explanation so that you can like recapitulate it like a course.
recapitulate it like a course.
recapitulate it like a course. Uh
Uh
Uh there's 10,000 ways to go and we've
there's 10,000 ways to go and we've
there's 10,000 ways to go and we've covered a lot of them.
covered a lot of them.
covered a lot of them. We got a few left and I got
We got a few left and I got
We got a few left and I got instructions. What about the last three
instructions. What about the last three
instructions. What about the last three or four?
All right. So I thought this morning,
All right. So I thought this morning, yes, uh we'll start with the end. We
yes, uh we'll start with the end. We
yes, uh we'll start with the end. We always tell people that um one way to
always tell people that um one way to
always tell people that um one way to realize the presence of God as the
realize the presence of God as the
realize the presence of God as the source of your own existence, you know,
source of your own existence, you know,
source of your own existence, you know, is to constantly be in a contemplative
is to constantly be in a contemplative
is to constantly be in a contemplative state. Contemplative state. And in the
state. Contemplative state. And in the
state. Contemplative state. And in the contemplative state all of a sudden out
contemplative state all of a sudden out
contemplative state all of a sudden out of nowhere you witness that everything
of nowhere you witness that everything
of nowhere you witness that everything is spontaneously happen happening of its
is spontaneously happen happening of its
is spontaneously happen happening of its own that nothing is being caused by
own that nothing is being caused by
own that nothing is being caused by anything. That gets you out of
anything. That gets you out of
anything. That gets you out of identifying with the linear
identifying with the linear
identifying with the linear linear domain of content and takes you
linear domain of content and takes you
linear domain of content and takes you into context. And you see that all is
into context. And you see that all is
into context. And you see that all is happening spontaneously
happening spontaneously
happening spontaneously uh of its own because what you're
uh of its own because what you're
uh of its own because what you're witnessing
witnessing
witnessing is evolution and creation are one and
is evolution and creation are one and
is evolution and creation are one and the same thing. The universe was
the same thing. The universe was
the same thing. The universe was created, you know, is a spontaneous
created, you know, is a spontaneous
created, you know, is a spontaneous eulgence of divinity which by its own
eulgence of divinity which by its own
eulgence of divinity which by its own nature nature is evolutionary
nature nature is evolutionary
nature nature is evolutionary both in the linear domain we see in the
both in the linear domain we see in the
both in the linear domain we see in the physical world and in the nonlinear
physical world and in the nonlinear
physical world and in the nonlinear domain. Our spiritual evolution
domain. Our spiritual evolution
domain. Our spiritual evolution is facilitated by this world the way it
is facilitated by this world the way it
is facilitated by this world the way it is.
A lot of people don't surrender the ego
A lot of people don't surrender the ego and give up and experience God until you
and give up and experience God until you
and give up and experience God until you put a gun to their head. Bam.
Therefore, demeaning guns, you see what
Therefore, demeaning guns, you see what I'm saying? You're depriving people of a
I'm saying? You're depriving people of a
I'm saying? You're depriving people of a pathway to God.
There's no point in moaning about the
There's no point in moaning about the way the world is because everything is
way the world is because everything is
way the world is because everything is perfect for our own spiritual evolution.
perfect for our own spiritual evolution.
perfect for our own spiritual evolution. When when you stop thinking of the world
When when you stop thinking of the world
When when you stop thinking of the world critically, then you see it's perfect
critically, then you see it's perfect
critically, then you see it's perfect just the way it is. Maximum karmic
just the way it is. Maximum karmic
just the way it is. Maximum karmic opportunity. Undo negative karma, gain
opportunity. Undo negative karma, gain
opportunity. Undo negative karma, gain uh positive karma at every instant. Then
uh positive karma at every instant. Then
uh positive karma at every instant. Then this world is perfect.
Agreed.
Agreed. >> Thank you.
There are 10,000 ways to God. And uh
There are 10,000 ways to God. And uh we'll get into them next year. We've got
we'll get into them next year. We've got
we'll get into them next year. We've got gotten quite a few hundred done already,
gotten quite a few hundred done already,
gotten quite a few hundred done already, but uh so I thought we'll start um with
but uh so I thought we'll start um with
but uh so I thought we'll start um with the last uh slide. Uh have we got a last
the last uh slide. Uh have we got a last
the last uh slide. Uh have we got a last slide? Oh, yes, we do.
slide? Oh, yes, we do.
slide? Oh, yes, we do. Oh, that's today's lecture. I never know
Oh, that's today's lecture. I never know
Oh, that's today's lecture. I never know what today's lecture is till I see it on
what today's lecture is till I see it on
what today's lecture is till I see it on the screen.
the screen.
the screen. People say, "What are you talking about
People say, "What are you talking about
People say, "What are you talking about today?" I said, "I don't know.
today?" I said, "I don't know.
today?" I said, "I don't know. I don't know till I get here." But
I don't know till I get here." But
I don't know till I get here." But people don't like that. They want want
people don't like that. They want want
people don't like that. They want want you to have a label for for it. You see
you to have a label for for it. You see
you to have a label for for it. You see that, right? The girls in the office say
that, right? The girls in the office say
that, right? The girls in the office say people call and say, "What's the lecture
people call and say, "What's the lecture
people call and say, "What's the lecture about?" Well, what do you think it's
about?" Well, what do you think it's
about?" Well, what do you think it's about? It's about everything. Anyway,
we have to make up something for them to
we have to make up something for them to be happy so they sleep.
be happy so they sleep.
be happy so they sleep. You notice when you pass churches, they
You notice when you pass churches, they
You notice when you pass churches, they always have Reverend so he's speaking
always have Reverend so he's speaking
always have Reverend so he's speaking Sunday on and then they he's probably
Sunday on and then they he's probably
Sunday on and then they he's probably making it up. They'll say, "I don't
making it up. They'll say, "I don't
making it up. They'll say, "I don't know. Put anything up there looks good."
know. Put anything up there looks good."
know. Put anything up there looks good." Faith and prayer. That's a good one.
Faith and prayer. That's a good one.
Faith and prayer. That's a good one. Faith and prayer.
Why? Because
Why? Because every point in life is an avenue to God.
every point in life is an avenue to God.
every point in life is an avenue to God. Every single point at every instant is
Every single point at every instant is
Every single point at every instant is an absolute doorway.
an absolute doorway.
an absolute doorway. Uh but today we are talking about
Uh but today we are talking about
Uh but today we are talking about spiritual fiction and myths. Uh we try
spiritual fiction and myths. Uh we try
spiritual fiction and myths. Uh we try to you know be timely as well. We live
to you know be timely as well. We live
to you know be timely as well. We live in a world and uh we don't want to
in a world and uh we don't want to
in a world and uh we don't want to disparage the world but see what's going
disparage the world but see what's going
disparage the world but see what's going on. And of course right now spiritual
on. And of course right now spiritual
on. And of course right now spiritual fiction is is selling very big.
The only trouble is a good part of the
The only trouble is a good part of the population doesn't realize it's fiction.
population doesn't realize it's fiction.
population doesn't realize it's fiction. Let's see what percent. We never asked
Let's see what percent. We never asked
Let's see what percent. We never asked of this kind of stuff up here. Uh the we
of this kind of stuff up here. Uh the we
of this kind of stuff up here. Uh the we we can ask about the percent of the
we can ask about the percent of the
we can ask about the percent of the population.
population.
population. Uh more than 20% think it's real. More
Uh more than 20% think it's real. More
Uh more than 20% think it's real. More than 40%.
than 40%.
than 40%. 42%. 43%. All right. So 42% of people
42%. 43%. All right. So 42% of people
42%. 43%. All right. So 42% of people believe that this fiction, spiritual
believe that this fiction, spiritual
believe that this fiction, spiritual fiction is real. Real.
fiction is real. Real.
fiction is real. Real. Uh so I thought just for the record, we
Uh so I thought just for the record, we
Uh so I thought just for the record, we should um
should um
should um give it our impremature.
give it our impremature.
give it our impremature. You know what the impremature is? The
You know what the impremature is? The
You know what the impremature is? The Catholic Church did it for many
Catholic Church did it for many
Catholic Church did it for many centuries and uh with good cause. the
centuries and uh with good cause. the
centuries and uh with good cause. the spirit the church in a sort of a
spirit the church in a sort of a
spirit the church in a sort of a paternalistic fashion
paternalistic fashion
paternalistic fashion uh read all books and an impremature you
uh read all books and an impremature you
uh read all books and an impremature you didn't read a book unless an immature
didn't read a book unless an immature
didn't read a book unless an immature premature means that it was read and
premature means that it was read and
premature means that it was read and approved it's not leading to heresy or
approved it's not leading to heresy or
approved it's not leading to heresy or degeneracy or immorality etc. The
degeneracy or immorality etc. The
degeneracy or immorality etc. The intention of that is 375. The intention
intention of that is 375. The intention
intention of that is 375. The intention is integris
is integris
is integris to protect the innocent from being
to protect the innocent from being
to protect the innocent from being seduced by this kind of thing which in
seduced by this kind of thing which in
seduced by this kind of thing which in today's world is almost impossible. So I
today's world is almost impossible. So I
today's world is almost impossible. So I don't know if they even do it anymore
don't know if they even do it anymore
don't know if they even do it anymore because the television and the media is
because the television and the media is
because the television and the media is so powerful that
so powerful that
so powerful that but in the old days and if a book was
but in the old days and if a book was
but in the old days and if a book was disapproved it was placed in the index
disapproved it was placed in the index
disapproved it was placed in the index in the Vatican and the Vatican has
in the Vatican and the Vatican has
in the Vatican and the Vatican has thousands of volumes of books that are
thousands of volumes of books that are
thousands of volumes of books that are condemned to be heretical heretical
condemned to be heretical heretical
condemned to be heretical heretical uh in today's world of libert
uh in today's world of libert
uh in today's world of libert libertarianism. I guess that would sound
libertarianism. I guess that would sound
libertarianism. I guess that would sound repressive. However, the intention is
repressive. However, the intention is
repressive. However, the intention is 375. So, it's an integrous intention.
375. So, it's an integrous intention.
375. So, it's an integrous intention. It's just paternalistic in which the
It's just paternalistic in which the
It's just paternalistic in which the church takes some responsibility for the
church takes some responsibility for the
church takes some responsibility for the evolution of your soul and tries to be,
evolution of your soul and tries to be,
evolution of your soul and tries to be, you know, an adequate parent. So,
you know, an adequate parent. So,
you know, an adequate parent. So, all right, spiritual fiction and myths.
all right, spiritual fiction and myths.
all right, spiritual fiction and myths. Uh many of these we've spoken about
Uh many of these we've spoken about
Uh many of these we've spoken about before in various different ways and I
before in various different ways and I
before in various different ways and I think there may be in truth versus
think there may be in truth versus
think there may be in truth versus false. Uh alien abduction. Alien
false. Uh alien abduction. Alien
false. Uh alien abduction. Alien abduction
abduction
abduction uh you know has a big press.
uh you know has a big press.
uh you know has a big press. Alien abduction is is a little
Alien abduction is is a little
Alien abduction is is a little complicated. In fact, I don't know
complicated. In fact, I don't know
complicated. In fact, I don't know anybody that's really understood it yet.
anybody that's really understood it yet.
anybody that's really understood it yet. Uh people that visit other domains other
Uh people that visit other domains other
Uh people that visit other domains other than our own domain uh do so very often
than our own domain uh do so very often
than our own domain uh do so very often in their astral body. So people and I
in their astral body. So people and I
in their astral body. So people and I knew one in Sedona very very convincing
knew one in Sedona very very convincing
knew one in Sedona very very convincing uh visit another domain and of course
uh visit another domain and of course
uh visit another domain and of course revelations in the New Testament is
revelations in the New Testament is
revelations in the New Testament is another is another domain uh way down in
another is another domain uh way down in
another is another domain uh way down in number 70 or something.
number 70 or something.
number 70 or something. What happens is the
What happens is the
What happens is the is the psychic body the spiritual body
is the psychic body the spiritual body
is the psychic body the spiritual body I'm not using thinking the right term
I'm not using thinking the right term
I'm not using thinking the right term the third body uh leaves the physical
the third body uh leaves the physical
the third body uh leaves the physical body and visits other domains at the uh
body and visits other domains at the uh
body and visits other domains at the uh appeal of other entities etc. So what
appeal of other entities etc. So what
appeal of other entities etc. So what the person the reason people who have
the person the reason people who have
the person the reason people who have been abducted are so convincing is
been abducted are so convincing is
been abducted are so convincing is because that's what they did experience
because that's what they did experience
because that's what they did experience not in this dimension not in physical
not in this dimension not in physical
not in this dimension not in physical body but like a dream but you're awake
body but like a dream but you're awake
body but like a dream but you're awake during the dream they went there and
during the dream they went there and
during the dream they went there and literally experienced that
literally experienced that
literally experienced that and there was a spiritual teacher here
and there was a spiritual teacher here
and there was a spiritual teacher here in Sedona who brought a lot of people
in Sedona who brought a lot of people
in Sedona who brought a lot of people out here
out here
out here the purpose was he had visited that
the purpose was he had visited that
the purpose was he had visited that domain and uh so but alen adduction. So
domain and uh so but alen adduction. So
domain and uh so but alen adduction. So because you you have an subjective
because you you have an subjective
because you you have an subjective experience of it, it's very real. The
experience of it, it's very real. The
experience of it, it's very real. The only thing that you realize is that it's
only thing that you realize is that it's
only thing that you realize is that it's not the same domain is this domain. Huh.
not the same domain is this domain. Huh.
not the same domain is this domain. Huh. Uh a million little pieces. I don't know
Uh a million little pieces. I don't know
Uh a million little pieces. I don't know what that is. Uh well, these are
what that is. Uh well, these are
what that is. Uh well, these are bestselling books. I guess that was on
bestselling books. I guess that was on
bestselling books. I guess that was on Oprah's Winfrey. Yeah. Uh in which
Oprah's Winfrey. Yeah. Uh in which
Oprah's Winfrey. Yeah. Uh in which there's fiction put in. In fact, uh all
there's fiction put in. In fact, uh all
there's fiction put in. In fact, uh all apocalyptic
apocalyptic
apocalyptic prophecies
prophecies
prophecies uh are fellacious.
uh are fellacious.
uh are fellacious. Uh if you've heard what the lecture
Uh if you've heard what the lecture
Uh if you've heard what the lecture said,
life is evolutionary
life is evolutionary and the evolution is dependent on
and the evolution is dependent on
and the evolution is dependent on agreements of the of the will
agreements of the of the will
agreements of the of the will individually and collectively.
individually and collectively.
individually and collectively. So therefore, the future is not knowable
So therefore, the future is not knowable
So therefore, the future is not knowable because it hasn't been created yet. How
because it hasn't been created yet. How
because it hasn't been created yet. How can you go ahead to that which is
can you go ahead to that which is
can you go ahead to that which is uncreated and make a prophecy?
uncreated and make a prophecy?
uncreated and make a prophecy? The world until I make up what I'm going
The world until I make up what I'm going
The world until I make up what I'm going to have for breakfast is not going to be
to have for breakfast is not going to be
to have for breakfast is not going to be the same. You understand?
the same. You understand?
the same. You understand? Because we we ourselves by our own
Because we we ourselves by our own
Because we we ourselves by our own spiritual decisions are you know making
spiritual decisions are you know making
spiritual decisions are you know making uh deciding what the future will be.
uh deciding what the future will be.
uh deciding what the future will be. All apocalyptic prophecies
All apocalyptic prophecies
All apocalyptic prophecies are uh false.
are uh false.
are uh false. >> Resist. We have permission. Resist.
>> Resist. We have permission. Resist.
>> Resist. We have permission. Resist. Sorry.
Just once more, David. You're going to
Just once more, David. You're going to get it. That's
get it. That's
get it. That's I have a thing in my ear that goes right
I have a thing in my ear that goes right
I have a thing in my ear that goes right to God.
Get preachers get on TV. God told me
Get preachers get on TV. God told me this morning that, and you notice he's
this morning that, and you notice he's
this morning that, and you notice he's got a little thing in his ear,
apocalyptic prophecies,
apocalyptic prophecies, uh, Aquarian cults, Aquarian cults,
uh, Aquarian cults, Aquarian cults,
uh, Aquarian cults, Aquarian cults, uh, area, all these conspiracy theories,
uh, area, all these conspiracy theories,
uh, area, all these conspiracy theories, you know, behind everything there's a
you know, behind everything there's a
you know, behind everything there's a conspiracy theory. And a lot of these,
conspiracy theory. And a lot of these,
conspiracy theory. And a lot of these, of course, are just conspiracy theories.
of course, are just conspiracy theories.
of course, are just conspiracy theories. Uh most conspiracy theories of course
Uh most conspiracy theories of course
Uh most conspiracy theories of course are just uh projections of your own
are just uh projections of your own
are just uh projections of your own imagination.
imagination.
imagination. Area 51, we've checked it out many times
Area 51, we've checked it out many times
Area 51, we've checked it out many times and there's nothing going on.
and there's nothing going on.
and there's nothing going on. I'll tell you the truth about Area 51.
I'll tell you the truth about Area 51.
I'll tell you the truth about Area 51. You won't tell anybody.
You won't tell anybody.
You won't tell anybody. It's boring and there's nothing going on
It's boring and there's nothing going on
It's boring and there's nothing going on there.
The local tourist
The local tourist information bureau is not happy with
information bureau is not happy with
information bureau is not happy with that. But it's true.
that. But it's true.
that. But it's true. Astrological religions. See, because
Astrological religions. See, because
Astrological religions. See, because you're getting cause and effect and the
you're getting cause and effect and the
you're getting cause and effect and the the dimensions all mixed up.
the dimensions all mixed up.
the dimensions all mixed up. The planets exist in a in a physical
The planets exist in a in a physical
The planets exist in a in a physical dimension.
dimension.
dimension. There are three-dimensional.
There are three-dimensional.
There are three-dimensional. Yes.
Yes.
Yes. The truth of what you are spiritually is
The truth of what you are spiritually is
The truth of what you are spiritually is nonlinear.
nonlinear.
nonlinear. So what astrologic religions are saying
So what astrologic religions are saying
So what astrologic religions are saying is that the linear has dominion over the
is that the linear has dominion over the
is that the linear has dominion over the nonlinear.
nonlinear.
nonlinear. No such thing. The planetary system is
No such thing. The planetary system is
No such thing. The planetary system is content.
content.
content. Divinity, spirituality, consciousness,
Divinity, spirituality, consciousness,
Divinity, spirituality, consciousness, the spirit is nonlinear.
the spirit is nonlinear.
the spirit is nonlinear. The nonlinear is not subject to the
The nonlinear is not subject to the
The nonlinear is not subject to the linear.
linear.
linear. much less by causality.
much less by causality.
much less by causality. Much less by causality.
Much less by causality.
Much less by causality. So if Mercury is going over your
So if Mercury is going over your
So if Mercury is going over your outhouse tomorrow morning,
doesn't mean your mother-in-law is going
doesn't mean your mother-in-law is going to have a heart attack. You know what
to have a heart attack. You know what
to have a heart attack. You know what I'm saying?
Because all exists in one universe.
Because all exists in one universe. However, there is sometimes a
However, there is sometimes a
However, there is sometimes a correlation, but not a not a causal one.
correlation, but not a not a causal one.
correlation, but not a not a causal one. The most propitious moment for certain
The most propitious moment for certain
The most propitious moment for certain things is because the context and the
things is because the context and the
things is because the context and the content tend to be in agreement, but not
content tend to be in agreement, but not
content tend to be in agreement, but not causally. Not causally. Understand what
causally. Not causally. Understand what
causally. Not causally. Understand what I'm saying? Mercury isn't going to
I'm saying? Mercury isn't going to
I'm saying? Mercury isn't going to poison your bathtub. You know,
poison your bathtub. You know,
poison your bathtub. You know, uh Baba G is a is an old myth. I heard
uh Baba G is a is an old myth. I heard
uh Baba G is a is an old myth. I heard about Baba G when I first got into
about Baba G when I first got into
about Baba G when I first got into spiritual
4,000 years old. He lives in the
4,000 years old. He lives in the Himalayas. Right. Yeah.
The Bible code. All codes, all spiritual
The Bible code. All codes, all spiritual codes are felicious.
codes are felicious.
codes are felicious. I don't care if they're the number of
I don't care if they're the number of
I don't care if they're the number of hairs in a camel's nose.
hairs in a camel's nose.
hairs in a camel's nose. I have permission to ask this if I
I have permission to ask this if I
I have permission to ask this if I wanted. What I just stated is true. Yes.
wanted. What I just stated is true. Yes.
wanted. What I just stated is true. Yes. Correct.
Correct.
Correct. You can see that just by knowing it your
You can see that just by knowing it your
You can see that just by knowing it your own self. All supposed secret codes,
own self. All supposed secret codes,
own self. All supposed secret codes, secret codes in the DNA and in the germs
secret codes in the DNA and in the germs
secret codes in the DNA and in the germs and in microbes and the book of
and in microbes and the book of
and in microbes and the book of revelation we know about quite well. And
revelation we know about quite well. And
revelation we know about quite well. And of course this is affirms that
of course this is affirms that
of course this is affirms that apocalyptic prophecies
apocalyptic prophecies
apocalyptic prophecies and celestine prophecies
and celestine prophecies
and celestine prophecies uh channeling we've already spoken about
uh channeling we've already spoken about
uh channeling we've already spoken about it's a limitation.
it's a limitation.
it's a limitation. uh crop circles turned out to be also
uh crop circles turned out to be also
uh crop circles turned out to be also facious.
facious.
facious. Then we have imaginary things like
Then we have imaginary things like
Then we have imaginary things like crystal children etc. uh the Da Vinci
crystal children etc. uh the Da Vinci
crystal children etc. uh the Da Vinci code and Da Vinci Code decoded.
code and Da Vinci Code decoded.
code and Da Vinci Code decoded. How about the decoding of the decoded
How about the decoding of the decoded
How about the decoding of the decoded code of the decoded
code of the decoded
code of the decoded is just as dumb as the Da Vinci Code.
is just as dumb as the Da Vinci Code.
is just as dumb as the Da Vinci Code. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. As we said about prophecies about the
As we said about prophecies about the
As we said about prophecies about the future disappearance of the universe is
future disappearance of the universe is
future disappearance of the universe is an impossibility
an impossibility
an impossibility that would be somethingness becoming
that would be somethingness becoming
that would be somethingness becoming nothingness.
nothingness.
nothingness. The idea is that the whole universe is
The idea is that the whole universe is
The idea is that the whole universe is an illusion and that's an illusion that
an illusion and that's an illusion that
an illusion and that's an illusion that the whole universe is an illusion.
the whole universe is an illusion.
the whole universe is an illusion. How you perceive it of course is a
How you perceive it of course is a
How you perceive it of course is a projection. Perception is projection.
projection. Perception is projection.
projection. Perception is projection. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. Uh all forms of divination etc. Then we
Uh all forms of divination etc. Then we
Uh all forms of divination etc. Then we hear we have the DNA code, the end time
hear we have the DNA code, the end time
hear we have the DNA code, the end time prophecies,
prophecies,
prophecies, extraterrestrials,
extraterrestrials,
extraterrestrials, and ghosts. Everybody agree with that?
and ghosts. Everybody agree with that?
and ghosts. Everybody agree with that? Anybody believe in ghosts?
Anybody believe in ghosts?
Anybody believe in ghosts? I didn't believe in ghosts. My mother
I didn't believe in ghosts. My mother
I didn't believe in ghosts. My mother didn't believe in ghosts. And one time I
didn't believe in ghosts. And one time I
didn't believe in ghosts. And one time I went to school in kindergarten someplace
went to school in kindergarten someplace
went to school in kindergarten someplace around there and kids start telling me
around there and kids start telling me
around there and kids start telling me about ghosts.
about ghosts.
about ghosts. I got scared of ghosts.
I got scared of ghosts.
I got scared of ghosts. So my mother took me by the hand and we
So my mother took me by the hand and we
So my mother took me by the hand and we searched the house for ghosts.
We're in the basement. We open the
We're in the basement. We open the closets.
So carrying this then by caring this we
So carrying this then by caring this we eliminate the fear the fear of ghosts.
eliminate the fear the fear of ghosts.
eliminate the fear the fear of ghosts. Okay. See man has a certain fascination
Okay. See man has a certain fascination
Okay. See man has a certain fascination with all these illusions the romance and
with all these illusions the romance and
with all these illusions the romance and excitement of it. What could be more
excitement of it. What could be more
excitement of it. What could be more exciting than all this stuff here? You
exciting than all this stuff here? You
exciting than all this stuff here? You know what I'm saying? Incoming fifth
know what I'm saying? Incoming fifth
know what I'm saying? Incoming fifth dimensions. That's the future etc.
dimensions. That's the future etc.
dimensions. That's the future etc. Uh the Judas gospel as we calibrated 170
Uh the Judas gospel as we calibrated 170
Uh the Judas gospel as we calibrated 170 or something. Maitraa is another thing.
or something. Maitraa is another thing.
or something. Maitraa is another thing. Another thing myra is always showing up
Another thing myra is always showing up
Another thing myra is always showing up much like Baba
much like Baba
much like Baba and you get it. You read it on the
and you get it. You read it on the
and you get it. You read it on the internet. They spotted Maitraa in a
internet. They spotted Maitraa in a
internet. They spotted Maitraa in a coffee shop in Chicago.
coffee shop in Chicago.
coffee shop in Chicago. The return of the Christ is having a
The return of the Christ is having a
The return of the Christ is having a cheeseburger.
Now he's really spotted all over the
Now he's really spotted all over the place. Mayan calendar predictions. And
place. Mayan calendar predictions. And
place. Mayan calendar predictions. And people are are always sending me
people are are always sending me
people are are always sending me something about the Mayan calendars. I
something about the Mayan calendars. I
something about the Mayan calendars. I don't like the Mayan calendars. I think
don't like the Mayan calendars. I think
don't like the Mayan calendars. I think they're horrid. Don't send me anymore.
they're horrid. Don't send me anymore.
they're horrid. Don't send me anymore. I got piles of books about Mayan
I got piles of books about Mayan
I got piles of books about Mayan calendar provies.
calendar provies.
calendar provies. All prophecies about the future are
All prophecies about the future are
All prophecies about the future are impossible.
impossible.
impossible. Why? Because that which is contributo,
Why? Because that which is contributo,
Why? Because that which is contributo, not causal, but contributo to the future
not causal, but contributo to the future
not causal, but contributo to the future hasn't even happened yet. So how can you
hasn't even happened yet. So how can you
hasn't even happened yet. So how can you know the future? You understand?
know the future? You understand?
know the future? You understand? If you shoot billiards, if you shoot
If you shoot billiards, if you shoot
If you shoot billiards, if you shoot pool, you know, not until the pool ball
pool, you know, not until the pool ball
pool, you know, not until the pool ball hits and reverberates do you know what
hits and reverberates do you know what
hits and reverberates do you know what the future's going to be. The next ball
the future's going to be. The next ball
the future's going to be. The next ball is going to be hitting. You understand?
is going to be hitting. You understand?
is going to be hitting. You understand? You can't skip you can't skip it in pool
You can't skip you can't skip it in pool
You can't skip you can't skip it in pool or Yeah.
or Yeah.
or Yeah. Um natural healing. There's a book out
Um natural healing. There's a book out
Um natural healing. There's a book out there that is just absolutely Oh, I know
there that is just absolutely Oh, I know
there that is just absolutely Oh, I know why I put these things on there. because
why I put these things on there. because
why I put these things on there. because they're big sellers. People are
they're big sellers. People are
they're big sellers. People are impressed if it's popular. I think this
impressed if it's popular. I think this
impressed if it's popular. I think this was the number one book for a while and
was the number one book for a while and
was the number one book for a while and Da Vinci was number one. Celestine
Da Vinci was number one. Celestine
Da Vinci was number one. Celestine Prophecy was number one. People think,
Prophecy was number one. People think,
Prophecy was number one. People think, well, if everybody agrees with it and if
well, if everybody agrees with it and if
well, if everybody agrees with it and if everybody's buying it, it must be
everybody's buying it, it must be
everybody's buying it, it must be something I'm missing.
something I'm missing.
something I'm missing. So, popularity is no indication of
So, popularity is no indication of
So, popularity is no indication of truth.
natural healing book negative prayer
natural healing book negative prayer healing study was in the journal of
healing study was in the journal of
healing study was in the journal of cardiology and uh I don't know if I
cardiology and uh I don't know if I
cardiology and uh I don't know if I mentioned it last time or not was I
mentioned it last time or not was I
mentioned it last time or not was I forget what issue April or something
forget what issue April or something
forget what issue April or something anyway it got big headlines it was
anyway it got big headlines it was
anyway it got big headlines it was supported by the temple foundation at
supported by the temple foundation at
supported by the temple foundation at over a million dollars
over a million dollars
over a million dollars prayer you know healing prayer studies
prayer you know healing prayer studies
prayer you know healing prayer studies have been done for a long long time and
have been done for a long long time and
have been done for a long long time and the institute of noic science I think
the institute of noic science I think
the institute of noic science I think has a whole department of it listing
has a whole department of it listing
has a whole department of it listing hundreds and hundreds hundreds of them.
hundreds and hundreds hundreds of them.
hundreds and hundreds hundreds of them. Therefore, uh how could a negative pair
Therefore, uh how could a negative pair
Therefore, uh how could a negative pair healing
healing
healing uh it should have been neutral, right?
uh it should have been neutral, right?
uh it should have been neutral, right? No, it was negative. Showed that it was
No, it was negative. Showed that it was
No, it was negative. Showed that it was of no use. No use.
of no use. No use.
of no use. No use. That's contrary to 50 years of clinical
That's contrary to 50 years of clinical
That's contrary to 50 years of clinical experience of my my own self. So if
experience of my my own self. So if
experience of my my own self. So if prayer and spiritual contextualization
prayer and spiritual contextualization
prayer and spiritual contextualization did not affect healing
did not affect healing
did not affect healing then the millions of people who have
then the millions of people who have
then the millions of people who have recovered in alcoholic synonymous would
recovered in alcoholic synonymous would
recovered in alcoholic synonymous would not have recovered. Isn't that so? So
not have recovered. Isn't that so? So
not have recovered. Isn't that so? So the clinical evidence is all these
the clinical evidence is all these
the clinical evidence is all these millions of people had a hopeless
millions of people had a hopeless
millions of people had a hopeless progressive disease which condemns you
progressive disease which condemns you
progressive disease which condemns you to insanity and before aa appeared
to insanity and before aa appeared
to insanity and before aa appeared everybody died of alcoholism with wet
everybody died of alcoholism with wet
everybody died of alcoholism with wet brain and dementia and convulsions
brain and dementia and convulsions
brain and dementia and convulsions and now the recovery rate is
and now the recovery rate is
and now the recovery rate is extraordinary millions. So if prayer and
extraordinary millions. So if prayer and
extraordinary millions. So if prayer and spiritual intention had no effect how
spiritual intention had no effect how
spiritual intention had no effect how did all those millions of people
did all those millions of people
did all those millions of people recover? How did they recover and how do
recover? How did they recover and how do
recover? How did they recover and how do you account for that? Well, science
you account for that? Well, science
you account for that? Well, science which is in the 400s doesn't consider
which is in the 400s doesn't consider
which is in the 400s doesn't consider spirituality reality. So when they do
spirituality reality. So when they do
spirituality reality. So when they do their statistics, they don't even
their statistics, they don't even
their statistics, they don't even uh put it in. And I was reading recovery
uh put it in. And I was reading recovery
uh put it in. And I was reading recovery groups and alcohol the other day in a
groups and alcohol the other day in a
groups and alcohol the other day in a psychiatric journal and it says and and
psychiatric journal and it says and and
psychiatric journal and it says and and they're also advised to seek spiritual
they're also advised to seek spiritual
they're also advised to seek spiritual counseling, but then they don't divide
counseling, but then they don't divide
counseling, but then they don't divide up the groups based on whether they did
up the groups based on whether they did
up the groups based on whether they did or did not. And of course we know the
or did not. And of course we know the
or did not. And of course we know the recovery rate is extremely high in those
recovery rate is extremely high in those
recovery rate is extremely high in those who do and is zero in those who do not.
who do and is zero in those who do not.
who do and is zero in those who do not. So when we calibrated this million
So when we calibrated this million
So when we calibrated this million dollar study and you know the Templeton
dollar study and you know the Templeton
dollar study and you know the Templeton Foundation itself it's quite integrous
Foundation itself it's quite integrous
Foundation itself it's quite integrous calibrates at 500. Uh let's just
calibrates at 500. Uh let's just
calibrates at 500. Uh let's just recalibrate that that cardiology study.
recalibrate that that cardiology study.
recalibrate that that cardiology study. Uh we have permission to recalibrate it.
Uh we have permission to recalibrate it.
Uh we have permission to recalibrate it. It's over 190 195
It's over 190 195
It's over 190 195 at 190 supposed to be a scientific
at 190 supposed to be a scientific
at 190 supposed to be a scientific milliondoll study calibrates at 190. It
milliondoll study calibrates at 190. It
milliondoll study calibrates at 190. It means it's non-integrous by design plus
means it's non-integrous by design plus
means it's non-integrous by design plus by execution.
by execution.
by execution. And what it means to me is people who
And what it means to me is people who
And what it means to me is people who are atheistic and really hate to give
are atheistic and really hate to give
are atheistic and really hate to give any credit to God made sure that the
any credit to God made sure that the
any credit to God made sure that the statistics would come out supporting
statistics would come out supporting
statistics would come out supporting their position.
their position.
their position. Templeton, you know, who was very much
Templeton, you know, who was very much
Templeton, you know, who was very much into spirituality,
into spirituality,
into spirituality, uh, frankly got screwed out of $1
uh, frankly got screwed out of $1
uh, frankly got screwed out of $1 million.
million.
million. I could have saved him a million.
I could have saved him a million.
I could have saved him a million. >> Send it to Dave.
Susan give you answer in two seconds.
Susan give you answer in two seconds. This project is worth investing in. Her
This project is worth investing in. Her
This project is worth investing in. Her arm goes weak. You just saved a million
arm goes weak. You just saved a million
arm goes weak. You just saved a million dollars. I mean, you don't have to go
dollars. I mean, you don't have to go
dollars. I mean, you don't have to go through the whole loss, right? All
through the whole loss, right? All
through the whole loss, right? All right. So false u false opacity
right. So false u false opacity
right. So false u false opacity uh negative prayer healing study it was
uh negative prayer healing study it was
uh negative prayer healing study it was the journal of cardiology was April I
the journal of cardiology was April I
the journal of cardiology was April I think or so uh new aism itself is I say
think or so uh new aism itself is I say
think or so uh new aism itself is I say like a like a circus and it's full of
like a like a circus and it's full of
like a like a circus and it's full of all kinds of attractive
all kinds of attractive
all kinds of attractive byways most of many of them occult quite
byways most of many of them occult quite
byways most of many of them occult quite a few of them frankly quite dangerous to
a few of them frankly quite dangerous to
a few of them frankly quite dangerous to fool with people think oh this is
fool with people think oh this is
fool with people think oh this is innocent and um you know famously Ouija
innocent and um you know famously Ouija
innocent and um you know famously Ouija boards and other forms of divination and
boards and other forms of divination and
boards and other forms of divination and all kinds of tarot card readings etc. uh
all kinds of tarot card readings etc. uh
all kinds of tarot card readings etc. uh they they all calibrate below 200 and if
they they all calibrate below 200 and if
they they all calibrate below 200 and if you ask is this okay for me to go into
you ask is this okay for me to go into
you ask is this okay for me to go into you will always get a no you'll always
you will always get a no you'll always
you will always get a no you'll always get advised to leave it alone all right
get advised to leave it alone all right
get advised to leave it alone all right during one's spiritual adolescent
during one's spiritual adolescent
during one's spiritual adolescent naturally you got to check out
naturally you got to check out
naturally you got to check out everything and go to the nearest new age
everything and go to the nearest new age
everything and go to the nearest new age fair you know and of course it is a fair
fair you know and of course it is a fair
fair you know and of course it is a fair you know you go past all the booze and
you know you go past all the booze and
you know you go past all the booze and all the and all the pitchmen and all the
all the and all the pitchmen and all the
all the and all the pitchmen and all the beautiful rotating figures and and it's
beautiful rotating figures and and it's
beautiful rotating figures and and it's always mind dazzling you
always mind dazzling you
always mind dazzling you The the magic healing balls.
The the magic healing balls.
The the magic healing balls. Now they have them electronic.
The magic healing rays
The magic healing rays 42.95. You know,
okay, people check it out for the fun of
okay, people check it out for the fun of it. Opus day code. Again, you see the
it. Opus day code. Again, you see the
it. Opus day code. Again, you see the word code. It's again false protocol of
word code. It's again false protocol of
word code. It's again false protocol of the elders of Zion. And I I put in
the elders of Zion. And I I put in
the elders of Zion. And I I put in because
because
because falsity has such a profound effect.
falsity has such a profound effect.
falsity has such a profound effect. Um I had the snake pit. Oh, I still have
Um I had the snake pit. Oh, I still have
Um I had the snake pit. Oh, I still have it.
it.
it. Things that are false, people say, "Oh,
Things that are false, people say, "Oh,
Things that are false, people say, "Oh, you know, so it's not right." Have a
you know, so it's not right." Have a
you know, so it's not right." Have a profound effect. The whole nazi era of
profound effect. The whole nazi era of
profound effect. The whole nazi era of course the whole Nazi era was energized
course the whole Nazi era was energized
course the whole Nazi era was energized by the energy the protocol of the elders
by the energy the protocol of the elders
by the energy the protocol of the elders of Zion which I think calibrates I don't
of Zion which I think calibrates I don't
of Zion which I think calibrates I don't know 70 or 90 or something.
know 70 or 90 or something.
know 70 or 90 or something. So people you see how popular falsehood
So people you see how popular falsehood
So people you see how popular falsehood is
is
is people
people
people close to half the population still
close to half the population still
close to half the population still believes that fiction is truth. So the
believes that fiction is truth. So the
believes that fiction is truth. So the protocol the elders of Zion
protocol the elders of Zion
protocol the elders of Zion uh sucked in you know Henry Ford and
uh sucked in you know Henry Ford and
uh sucked in you know Henry Ford and great many people
great many people
great many people he printed up copies of it and sent out
he printed up copies of it and sent out
he printed up copies of it and sent out tens of thousands and anti-semitism
tens of thousands and anti-semitism
tens of thousands and anti-semitism of course was part of the fire of the
of course was part of the fire of the
of course was part of the fire of the Nazis whole the death camps etc. So
Nazis whole the death camps etc. So
Nazis whole the death camps etc. So they're not just innocent. You say oh
they're not just innocent. You say oh
they're not just innocent. You say oh that's just fiction. Yeah just fiction.
that's just fiction. Yeah just fiction.
that's just fiction. Yeah just fiction. 100 million people died in World War II.
100 million people died in World War II.
100 million people died in World War II. 100 million people protocol of the elder
100 million people protocol of the elder
100 million people protocol of the elder illers of Zion was part of the engine
illers of Zion was part of the engine
illers of Zion was part of the engine that drove it. Hatred picturing Jews as
that drove it. Hatred picturing Jews as
that drove it. Hatred picturing Jews as worms and you know uh the propaganda
worms and you know uh the propaganda
worms and you know uh the propaganda films.
films.
films. So therefore
So therefore
So therefore that which it pretends to be truth but
that which it pretends to be truth but
that which it pretends to be truth but is really fiction and fallacy
is really fiction and fallacy
is really fiction and fallacy you can see can be quite dangerous to
you can see can be quite dangerous to
you can see can be quite dangerous to life and quite devastating. Mhm.
life and quite devastating. Mhm.
life and quite devastating. Mhm. Therefore to know the truth of the
Therefore to know the truth of the
Therefore to know the truth of the falsehood about a matter is critical and
falsehood about a matter is critical and
falsehood about a matter is critical and the one the one reason so few people
the one the one reason so few people
the one the one reason so few people become actually enlightened in human
become actually enlightened in human
become actually enlightened in human life is because the way is strewn with
life is because the way is strewn with
life is because the way is strewn with falsehood. You could spend lifetimes
falsehood. You could spend lifetimes
falsehood. You could spend lifetimes going down these byways and following
going down these byways and following
going down these byways and following weird cults etc. Uh so it's important to
weird cults etc. Uh so it's important to
weird cults etc. Uh so it's important to see what is the impact of falsehood
see what is the impact of falsehood
see what is the impact of falsehood protocol enters a Zion. I'm sure kind
protocol enters a Zion. I'm sure kind
protocol enters a Zion. I'm sure kind some of these things that are current
some of these things that are current
some of these things that are current are having the same negative effect in
are having the same negative effect in
are having the same negative effect in other ways.
other ways.
other ways. Aliens of course are based on
Aliens of course are based on
Aliens of course are based on extraterrestrials and the idea that
extraterrestrials and the idea that
extraterrestrials and the idea that reincarnated is a lesser species. I have
reincarnated is a lesser species. I have
reincarnated is a lesser species. I have respect for it because of its ancient
respect for it because of its ancient
respect for it because of its ancient Hindu tradition. Let me ask if I have
Hindu tradition. Let me ask if I have
Hindu tradition. Let me ask if I have permission
permission
permission I have permission to ask about
I have permission to ask about
I have permission to ask about reincarnation as a luscious fury.
reincarnation as a luscious fury.
reincarnation as a luscious fury. That is a fact resistant.
That is a fact resistant.
That is a fact resistant. It does happen. It does not happen.
It is possible to reincarnate. Oh, for
It is possible to reincarnate. Oh, for Oh, I see. For humans to reincarnate at
Oh, I see. For humans to reincarnate at
Oh, I see. For humans to reincarnate at a lesser species resist.
a lesser species resist.
a lesser species resist. >> We've always gotten no on that.
>> We've always gotten no on that.
>> We've always gotten no on that. It's possible for a human
It's possible for a human
It's possible for a human who has certain karma to reincarnate
who has certain karma to reincarnate
who has certain karma to reincarnate on this plane as a lesser animal
on this plane as a lesser animal
on this plane as a lesser animal species. Resist.
species. Resist.
species. Resist. Isn't that funny? Now,
Isn't that funny? Now,
Isn't that funny? Now, >> we might not be asking it right.
>> we might not be asking it right.
>> we might not be asking it right. >> I may not have been asking the same way.
>> I may not have been asking the same way.
>> I may not have been asking the same way. We've always gotten that it is not so.
We've always gotten that it is not so.
We've always gotten that it is not so. However, I have respect for the Hindu,
However, I have respect for the Hindu,
However, I have respect for the Hindu, the ancient Hindu knowingness and
the ancient Hindu knowingness and
the ancient Hindu knowingness and tradition and spiritual awareness which
tradition and spiritual awareness which
tradition and spiritual awareness which says that it does happen. I mean, I have
says that it does happen. I mean, I have
says that it does happen. I mean, I have no objection to it. You know what I'm
no objection to it. You know what I'm
no objection to it. You know what I'm saying?
saying?
saying? I say we're up to four cats now
I say we're up to four cats now
I say we're up to four cats now when they got 60 to go to hit the
when they got 60 to go to hit the
when they got 60 to go to hit the record, the Johnson record here.
We're learning more and more about
We're learning more and more about multiple cats.
So we'll have to research that further.
So we'll have to research that further. So when we get a paradox like that, when
So when we get a paradox like that, when
So when we get a paradox like that, when we're alone, we will have to retract why
we're alone, we will have to retract why
we're alone, we will have to retract why we got that at that time, why we got
we got that at that time, why we got
we got that at that time, why we got this at this time. So we will have to
this at this time. So we will have to
this at this time. So we will have to research the mystery.
research the mystery.
research the mystery. All right.
All right.
All right. Reincarnation. This was the occurren
Reincarnation. This was the occurren
Reincarnation. This was the occurren reincarnation of the Buddha.
reincarnation of the Buddha.
reincarnation of the Buddha. uh Ram Baja banjam and that is that is
uh Ram Baja banjam and that is that is
uh Ram Baja banjam and that is that is not so the shroud of trin we've said
not so the shroud of trin we've said
not so the shroud of trin we've said before is also fake the book the snake
before is also fake the book the snake
before is also fake the book the snake pit I put in for the same reason as some
pit I put in for the same reason as some
pit I put in for the same reason as some of these others the devastating effect
of these others the devastating effect
of these others the devastating effect of a book of falsehood like the snake
of a book of falsehood like the snake
of a book of falsehood like the snake pit um is uh the fallout is tremendous
pit um is uh the fallout is tremendous
pit um is uh the fallout is tremendous you create um you create a false picture
you create um you create a false picture
you create um you create a false picture of reality. The public buys it. The
of reality. The public buys it. The
of reality. The public buys it. The political groups then uh group behind it
political groups then uh group behind it
political groups then uh group behind it and the next thing you know you have
and the next thing you know you have
and the next thing you know you have social destruction right in front of
social destruction right in front of
social destruction right in front of your eyes.
your eyes.
your eyes. Uh
Uh
Uh you know I practiced psychiatry 50 years
you know I practiced psychiatry 50 years
you know I practiced psychiatry 50 years in every possible way. Giant state
in every possible way. Giant state
in every possible way. Giant state hospitals,
hospitals,
hospitals, private practice. I had the largest
private practice. I had the largest
private practice. I had the largest psychiatric practice in the United
psychiatric practice in the United
psychiatric practice in the United States. I've served as
States. I've served as
States. I've served as uh New York State Department of Mental
uh New York State Department of Mental
uh New York State Department of Mental Hygiene. I was supervising psychiatrist.
Hygiene. I was supervising psychiatrist.
Hygiene. I was supervising psychiatrist. I've seen every aspect of psychiatry
I've seen every aspect of psychiatry
I've seen every aspect of psychiatry from left to right, private hospital,
from left to right, private hospital,
from left to right, private hospital, public hospital.
public hospital.
public hospital. None of what you see in these horrible
None of what you see in these horrible
None of what you see in these horrible things like the snake pit occurs.
things like the snake pit occurs.
things like the snake pit occurs. It's all felicious.
It's all felicious.
It's all felicious. The recount of the next patient from a
The recount of the next patient from a
The recount of the next patient from a hospital that is comes out paranoid is
hospital that is comes out paranoid is
hospital that is comes out paranoid is because they're paranoid.
because they're paranoid.
because they're paranoid. That's why they were in the pokey.
No, the psychologist were not
No, the psychologist were not experimenting on them
experimenting on them
experimenting on them etc. All right. All right. But what is
etc. All right. All right. But what is
etc. All right. All right. But what is the effect of this kind of thing? What
the effect of this kind of thing? What
the effect of this kind of thing? What the effect of that was? Well, it was
the effect of that was? Well, it was
the effect of that was? Well, it was really the combination of relativism
really the combination of relativism
really the combination of relativism plus things like the snake pit. What
plus things like the snake pit. What
plus things like the snake pit. What happened is that the hospitals emptied
happened is that the hospitals emptied
happened is that the hospitals emptied out. See, and now the mentally ill will
out. See, and now the mentally ill will
out. See, and now the mentally ill will wander the streets where they get no
wander the streets where they get no
wander the streets where they get no treatment, no dental care, no health
treatment, no dental care, no health
treatment, no dental care, no health care, no nutritionist care, no
care, no nutritionist care, no
care, no nutritionist care, no counseling, no psychiatric meds, no
counseling, no psychiatric meds, no
counseling, no psychiatric meds, no doctor, no protection from being savaged
doctor, no protection from being savaged
doctor, no protection from being savaged by the lower elements. And the old
by the lower elements. And the old
by the lower elements. And the old fashioned state hospital,
fashioned state hospital,
fashioned state hospital, uh, you know, which I knew extremely
uh, you know, which I knew extremely
uh, you know, which I knew extremely well,
well,
well, uh, was a home and a and a source of
uh, was a home and a and a source of
uh, was a home and a and a source of protection. And it was its own community
protection. And it was its own community
protection. And it was its own community where everybody understood each other
where everybody understood each other
where everybody understood each other and then they just accepted you for who
and then they just accepted you for who
and then they just accepted you for who you were. And if you got well enough to
you were. And if you got well enough to
you were. And if you got well enough to get out, the hospital was glad to get
get out, the hospital was glad to get
get out, the hospital was glad to get rid of you. I mean, the hospital didn't
rid of you. I mean, the hospital didn't
rid of you. I mean, the hospital didn't make money on patients. We were a state
make money on patients. We were a state
make money on patients. We were a state hospital. We got paid by the bid.
hospital. We got paid by the bid.
hospital. We got paid by the bid. Whether the bid was full or not, we
Whether the bid was full or not, we
Whether the bid was full or not, we didn't care. So, there was no reason,
didn't care. So, there was no reason,
didn't care. So, there was no reason, etc. So, a great tragedy came out of it.
etc. So, a great tragedy came out of it.
etc. So, a great tragedy came out of it. And now you see how the mentally ill are
And now you see how the mentally ill are
And now you see how the mentally ill are in everyday's paper. They're involved in
in everyday's paper. They're involved in
in everyday's paper. They're involved in burglary and drugs and rape and and uh
burglary and drugs and rape and and uh
burglary and drugs and rape and and uh starve to death on the streets and
starve to death on the streets and
starve to death on the streets and become savaged and and and of course
become savaged and and and of course
become savaged and and and of course they're addicted to drugs and alcohol.
they're addicted to drugs and alcohol.
they're addicted to drugs and alcohol. So what what was a nurturing environment
So what what was a nurturing environment
So what what was a nurturing environment the old state hospital I calibrated at
the old state hospital I calibrated at
the old state hospital I calibrated at what what did I was 350 or something you
what what did I was 350 or something you
what what did I was 350 or something you know anyway positive you know and uh and
know anyway positive you know and uh and
know anyway positive you know and uh and now the street culture calibrates you
now the street culture calibrates you
now the street culture calibrates you know about 110 or something like that
know about 110 or something like that
know about 110 or something like that about 110 so what they did is take them
about 110 so what they did is take them
about 110 so what they did is take them out of a safe protective environment
out of a safe protective environment
out of a safe protective environment that had hope for the future and threw
that had hope for the future and threw
that had hope for the future and threw them on the street where they have no
them on the street where they have no
them on the street where they have no hope for the future and that was
hope for the future and that was
hope for the future and that was primarily the result of falsehood
primarily the result of falsehood
primarily the result of falsehood Snake Pit. There was another movie like
Snake Pit. There was another movie like
Snake Pit. There was another movie like that. Um. Mhm.
that. Um. Mhm.
that. Um. Mhm. and Scientology picked up on that anti-
and Scientology picked up on that anti-
and Scientology picked up on that anti- establishment um
establishment um
establishment um psychiatrist wicked same trip you know
psychiatrist wicked same trip you know
psychiatrist wicked same trip you know and of course all of that was also
and of course all of that was also
and of course all of that was also fueled by relativism
fueled by relativism
fueled by relativism and relativism some of the best
and relativism some of the best
and relativism some of the best philosophers
philosophers
philosophers uh behind relativism I'm ashamed to say
uh behind relativism I'm ashamed to say
uh behind relativism I'm ashamed to say were psychiatrists
were psychiatrists
were psychiatrists and uh so that kind of thinking that
and uh so that kind of thinking that
and uh so that kind of thinking that kind of thinking then putting the blame
kind of thinking then putting the blame
kind of thinking then putting the blame on somebody etc. It's a relativism I
on somebody etc. It's a relativism I
on somebody etc. It's a relativism I don't want to get off on because that's
don't want to get off on because that's
don't want to get off on because that's a whole uh lecture in itself
a whole uh lecture in itself
a whole uh lecture in itself reincarnation of the Buddha that's not
reincarnation of the Buddha that's not
reincarnation of the Buddha that's not the Buddha reincarnated there despite
the Buddha reincarnated there despite
the Buddha reincarnated there despite the papers the turin as we said
the papers the turin as we said
the papers the turin as we said this book had a very injurious solar
this book had a very injurious solar
this book had a very injurious solar temple is I forget the name of that guy
temple is I forget the name of that guy
temple is I forget the name of that guy he's esoteric
he's esoteric
he's esoteric star seed children
star seed children
star seed children trans mediumship we said UFOs UFO
trans mediumship we said UFOs UFO
trans mediumship we said UFOs UFO religions and everybody asked me about
religions and everybody asked me about
religions and everybody asked me about the uranche book. I hate to tell them
the uranche book. I hate to tell them
the uranche book. I hate to tell them that it's only 150, but that's a fact.
that it's only 150, but that's a fact.
that it's only 150, but that's a fact. I've rechecked it over and over again,
I've rechecked it over and over again,
I've rechecked it over and over again, and I know lots of people like it. It's
and I know lots of people like it. It's
and I know lots of people like it. It's a very thick book and it'll keep you
a very thick book and it'll keep you
a very thick book and it'll keep you entertained for a few years.
entertained for a few years.
entertained for a few years. Another dimension in which they claim
Another dimension in which they claim
Another dimension in which they claim Christ is part of the other dimension. I
Christ is part of the other dimension. I
Christ is part of the other dimension. I thought that's interesting.
thought that's interesting.
thought that's interesting. All right. It's just good to know about
All right. It's just good to know about
All right. It's just good to know about it because the pitfalls along the way uh
it because the pitfalls along the way uh
it because the pitfalls along the way uh the attraction of these things appeals
the attraction of these things appeals
the attraction of these things appeals to the curious child in us. The child in
to the curious child in us. The child in
to the curious child in us. The child in us is innocent.
us is innocent.
us is innocent. So the child in us is both our salvation
So the child in us is both our salvation
So the child in us is both our salvation uh and our downfall.
uh and our downfall.
uh and our downfall. Why? Because spiritual progress is only
Why? Because spiritual progress is only
Why? Because spiritual progress is only made by faith. Made by faith and trust.
made by faith. Made by faith and trust.
made by faith. Made by faith and trust. In fact, we don't know anything except
In fact, we don't know anything except
In fact, we don't know anything except by faith and trust. So faith and trust
by faith and trust. So faith and trust
by faith and trust. So faith and trust is intrinsic
is intrinsic
is intrinsic uh to the human mentality. It arises in
uh to the human mentality. It arises in
uh to the human mentality. It arises in children.
The human mind because it can't tell
The human mind because it can't tell essence from perception is extremely
essence from perception is extremely
essence from perception is extremely naive and innocent and vulnerable
naive and innocent and vulnerable
naive and innocent and vulnerable therefore to falsehood and to error.
therefore to falsehood and to error.
therefore to falsehood and to error. Faith and trust are the basics by which
Faith and trust are the basics by which
Faith and trust are the basics by which all spiritual progress is made.
all spiritual progress is made.
all spiritual progress is made. Now that's the problem. That's the re
Now that's the problem. That's the re
Now that's the problem. That's the re the wonderful thing. That's also the
the wonderful thing. That's also the
the wonderful thing. That's also the downside.
downside.
downside. The downside why nobody gets enlightened
The downside why nobody gets enlightened
The downside why nobody gets enlightened is because it is innocent and naive. It
is because it is innocent and naive. It
is because it is innocent and naive. It can't tell truth from falsehood and it
can't tell truth from falsehood and it
can't tell truth from falsehood and it buys falsehood because of its basic
buys falsehood because of its basic
buys falsehood because of its basic innocence.
innocence.
innocence. Without that basic capacity for trust
Without that basic capacity for trust
Without that basic capacity for trust and faith, spiritual progress is not
and faith, spiritual progress is not
and faith, spiritual progress is not possible.
possible.
possible. So first of all, it's a requirement.
So first of all, it's a requirement.
So first of all, it's a requirement. On the other hand, it has faith and
On the other hand, it has faith and
On the other hand, it has faith and trust in illusion with the same tenacity
trust in illusion with the same tenacity
trust in illusion with the same tenacity it does in truth. So the mind unaded is
it does in truth. So the mind unaded is
it does in truth. So the mind unaded is unable to discern truth from falsehood.
unable to discern truth from falsehood.
unable to discern truth from falsehood. The human mind unaded. Anybody doubt
The human mind unaded. Anybody doubt
The human mind unaded. Anybody doubt that
that
that the Buddha is not here today? Okay.
Therefore, all the great teachers have
Therefore, all the great teachers have said there's only one human error and
said there's only one human error and
said there's only one human error and that is ignorance. The ignorance
that is ignorance. The ignorance
that is ignorance. The ignorance unfortunately is inbornne. It's
unfortunately is inbornne. It's
unfortunately is inbornne. It's intrinsic to the human condition. So
intrinsic to the human condition. So
intrinsic to the human condition. So we're here, you know, to transcend what
we're here, you know, to transcend what
we're here, you know, to transcend what is an intrinsic
is an intrinsic
is an intrinsic uh on the one hand defect and on the
uh on the one hand defect and on the
uh on the one hand defect and on the other hand it's the road to
other hand it's the road to
other hand it's the road to enlightenment.
enlightenment.
enlightenment. There are 10,000 ways to God as I said
There are 10,000 ways to God as I said
There are 10,000 ways to God as I said and we've covered quite a few of them.
and we've covered quite a few of them.
and we've covered quite a few of them. For any of them to work, you have to
For any of them to work, you have to
For any of them to work, you have to have faith and confidence and trust.
have faith and confidence and trust.
have faith and confidence and trust. Faith, confidence, and trust in today's
Faith, confidence, and trust in today's
Faith, confidence, and trust in today's world has been ravaged. Ravaged. It's a
world has been ravaged. Ravaged. It's a
world has been ravaged. Ravaged. It's a wonder to me that anybody is still
wonder to me that anybody is still
wonder to me that anybody is still capable of faith and trust
capable of faith and trust
capable of faith and trust seeing as
seeing as
seeing as the fallacy that goes on in the media uh
the fallacy that goes on in the media uh
the fallacy that goes on in the media uh just you know ordinary media just the
just you know ordinary media just the
just you know ordinary media just the ordinary media uh let's see uh newspaper
ordinary media uh let's see uh newspaper
ordinary media uh let's see uh newspaper I have in mind I can calibrate the
I have in mind I can calibrate the
I have in mind I can calibrate the editorial pages it's over 190 195
editorial pages it's over 190 195
editorial pages it's over 190 195 New York Times editorial pages is
New York Times editorial pages is
New York Times editorial pages is currently calibrated 190. So in as much
currently calibrated 190. So in as much
currently calibrated 190. So in as much as truth starts at 200,
as truth starts at 200,
as truth starts at 200, what hope is there for mankind? I don't
what hope is there for mankind? I don't
what hope is there for mankind? I don't know
know
know what hope is there for mankind.
what hope is there for mankind.
what hope is there for mankind. Surrounded by fallacy, the human mind
Surrounded by fallacy, the human mind
Surrounded by fallacy, the human mind unaded is unable to discern truth from
unaded is unable to discern truth from
unaded is unable to discern truth from falsehood.
falsehood.
falsehood. And then of course
And then of course
And then of course within that is the innocence of the
within that is the innocence of the
within that is the innocence of the child that has a provisional faith and
child that has a provisional faith and
child that has a provisional faith and trust in everything as it crosses their
trust in everything as it crosses their
trust in everything as it crosses their vision. Faith and trust. It's the faith
vision. Faith and trust. It's the faith
vision. Faith and trust. It's the faith and trust that grows out of the child's
and trust that grows out of the child's
and trust that grows out of the child's dependence on the parent. Therefore it
dependence on the parent. Therefore it
dependence on the parent. Therefore it is contextualized as necessary for
is contextualized as necessary for
is contextualized as necessary for survival.
survival.
survival. You have to have faith and trust. So you
You have to have faith and trust. So you
You have to have faith and trust. So you see the tremendous importance of being
see the tremendous importance of being
see the tremendous importance of being able to discern truth from falsehood.
able to discern truth from falsehood.
able to discern truth from falsehood. So the gift I was given on asked was
So the gift I was given on asked was
So the gift I was given on asked was suddenly out of nothing seeing it.
suddenly out of nothing seeing it.
suddenly out of nothing seeing it. Suddenly out of nothing seeing for the
Suddenly out of nothing seeing for the
Suddenly out of nothing seeing for the first time the discernment of truth to
first time the discernment of truth to
first time the discernment of truth to falsehood in all of human history. Wow.
falsehood in all of human history. Wow.
falsehood in all of human history. Wow. What a responsibility. You know what I'm
What a responsibility. You know what I'm
What a responsibility. You know what I'm saying?
I can see what's going to happen to the
I can see what's going to happen to the rest of my life because you can't
rest of my life because you can't
rest of my life because you can't exactly just ignore that. Dedicated to
exactly just ignore that. Dedicated to
exactly just ignore that. Dedicated to demonstrating it, calibrating it,
demonstrating it, calibrating it,
demonstrating it, calibrating it, explaining it, documenting it, and then
explaining it, documenting it, and then
explaining it, documenting it, and then doing it thousands of times and then
doing it thousands of times and then
doing it thousands of times and then sharing it with everyone for the
sharing it with everyone for the
sharing it with everyone for the long-term benefit. Don't you wish you
long-term benefit. Don't you wish you
long-term benefit. Don't you wish you had a list like this for your stocks,
had a list like this for your stocks,
had a list like this for your stocks, stock market, right?
You wish you knew the winners and were
You wish you knew the winners and were the losers.
the losers.
the losers. So
So
So the value then of knowing truth from
the value then of knowing truth from
the value then of knowing truth from falsehood is it saves many lifetimes.
falsehood is it saves many lifetimes.
falsehood is it saves many lifetimes. the likelihood of becoming enlightened
the likelihood of becoming enlightened
the likelihood of becoming enlightened in today's world as we've said before
in today's world as we've said before
in today's world as we've said before and to by today's world I mean that the
and to by today's world I mean that the
and to by today's world I mean that the information that we we share here is
information that we we share here is
information that we we share here is 1,000 times greater than before this
1,000 times greater than before this
1,000 times greater than before this information was available chances of
information was available chances of
information was available chances of becoming enlightened are 1,000 times
becoming enlightened are 1,000 times
becoming enlightened are 1,000 times greater
greater
greater because you now have uh a pathway that's
because you now have uh a pathway that's
because you now have uh a pathway that's been searched light you know we've
been searched light you know we've
been searched light you know we've looked at this pathway was search light
looked at this pathway was search light
looked at this pathway was search light and we've verified it we've already made
and we've verified it we've already made
and we've verified it we've already made the trip ahead of time that it's a safe
the trip ahead of time that it's a safe
the trip ahead of time that it's a safe pathway and that it takes you to truth
pathway and that it takes you to truth
pathway and that it takes you to truth and then you can verify your trip all
and then you can verify your trip all
and then you can verify your trip all along the way.
along the way.
along the way. So the value of consciousness research
So the value of consciousness research
So the value of consciousness research is for the first time it gave us a
is for the first time it gave us a
is for the first time it gave us a compass and the mankind before was like
compass and the mankind before was like
compass and the mankind before was like a sailor without a compass and hopefully
a sailor without a compass and hopefully
a sailor without a compass and hopefully this was the right direction and
this was the right direction and
this was the right direction and hopefully that was the right direction
hopefully that was the right direction
hopefully that was the right direction but the number of ships at the bottom of
but the number of ships at the bottom of
but the number of ships at the bottom of the sea. I remember program on the great
the sea. I remember program on the great
the sea. I remember program on the great lakes I can hardly believe it there are
lakes I can hardly believe it there are
lakes I can hardly believe it there are 6,000 ships at the bottom of the great
6,000 ships at the bottom of the great
6,000 ships at the bottom of the great lakes alone. 6,000 just the great lakes.
lakes alone. 6,000 just the great lakes.
lakes alone. 6,000 just the great lakes. Imagine what must be in the oceans.
Imagine what must be in the oceans.
Imagine what must be in the oceans. Well, from not having a compass, not
Well, from not having a compass, not
Well, from not having a compass, not knowing which way you're going and uh
knowing which way you're going and uh
knowing which way you're going and uh not being able to control your own
not being able to control your own
not being able to control your own destiny. Of course, you can't control
destiny. Of course, you can't control
destiny. Of course, you can't control your own destiny, but you can certainly
your own destiny, but you can certainly
your own destiny, but you can certainly set up likelihoods.
set up likelihoods.
set up likelihoods. So, by devotion to truth and that's the
So, by devotion to truth and that's the
So, by devotion to truth and that's the reason for the title of devotional
reason for the title of devotional
reason for the title of devotional non-duality. By devotion to truth uh you
non-duality. By devotion to truth uh you
non-duality. By devotion to truth uh you bring to yourself you bring you now
bring to yourself you bring you now
bring to yourself you bring you now bring to yourself information and the
bring to yourself information and the
bring to yourself information and the capacity to understand things that did
capacity to understand things that did
capacity to understand things that did not exist before
not exist before
not exist before because intention is very powerful. Your
because intention is very powerful. Your
because intention is very powerful. Your intention to become enlightened your
intention to become enlightened your
intention to become enlightened your intention to know the truth to transcend
intention to know the truth to transcend
intention to know the truth to transcend negativity etc. That intention alone
negativity etc. That intention alone
negativity etc. That intention alone already begins to change uh the effects
already begins to change uh the effects
already begins to change uh the effects and we know that's been supported by
and we know that's been supported by
and we know that's been supported by advanced theoretical physics. is the
advanced theoretical physics. is the
advanced theoretical physics. is the Heisenberg principle.
Heisenberg principle.
Heisenberg principle. Other things that we've said here that
Other things that we've said here that
Other things that we've said here that are outrageous and some things I haven't
are outrageous and some things I haven't
are outrageous and some things I haven't even said them because they are too
even said them because they are too
even said them because they are too outrageous.
I wait till there's some corroboration
I wait till there's some corroboration out there and then I said but I did say
out there and then I said but I did say
out there and then I said but I did say you know one of the books or lectures
you know one of the books or lectures
you know one of the books or lectures somewhere you know that even time and
somewhere you know that even time and
somewhere you know that even time and and position in space uh are
and position in space uh are
and position in space uh are projectionists. They have no independent
projectionists. They have no independent
projectionists. They have no independent existence.
existence.
existence. There isn't a such thing as time in
There isn't a such thing as time in
There isn't a such thing as time in reality. It's a projection that we put
reality. It's a projection that we put
reality. It's a projection that we put on to a sequence. We see sequence.
on to a sequence. We see sequence.
on to a sequence. We see sequence. Therefore, we call it time and see it as
Therefore, we call it time and see it as
Therefore, we call it time and see it as sequential. Uh so the latest thing that
sequential. Uh so the latest thing that
sequential. Uh so the latest thing that I read recently in the advanced
I read recently in the advanced
I read recently in the advanced theoretical physics is by um is by um
theoretical physics is by um is by um
theoretical physics is by um is by um is by um
is by um
is by um I don't know who is spying
anyway it'll come to me who is spying
anyway it'll come to me who is spying and uh it it jump it jumps that advanced
and uh it it jump it jumps that advanced
and uh it it jump it jumps that advanced theoretical physics is now um it'll come
theoretical physics is now um it'll come
theoretical physics is now um it'll come to me the
to me the
to me the uh it comes to the conclusion that that
uh it comes to the conclusion that that
uh it comes to the conclusion that that time in fact any period periods of time
time in fact any period periods of time
time in fact any period periods of time etc are all projections from
etc are all projections from
etc are all projections from consciousness which is what we've said
consciousness which is what we've said
consciousness which is what we've said all along that time and sequence and all
all along that time and sequence and all
all along that time and sequence and all those are all projections within reality
those are all projections within reality
those are all projections within reality you know all things are emerging where
you know all things are emerging where
you know all things are emerging where because what you're seeing is
because what you're seeing is
because what you're seeing is potentiality becoming actuality
potentiality becoming actuality
potentiality becoming actuality when it's energized by uh intention
when it's energized by uh intention
when it's energized by uh intention Especially by intention
Especially by intention
Especially by intention potentiality becomes actuality and
potentiality becomes actuality and
potentiality becomes actuality and therefore becomes experiential.
therefore becomes experiential.
therefore becomes experiential. The potential therefore for
The potential therefore for
The potential therefore for enlightenment resides within everyone
enlightenment resides within everyone
enlightenment resides within everyone here. Let's check make sure there's no
here. Let's check make sure there's no
here. Let's check make sure there's no you know what's here.
you know what's here.
you know what's here. It's 100% for this audience resist.
It's 100% for this audience resist.
It's 100% for this audience resist. That means you
That means you
That means you all right for some reason this group
all right for some reason this group
all right for some reason this group selected
selected
selected self- selected have come together
self- selected have come together
self- selected have come together uh because they have sensed by probably
uh because they have sensed by probably
uh because they have sensed by probably by karmic something or other that uh
by karmic something or other that uh
by karmic something or other that uh I don't know I can't remember the name
I don't know I can't remember the name
I don't know I can't remember the name of that oh yes
of that oh yes
of that oh yes >> Peter Lind l y n d Peter quantum mechan
>> Peter Lind l y n d Peter quantum mechan
>> Peter Lind l y n d Peter quantum mechan mechanics studied so Peter Lind he's on
mechanics studied so Peter Lind he's on
mechanics studied so Peter Lind he's on the email internet thing ww WW machine
the email internet thing ww WW machine
the email internet thing ww WW machine thing as a
thing as a
thing as a you put Lynch Peter. No, what is the
you put Lynch Peter. No, what is the
you put Lynch Peter. No, what is the name? Yeah. Anyway, you put it in there
name? Yeah. Anyway, you put it in there
name? Yeah. Anyway, you put it in there and uh then you get you get the whole
and uh then you get you get the whole
and uh then you get you get the whole print out. It's very interesting. L Y N
print out. It's very interesting. L Y N
print out. It's very interesting. L Y N D Peter Quantum
D Peter Quantum
D Peter Quantum Mechanics confirms
Mechanics confirms
Mechanics confirms our own consciousness studies that time
our own consciousness studies that time
our own consciousness studies that time itself is a projection.
itself is a projection.
itself is a projection. Consequently, as you see from this
Consequently, as you see from this
Consequently, as you see from this morning's slide, all things about the
morning's slide, all things about the
morning's slide, all things about the future uh uh make your arm of the week,
future uh uh make your arm of the week,
future uh uh make your arm of the week, man. We just got confirmation of that
man. We just got confirmation of that
man. We just got confirmation of that from quantum mechanics, didn't we? We
from quantum mechanics, didn't we? We
from quantum mechanics, didn't we? We just got
just got
just got if there is no such reality
if there is no such reality
if there is no such reality as time
as time
as time then how can we predict what's in the
then how can we predict what's in the
then how can we predict what's in the future
future
future as much as time doesn't exist as a
as much as time doesn't exist as a
as much as time doesn't exist as a reality. You understand? Therefore all
reality. You understand? Therefore all
reality. You understand? Therefore all predictions about the future are
predictions about the future are
predictions about the future are fantasies
fantasies
fantasies are fantasies. that we said that
are fantasies. that we said that
are fantasies. that we said that heretical scientific statement here a
heretical scientific statement here a
heretical scientific statement here a long time ago that the universe that you
long time ago that the universe that you
long time ago that the universe that you see is a projection. It's evolutionary
see is a projection. It's evolutionary
see is a projection. It's evolutionary and there's no way of saying anything
and there's no way of saying anything
and there's no way of saying anything about the future. There's probabilities
about the future. There's probabilities
about the future. There's probabilities within the three-dimensional
within the three-dimensional
within the three-dimensional linear domain probabilities. Yes, there
linear domain probabilities. Yes, there
linear domain probabilities. Yes, there is.
is.
is. But it's not causal. is each thing being
But it's not causal. is each thing being
But it's not causal. is each thing being uh the fullest of what it can be when
uh the fullest of what it can be when
uh the fullest of what it can be when local conditions are appropriate.
local conditions are appropriate.
local conditions are appropriate. So if there's no time then neither are
So if there's no time then neither are
So if there's no time then neither are there intervals. Neither is there any
there intervals. Neither is there any
there intervals. Neither is there any such thing as now. Neither is there any
such thing as now. Neither is there any
such thing as now. Neither is there any such thing as then or the future or the
such thing as then or the future or the
such thing as then or the future or the past. These are all uh which way you're
past. These are all uh which way you're
past. These are all uh which way you're running the film. You can run it
running the film. You can run it
running the film. You can run it backwards and you can run it forwards,
backwards and you can run it forwards,
backwards and you can run it forwards, but that's just a readout and no such
but that's just a readout and no such
but that's just a readout and no such thing exists in reality with a capital
thing exists in reality with a capital
thing exists in reality with a capital R. In reality with a capital R, there's
R. In reality with a capital R, there's
R. In reality with a capital R, there's no past, present, future. Yes. And there
no past, present, future. Yes. And there
no past, present, future. Yes. And there is no such thing as time.
is no such thing as time.
is no such thing as time. So, um, I thought I'll send Peter, what
So, um, I thought I'll send Peter, what
So, um, I thought I'll send Peter, what is his name again? Lynn. Oh, yes.
I don't know how to do an email. So, I
I don't know how to do an email. So, I tell the girls, send him an email and
tell the girls, send him an email and
tell the girls, send him an email and say, "We think it's great and we have
say, "We think it's great and we have
say, "We think it's great and we have certain cooperation. You'd like to know
certain cooperation. You'd like to know
certain cooperation. You'd like to know if I've been agreeing with them all
if I've been agreeing with them all
if I've been agreeing with them all along from the viewpoint of
along from the viewpoint of
along from the viewpoint of consciousness." So this is the first
consciousness." So this is the first
consciousness." So this is the first time that other than the Heisenberg
time that other than the Heisenberg
time that other than the Heisenberg principle that advanced theoretical
principle that advanced theoretical
principle that advanced theoretical physics, quantum mechanics, etc. is
physics, quantum mechanics, etc. is
physics, quantum mechanics, etc. is being looked at strictly from the
being looked at strictly from the
being looked at strictly from the viewpoint of consciousness. From the
viewpoint of consciousness. From the
viewpoint of consciousness. From the viewpoint of consciousness, no such
viewpoint of consciousness, no such
viewpoint of consciousness, no such thing is possible as time and therefore
thing is possible as time and therefore
thing is possible as time and therefore interval. Isn't that interesting?
interval. Isn't that interesting?
interval. Isn't that interesting? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Okay. I know on your way home you'll be
>> Okay. I know on your way home you'll be
>> Okay. I know on your way home you'll be happy without it.
I just think it's interesting when we
I just think it's interesting when we get corroboration from other fields. So
get corroboration from other fields. So
get corroboration from other fields. So the closest thing within the linear
the closest thing within the linear
the closest thing within the linear domain, scientific domain and what we uh
domain, scientific domain and what we uh
domain, scientific domain and what we uh talk about is actually quantum mechanics
talk about is actually quantum mechanics
talk about is actually quantum mechanics and advanced uh theoretical physics is
and advanced uh theoretical physics is
and advanced uh theoretical physics is pretty pretty well correlated. We're
pretty pretty well correlated. We're
pretty pretty well correlated. We're pretty well correlated and this sort of
pretty well correlated and this sort of
pretty well correlated and this sort of puts in the last missing link. All
puts in the last missing link. All
puts in the last missing link. All right. So I want to go back to the
right. So I want to go back to the
right. So I want to go back to the slides. Is there any question about what
slides. Is there any question about what
slides. Is there any question about what we've spoken about this morning? Anybody
we've spoken about this morning? Anybody
we've spoken about this morning? Anybody have doubts? Um,
have doubts? Um,
have doubts? Um, is it okay with you? What
is it okay with you? What
is it okay with you? What >> channel?
>> Somebody have to repeat a question to
>> Somebody have to repeat a question to me.
me.
me. >> What?
>> What?
>> What? >> And
>> And
>> And supposedly I'm not sure. I heard that it
supposedly I'm not sure. I heard that it
supposedly I'm not sure. I heard that it was channel. I'm not sure how it was
was channel. I'm not sure how it was
was channel. I'm not sure how it was written, but it was something like
written, but it was something like
written, but it was something like >> um it's it's unique. You know the course
>> um it's it's unique. You know the course
>> um it's it's unique. You know the course of miracles calibrates the workbook at
of miracles calibrates the workbook at
of miracles calibrates the workbook at 600.
600.
600. Uh I knew Helen, I knew Bill, I knew all
Uh I knew Helen, I knew Bill, I knew all
Uh I knew Helen, I knew Bill, I knew all the people involved with the whole
the people involved with the whole
the people involved with the whole thing. And uh Helen took it by inner
thing. And uh Helen took it by inner
thing. And uh Helen took it by inner dictation.
dictation.
dictation. Uh it was not another some external
Uh it was not another some external
Uh it was not another some external entity. It came as a knowingness and she
entity. It came as a knowingness and she
entity. It came as a knowingness and she typed the knowingness as it came in. She
typed the knowingness as it came in. She
typed the knowingness as it came in. She herself didn't even understand it nor
herself didn't even understand it nor
herself didn't even understand it nor did she follow it. She didn't even
did she follow it. She didn't even
did she follow it. She didn't even practice the course of miracles.
She was a severe obsessive also at worry
She was a severe obsessive also at worry war and she just never surrendered and
war and she just never surrendered and
war and she just never surrendered and did the course you know
did the course you know
did the course you know so the course of miracles itself is
so the course of miracles itself is
so the course of miracles itself is unique you know you could do a lot of
unique you know you could do a lot of
unique you know you could do a lot of research on it and discovered a lot of
research on it and discovered a lot of
research on it and discovered a lot of things about it uh all I'm interested in
things about it uh all I'm interested in
things about it uh all I'm interested in is that it's practical and that it works
is that it's practical and that it works
is that it's practical and that it works it's practical and it works and of
it's practical and it works and of
it's practical and it works and of course a lot of people do it along with
course a lot of people do it along with
course a lot of people do it along with other things you know you do this that
other things you know you do this that
other things you know you do this that and you also do the course of miracles
and you also do the course of miracles
and you also do the course of miracles And many people of course have recovered
And many people of course have recovered
And many people of course have recovered from many illnesses in the clinic back
from many illnesses in the clinic back
from many illnesses in the clinic back east. Uh you know we had the second
east. Uh you know we had the second
east. Uh you know we had the second attitudinal healing center in the United
attitudinal healing center in the United
attitudinal healing center in the United States. The first was in Tibon
States. The first was in Tibon
States. The first was in Tibon uh and we had the second in the United
uh and we had the second in the United
uh and we had the second in the United States and we saw you know miraculous
States and we saw you know miraculous
States and we saw you know miraculous recoveries from all kinds of things all
recoveries from all kinds of things all
recoveries from all kinds of things all kinds of things. All kinds of
kinds of things. All kinds of
kinds of things. All kinds of non-reoverable illnesses. If you do the
non-reoverable illnesses. If you do the
non-reoverable illnesses. If you do the course of miracles, you won't care
course of miracles, you won't care
course of miracles, you won't care whether you're if you've done it. If
whether you're if you've done it. If
whether you're if you've done it. If you've really done the course of
you've really done the course of
you've really done the course of miracles, whether you recover physically
miracles, whether you recover physically
miracles, whether you recover physically or not is irrelevant.
In the beginning, you're trying to
In the beginning, you're trying to control it. You know, you got karmic
control it. You know, you got karmic
control it. You know, you got karmic consequences all over the place and
consequences all over the place and
consequences all over the place and you're going to try and control it.
you're going to try and control it.
you're going to try and control it. Yeah. Right. So, if you do the course of
Yeah. Right. So, if you do the course of
Yeah. Right. So, if you do the course of miracles, uh you surrender at such a
miracles, uh you surrender at such a
miracles, uh you surrender at such a depth that whether this illness
depth that whether this illness
depth that whether this illness disappears or not is, you know,
disappears or not is, you know,
disappears or not is, you know, academic. It's nice if it does. I can
academic. It's nice if it does. I can
academic. It's nice if it does. I can leave the grudges home and if you don't
leave the grudges home and if you don't
leave the grudges home and if you don't I'll keep the grudges you know what so
I'll keep the grudges you know what so
I'll keep the grudges you know what so when you've really done the course of
when you've really done the course of
when you've really done the course of miracles you've completely surrendered
miracles you've completely surrendered
miracles you've completely surrendered it to God and to God's will and you see
it to God and to God's will and you see
it to God and to God's will and you see it differently that it's the fulfillment
it differently that it's the fulfillment
it differently that it's the fulfillment of some potential that is of great
of some potential that is of great
of some potential that is of great benefit. So therefore to really do the
benefit. So therefore to really do the
benefit. So therefore to really do the course um in order to recover that's
course um in order to recover that's
course um in order to recover that's what attracts a lot of people beginning
what attracts a lot of people beginning
what attracts a lot of people beginning in order to recover. Uh they've heard
in order to recover. Uh they've heard
in order to recover. Uh they've heard that you can recover from anything with
that you can recover from anything with
that you can recover from anything with the course of miracles and I've seen
the course of miracles and I've seen
the course of miracles and I've seen people recover from just about
people recover from just about
people recover from just about everything. That's a fact. On the other
everything. That's a fact. On the other
everything. That's a fact. On the other hand they also forget karmic
hand they also forget karmic
hand they also forget karmic propensities that you may or may not
propensities that you may or may not
propensities that you may or may not recover during the course of miracles.
recover during the course of miracles.
recover during the course of miracles. However, you certainly have gained a lot
However, you certainly have gained a lot
However, you certainly have gained a lot of spiritual merit and I don't suppose
of spiritual merit and I don't suppose
of spiritual merit and I don't suppose God will be angry that you did the
God will be angry that you did the
God will be angry that you did the course of miracles
course of miracles
course of miracles that you've applied Christian principles
that you've applied Christian principles
that you've applied Christian principles at a very deep uh level and it has an
at a very deep uh level and it has an
at a very deep uh level and it has an effect on other people. The fact that
effect on other people. The fact that
effect on other people. The fact that you're doing the course has a positive
you're doing the course has a positive
you're doing the course has a positive benefit on other people. So the other
benefit on other people. So the other
benefit on other people. So the other reason you can do it is not only just
reason you can do it is not only just
reason you can do it is not only just for yourself but for the good of
for yourself but for the good of
for yourself but for the good of mankind. All of us contribute to the
mankind. All of us contribute to the
mankind. All of us contribute to the advance of human consciousness.
advance of human consciousness.
advance of human consciousness. Now we keep track on it. Okay, let's
Now we keep track on it. Okay, let's
Now we keep track on it. Okay, let's let's track u the consciousness level of
let's track u the consciousness level of
let's track u the consciousness level of mankind. We have permission to do it
mankind. We have permission to do it
mankind. We have permission to do it right now. It's over 205
right now. It's over 205
right now. It's over 205 206
206 207
207 went from 207 down to 206. Went down one
went from 207 down to 206. Went down one
went from 207 down to 206. Went down one point last year or two. In America it's
point last year or two. In America it's
point last year or two. In America it's over 425.
over 425.
over 425. 426
426 427. America's staying at 425. The world
427. America's staying at 425. The world
427. America's staying at 425. The world went down one point,
went down one point,
went down one point, >> 426,
>> 426,
>> 426, >> whatever.
>> 424 or 425.
>> 424 or 425. >> Another million die. One point. Millions
>> Another million die. One point. Millions
>> Another million die. One point. Millions die. Oh, well.
die. Oh, well.
die. Oh, well. >> It was 426.
>> It was 426.
>> It was 426. >> It was
>> It was
>> It was >> America.
>> America.
>> America. >> That's right. God.
>> That's right. God.
>> That's right. God. >> Oh, I I don't remember a little.
>> Oh, I I don't remember a little.
>> Oh, I I don't remember a little. >> But didn't we get 426? Yeah.
>> But didn't we get 426? Yeah.
>> But didn't we get 426? Yeah. >> Yeah. And then we did uh Singapore.
>> Yeah. And then we did uh Singapore.
>> Yeah. And then we did uh Singapore. Okay, let's do Singapore again. Uh
Okay, let's do Singapore again. Uh
Okay, let's do Singapore again. Uh Singapore is over uh 430 435
Singapore is over uh 430 435
Singapore is over uh 430 435 434 435. Singapore is 434 and America's
434 435. Singapore is 434 and America's
434 435. Singapore is 434 and America's 426.
426.
426. Oh dear, that's not right. But can't
Oh dear, that's not right. But can't
Oh dear, that's not right. But can't Singaporean foreigners be ahead of us?
Singaporean foreigners be ahead of us?
Singaporean foreigners be ahead of us? What in the world are they doing? Let's
What in the world are they doing? Let's
What in the world are they doing? Let's find out.
find out.
find out. >> They're Canadian people. Well, they uh
>> They're Canadian people. Well, they uh
>> They're Canadian people. Well, they uh if you throw trash on the street, you
if you throw trash on the street, you
if you throw trash on the street, you get a $50 fine instantly.
get a $50 fine instantly.
get a $50 fine instantly. No smoking gum on, you know, chewing gum
No smoking gum on, you know, chewing gum
No smoking gum on, you know, chewing gum on the sidewalk. Oh,
on the sidewalk. Oh,
on the sidewalk. Oh, sounds
sounds
sounds repressive, right?
repressive, right?
repressive, right? To a libertarian.
To a libertarian.
To a libertarian. Sounds repressive.
Sounds repressive.
Sounds repressive. You can't even throw your trash on the
You can't even throw your trash on the
You can't even throw your trash on the street. Good God. Where's freedom?
Now freedom of speech is has been spread
Now freedom of speech is has been spread to freedom of action. Action is symbolic
to freedom of action. Action is symbolic
to freedom of action. Action is symbolic speech.
speech.
speech. So can't isn't my my right to freedom of
So can't isn't my my right to freedom of
So can't isn't my my right to freedom of speech to throw trash on the side. Well,
speech to throw trash on the side. Well,
speech to throw trash on the side. Well, well, that's why they're at four
well, that's why they're at four
well, that's why they're at four whatever they are and we're at four
whatever they are and we're at four
whatever they are and we're at four something. Yeah. So it demonstrates uh
something. Yeah. So it demonstrates uh
something. Yeah. So it demonstrates uh things we've written about uh the
things we've written about uh the
things we've written about uh the advantage of an oligarchy you know
advantage of an oligarchy you know
advantage of an oligarchy you know because Singapore is an oligarchy
because Singapore is an oligarchy
because Singapore is an oligarchy and um mankind really existed because of
and um mankind really existed because of
and um mankind really existed because of the tribal chiefs you know it was the
the tribal chiefs you know it was the
the tribal chiefs you know it was the elders of the tribe. Most tribes
elders of the tribe. Most tribes
elders of the tribe. Most tribes survived because they listened to the
survived because they listened to the
survived because they listened to the elders revered the elders. Many ancient
elders revered the elders. Many ancient
elders revered the elders. Many ancient cultures survive because they listen to
cultures survive because they listen to
cultures survive because they listen to the elders. And an oligarchy is one in
the elders. And an oligarchy is one in
the elders. And an oligarchy is one in which a council of the elders dominates
which a council of the elders dominates
which a council of the elders dominates the the government. We have a democracy
the the government. We have a democracy
the the government. We have a democracy which calibrates less uh less. And of
which calibrates less uh less. And of
which calibrates less uh less. And of course as Socrates says the downside of
course as Socrates says the downside of
course as Socrates says the downside of a democracy
a democracy
a democracy is the 50% of the people in America uh
is the 50% of the people in America uh
is the 50% of the people in America uh who calibrate below 200 have an equal
who calibrate below 200 have an equal
who calibrate below 200 have an equal vote to the 200 above. You see
vote to the 200 above. You see
vote to the 200 above. You see and therefore they they put themselves
and therefore they they put themselves
and therefore they they put themselves out of business usually in two to 300
out of business usually in two to 300
out of business usually in two to 300 years. Um so the wis the wisdom of the
years. Um so the wis the wisdom of the
years. Um so the wis the wisdom of the elders uh the respect for for for
elders uh the respect for for for
elders uh the respect for for for experience
experience
experience uh legitimate
uh legitimate
uh legitimate what is authority. So true authority is
what is authority. So true authority is
what is authority. So true authority is uh integrity of essence. That's true
uh integrity of essence. That's true
uh integrity of essence. That's true authority. Uh you know h you know how to
authority. Uh you know h you know how to
authority. Uh you know h you know how to do a thing because you've successfully
do a thing because you've successfully
do a thing because you've successfully done it. Now you've got the true true
done it. Now you've got the true true
done it. Now you've got the true true authority uh and to differentiate it
authority uh and to differentiate it
authority uh and to differentiate it from false authority. So rebelling
from false authority. So rebelling
from false authority. So rebelling against false authority is one thing. Uh
against false authority is one thing. Uh
against false authority is one thing. Uh to rebel against true authority shows a
to rebel against true authority shows a
to rebel against true authority shows a certain ignorance. So there's a great
certain ignorance. So there's a great
certain ignorance. So there's a great value to the wisdom of the elders. And
value to the wisdom of the elders. And
value to the wisdom of the elders. And if it wasn't for the council of the
if it wasn't for the council of the
if it wasn't for the council of the elders, most of uh many societies would
elders, most of uh many societies would
elders, most of uh many societies would not have existed. Yeah. Because the
not have existed. Yeah. Because the
not have existed. Yeah. Because the elder to me an elder is one who's had it
elder to me an elder is one who's had it
elder to me an elder is one who's had it with the world and really not doesn't
with the world and really not doesn't
with the world and really not doesn't need or want anything more from it. Uh
need or want anything more from it. Uh
need or want anything more from it. Uh who who's that big financer? Buffett.
who who's that big financer? Buffett.
who who's that big financer? Buffett. Buffett. People like that. I mean he's
Buffett. People like that. I mean he's
Buffett. People like that. I mean he's made trillions. He don't need any more
made trillions. He don't need any more
made trillions. He don't need any more money. So what he shares he shares out
money. So what he shares he shares out
money. So what he shares he shares out of the integrity and value of his own
of the integrity and value of his own
of the integrity and value of his own inner experience. This is what I did.
inner experience. This is what I did.
inner experience. This is what I did. This is what I learned. I share it with
This is what I learned. I share it with
This is what I learned. I share it with you. Uh so uh Warren Buffett is an
you. Uh so uh Warren Buffett is an
you. Uh so uh Warren Buffett is an authority. So we don't you know have the
authority. So we don't you know have the
authority. So we don't you know have the Dixie Chicks parading you know screw
Dixie Chicks parading you know screw
Dixie Chicks parading you know screw screw Warren Buffett.
I got a kick out of that time cover.
I got a kick out of that time cover. Especially the girl on the far right.
Especially the girl on the far right.
Especially the girl on the far right. You can just calibrate her just just by
You can just calibrate her just just by
You can just calibrate her just just by looking at her face. You know what she
looking at her face. You know what she
looking at her face. You know what she calibrates. If that ain't 170 or 180. I
calibrates. If that ain't 170 or 180. I
calibrates. If that ain't 170 or 180. I never saw it. It's like
never saw it. It's like
never saw it. It's like in your face. In your face.
Uh it's funny. You don't see people
Uh it's funny. You don't see people doing that with Warren Buffett, do you?
doing that with Warren Buffett, do you?
doing that with Warren Buffett, do you? >> We have a little surprise for you.
>> We have a little surprise for you.
>> We have a little surprise for you. >> Uhhuh. What? Is it time for a break?
>> Uhhuh. What? Is it time for a break?
>> Uhhuh. What? Is it time for a break? >> Almost. But we have a little surprise
>> Almost. But we have a little surprise
>> Almost. But we have a little surprise for you.
for you.
for you. >> A little one?
>> A little one?
>> A little one? >> Yeah.
No, we don't have anybody say we
No, we don't have anybody say we disrespect Warren Buffett.
Isn't that funny to think of it? We
Isn't that funny to think of it? We disrespect Warren Buffet.
disrespect Warren Buffet.
disrespect Warren Buffet. >> Happy birthday
>> Happy birthday
>> Happy birthday to you.
to you.
to you. >> Something for you. See the incription.
>> Something for you. See the incription.
>> Something for you. See the incription. >> Wow. Thank you.
>> Wow. Thank you.
>> Wow. Thank you. >> Happy birthday dear.
Happy birthday.
Happy birthday. >> Oh dear. Isn't that fantastic?
That's a good Thank you.
That's a good Thank you. Wow. Wow. Wow.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much. Well, this is the big 8 coming up. You
Well, this is the big 8 coming up. You
Well, this is the big 8 coming up. You know what I'm saying? So,
know what I'm saying? So,
know what I'm saying? So, >> I don't know. When do you become an
>> I don't know. When do you become an
>> I don't know. When do you become an elder? When you I think 8 makes it
to be alive and kicking it 80 is still
to be alive and kicking it 80 is still okay.
okay.
okay. >> Did you get to read what it say before
>> Did you get to read what it say before
>> Did you get to read what it say before we cut it? We want you to see
we cut it? We want you to see
we cut it? We want you to see >> Gloria in Excelsious Deal.
>> Gloria in Excelsious Deal.
>> Gloria in Excelsious Deal. >> There you go.
Oh, what a perfect birthday I've had.
Oh, what a perfect birthday I've had. All right. And thank you all. You can
All right. And thank you all. You can
All right. And thank you all. You can relax. And uh
relax. And uh
relax. And uh and I got my Father's Day present
and I got my Father's Day present
and I got my Father's Day present already, too.
already, too.
already, too. Uh a new cat.
A new cat. A new cat. Yeah. Plus, we
A new cat. A new cat. Yeah. Plus, we have two little kittens to begin with,
have two little kittens to begin with,
have two little kittens to begin with, and now we've got So, now we're going to
and now we've got So, now we're going to
and now we've got So, now we're going to have three new cats. Anyway, it's what
have three new cats. Anyway, it's what
have three new cats. Anyway, it's what it's interesting to watch them interact,
it's interesting to watch them interact,
it's interesting to watch them interact, you see. And we brought in the two male
you see. And we brought in the two male
you see. And we brought in the two male castrated.
The quickest way to heaven fell is just
The quickest way to heaven fell is just to get castrated. It'll save you all
to get castrated. It'll save you all
to get castrated. It'll save you all kinds of trouble.
All kinds of trouble.
All kinds of trouble. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. We brought in the new cat. We're a
We brought in the new cat. We're a
We brought in the new cat. We're a little apprehensive. How are they going
little apprehensive. How are they going
little apprehensive. How are they going to get along? I was projecting my
to get along? I was projecting my
to get along? I was projecting my protectionism
protectionism
protectionism to not hurt the feelings of the old
to not hurt the feelings of the old
to not hurt the feelings of the old recat that there's new ones here. And uh
recat that there's new ones here. And uh
recat that there's new ones here. And uh then I just uh surrender the whole thing
then I just uh surrender the whole thing
then I just uh surrender the whole thing to God and they get along beautifully.
to God and they get along beautifully.
to God and they get along beautifully. They love each other and
They love each other and
They love each other and uh and they're very respectful of
uh and they're very respectful of
uh and they're very respectful of elders. Now the young cat, you know,
elders. Now the young cat, you know,
elders. Now the young cat, you know, could beat up the old cat easy. But what
could beat up the old cat easy. But what
could beat up the old cat easy. But what happens is the young cat stands back and
happens is the young cat stands back and
happens is the young cat stands back and lets the elder have his dinner. He just
lets the elder have his dinner. He just
lets the elder have his dinner. He just lays there patiently. When the eler's
lays there patiently. When the eler's
lays there patiently. When the eler's done, he walks over and has his. So
done, he walks over and has his. So
done, he walks over and has his. So perfect harmony. Isn't that neat?
perfect harmony. Isn't that neat?
perfect harmony. Isn't that neat? Perfect harmony. And they get along
Perfect harmony. And they get along
Perfect harmony. And they get along wonderfully. Of course, they don't know
wonderfully. Of course, they don't know
wonderfully. Of course, they don't know there's two little kittens waiting to
there's two little kittens waiting to
there's two little kittens waiting to come in and join the crowd.
come in and join the crowd.
come in and join the crowd. Let's see how happy they are then.
Yes, Sue and I were joking about the
Yes, Sue and I were joking about the most dangerous thing on the planet is
most dangerous thing on the planet is
most dangerous thing on the planet is testosterone.
testosterone.
testosterone. The most dangerous substance on the
The most dangerous substance on the
The most dangerous substance on the planet is testosterone. It's kill more
planet is testosterone. It's kill more
planet is testosterone. It's kill more people than all anything in history.
people than all anything in history.
people than all anything in history. Testosterone.
Testosterone.
Testosterone. the mad crazed hordes
the mad crazed hordes
the mad crazed hordes savaging, chopping off people's, you
savaging, chopping off people's, you
savaging, chopping off people's, you know, butchering people.
know, butchering people.
know, butchering people. So, you know, universal castration might
So, you know, universal castration might
So, you know, universal castration might bring us all to heaven earlier. I don't
bring us all to heaven earlier. I don't
bring us all to heaven earlier. I don't know.
Huh.
Huh. you're going to be very popular today.
>> Uh anyway,
>> Uh anyway, those things are all part of our karmic
those things are all part of our karmic
those things are all part of our karmic inheritance
inheritance
inheritance because of the evolutionary nature of
because of the evolutionary nature of
because of the evolutionary nature of human nature. You know, we evolved as
human nature. You know, we evolved as
human nature. You know, we evolved as you can see how consciousness has
you can see how consciousness has
you can see how consciousness has evolved from the prozzoa, the amoeba on
evolved from the prozzoa, the amoeba on
evolved from the prozzoa, the amoeba on up through all of evolution. And you
up through all of evolution. And you
up through all of evolution. And you see, you know, that evolution and
see, you know, that evolution and
see, you know, that evolution and creation are one and the same thing.
creation are one and the same thing.
creation are one and the same thing. That is so simple to see. Um the
That is so simple to see. Um the
That is so simple to see. Um the intelligent design argument of course is
intelligent design argument of course is
intelligent design argument of course is um political posturing and um one reason
um political posturing and um one reason
um political posturing and um one reason they don't like it is the idea of the
they don't like it is the idea of the
they don't like it is the idea of the slippery slope.
slippery slope.
slippery slope. The slippery slope argument of course is
The slippery slope argument of course is
The slippery slope argument of course is fellacious because it's the hypothetical
fellacious because it's the hypothetical
fellacious because it's the hypothetical and the hypothetical is not real. You're
and the hypothetical is not real. You're
and the hypothetical is not real. You're not real. U but anyway that the creation
not real. U but anyway that the creation
not real. U but anyway that the creation and evolution are one and the same thing
and evolution are one and the same thing
and evolution are one and the same thing is so easy to see. In fact, we
is so easy to see. In fact, we
is so easy to see. In fact, we calibrated to to to grasp that evolution
calibrated to to to grasp that evolution
calibrated to to to grasp that evolution and creation one the same thing that
and creation one the same thing that
and creation one the same thing that evolution is the way creation appears
evolution is the way creation appears
evolution is the way creation appears for in other words creation is
for in other words creation is
for in other words creation is progressive
progressive
progressive and it was created to be that way. You
and it was created to be that way. You
and it was created to be that way. You don't you only have to calibrate at 375
don't you only have to calibrate at 375
don't you only have to calibrate at 375 at 37 from 375 on is the level of
at 37 from 375 on is the level of
at 37 from 375 on is the level of consciousness required
consciousness required
consciousness required to sort of inuit it and be able to see
to sort of inuit it and be able to see
to sort of inuit it and be able to see oh yes evolution and creation the way
oh yes evolution and creation the way
oh yes evolution and creation the way creation appears evolutionary right it's
creation appears evolutionary right it's
creation appears evolutionary right it's simple simple very simple to see only
simple simple very simple to see only
simple simple very simple to see only takes 375 so
takes 375 so
takes 375 so uh because America is at 420 something
uh because America is at 420 something
uh because America is at 420 something rather uh means most of America you know
rather uh means most of America you know
rather uh means most of America you know the capacity to understand the reality
the capacity to understand the reality
the capacity to understand the reality is there then comes the willingness and
is there then comes the willingness and
is there then comes the willingness and then of course the the difficulty with
then of course the the difficulty with
then of course the the difficulty with today's world is nobody knows who to
today's world is nobody knows who to
today's world is nobody knows who to trust that's the subject of the work
trust that's the subject of the work
trust that's the subject of the work book chapters I'm working on right now
book chapters I'm working on right now
book chapters I'm working on right now for a new book how can you how can you
for a new book how can you how can you
for a new book how can you how can you trust anymore who can you trust in fact
trust anymore who can you trust in fact
trust anymore who can you trust in fact isn't trust untrustable
isn't trust untrustable
isn't trust untrustable isn't trust isn't it stupid to trust
isn't trust isn't it stupid to trust
isn't trust isn't it stupid to trust anything or anyone so you see a
anything or anyone so you see a
anything or anyone so you see a protective uh skepticism in society. Um
protective uh skepticism in society. Um
protective uh skepticism in society. Um and in spiritual history and currently
and in spiritual history and currently
and in spiritual history and currently you can see that unless truth is
you can see that unless truth is
you can see that unless truth is corroborated you are taking a certain
corroborated you are taking a certain
corroborated you are taking a certain risk and uh if you have faith in a good
risk and uh if you have faith in a good
risk and uh if you have faith in a good teacher and the teacher fulfills all the
teacher and the teacher fulfills all the
teacher and the teacher fulfills all the requirements then a good teacher will
requirements then a good teacher will
requirements then a good teacher will will direct you to a source of truth
will direct you to a source of truth
will direct you to a source of truth that's independent of him. You don't
that's independent of him. You don't
that's independent of him. You don't need him, you know. You don't once he's
need him, you know. You don't once he's
need him, you know. You don't once he's given you the word, what do you need him
given you the word, what do you need him
given you the word, what do you need him for? Get rid of it. You're on your own.
for? Get rid of it. You're on your own.
for? Get rid of it. You're on your own. So the teacher then g, you know,
So the teacher then g, you know,
So the teacher then g, you know, supports your inspiration, tries to
supports your inspiration, tries to
supports your inspiration, tries to share personal experience,
share personal experience,
share personal experience, uh tries to show the way to the the
uh tries to show the way to the the
uh tries to show the way to the the verifiable truth, and then you're on
verifiable truth, and then you're on
verifiable truth, and then you're on your own because the teacher wants
your own because the teacher wants
your own because the teacher wants nothing from you except a cake.
nothing from you except a cake.
nothing from you except a cake. He did want a blue cake. He did want a
He did want a blue cake. He did want a
He did want a blue cake. He did want a blue cake. He did want a blue cake.
blue cake. He did want a blue cake.
blue cake. He did want a blue cake. Okay. All right. We're going to take a
Okay. All right. We're going to take a
Okay. All right. We're going to take a break and uh then we'll reconvene in
break and uh then we'll reconvene in
break and uh then we'll reconvene in what? 15 minutes.
>> We are.
>> We are. >> The cake will be in the bar building
>> The cake will be in the bar building
>> The cake will be in the bar building over there where the cafeteria is. So,
over there where the cafeteria is. So,
over there where the cafeteria is. So, >> Oh, okay. We can all have a piece of
>> Oh, okay. We can all have a piece of
>> Oh, okay. We can all have a piece of cake. Life's a piece of cake, ain't it?
All right, I share with you what I know
All right, I share with you what I know and through of an intuitive uh you just
and through of an intuitive uh you just
and through of an intuitive uh you just know it. And um this morning we got our
know it. And um this morning we got our
know it. And um this morning we got our wrong answers which gave us a wonderful
wrong answers which gave us a wonderful
wrong answers which gave us a wonderful chance to uh we try to show a little bit
chance to uh we try to show a little bit
chance to uh we try to show a little bit about kinesiology every time. And uh
about kinesiology every time. And uh
about kinesiology every time. And uh this morning we demonstrated a thing. We
this morning we demonstrated a thing. We
this morning we demonstrated a thing. We uh remember I said uh the Hindu
uh remember I said uh the Hindu
uh remember I said uh the Hindu tradition is that you can come back if
tradition is that you can come back if
tradition is that you can come back if you got bad karma as a lower animal. And
you got bad karma as a lower animal. And
you got bad karma as a lower animal. And uh I've always gotten no. This morning
uh I've always gotten no. This morning
uh I've always gotten no. This morning we got a yes.
we got a yes.
we got a yes. So as I said we have to research that
So as I said we have to research that
So as I said we have to research that out. Which brings up u
out. Which brings up u
out. Which brings up u if if you mill around with a lot of
if if you mill around with a lot of
if if you mill around with a lot of people or expose yourself to music etc.
people or expose yourself to music etc.
people or expose yourself to music etc. uh you can sort of uh go out your
uh you can sort of uh go out your
uh you can sort of uh go out your energies go out without you realizing
energies go out without you realizing
energies go out without you realizing it. It happened to Susan. She said, you
it. It happened to Susan. She said, you
it. It happened to Susan. She said, you know, I felt something go out and I just
know, I felt something go out and I just
know, I felt something go out and I just cleared it in myself with the diamond uh
cleared it in myself with the diamond uh
cleared it in myself with the diamond uh thumb. You know, you you hold somebody
thumb. You know, you you hold somebody
thumb. You know, you you hold somebody you love in mindump
you love in mindump
you love in mindump smile.
Now she did that. Okay, let's ask the
Now she did that. Okay, let's ask the question again.
question again.
question again. Uh the ancient Hind belief is that with
Uh the ancient Hind belief is that with
Uh the ancient Hind belief is that with bad karma you can come back as a lesser
bad karma you can come back as a lesser
bad karma you can come back as a lesser creature. Uh that is true. Resist.
creature. Uh that is true. Resist.
creature. Uh that is true. Resist. Okay. That's always the answer we've
Okay. That's always the answer we've
Okay. That's always the answer we've gotten. So if anything is in doubt, just
gotten. So if anything is in doubt, just
gotten. So if anything is in doubt, just do the thyic thump. You hold in mind
do the thyic thump. You hold in mind
do the thyic thump. You hold in mind somebody you love. You thump over the
somebody you love. You thump over the
somebody you love. You thump over the thymus corn and say haha. And that
thymus corn and say haha. And that
thymus corn and say haha. And that corrects the imbalance in the
corrects the imbalance in the
corrects the imbalance in the acupuncture system. So I don't like to
acupuncture system. So I don't like to
acupuncture system. So I don't like to bring out, you know, because it makes
bring out, you know, because it makes
bring out, you know, because it makes you paranoid. But actually, anybody can
you paranoid. But actually, anybody can
you paranoid. But actually, anybody can blow you out if they have a very
blow you out if they have a very
blow you out if they have a very negative energy. And half of America
negative energy. And half of America
negative energy. And half of America gets blown out every night watching the
gets blown out every night watching the
gets blown out every night watching the news because people who come up
news because people who come up
news because people who come up calibrate about 160
calibrate about 160
calibrate about 160 are very um it's the energy with which
are very um it's the energy with which
are very um it's the energy with which they put it forth, the fervor. You know
they put it forth, the fervor. You know
they put it forth, the fervor. You know what I mean? Like if evil is destroyed,
what I mean? Like if evil is destroyed,
what I mean? Like if evil is destroyed, they're going to go up in flame. So they
they're going to go up in flame. So they
they're going to go up in flame. So they make sure that evil is going to stay
make sure that evil is going to stay
make sure that evil is going to stay here.
here.
here. And after you watch them, uh, I want to
And after you watch them, uh, I want to
And after you watch them, uh, I want to watch, let's address this. Can we ask
watch, let's address this. Can we ask
watch, let's address this. Can we ask the percentage of people to get blown
the percentage of people to get blown
the percentage of people to get blown out watching the evening news in the
out watching the evening news in the
out watching the evening news in the naive populace? Probably over 30%.
naive populace? Probably over 30%.
naive populace? Probably over 30%. 50%. Probably over 40%, probably 40%
50%. Probably over 40%, probably 40%
50%. Probably over 40%, probably 40% their whole energy field is reversed by
their whole energy field is reversed by
their whole energy field is reversed by the evening news.
the evening news.
the evening news. That's one of the reasons it's spiritual
That's one of the reasons it's spiritual
That's one of the reasons it's spiritual tradition. One's spiritual tradition of
tradition. One's spiritual tradition of
tradition. One's spiritual tradition of course is that of the renunciator who
course is that of the renunciator who
course is that of the renunciator who renounces the world does not expose
renounces the world does not expose
renounces the world does not expose himself to that negativity because he
himself to that negativity because he
himself to that negativity because he had no means to defend himself nor uh
had no means to defend himself nor uh
had no means to defend himself nor uh you know could he do kinesiology and
you know could he do kinesiology and
you know could he do kinesiology and find out that hey I just got blown out
find out that hey I just got blown out
find out that hey I just got blown out by something and correct it you know uh
by something and correct it you know uh
by something and correct it you know uh so that was sort of interesting wasn't
so that was sort of interesting wasn't
so that was sort of interesting wasn't it I'm glad it happened
it I'm glad it happened
it I'm glad it happened >> and uh she intuited right away she says
>> and uh she intuited right away she says
>> and uh she intuited right away she says something must have gotten blown out and
something must have gotten blown out and
something must have gotten blown out and she corrected it So that was a very uh
she corrected it So that was a very uh
she corrected it So that was a very uh interesting teaching examples. All
interesting teaching examples. All
interesting teaching examples. All right. This morning we um we did what we
right. This morning we um we did what we
right. This morning we um we did what we wanted to do for the new information and
wanted to do for the new information and
wanted to do for the new information and uh so I want to go back honey. We'll go
uh so I want to go back honey. We'll go
uh so I want to go back honey. We'll go back to um the way we usually present
back to um the way we usually present
back to um the way we usually present it. We usually present it more
it. We usually present it more
it. We usually present it more academically.
academically.
academically. Uh but every time we go back over the
Uh but every time we go back over the
Uh but every time we go back over the same material, we learn something new
same material, we learn something new
same material, we learn something new and reexposure.
and reexposure.
and reexposure. Uh and of course you learn learn as Dr.
Uh and of course you learn learn as Dr.
Uh and of course you learn learn as Dr. Kbach says repetition is the world's
Kbach says repetition is the world's
Kbach says repetition is the world's best teacher.
best teacher.
best teacher. You struggle to understand it but after
You struggle to understand it but after
You struggle to understand it but after you've heard it about six times it's
you've heard it about six times it's
you've heard it about six times it's like yeah I mean it's you've like
like yeah I mean it's you've like
like yeah I mean it's you've like incorporated it you see so that's the
incorporated it you see so that's the
incorporated it you see so that's the colog principle that we
unity church and that's the unity
unity church and that's the unity church.
church.
church. >> Oh you said I I don't remember that you
>> Oh you said I I don't remember that you
>> Oh you said I I don't remember that you she forgot to renounce something unity
she forgot to renounce something unity
she forgot to renounce something unity church. Oh, this coming Sunday. Oh, yes.
church. Oh, this coming Sunday. Oh, yes.
church. Oh, this coming Sunday. Oh, yes. >> This coming Sunday, we'll be speaking at
>> This coming Sunday, we'll be speaking at
>> This coming Sunday, we'll be speaking at Unity Both Services, which is uh June
Unity Both Services, which is uh June
Unity Both Services, which is uh June 25th, and that's here in Sedona.
25th, and that's here in Sedona.
25th, and that's here in Sedona. >> The sermon.
>> The sermon.
>> The sermon. >> The ser I said both services. The
>> The ser I said both services. The
>> The ser I said both services. The sermon.
sermon.
sermon. >> The sermon. What is it? 9 and 11.
>> The sermon. What is it? 9 and 11.
>> The sermon. What is it? 9 and 11. >> Um I think it's 9 and 11. You can go to
>> Um I think it's 9 and 11. You can go to
>> Um I think it's 9 and 11. You can go to the website and double check that. Okay.
the website and double check that. Okay.
the website and double check that. Okay. We'll be speaking at next weekend.
We'll be speaking at next weekend.
We'll be speaking at next weekend. >> This next weekend.
>> This next weekend.
>> This next weekend. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> The 25th.
>> I don't know. It's a very small church.
>> I don't know. It's a very small church. You do have to make room.
You do have to make room.
You do have to make room. >> Okay. Well, it's a small church and we
>> Okay. Well, it's a small church and we
>> Okay. Well, it's a small church and we might just blow their socks off. So,
might just blow their socks off. So,
might just blow their socks off. So, >> send
>> send
>> send the minister Sandra Keep. Very sweet
the minister Sandra Keep. Very sweet
the minister Sandra Keep. Very sweet lady.
lady.
lady. >> Yeah. I spoke at uh Unity when I first
>> Yeah. I spoke at uh Unity when I first
>> Yeah. I spoke at uh Unity when I first came to Sedona and introduced the course
came to Sedona and introduced the course
came to Sedona and introduced the course of miracles. Didn't they didn't have it
of miracles. Didn't they didn't have it
of miracles. Didn't they didn't have it in Sedona and you couldn't get it in the
in Sedona and you couldn't get it in the
in Sedona and you couldn't get it in the bookstore. and we gave a lecture on the
bookstore. and we gave a lecture on the
bookstore. and we gave a lecture on the course of the course miracles and and at
course of the course miracles and and at
course of the course miracles and and at the end of which we had 100 members
the end of which we had 100 members
the end of which we had 100 members and the population of Sedona at that
and the population of Sedona at that
and the population of Sedona at that time was 3,000.
time was 3,000.
time was 3,000. So 100 members meditating according to
So 100 members meditating according to
So 100 members meditating according to research done by I forget what spiritual
research done by I forget what spiritual
research done by I forget what spiritual group it is uh will actually affect the
group it is uh will actually affect the
group it is uh will actually affect the crime rate in the town
crime rate in the town
crime rate in the town >> over five over 5% if over 5% of the
>> over five over 5% if over 5% of the
>> over five over 5% if over 5% of the population uh meditates et etc the crime
population uh meditates et etc the crime
population uh meditates et etc the crime rate in the town actually decreases
rate in the town actually decreases
rate in the town actually decreases you know the Masharishi Maharishi's
you know the Masharishi Maharishi's
you know the Masharishi Maharishi's organization I forget the name of it
organization I forget the name of it
organization I forget the name of it Huh?
The other celebrity news for the week is
The other celebrity news for the week is two. Last week we were on channel 3. Uh
two. Last week we were on channel 3. Uh
two. Last week we were on channel 3. Uh what's that nice lady's name? Uh
what's that nice lady's name? Uh
what's that nice lady's name? Uh >> Tanya.
>> Tanya.
>> Tanya. >> Tanya Monk. Yeah. And Lee. It's a
>> Tanya Monk. Yeah. And Lee. It's a
>> Tanya Monk. Yeah. And Lee. It's a wonderful program to be on. And we ran a
wonderful program to be on. And we ran a
wonderful program to be on. And we ran a whole half hour. We had such a good time
whole half hour. We had such a good time
whole half hour. We had such a good time and we talked about all these things
and we talked about all these things
and we talked about all these things that I thought would really blow the
that I thought would really blow the
that I thought would really blow the socks off people and they actually liked
socks off people and they actually liked
socks off people and they actually liked it and we did kinesiology right on the
it and we did kinesiology right on the
it and we did kinesiology right on the show and use her as the example. It was
show and use her as the example. It was
show and use her as the example. It was fun.
fun.
fun. All right. Map of consciousness.
All right. Map of consciousness.
All right. Map of consciousness. Uh we've of course included this in all
Uh we've of course included this in all
Uh we've of course included this in all of our writings and we refer to it
of our writings and we refer to it
of our writings and we refer to it because um the discovery was sort of
because um the discovery was sort of
because um the discovery was sort of mind-boggling and I've told you about
mind-boggling and I've told you about
mind-boggling and I've told you about the discovery that I had some people in
the discovery that I had some people in
the discovery that I had some people in the course of miracles and uh they did
the course of miracles and uh they did
the course of miracles and uh they did not respond uh they did not go weak to
not respond uh they did not go weak to
not respond uh they did not go weak to negative stimuli and that started the
negative stimuli and that started the
negative stimuli and that started the whole investigation. I was going to give
whole investigation. I was going to give
whole investigation. I was going to give a lecture on kinesiology
a lecture on kinesiology
a lecture on kinesiology and I just grabbed these students at the
and I just grabbed these students at the
and I just grabbed these students at the course of miracles because we had an
course of miracles because we had an
course of miracles because we had an attitudinal healing center there run by
attitudinal healing center there run by
attitudinal healing center there run by the course of miracles people for people
the course of miracles people for people
the course of miracles people for people with hopeless diseases
with hopeless diseases
with hopeless diseases and uh when I when they looked at you
and uh when I when they looked at you
and uh when I when they looked at you everybody looks when if you look at
everybody looks when if you look at
everybody looks when if you look at fluorescent lights everybody goes weak
fluorescent lights everybody goes weak
fluorescent lights everybody goes weak and if you hold pesticides or the solar
and if you hold pesticides or the solar
and if you hold pesticides or the solar plexus uh or sweet and low you go weak
plexus uh or sweet and low you go weak
plexus uh or sweet and low you go weak and these people didn't go weak with
and these people didn't go weak with
and these people didn't go weak with anything. I thought what? They didn't go
anything. I thought what? They didn't go
anything. I thought what? They didn't go weak. I thought they were sick or
weak. I thought they were sick or
weak. I thought they were sick or abnormal or something.
abnormal or something.
abnormal or something. And then we began to research it with
And then we began to research it with
And then we began to research it with people who started the course of
people who started the course of
people who started the course of miracles. We would test them in the
miracles. We would test them in the
miracles. We would test them in the beginning. We tested them every couple
beginning. We tested them every couple
beginning. We tested them every couple of weeks and around about lesson 75 from
of weeks and around about lesson 75 from
of weeks and around about lesson 75 from there on up. Uh they no longer wet went
there on up. Uh they no longer wet went
there on up. Uh they no longer wet went weak. They because they realized I'm
weak. They because they realized I'm
weak. They because they realized I'm only subject to what I hold in mind. And
only subject to what I hold in mind. And
only subject to what I hold in mind. And uh therefore they were no longer went
uh therefore they were no longer went
uh therefore they were no longer went weak. Oh, that was a really amazing
weak. Oh, that was a really amazing
weak. Oh, that was a really amazing discovery. What the shift in spiritual
discovery. What the shift in spiritual
discovery. What the shift in spiritual orientation can totally shift the
orientation can totally shift the
orientation can totally shift the response of your acupuncture system and
response of your acupuncture system and
response of your acupuncture system and your whole physiology. And of course, as
your whole physiology. And of course, as
your whole physiology. And of course, as we've learned since also your brain
we've learned since also your brain
we've learned since also your brain physiology shifts from left brain to
physiology shifts from left brain to
physiology shifts from left brain to right brain, your neurotransmitters
right brain, your neurotransmitters
right brain, your neurotransmitters change with spiritual intention
change with spiritual intention
change with spiritual intention and you put out endorphins and you
and you put out endorphins and you
and you put out endorphins and you perceive the world differently. That
perceive the world differently. That
perceive the world differently. That gives us a certain compassion for people
gives us a certain compassion for people
gives us a certain compassion for people who see the world differently than we
who see the world differently than we
who see the world differently than we do. It's because their brain physiology
do. It's because their brain physiology
do. It's because their brain physiology is such that that's the way they see it
is such that that's the way they see it
is such that that's the way they see it and they put out adrenaline
and they put out adrenaline
and they put out adrenaline and uh spiritually oriented people see
and uh spiritually oriented people see
and uh spiritually oriented people see it with a compassionate understanding of
it with a compassionate understanding of
it with a compassionate understanding of the limitations of human evolution
the limitations of human evolution
the limitations of human evolution and therefore uh they see the world
and therefore uh they see the world
and therefore uh they see the world through predominantly right brain
through predominantly right brain
through predominantly right brain physiology and the influence of
physiology and the influence of
physiology and the influence of endorphins rather than adrenaline or
endorphins rather than adrenaline or
endorphins rather than adrenaline or cortisone.
cortisone.
cortisone. Uh so that's going ahead of oursel.
Uh so that's going ahead of oursel.
Uh so that's going ahead of oursel. Anyway, we find this is extremely useful
Anyway, we find this is extremely useful
Anyway, we find this is extremely useful in many ways and of course the book
in many ways and of course the book
in many ways and of course the book truth versus false and we demonstrate
truth versus false and we demonstrate
truth versus false and we demonstrate the many ways it can be used from
the many ways it can be used from
the many ways it can be used from international politics uh uh to doing
international politics uh uh to doing
international politics uh uh to doing research. Uh I'm interested in it saving
research. Uh I'm interested in it saving
research. Uh I'm interested in it saving money in research.
money in research.
money in research. Uh you know big foundations are about to
Uh you know big foundations are about to
Uh you know big foundations are about to put huge amounts of money in in various
put huge amounts of money in in various
put huge amounts of money in in various programs. If they knew how to calibrate
programs. If they knew how to calibrate
programs. If they knew how to calibrate the programs, they would know where
the programs, they would know where
the programs, they would know where their money would do the the most good
their money would do the the most good
their money would do the the most good instead of spending hundred million
instead of spending hundred million
instead of spending hundred million dollars and find it doesn't work.
dollars and find it doesn't work.
dollars and find it doesn't work. $100 million on a project doesn't work.
$100 million on a project doesn't work.
$100 million on a project doesn't work. That's done all the time. Look at the
That's done all the time. Look at the
That's done all the time. Look at the money that's been poured into Haiti.
money that's been poured into Haiti.
money that's been poured into Haiti. Haiti
Haiti
Haiti and the research shows the more money
and the research shows the more money
and the research shows the more money you pour pour into Haiti, the worse the
you pour pour into Haiti, the worse the
you pour pour into Haiti, the worse the people become.
people become.
people become. The more money you put put in, the
The more money you put put in, the
The more money you put put in, the higher the poverty rate. that you would
higher the poverty rate. that you would
higher the poverty rate. that you would know a kinesiology that you're doing
know a kinesiology that you're doing
know a kinesiology that you're doing something wrong. You're making the
something wrong. You're making the
something wrong. You're making the people worse, not better. So, uh it's
people worse, not better. So, uh it's
people worse, not better. So, uh it's very useful for research. So, we're all
very useful for research. So, we're all
very useful for research. So, we're all very familiar with that and all the
very familiar with that and all the
very familiar with that and all the books refer to it in different ways.
books refer to it in different ways.
books refer to it in different ways. Transcending levels of consciousness, of
Transcending levels of consciousness, of
Transcending levels of consciousness, of course, um shows us how to move from one
course, um shows us how to move from one
course, um shows us how to move from one one level into another. Um the
one level into another. Um the
one level into another. Um the willingness to let go of the payoff.
willingness to let go of the payoff.
willingness to let go of the payoff. And if you feel like you're stuck
And if you feel like you're stuck
And if you feel like you're stuck anywhere, there's only one rule. There's
anywhere, there's only one rule. There's
anywhere, there's only one rule. There's only you don't have to worry about uh
only you don't have to worry about uh
only you don't have to worry about uh you really don't have to worry about all
you really don't have to worry about all
you really don't have to worry about all these things here. Uh all these negative
these things here. Uh all these negative
these things here. Uh all these negative feelings. All you have to figure out is
feelings. All you have to figure out is
feelings. All you have to figure out is one thing. There's only one thing you
one thing. There's only one thing you
one thing. There's only one thing you you only have to surrender.
you only have to surrender.
you only have to surrender. The payoff you're getting from whatever
The payoff you're getting from whatever
The payoff you're getting from whatever positionality you're stuck in, that's
positionality you're stuck in, that's
positionality you're stuck in, that's all you got to let go. You don't have to
all you got to let go. You don't have to
all you got to let go. You don't have to let go of hating people,
let go of hating people,
let go of hating people, being afraid.
being afraid.
being afraid. You don't have to let go of wanting to
You don't have to let go of wanting to
You don't have to let go of wanting to be a terrorist.
be a terrorist.
be a terrorist. Blow up bus loads of children. I know
Blow up bus loads of children. I know
Blow up bus loads of children. I know that's tempting, but
that's tempting, but
that's tempting, but you have to forego the pleasure.
All right? So, it's the pleasure,
All right? So, it's the pleasure, gratification, and satisfaction that you
gratification, and satisfaction that you
gratification, and satisfaction that you get out of that position. That's what
get out of that position. That's what
get out of that position. That's what you're stuck on. So, you understand? you
you're stuck on. So, you understand? you
you're stuck on. So, you understand? you still hate your mother-in-law. What
still hate your mother-in-law. What
still hate your mother-in-law. What you're stuck on is not your
you're stuck on is not your
you're stuck on is not your mother-in-law and not your hatred. What
mother-in-law and not your hatred. What
mother-in-law and not your hatred. What you're stuck on is that you get a
you're stuck on is that you get a
you're stuck on is that you get a satisfaction and a pleasure like sort of
satisfaction and a pleasure like sort of
satisfaction and a pleasure like sort of a vengeful.
You only have to let go whatever payoff
You only have to let go whatever payoff you're getting. That payoff is an
you're getting. That payoff is an
you're getting. That payoff is an energy. And once you identify it, you'll
energy. And once you identify it, you'll
energy. And once you identify it, you'll see it come up. You'll see it come up.
see it come up. You'll see it come up.
see it come up. You'll see it come up. Every negative thing that's holding you
Every negative thing that's holding you
Every negative thing that's holding you back from enlightenment is due to the
back from enlightenment is due to the
back from enlightenment is due to the payoff that you're getting secretly from
payoff that you're getting secretly from
payoff that you're getting secretly from the ego. You say, "Oh, I don't get
the ego. You say, "Oh, I don't get
the ego. You say, "Oh, I don't get anything payoff." Oh, yes, you do. You
anything payoff." Oh, yes, you do. You
anything payoff." Oh, yes, you do. You get
get
get there's a lady that the virus is using
there's a lady that the virus is using
there's a lady that the virus is using right now and they gallop her around and
right now and they gallop her around and
right now and they gallop her around and uh she gets arrested and when she got
uh she gets arrested and when she got
uh she gets arrested and when she got arrested,
arrested,
arrested, I'll never forget that look. She was
I'll never forget that look. She was
I'll never forget that look. She was like jubilant. The police are ticking
like jubilant. The police are ticking
like jubilant. The police are ticking her away and she's jubilant in a state
her away and she's jubilant in a state
her away and she's jubilant in a state of ecstasy.
of ecstasy.
of ecstasy. Jubilant. Jubilant. Okay, there the
Jubilant. Jubilant. Okay, there the
Jubilant. Jubilant. Okay, there the satisfaction is gross and right on the
satisfaction is gross and right on the
satisfaction is gross and right on the surface with ourselves that are more
surface with ourselves that are more
surface with ourselves that are more sophisticated. Of course, we would
sophisticated. Of course, we would
sophisticated. Of course, we would repress the fact that we're getting off
repress the fact that we're getting off
repress the fact that we're getting off on it.
She got to be a celebrity, you know.
She got to be a celebrity, you know. Yeah. Anyway,
Yeah. Anyway,
Yeah. Anyway, God bless her. She was abused, I think.
God bless her. She was abused, I think.
God bless her. She was abused, I think. Anyway, so
Anyway, so
Anyway, so the payoff, so just don't worry about
the payoff, so just don't worry about
the payoff, so just don't worry about sin and guilt and all that stuff, fear
sin and guilt and all that stuff, fear
sin and guilt and all that stuff, fear of hell and all that stuff. Just look at
of hell and all that stuff. Just look at
of hell and all that stuff. Just look at look at what you're getting out of it.
look at what you're getting out of it.
look at what you're getting out of it. And um each one of these negative
And um each one of these negative
And um each one of these negative feelings is hooked in with others.
feelings is hooked in with others.
feelings is hooked in with others. Each one is hooked in with others. Not
Each one is hooked in with others. Not
Each one is hooked in with others. Not one of them ever exists alone. You're
one of them ever exists alone. You're
one of them ever exists alone. You're angry because you're prideful, because
angry because you're prideful, because
angry because you're prideful, because you're disappointed, because you didn't
you're disappointed, because you didn't
you're disappointed, because you didn't acquire a gain. You see, you've got five
acquire a gain. You see, you've got five
acquire a gain. You see, you've got five or six linked together. So, each uh
or six linked together. So, each uh
or six linked together. So, each uh brick that you pull out weakens the
brick that you pull out weakens the
brick that you pull out weakens the whole wall and eventually the whole ego
whole wall and eventually the whole ego
whole wall and eventually the whole ego collapses because you see that there's
collapses because you see that there's
collapses because you see that there's only one thing that you've been ever
only one thing that you've been ever
only one thing that you've been ever getting out of it all the time. And
getting out of it all the time. And
getting out of it all the time. And that's the narcissistic core. The ego
that's the narcissistic core. The ego
that's the narcissistic core. The ego loves to juice negativity because that's
loves to juice negativity because that's
loves to juice negativity because that's how it survives. Without it, it can't
how it survives. Without it, it can't
how it survives. Without it, it can't survive. Spiritual work is a tremendous
survive. Spiritual work is a tremendous
survive. Spiritual work is a tremendous threat to the narcissistic core of the
threat to the narcissistic core of the
threat to the narcissistic core of the ego.
ego.
ego. Why? Because the narcissistic core of
Why? Because the narcissistic core of
Why? Because the narcissistic core of the ego considers itself to be divine.
the ego considers itself to be divine.
the ego considers itself to be divine. It's God and it is the source of your
It's God and it is the source of your
It's God and it is the source of your life. The ego has you convinced that
life. The ego has you convinced that
life. The ego has you convinced that without the ego, you will die and that
without the ego, you will die and that
without the ego, you will die and that it is the core and source of your life.
it is the core and source of your life.
it is the core and source of your life. And you don't really discover how
And you don't really discover how
And you don't really discover how powerful and long acting that has been
powerful and long acting that has been
powerful and long acting that has been that delusion until you fa face what I
that delusion until you fa face what I
that delusion until you fa face what I call the final door of infinite silence
call the final door of infinite silence
call the final door of infinite silence and infinite nothingness. You've got
and infinite nothingness. You've got
and infinite nothingness. You've got nothing left to surrender to God except
nothing left to surrender to God except
nothing left to surrender to God except your life. It's the only thing you got
your life. It's the only thing you got
your life. It's the only thing you got left. You don't any programs. You don't
left. You don't any programs. You don't
left. You don't any programs. You don't there's nobody there. There's no angel
there's nobody there. There's no angel
there's nobody there. There's no angel guides and all that stuff you read
guides and all that stuff you read
guides and all that stuff you read about.
about.
about. Absolute alone.
Absolute alone.
Absolute alone. Absolute silence.
Absolute silence.
Absolute silence. nothing else to lay down except your
nothing else to lay down except your
nothing else to lay down except your life.
life.
life. Then the terror comes up. Unto thee, oh
Then the terror comes up. Unto thee, oh
Then the terror comes up. Unto thee, oh Lord, do I surrender my life.
Lord, do I surrender my life.
Lord, do I surrender my life. And uh then up comes the terror. And it
And uh then up comes the terror. And it
And uh then up comes the terror. And it is a terror. Not going to tell you that
is a terror. Not going to tell you that
is a terror. Not going to tell you that it's pleasant and cheerful. It is an
it's pleasant and cheerful. It is an
it's pleasant and cheerful. It is an absolute terror that you are dying.
absolute terror that you are dying.
absolute terror that you are dying. And it's because you never have died.
And it's because you never have died.
And it's because you never have died. You've only gone out of body and come
You've only gone out of body and come
You've only gone out of body and come back again. You've never faced the
back again. You've never faced the
back again. You've never faced the narcissistic core of the ego which is
narcissistic core of the ego which is
narcissistic core of the ego which is your final
your final
your final that's the final
that's the final
that's the final and then you die. You don't have to be
and then you die. You don't have to be
and then you die. You don't have to be afraid of dying. You do
after that you don't have any fear of
after that you don't have any fear of dying because you already did it.
So the the technology of spiritual
So the the technology of spiritual evolution then is to see that there's
evolution then is to see that there's
evolution then is to see that there's only one thing going on that's your
only one thing going on that's your
only one thing going on that's your enemy. That's the unconscious payoff,
enemy. That's the unconscious payoff,
enemy. That's the unconscious payoff, the narcissistic core the ego gets
the narcissistic core the ego gets
the narcissistic core the ego gets constantly
constantly
constantly secretly juicing everything.
secretly juicing everything.
secretly juicing everything. I wish I had that picture of that lady
I wish I had that picture of that lady
I wish I had that picture of that lady on TV because I'll never forget when the
on TV because I'll never forget when the
on TV because I'll never forget when the police hauled her away, the jubilation.
police hauled her away, the jubilation.
police hauled her away, the jubilation. And I thought, there's the narcissistic
And I thought, there's the narcissistic
And I thought, there's the narcissistic core of the ego just
core of the ego just
core of the ego just getting all the glamour, the TV, the
getting all the glamour, the TV, the
getting all the glamour, the TV, the headlines. Man, she was in her glory.
Just a simple person who would not
Just a simple person who would not understand anything we're talking about.
understand anything we're talking about.
understand anything we're talking about. Okay, we'll go on then. And so we always
Okay, we'll go on then. And so we always
Okay, we'll go on then. And so we always just review that
just review that
just review that we uh constantly confirm spiritual
we uh constantly confirm spiritual
we uh constantly confirm spiritual reality
reality
reality uh what we do is we calibrate all these
uh what we do is we calibrate all these
uh what we do is we calibrate all these things you see all calibrate all these
things you see all calibrate all these
things you see all calibrate all these things
things
things because is spiritual belief and that's
because is spiritual belief and that's
because is spiritual belief and that's what I'm writing about now
what I'm writing about now
what I'm writing about now what can modern man how can he handle
what can modern man how can he handle
what can modern man how can he handle spiritual reality first of all in a
spiritual reality first of all in a
spiritual reality first of all in a society in which there isn't any truth
society in which there isn't any truth
society in which there isn't any truth available without expertise And how can
available without expertise And how can
available without expertise And how can he corroborate the the truth of what
he corroborate the the truth of what
he corroborate the the truth of what he's reading? What out of a couple of
he's reading? What out of a couple of
he's reading? What out of a couple of pages of oldfashioned scripture, you
pages of oldfashioned scripture, you
pages of oldfashioned scripture, you know, is actual fact and believable? How
know, is actual fact and believable? How
know, is actual fact and believable? How much is just cultural myth? The Old
much is just cultural myth? The Old
much is just cultural myth? The Old Testament and of course all all things
Testament and of course all all things
Testament and of course all all things like that are full of all kinds of
like that are full of all kinds of
like that are full of all kinds of cultural myths. And that's the whole
cultural myths. And that's the whole
cultural myths. And that's the whole Scopes trial dilemma, you know. Do you
Scopes trial dilemma, you know. Do you
Scopes trial dilemma, you know. Do you really believe that Jonah got swallowed
really believe that Jonah got swallowed
really believe that Jonah got swallowed into the stomach of a whale for three
into the stomach of a whale for three
into the stomach of a whale for three days? You know, give me a break, you
days? You know, give me a break, you
days? You know, give me a break, you know.
know.
know. You can see Darl's exasperation.
You can see Darl's exasperation.
You can see Darl's exasperation. You want me to buy that three days in
You want me to buy that three days in
You want me to buy that three days in this then I give a whale? Give me a
this then I give a whale? Give me a
this then I give a whale? Give me a break. So that's modern man's dilemma to
break. So that's modern man's dilemma to
break. So that's modern man's dilemma to differentiate what is myth, what is
differentiate what is myth, what is
differentiate what is myth, what is cultural myth, what is legend. And so
cultural myth, what is legend. And so
cultural myth, what is legend. And so much of ancient
much of ancient
much of ancient religious tradition incorporates a great
religious tradition incorporates a great
religious tradition incorporates a great deal of myth. Okay, we'll move on.
deal of myth. Okay, we'll move on.
deal of myth. Okay, we'll move on. uh this is uh we we see the majority of
uh this is uh we we see the majority of
uh this is uh we we see the majority of the world's population
the world's population
the world's population uh close to 80%
uh close to 80%
uh close to 80% calibrates below the level of integrity
calibrates below the level of integrity
calibrates below the level of integrity which makes the daily news quite
which makes the daily news quite
which makes the daily news quite comprehensible does it not if 80% of the
comprehensible does it not if 80% of the
comprehensible does it not if 80% of the people can't tell truth from falsehood
people can't tell truth from falsehood
people can't tell truth from falsehood and uh you know the these leaders are
and uh you know the these leaders are
and uh you know the these leaders are messianic
messianic
messianic narcissistic messianic megalamania
narcissistic messianic megalamania
narcissistic messianic megalamania the world doesn't even know about that.
the world doesn't even know about that.
the world doesn't even know about that. How do they know
How do they know
How do they know this? It's the same syndrome over and
this? It's the same syndrome over and
this? It's the same syndrome over and over. Hitler, Stalin,
over. Hitler, Stalin,
over. Hitler, Stalin, Paul Pot or Pot Paul, I never forget if
Paul Pot or Pot Paul, I never forget if
Paul Pot or Pot Paul, I never forget if he's a pot of Paul or a Paul, whatever
he's a pot of Paul or a Paul, whatever
he's a pot of Paul or a Paul, whatever it is. Chairman Mayo, they all calibrate
it is. Chairman Mayo, they all calibrate
it is. Chairman Mayo, they all calibrate the same. They all have identical
the same. They all have identical
the same. They all have identical characteristics. And mankind over and
characteristics. And mankind over and
characteristics. And mankind over and over gets slaughtered by them. Not
over gets slaughtered by them. Not
over gets slaughtered by them. Not slaughtered, I mean a 100 million. Is
slaughtered, I mean a 100 million. Is
slaughtered, I mean a 100 million. Is wouldn't that would sort of wake you up
wouldn't that would sort of wake you up
wouldn't that would sort of wake you up a little bit? 100 million. Wouldn't that
a little bit? 100 million. Wouldn't that
a little bit? 100 million. Wouldn't that be a wakeup call? What's the cause of
be a wakeup call? What's the cause of
be a wakeup call? What's the cause of this? What's the trigger? 100 million
this? What's the trigger? 100 million
this? What's the trigger? 100 million people by Stalin. Another 100 million in
people by Stalin. Another 100 million in
people by Stalin. Another 100 million in World War II by Hitler. Uh the massacres
World War II by Hitler. Uh the massacres
World War II by Hitler. Uh the massacres of the Japanese and Manuria over and
of the Japanese and Manuria over and
of the Japanese and Manuria over and over and over again. The Goss and the
over and over again. The Goss and the
over and over again. The Goss and the Slavs and the
Slavs and the
Slavs and the Genghask Khan,
Genghask Khan,
Genghask Khan, uh
uh
uh all the mad Zars of Russia,
all the mad Zars of Russia,
all the mad Zars of Russia, exterminating people by the hundreds of
exterminating people by the hundreds of
exterminating people by the hundreds of millions. And the person who does it is
millions. And the person who does it is
millions. And the person who does it is identical, just has a different name,
identical, just has a different name,
identical, just has a different name, different era, calibrates the same. And
different era, calibrates the same. And
different era, calibrates the same. And of course, in truth versus falsehood, we
of course, in truth versus falsehood, we
of course, in truth versus falsehood, we put a couple of pages because mankind
put a couple of pages because mankind
put a couple of pages because mankind doesn't seem to be able to recognize the
doesn't seem to be able to recognize the
doesn't seem to be able to recognize the pathology
pathology
pathology involved. Okay? So, we move on. And of
involved. Okay? So, we move on. And of
involved. Okay? So, we move on. And of course, this this percentage of the
course, this this percentage of the
course, this this percentage of the population would not be able to see it.
population would not be able to see it.
population would not be able to see it. this percentage of the population
this percentage of the population
this percentage of the population because it lacks integrity
because it lacks integrity
because it lacks integrity uh can't see non- integrity out there.
uh can't see non- integrity out there.
uh can't see non- integrity out there. Okay. So the innocence it's the
Okay. So the innocence it's the
Okay. So the innocence it's the innocence of these people the ignorance.
innocence of these people the ignorance.
innocence of these people the ignorance. Jesus Christ and the Buddha both say
Jesus Christ and the Buddha both say
Jesus Christ and the Buddha both say there's only one problem and that is
there's only one problem and that is
there's only one problem and that is ignorance. Okay.
ignorance. Okay.
ignorance. Okay. This is the rapidity of the evolution of
This is the rapidity of the evolution of
This is the rapidity of the evolution of consciousness
consciousness
consciousness uh according to dated history including
uh according to dated history including
uh according to dated history including up to the present and we see the
up to the present and we see the
up to the present and we see the evolution of consciousness until last
evolution of consciousness until last
evolution of consciousness until last week or so was going on pretty good.
week or so was going on pretty good.
week or so was going on pretty good. What's 207 now we see it's down to 206.
What's 207 now we see it's down to 206.
What's 207 now we see it's down to 206. With a little research you can find out
With a little research you can find out
With a little research you can find out why because you see for the collective
why because you see for the collective
why because you see for the collective to go down one point is a lot. For one
to go down one point is a lot. For one
to go down one point is a lot. For one person to go down one point the world
person to go down one point the world
person to go down one point the world will not suffer. Even one point is
will not suffer. Even one point is
will not suffer. Even one point is extremely important. Uh and why did the
extremely important. Uh and why did the
extremely important. Uh and why did the world go down one point? You can with
world go down one point? You can with
world go down one point? You can with you can research it with kinesiology.
you can research it with kinesiology.
you can research it with kinesiology. What factors what agreements? What
What factors what agreements? What
What factors what agreements? What agreements?
agreements?
agreements? Usually it's a collective agreement to a
Usually it's a collective agreement to a
Usually it's a collective agreement to a falsehood. Collective support of a
falsehood. Collective support of a
falsehood. Collective support of a falsehood and then it comes down.
falsehood and then it comes down.
falsehood and then it comes down. Okay, we'll move on. Earth epics. I
Okay, we'll move on. Earth epics. I
Okay, we'll move on. Earth epics. I think this is quite interesting because
think this is quite interesting because
think this is quite interesting because it t demon it takes away the
it t demon it takes away the
it t demon it takes away the demonization of sin and error because
demonization of sin and error because
demonization of sin and error because you see that consciousness is
you see that consciousness is
you see that consciousness is evolutionary evolutionary if it's
evolutionary evolutionary if it's
evolutionary evolutionary if it's evolutionary
evolutionary
evolutionary you know what can I expect an octopus to
you know what can I expect an octopus to
you know what can I expect an octopus to know
we'll move on
we'll move on uh I think it takes the guilt out of the
uh I think it takes the guilt out of the
uh I think it takes the guilt out of the ego if you see that
ego if you see that
ego if you see that The evolution was such that uh that's
The evolution was such that uh that's
The evolution was such that uh that's the way it evolved through creation.
the way it evolved through creation.
the way it evolved through creation. Then you can stop feeling guilty about
Then you can stop feeling guilty about
Then you can stop feeling guilty about the ego and its obvious influence on our
the ego and its obvious influence on our
the ego and its obvious influence on our behaviors. So we are part of an
behaviors. So we are part of an
behaviors. So we are part of an evolutionary
evolutionary
evolutionary uh species and this planet is the
uh species and this planet is the
uh species and this planet is the optimum
optimum
optimum spiritual school optimum
spiritual school optimum
spiritual school optimum for spiritual advancement for karmic
for spiritual advancement for karmic
for spiritual advancement for karmic opportunity to undo negative karma and
opportunity to undo negative karma and
opportunity to undo negative karma and acquire positive karma.
acquire positive karma.
acquire positive karma. Therefore,
Therefore,
Therefore, great catastrophes
great catastrophes
great catastrophes uh look horren horrendous on the
uh look horren horrendous on the
uh look horren horrendous on the surface. At the same time, they undo
surface. At the same time, they undo
surface. At the same time, they undo tremendous amounts of negative karma
and do mass amounts of negative karma.
and do mass amounts of negative karma. Yeah. So, there's a certain benefit
Yeah. So, there's a certain benefit
Yeah. So, there's a certain benefit hidden benefit to all that occurs. It is
hidden benefit to all that occurs. It is
hidden benefit to all that occurs. It is not apparent to perception. But if you
not apparent to perception. But if you
not apparent to perception. But if you use kinesiology
use kinesiology
use kinesiology and you say did all the people in that
and you say did all the people in that
and you say did all the people in that benefit karmically you'll get yes. You
benefit karmically you'll get yes. You
benefit karmically you'll get yes. You all paid off huge debts all at once.
all paid off huge debts all at once.
all paid off huge debts all at once. Plus they got to do it collectively so
Plus they got to do it collectively so
Plus they got to do it collectively so you're not you know all alone on the
you're not you know all alone on the
you're not you know all alone on the golf course when the lightning strikes
golf course when the lightning strikes
golf course when the lightning strikes you.
Octopus.
Octopus. Here's octopus at 20. I want to do the
Here's octopus at 20. I want to do the
Here's octopus at 20. I want to do the giant squid. We never did the giant
giant squid. We never did the giant
giant squid. We never did the giant squid.
squid.
squid. The giant squid, we have permission.
The giant squid, we have permission.
The giant squid, we have permission. Calibrates over 20.
Calibrates over 20.
Calibrates over 20. Calibrates over 18. 19. Giant squid is
Calibrates over 18. 19. Giant squid is
Calibrates over 18. 19. Giant squid is 18.
18.
18. It's a ferocious beast. You don't want
It's a ferocious beast. You don't want
It's a ferocious beast. You don't want to get involved with them.
The giant squid. Anyway, they we we try
The giant squid. Anyway, they we we try to calibrate everything we come across.
to calibrate everything we come across.
to calibrate everything we come across. Why? Because from the whole collective,
Why? Because from the whole collective,
Why? Because from the whole collective, you begin to be able to intuitit a thing
you begin to be able to intuitit a thing
you begin to be able to intuitit a thing to the point where you can look at it
to the point where you can look at it
to the point where you can look at it and guess, you know, that's about 180.
and guess, you know, that's about 180.
and guess, you know, that's about 180. You know, somebody comes on some
You know, somebody comes on some
You know, somebody comes on some talk show at night and you got if that
talk show at night and you got if that
talk show at night and you got if that guy's over 180, I'll eat my shirt. You
guy's over 180, I'll eat my shirt. You
guy's over 180, I'll eat my shirt. You know what I mean?
know what I mean?
know what I mean? On the other hand, you can see people
On the other hand, you can see people
On the other hand, you can see people that are very, very integrous, even
that are very, very integrous, even
that are very, very integrous, even though you may not agree with them. You
though you may not agree with them. You
though you may not agree with them. You know, you can see it's coming out of
know, you can see it's coming out of
know, you can see it's coming out of their faith, out of their concern for
their faith, out of their concern for
their faith, out of their concern for mankind, out of their inner honesty.
mankind, out of their inner honesty.
mankind, out of their inner honesty. Doesn't mean they can't make a mistake.
Doesn't mean they can't make a mistake.
Doesn't mean they can't make a mistake. They can. Okay. So, we'll move on. The
They can. Okay. So, we'll move on. The
They can. Okay. So, we'll move on. The cat's purr, I think, is interesting. The
cat's purr, I think, is interesting. The
cat's purr, I think, is interesting. The cat's purr and the and the dog, I think,
cat's purr and the and the dog, I think,
cat's purr and the and the dog, I think, are two pets that are like gifts uh to
are two pets that are like gifts uh to
are two pets that are like gifts uh to our inner child from God.
our inner child from God.
our inner child from God. I'm sure you folks are all alone mankind
I'm sure you folks are all alone mankind
I'm sure you folks are all alone mankind on the planet. So, we'll send you a
on the planet. So, we'll send you a
on the planet. So, we'll send you a doggy and a kitty.
I know they increase longevity. People
I know they increase longevity. People live longer who have pets and their
live longer who have pets and their
live longer who have pets and their health is higher.
health is higher.
health is higher. It is a positive health and longevity uh
It is a positive health and longevity uh
It is a positive health and longevity uh benefit. Okay.
benefit. Okay.
benefit. Okay. uh the great books of the western world
uh the great books of the western world
uh the great books of the western world I refer to often because it is sort of
I refer to often because it is sort of
I refer to often because it is sort of the the benchmark of intellectual
the the benchmark of intellectual
the the benchmark of intellectual integrity and anything that calibrates
integrity and anything that calibrates
integrity and anything that calibrates uh less than this uh would lack
uh less than this uh would lack
uh less than this uh would lack intellectual integrity
intellectual integrity
intellectual integrity right so like we said the Catholic
right so like we said the Catholic
right so like we said the Catholic Church the impermature is 375
Church the impermature is 375
Church the impermature is 375 that's not 460 see 460 might have put
that's not 460 see 460 might have put
that's not 460 see 460 might have put some other books on the index that they
some other books on the index that they
some other books on the index that they didn't put and removed some of the ones
didn't put and removed some of the ones
didn't put and removed some of the ones that they have on the index. So, it
that they have on the index. So, it
that they have on the index. So, it tells you the degree of reliability and
tells you the degree of reliability and
tells you the degree of reliability and credibility.
credibility.
credibility. Uh, we told you about a new discovery.
Uh, we told you about a new discovery.
Uh, we told you about a new discovery. What's that guy's name this morning?
What's that guy's name this morning?
What's that guy's name this morning? This um Oh, isn't that awful?
This um Oh, isn't that awful?
This um Oh, isn't that awful? >> Peter,
>> Peter,
>> Peter, >> what's his name? Peter Lind.
>> what's his name? Peter Lind.
>> what's his name? Peter Lind. >> Let's do Peter Lind.
>> Let's do Peter Lind.
>> Let's do Peter Lind. We have permission to do Peter Lynn's
We have permission to do Peter Lynn's
We have permission to do Peter Lynn's theory, not Peter Lynn personally. his
theory, not Peter Lynn personally. his
theory, not Peter Lynn personally. his theory
theory
theory calibrates over 480 485 480 that's a
calibrates over 480 485 480 that's a
calibrates over 480 485 480 that's a very very high level of intellectual
very very high level of intellectual
very very high level of intellectual acuity 480 so we would guess that at 480
acuity 480 so we would guess that at 480
acuity 480 so we would guess that at 480 he's quite likely correct huh uh so
he's quite likely correct huh uh so
he's quite likely correct huh uh so these are the history of mankind the
these are the history of mankind the
these are the history of mankind the electional history of mankind beginning
electional history of mankind beginning
electional history of mankind beginning really with Plato beginning around 350
really with Plato beginning around 350
really with Plato beginning around 350 BC in Greece the golden period of Greece
BC in Greece the golden period of Greece
BC in Greece the golden period of Greece has frankly not been improved on in the
has frankly not been improved on in the
has frankly not been improved on in the centuries since
sorry guys I don't mean to say that I
sorry guys I don't mean to say that I don't mean that personally but frankly
don't mean that personally but frankly
don't mean that personally but frankly not much has been discovered since
not much has been discovered since
not much has been discovered since Socrates or Plato in the intellectual
Socrates or Plato in the intellectual
Socrates or Plato in the intellectual realm. Yeah. Uh so you see intellectual
realm. Yeah. Uh so you see intellectual
realm. Yeah. Uh so you see intellectual integrity and we always point out
integrity and we always point out
integrity and we always point out Engle's just on the border at 200 and
Engle's just on the border at 200 and
Engle's just on the border at 200 and here's the co here's the cause of a
here's the co here's the cause of a
here's the co here's the cause of a couple hundred million people's death
couple hundred million people's death
couple hundred million people's death Karl Marx at 130. Therefore, the
Karl Marx at 130. Therefore, the
Karl Marx at 130. Therefore, the calibration is very important, isn't it?
calibration is very important, isn't it?
calibration is very important, isn't it? Out of one person, you have Einstein.
Out of one person, you have Einstein.
Out of one person, you have Einstein. Out of out of you have uh Socrates
Out of out of you have uh Socrates
Out of out of you have uh Socrates and out of 130, you've got enormous
and out of 130, you've got enormous
and out of 130, you've got enormous destruction. The goolog put to death
destruction. The goolog put to death
destruction. The goolog put to death tens of millions. Chairman Mayo's 30
tens of millions. Chairman Mayo's 30
tens of millions. Chairman Mayo's 30 million people starved. So, you see,
million people starved. So, you see,
million people starved. So, you see, it's not just academic.
it's not just academic.
it's not just academic. This 130 has cost the life of probably
This 130 has cost the life of probably
This 130 has cost the life of probably 300 million people. probably half a
300 million people. probably half a
300 million people. probably half a billion because it's not done yet. Yep.
billion because it's not done yet. Yep.
billion because it's not done yet. Yep. The killing fields
The killing fields
The killing fields how important that is. Yeah. And Darwin
how important that is. Yeah. And Darwin
how important that is. Yeah. And Darwin at 450. Uhhuh. Darwinism is at 450. And
at 450. Uhhuh. Darwinism is at 450. And
at 450. Uhhuh. Darwinism is at 450. And of course intelligent design.
of course intelligent design.
of course intelligent design. What? I always forget what intelligent
What? I always forget what intelligent
What? I always forget what intelligent design is at. Can we do intelligent
design is at. Can we do intelligent
design is at. Can we do intelligent design?
design?
design? We have permission to do intelligent
We have permission to do intelligent
We have permission to do intelligent design. It's over 450 460.
design. It's over 450 460.
design. It's over 450 460. 455
455 450 it's right at 450
450 it's right at 450
450 it's right at 450 huh intelligence is 450
huh intelligence is 450
huh intelligence is 450 I thought it would be a little higher
I thought it would be a little higher
I thought it would be a little higher than that
than that
than that well the intelligence is innate
well the intelligence is innate
well the intelligence is innate biologically see and of course people
biologically see and of course people
biologically see and of course people don't like it because it's a slippery
don't like it because it's a slippery
don't like it because it's a slippery slope next thing you're going to say is
slope next thing you're going to say is
slope next thing you're going to say is behind intelligent design there's a
behind intelligent design there's a
behind intelligent design there's a divinity so
divinity so
divinity so that's the slippery slope argument
that's the slippery slope argument
that's the slippery slope argument all right So we could of course spend uh
all right So we could of course spend uh
all right So we could of course spend uh you know several lectures just on the
you know several lectures just on the
you know several lectures just on the content of all of this. These were were
content of all of this. These were were
content of all of this. These were were my companions of childhood. Well,
my companions of childhood. Well,
my companions of childhood. Well, everybody was out there playing
everybody was out there playing
everybody was out there playing stickball. I was stuck in a chair
stickball. I was stuck in a chair
stickball. I was stuck in a chair because we had the great books of the
because we had the great books of the
because we had the great books of the western world and uh I so I was a you
western world and uh I so I was a you
western world and uh I so I was a you know the little ectomorph with glasses.
know the little ectomorph with glasses.
know the little ectomorph with glasses. Well other guys are doing disgusting
Well other guys are doing disgusting
Well other guys are doing disgusting things like digging their fingers in
things like digging their fingers in
things like digging their fingers in each other's eyes and mud and socking
each other's eyes and mud and socking
each other's eyes and mud and socking each other and jumping each other. I was
each other and jumping each other. I was
each other and jumping each other. I was reading Socrates, you know.
Oh god. So, okay, there we go. The next
Oh god. So, okay, there we go. The next here we have we talk about context,
here we have we talk about context,
here we have we talk about context, approximate content and the event. This
approximate content and the event. This
approximate content and the event. This is the basis of u of course situational
is the basis of u of course situational
is the basis of u of course situational ethics that an event cannot be
ethics that an event cannot be
ethics that an event cannot be understood, comprehended or judged
understood, comprehended or judged
understood, comprehended or judged unless you state the context. And this
unless you state the context. And this
unless you state the context. And this is the avenue for um political fallacy.
is the avenue for um political fallacy.
is the avenue for um political fallacy. You know, people attack a certain
You know, people attack a certain
You know, people attack a certain concept and so and then they for and
concept and so and then they for and
concept and so and then they for and then but they don't state the context.
then but they don't state the context.
then but they don't state the context. They don't state the context which
They don't state the context which
They don't state the context which totally changes it. So one way of
totally changes it. So one way of
totally changes it. So one way of rhetorical falsehood
rhetorical falsehood
rhetorical falsehood is to purposely admit the context.
is to purposely admit the context.
is to purposely admit the context. Is a certain thing okay or not okay?
Is a certain thing okay or not okay?
Is a certain thing okay or not okay? Depends on a lot of things, right?
Depends on a lot of things, right?
Depends on a lot of things, right? uh like whether you're at war or not.
uh like whether you're at war or not.
uh like whether you're at war or not. Makes the next leather
Makes the next leather
Makes the next leather whether you're poor or not, whether
whether you're poor or not, whether
whether you're poor or not, whether you're, you know, getting insurance
you're, you know, getting insurance
you're, you know, getting insurance money. I mean, a lot of the it all
money. I mean, a lot of the it all
money. I mean, a lot of the it all depends on context. So, of course,
depends on context. So, of course,
depends on context. So, of course, courts recognize that. Uh motivation,
courts recognize that. Uh motivation,
courts recognize that. Uh motivation, it's called motivation. Uh so, how you
it's called motivation. Uh so, how you
it's called motivation. Uh so, how you know severe should the punishment be?
know severe should the punishment be?
know severe should the punishment be? Well, it depends on the context. Then
Well, it depends on the context. Then
Well, it depends on the context. Then sometimes that's misused because the
sometimes that's misused because the
sometimes that's misused because the person is mentally ill. There's no
person is mentally ill. There's no
person is mentally ill. There's no consequences.
consequences.
consequences. Why should mentally ill people be exempt
Why should mentally ill people be exempt
Why should mentally ill people be exempt from consequences when mentally healthy
from consequences when mentally healthy
from consequences when mentally healthy people pay them? Tell me why they should
people pay them? Tell me why they should
people pay them? Tell me why they should be excused. Well, they should be handled
be excused. Well, they should be handled
be excused. Well, they should be handled differently. And I agree with that. So
differently. And I agree with that. So
differently. And I agree with that. So sometimes this contextualization is
sometimes this contextualization is
sometimes this contextualization is misused by certain judges uh as we see
misused by certain judges uh as we see
misused by certain judges uh as we see on the evening news. Okay. Next
on the evening news. Okay. Next
on the evening news. Okay. Next uh content field. You see the content is
uh content field. You see the content is
uh content field. You see the content is linear. Uh this is the time and space
linear. Uh this is the time and space
linear. Uh this is the time and space the Newtonian dimension of causality.
the Newtonian dimension of causality.
the Newtonian dimension of causality. Causality is based on force over time
Causality is based on force over time
Causality is based on force over time and it has to do with location.
and it has to do with location.
and it has to do with location. Therefore how it links in with Peter
Therefore how it links in with Peter
Therefore how it links in with Peter Lynch's uh
Lynch's uh
Lynch's uh recent uh discovery is quite
recent uh discovery is quite
recent uh discovery is quite interesting. and the approximate field
interesting. and the approximate field
interesting. and the approximate field we talk about the spiritual ego and in
we talk about the spiritual ego and in
we talk about the spiritual ego and in um teachers should always be sure to
um teachers should always be sure to
um teachers should always be sure to bring this up the spiritual ego and um I
bring this up the spiritual ego and um I
bring this up the spiritual ego and um I feel a teacher's responsible make sure
feel a teacher's responsible make sure
feel a teacher's responsible make sure that you hear about the downside before
that you hear about the downside before
that you hear about the downside before you fall into it
you fall into it
you fall into it the more you learn the more the
the more you learn the more the
the more you learn the more the spiritual the ego is threatened so it's
spiritual the ego is threatened so it's
spiritual the ego is threatened so it's clever it it camouflages itself and
clever it it camouflages itself and
clever it it camouflages itself and comes back to spiritual ego which you're
comes back to spiritual ego which you're
comes back to spiritual ego which you're more holy than somebody else and this
more holy than somebody else and this
more holy than somebody else and this and that. Yeah. And um spiritual
and that. Yeah. And um spiritual
and that. Yeah. And um spiritual teachers get it too. Spiritual teachers
teachers get it too. Spiritual teachers
teachers get it too. Spiritual teachers get it. You can tell by their
get it. You can tell by their
get it. You can tell by their grandiosity of the robes and the giant
grandiosity of the robes and the giant
grandiosity of the robes and the giant palaces and the retinue and the drama
palaces and the retinue and the drama
palaces and the retinue and the drama and the theatrics to go with the whole
and the theatrics to go with the whole
and the theatrics to go with the whole presentation.
presentation.
presentation. Uh so the spiritual ego
Uh so the spiritual ego
Uh so the spiritual ego uh takes the place of the old ego. And
uh takes the place of the old ego. And
uh takes the place of the old ego. And of course as you let the spiritual ego
of course as you let the spiritual ego
of course as you let the spiritual ego you you do the same thing. The spiritual
you you do the same thing. The spiritual
you you do the same thing. The spiritual ego is getting some kind of juice over
ego is getting some kind of juice over
ego is getting some kind of juice over this. Yeah. They're you're feeling more
this. Yeah. They're you're feeling more
this. Yeah. They're you're feeling more holy. That means you're superior. That's
holy. That means you're superior. That's
holy. That means you're superior. That's pride. So it's very easy to spirit. See
pride. So it's very easy to spirit. See
pride. So it's very easy to spirit. See the spiritual ego if somebody warns you
the spiritual ego if somebody warns you
the spiritual ego if somebody warns you it's inevitable as you advance the
it's inevitable as you advance the
it's inevitable as you advance the spiritual ego is going to come up. Okay?
spiritual ego is going to come up. Okay?
spiritual ego is going to come up. Okay? Because frankly in some ways you are
Because frankly in some ways you are
Because frankly in some ways you are holier than a lot of people.
Well, nobody here is going to blow up a
Well, nobody here is going to blow up a busload of innocent children. Are you?
busload of innocent children. Are you?
busload of innocent children. Are you? Anybody here want to blow up a busload
Anybody here want to blow up a busload
Anybody here want to blow up a busload of kids? Maybe later. I'll meet you
of kids? Maybe later. I'll meet you
of kids? Maybe later. I'll meet you later. Yeah.
To prove how holy you are, you blow up a
To prove how holy you are, you blow up a busload of kids. You put dynam around
busload of kids. You put dynam around
busload of kids. You put dynam around yourself and you blow yourself up,
yourself and you blow yourself up,
yourself and you blow yourself up, right? All right. So, our spiritual ego
right? All right. So, our spiritual ego
right? All right. So, our spiritual ego says, "God, how stupid." I mean, you
says, "God, how stupid." I mean, you
says, "God, how stupid." I mean, you know, it calibrates at 90. How can you
know, it calibrates at 90. How can you
know, it calibrates at 90. How can you sell people on something that calibrates
sell people on something that calibrates
sell people on something that calibrates at 90? So, the spiritual ego comes up
at 90? So, the spiritual ego comes up
at 90? So, the spiritual ego comes up and we have to watch it.
and we have to watch it.
and we have to watch it. Uh, first we attack this ego. This one's
Uh, first we attack this ego. This one's
Uh, first we attack this ego. This one's easy to see right off the chart. This
easy to see right off the chart. This
easy to see right off the chart. This one we got to watch because it sneaks up
one we got to watch because it sneaks up
one we got to watch because it sneaks up and holy. It's called holier than thou.
and holy. It's called holier than thou.
and holy. It's called holier than thou. It's also the far love position. The far
It's also the far love position. The far
It's also the far love position. The far political position is holier than thou.
political position is holier than thou.
political position is holier than thou. It's called spiritual superiority or
It's called spiritual superiority or
It's called spiritual superiority or what do they call it? They call
what do they call it? They call
what do they call it? They call spiritually correct. Correct. Correct.
spiritually correct. Correct. Correct.
spiritually correct. Correct. Correct. Correct. So you see the ego appeal to be
Correct. So you see the ego appeal to be
Correct. So you see the ego appeal to be correct because if you're correct then
correct because if you're correct then
correct because if you're correct then everybody else is incorrect
everybody else is incorrect
everybody else is incorrect that's a neat place to be. Yeah. All
that's a neat place to be. Yeah. All
that's a neat place to be. Yeah. All right. Spiritual I mean what do they
right. Spiritual I mean what do they
right. Spiritual I mean what do they call politically correct PC or
call politically correct PC or
call politically correct PC or >> politically correct.
>> politically correct.
>> politically correct. >> So whatever it is anyway uh you can see
>> So whatever it is anyway uh you can see
>> So whatever it is anyway uh you can see you know you sound idealistic which you
you know you sound idealistic which you
you know you sound idealistic which you what you don't realize you're feel is
what you don't realize you're feel is
what you don't realize you're feel is you're sounding adolescent. You're
you're sounding adolescent. You're
you're sounding adolescent. You're sounding adolescent
sounding adolescent
sounding adolescent and but you think you're superior. Okay.
and but you think you're superior. Okay.
and but you think you're superior. Okay. So that's the spiritual ego coming up
So that's the spiritual ego coming up
So that's the spiritual ego coming up and it loves to feed on being superior
and it loves to feed on being superior
and it loves to feed on being superior and correct. Yes, superior. That's it.
and correct. Yes, superior. That's it.
and correct. Yes, superior. That's it. Seriously, politically superior,
Seriously, politically superior,
Seriously, politically superior, correct? Whatever it is. Okay, we'll
correct? Whatever it is. Okay, we'll
correct? Whatever it is. Okay, we'll move on then.
move on then.
move on then. The virtues are often overlooked. Um
The virtues are often overlooked. Um
The virtues are often overlooked. Um these we we presume uh are part and
these we we presume uh are part and
these we we presume uh are part and parcel of traditional bringing up in
parcel of traditional bringing up in
parcel of traditional bringing up in America. the America I grew up which is
America. the America I grew up which is
America. the America I grew up which is now ridiculed as traditional America. Uh
now ridiculed as traditional America. Uh
now ridiculed as traditional America. Uh this was reality
this was reality
this was reality and every everybody was pretty much this
and every everybody was pretty much this
and every everybody was pretty much this way. Frankly, everybody
way. Frankly, everybody
way. Frankly, everybody was pretty much in the positive 200.
was pretty much in the positive 200.
was pretty much in the positive 200. They certainly were in the 300s. Uh if
They certainly were in the 300s. Uh if
They certainly were in the 300s. Uh if you were moving, all your neighbors
you were moving, all your neighbors
you were moving, all your neighbors offered to help. They offered to loan
offered to help. They offered to loan
offered to help. They offered to loan you a van, a truck,
you a van, a truck,
you a van, a truck, moved in a new neighborhood. The ladies
moved in a new neighborhood. The ladies
moved in a new neighborhood. The ladies around brought in a cake that they baked
around brought in a cake that they baked
around brought in a cake that they baked and they greeted you and told you who
and they greeted you and told you who
and they greeted you and told you who they were. If you lent somebody your
they were. If you lent somebody your
they were. If you lent somebody your lawnmower, you always got it back. So
lawnmower, you always got it back. So
lawnmower, you always got it back. So I guess compared to nowadays, it was a
I guess compared to nowadays, it was a
I guess compared to nowadays, it was a dream world. A dream world. Uh,
dream world. A dream world. Uh,
dream world. A dream world. Uh, and of course a really good neighbor not
and of course a really good neighbor not
and of course a really good neighbor not only returns it but sharpens the blades
only returns it but sharpens the blades
only returns it but sharpens the blades so it comes back in better shape than it
so it comes back in better shape than it
so it comes back in better shape than it was. So all of us strove to be that kind
was. So all of us strove to be that kind
was. So all of us strove to be that kind of thoughtful, considerate,
of thoughtful, considerate,
of thoughtful, considerate, easygoing, non-malicious,
easygoing, non-malicious,
easygoing, non-malicious, non-selicious and pornography was not
non-selicious and pornography was not
non-selicious and pornography was not cool or in
cool or in
cool or in uh so it was a reasonably virtuous
uh so it was a reasonably virtuous
uh so it was a reasonably virtuous foundation. And I say before you go on
foundation. And I say before you go on
foundation. And I say before you go on to become enlightened this week, just
to become enlightened this week, just
to become enlightened this week, just look down and ask in what way is here.
look down and ask in what way is here.
look down and ask in what way is here. Can I be warmer to people, more kind?
Can I be warmer to people, more kind?
Can I be warmer to people, more kind? And you'll see no matter how far you are
And you'll see no matter how far you are
And you'll see no matter how far you are along the spiritual pathway,
along the spiritual pathway,
along the spiritual pathway, these are always open. You can always be
these are always open. You can always be
these are always open. You can always be a little more tolerant. You can always
a little more tolerant. You can always
a little more tolerant. You can always uh reject being upset by something that
uh reject being upset by something that
uh reject being upset by something that goes on and say
goes on and say
goes on and say I'm choosing to remain calm the heck
I'm choosing to remain calm the heck
I'm choosing to remain calm the heck with it. Uh you can always be more
with it. Uh you can always be more
with it. Uh you can always be more respectful perhaps
respectful perhaps
respectful perhaps uh be more sane. I don't know if that's
uh be more sane. I don't know if that's
uh be more sane. I don't know if that's possible but we try.
possible but we try.
possible but we try. Everybody is a little messy and messy
Everybody is a little messy and messy
Everybody is a little messy and messy and give you a little more. So we try to
and give you a little more. So we try to
and give you a little more. So we try to be friendly and cordial. We try to be a
be friendly and cordial. We try to be a
be friendly and cordial. We try to be a good host to everyone we run into. So if
good host to everyone we run into. So if
good host to everyone we run into. So if you do that, you'll be uh you know
you do that, you'll be uh you know
you do that, you'll be uh you know achieve what's going on call good
achieve what's going on call good
achieve what's going on call good personhood.
personhood.
personhood. And you may uh you say well I presume
And you may uh you say well I presume
And you may uh you say well I presume that's the way everybody is. It's not
that's the way everybody is. It's not
that's the way everybody is. It's not because as you thank clerks and various
because as you thank clerks and various
because as you thank clerks and various people like that you'll often see their
people like that you'll often see their
people like that you'll often see their face go
Most people give you give them the
Most people give you give them the credit card and you walk away. Nobody
credit card and you walk away. Nobody
credit card and you walk away. Nobody said, "Gee, thanks for the trouble."
said, "Gee, thanks for the trouble."
said, "Gee, thanks for the trouble." Wow. I mean, it sort of knocks them
Wow. I mean, it sort of knocks them
Wow. I mean, it sort of knocks them over. Just being kind to people because
over. Just being kind to people because
over. Just being kind to people because it's loving to to be appreciative, to
it's loving to to be appreciative, to
it's loving to to be appreciative, to give recognition. So, one way you can be
give recognition. So, one way you can be
give recognition. So, one way you can be loving to people is to give recognition
loving to people is to give recognition
loving to people is to give recognition to who they are. You know what I mean?
to who they are. You know what I mean?
to who they are. You know what I mean? Uh the guy who picks up our trash, the
Uh the guy who picks up our trash, the
Uh the guy who picks up our trash, the big monster truck, always falls over
big monster truck, always falls over
big monster truck, always falls over when we tell him, "Gee, whiz, you're
when we tell him, "Gee, whiz, you're
when we tell him, "Gee, whiz, you're doing a great job." And of course, I
doing a great job." And of course, I
doing a great job." And of course, I give him five or 10 bucks anyway, just
give him five or 10 bucks anyway, just
give him five or 10 bucks anyway, just because it's more than just, you know,
because it's more than just, you know,
because it's more than just, you know, saying it. You actually do mean it. And
saying it. You actually do mean it. And
saying it. You actually do mean it. And he always goes,
he always goes,
he always goes, I mean, nobody complimented him for
I mean, nobody complimented him for
I mean, nobody complimented him for bring picking up their trash. They So
bring picking up their trash. They So
bring picking up their trash. They So just try for fun and you'll see the
just try for fun and you'll see the
just try for fun and you'll see the amazing response of people. You think,
amazing response of people. You think,
amazing response of people. You think, well, everybody says thank you. No, they
well, everybody says thank you. No, they
well, everybody says thank you. No, they do not. So if I ask the trash man, how
do not. So if I ask the trash man, how
do not. So if I ask the trash man, how many people run up and as you dump them
many people run up and as you dump them
many people run up and as you dump them and gee say thanks. Thanks a lot. You
and gee say thanks. Thanks a lot. You
and gee say thanks. Thanks a lot. You know, frankly,
know, frankly,
know, frankly, so there's always room for always room
so there's always room for always room
so there's always room for always room for improvement. No matter where you
for improvement. No matter where you
for improvement. No matter where you are, there's still room for improvement.
are, there's still room for improvement.
are, there's still room for improvement. Still room for improvement. Especially
Still room for improvement. Especially
Still room for improvement. Especially with one spouse.
That is a great area for improvement
That is a great area for improvement because the two of you always bring up
because the two of you always bring up
because the two of you always bring up what needs
what needs
what needs to be looked at. That's why it's so
to be looked at. That's why it's so
to be looked at. That's why it's so valuable. You can see you're being uh
valuable. You can see you're being uh
valuable. You can see you're being uh you know short-tempered or uh what do I
you know short-tempered or uh what do I
you know short-tempered or uh what do I do? I lose patient. Lose patience. You
do? I lose patient. Lose patience. You
do? I lose patient. Lose patience. You lose patience.
lose patience.
lose patience. Okay. Uh we'll go on to the next.
Okay. Uh we'll go on to the next.
Okay. Uh we'll go on to the next. uh the uh we said that the mind uh has
uh the uh we said that the mind uh has
uh the uh we said that the mind uh has us all hypnotized
us all hypnotized
us all hypnotized that actually 99% of the mind is silent.
that actually 99% of the mind is silent.
that actually 99% of the mind is silent. This is a really good thing to know
This is a really good thing to know
This is a really good thing to know because people go into despair. They go
because people go into despair. They go
because people go into despair. They go to meditate and the mind just will not
to meditate and the mind just will not
to meditate and the mind just will not stop like a TV set with no off switch
stop like a TV set with no off switch
stop like a TV set with no off switch and it's because they're looking at the
and it's because they're looking at the
and it's because they're looking at the wrong place. They're looking at the
wrong place. They're looking at the
wrong place. They're looking at the content of consciousness. And what we
content of consciousness. And what we
content of consciousness. And what we need to look at is the field out of
need to look at is the field out of
need to look at is the field out of which uh thinkingness arises.
which uh thinkingness arises.
which uh thinkingness arises. Uh right now 99% of your mind is silent.
Uh right now 99% of your mind is silent.
Uh right now 99% of your mind is silent. 99% of your mind is silent. Let's see.
99% of your mind is silent. Let's see.
99% of your mind is silent. Let's see. We have permission to ask that. 99% of
We have permission to ask that. 99% of
We have permission to ask that. 99% of their mind is silent. 99% of your mind
their mind is silent. 99% of your mind
their mind is silent. 99% of your mind is silent. What are you complaining
is silent. What are you complaining
is silent. What are you complaining about?
The ocean
The ocean is still and silent all the way down and
is still and silent all the way down and
is still and silent all the way down and the waves are only on the surface. You
the waves are only on the surface. You
the waves are only on the surface. You see, you don't have to still the whole
see, you don't have to still the whole
see, you don't have to still the whole ocean. You know, you only have to watch
ocean. You know, you only have to watch
ocean. You know, you only have to watch the waves. All right? So, the place to
the waves. All right? So, the place to
the waves. All right? So, the place to focus in both meditation and uh
focus in both meditation and uh
focus in both meditation and uh contemplation
contemplation
contemplation is to identify with the field. As I'm
is to identify with the field. As I'm
is to identify with the field. As I'm speaking right now, there's absolute
speaking right now, there's absolute
speaking right now, there's absolute silence below the field that's speaking.
silence below the field that's speaking.
silence below the field that's speaking. The speaking is not
The speaking is not
The speaking is not uh myself. The speakingness is a surface
uh myself. The speakingness is a surface
uh myself. The speakingness is a surface phenomena.
phenomena.
phenomena. The self really has nothing to say right
The self really has nothing to say right
The self really has nothing to say right now and is absolutely silent.
now and is absolutely silent.
now and is absolutely silent. I mean, what's there to say?
I mean, what's there to say?
I mean, what's there to say? Nothing to say except to be with all
Nothing to say except to be with all
Nothing to say except to be with all that is as it is. To be with requires no
that is as it is. To be with requires no
that is as it is. To be with requires no commentary. So you see the egotism of
commentary. So you see the egotism of
commentary. So you see the egotism of the vanity of the mind that it always
the vanity of the mind that it always
the vanity of the mind that it always has to to add to or make commentary on
has to to add to or make commentary on
has to to add to or make commentary on what's going on. If you ask the mind,
what's going on. If you ask the mind,
what's going on. If you ask the mind, you know, to stop making commentary, I'm
you know, to stop making commentary, I'm
you know, to stop making commentary, I'm frankly not interested in your mind in
frankly not interested in your mind in
frankly not interested in your mind in your viewpoints.
your viewpoints.
your viewpoints. Oh,
Oh,
Oh, are you interested in your view my
are you interested in your view my
are you interested in your view my viewpoints?
viewpoints?
viewpoints? But aren't you supposed to stand up for
But aren't you supposed to stand up for
But aren't you supposed to stand up for yourself? Look at all the stuff in the
yourself? Look at all the stuff in the
yourself? Look at all the stuff in the society that encourages
society that encourages
society that encourages the vanity of egotism. You know, you're
the vanity of egotism. You know, you're
the vanity of egotism. You know, you're supposed to do this, you're supposed to
supposed to do this, you're supposed to
supposed to do this, you're supposed to do that.
do that.
do that. All kinds of rights and stuff come up,
All kinds of rights and stuff come up,
All kinds of rights and stuff come up, you know, but it isn't my right to it's
you know, but it isn't my right to it's
you know, but it isn't my right to it's your right to think, but keep it to
your right to think, but keep it to
your right to think, but keep it to yourself.
All right? So, the mind is seductive.
All right? So, the mind is seductive. It appeals to the narcissistic core of
It appeals to the narcissistic core of
It appeals to the narcissistic core of the ego.
the ego.
the ego. There's nobody your mind likes to listen
There's nobody your mind likes to listen
There's nobody your mind likes to listen to better than yourself.
to better than yourself.
to better than yourself. It loves talking to yourself, listening
It loves talking to yourself, listening
It loves talking to yourself, listening to yourself, all your complaints,
to yourself, all your complaints,
to yourself, all your complaints, your wonderful ideas.
your wonderful ideas.
your wonderful ideas. You catch the vanity of it and you catch
You catch the vanity of it and you catch
You catch the vanity of it and you catch the seduction of the mind. So the
the seduction of the mind. So the
the seduction of the mind. So the narcissistic ego is vested in
narcissistic ego is vested in
narcissistic ego is vested in mentalizing everything and uh
mentalizing everything and uh
mentalizing everything and uh emotionalizing about it. Whereas in fact
emotionalizing about it. Whereas in fact
emotionalizing about it. Whereas in fact there's nothing there underneath all
there's nothing there underneath all
there's nothing there underneath all that talkingness. There's infinite
that talkingness. There's infinite
that talkingness. There's infinite silence. There's actually nothing
silence. There's actually nothing
silence. There's actually nothing happening.
happening.
happening. Nothing happening. Why? Because it's
Nothing happening. Why? Because it's
Nothing happening. Why? Because it's outside of time and it's nonlinear. So
outside of time and it's nonlinear. So
outside of time and it's nonlinear. So how can anything be happening in a
how can anything be happening in a
how can anything be happening in a nonlinear
nonlinear
nonlinear infinite dimension? The field of
infinite dimension? The field of
infinite dimension? The field of consciousness itself there is a
consciousness itself there is a
consciousness itself there is a potentiality
even in divinity
even in divinity prior to God is the Godhead. The Godhead
prior to God is the Godhead. The Godhead
prior to God is the Godhead. The Godhead is the infinite potential out of which
is the infinite potential out of which
is the infinite potential out of which divinity and godness arises.
divinity and godness arises.
divinity and godness arises. The infinite silence which is not busy
The infinite silence which is not busy
The infinite silence which is not busy creating or doing anything. It's an
creating or doing anything. It's an
creating or doing anything. It's an infinite potential out of which arises
infinite potential out of which arises
infinite potential out of which arises divinity. Out of which arises all of
divinity. Out of which arises all of
divinity. Out of which arises all of creation is the light of God
creation is the light of God
creation is the light of God is the radiance of consciousness. And as
is the radiance of consciousness. And as
is the radiance of consciousness. And as consciousness encounters matter, it
consciousness encounters matter, it
consciousness encounters matter, it springs forth organicity which emerges
springs forth organicity which emerges
springs forth organicity which emerges as life. Yeah. Uh but it all radiates
as life. Yeah. Uh but it all radiates
as life. Yeah. Uh but it all radiates out of the infinite silence
out of the infinite silence
out of the infinite silence that we call the godhead.
Let's see if that's correct.
Let's see if that's correct. That is correct. Resist the Godhead is
That is correct. Resist the Godhead is
That is correct. Resist the Godhead is infinite silence and it's just infinite
infinite silence and it's just infinite
infinite silence and it's just infinite infinite potentiality. Infinite
infinite potentiality. Infinite
infinite potentiality. Infinite potentiality.
potentiality.
potentiality. Okay. And where did God that all where
Okay. And where did God that all where
Okay. And where did God that all where did that arise from? And this is the
did that arise from? And this is the
did that arise from? And this is the hard part. It always was.
Hardest thing for religion to get is
Hardest thing for religion to get is that divinity always was.
that divinity always was.
that divinity always was. There is no first cause because it's not
There is no first cause because it's not
There is no first cause because it's not linear. That which is forever has no
linear. That which is forever has no
linear. That which is forever has no beginning or ending. Therefore, it's
beginning or ending. Therefore, it's
beginning or ending. Therefore, it's beyond causality. Needs no explanation.
beyond causality. Needs no explanation.
beyond causality. Needs no explanation. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. I saw that back in theology and
Yeah. I saw that back in theology and
Yeah. I saw that back in theology and Jesuit University playing Bob first
Jesuit University playing Bob first
Jesuit University playing Bob first cause Thomas Aquinus and I thought that
cause Thomas Aquinus and I thought that
cause Thomas Aquinus and I thought that which is infinite doesn't have any
which is infinite doesn't have any
which is infinite doesn't have any cause. It would have to have a beginning
cause. It would have to have a beginning
cause. It would have to have a beginning and an end. It would therefore have to
and an end. It would therefore have to
and an end. It would therefore have to be finite. How could that which is
be finite. How could that which is
be finite. How could that which is infinite be finite? It's beyond cause.
infinite be finite? It's beyond cause.
infinite be finite? It's beyond cause. The cause is a mentalization
The cause is a mentalization
The cause is a mentalization that you project onto the world. All
that you project onto the world. All
that you project onto the world. All right? So this is how the mind keeps
right? So this is how the mind keeps
right? So this is how the mind keeps itself busy. Keeps you fascinated and
itself busy. Keeps you fascinated and
itself busy. Keeps you fascinated and entrapped entrapped. On the end one hand
entrapped entrapped. On the end one hand
entrapped entrapped. On the end one hand you have fun out of it. On the other
you have fun out of it. On the other
you have fun out of it. On the other hand you're its victim. Okay let it go.
hand you're its victim. Okay let it go.
hand you're its victim. Okay let it go. So when you we'll move the move on. So
So when you we'll move the move on. So
So when you we'll move the move on. So when you don't want to be victim of the
when you don't want to be victim of the
when you don't want to be victim of the mind anymore, you have to be willing to
mind anymore, you have to be willing to
mind anymore, you have to be willing to give those things upl