excited pretty soon we're going to have a hundred slides wow unconsciousness level unconditional
love unconditional love is really at 540 and the miraculous is common at 540 540 is the
calibration level of 12 step groups etc of course the miracles and the miraculous occurs there all
the time of course and so that's what people seek through spiritual healing they speak they
what they're seeking is the reach of field in which the energy of the field is such that it
has a more powerful effect as context so we're saying that they're spontaneous they're autonomous
they're part of the emergence of creation and the power of faith and belief potentiates their
likelihood the likelihood is they with faith and belief and of course constantine
demonstrated that principle that he prayed earnestly to a god and not even the god that we
are familiar with but whatever god there might be and transformed all of western the western world
and i forgot to mention of course as a consequence of constantine emerged the council of nicaea
and of course constantinople as dr kalmbach was briefing me on the history he's a history buff he
knows everything that ever happened in it
whenever my mind is bottled i'm recovering from it
council of nicaea and of course constantinople which when editurk took over in turkey he changed
the name to uh istanbul istanbul
i like constantinople better but it's in blue
sounds mysterious
all right so we think that when what we hope will occur
doesn't occur that somehow we've lost god is not answering our prayer
miracles is not a possibility everybody's busy praying for healings of something
and giving god advice in all kinds of matters there's a considerable benefit in
not hate not
non-healing, and as I mentioned, the last pope signified that, that it is, if accepted
with grace, you accept that for reasons I know not, that you take on some of the suffering
of your own life, and maybe even have volunteered to do so for others, for the undoing of perhaps
negative karmic events in the past, so if a thing doesn't heal, it doesn't mean you've
lost, it means that it now has taken on a different significance or meaning, I've had
a whole textbook of physical illnesses in this lifetime, and any one of which should
have killed me, and half a dozen at one time, and came close to death very, not infrequently,
and somehow miraculously they healed.
I can just, you know, we give testimony to the miraculous in our own life, and of course
that's what I'm doing now, in my own life, there were many grave illnesses, and I just
refused regular medical treatment, and for instance, I was dying of heart failure, and
this was in Sedona, not that many years ago, 25 or so, 20 years ago, and I went to see
an internist, and he said, well, you know, I'm going to go to Sedona, and I'm going to
see if you've got COPD and right-hearted heart failure, there isn't anything we can
do about it, so I went home to die, and I had a pinning edema, it's called anisarcha,
it's so severe that your whole body swells up right about to here, so when it gets to
the heart, you croak, so I figured, well, I put the house in order, I'm very neat, you
know, compulsive type, make sure everything's neat and sweet and orderly.
And ready to go, and at the same time, I had a voracious appetite, I was eating, I figured,
6,000 calories a day, and losing weight, I weighed about 110, and I was still director,
chief of staff at this recovery house in Prescott Valley, so I didn't want them to know about
my condition, so I smuggled in little oxygen tanks in my black bag.
And then periodically, I would breathe oxygen, and because to go to the girl's ranch, you
have to go over Mingus Mountain, which is 7,200 feet, and Sedona's at 45, and the girl's
ranch is at about 6, so I smuggled oxygen in, and they wouldn't know that I was having
this problem, and I just kept going as long as possible.
One day, a cop stopped me.
And he said, Doc, you're not driving right today.
He says, you better go see your doctor.
So anyway, I went to an emergency room in Cottonwood, and their wonderful doctor, an
internist who's been my internist ever since, looked at me, and he said, that's the worst
case of greatest disease I've ever seen.
And the internist I'd seen before in Sedona, it wasn't even a differential diagnosis.
He hadn't even thought of that.
But anyway, the thyroid was enlarged, and the protein-bound iodine, everything was way
off.
So they said, well, we'll have to take the thyroid out surgically.
I said, well, I don't think I want to do that.
No, I have my own ways of doing things.
So then they decided radiation was the way to go, and I said, I don't think so.
Radiation sickness, no, I don't think I'll take that.
And anyway, I slowly recovered.
I take, I'll show you how we practice medicine at home.
We save thousands of dollars.
That's how you do it.
Okay, my PBI is currently normal.
That saved $150.
You're going to put all your colleagues out of business.
My chest x-ray is currently normal.
Okay, and the right upper apex, I mean, these are all these illnesses.
They're boring.
Listen to me.
But this is the only opportunity I'll ever get this time.
I got to cap the bodies to tell them all my medical problems.
In the meantime, by chest x-ray, they discovered a mass in the right,
the apex of the right lung.
It says, well, it's either neoplastic or it's something or other.
And so anyway, they did a thoracentesis.
They stick a needle through your chest.
And I had no anesthesia.
I can't take anesthesia.
So it wasn't exactly fun.
And the lung collapsed.
And I turned blue and couldn't breathe.
And they wanted to take that out surgically.
So I said, no, I don't think so.
I have my own ways of doing things.
All these illnesses recovered.
And the chest x-ray eventually became clear.
It was a formidable procedure.
As I say, the lung collapsed.
And when you have a Graves' disease, all your joints are very painful.
And they want me to put my arms up underneath this thing
that they run you through, you know.
And God, I couldn't stand the pain in my shoulders, you know.
So finally, the guy got sort of mad at me.
He said, you got to put them up there.
So I said, okay.
So there you're dying of heart disease.
And heart failure.
And what's the name of that disease?
I just said the Graves' disease.
Yeah, right.
And you've got a neoplasm in your right upper lung.
And your lung has collapsed.
And you're also in heart failure.
Other than that, you're in pretty good shape.
So anyway, as you can see, all those things disappeared.
Do the good home cooking.
Yeah, I was still single at the time, but they're real.
You can see what happens when you're single.
You get all these diseases.
Anyway, they all recovered.
Then the biopsy from the apex of the right upper lobe
said it's not neoplasm.
It's an incurable form of aviary tuberculosis, which can't be cured.
However, if you take about eight or 10
antibiotics, there's a 50% chance that you
will recover in a couple of years.
And the price was $10,000 a month.
I think it was $10,000 a month.
See if I'm remembering correctly, at the time, I had no money.
So $10,000 a month seemed like a lot.
It was $10,000 a month.
So, oh my god, it was $10,000 a month, about six or eight
exotic antibiotics.
And they would make you sick and nauseous.
So you were sick and nauseous spending $10,000 a month.
With a 50-50 chance, they're just going to cure you.
Didn't seem like too good a bet.
So I thought, whatever cured all the other ailments of the lung.
And you also have atelectasis, which
means a part of your lung has collapsed, which I probably
still have.
So anyway, you just don't pay attention to these things.
And you just keep doing the course of miracles.
And you just keep forgiving, and you just follow
your spiritual pathway.
And either they heal or they don't.
And I thought, well, if they heal, you live.
And if they don't, then you don't.
So what's the big deal?
So there were many illnesses like that.
I had a pilonidal cyst in the back of the base of the spine.
And that's surgical.
You've got to take it out.
And I picture that as disappeared.
And it disappeared.
Didn't have surgery for that either.
I had so many illnesses, I forget them all.
Oh, yeah, I'd gout.
I had all these at the same time.
Then I'd gout.
I had to keep emergency gout medicine in my pocket.
Because you could be walking down the sidewalk,
and gout is weird.
It hits you like lightning.
No warning.
Just you're feeling perfectly fine.
All of a sudden, there's an excruciating pain in your leg,
like somebody just stuck a sword right through your shin bone.
And you fall to the ground from the pain.
So I had to carry gout medicine around with me.
In the meantime, the heart was doing
all kinds of other peculiar things.
And the gastrointestinal tract was
threatening to perforate over the years.
Because the duodenal ulcer would reoccur in different places.
Then it started to burrow into the pancreas, into the back.
You see?
They said, well, I have to do a subtotal gastrectomy.
And I said, I don't think I'll have that either.
Yes, then I landed in the hospital with diverticulitis,
hemorrhagic diverticulitis.
I mean, I had to have transfusions,
three or four bottles of blood.
I mean, I really bled a lot.
So I would land in the hospital for a transfusion.
Because of hemorrhagic diverticulitis.
And how it got a chance with the ulcer,
trying to hold the main attention, I don't know.
But it would manage to do that too.
And farther down the gastrointestinal tract,
other problems arose.
So it was like a mess.
The gastrointestinal tract, the acute pancreatitis,
I had that at one time, diverticulitis,
and all these things.
You're hemorrhaging, and you're dying of all of them.
And I didn't do anything about all of them.
Any of them.
You know where I am today.
I wouldn't advise lots of people in the world
to try what I tried, but.
However, the power of spirit, and prayer, and healing,
and surrendering to God, and all these things disappeared.
And of course, a lot of other illnesses I've forgotten about.
Because there were so many of them.
Something like 27 active diseases at one time,
I remember.
And.
That's why I've forgotten half of the other ones.
Half of the rest of them.
Anyway, they all served some karmic for,
they all served some karmic, karmic benefit.
You don't have to look there.
They all served a karmic benefit, resist.
They all served a karmic benefit.
So here you think you're losing, and you're winning.
You're paying off the credit bureau every month.
You're looking, you still owe $5,000.
But you forget, you once owned $42,000.
You're down to $5,000.
So all these things heal themselves one after another.
And as I say, there's so many of them that I forget them all.
Forget them all.
So therefore, illness can serve some karmic benefit.
And of course, unconscious guilt,
according to the course of miracles,
and according to my own understanding, unconscious guilt
does play a role.
So whatever I get wrong with myself throughout the years,
I would forgive myself and repent
for having done that to others.
I'm sorry that I have caused others
to lose great quantities of blood.
And I told you about the surgery I had in the hernia.
This time, I wasn't able to go surrender faster than the pain.
With the amputation, I was lifted into a beatific state.
With the hernia repair, I was not.
Ha!
And I was counting on it.
Right in the middle of it, the pain was excruciating.
It was severe, like bad, bad, bad.
And the nurse had to grit her teeth.
She said, I never saw anything like this.
And the nurse kept me going.
She kept looking in my eyes, and her spirit
was holding my spirit's hand.
Got through surgery without anesthesia.
And I told you, in the middle of that surgery, the question was,
why God?
You know?
It didn't work like it always worked in other situations,
surrendering to the pain and thereby eliminating it.
And that's when I remembered putting the spear right
through that warrior's groin and leaving him to die.
I've told you that before.
It wasn't, see, the honor of one warrior to another.
I should have left him one bullet in his revolver.
In those days, we only had spears.
And I speared him right through the groin.
And it wasn't fatal.
And I lacked the temerity to finish him off.
And that bothered me for some, many a lifetime, I guess.
Because I had two or three hernia repairs in this lifetime.
You know, I had three of them, come to think of it.
Well, just out of that.
And right in the middle of it, I remembered my guilt that I had not
granted him the favor.
Oh.
Of allowing him to die quickly.
Because in those days, to die of a wound took weeks of agony and fever
and finally convulsing and you die.
So I undid that karmic debt.
So not healing, then.
Don't feel that it's a failure.
You can look inside yourself and say, well,
I don't know what this is compensating for.
But I surrender it to thee, O Lord, that it may serve the highest good.
So you can surrender your illnesses to serve the highest good in what
way you may not remember individually.
You may have also collectively accumulated some negative karma.
While one man stands and shoots another's,
the six who stand on the sidewalk and cheer
are joining into his karma.
You understand that?
That which you agree with, you join with.
So that which you agree with, you join with.
Resist.
That which you agree with, you join with.
So the bystander who eggs people on thinks they're a scammer.
They're escaping the karmic consequences, but they are not.
And we see that.
Because when they come back, you see whole ethnic groups wiped out,
whole sections of the country wiped out, tsunamis wiping out.
And you think all these people are innocent.
No, they all came around the planet.
They all went into agreement about such and such.
And they all now have collectively the karmic debt of undoing that agreement.
You think of the Goths and the Vikings and the Visigoths.
And all the people that used to swarm and then killed everybody, killed all the innocent,
killed the children, etc.
What is the karmic consequence of that?
I don't know.
Maybe you come back to Hiroshima or some other place.
That's what makes sense to me, anyway.
It may not be the way it is.
On the other hand, it probably is.
It is the way it is, resist.
It is the way it is, collective karma.
So we see big group phenomena, and people think, look at all those innocents.
No, they were not all innocents.
Because of karmic propensity, they just happened to be there as a part of that group to experience
out the disasters that they had visited upon others, yes?
So let's see that slide again.
So that's enough of my own sad story.
.
We want to bring up healing versus treating.
That's going to be coming up at this medical conference we'll have on October.
It's interesting, treating and healing.
What the average doctor does is treat, and what's the difference?
A doctor-doctor, a doctor-doctor calibrates probably, is practicing medicine at about
440, 445.
Excuse me.
445.
The average academically trained doctor is practicing at a consciousness level of about 440.
Now, and he usually sticks to academically approved things.
He's always looking for approval and approval of his peers and looking for scientific evidence, etc.
The healer comes from a different dimension.
Let's see. The healer would be probably 450, 460, 470, 465.
The healer is coming from 465.
Well, 440 to 465 is a big difference, big difference, because these are logarithmic numbers.
So 465 is a far more powerful healing field than that below it.
So there's the academic medical practitioner.
And then there is the healer, who is usually holistic and willing to do anything to help a patient.
And I remember having to make that decision.
Here's this patient sitting in front of me in the office, desperately ill, seeing everybody in the world and hopeless.
And I had to make a decision then.
Was I going to stick to academic medicine and gain the approval of my colleagues?
Or what?
Or was I going to try non-traditional healing techniques and lose their approval?
And I thought, on this bed, I am answerable to God for this patient, this soul lord.
He's given to me to heal.
So I made that decision.
So then I used everything that would possibly be beneficial.
Acupuncture and all kinds of health techniques and rotation diets.
And I remember, I think I told you about the patient who was sitting there, he was schizophrenic as all get out.
And he'd seen everybody in the world, came from a very rich family.
We treated it.
It was a low-cost clinic, but we treated a lot of wealthy people because they had been everywhere.
They'd fly him in from Paris or wherever, in Uganda, God knows where.
And as he's sitting there talking to me, in the back of my mind, he's hopeless schizophrenic.
All the antipsychotics have been tried.
And as he's talking on, I'm thinking to myself, not thinking to myself, but the thought comes into me, he's as mad as a hatter.
He was as mad as a hatter.
You know, in the old days, hatters would lick a brush and get mercury and get mercury poisoning and become crazy.
And old hatters were rather routinely quite crazy.
So I said, he's mad as a hatter.
Sure enough.
So I said, we'll get a hair test and test it for trace metals.
Anyway, we got it.
So he turned out to have all kinds of mercury in his brain.
And also, he was allergic to wheat, and I did rotation diets and acupuncture.
I did all the things that traditional medicine pooh-poohs is ridiculous, and he recovered.
And that was routine at that clinic.
And, of course, that's why we had such a huge clinic.
We had 2,000 outpatients and 1,000 new ones a year and a staff of 50 people.
And I had a huge library.
I had all kinds of laboratories and 50 people working for me.
So that was only the difference between treating and healing.
They'd all been in treatment, but as yet, they weren't healed.
So the intention of the healer, then, as you see by the Heisenberg principle, the intention of the healer has a profound effect.
So two doctors with the same kind of a patient and similar kinds of treatments will get two different kinds of results.
And it's true.
It's because of the energy field of the physician.
So if you're not getting well, look around.
My intention is, and I'm going to give my all, that this patient is going to recover.
By God, you're going to recover.
You're going to recover whether you like it or not.
So, you know, even after I retired and came out here, I treated lots of hopeless patients.
And they would recover.
And I've told you about a lot of them.
The guy with the oxygen tank, and he asked me to light a cigarette.
And I said, do you do that at home?
He said, yeah.
Nothing happened.
I said, okay.
So I lit a cigarette.
We didn't blow up.
No, we didn't.
He said we didn't.
So I said, okay.
Right.
So the contribution of the Heisenberg principle.
Intention is very powerful.
Now, we haven't talked about intention.
And nobody has, you know, researched this yet.
It's one, if I was 10 years younger.
I do.
Because, you know, the Heisenberg principle is to merely observe a phenomenon.
To observe an experiment already changes the result.
That's why you can't do the same experiment twice.
Because the first time, having looked at it, you've already changed it.
You can't put your foot in the same river twice.
So the Heisenberg principle, then, nobody has ever researched.
We'll find out.
We'll find out the answers ourselves without bothering with all that research and stuff.
Easy way.
What I'm holding in mind is true.
So the more powerful the level of consciousness of the witness observer,
the more powerful the effect is going to be on the outcome.
See?
So a person who is not to evolve will witness a phenomena
and bring about very little change.
Just a little change.
It's just the energy field of humanness itself.
But a person of a much higher level of consciousness
is going to have a very powerful effect.
So via the Heisenberg principle, then, the healer, from a scientific viewpoint,
would statistically have better results rather regularly
because of who they are and the power of their intention.
So a doctor who calibrates at 540 once you get well
is going to have a higher recovery rate than a doctor who calibrates at 540.
So a doctor who calibrates at 205 is really an atheist.
I guess that's the first thing I'd ask a doctor now.
Are you an atheist?
It's a free country.
I know.
You can be an atheist.
I'm not objecting.
I don't want to offend the left wing.
Anyway, no, you're perfectly fine to be an atheist.
So anyway, the power of intention, then.
You see what you hold in mind tends to manifest.
It depends.
It depends on who you are.
Some people, if they hold the thing in mind, it's going to happen.
Other people, for karmic reasons as well, it's not likely going to happen.
But I know every place I've lived in for the last 40 years or 50 years or whatever,
I merely envisioned the kind of place that I would really like to live in.
That's all I ever did.
And the next thing that I knew, it would appear out of nowhere.
Somebody would call me and say,
the house next door is for sale.
So what you hold in mind,
it's to manifest.
Therefore, if you hold in mind what you don't want,
spirit doesn't get the don't.
It just gets tumbled down brick shack, huh?
Here's his.
What you've been holding in mind.
So, therefore, you hold in mind what you do want and not what you don't want.
Okay?
That's the difference between healing and treating.
And we talked about non-healing as a benefit.
The obvious.
Obviously, the power of faith and belief to a group like this is, of course, starkly obvious.
Now, do we have one more slide on this one?
Okay.
All right.
What prevents the miraculous from happening or seemingly prevents it?
As we said, people below 200 do not experience miracles.
It's hard to believe.
People below 200 do not experience miracles.
No wonder they're skeptical.
Can't blame them.
So, that brings up lack of karmic merit.
All it takes is like Constantine did.
Constantine calibrated at 195.
And he was a great emperor on his own at 195.
But the minute he began to search for God, search for God,
and if there is a God, I ask him to help me.
And I ask for a sign.
I ask for a sign.
He instantly went up to 250 or 245, whatever it was.
So, the person who experienced the miracle looked up at the sky and saw that sign,
didn't calibrate at 190, calibrated at 250, see?
245.
So, therefore, intention can change the conditions and the likelihood.
Therefore, I think prayer is a very powerful tool.
But it's not causal.
So, again, the skeptic will say,
well, look at millions of people pray for something or other and it doesn't happen.
So, he negates the power of prayer because he's looking at it as cause and effect.
Cause and effect.
What happened to my slide?
I'll give you a dollar for the slide.
We're just talking about the blocks, yeah.
Lack of karmic merit.
It's just that you haven't paid off enough to have gotten to the place.
That it's much of a likelihood.
There's a lack of willingness to surrender secondary gain.
Oh, how we punish other people with our suffering.
Oh, look how I suffer.
Look how I suffer.
Lack of willingness to surrender secondary gain.
Look at all the advantages you get from having problems and difficulties and being sick and all.
And the secondary gain of hating people.
I mean, what could be more fun than hating people?
Every night on television you see it, there's always a crowd protesting something.
Protesting.
Exhibiting hate and anger.
Throwing rocks.
Throwing rocks at the police.
You know, provoking the police into action so you can make the police wrong.
You know, just as the policeman says,
stop, you go like this.
And he shoots you.
You're going to wait until he gets shot?
I mean, one of you is going to go.
God was trained.
So, what we do is we try.
We try to trick, trick that which is legitimate into looking at that which is illegitimate so we can have the good fun of, uh, hating them.
So, the lack of willingness to surrender the secondary gain.
The secondary gain, the most common one, is being right.
The contest in today's world is a moral one of who, who is the most moral you can watch.
Every single thing that's on television is struggling
to be moral.
To be morally superior.
To be the morally right.
Every single story is a struggle.
Who has the moral high ground?
End the struggle for moral high ground.
That's all, all it's about.
Take any story that's out in there.
And you see the struggle for the moral high ground.
Moral high ground is I'm justified in doing this, or the troops are justified in doing that.
Yeah, so the moral high ground gives you justification.
And then the justification, justification to what?
It's the what that comes up next.
So, politics is really the struggle over moral, uh, superiority.
Who is right and who has the, and who should feel guilty, etc.
Yeah.
Lack of willingness to surrender the secondary gain.
So, truth, as you can see, becomes inconsequential.
Truth is inconsequential.
It's who is holding the moral high ground.
That's it.
Who, it's not who wins.
It's who looks the goodest on television.
So, image is what it's all about.
Yeah.
Image is what it's all about.
There's so much gain.
So, the ego juice, we say the way to get off, get unhooked from anything.
We'll probably do a whole lecture on getting unhooked.
Is, uh, the willingness to let go of the gain.
First to find out what is the juice you're getting out of it.
And then ask yourself if you're willing to let go of the secondary gain.
The satisfaction, the grim satisfaction, usually of being right, of watching other
people suffer, and hitting them over the head with guilt.
So, guilt is the weapon that's used today.
It, this is the international game.
Uh, you were wrong in blowing up them, and they were wrong, we were right in blowing
up them, because they blew up us.
Now, if you run out of current events, you can go back 400 years.
Well, 400 years ago, when they invaded so-and-so.
So, when you run out of something current, history is full of it.
Blacks versus whites, women versus men, you name the political conflict in today's world.
Uh, you can always go back into history and justify it.
Uh, why we should hate somebody or not hate somebody.
And, uh, so there's no, no, uh, deficit of reasons that justify hatred and, uh, thereby guilt.
So, these resentments are then called, uh, justified.
And, of course, one of the first things we learn in a 12-step group is there are no justified resentments.
Whoa!
I'm not joining that group.
After all my mother did to me, and after, uh, my first wife did, and, uh, you know.
No, people, um, suck that guy for years and years.
I've seen people who carry, you know, resentments 60, 70 years.
80 years old, and they still got a resentment against their little sister or their mother or a neighbor.
God knows what.
Can't seem to let it go.
So, the willingness to let it go.
So, if you need a miracle, what you ask for is a miracle to see how you can surrender that.
That's causing you so much pain and disrupting the life of everybody around you.
The miracle you could ask for is then, ask the old Lord to show me how I can let go.
Being hooked on the gain I'm getting from this resentment, from this self-pity, from this fear, from this anger, from this self-hatred, etc.
So, the miracle you want is internal.
You're not trying to change the world.
I don't pray for the miracle that one side should win or the other side not win.
But you pray for the miracle that you can, that your ego is willing to surrender to God's will in the matter.
Uh-huh.
I ask the Lord.
You know.
So, then there comes like a new way of looking at it and a new way of looking at it.
And I like something it says in the fifth chapter in the AA book that people can't help being the way they are.
You know, instead of resenting them or hating them, there are people who are born that way.
They seem to be innocent.
They seem to be born that way and they don't seem to be able to do anything about it.
Isn't that a neat way of putting it?
Socrates or Jesus Christ's admonition into practice.
Jesus said, forgive them for they know not what they do.
And, of course, Christians have had a hard time applying that over the centuries.
And, therefore, I was telling them to get around that one because everybody's got a resentment that Jesus put them on the spot by saying that.
Everybody got a resentment about Jesus for that?
Oh, I always had a resentment about Jesus.
I always had a resentment about that because he made you feel guilty that you, you know, were angry or resentful about somebody.
You're supposed to be forgiving him.
How can you forgive him when he just ran over your favorite toy?
You know what I mean?
Squashed it with his bicycle.
So, I'm trying to forgive him for wrecking my toy with his bicycle because Jesus said that.
But I finally couldn't.
I still was mad at the kid.
So, now you got two problems.
One, you're mad at the kid.
Second, you feel guilty because you're mad at the kid.
That's why I used to go for religious counseling.
They called it, what did they call it?
Scrupulosity.
Alright, so you want to get over the justified resentment.
You see the juice you're willing to, that you're getting out of it.
And you try to surrender to the karma of the other person who probably is completely unable to be any different they are.
How do you know?
Because if they were able to be different than what they are, they would be.
Everybody is only what they are.
Okay, so the stunning reality that everyone is being exactly what they are.
And if they could be some other way, they would be, answers the whole problem.
They're full of hatred.
If they could be forgiving, they would be.
Obviously, they can't be.
We have all generations in parts of the world now that are being brainwashed and trained in this.
Being brainwashed and trained into hatred.
We see them on Dennis, whatchamacallit's program.
Little children getting out there and they've been indoctrinated with hate at age five or six.
He's shouting all these slogans of hate.
So, this is the justified resentment.
There is no such thing as a justified resentment.
And the resentment is only because of the way you're seeing it.
So I agree with the course of miracles.
They re-contextualize it differently.
Then you're automatically released.
You say that people cannot help being what they are at the time.
You say, well, they could be.
But that's the hypothetical.
The hypothetical is always fallacious.
It doesn't exist in reality.
Why does it count very below 200?
Because it doesn't exist in reality.
It's a fantasy that you use to project onto other people as a make wrong.
Well, they could be different than they are.
If they could be, they would be.
Does anybody see the reality of that?
If you could be, you would be.
You would automatically be that which you could be.
If you could be that, you would be that.
Everybody see that?
Yay!
People can't be different than what they are, see?
Oh, justified resentments, we let them go.
The desire to control others.
The desire to control others is a difficult one.
And I don't know if it's possible within the human domain.
To transcend it.
It's possible to do it in major areas.
But in small areas, it's almost like ubiquitous.
It's almost like inherent.
Demands animal nature.
It's almost like because of our biologic origin,
we have preferences and we have frictions with others.
Desire to control is very difficult to overcome.
I think.
Because of our biologic inheritance.
All right.
So when we trace the emergence of consciousness and life on this planet from the beginning of time,
we see that the bacteria has to get energy elsewhere.
He's not full of chlorophyll.
And he's got to have energy.
So the protozoa, the amoeba, the smallest early forms of life,
have to be able to detect what's out there so they can take it into itself
because it doesn't have chlorophyll to create energy out of sunlight.
So all biologic life has to seek and find,
has to be able to sample what's out there,
see if it's digestible, if it's good.
Without that, they would...
Life would stop because you'd fail energy.
So the mind is always searching out there.
And we call that the experiencer.
The leading edge of the ego is sampling everything around you
and savoring,
whether it's good for your survival or not.
So it's instinctual.
The desire to control is basic to the existence of life.
It's intrinsic, inborn.
You have to control it.
You've either got to eat this or spit it out.
It's either poison or it's food.
Yeah.
So the desire to control.
Then when you begin to see its forms of expression,
you can see that what you're looking for in other people
is to have your own way.
It's your own way.
So you begin to detect the narcissistic core of it,
and that you can let go of.
The desire to control in and of itself,
I don't think it's possible.
It's automatic.
Without the desire to control,
you wouldn't get too far in the highway, you know?
That's what the steering wheel and the brake are for.
Yeah.
One form a desire to control takes is, of course,
outlining.
Outlining is a technical term,
meaning telling God how you want things to happen.
I want her to get married and then have three children,
and in the meantime,
you're going to do this and the other thing.
So you're telling God,
Dear God, please let my sister-in-law
move out of this town.
You're telling God how to do it.
Yeah.
So a lot of praying to God is really manipulation,
thinking you can use divinity,
and entreaty through prayer.
Oh, Lord, please let me so.
See, you're not asking for revelation and understanding.
So Constantine was asking for revelation.
He was praying to God for some kind of a sign.
He's not saying,
Please let me win over my brother-in-law.
Please let me be the sole emperor of Rome.
He's just asking,
for some kind of a sign,
some kind of a signal,
something of a significance
to affirm his faith and his belief.
And there it manifested
and changed all of.
So he didn't tell God what to do.
He pleaded with God.
And as we've calibrated here,
those who acknowledge
the divinity of God
and devote themselves
to God,
their prayers cannot be refused.
Doesn't mean they will be answered in the way you want,
but they will be heard.
Those who turn their life over to God
are mine,
saith the Lord.
91st Psalm.
Krishna says the same thing.
Those who worship me
are mine.
That's a fact.
Those who acknowledge God
and worship God
and willing to accept God's will in all matters
belong to me,
saith the Lord.
They don't belong to me.
God says you belong to me.
Therefore,
when you're speaking to God now,
you're talking to him
as one who belongs to God.
So God's answer then
is in whatever is going to serve the highest good.
And whatever is going to serve the highest good
may not be
the way you would like it to work.
Because that is not going to serve your highest good
and it's not going to serve your
greatest long-term happiness.
Because sometimes to go down the wrong road
is the only way you can learn
not to go down that road anymore.
Overcoming negative karma
means a willingness to accept responsibility
and to face it.
So,
the habit I had over the years was
anything that happened untoward in my environment,
I took responsibility
for being
a part of the
source of that phenomenon.
And as I say,
if I
bled to death,
bled from something,
I would
pray for forgiveness
for the one in me
who cut somebody else's jugular vein.
You know,
because I'm sure
you can't have lived all these lifetimes
in the world the way it was
in barbarian days
and not have cut somebody's throat.
There ain't no way
that you could have survived very long.
You pretty much got to
hack somebody to death.
And if you're not,
then the captain behind you
will put you to death
for being a bad soldier.
So you're going to kill
whether you like it or not.
All of us then,
we may not take on,
we take on
responsibility
but not culpability.
So that's an important point.
Responsibility
vis-a-vis culpability.
You can be karmically responsible,
that means accountable.
You're accountable if you did it.
Culpability means degree of
moral responsibility,
therefore of guilt.
You can have done it,
but done it innocently.
So you have accountability,
you owe that life that you took,
but you may not have culpability.
No one will necessarily have to suffer for it.
On the other hand,
you could do a thing out of,
you might say,
wickedness,
which seems minor
and you don't have much to undo,
but you're accountable
and so you can do
and you're accountable
and you're culpable.
So culpable is degree of guilt,
you might say.
Even the courts,
that's,
even courts recognize that.
The degree,
there's no question that the person did it.
But what was his motive?
So,
not only do things happen,
but they happen in different circumstances
with different degrees of motivation.
Taking on full personal motivation,
now you're taking on full culpability.
Full culpability.
As well as accountability.
So I can see
some of the things that go on in the world
because of what the people believe.
Yeah.
They're accountable for that.
But then the way in which they do it
changes the degree of culpability.
Is it volitional?
Are they just brainwashed?
Etc.
Unwilling to,
to do negative karma then.
So when you've done the best you can
with the thing
and you still are stuck with it,
you just surrender it to God and say,
that must be coming from some place
and I accept my responsibility
to undo that for the benefit of
myself and perhaps others.
I think some people take on
other people's negative karma.
Let's see if they do it willingly.
Some people will take on
other people's negative karma.
Willingly resist.
Yes.
So,
we don't know the reason then.
Overblown emotionality and hysteria
is another problem.
It's bad enough
that you lose a body part
or your car gets crashed
or your child marries a horrible person.
But going into hysterics about it
is a whole different phenomena.
So a lot of times
when you see people praying up a storm,
what they're really doing
is reacting to the hysteria
of the event.
The hysteria of the event.
The miraculous can occur
in very profound ways.
If you watch the History Channel,
you'll see the miraculous frequently.
Almost every survivor
of giant tornadoes and hurricanes and all,
when they're being interviewed
on the Weather Channel,
will tell you that they prayed.
And an interesting one that recurs
relatively, not infrequently,
is in the middle of a hurricane,
or no, a tornado.
In the middle of a tornado,
the person is lifted high up into the air,
not in the eye of the storm.
Right in the middle of the worst of the storm.
I remember the first one that said this,
and I calibrated it at the event at 600.
In the middle of the storm,
with the whole everything being torn to pieces,
she was lifted up in the air about 40 feet
and suspended.
And suspended like in space.
Suspended by the hurricane.
And went into a state of infinite profound peace.
The same as I had in the snow bank as a kid.
Infinite state of infinite peace.
Here's the world flying around in pieces,
people dying,
and we've heard that more than once.
Yeah.
So that,
that is at 600.
Yeah.
So you'll see God,
what he said,
God's opportunity is your spirit's,
your,
your calamity is God's opportunity.
But you'll notice that you watch the weather channel,
one after another,
it says I really prayed up a storm.
Every one of them that survives,
about 90%,
well spontaneously,
they're not questioning about it,
they say I prayed up a storm.
And every once in a while,
about twice a year,
you'll see somebody suspended in the middle of the storm,
and went into a state of profound peace.
And went into a state of profound and infinite peace.
The miraculous,
right?
So you got your choice in the middle of a storm.
You can panic and,
and scream,
or you can just surrender to the whole thing
and go into a state of infinite peace.
That's option.
That option is ours.
Complete surrendering.
Yep.
Oh.
How about your signal light?
I thought you were going to turn on your signal light.
See the signal light.
Okay.
All right.
I think the miraculous,
as you can see,
is a wonderful place for research.
And people exchanging,
the reason 12 step groups
and miracles groups and all,
to do so well,
is because you like share that energy.
And what seems like a potentiality
now becomes a reality.
People all begin to exchange experiences.
And,
I am getting a signal
from one of the people
that I'm talking to right now.
And,
you know,
I don't know.
I'm getting a signal
from outer space.
Here is my space signal.
It says,
she does assembly like this.
We'll meet again at what time?
We'll meet again at 2 o'clock.
Thank you very much.
That looks just terrific.
I love that little thing.
I know,
it's like toys.
Well,
we learned another secret
of human life,
at lunch.
Women are more non-linear
than men.
Isn't that a great
teaching,
isn't it?
Yes,
yes,
yes.
discovery? Women are more non-linear than men. Understanding that will increase compatibility
between the sexes. That does explain a lot of things. A woman has more tendency to read
the field and the man has more tendency to read the content of the field. They call it
intuition. It doesn't apply to driving, though. That's the serious part of the program. Now
we'll get to the light-hearted one. I thought I'd ring up dying. Is that okay? Well, I'm
sorry. See, everybody, there's various levels of consciousness in which dying means different
things, of course. If you think you're only a physical being, you're afraid you're going
to expire, etc. But the process of dying itself, if we recontextualize it, you'll see that
nobody's really afraid of it. What you're afraid of on multiple levels, there's multiple
things you're afraid of with dying. That's a whole lecture in itself. But losing control
and all that kind of thing.
But what you're really afraid of is being alone. Now, when you think about this, you'll
see it's so. You picture yourself dying, and what's the tragedy? Everybody else is still
living. It isn't dying, it's being separated. All right. So now we're facing a possible
cataclysmic catastrophe, atomic, courtesy of the president of Iran or somebody, who
will bring in the next imam.
Our expense? The next Mahdi, the next Mahdi. The 12th imam, when he expires, will bring
in the Mahdi. And it will be apocalyptic. And he believes that as a fact. Okay. So that
means that, you know, unless you just don't watch the news at all, that there is a possibility
we may all be leaving. Who knows? Now, look at this. If we all leave together, all of
us, is there any problem? No.
If the atomic bomb just blows me out and leaves you all here, I'm going to feel poor about
it.
Now, we all stay here together, and we all, as I said in previous lectures, this group
tends to swoop in like birds. You know, they swoop in at a certain time and then they swoop
out. This whole group has swept in and out of human existence a number of times. And
if you do research, you can get the details of it. But it's not. It's not. It's not. It's
not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's
not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not. It's not.
And I think that's important. But if we all go together, there's no problem. Let's say
I give you a guarantee that at an exact moment we all leave together. Everybody got a problem?
No problem. So it isn't if you're a dying, is it? If you're leaving the familiarity,
the family of mankind, the family, and it's a family matter. So, if we all hang out together,
now we all tend to swoop in.
in and swoop out of this planet as a group. Let's see, we checked this out before. This
group tends to swoop in and swoop out at about the same time. The whole group, we all come
in and we settle here like flamingos. This group tends to sweep into karmic karma, group
karma. People say, well, Christianity doesn't believe in karma, but they do. Oh yes, they
believe. What do you need a savior for? Because you've inherited original sin. You've got
plenty of karma. Karma being human, you're born in sin, therefore you need a savior.
Isn't that so? So don't tell me you don't believe in karma or Jesus wouldn't have had
to bother. Oh yes, you have destiny that you inherit virtue by virtue of being human, period.
Yes, just for one thing, you're protoplasmic and protoplasmic has a very definite time limit
on it. That which is eternal in the spirit is different. So it's sort of a comforting
thought that we all tend to swoop in together and if we all leave in what we view as prematurely,
actually it won't be premature, it will be perfect timing, we'll probably be able to
do it.
We all go together if, you know, certain cataclysmic things happen. So there's no point to worry
about it. Is that okay? We all die together. Everybody for it? Yay! Okay, anybody want
to stay here after we all leave? Anybody want to hang in? We've all left. Isn't that a strange
thing when you reconsexualize it, you realize, I don't want to be the only one left here
without everybody here.
No. So love then, love then brings us together and the mutuality of that field of love is
what we don't want to leave, see? You don't want to be left alone on a desert island and
the steamship goes away with everybody except you. And we have all these things to accomplish
while we're here. I've been busy living through all this karma. I told you all the physical
ailments.
And I forgot, I had some money in my, I can't even remember them all. I forgot breaking
my back. That was sort of an oozes too. I told you, I lifted something and my back collapsed,
three vertebrae collapsed.
Lifting a skunk, yes. Well, yes. It was a skunk trap and I lifted the skunk trap and
I felt this shrieking pain down my back. God. And three vertebrae collapsed, yeah. Osteoporosis.
So you pick up things from the collective. I thought, well, I've never held in mind,
you know, you tend to manifest what you hold in mind. I've never pictured that men get
osteoporosis. You know, I was pictured little bent old ladies, you know. When I grew up,
there was all little bent over ladies and they all had severe osteoporosis and kyphosis.
And so I never thought it assailed men. So it wasn't something I was personally holding
in mind. So that means we're all a similar subject.
To what is being held in the collective consciousness. So instead of berating yourself for some kind
of negative experience and thinking, boy, I must have bad karma or something, it can
be something you've picked up from the collective. And that helps you bear some things. So we
can, we often pick up from the collective and experience it out for the sake of all
of us here at Resist.
When we're all together, you realize when you look into the eyes of anybody, anybody
in the group, if God said to you, would you go through some agony so that she would have
to bear less? You would say yes, wouldn't you? You would just automatically sort of
say yes. Why? Because love knows no boundaries. So for the sake of a loved one, there's no
higher love than spiritual love. Out of spiritual love, you would. You would, I agree. Yes,
I would bear that.
For that person. And because you're doing it voluntarily, it's willing. So if you allow
any kind of suffering in your life to be voluntary, you've already eliminated 90% of the suffering.
The rest is purely physical. But the suffering is really the mental anguish, isn't it? It's
the anguish. The anguish.
I drove myself up, up the road with this busted back.
Oh, God.
It was the anguish that I wasn't going to get there.
I didn't know if the body would hang in long enough
or I might pass out on 89A trying to get to the hospital.
So although the pain was severe,
it was really the anguish of your capacity to handle it
and then the situation in which you're in.
So you can look at pain and suffering and death in different ways.
It becomes recontextualized,
and now you say, can you bear the physicality for a period of time?
Yeah, you can bear the physicality.
It's the anguish that makes it seem unbearable.
So it isn't the pain, it's the anguish,
that it's going to last forever, it's never going to come to an end, etc.
When all hope is gone, that's characteristic of hell.
In the depths of hell, there is no hope.
Abandon all hope, you enter.
You enter here, and you enter agony forever.
Oh, Christ.
It's not the agony, although that is severe.
It's the forever, and you begin to experience out what eternity is.
And eternity is foreverness, and with no hope, with no hope ever.
And that's the agony of hopelessness.
So it is our hope and how we contextualize an experience,
that makes it either excruciating or bearable.
Excruciating or bearable.
The physicality can be handled.
And, of course, I've explained how to handle the physicality,
the way I handle all these things that have ailed me at various times,
was constantly not labeling it, and letting go, resisting it.
Constantly letting go, resisting it.
And as you do that, you get closer and closer to the source of the pain or the discomfort.
And you stop labeling it.
You don't call it guess.
You don't call it gastritis, or migraine, or whatever.
You just let go, resisting the sensation, whatever the sensation is.
And by constantly letting go, resisting it, you transcend it.
You overcome it.
You can bypass it.
It no longer bothers you.
So if you can let go of your fear of death, you can let go of fear of anything, huh?
How about your fear of being short?
But I got used to it.
Now, sure, I wasn't stupid.
But they wouldn't let me on the ball field, though.
The coach would never pass me, and the school doctor would never pass me for participatory sports.
All right.
Let's see.
We're doing the last 99, I think.
This is slide number 99.
That's the last one, correct?
Yes?
99?
Yes.
You were talking about the blocks.
Yeah, okay.
So that should remove the blocks, then.
And once you remove the blocks, the way is open for the miraculous.
And the miraculous really gets quite strong around level, as I say, around level 560, 570.
The miraculous becomes absolutely continuous.
All you have to do is hold the thing in mind.
And it might...
You're driving down the road in the old truck, and I think the water pump was falling off.
I had it wired on.
I don't know why it fell off.
Anyway.
So to correct it, I needed a pair of pliers.
Well, you wouldn't believe in that whole truck with all the crap I had in there.
I could not find a pair of pliers.
So I said to the guy who was with me, I said, all we need is a pair of pliers.
And 20 foot ahead of us on the right-hand side of the highway,
was a pair of pliers.
Now I wore the pair of pliers.
They were brand new, never used pair of pliers.
That kind of thing was just continuous.
Just when you run out of water, you pull up next to something,
and you see that there's a pump handle behind it.
And it's just miraculous.
Your car breaks down a million miles from nowhere.
And that happened to me a number of times.
And the old truck would break down in strange places.
Nobody knew I was even there.
And some old pal from years ago would suddenly drive out of nowhere and come up and say,
hey, you've broken down here.
You need help?
Yep.
I don't know if I told you one time I was down near the Mexican border.
And when I first came out, I drove all over the place with my truck,
getting used to the wild, wild west, you know?
Down near the Mexican border.
And it was super hot.
And there's nothing in any direction.
You know?
If you get down just north of the Mexican border, near Patagonia, yeah, right.
There's places where, you know, for 50 miles, there's nothing.
And so I pulled the truck in someplace, and it died.
And smoke shot out.
It was smoke.
It was a fire under the hood.
Here's the fire under the hood on a million miles from nowhere.
And the smoke is going up.
The whole cab is full of smoke.
And it's hopeless.
You wouldn't be able to walk.
I mean, you wouldn't get more than a quarter of a mile in that heat with no water.
And so I thought, well, you're leaving now.
So I sat back and waited to leave.
You got to die sometimes.
So why not now?
So I'm sitting there waiting to leave.
It's okay with me to go.
Every time I've been okay to go, it never happens.
What I should do is resist it.
Now I'm not going.
I would sit back and say,
Well, if you go, so you go.
You're not going to be able to walk for water.
And the machine's on fire.
So what can you do?
Then a little voice inside my head,
didn't come from elsewhere.
It was from within.
It said, it had a paper cup with about this much coffee in the bottom.
It said, take this paper cup.
Now, in the bottom of the glove compartment,
it's made of heavy-duty cardboard.
It says, take a screwdriver,
and jam it through there.
So I took a screwdriver,
and I jammed it through the cardboard in the bottom of the glove compartment.
And then the knowingness, it wasn't a voice, it was a knowingness.
The knowingness was to pour that through the hole, which I did.
And it went like that.
And that was the electrical fire.
And the hole was exactly over in the electrical apparatus in my old truck,
which is still very bad.
Many years of amateur electrical wiring is a rat's nest.
But you'd never find in there, using the intellect or your brain,
where the fire was coming from.
But there it was exact.
So I was a little disappointed.
I thought I was out of here.
But that put the fire out.
And so I didn't leave then.
Any time I was ready to leave, something similar would happen.
And I said, I've had it happen right in the middle of a lecture, walking down the aisle.
And it's like invitation.
Level 600.
From 600 up, it recurs.
And it's like invitational.
It's like a very open, welcome door.
And you have an okay.
You've got permission to walk through.
You never know what's going to happen.
And so if the body walks on, I guess that was the karmic momentum to do so.
And fulfill your obligation to Doug, to God, that he gave you certain information.
And it's like invitation.
And it's your obligation to teach others with what you have learned.
So you accept that that is to go on and that it's not finished yet.
So that's what keeps you going.
It's because you're fulfilling some karmic propensity and even an agreement.
I remember agreement beforehand, in fact, that you're filling a certain contract and obligation
to a group of spirits.
You might say a group of souls.
Like we all have a certain commitment to each other.
So everybody ready to die any old time?
Are we ready to go together?
Well, give it the old gung-ho.
It's time to go, man.
We're just going to hold everybody else in mind and give it the old college cheer.
Boom, off we go.
Fracture of life.
Trumpets sounding on the other side.
. . .
Here comes that wonderful group from Sedona.
They hang festoons up.
Oh, they're back, they're back, they're back.
Happy times are here again.
. . .
Well, inevitably they get tired of the long faces, you know.
They get tired of the sackcloth and ashes type, you know.
. . .
Something to break up the monotony.
Oh, sin and guilt and sackcloth and ashes crowd.
. . .
You see, sin and guilt and self-recrimination and penance and all that is at the bottom of the chart.
And joy and happiness is at the top of the chart.
Seeking God as you wallow around in guilt.
Uh, so guilt, as Buddhism says, is self-indulgent.
Guilt is a self-indulgence.
And so, instead of feeling good about thrashing your self.
. . .
feeling guilt. Shame on you for feeling guilty. So that's guilt. A block to the miraculous.
Desire to control, we said, has underpinnings. Death itself is probably the most fearsome
of all fears. When you surrender your fear of death, nothing will really frighten you
after that. The worst that can happen is just so you go, so, so you go, so. And that's the
attitude that comes up. Once you surrender your fear, so all the negative fears that
we have boil down unconsciously to death in one form or another. If you don't live up
to certain standards, etc. Disapproval, all these things that would make you, they would
throw you off.
Throw you out of the pack. Yeah, throw you out of the pack. So the blocks then are the
desire to control, to resist it. Outlining, we already covered. That's telling God what
you want and why you want it. Advice to God. Advice to God. Sometimes he grants it, he
feels sorry for you. Throw him a few crumbs because he's going to give up if you don't.
All right. Unwillingness to undo the negative karma. All right. As we said, Christianity
doesn't believe in karma per se as a, as a, as a concept, as a concept. It does believe
in collective human karma, obviously. Adam and Eve and the Garden of Eden and the apple
and the whole story. It's our karmic inheritance. Seeking short-term goals versus long-term
benefits. Serving the self for the small S instead of the self for the large S. There's
not, it's not always possible.
To see what is of the long, most long-term benefit for the self. We say that the relief
of suffering is what the ego wants for now, but we don't know that that serves the highest
good. So whenever we use kinesiology, we always say in the name of the highest good. Is it
okay to mention this in the name of the highest good? So that is the self with a capital S.
Clinging to the truth we've already described is the basic problem of the self. It's the
problem of the ego. And overblown emotionality is, of course, today's society in which everything
is juiced for its sensationalism. And the media have really brought down the level of
consciousness. Mm-hmm. Participated. The level of consciousness of America right now
is over 426, 427, 426. All right. Mankind is currently over 205.
206. The Mankind, remember, was 207. Yeah. And America was up five more points. So the
collective impact of negativity, the sensationalism of the media, the whole philosophic concept
of relativism, and Islamic terrorism because it creates fear and anger. You see? So collectively
the energy fear.
Yes.
And the feeling of the mankind is currently down. In fact, you know, here in Sedona, we're
probably holding it up.
Wasn't for this group it would collapse. I'll take it. Now, but this group alone has
a very powerful effect. See? Because we get familiar with each other. We don't realize
the role we're playing. This group, we have permission to ask about it. This group plays
a significant role in the system.
Yeah.
upholding the consciousness level of America resists. This group, here, now, because of
the enormous power of spiritual intention, is only helping to hold up. She's catatonic.
Thank you, sweetheart. You know, we couldn't do the work without her because, yeah, 20
times a day I interrupt whatever she's doing, and she looks at me, okay. I had to get Constantine
before the year 312, and Constantine after 312, and so all those myriad things. Without
kinesiology, you realize how much information is shut off from the rest of the world. People
under 200 can't do it, and those above have to be motivated, and, you know, you have to
have at least a minimal amount of skill.
Yeah, and the difficulty is trying to remain objective, not having a stake in the answer,
and you can find ways in which to remain as objective as possible, and I think asking
in the name of the highest good is the best, and sometimes you'll get a no, but anyway.
It's very serviceable. I mean, how else can you make a diagnosis and design a treatment
for a hopeless condition?
Well, I was diagnosed with a condition in less than a minute flat for no money at all.
Just about everything I had wrong with me, I got the wrong diagnosis. I did. Wrong diagnosis.
He said, I forgot all these illnesses. There were so many of them. Anyway, there was terrible
prosthetic problems. All older men are supposed to have prostate problems, and therefore to
go along with being an older man, you have it. And so I see this guy, G.U. man, and I
went to see him, and he says, oh God, you're going to have to remove it, and fluoroscopy
and all this. He decided, you know, we've got to remove it, and you have to go for surgery.
So I said, well, okay, I'll call you. I always get a second opinion.
So I went to see another G.U. man, and I sat down, and he was chief of G.U. at the Cottonwood
Hospital, now retired. Anyway, I sat down, and I told him, I said, I don't know, I just
can't go, and I don't want to go anymore. He says, are you taking anything for your
nose, like Sudafed? I said, yeah. He said, well, stop that, and it'll cure it. I stopped
the Sudafed, and it cured it. I always get a second opinion. The doctor that told me
to go home, you're going to die of right-sided heart failure was wrong. It was thyroid. The
guy who said, you're going to die of right-sided heart failure, he said, you're going to die
of aviary tuberculosis. It's not curable. It's gone. The person who said he had a tumor
in the apex of the right lung, it's gone. The person who says, you know, you've got
atelectasis, it's gone. Pancreatitis is gone. Recurrent duodenal ulcers are gone. I told
you the duodenal ulcer story, intractable, perforating through the, and that would get
it re-X-rayed, and there'd be a new ulcer in a new place. But that was excruciating.
It's burrowing in the back of the duodenum.
I thought I was going to die, and I thought I was going to die. And I thought I was going
to die, and I thought I was going to die. But it's still going to die. You know, I
can't remember.
So, I went to the hospital. I went to the doctor, and I saw a medical doctor. A doctor
from the clinic in Washington, D.C. He came into the pancreas, and gave me acute pancreatitis.
So, I heard about acupuncture. Is it something else? Traditional medicine, poo-poos. All
the things that cure me are all things that medicine poo-poos. Hypoglycemia, acupuncture,
all these things. So, anyway, I heard that there was a Chinese coming from China, and
they were going to have the first acupuncture clinic in America, in Washington D.C. So,
So I went there, you had to get permission and you had to have medical records with you
and they took x-rays beforehand.
And I saw the acupuncturist.
Have I told you this story before?
No?
All right.
So he didn't speak any English, he had a translator.
It was the first acupuncture clinic in America, it was in DC and it was under federal study.
And so you had to have all the documentation.
So I brought all my x-rays of all the ulcers and all that.
So anyway, I laid down and he took all these pins in you and they had moxie combustion,
you smell like you're smoking, you know, something illegal, these little puffs of smoke and these
needles are all over the place.
And then he went, he put one right through here, I'll never forget that.
I thought acupuncture was painless.
Well, he put a needle through here and it came out the back and I screamed and jumped
off the table.
So he says, ho, ho, ho, bad ulcer, huh?
Yeah.
Ho, ho.
Ho, ho, bad ulcer.
Ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho, ho.
And from the third treatment, it was healed.
In three treatments, I'd had it for over 25 years, lived on antacids and antispasmodics,
lived on them.
Couldn't drink coffee.
Look at me, I drink espresso all day around the clock.
Would have killed me.
And three acupuncture treatments and it was healed.
And anxiety attacks and depression attacks.
It was healed by stopping eating sugar and sweets.
Functional hypoglycemia.
You eat sugar, it goes way up, releases insulin, your sugar drops way down.
Then you get the shakes, you get angry, you get depressed.
So, Saturday night, I used to always have a double chocolate sundae.
Every Sunday, I would get depressed.
I spent at least a year or two before I discovered what it was.
Every Sunday, depressed, feeling horrible.
And the minute I stopped eating that, it was gone.
I stopped eating that double hot-faced chocolate sundaes and the depression disappeared.
The same with anxiety attacks.
So, these are some of the things I'm going to be talking about later in the year because
they're having a meeting here at Restorative Medicine and we're going to recall some of these things.
But what I really mean to say is I always get a second opinion.
Look at all the alternate methods that people have used.
They've used the Course in Miracles.
I know people in the Course in Miracles that have recovered from just about every disease known to mankind.
Use the 12-step formula.
Use the 12-step programs.
Use Stop Eating Sugar and Sweets if you're depressed and anxious.
Anybody here depressed or anxious at times?
Do you ever try Stop Eating Sugar and Sweets?
All right.
That's the first thing to try.
How about a second opinion?
Well, you're talking to a double hot-faced sundae man right here.
That's what I'm going to do when they say,
Doc, you've only got a couple of days left to live.
Bring on the double hot-faced chocolate sundae.
You'll leave the world with a happy smile on your face.
Full of hot fudge.
Functional hypoglycemia.
We're going to have to quit because we're going to do a longer question and answer period.
But I had a good friend who weighed 400 pounds and came from a well, a great family.
And I met him through some exclusive channels.
And anyway, he had a terrible problem abusing his wife, alcohol and abuse.
And so I, and he would try AA and he would get drunk.
So I told him, I said, you've got functional hypoglycemia.
And if you stop eating sugar and sweets, you'll be cured.
Well, he hated the idea, but he tried it.
By God, he got sober.
He stopped beating up his wife.
He did very fine.
But he didn't like being off sugar and sweets because he was a sugar freak, you know.
And you could tell.
I would watch him at a dining room table.
The way he would look at the dessert, you just got the energy of it, like rapacious.
I mean, ooh.
So anyway, he went to see a well-known medical doctor who was, I think at the time, head of the National Alcoholism Association.
And she told him, poo-poo, hypoglycemia is not medically proven.
And so he said, great.
Started eating sugar and sweets.
Soon got drunk.
Soon assaulted his wife.
And soon died.
So, yes, dead.
Dead, drunk, abusive, and dead.
All from poo-pooing.
So alternative medicine can be of enormous value.
I had acupuncture for the fractured three vertebrae.
And I had acupuncture for the ulcer.
It cured both things.
It won't cure everything.
I tried it for migraine headache, and it didn't work.
I was disappointed.
But then along, having good karma, I lived in an age where Imitrex got invented.
And I discovered Imitrex, and that cured the headache.
But before that, nothing cured the headache.
Nothing.
Not even codeine.
Nothing cured migraine headaches.
And sometimes every day for three months, one time for three months, every single day I had migraine headache.
So those are just the karmic things that we inherit by virtue of being human.
Plus what we've picked up over previous lifetimes.
Plus whatever voluntary kinds of spiritual work we have offered to do for others and may well have forgotten about.
And then we have our responsibility and our commitment to our group.
Often unstated.
Or else, if stated, you have to sign a vow and sign a paper or something.
But here it's strictly voluntary.
We come together because we have an enormously strong bond.
We have an enormously powerful spiritual energy, as you see.
We are helping lift the consciousness level of America itself.
So I thought we'll take a break and we'll give a little longer to question and answer period.
Anything I haven't covered, I tried to cover some general areas that we have sort of slided over in the past.
And so that we could conclude them.
Yes?
So we'll take a how long break?
Ten minutes?
Ten to fifteen minutes.
Okay.
Fifteen?
And then we'll do questions and answers and we'll have a little more time for them.
When we finish all those slides, we have 99 slides.
So that was number 99, huh?
99.
Okay.
The next slide we do will be number 100.
Hi, Don.
This is for you.
Oh.
Not in your coffee.
Thank you so much.
Want me to sign it?
Yes.
Well, thank you.
He needs to open it though.
How you doing?
Good.
December 06.
Yes.
We've been doing this for six years.
Is that right?
Yes.
Wowzy.
The first one was in, I think, early December.
We were in Prescott Valley.
That's right.
And you had over 500 people show up that got you an idea.
That maybe these things might help people.
And I'm really grateful for the six years of being able to come and learn and be in
your presence.
And, you know, it's been a pleasure.
Thank you.
That's what I find great about unity church, is the certificates.
I think at a great level, I think, many also wait and say, ooh, am I not a serious
man.
In other words, you're a great man.
And the whole crowd took a hush.
Whoa.
I thought, this is really good stuff.
Yeah, he was the bad guy of the era, wasn't he?
Timothy McVeigh.
And the mad bomber, too.
Yes, the mad bomber, yes.
He was in there.
But I missed the October seminar, and that's when my question comes in.
I got to be with some Hopi elders and some Cherokee elders.
Some what?
Some Hopi and Cherokee elders.
Oh, yes, okay.
Doing some ceremony.
That's a miracle I forgot to mention.
Okay, go ahead.
A little bit closer, okay.
And the Hopi had been on the mesas for thousands of years doing ceremony.
And we're coming into a time period here in 207 that they say is a very important time.
And I hate.
I hate predictions of time periods and things like that.
We may all be saying goodbye here.
Oh, no, no, this is positive.
That's why I was meant by something positive.
So my gift to you today is some medicine from that gathering.
And they were talking about how the Karmapa will be coming in 207 to coming to Arizona.
And I know you had spent some time studying with the Karmapa, I think, when he came through Arizona.
Oh, that's true.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And my question is, it seems like you were talking today about the synergies and the blocks that we need to all work on in letting go.
And in this preparation, I think everyone right now seems to be, we're going through a time period that's calling for us all to what we call an AA,
right?
Right.
On a deeper level of step four, surrender.
And the surrender I'm going through right now is maybe moving up to a small mountain town up near Strawberry.
And would you have any advice?
Yes, good idea.
Thank you.
He's far away from a major metropolitan area.
He's also smart.
But it reminded me of miracles.
And miracles, I forgot to mention one today.
I went to the...
Okay.
I'm sorry.
I forgot to mention one today.
It was a big one.
It rained snake-eyed snow.
And it was the last one that I think they allowed white men, because white men were drunk and disorderly.
Anyway, when we went, it was up in Old O'Reilly.
Wait a minute till I finish.
It was up in Old O'Reilly.
It hadn't rained in, I forget, four months, six months or something.
Old O'Reilly is up on the top, and then there's a cliff that drops off, and the crops grow down below.
And I had some corn that I was given by a white bear,
and I planted it Hopi style, you know, six inches down.
And so anyway, I went up for the snake dance,
and they said there were hardly any white men there.
And everybody was sitting on the top of these hogans.
And as they assembled, the, what do you call it, dancers started.
The first ones, the...
Hopi dancers?
Kachinas?
Huh?
The kachina dancers?
No, no, the antelope dancers, antelope dancers came out.
And then the old, the best seats there, it was crowded.
The best seats were saved for the elders.
And as the antelope dancers began to dance,
the elders came out with umbrellas.
It hadn't rained in four to six months.
And the Hopi, the elders came out
with umbrellas.
And I thought, umbrellas?
It hasn't rained in six months.
And as the antelope dancers danced, the clouds began to collect.
And by the time the snake dancers came out, it was raining.
Raining just on Old Aravi.
From the cliff, the town is here,
and then the cliff, and then the crops are way down low.
So help me God, the rain was raining on the crops.
And not on the town of Old Aravi.
And that was the miraculous.
That was the miraculous.
So they know how to somehow work the synergy of nature
and manifest that by collective intention in the faith.
The old ones coming out with the umbrellas,
and it hadn't rained in six months,
and it looked ridiculous.
And then the rain began to fall.
So I witnessed it and experienced it.
And they let go of the snake.
And the snake ran.
It ran over to me.
And then went right by.
And nobody was afraid of the snakes at all.
It was a wonderful experience.
I've learned from the Native Americans, too.
Thank you, Doc.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Doc, I would like to thank you and Susan
for being my teachers for the last three years.
I'm very grateful.
Well, the question I have is,
I've worked.
After reading Power Versus Force,
I started a serious AA 12-step program.
And I've worked real hard on it.
And my question is,
do I move forward into A Course in Miracles?
Is this something that would enhance my...
You're in a 12-step program now?
Yes.
All right.
And you want to follow it up with A Course in Miracles?
I was wondering,
if this is...
It's very often done.
A lot of people in either group
tend to co-mingle with those in the other group.
It won't mess up my AA program to do it.
No.
It won't mess up your AA.
Okay.
So...
AA calibrates at 540.
The workbook of A Course in Miracles calibrates at 600.
So it isn't that big a jump.
Okay.
It's pretty easy to take the third step
on everything as it occurs.
Right.
Everything as it occurs,
it takes...
You take the third step on it.
So a follow-up in this is something that...
It would just enhance...
You don't need it,
but if you do the third and the 11th step,
you don't really need anything beyond that.
Okay.
But maybe as a consequence of doing the third and the 11th,
you're led to do the A Course in Miracles.
Okay.
Yeah.
Thank you very much.
And I have one little small other question.
In one of the previous lectures,
you had mentioned that the number of...
lifetimes that people have reincarnated is around six.
Did I misunderstand that?
Well, we were asking the average.
We have permission to ask the average.
The average person...
Well, this is an exceptional group.
Let's say the average human
has already had about six lifetimes.
That's what it says.
And this group?
Would you have an average?
This group, I don't know.
It's probably...
Okay.
This group may have had...
We've had many more.
Yeah.
This group...
Thank you very much.
Merry Christmas.
Thank you.
So we've been hanging around a while.
Oh, boy.
Thank you very much.
I want to ask you for your blessing.
You don't have to ask.
I'm honored by your presence.
Thank you.
The calibration of your life when you're born
is set at birth?
Yes.
And also the time of your death is set?
Well, that's what we get.
Okay.
All right.
Is that time as in relative to time itself
or is it relative to karmic,
what you have done in that lifetime?
Let's ask over again.
We have permission to ask this.
You already have a level of consciousness
at the time of birth through this.
So without previous lifetimes,
how would you...
How would you have acquired it?
Do you understand what I'm saying?
And the time...
No, it wouldn't be...
The time of your leaving
is sequential time,
not clock time or just...
So it would be like after having fulfilled
this and that and the other thing,
now you can leave.
Okay.
Thank you.
Merry Christmas.
I'll get busy suffering.
Yes.
No, wait.
Wait, he's still signing.
Okay.
So when you fulfill...
Okay, so when you have fulfilled
certain karmic tasks or obligations,
then you're free to go.
Okay, so I see.
Good question.
Yeah.
So if you struggle and resist,
you get to stay longer, right?
Yeah.
Now I ain't forgiving that guy.
Merry Christmas.
Thank you.
Why do you keep getting all these books?
Oh, Gabe keeps giving them to me.
Oh, he graces me a lot.
Sure, you bet.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
About 15 years ago,
in the summer of 1991,
my wife and I went to Charts in France.
Charts Cathedral.
Oh, yes.
We had the great opportunity to walk the circle.
Oh, great.
Without a cell phone.
Yeah.
Hey, the chairs were pulled up when you were there.
They were bowed up.
They put the chairs there
every time we've been there,
so you can't walk it.
It's a little bit different now,
and I had picked up a poster
that I wanted to present to you and Susan
for Christmas back then.
Merry Christmas.
Oh, thank you so much.
Isn't that gorgeous?
I can see what it is.
Yeah.
Oh, beautiful.
That's the...
That's one of the windows.
The windows.
The windows inside.
This is one of the windows.
My favorite cathedral.
Sure, it is my favorite cathedral.
I thought maybe if you would put it inside your home somewhere,
it'd be great,
and if not,
in your pickup truck where your shotgun goes,
you could hang it on that rack there.
But I did have a question for you, sir.
Yeah.
Relating to the Course of Miracles,
when you took the Course of Miracles,
what was the biggest blockage that you had
in absorbing the information at the time?
I didn't have any.
I was just...
I was just enthused about it.
And sometimes the phraseology,
I would have to think out the phraseology,
but the basic concept was already experiential, you see?
You see things differently.
If you see people as innocent,
then you don't have to worry about hating them
or being angry or revenge,
because you see they can't help being anything
other than what they are at this point in their evolution.
Huh?
I don't have any resistance to anything in it.
Wanted to thank you for everything you've done
for the last four years for us.
It's been wonderful.
Thank you.
Can we take a picture?
You can take a picture.
It's a dollar.
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no dollar, no.
I shouldn't say that as a joke.
Actually, it's five.
Anyway.
Yeah.
Merry Christmas.
Thank you.
Najas.
Following you.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Merry Christmas.
Thank you very much.
It was similar going here.