So
Yeah.
>> I
>> I just
>> I just wanted
>> I just wanted to
>> I just wanted to say
>> I just wanted to say that
>> I just wanted to say that I'm
>> I just wanted to say that I'm very
honored
honored to
>> I just wanted to say that I'm very
honored to be
honored to be here.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. and
>> Yes. and I
>> Yes. and I waited
>> Yes. and I waited all
>> Yes. and I waited all year
>> Yes. and I waited all year to
>> Yes. and I waited all year to come
>> Yes. and I waited all year to come here.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, I
>> Yes. and I waited all year to come here.
>> Yes, I know
>> Yes, I know we
>> Yes. and I waited all year to come here.
>> Yes, I know we had
>> Yes, I know we had this
>> Yes. and I waited all year to come here.
>> Yes, I know we had this just
>> Yes, I know we had this just for
>> Yes. and I waited all year to come here.
>> Yes, I know we had this just for people
that
that couldn't
that couldn't get
that couldn't get into
that couldn't get into the
that couldn't get into the lectures.
>> Um,
>> Um, other
that couldn't get into the lectures.
>> Um, other than
>> Um, other than uh
that couldn't get into the lectures.
>> Um, other than uh hopefully
>> Um, other than uh hopefully raising
that couldn't get into the lectures.
>> Um, other than uh hopefully raising the
level
level of
level of my
level of my awareness
level of my awareness by
level of my awareness by being
level of my awareness by being here,
level of my awareness by being here, my
question
question is
level of my awareness by being here, my
question is on
question is on behalf
level of my awareness by being here, my
question is on behalf of
question is on behalf of my
level of my awareness by being here, my
question is on behalf of my son.
question is on behalf of my son. I
level of my awareness by being here, my
question is on behalf of my son. I have
a
a son
a son that's
a son that's 12
a son that's 12 years
a son that's 12 years old
a son that's 12 years old and
a son that's 12 years old and ever
a son that's 12 years old and ever since
he
he was
a son that's 12 years old and ever since
he was three,
he was three, um
a son that's 12 years old and ever since
he was three, um he's
he was three, um he's been
a son that's 12 years old and ever since
he was three, um he's been talking
he was three, um he's been talking to
what
what he
what he believes
what he believes to
what he believes to be
what he believes to be those
what he believes to be those who
what he believes to be those who are
deceased.
deceased. And
what he believes to be those who are
deceased. And I
deceased. And I remember
what he believes to be those who are
deceased. And I remember reading
uh
uh in
uh in your
uh in your work
uh in your work that
uh in your work that there
uh in your work that there are
uh in your work that there are no
ghosts,
ghosts, there
uh in your work that there are no
ghosts, there are
ghosts, there are no
uh in your work that there are no
ghosts, there are no hauntings.
ghosts, there are no hauntings. And
uh in your work that there are no
ghosts, there are no hauntings. And I
was
was wondering
was wondering in
was wondering in in
was wondering in in a
was wondering in in a better
was wondering in in a better way
was wondering in in a better way to
was wondering in in a better way to deal
with
with him
was wondering in in a better way to deal
with him and
with him and understanding
was wondering in in a better way to deal
with him and understanding what
with him and understanding what he's
seeing.
seeing. I
seeing. I don't
seeing. I don't want
seeing. I don't want to
seeing. I don't want to discredit
seeing. I don't want to discredit him.
I'm
I'm just
seeing. I don't want to discredit him.
I'm just not
I'm just not exactly
seeing. I don't want to discredit him.
I'm just not exactly sure
I'm just not exactly sure what
seeing. I don't want to discredit him.
I'm just not exactly sure what it
I'm just not exactly sure what it is.
seeing. I don't want to discredit him.
I'm just not exactly sure what it is. Do
people
people actually
people actually have
people actually have gifts
people actually have gifts of
people actually have gifts of seeing
those?
>> He
>> He sees
>> He sees people.
>> Yes.
>> He
>> He sees
>> He sees them
>> different
>> different ones
>> He sees them
>> different ones from
>> different ones from time
>> He sees them
>> different ones from time to
>> other
>> other dimensions.
>> He
>> He says
>> other dimensions.
>> He says he
>> He says he sees
>> other dimensions.
>> He says he sees them
>> He says he sees them like
>> other dimensions.
>> He says he sees them like you
>> He says he sees them like you and
>> other dimensions.
>> He says he sees them like you and I
>> He says he sees them like you and I are
sitting
sitting here
>> and
>> and sometimes
sitting here
>> and sometimes they
>> and sometimes they scare
sitting here
>> and sometimes they scare him
>> and sometimes they scare him and
sometimes
sometimes he
sometimes he feels
>> the
>> the astral
sometimes he feels
>> the astral domain.
>> the astral domain. Yeah.
sometimes he feels
>> the astral domain. Yeah. Okay.
>> And
>> And I
>> And I that's
>> And I that's what
>> And I that's what I
>> And I that's what I was
>> And I that's what I was wondering.
>> It's
>> It's probably
>> And I that's what I was wondering.
>> It's probably some
>> It's probably some kind
>> And I that's what I was wondering.
>> It's probably some kind of
>> It's probably some kind of a
>> And I that's what I was wondering.
>> It's probably some kind of a special
gift
gift or
gift or something
gift or something that
gift or something that would
gift or something that would take
individual
individual research
gift or something that would take
individual research to
individual research to see
gift or something that would take
individual research to see what
individual research to see what it
means.
means. In
means. In this
means. In this particular
means. In this particular case,
means. In this particular case, it's
means. In this particular case, it's a
natural
natural spontaneous
means. In this particular case, it's a
natural spontaneous phenomena.
Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> All
>> All right.
>> All right. So,
>> All right. So, he's
>> All right. So, he's probably
experiencing
entities
entities on
entities on the
entities on the other
entities on the other side
entities on the other side that
entities on the other side that could
give
give him
entities on the other side that could
give him an
give him an explanation.
>> I
>> I never
>> I never wanted
>> I never wanted to
>> I never wanted to discredit
>> I never wanted to discredit him.
>> I never wanted to discredit him. I
>> I never wanted to discredit him. I just
didn't
didn't understand
>> I never wanted to discredit him. I just
didn't understand completely
didn't understand completely how
>> I never wanted to discredit him. I just
didn't understand completely how to
didn't understand completely how to to
help
help him
help him with
help him with that.
>> Well,
>> Well, why
help him with that.
>> Well, why do
>> Well, why do you
help him with that.
>> Well, why do you say
>> Well, why do you say he
help him with that.
>> Well, why do you say he needs
>> Well, why do you say he needs help?
>> Okay.
>> Okay. He
>> Okay. He doesn't.
>> Why
>> Why don't
>> Okay. He doesn't.
>> Why don't you
>> Why don't you look
>> Okay. He doesn't.
>> Why don't you look at
>> Why don't you look at as
>> Okay. He doesn't.
>> Why don't you look at as a
>> Why don't you look at as a gift?
>> Okay. He doesn't.
>> Why don't you look at as a gift? Maybe.
>> Yeah.
>> I
>> I wanted
>> Yeah.
>> I wanted to
>> I wanted to make
>> Yeah.
>> I wanted to make sure
>> I wanted to make sure it
>> Yeah.
>> I wanted to make sure it was
>> I wanted to make sure it was a
>> Yeah.
>> I wanted to make sure it was a positive
and
and nothing
and nothing was
and nothing was negative.
>> I don't
>> I don't know.
and nothing was negative.
>> I don't know. It
>> I don't know. It would
and nothing was negative.
>> I don't know. It would take
>> I don't know. It would take some
individual
individual research.
individual research. It's
individual research. It's sort
individual research. It's sort of
individual research. It's sort of an
unusual
unusual occurrence.
>> Mhm.
>> And
>> And uh
>> Mhm.
>> And uh we
>> And uh we have
>> Mhm.
>> And uh we have to
>> And uh we have to see
>> Mhm.
>> And uh we have to see what
>> And uh we have to see what it
>> Mhm.
>> And uh we have to see what it means.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> If
>> If it's
>> If it's spontaneous,
>> If it's spontaneous, I
>> If it's spontaneous, I wouldn't
>> If it's spontaneous, I wouldn't worry
about
about it.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, it's
>> Thank you.
>> Yes, it's spontaneous.
>> Yes, it's spontaneous. Yeah.
>> It's
>> It's not
>> It's not an
>> It's not an induced
>> It's not an induced state.
>> So,
>> So, it's
>> It's not an induced state.
>> So, it's natural
>> So, it's natural for
>> It's not an induced state.
>> So, it's natural for some
>> So, it's natural for some reason.
>> Yes.
>> That
>> That would
>> Yes.
>> That would very
>> That would very make
>> Yes.
>> That would very make a
>> That would very make a very
>> Yes.
>> That would very make a very interesting
case
case for
case for research
case for research karmically.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Okay.
case for research karmically.
>> Okay. Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you.
case for research karmically.
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you. Is
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you. Is it
case for research karmically.
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you. Is it a
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you. Is it a gift?
case for research karmically.
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you. Is it a gift? Is
he
he to
he to use
he to use it
he to use it for
he to use it for others
he to use it for others or
he to use it for others or what?
he to use it for others or what? You
know,
>> yes.
>> No,
>> No, don't
>> yes.
>> No, don't worry
>> No, don't worry about
>> yes.
>> No, don't worry about it.
>> No, don't worry about it. I
>> yes.
>> No, don't worry about it. I can
>> No, don't worry about it. I can only
move
move as
move as fast
move as fast as
move as fast as I
move as fast as I can
move as fast as I can move.
>> Good
>> Good afternoon.
move as fast as I can move.
>> Good afternoon. You've
>> Good afternoon. You've already
move as fast as I can move.
>> Good afternoon. You've already signed
>> Good afternoon. You've already signed my
book.
book. Thank
book. Thank you
book. Thank you for
book. Thank you for the
book. Thank you for the difference
you're
you're making
book. Thank you for the difference
you're making in
you're making in my
book. Thank you for the difference
you're making in my life.
you're making in my life. And
book. Thank you for the difference
you're making in my life. And my
question
question is,
question is, could
question is, could you
question is, could you please
question is, could you please show
question is, could you please show me
how
how to
question is, could you please show me
how to do
how to do muscle
question is, could you please show me
how to do muscle testing
how to do muscle testing with
question is, could you please show me
how to do muscle testing with another
person?
>> She
>> She and
person?
>> She and I
>> She and I did
person?
>> She and I did it
>> She and I did it for
person?
>> She and I did it for you
>> She and I did it for you this
person?
>> She and I did it for you this morning,
>> but
>> but I
>> but I wasn't
>> but I wasn't sure
>> but I wasn't sure how
>> but I wasn't sure how hard
>> but I wasn't sure how hard you
>> but I wasn't sure how hard you pressed.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, here
>> but I wasn't sure how hard you pressed.
>> Oh, here we'll
>> Oh, here we'll do
>> but I wasn't sure how hard you pressed.
>> Oh, here we'll do it
>> Oh, here we'll do it again
>> but I wasn't sure how hard you pressed.
>> Oh, here we'll do it again right
>> Oh, here we'll do it again right now.
>> If
>> If you
>> If you could
>> I
>> I used
>> If you could
>> I used two
>> I used two fingers.
>> Two
>> Two fingers.
>> I
>> I press
>> Two fingers.
>> I press down
>> I press down with
>> Two fingers.
>> I press down with uh
>> I press down with uh yeah,
>> Two fingers.
>> I press down with uh yeah, 10
>> I press down with uh yeah, 10 ounces
>> Two fingers.
>> I press down with uh yeah, 10 ounces of
pressure
pressure or
pressure or you
pressure or you know what
pressure or you know what I
pressure or you know what I mean?
pressure or you know what I mean? And
pressure or you know what I mean? And I
say
say resist.
That's
That's all.
That's all. I
That's all. I don't
That's all. I don't try
That's all. I don't try to
That's all. I don't try to force
That's all. I don't try to force her
down
down like
That's all. I don't try to force her
down like a
down like a truck
That's all. I don't try to force her
down like a truck driver,
down like a truck driver, you
That's all. I don't try to force her
down like a truck driver, you know?
down like a truck driver, you know? And
and
and then
and then I
and then I say
and then I say then
and then I say then I
and then I say then I hold
and then I say then I hold something
else
else in
and then I say then I hold something
else in mind
else in mind and
and then I say then I hold something
else in mind and I
else in mind and I say
and then I say then I hold something
else in mind and I say resist.
else in mind and I say resist. And
and then I say then I hold something
else in mind and I say resist. And then
there's
there's a
there's a difference.
There's
There's a
there's a difference.
There's a difference.
There's a difference. See
>> you
>> you ask
>> you ask permission
>> you ask permission though
>> you ask permission though to
>> I
>> I always
>> you ask permission though to
>> I always ask
>> I always ask permission
>> you ask permission though to
>> I always ask permission especially
>> I always ask permission especially in
front
front of
front of an
front of an audience
>> and
>> and then
front of an audience
>> and then you
>> and then you say
front of an audience
>> and then you say resist.
>> I
>> I have
>> I have permission
>> I have permission to
>> I have permission to ask
>> I have permission to ask the
>> I have permission to ask the question.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. I
>> I have permission to ask the question.
>> Yes. I have
>> Yes. I have permission
>> I have permission to ask the question.
>> Yes. I have permission to
>> Yes. I have permission to ask
>> I have permission to ask the question.
>> Yes. I have permission to ask the
question.
question. Resist.
question. Resist. Okay.
question. Resist. Okay. So
question. Resist. Okay. So I
question. Resist. Okay. So I got
question. Resist. Okay. So I got a
question. Resist. Okay. So I got a yes.
>> And
>> And you
question. Resist. Okay. So I got a yes.
>> And you ask
>> And you ask the
question. Resist. Okay. So I got a yes.
>> And you ask the question
>> And you ask the question inside
question. Resist. Okay. So I got a yes.
>> And you ask the question inside your
head.
head. Well,
head. Well, I
head. Well, I can
head. Well, I can verbalize
head. Well, I can verbalize it,
head. Well, I can verbalize it, but
head. Well, I can verbalize it, but to
make
make it
head. Well, I can verbalize it, but to
make it more
make it more pure
>> for
>> for the
>> for the sake
>> for the sake of
>> for the sake of the
>> for the sake of the audience
>> for the sake of the audience because
there's
there's doubting
>> for the sake of the audience because
there's doubting Thomas's
there's doubting Thomas's everywhere,
you
you know,
you know, and
you know, and they'll
you know, and they'll say,
you know, and they'll say, "Well,
you know, and they'll say, "Well, she
heard
heard you
you know, and they'll say, "Well, she
heard you say
heard you say it,
you know, and they'll say, "Well, she
heard you say it, that's
heard you say it, that's why
you know, and they'll say, "Well, she
heard you say it, that's why she
heard you say it, that's why she reacted
that
that way."
that way." So,
that way." So, I
that way." So, I don't
that way." So, I don't tell
that way." So, I don't tell anybody
because
because otherwise
that way." So, I don't tell anybody
because otherwise they
because otherwise they try
that way." So, I don't tell anybody
because otherwise they try to
because otherwise they try to use
that way." So, I don't tell anybody
because otherwise they try to use that
to
to negate
to negate it.
>> Well,
>> Well, thank
to negate it.
>> Well, thank you.
>> Because
>> Because it's
>> Because it's coming
>> Because it's coming out
>> Because it's coming out of
>> Because it's coming out of the
nonlinear.
nonlinear. See,
>> Because it's coming out of the
nonlinear. See, and
nonlinear. See, and scientific
>> Because it's coming out of the
nonlinear. See, and scientific person
says,
says, well,
says, well, you
says, well, you know,
says, well, you know, they
says, well, you know, they want
says, well, you know, they want to
says, well, you know, they want to try
and
and disprove
says, well, you know, they want to try
and disprove it.
and disprove it. Uh
says, well, you know, they want to try
and disprove it. Uh but
and disprove it. Uh but it
says, well, you know, they want to try
and disprove it. Uh but it doesn't
and disprove it. Uh but it doesn't make
any
any difference
any difference because
any difference because if
any difference because if you're
any difference because if you're you
any difference because if you're you can
hold
hold it.
any difference because if you're you can
hold it. I
hold it. I was
any difference because if you're you can
hold it. I was going
hold it. I was going to
any difference because if you're you can
hold it. I was going to bring
hold it. I was going to bring some
pictures
pictures with
pictures with me
pictures with me today
pictures with me today that
pictures with me today that we
pictures with me today that we were
going
going to
pictures with me today that we were
going to do
going to do uh
pictures with me today that we were
going to do uh just
going to do uh just to
pictures with me today that we were
going to do uh just to demonstrate
kinesiology
kinesiology and
kinesiology and I
kinesiology and I forgot
kinesiology and I forgot them.
kinesiology and I forgot them. So
kinesiology and I forgot them. So what
kinesiology and I forgot them. So what I
did
did is
kinesiology and I forgot them. So what I
did is I
did is I held
kinesiology and I forgot them. So what I
did is I held them
did is I held them in
kinesiology and I forgot them. So what I
did is I held them in mind
did is I held them in mind instead.
kinesiology and I forgot them. So what I
did is I held them in mind instead. So
instead
instead of
instead of bringing
instead of bringing the
instead of bringing the pictures,
instead of bringing the pictures, I
instead of bringing the pictures, I just
held
held them
instead of bringing the pictures, I just
held them in
held them in mind
instead of bringing the pictures, I just
held them in mind and
held them in mind and I
instead of bringing the pictures, I just
held them in mind and I got
held them in mind and I got the
instead of bringing the pictures, I just
held them in mind and I got the same
response
response as
response as if
response as if I'd
response as if I'd had
response as if I'd had the
response as if I'd had the pictures
here.
here. You
response as if I'd had the pictures
here. You see?
>> Wow.
Well,
Well, thank
>> Wow.
Well, thank you.
Well, thank you. That
>> Wow.
Well, thank you. That helps.
>> In
>> In other
>> In other words,
>> In other words, they
>> In other words, they recently
>> In other words, they recently discovered
recently
recently a
>> In other words, they recently discovered
recently a couple
recently a couple years
>> In other words, they recently discovered
recently a couple years ago
recently a couple years ago a
>> In other words, they recently discovered
recently a couple years ago a missing
verir
verir I
verir I think
verir I think it
verir I think it was.
verir I think it was. And
verir I think it was. And she
verir I think it was. And she and
verir I think it was. And she and I
verir I think it was. And she and I knew
it
it was
verir I think it was. And she and I knew
it was authentic
it was authentic long
verir I think it was. And she and I knew
it was authentic long before
it was authentic long before the
verir I think it was. And she and I knew
it was authentic long before the experts
did.
did. Just
did. Just held
did. Just held the
did. Just held the premiere
did. Just held the premiere in
did. Just held the premiere in mind
did. Just held the premiere in mind and
said,
said, "Yes,
did. Just held the premiere in mind and
said, "Yes, it's
said, "Yes, it's it's
did. Just held the premiere in mind and
said, "Yes, it's it's authentic."
said, "Yes, it's it's authentic." Yep.
>> When
>> When all
>> When all the
>> When all the world
>> When all the world experts
>> When all the world experts couldn't
decide,
decide, we
>> When all the world experts couldn't
decide, we knew
decide, we knew within
>> When all the world experts couldn't
decide, we knew within seconds.
So
So it
So it is
So it is of
So it is of use.
>> We
>> We know
So it is of use.
>> We know things
>> We know things the
So it is of use.
>> We know things the whole
>> We know things the whole world
So it is of use.
>> We know things the whole world doesn't
We
We don't
We don't even
We don't even dare
We don't even dare write
We don't even dare write them
We don't even dare write them or
We don't even dare write them or speak
about
about them.
We don't even dare write them or speak
about them. We
about them. We know
We don't even dare write them or speak
about them. We know things.
about them. We know things. It's
We don't even dare write them or speak
about them. We know things. It's routine
to
to know
to know things
to know things the
to know things the whole
to know things the whole world
to know things the whole world doesn't
have
have the
to know things the whole world doesn't
have the size
have the size idea
to know things the whole world doesn't
have the size idea about.
>> I
>> I love
>> I love using
>> I love using this
>> I love using this little
>> I love using this little system.
>> I love using this little system. I
>> I love using this little system. I mean,
it's
it's it's
>> I love using this little system. I mean,
it's it's saved
it's it's saved me
>> I love using this little system. I mean,
it's it's saved me countless
it's it's saved me countless hours.
That's
That's an
That's an old
That's an old system.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. O-ring.
>> O-ring.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You
>> O-ring.
>> Yeah. You see?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you
>> Oh, you pull.
>> Is
>> Is this
>> Oh, you pull.
>> Is this hairdresser
>> Is this hairdresser good?
>> No,
>> No, that's
>> No, that's a
>> No, that's a question.
>> No, that's a question. This
>> No, that's a question. This hairdresser
>> is
>> is okay
>> No, that's a question. This hairdresser
>> is okay for
>> is okay for me.
>> No, that's a question. This hairdresser
>> is okay for me. Resist.
>> is okay for me. Resist. Okay.
>> No, that's a question. This hairdresser
>> is okay for me. Resist. Okay. This
hairdresser
hairdresser is
hairdresser is not
hairdresser is not okay
hairdresser is not okay for
hairdresser is not okay for me
hairdresser is not okay for me or
hairdresser is not okay for me or is
hairdresser is not okay for me or is not
okay.
okay. Okay.
>> That's
>> That's just
>> That's just what
>> That's just what I
>> That's just what I wanted.
>> That's
>> That's your
>> That's just what I wanted.
>> That's your hairdressers.
>> It
>> It has
>> It has to
>> It has to be
>> It has to be It
>> It has to be It has
>> It has to be It has to
>> It has to be It has to be
>> It has to be It has to be in
>> It has to be It has to be in the
>> It has to be It has to be in the form
>> It has to be It has to be in the form of
a
a statement.
>> You
>> You make
>> You make a
>> You make a statement.
>> You make a statement. Yeah.
>> Got
>> Got that.
>> And
>> And the
>> And the statement
>> And the statement is
>> And the statement is either
>> And the statement is either true
>> And the statement is either true or
false.
>> I
>> I surely
>> I surely do.
>> I surely do. Thank
>> I surely do. Thank you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> I surely do. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Uhhuh.
>> Nice
>> Nice to
>> Nice to see
>> Nice to see you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Nice to see you.
>> Thank you so
>> Thank you so much.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I've
>> I've been
>> Uhhuh.
>> I've been going
>> I've been going through
>> Uhhuh.
>> I've been going through an
>> I've been going through an evolutionary
process
process in
process in my
process in my religious
process in my religious life.
>> In
>> In your
process in my religious life.
>> In your religious
>> In your religious life?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, okay. And
>> Oh, okay. And uh
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, okay. And uh I
>> Oh, okay. And uh I re
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, okay. And uh I re recently
>> Oh, okay. And uh I re recently came
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, okay. And uh I re recently came to
the
the realization
the realization for
the realization for me
the realization for me myself
the realization for me myself that
the realization for me myself that God
is
is energy.
>> Yes.
>> Only
>> Only energy.
>> Mhm.
>> Without
>> Without so-called
>> Mhm.
>> Without so-called feelings,
>> Without so-called feelings, without
>> Mhm.
>> Without so-called feelings, without need
to
to pray
to pray to
to pray to him
to pray to him for
to pray to him for anything.
>> How
>> How does
to pray to him for anything.
>> How does that
>> How does that equate
to pray to him for anything.
>> How does that equate with
>> How does that equate with what
to pray to him for anything.
>> How does that equate with what you've
been
been telling
been telling us?
Uh
Uh certainly
been telling us?
Uh certainly it
Uh certainly it equates
been telling us?
Uh certainly it equates because
uh
uh the
uh the presence
uh the presence of the
uh the presence of the divinity
uh the presence of the divinity divinity
is
is a
uh the presence of the divinity divinity
is a radiance
is a radiance indescribable.
uh the presence of the divinity divinity
is a radiance indescribable. The
is a radiance indescribable. The most
nearest
nearest thing
nearest thing you
nearest thing you could
nearest thing you could describe
nearest thing you could describe it
nearest thing you could describe it as
is
is what
nearest thing you could describe it as
is what I've
is what I've described
nearest thing you could describe it as
is what I've described already
is what I've described already today.
But
But that's
But that's the
But that's the subjective
But that's the subjective experience
But that's the subjective experience of
that
that presence.
But that's the subjective experience of
that presence. Mhm.
>> It's
>> It's beyond
>> It's beyond anth,
>> It's beyond anth, you
>> It's beyond anth, you know,
>> It's beyond anth, you know, it's
>> It's beyond anth, you know, it's not
anthropomorphic,
anthropomorphic, you
>> It's beyond anth, you know, it's not
anthropomorphic, you know,
anthropomorphic, you know, and
>> It's beyond anth, you know, it's not
anthropomorphic, you know, and the
anthropomorphic
anthropomorphic depictions
anthropomorphic depictions of
anthropomorphic depictions of God,
anthropomorphic depictions of God, you
know,
know, is
anthropomorphic depictions of God, you
know, is sort
know, is sort of
anthropomorphic depictions of God, you
know, is sort of an
know, is sort of an angry
anthropomorphic depictions of God, you
know, is sort of an angry old
know, is sort of an angry old guy
anthropomorphic depictions of God, you
know, is sort of an angry old guy and
you
you got
you got to
you got to please
you got to please him
you got to please him and
you got to please him and he
you got to please him and he favors
you got to please him and he favors you
or
or he's
you got to please him and he favors you
or he's mad
or he's mad at
you got to please him and he favors you
or he's mad at you
or he's mad at you and
you got to please him and he favors you
or he's mad at you and throws
or he's mad at you and throws you
you got to please him and he favors you
or he's mad at you and throws you in
hell.
>> Was
>> Was one
hell.
>> Was one of
>> Was one of the
hell.
>> Was one of the reasons
>> Was one of the reasons I
hell.
>> Was one of the reasons I became
>> Was one of the reasons I became an
atheist.
>> But
>> But the
atheist.
>> But the using
>> But the using energy
atheist.
>> But the using energy as
>> But the using energy as being
atheist.
>> But the using energy as being the
presence
presence of
presence of God
presence of God everywhere
presence of God everywhere in
presence of God everywhere in the
presence of God everywhere in the world
all
all the
presence of God everywhere in the world
all the time.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. It's
>> Yes. It's the
>> Yes. It's the infinite
>> Yes. It's the infinite presence
>> and
>> and it
>> Yes. It's the infinite presence
>> and it reveals
>> and it reveals itself
>> Yes. It's the infinite presence
>> and it reveals itself as
>> and it reveals itself as the
>> Yes. It's the infinite presence
>> and it reveals itself as the unfolding
of
of creation.
of creation. Evolution
of creation. Evolution is
of creation. Evolution is the
of creation. Evolution is the unfolding
of
of creation.
of creation. Evolution is the unfolding
of creation. So
of creation. So when
of creation. Evolution is the unfolding
of creation. So when you
of creation. So when you get
of creation. Evolution is the unfolding
of creation. So when you get beyond
causality,
uh
uh there
causality,
uh there isn't,
uh there isn't, you
causality,
uh there isn't, you know,
uh there isn't, you know, the
causality,
uh there isn't, you know, the god
uh there isn't, you know, the god of
causality,
uh there isn't, you know, the god of the
uh
uh ruling
uh ruling the
uh ruling the the
uh ruling the the bowling
uh ruling the the bowling ball,
uh ruling the the bowling ball, you
know,
know, there
uh ruling the the bowling ball, you
know, there shot
know, there shot it
uh ruling the the bowling ball, you
know, there shot it down
know, there shot it down the
uh ruling the the bowling ball, you
know, there shot it down the thing.
know, there shot it down the thing. Uh
it's
it's it's
it's it's continuous.
it's it's continuous. So
it's it's continuous. So the
it's it's continuous. So the the
universe
universe is
it's it's continuous. So the the
universe is an
universe is an expression
it's it's continuous. So the the
universe is an expression of
universe is an expression of divinity
and
and um
and um it's
and um it's evolutionary.
and um it's evolutionary. So
>> the
>> the fate
and um it's evolutionary. So
>> the fate of
>> the fate of consciousness
and um it's evolutionary. So
>> the fate of consciousness is
>> the fate of consciousness is to
and um it's evolutionary. So
>> the fate of consciousness is to evolve.
>> Yeah.
>> Fine.
>> Fine. Thank
>> Yeah.
>> Fine. Thank you
>> Fine. Thank you very
>> Yeah.
>> Fine. Thank you very much.
>> Fine. Thank you very much. Appreciate
it.
>> Yes.
Hi.
Hi. Um,
Hi. Um, my
Hi. Um, my question
Hi. Um, my question is
Hi. Um, my question is about
Hi. Um, my question is about you
Hi. Um, my question is about you spoke
um
um on
Hi. Um, my question is about you spoke
um on Wednesday
um on Wednesday night
Hi. Um, my question is about you spoke
um on Wednesday night about
um on Wednesday night about the
>> path
>> path of
>> path of the
>> path of the heart
>> path of the heart and
>> path of the heart and the
>> path of the heart and the path
>> path of the heart and the path of
>> path of the heart and the path of the
head.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And I
>> Yes.
>> And I was
>> And I was wondering
>> Yes.
>> And I was wondering how
>> And I was wondering how a
>> Yes.
>> And I was wondering how a person
>> And I was wondering how a person would
determine
determine which
determine which would
determine which would be
determine which would be the
determine which would be the best
determine which would be the best path
for
for that
determine which would be the best path
for that person
for that person and
determine which would be the best path
for that person and if
for that person and if it
determine which would be the best path
for that person and if it had
for that person and if it had anything
to
to do
to do with
to do with their
to do with their gender.
to do with their gender. Is
to do with their gender. Is there
typically
>> No,
>> No, nothing
>> No, nothing to
>> No, nothing to do
>> No, nothing to do with
>> No, nothing to do with gender.
>> No, nothing to do with gender. It
>> No, nothing to do with gender. It has
>> No, nothing to do with gender. It has to
do
do with
>> No, nothing to do with gender. It has to
do with your
do with your inclination,
your
your karmic
your karmic propensities.
you
you know
your karmic propensities.
you know perhaps
you know perhaps you're
your karmic propensities.
you know perhaps you're young
you know perhaps you're young archetypal
personality
personality type
personality type whether
personality type whether you're
personality type whether you're an
introvert
introvert whether
personality type whether you're an
introvert whether you're
introvert whether you're an
personality type whether you're an
introvert whether you're an extrovert
etc.
etc. So
etc. So certain
etc. So certain styles
etc. So certain styles would
etc. So certain styles would be
etc. So certain styles would be uh
etc. So certain styles would be uh you
know
know in
etc. So certain styles would be uh you
know in accord
know in accord and
etc. So certain styles would be uh you
know in accord and harmonious
know in accord and harmonious with
etc. So certain styles would be uh you
know in accord and harmonious with your
personality
and
and uh
personality
and uh so
and uh so if
personality
and uh so if you're
and uh so if you're an
personality
and uh so if you're an introvert
and uh so if you're an introvert you
probably
probably pick
probably pick a
probably pick a quiet
probably pick a quiet inner
probably pick a quiet inner meditative
style
style if
probably pick a quiet inner meditative
style if you're
style if you're an
probably pick a quiet inner meditative
style if you're an extrovert
style if you're an extrovert you
probably pick a quiet inner meditative
style if you're an extrovert you may
join
join a
join a church
join a church you
join a church you may
join a church you may join
join a church you may join the
join a church you may join the choir
join a church you may join the choir and
etc
etc you
join a church you may join the choir and
etc you know
etc you know so
join a church you may join the choir and
etc you know so each
etc you know so each one
join a church you may join the choir and
etc you know so each one will
etc you know so each one will select
something
something that's
something that's appropriate
something that's appropriate for
something that's appropriate for their
stage
stage of
something that's appropriate for their
stage of evolution
you'll
you'll be
you'll be attracted
you'll be attracted to
you'll be attracted to that
you'll be attracted to that which
you'll be attracted to that which you're
compatible
compatible with
>> and
>> and does
>> and does it
>> and does it tend
>> and does it tend to
>> and does it tend to be
>> and does it tend to be the
>> and does it tend to be the same
>> and does it tend to be the same over
lifime
lifime times
>> and does it tend to be the same over
lifime times if
lifime times if you
>> and does it tend to be the same over
lifime times if you does
lifime times if you does it
>> and does it tend to be the same over
lifime times if you does it carry
lifime times if you does it carry over
lifetime
lifetime to
lifetime to life.
>> I
>> I don't
lifetime to life.
>> I don't know
>> I don't know any
lifetime to life.
>> I don't know any they
>> I don't know any they probably
lifetime to life.
>> I don't know any they probably are
immaterial.
immaterial. All
immaterial. All you
immaterial. All you got
immaterial. All you got to
immaterial. All you got to worry
immaterial. All you got to worry about
is
is this
immaterial. All you got to worry about
is this lifetime
is this lifetime here
immaterial. All you got to worry about
is this lifetime here and
is this lifetime here and here
immaterial. All you got to worry about
is this lifetime here and here now.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. All right.
>> If
>> If you
>> Okay. All right.
>> If you like
>> If you like to
>> Okay. All right.
>> If you like to join
>> If you like to join the
>> Okay. All right.
>> If you like to join the choir
>> If you like to join the choir and
>> Okay. All right.
>> If you like to join the choir and shout
hallelujah,
hallelujah, that's
hallelujah, that's the
hallelujah, that's the way
hallelujah, that's the way you
hallelujah, that's the way you should
go.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> If
>> If you
>> Thank you.
>> If you like
>> If you like to
>> Thank you.
>> If you like to meditate
>> If you like to meditate alone
>> Thank you.
>> If you like to meditate alone in
>> If you like to meditate alone in a
>> Thank you.
>> If you like to meditate alone in a giant
cathedral
cathedral at
cathedral at midnight,
that's
that's another
cathedral at midnight,
that's another way.
that's another way. I've
cathedral at midnight,
that's another way. I've tried
that's another way. I've tried them
cathedral at midnight,
that's another way. I've tried them all.
>> Thanks.
meditated
meditated all
>> Thanks.
meditated all night
meditated all night in
>> Thanks.
meditated all night in one
meditated all night in one of
>> Thanks.
meditated all night in one of the
meditated all night in one of the great
pyramids
pyramids in
pyramids in Egypt.
pyramids in Egypt. Obama
>> you
>> you wrote
pyramids in Egypt. Obama
>> you wrote about
>> you wrote about moving
pyramids in Egypt. Obama
>> you wrote about moving energy
>> you wrote about moving energy through
your
your brain.
your brain. I
your brain. I don't
your brain. I don't remember
your brain. I don't remember what
your brain. I don't remember what book
it
it was.
your brain. I don't remember what book
it was. Is
it was. Is that
your brain. I don't remember what book
it was. Is that something
it was. Is that something you
your brain. I don't remember what book
it was. Is that something you know
it was. Is that something you know you
do
do or
do or you
do or you feel
do or you feel you
do or you feel you do
do or you feel you do it?
>> You
>> You wrote
do or you feel you do it?
>> You wrote about
>> moving
>> moving energy
>> through
>> through your
>> moving energy
>> through your brain.
>> Is
>> Is that
>> Is that Do
>> Is that Do you
>> Is that Do you feel
>> Is that Do you feel energy
>> Is that Do you feel energy or
>> Is that Do you feel energy or do
>> Is that Do you feel energy or do you
know
know you
>> Is that Do you feel energy or do you
know you have
know you have energy?
I
I don't
I don't know
I don't know what
I don't know what you're
I don't know what you're asking.
>> Are
>> Are you
I don't know what you're asking.
>> Are you talking
>> Are you talking about
I don't know what you're asking.
>> Are you talking about today's
>> Are you talking about today's lecture?
We
We talked
We talked about
We talked about the
We talked about the two
We talked about the two sides
We talked about the two sides of
We talked about the two sides of the
brain.
>> Nothing
>> Nothing about
>> Nothing about it
>> Nothing about it was
>> Nothing about it was in
>> Nothing about it was in a
>> Nothing about it was in a book.
>> Okay.
>> What
>> What are
>> What are you
>> What are you talking
>> What are you talking about?
>> Okay.
>> Okay. It's
>> What are you talking about?
>> Okay. It's taken
>> Okay. It's taken out
>> What are you talking about?
>> Okay. It's taken out of
>> Okay. It's taken out of context.
>> What are you talking about?
>> Okay. It's taken out of context. So
>> Okay. It's taken out of context. So sure
that
that we
that we can
that we can even
that we can even track
that we can even track as
that we can even track as to
that we can even track as to what
that we can even track as to what book
it
it was
that we can even track as to what book
it was out
it was out of
that we can even track as to what book
it was out of like
it was out of like this.
that we can even track as to what book
it was out of like this. So
it was out of like this. So I
that we can even track as to what book
it was out of like this. So I can't
>> say
>> say it
>> say it again.
>> say it again. What
>> say it again. What is
>> say it again. What is it
>> say it again. What is it you
>> say it again. What is it you want
>> say it again. What is it you want to
know?
>> I
>> I read
>> I read about
>> I read about um
>> I read about um how
>> I read about um how you
>> I read about um how you moved
>> I read about um how you moved energy
>> I read about um how you moved energy in
your
your brain.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, that's
>> Oh, that's the
>> Oh, that's the flowing
>> Oh, that's the flowing of
>> Oh, that's the flowing of the
>> Oh, that's the flowing of the condolina.
The
The condolini.
>> Oh, that's the flowing of the condolina.
The condolini. Yes.
The condolini. Yes. Yes.
>> Do
>> Do you
>> Do you feel
>> Do you feel that
>> Do you feel that or
>> Do you feel that or do
>> Do you feel that or do you
>> You
>> You feel
>> Do you feel that or do you
>> You feel You
>> You feel You feel
>> Do you feel that or do you
>> You feel You feel it
>> physically.
>> You
>> You feel
>> physically.
>> You feel it.
>> You feel it. Yes.
>> What
>> What does
>> What does it
>> What does it feel
>> What does it feel like?
>> When
>> When does
>> What does it feel like?
>> When does it
>> When does it What?
>> What
>> What does
>> What does it
>> What does it feel
>> What does it feel like?
>> Or
>> exquisite.
>> Exquisite.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Exquisite
>> Exquisite pleasure
>> Thank you.
>> Exquisite pleasure beyond
>> Exquisite pleasure beyond description.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> And
>> And it
>> Thank you.
>> And it flows.
>> And it flows. If
>> Thank you.
>> And it flows. If you
>> And it flows. If you think
>> Thank you.
>> And it flows. If you think of
>> And it flows. If you think of the
>> Thank you.
>> And it flows. If you think of the right
side
side of
side of your
side of your brain,
side of your brain, it
side of your brain, it flows
side of your brain, it flows into
side of your brain, it flows into that.
If
If you
side of your brain, it flows into that.
If you put
If you put your
side of your brain, it flows into that.
If you put your attention
If you put your attention on
side of your brain, it flows into that.
If you put your attention on the
If you put your attention on the left
side
side of
side of your
side of your brain,
side of your brain, it
side of your brain, it flows
side of your brain, it flows into
side of your brain, it flows into there.
Wherever
Wherever you
side of your brain, it flows into there.
Wherever you might
Wherever you might focus
side of your brain, it flows into there.
Wherever you might focus your
Wherever you might focus your attention,
it
it flows
it flows there.
it flows there. If
it flows there. If it
it flows there. If it flows
it flows there. If it flows to
it flows there. If it flows to somebody
who's
who's just
it flows there. If it flows to somebody
who's just had
who's just had an
it flows there. If it flows to somebody
who's just had an accident
who's just had an accident by
it flows there. If it flows to somebody
who's just had an accident by the
who's just had an accident by the side
of
of the
of the road,
of the road, it
of the road, it flows
of the road, it flows out
of the road, it flows out seem
of the road, it flows out seem to
of the road, it flows out seem to come
out
out through
of the road, it flows out seem to come
out through the
out through the heart
of the road, it flows out seem to come
out through the heart chakra
out through the heart chakra and
of the road, it flows out seem to come
out through the heart chakra and flow
out through the heart chakra and flow as
a
a very
a very powerful
a very powerful energy
a very powerful energy right
a very powerful energy right into
a very powerful energy right into the
people.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> It's
>> It's part
>> Thank you very much.
>> It's part of
>> It's part of the
>> Thank you very much.
>> It's part of the city's
>> It's part of the city's condundalin
energy
energy begins
energy begins to
energy begins to flow.
energy begins to flow. Yeah.
>> Thanks.
>> It's
>> It's exquisite.
>> It's exquisite. You
>> It's exquisite. You you
>> It's exquisite. You you won't
>> It's exquisite. You you won't miss
>> It's exquisite. You you won't miss it
when
when it
>> It's exquisite. You you won't miss it
when it happens.
It
It supersedes
It supersedes anything
It supersedes anything you've
experienced
experienced prior.
That
That occurs
That occurs around
That occurs around 570
That occurs around 570 around
That occurs around 570 around that
That occurs around 570 around that area.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. Hello.
>> How
>> How you
>> How you doing?
>> Yes.
>> Um,
>> Um, Dr.
>> Um, Dr. Hawkins,
>> Um, Dr. Hawkins, I've
>> Um, Dr. Hawkins, I've been
>> Um, Dr. Hawkins, I've been experiencing
what
what I
>> Um, Dr. Hawkins, I've been experiencing
what I would
what I would call
>> Um, Dr. Hawkins, I've been experiencing
what I would call spiritual
what I would call spiritual vanity.
>> Yes.
wanting
wanting to
>> Yes.
wanting to appear
wanting to appear spiritual
>> Yes.
wanting to appear spiritual to
wanting to appear spiritual to other
people.
>> Oh
>> Oh yes.
>> And
>> And to
>> And to perhaps
>> And to perhaps grow
>> And to perhaps grow more
>> And to perhaps grow more than
>> And to perhaps grow more than would
>> And to perhaps grow more than would be
natural.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, spiritual
>> Oh, spiritual ambition.
>> Oh, spiritual ambition. Yes.
>> Spiritual
>> Spiritual ambition
>> Oh, spiritual ambition. Yes.
>> Spiritual ambition is
>> Spiritual ambition is natural.
>> Oh, spiritual ambition. Yes.
>> Spiritual ambition is natural. And
>> Spiritual ambition is natural. And so
the
the only
the only thing
the only thing is
the only thing is to
the only thing is to become
the only thing is to become aware
the only thing is to become aware of
the only thing is to become aware of it.
Once
Once you
the only thing is to become aware of it.
Once you become
Once you become aware
the only thing is to become aware of it.
Once you become aware of
Once you become aware of it
the only thing is to become aware of it.
Once you become aware of it that
Once you become aware of it that the
spirit
spirit the
spirit the spiritual
spirit the spiritual ego
spirit the spiritual ego has
spirit the spiritual ego has the
spirit the spiritual ego has the same
vanities,
vanities, desires
spirit the spiritual ego has the same
vanities, desires etc.
vanities, desires etc. as
spirit the spiritual ego has the same
vanities, desires etc. as the
vanities, desires etc. as the regular
ego,
ego, you've
ego, you've already
ego, you've already conquered
ego, you've already conquered most
ego, you've already conquered most of
it.
it. The
ego, you've already conquered most of
it. The danger
it. The danger of
ego, you've already conquered most of
it. The danger of it
it. The danger of it is
ego, you've already conquered most of
it. The danger of it is it
it. The danger of it is it goes
unrecognized.
So
So if
unrecognized.
So if you
So if you recognize,
unrecognized.
So if you recognize, in
So if you recognize, in fact,
unrecognized.
So if you recognize, in fact, everybody
should
should assume
should assume that
should assume that you
should assume that you want
should assume that you want to
should assume that you want to calibrate
more
more than
should assume that you want to calibrate
more than other
more than other people.
should assume that you want to calibrate
more than other people. You
more than other people. You want
should assume that you want to calibrate
more than other people. You want to
more than other people. You want to be
higher,
higher, you
higher, you want
higher, you want to
higher, you want to be
higher, you want to be more
higher, you want to be more evolved.
That's
That's only
higher, you want to be more evolved.
That's only natural.
And
And u
And u you
And u you don't
And u you don't feel
And u you don't feel guilty
And u you don't feel guilty about
And u you don't feel guilty about it.
You
You just
And u you don't feel guilty about it.
You just become
You just become aware
And u you don't feel guilty about it.
You just become aware that
You just become aware that the
And u you don't feel guilty about it.
You just become aware that the spiritual
ego
ego also
ego also has
ego also has vanity,
ego also has vanity, you
ego also has vanity, you know,
ego also has vanity, you know, and
ego also has vanity, you know, and would
like
like to
ego also has vanity, you know, and would
like to be
like to be a
ego also has vanity, you know, and would
like to be a mount
like to be a mount senior
ego also has vanity, you know, and would
like to be a mount senior or
like to be a mount senior or cardinal
or
or even
or even the
or even the pope.
or even the pope. No,
or even the pope. No, I
or even the pope. No, I don't want
or even the pope. No, I don't want to
or even the pope. No, I don't want to be
the
the pope.
You
You got
You got to
You got to ride
You got to ride the
You got to ride the pope
You got to ride the pope mobile.
You got to ride the pope mobile. It's
You got to ride the pope mobile. It's no
good.
You
You want
You want to
You want to be
You want to be pope?
>> No.
>> No. Okay,
we're
we're ahead
we're ahead of
we're ahead of the
we're ahead of the game.
I
I I
we're ahead of the game.
I I appreciate
I I appreciate and
we're ahead of the game.
I I appreciate and I
I I appreciate and I respect
we're ahead of the game.
I I appreciate and I respect the
I I appreciate and I respect the pope.
You
You know,
You know, that's
You know, that's why
You know, that's why I
You know, that's why I can
You know, that's why I can make
You know, that's why I can make jokes
about
about it
You know, that's why I can make jokes
about it because
about it because I
You know, that's why I can make jokes
about it because I basically
about it because I basically respect
You know, that's why I can make jokes
about it because I basically respect the
position
position that
position that he
position that he is
position that he is has
position that he is has and
position that he is has and the
responsibility
responsibility and
position that he is has and the
responsibility and the
responsibility and the burden
position that he is has and the
responsibility and the burden of
responsibility and the burden of it
position that he is has and the
responsibility and the burden of it all.
I
I thought
I thought you
I thought you wouldn't
I thought you wouldn't want
I thought you wouldn't want to
I thought you wouldn't want to be
I thought you wouldn't want to be pope.
>> Well,
>> Well, thanks.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Tough
>> Tough job.
>> Your
>> Your question
>> Your question just
You're
You're my
>> Your question just
You're my teacher
and
and devotion.
>> That's
>> That's all
and devotion.
>> That's all it's
>> That's all it's necessary.
>> I
>> I got
>> I got it.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> The
>> The grace
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> The grace of
>> The grace of the
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> The grace of the guru
>> The grace of the guru is
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> The grace of the guru is yours
>> The grace of the guru is yours for
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> The grace of the guru is yours for the
asking.
>> Yep.
It's
It's unconditional.
Is
Is it
It's unconditional.
Is it in
Is it in the
It's unconditional.
Is it in the highest
Is it in the highest good
It's unconditional.
Is it in the highest good for
Is it in the highest good for my
It's unconditional.
Is it in the highest good for my wife
and
and I
and I to
and I to move
and I to move to
and I to move to Sedona?
Let's
Let's see.
and I to move to Sedona?
Let's see. We
Let's see. We have
and I to move to Sedona?
Let's see. We have permission
Let's see. We have permission to
and I to move to Sedona?
Let's see. We have permission to ask
Let's see. We have permission to ask the
question.
question. We
question. We have
question. We have permission
question. We have permission to
question. We have permission to ask
question. We have permission to ask the
question
question right
question. We have permission to ask the
question right here
question right here and
question. We have permission to ask the
question right here and now.
question right here and now. Resist.
question. We have permission to ask the
question right here and now. Resist. Uh
they're
they're moving
they're moving here
they're moving here would
they're moving here would be
they're moving here would be in
they're moving here would be in their
highest
highest good.
they're moving here would be in their
highest good. Resist.
Wow.
You
You see,
Wow.
You see, we
You see, we always
Wow.
You see, we always ask
You see, we always ask in
Wow.
You see, we always ask in the
You see, we always ask in the name
Wow.
You see, we always ask in the name of
the
the highest
the highest good
the highest good because
the highest good because we
the highest good because we we
the highest good because we we think
the highest good because we we think in
terms
terms of
the highest good because we we think in
terms of what's
terms of what's good
the highest good because we we think in
terms of what's good for
terms of what's good for us
the highest good because we we think in
terms of what's good for us moving
terms of what's good for us moving here
and
and and
and and we
and and we forget
and and we forget that
and and we forget that our
and and we forget that our moving
and and we forget that our moving here
may
may may
and and we forget that our moving here
may may be
may may be good
and and we forget that our moving here
may may be good for
may may be good for others.
and and we forget that our moving here
may may be good for others. You
may may be good for others. You know
what
what I'm
what I'm saying?
what I'm saying? We've
what I'm saying? We've accumulated
what I'm saying? We've accumulated quite
a
a spiritual
what I'm saying? We've accumulated quite
a spiritual community
a spiritual community here
what I'm saying? We've accumulated quite
a spiritual community here together
a spiritual community here together and
collectively
collectively the
collectively the emanation
collectively the emanation from
collectively the emanation from that.
You
You see,
collectively the emanation from that.
You see, so
You see, so it
collectively the emanation from that.
You see, so it may
You see, so it may not,
collectively the emanation from that.
You see, so it may not, you
You see, so it may not, you know,
collectively the emanation from that.
You see, so it may not, you know, it
You see, so it may not, you know, it may
be
be for
be for multiple
be for multiple reasons.
be for multiple reasons. We
be for multiple reasons. We don't
be for multiple reasons. We don't know.
>> Hi.
>> Um,
>> Um, I
>> Hi.
>> Um, I have
>> Um, I have a
>> Hi.
>> Um, I have a question
>> Um, I have a question about
>> Hi.
>> Um, I have a question about uh
>> Um, I have a question about uh choice.
>> Hi.
>> Um, I have a question about uh choice. I
studied
studied Robert
studied Robert Adams
studied Robert Adams and
studied Robert Adams and uh
studied Robert Adams and uh he
studied Robert Adams and uh he talks
about
about everything
studied Robert Adams and uh he talks
about everything is
about everything is pre-ordained.
>> What?
>> Um,
>> Um, it's
>> What?
>> Um, it's about
>> Um, it's about choice,
>> What?
>> Um, it's about choice, free
>> Um, it's about choice, free will.
>> What?
>> Um, it's about choice, free will. Is
>> Um, it's about choice, free will. Is is
there
there choice?
>> What
>> What about,
there choice?
>> What about, you
>> What about, you know,
there choice?
>> What about, you know, everything
>> What about, you know, everything is
>> Do
>> Do you
>> Do you know
>> Do you know Robert
>> Do you know Robert Adams?
>> Nothing's
>> Nothing's pre-ordained.
>> Do you know Robert Adams?
>> Nothing's pre-ordained. No.
>> Nothing's pre-ordained. No. You
>> Do you know Robert Adams?
>> Nothing's pre-ordained. No. You have
karmic
karmic propensities,
karmic propensities, but
karmic propensities, but they're
karmic propensities, but they're not
have
have to.
karmic propensities, but they're not
have to. They're
have to. They're tendencies.
Uh
like
like in
Uh
like in this
like in this lifetime,
Uh
like in this lifetime, no
like in this lifetime, no doubt,
Uh
like in this lifetime, no doubt, you
know,
know, to
know, to be
know, to be spiritually
know, to be spiritually inclined,
know, to be spiritually inclined, it
know, to be spiritually inclined, it was
natural.
natural. Yeah.
But
But it's
But it's not
But it's not forced
But it's not forced or
But it's not forced or anything.
But it's not forced or anything. It's
But it's not forced or anything. It's by
one's
one's choice.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Um
>> Okay. Um another
>> Okay. Um another question
>> Okay. Um another question is
>> Okay. Um another question is um
>> Okay. Um another question is um I'm
>> Okay. Um another question is um I'm a
condalini
condalini yoga
>> Okay. Um another question is um I'm a
condalini yoga teacher.
condalini yoga teacher. She's
>> Okay. Um another question is um I'm a
condalini yoga teacher. She's right.
>> I'm
>> I'm a
>> I'm a kundalini
>> I'm a kundalini yoga
>> I'm a kundalini yoga teacher
>> I'm a kundalini yoga teacher and
>> I'm a kundalini yoga teacher and after
hearing
hearing your
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yes.
>> Oh, yes. Yes.
>> your
>> your talk
>> Oh, yes. Yes.
>> your talk today,
>> your talk today, I'm
>> Oh, yes. Yes.
>> your talk today, I'm a
>> your talk today, I'm a little
>> Oh, yes. Yes.
>> your talk today, I'm a little um
confused.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. Uh
confused.
>> Oh. Uh yoga,
>> Oh. Uh yoga, you
confused.
>> Oh. Uh yoga, you know,
>> Oh. Uh yoga, you know, is
confused.
>> Oh. Uh yoga, you know, is one
>> Oh. Uh yoga, you know, is one of
confused.
>> Oh. Uh yoga, you know, is one of the
great
great yogas
>> and
>> and uh
great yogas
>> and uh so
>> and uh so long
great yogas
>> and uh so long as
>> and uh so long as you
great yogas
>> and uh so long as you follow
>> and uh so long as you follow that
tradition
tradition and
tradition and you
tradition and you uh
tradition and you uh you
tradition and you uh you know,
tradition and you uh you know, you're
tradition and you uh you know, you're a
teacher,
>> uh
>> uh then
>> uh then you
>> uh then you won't
>> uh then you won't become
at
at the
>> uh then you won't become
at the effect
at the effect of
>> uh then you won't become
at the effect of it.
See
See the
See the uh
See the uh I've
See the uh I've done
See the uh I've done all
See the uh I've done all of
See the uh I've done all of them
See the uh I've done all of them myself.
I've
I've done
See the uh I've done all of them myself.
I've done all
I've done all the
See the uh I've done all of them myself.
I've done all the I've
I've done all the I've done
See the uh I've done all of them myself.
I've done all the I've done them
I've done all the I've done them all
See the uh I've done all of them myself.
I've done all the I've done them all the
yogas
>> and
>> and uh
yogas
>> and uh except
>> and uh except pranayana.
yogas
>> and uh except pranayana. I
>> and uh except pranayana. I just
yogas
>> and uh except pranayana. I just couldn't
handle
handle that
handle that nose
handle that nose job
handle that nose job there.
>> I
>> I know
handle that nose job there.
>> I know too
>> I know too much.
>> I
>> I couldn't
>> I couldn't handle
>> I couldn't handle pran.
Uh
Uh here's
>> I couldn't handle pran.
Uh here's what
Uh here's what we
>> I couldn't handle pran.
Uh here's what we do.
Uh here's what we do. We
>> I couldn't handle pran.
Uh here's what we do. We investigate
Uh here's what we do. We investigate all
these
these things
these things as
these things as we
these things as we grow
these things as we grow and
these things as we grow and they
these things as we grow and they serve
these things as we grow and they serve a
purpose
purpose for
these things as we grow and they serve a
purpose for a
purpose for a certain
these things as we grow and they serve a
purpose for a certain period
purpose for a certain period of
these things as we grow and they serve a
purpose for a certain period of time.
But
once
once you
But
once you cross
once you cross the
But
once you cross the stream,
once you cross the stream, you
But
once you cross the stream, you don't
need
need the
need the canoe
need the canoe anymore.
So
So the
need the canoe anymore.
So the you
So the you know
need the canoe anymore.
So the you know but
So the you know but I
need the canoe anymore.
So the you know but I think
So the you know but I think it's
necessary
necessary for
necessary for us
necessary for us to
necessary for us to try
necessary for us to try these
necessary for us to try these various
things
things at
necessary for us to try these various
things at various
things at various times
necessary for us to try these various
things at various times and
things at various times and I
necessary for us to try these various
things at various times and I think
things at various times and I think they
do
do serve
do serve a
do serve a purpose
>> because
>> because would
do serve a purpose
>> because would that
>> because would that be
do serve a purpose
>> because would that be the
>> because would that be the physical
do serve a purpose
>> because would that be the physical you
know
know level
know level you
know level you said
know level you said deal
know level you said deal with
know level you said deal with things
know level you said deal with things you
know
know all
know level you said deal with things you
know all all
know all all realms
know level you said deal with things you
know all all realms so
know all all realms so yoga
know level you said deal with things you
know all all realms so yoga is
>> well
>> well you're
>> well you're trying
>> well you're trying to
>> well you're trying to you
>> well you're trying to you know
>> well you're trying to you know you're
trying
trying to
>> well you're trying to you know you're
trying to raise
trying to raise the
>> well you're trying to you know you're
trying to raise the kind
trying to raise the kind of
>> well you're trying to you know you're
trying to raise the kind of lady
trying to raise the kind of lady energy
uh
uh if
uh if you
uh if you raise
uh if you raise it
uh if you raise it too
uh if you raise it too fast
uh if you raise it too fast beyond
uh if you raise it too fast beyond where
it
it it's
uh if you raise it too fast beyond where
it it's good
it it's good uh
uh if you raise it too fast beyond where
it it's good uh it
it it's good uh it would
uh if you raise it too fast beyond where
it it's good uh it would have
it it's good uh it would have an
injurious
injurious effect
injurious effect that's
injurious effect that's correct
injurious effect that's correct too
isn't
isn't that
>> uh
>> uh who's
>> uh who's the
>> uh who's the the
>> uh who's the the famous
get
get lopsided.
>> uh who's the the famous
get lopsided. Who
get lopsided. Who who
>> uh who's the the famous
get lopsided. Who who was
get lopsided. Who who was the
>> uh who's the the famous
get lopsided. Who who was the famous
get lopsided. Who who was the famous guy
that
that wrote
that wrote the
that wrote the book
that wrote the book about
that wrote the book about the
that wrote the book about the condolini
energy
energy went
that wrote the book about the condolini
energy went up
energy went up one
that wrote the book about the condolini
energy went up one side
energy went up one side of
that wrote the book about the condolini
energy went up one side of his
energy went up one side of his brain
go
>> yeah
>> yeah go
go
>> yeah go Krishna
>> yeah go Krishna yeah
keeping
keeping the
keeping the example
keeping the example of
keeping the example of gopr
keeping the example of gopr in
keeping the example of gopr in mind
keeping the example of gopr in mind yeah
>> okay
>> okay thank
keeping the example of gopr in mind yeah
>> okay thank you
>> okay thank you that's
keeping the example of gopr in mind yeah
>> okay thank you that's it
>> get
>> get a
>> get a picture
>> that
>> that was
>> get a picture
>> that was a
>> that was a great
>> get a picture
>> that was a great book
>> that was a great book Krishna
yeah
and
and are
yeah
and are you
and are you with
yeah
and are you with the
and are you with the spiritual
community.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You're
>> Yeah. You're pretty
>> Yeah. You're pretty safe.
>> Yeah. You're pretty safe. You
>> Yeah. You're pretty safe. You hang
>> Yeah. You're pretty safe. You hang out
with
with a
>> I
>> I do
>> I do both.
>> You
>> You hang
>> I do both.
>> You hang out
>> You hang out with
>> I do both.
>> You hang out with the
>> You hang out with the community.
>> I do both.
>> You hang out with the community. You
know,
know, the
know, the community
know, the community will
know, the community will tell
know, the community will tell you
know, the community will tell you if
you're
you're going
know, the community will tell you if
you're going off
you're going off in
know, the community will tell you if
you're going off in the
you're going off in the wrong
know, the community will tell you if
you're going off in the wrong direction
or
or something.
>> I
>> I think
or something.
>> I think each
>> I think each of
or something.
>> I think each of these
>> I think each of these things
or something.
>> I think each of these things serves
>> I think each of these things serves a
purpose
purpose at
purpose at a
purpose at a particular
purpose at a particular time.
>> But
>> But it's
purpose at a particular time.
>> But it's not
>> But it's not necessary
purpose at a particular time.
>> But it's not necessary to
>> But it's not necessary to cling
purpose at a particular time.
>> But it's not necessary to cling on
>> But it's not necessary to cling on to
them
them after
them after they
them after they serve
them after they serve their
them after they serve their usefulness.
>> Take
>> Take a
them after they serve their usefulness.
>> Take a picture.
>> Picture.
>> Picture. Yes.
>> Really?
>> Really? One,
>> Picture. Yes.
>> Really? One, two,
>> Really? One, two, three.
>> One,
>> One, two,
>> One, two, three.
>> One, two, three. Picture.
>> One, two, three. Picture. There
>> One, two, three. Picture. There you
>> One, two, three. Picture. There you go.
Okay.
Okay. My
>> One, two, three. Picture. There you go.
Okay. My question
Okay. My question is
>> One, two, three. Picture. There you go.
Okay. My question is I'm
Okay. My question is I'm actually
>> One, two, three. Picture. There you go.
Okay. My question is I'm actually a
Okay. My question is I'm actually a firm
believer
believer in
believer in the
believer in the chaos
believer in the chaos theory
believer in the chaos theory of
believer in the chaos theory of how
things
things are
believer in the chaos theory of how
things are moving
things are moving around
believer in the chaos theory of how
things are moving around on
things are moving around on Earth
believer in the chaos theory of how
things are moving around on Earth and
how
how things
how things are
how things are behaving.
>> You're
>> You're a
how things are behaving.
>> You're a believer
>> You're a believer in
how things are behaving.
>> You're a believer in what?
>> Chaos
>> Chaos theory.
>> Chaos theory,
>> right?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> We
>> We touched
>> We touched on
>> We touched on that
>> We touched on that once
>> We touched on that once before.
>> Yeah,
>> we
>> we did
>> we did talk
>> we did talk about
>> we did talk about it
>> we did talk about it a
>> we did talk about it a little
>> we did talk about it a little bit.
>> we did talk about it a little bit. You
mentioned
mentioned about
>> we did talk about it a little bit. You
mentioned about it
mentioned about it and
>> we did talk about it a little bit. You
mentioned about it and you
mentioned about it and you you
>> we did talk about it a little bit. You
mentioned about it and you you said
mentioned about it and you you said you
sort
sort of
sort of believed
sort of believed in
sort of believed in chaos,
sort of believed in chaos, but
sort of believed in chaos, but the
sort of believed in chaos, but the order
of
of things
sort of believed in chaos, but the order
of things is
of things is sort
sort of believed in chaos, but the order
of things is sort of
of things is sort of predestined
sort of believed in chaos, but the order
of things is sort of predestined with
flowers
flowers and
flowers and plants
flowers and plants and
flowers and plants and all
flowers and plants and all that,
flowers and plants and all that, but
flowers and plants and all that, but how
about
about behavior
flowers and plants and all that, but how
about behavior of
about behavior of people?
They're
They're all
They're all potentialities.
>> All
>> All potentialities,
They're all potentialities.
>> All potentialities, right?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. The
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. The potentiality.
>> Yeah. The potentiality. Then
out
out of
out of the
out of the radiance
out of the radiance of
out of the radiance of the
out of the radiance of the energy
out of the radiance of the energy of
your
your own
out of the radiance of the energy of
your own level
your own level of
out of the radiance of the energy of
your own level of consciousness
your own level of consciousness arises
choices.
The
The choices
choices.
The choices that
The choices that are
choices.
The choices that are options
The choices that are options are
correlated
correlated with
correlated with one's
correlated with one's level
correlated with one's level of
consciousness.
So
So as
So as one's
So as one's level
So as one's level of
So as one's level of consciousness
changes,
changes, the
So as one's level of consciousness
changes, the options
changes, the options change.
So as one's level of consciousness
changes, the options change. Yeah.
changes, the options change. Yeah. Mhm.
>> So
>> So the
>> So the higher
>> So the higher level,
>> So the higher level, the
>> So the higher level, the more
>> So the higher level, the more ability
you
you are
>> So the higher level, the more ability
you are to
you are to perceive
>> So the higher level, the more ability
you are to perceive of
you are to perceive of what's
>> So the higher level, the more ability
you are to perceive of what's going
you are to perceive of what's going on
and
and people
and people rising
and people rising to
and people rising to a
and people rising to a higher
and people rising to a higher level
and people rising to a higher level are
more
more conscious
and people rising to a higher level are
more conscious of
more conscious of situations
and people rising to a higher level are
more conscious of situations and
>> you
>> you have
>> you have different
>> you have different a
>> you have different a different
>> you have different a different choice.
Yes.
>> See,
>> See, because
>> See, because at
>> See, because at one
>> See, because at one level
>> See, because at one level you'd
>> See, because at one level you'd say,
>> See, because at one level you'd say, is
moving
moving here
>> See, because at one level you'd say, is
moving here good
moving here good for
>> See, because at one level you'd say, is
moving here good for me
moving here good for me and
>> See, because at one level you'd say, is
moving here good for me and you?
moving here good for me and you? And
>> See, because at one level you'd say, is
moving here good for me and you? And the
another
another level
another level you
another level you would
another level you would say
another level you would say is
another level you would say is it
another level you would say is it good
for
for everyone.
another level you would say is it good
for everyone. So
for everyone. So we
another level you would say is it good
for everyone. So we asked
for everyone. So we asked in
another level you would say is it good
for everyone. So we asked in the
for everyone. So we asked in the name
another level you would say is it good
for everyone. So we asked in the name of
the
the highest
the highest good
the highest good not
the highest good not just
the highest good not just for
the highest good not just for them
the highest good not just for them but
for
for the
the highest good not just for them but
for the impact
for the impact on
the highest good not just for them but
for the impact on life
for the impact on life community
the highest good not just for them but
for the impact on life community all
for the impact on life community all the
people
people here
people here in
people here in Sedona
people here in Sedona in
people here in Sedona in this
people here in Sedona in this group
right
>> so
>> so we
>> so we ask
>> so we ask in
>> so we ask in the
>> so we ask in the name
>> so we ask in the name of
>> so we ask in the name of the
>> so we ask in the name of the highest
good
good that
>> so we ask in the name of the highest
good that means
good that means everybody
>> so we ask in the name of the highest
good that means everybody and
good that means everybody and of
>> so we ask in the name of the highest
good that means everybody and of course
everybody
everybody includes
everybody includes them.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. All
everybody includes them.
>> Okay. All right.
>> Okay. All right. Sounds
everybody includes them.
>> Okay. All right. Sounds good
>> Okay. All right. Sounds good to
everybody includes them.
>> Okay. All right. Sounds good to me.
right.
right. Byebye.
right. Byebye. Thank
right. Byebye. Thank you.
I
I don't
right. Byebye. Thank you.
I don't I
I don't I want
right. Byebye. Thank you.
I don't I want I
I don't I want I don't
right. Byebye. Thank you.
I don't I want I don't want more
I don't I want I don't want more waste.
your
your time
your time or
your time or mine
your time or mine by
your time or mine by asking
your time or mine by asking their
your time or mine by asking their own
question.
question. So
your time or mine by asking their own
question. So I
question. So I think
your time or mine by asking their own
question. So I think I'm
question. So I think I'm going
your time or mine by asking their own
question. So I think I'm going to
question. So I think I'm going to ask
you
you the
you the question
you the question that
you the question that um
you the question that um that
you the question that um that I
you the question that um that I pose
you the question that um that I pose to
uh
uh to
you the question that um that I pose to
uh to God
uh to God every
you the question that um that I pose to
uh to God every day
uh to God every day and
you the question that um that I pose to
uh to God every day and it
uh to God every day and it is
you the question that um that I pose to
uh to God every day and it is um
despite
despite the
despite the best
despite the best efforts
despite the best efforts that
despite the best efforts that I
despite the best efforts that I can
make,
make, I
despite the best efforts that I can
make, I still
make, I still manage
despite the best efforts that I can
make, I still manage to
make, I still manage to remain
despite the best efforts that I can
make, I still manage to remain and
confusion.
And
And even
confusion.
And even though
And even though I
make
make a
make a lot
make a lot of
make a lot of mistakes,
make a lot of mistakes, I
make a lot of mistakes, I still
make a lot of mistakes, I still desire
to
align
align myself
align myself with
align myself with the
align myself with the truth
align myself with the truth and
align myself with the truth and live
align myself with the truth and live my
life
life in
align myself with the truth and live my
life in accordance
life in accordance with
align myself with the truth and live my
life in accordance with what
life in accordance with what that
teaches
teaches me.
Can
Can you
teaches me.
Can you give
Can you give me
teaches me.
Can you give me any
Can you give me any guidance?
um
um you
um you you
um you you choose
um you you choose uh
um you you choose uh your
um you you choose uh your alignment
um you you choose uh your alignment and
then
then you
um you you choose uh your alignment and
then you stay
then you stay with
um you you choose uh your alignment and
then you stay with it
then you stay with it no matter
um you you choose uh your alignment and
then you stay with it no matter what
comes
comes up.
comes up. And
comes up. And if
comes up. And if confusion
comes up. And if confusion is
comes up. And if confusion is what
comes up. And if confusion is what comes
up,
up, you
comes up. And if confusion is what comes
up, you surrender
up, you surrender your
comes up. And if confusion is what comes
up, you surrender your confusion
up, you surrender your confusion to
comes up. And if confusion is what comes
up, you surrender your confusion to God.
You
You can't
You can't get
You can't get much.
You can't get much. You
You can't get much. You can't
You can't get much. You can't really
make
make any
You can't get much. You can't really
make any progress
make any progress spiritually
You can't get much. You can't really
make any progress spiritually without
confusion.
>> Well,
>> Well, I
confusion.
>> Well, I must
>> Well, I must be
confusion.
>> Well, I must be doing
>> Well, I must be doing really
confusion.
>> Well, I must be doing really well.
>> You're
>> You're doing
>> You're doing really
>> You're doing really well.
I
I I
>> You're doing really well.
I I also
I I also wanted
>> You're doing really well.
I I also wanted to
I I also wanted to say
>> You're doing really well.
I I also wanted to say that
I I also wanted to say that I
>> You're doing really well.
I I also wanted to say that I I've
worked
worked with
worked with a
worked with a I
worked with a I lived
worked with a I lived in
worked with a I lived in a
worked with a I lived in a school
worked with a I lived in a school with
worked with a I lived in a school with a
where
where I
worked with a I lived in a school with a
where I was
where I was worked
worked with a I lived in a school with a
where I was worked with
where I was worked with a
worked with a I lived in a school with a
where I was worked with a teacher
where I was worked with a teacher for
worked with a I lived in a school with a
where I was worked with a teacher for a
number
number of
number of years.
number of years. So
number of years. So I
number of years. So I have
number of years. So I have a
number of years. So I have a uh
number of years. So I have a uh some
sense
sense of
number of years. So I have a uh some
sense of the
sense of the magnitude
number of years. So I have a uh some
sense of the magnitude of
sense of the magnitude of the
number of years. So I have a uh some
sense of the magnitude of the the
sense of the magnitude of the the gift
of
of your
of your presence
of your presence and
of your presence and I
of your presence and I I
of your presence and I I do
of your presence and I I do want
of your presence and I I do want to
of your presence and I I do want to say
u
I
I want
I want to
I want to extend
I want to extend my
I want to extend my appreciation
I want to extend my appreciation because
it
>> it's
>> it's very
>> it's very difficult
>> it's very difficult to
>> it's very difficult to be
>> it's very difficult to be here
>> it's very difficult to be here and
>> it's very difficult to be here and and
try
try to
>> it's very difficult to be here and and
try to like
>> you
>> you have
>> you have to
>> you have to understand
>> you have to understand that
>> you have to understand that the
confusion
confusion at
>> you have to understand that the
confusion at this
confusion at this point
>> you have to understand that the
confusion at this point I
confusion at this point I would
>> you have to understand that the
confusion at this point I would thank
God
God for
God for the
God for the confusion.
It's
It's better
God for the confusion.
It's better to
It's better to be
God for the confusion.
It's better to be confused
It's better to be confused than
God for the confusion.
It's better to be confused than to
It's better to be confused than to be
certain
certain that
certain that falsehood
certain that falsehood is
certain that falsehood is truth.
There's
There's a
certain that falsehood is truth.
There's a phase
There's a phase called
certain that falsehood is truth.
There's a phase called divine
There's a phase called divine stupidity.
Welcome.
Welcome. It
>> sounds
>> sounds pretty
Welcome. It
>> sounds pretty good.
>> sounds pretty good. Sounds
Welcome. It
>> sounds pretty good. Sounds like
>> sounds pretty good. Sounds like a
>> because
>> because you
>> because you realize
>> because you realize the
>> because you realize the truth
>> because you realize the truth of
>> because you realize the truth of the
>> because you realize the truth of the ego
that
that it
>> because you realize the truth of the ego
that it doesn't
that it doesn't and
>> because you realize the truth of the ego
that it doesn't and can't
that it doesn't and can't know
>> because you realize the truth of the ego
that it doesn't and can't know truth.
that it doesn't and can't know truth. So
there
there is
there is a
there is a period
there is a period called
there is a period called divine
stupidity.
What
What do
What do you
What do you think
What do you think about
What do you think about so
What do you think about so and
What do you think about so and so?
What do you think about so and so? I
don't
don't know.
What do you think about so and so? I
don't know. I
don't know. I don't
What do you think about so and so? I
don't know. I don't think
don't know. I don't think anything
What do you think about so and so? I
don't know. I don't think anything about
it.
What
What do
it.
What do you
What do you think
it.
What do you think about
What do you think about the
it.
What do you think about the world
What do you think about the world coming
to
to an
to an end?
to an end? I
to an end? I don't
to an end? I don't know.
to an end? I don't know. I
to an end? I don't know. I don't
to an end? I don't know. I don't think
about
about it
to an end? I don't know. I don't think
about it at
about it at all.
to an end? I don't know. I don't think
about it at all. You
about it at all. You know
to an end? I don't know. I don't think
about it at all. You know what
about it at all. You know what I'm
saying?
>> Yeah.
>> Divine
>> Divine stupidity.
>> And
>> And Susan
>> Divine stupidity.
>> And Susan and
>> And Susan and I
>> Divine stupidity.
>> And Susan and I have
>> And Susan and I have divine
>> Divine stupidity.
>> And Susan and I have divine stupidity.
We
We share
We share it.
We share it. Yeah.
Many
Many a
We share it. Yeah.
Many a time
Many a time I'll
We share it. Yeah.
Many a time I'll say
Many a time I'll say you
We share it. Yeah.
Many a time I'll say you I'll
Many a time I'll say you I'll think
We share it. Yeah.
Many a time I'll say you I'll think of
Many a time I'll say you I'll think of a
letter
letter I
letter I was
letter I was going
letter I was going to
letter I was going to write
letter I was going to write and
letter I was going to write and I
letter I was going to write and I said
letter I was going to write and I said I
don't
don't know
letter I was going to write and I said I
don't know should
don't know should I
letter I was going to write and I said I
don't know should I write
don't know should I write it
letter I was going to write and I said I
don't know should I write it or
don't know should I write it or not?
letter I was going to write and I said I
don't know should I write it or not? So
I
I ask
I ask her
I ask her you
I ask her you know
I ask her you know yeah
I ask her you know yeah it
I ask her you know yeah it says
I ask her you know yeah it says okay
send
send it.
I ask her you know yeah it says okay
send it. Okay
send it. Okay my
I ask her you know yeah it says okay
send it. Okay my stupidity
send it. Okay my stupidity I
I ask her you know yeah it says okay
send it. Okay my stupidity I can't
decide
decide whether
decide whether to
decide whether to write
decide whether to write send
decide whether to write send the
decide whether to write send the letter
I've
I've written
decide whether to write send the letter
I've written you
I've written you know
>> I
>> I dunk
>> I dunk in
>> I dunk in your
>> I dunk in your gut.
>> Okay.
>> It's
>> It's a
>> It's a relief
>> It's a relief not
>> It's a relief not to
>> It's a relief not to have
>> It's a relief not to have all
>> It's a relief not to have all the
answers
answers you
>> It's a relief not to have all the
answers you know.
answers you know. Yeah.
>> It's a relief not to have all the
answers you know. Yeah. I
answers you know. Yeah. I don't
>> let
>> let God
>> let God worry
>> let God worry about
>> let God worry about it,
>> let God worry about it, you
>> let God worry about it, you know.
>> Put
>> Put him
>> let God worry about it, you know.
>> Put him to
>> Put him to work.
>> Put
>> Put him
>> Put him to
>> Put him to work.
>> Yeah.
>> I
>> I guess
>> I guess that's
>> I guess that's it.
>> I guess that's it. Thank
>> I guess that's it. Thank you
>> I guess that's it. Thank you very
>> I guess that's it. Thank you very much.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Our
>> I guess that's it. Thank you very much.
>> Yeah. Our bird.
>> Yeah. Our bird. What
>> I guess that's it. Thank you very much.
>> Yeah. Our bird. What kind
>> Yeah. Our bird. What kind of
>> I guess that's it. Thank you very much.
>> Yeah. Our bird. What kind of a
>> Yeah. Our bird. What kind of a bird
>> I guess that's it. Thank you very much.
>> Yeah. Our bird. What kind of a bird is
that?
>> A
>> A gray.
>> Gray.
>> Huh?
>> African.
>> African
>> African gray.
>> African.
>> African gray. Yeah.
>> African gray. Yeah. He
>> African.
>> African gray. Yeah. He says,
>> African gray. Yeah. He says, "Uh,
>> African.
>> African gray. Yeah. He says, "Uh, don't
worry.
worry. Get
worry. Get a
worry. Get a job.
worry. Get a job. Go
worry. Get a job. Go to
worry. Get a job. Go to work.
worry. Get a job. Go to work. Get
worry. Get a job. Go to work. Get a
job."
job." That's
worry. Get a job. Go to work. Get a
job." That's what
job." That's what my
worry. Get a job. Go to work. Get a
job." That's what my my
job." That's what my my bird
worry. Get a job. Go to work. Get a
job." That's what my my bird at
job." That's what my my bird at home
says.
says. You
says. You walk
says. You walk into
says. You walk into the
says. You walk into the living
says. You walk into the living room
says. You walk into the living room and
say,
say, "Get
says. You walk into the living room and
say, "Get a
say, "Get a job.
Go
Go to
Go to work.
Go to work. Get
Go to work. Get a
Go to work. Get a job."
Tough
Tough love
Go to work. Get a job."
Tough love bird.
>> Yeah.
>> All
>> All right.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. First,
>> All right. First, I
>> Yeah.
>> All right. First, I wanted
>> All right. First, I wanted to
>> Yeah.
>> All right. First, I wanted to say
>> All right. First, I wanted to say thank
you.
you. And
you. And my
you. And my heart's
you. And my heart's like
you. And my heart's like racing
you. And my heart's like racing right
now.
now. And
you. And my heart's like racing right
now. And uh
now. And uh but
you. And my heart's like racing right
now. And uh but uh
now. And uh but uh I
you. And my heart's like racing right
now. And uh but uh I listened
now. And uh but uh I listened to
devoured
devoured so
devoured so many
devoured so many CDs
devoured so many CDs and
devoured so many CDs and the
devoured so many CDs and the tapes
devoured so many CDs and the tapes and
now
now I
devoured so many CDs and the tapes and
now I even
now I even have
devoured so many CDs and the tapes and
now I even have your
now I even have your CDs
devoured so many CDs and the tapes and
now I even have your CDs in
now I even have your CDs in my
devoured so many CDs and the tapes and
now I even have your CDs in my iPod,
which
which is
which is cool.
which is cool. So
which is cool. So on
which is cool. So on the
which is cool. So on the subways
which is cool. So on the subways in
which is cool. So on the subways in New
York,
York, uh
which is cool. So on the subways in New
York, uh you
York, uh you know,
which is cool. So on the subways in New
York, uh you know, I
York, uh you know, I I
which is cool. So on the subways in New
York, uh you know, I I can
York, uh you know, I I can kind
which is cool. So on the subways in New
York, uh you know, I I can kind of
devour
devour them
devour them some
devour them some more.
devour them some more. And
devour them some more. And and
devour them some more. And and I
devour them some more. And and I always
thought
thought what
devour them some more. And and I always
thought what I
thought what I would
devour them some more. And and I always
thought what I would ask
thought what I would ask if
devour them some more. And and I always
thought what I would ask if I
thought what I would ask if I got
devour them some more. And and I always
thought what I would ask if I got here,
and
and I'm
and I'm so
and I'm so thankful
and I'm so thankful that
and I'm so thankful that you
and I'm so thankful that you guys
and I'm so thankful that you guys had
this
this session,
and I'm so thankful that you guys had
this session, as
this session, as I'm
and I'm so thankful that you guys had
this session, as I'm sure
this session, as I'm sure so
and I'm so thankful that you guys had
this session, as I'm sure so many
this session, as I'm sure so many people
are
are thankful
are thankful for
are thankful for this
are thankful for this opportunity
are thankful for this opportunity to
are thankful for this opportunity to to
be
be in
are thankful for this opportunity to to
be in front
be in front of
are thankful for this opportunity to to
be in front of you.
be in front of you. So,
are thankful for this opportunity to to
be in front of you. So, uh
be in front of you. So, uh every
are thankful for this opportunity to to
be in front of you. So, uh every time
be in front of you. So, uh every time I
went
went in,
went in, it
went in, it was
went in, it was like
went in, it was like sold
went in, it was like sold out.
went in, it was like sold out. So,
went in, it was like sold out. So, uh
and
and I
went in, it was like sold out. So, uh
and I was
and I was like,
went in, it was like sold out. So, uh
and I was like, I
and I was like, I just
went in, it was like sold out. So, uh
and I was like, I just asked
and I was like, I just asked for
went in, it was like sold out. So, uh
and I was like, I just asked for the
grace
grace of
grace of God
grace of God just
grace of God just to
grace of God just to say
grace of God just to say what
grace of God just to say what I
grace of God just to say what I want
grace of God just to say what I want to
say
say clearly.
grace of God just to say what I want to
say clearly. Uh
say clearly. Uh okay,
grace of God just to say what I want to
say clearly. Uh okay, let's
say clearly. Uh okay, let's go.
grace of God just to say what I want to
say clearly. Uh okay, let's go. Um
right.
two
two years
right.
two years ago.
two years ago. Uh
right.
two years ago. Uh the
two years ago. Uh the vehicle
right.
two years ago. Uh the vehicle that
two years ago. Uh the vehicle that was
presented
presented to
presented to me
presented to me uh
presented to me uh uh
presented to me uh uh was
presented to me uh uh was my
presented to me uh uh was my Catholic
faith
faith that
presented to me uh uh was my Catholic
faith that I
faith that I kind
presented to me uh uh was my Catholic
faith that I kind of
faith that I kind of refound
presented to me uh uh was my Catholic
faith that I kind of refound and
faith that I kind of refound and was
presented to me uh uh was my Catholic
faith that I kind of refound and was a
blessing
blessing and
blessing and uh
blessing and uh it
blessing and uh it was
blessing and uh it was after
blessing and uh it was after law
blessing and uh it was after law school
and
and law
blessing and uh it was after law school
and law school
and law school was
blessing and uh it was after law school
and law school was so
and law school was so tough
blessing and uh it was after law school
and law school was so tough for
and law school was so tough for me
blessing and uh it was after law school
and law school was so tough for me and
and law school was so tough for me and I
made
made it
made it through
made it through but
made it through but I
made it through but I I
made it through but I I ended
made it through but I I ended up
made it through but I I ended up having
a
a lot
made it through but I I ended up having
a lot of
a lot of debt
made it through but I I ended up having
a lot of debt after
a lot of debt after law
made it through but I I ended up having
a lot of debt after law school
a lot of debt after law school but
made it through but I I ended up having
a lot of debt after law school but it
was
was so
was so tough
was so tough for
was so tough for me
was so tough for me that
was so tough for me that I
was so tough for me that I I
was so tough for me that I I kind
was so tough for me that I I kind of
drew
drew was
was so tough for me that I I kind of
drew was drawn
drew was drawn towards
was so tough for me that I I kind of
drew was drawn towards spiritual
principles
principles and
principles and I
principles and I was
principles and I was like
principles and I was like well
principles and I was like well I
principles and I was like well I work
principles and I was like well I work 80
hours
hours a
principles and I was like well I work 80
hours a week
hours a week for
principles and I was like well I work 80
hours a week for what?
hours a week for what? And
principles and I was like well I work 80
hours a week for what? And I
hours a week for what? And I saw
principles and I was like well I work 80
hours a week for what? And I saw my
parents
parents fighting
parents fighting over
parents fighting over money
parents fighting over money and
parents fighting over money and I
parents fighting over money and I said
parents fighting over money and I said I
was
was really
parents fighting over money and I said I
was really drawn
was really drawn towards
parents fighting over money and I said I
was really drawn towards helping
was really drawn towards helping people
maybe
maybe motivational
maybe motivational speaking
maybe motivational speaking maybe.
maybe motivational speaking maybe. Then
I
I I
maybe motivational speaking maybe. Then
I I discovered
I I discovered my
maybe motivational speaking maybe. Then
I I discovered my Catholic
I I discovered my Catholic faith
maybe motivational speaking maybe. Then
I I discovered my Catholic faith more
and
and I
and I just
and I just delved
and I just delved into
and I just delved into Theresa
and I just delved into Theresa Vavala,
John
John of
and I just delved into Theresa Vavala,
John of the
John of the Cross
and I just delved into Theresa Vavala,
John of the Cross and
John of the Cross and Thomas
and I just delved into Theresa Vavala,
John of the Cross and Thomas Merin.
John of the Cross and Thomas Merin. So
and I just delved into Theresa Vavala,
John of the Cross and Thomas Merin. So I
was
was really
was really going
was really going towards
was really going towards I
was really going towards I I
was really going towards I I was
discerning
discerning really.
was really going towards I I was
discerning really. I
discerning really. I was
was really going towards I I was
discerning really. I was spending
discerning really. I was spending time
in
in Italy
in Italy with
in Italy with the
in Italy with the Passionist
in Italy with the Passionist monks,
in Italy with the Passionist monks, the
Franciscans
Franciscans and
in Italy with the Passionist monks, the
Franciscans and a
Franciscans and a CC
in Italy with the Passionist monks, the
Franciscans and a CC and
Franciscans and a CC and I
in Italy with the Passionist monks, the
Franciscans and a CC and I was
Franciscans and a CC and I was even
spent
spent uh
spent uh 40-day
spent uh 40-day retreats
spent uh 40-day retreats with
spent uh 40-day retreats with the
Trappist
Trappist and
spent uh 40-day retreats with the
Trappist and that's
Trappist and that's ultimately
spent uh 40-day retreats with the
Trappist and that's ultimately who
Trappist and that's ultimately who I
spent uh 40-day retreats with the
Trappist and that's ultimately who I was
deciding
deciding on
deciding on being
deciding on being with.
deciding on being with. And
deciding on being with. And right
deciding on being with. And right at
towards
towards the
deciding on being with. And right at
towards the end
towards the end of
deciding on being with. And right at
towards the end of that
towards the end of that I
deciding on being with. And right at
towards the end of that I had
towards the end of that I had the
deciding on being with. And right at
towards the end of that I had the debt
towards the end of that I had the debt I
still
still had
still had to
still had to confront
still had to confront of
still had to confront of law
still had to confront of law school
still had to confront of law school the
money
money debt
still had to confront of law school the
money debt and
money debt and no
still had to confront of law school the
money debt and no religious
money debt and no religious religious
order
order was
order was going
order was going to
order was going to take
order was going to take me
order was going to take me in.
order was going to take me in. So
order was going to take me in. So I
order was going to take me in. So I was
confronted
confronted with,
order was going to take me in. So I was
confronted with, you
confronted with, you know
order was going to take me in. So I was
confronted with, you know what,
confronted with, you know what, go
order was going to take me in. So I was
confronted with, you know what, go back
out
out into
out into the
out into the world
out into the world and
out into the world and work
out into the world and work pay
out into the world and work pay it
out into the world and work pay it off
and
and do.
out into the world and work pay it off
and do. So
and do. So after
out into the world and work pay it off
and do. So after going
and do. So after going back
out into the world and work pay it off
and do. So after going back out
and do. So after going back out into
out into the world and work pay it off
and do. So after going back out into the
world
world in
world in New
world in New York
world in New York City
world in New York City and
world in New York City and uh
world in New York City and uh my
world in New York City and uh my ego
world in New York City and uh my ego to
deal
deal with
world in New York City and uh my ego to
deal with uh
deal with uh I
world in New York City and uh my ego to
deal with uh I I
deal with uh I I I
world in New York City and uh my ego to
deal with uh I I I kind
deal with uh I I I kind of
world in New York City and uh my ego to
deal with uh I I I kind of I
deal with uh I I I kind of I found
world in New York City and uh my ego to
deal with uh I I I kind of I found a
girlfriend
girlfriend very
girlfriend very quickly
girlfriend very quickly actually
girlfriend very quickly actually and
girlfriend very quickly actually and it
was
was it's
girlfriend very quickly actually and it
was it's been
was it's been a
girlfriend very quickly actually and it
was it's been a wonderful
was it's been a wonderful relationship
and
and and
and and and
and and and and
and and and and I
and and and and I and
and and and and I and for
and and and and I and for all
and and and and I and for all the
reasons
reasons where
and and and and I and for all the
reasons where why
reasons where why most
and and and and I and for all the
reasons where why most people
reasons where why most people kind
and and and and I and for all the
reasons where why most people kind of
drift
drift away
drift away from
drift away from the
drift away from the faith
drift away from the faith is
drift away from the faith is that
drift away from the faith is that I
wasn't
wasn't living
drift away from the faith is that I
wasn't living accordingly.
wasn't living accordingly. I
drift away from the faith is that I
wasn't living accordingly. I was
wasn't living accordingly. I was sinning
and
and whatever
and whatever and
and whatever and I
and whatever and I was
and whatever and I was dealt
and whatever and I was dealt with
and whatever and I was dealt with all
the
the scrupulosity.
I'm
I'm out
I'm out.
I'm out. Oh
I'm out
I'm out. Oh my
say
say I
say I was
say I was singing
say I was singing and
say I was singing and all
say I was singing and all the
scrupulosity
scrupulosity that
say I was singing and all the
scrupulosity that comes
scrupulosity that comes with
say I was singing and all the
scrupulosity that comes with that
question.
I
I was
question.
I was going
I was going to
question.
I was going to ask
I was going to ask for
question.
I was going to ask for your
I was going to ask for your blessing.
Thank
Thank you.
When
When when
Thank you.
When when you
When when you were
Thank you.
When when you were when
When when you were when you
Thank you.
When when you were when you were
When when you were when you were saying
earlier
earlier though
earlier though when
earlier though when you
earlier though when you were
earlier though when you were like,
earlier though when you were like, "Oh
my
my god,
earlier though when you were like, "Oh
my god, then
my god, then I
earlier though when you were like, "Oh
my god, then I have
my god, then I have to
earlier though when you were like, "Oh
my god, then I have to go
my god, then I have to go to
earlier though when you were like, "Oh
my god, then I have to go to confession
because
because I
because I just
because I just I
because I just I had
because I just I had that
because I just I had that I'd
because I just I had that I'd go
because I just I had that I'd go to
confession
confession then
because I just I had that I'd go to
confession then that
confession then that night
because I just I had that I'd go to
confession then that night I'd
confession then that night I'd be
because I just I had that I'd go to
confession then that night I'd be a
confession then that night I'd be a mess
and
and the
and the next
and the next day
and the next day I
and the next day I couldn't
and the next day I couldn't take
and the next day I couldn't take the
Eucharist
Eucharist cuz
and the next day I couldn't take the
Eucharist cuz which
Eucharist cuz which is,
and the next day I couldn't take the
Eucharist cuz which is, you
Eucharist cuz which is, you know,
and the next day I couldn't take the
Eucharist cuz which is, you know, so
Eucharist cuz which is, you know, so I
dealt
dealt with
dealt with all
dealt with all the
dealt with all the sin
dealt with all the sin on
dealt with all the sin on the
dealt with all the sin on the way
dealt with all the sin on the way to
church
>> and
>> and the
>> and the sin
>> and the sin on
>> and the sin on the
>> and the sin on the way
>> and the sin on the way to
>> and the sin on the way to church
>> and the sin on the way to church and
>> and the sin on the way to church and and
and
>> you
>> you open
>> you open the
>> you open the church
>> you open the church door
>> you open the church door and
>> you open the church door and there's
this
this girl
>> you open the church door and there's
this girl walks
this girl walks by
>> you open the church door and there's
this girl walks by with
this girl walks by with shirts
>> you open the church door and there's
this girl walks by with shirts screwed
on
on and
>> and
>> and it
on and
>> and it was
>> and it was over.
>> There
>> There you
>> There you go.
>> And
>> And it
>> There you go.
>> And it was
>> And it was over.
>> There you go.
>> And it was over. It
>> And it was over. It was
>> There you go.
>> And it was over. It was over.
>> And it was over. It was over. It
>> There you go.
>> And it was over. It was over. It was
over.
over. And
over. And uh
over. And uh so
over. And uh so all
over. And uh so all that
over. And uh so all that being
over. And uh so all that being and
over. And uh so all that being and and
so
so I
over. And uh so all that being and and
so I don't
so I don't want
over. And uh so all that being and and
so I don't want to
so I don't want to act
over. And uh so all that being and and
so I don't want to act I
so I don't want to act I had
over. And uh so all that being and and
so I don't want to act I had to
so I don't want to act I had to say
over. And uh so all that being and and
so I don't want to act I had to say that
story
story because
story because it
story because it wasn't
story because it wasn't as
story because it wasn't as if
story because it wasn't as if your
story because it wasn't as if your books
came
came along
story because it wasn't as if your books
came along and
came along and then
story because it wasn't as if your books
came along and then all
came along and then all of a
story because it wasn't as if your books
came along and then all of a sudden
came along and then all of a sudden I
left
left my
left my faith.
left my faith. No,
left my faith. No, but
left my faith. No, but at
left my faith. No, but at that
left my faith. No, but at that time
that's
that's when
left my faith. No, but at that time
that's when I
that's when I was
left my faith. No, but at that time
that's when I was through
that's when I was through Wayne
left my faith. No, but at that time
that's when I was through Wayne Dyer
that's
that's when
that's when I
that's when I heard
that's when I heard power
that's when I heard power versus
that's when I heard power versus force
and
and then
that's when I heard power versus force
and then I
and then I picked
that's when I heard power versus force
and then I picked up
and then I picked up that
that's when I heard power versus force
and then I picked up that and
and then I picked up that and I
that's when I heard power versus force
and then I picked up that and I was
and then I picked up that and I was like
read
read it
read it twice
read it twice before
read it twice before I
read it twice before I even
read it twice before I even moved
read it twice before I even moved on
read it twice before I even moved on to
the
the next
read it twice before I even moved on to
the next read
the next read that
read it twice before I even moved on to
the next read that twice
the next read that twice then
read it twice before I even moved on to
the next read that twice then the
the next read that twice then the next
book
book the
book the eye
book the eye you
book the eye you know
book the eye you know all
book the eye you know all of
book the eye you know all of them
book the eye you know all of them like
book the eye you know all of them like I
read
read twice
book the eye you know all of them like I
read twice and
read twice and highlighted
book the eye you know all of them like I
read twice and highlighted and
read twice and highlighted and they
book the eye you know all of them like I
read twice and highlighted and they all
about
about this
about this thick
about this thick cuz
about this thick cuz I
about this thick cuz I every
about this thick cuz I every one
about this thick cuz I every one of
about this thick cuz I every one of them
and
and uh
about this thick cuz I every one of them
and uh there's
and uh there's more
about this thick cuz I every one of them
and uh there's more highlighted
and uh there's more highlighted page
parts
parts than
parts than there
parts than there is
parts than there is white
parts than there is white parts.
parts than there is white parts. But
parts than there is white parts. But uh
so
>> sounding
>> sounding more
>> sounding more and
>> sounding more and more
>> sounding more and more like
>> sounding more and more like a
>> sounding more and more like a mad
>> sounding more and more like a mad monk.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Yes. Yes. Um
>> throws
>> throws all
>> Yes. Yes. Um
>> throws all caution
>> throws all caution to
>> Yes. Yes. Um
>> throws all caution to the
>> throws all caution to the wind.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Right.
>> Yeah. Right. Right.
>> Yeah. Right. Right. So
>> Yeah. Right. Right. So the
>> Yeah. Right. Right. So the question
I
I had
>> Yeah. Right. Right. So the question
I had I
I had I had
>> Yeah. Right. Right. So the question
I had I had to
I had I had to say
>> Yeah. Right. Right. So the question
I had I had to say that
I had I had to say that I
>> Yeah. Right. Right. So the question
I had I had to say that I had
I had I had to say that I had to
>> Yeah. Right. Right. So the question
I had I had to say that I had to cuz
I had I had to say that I had to cuz I
was
was going
was going to
was going to come
was going to come up
was going to come up and
was going to come up and ask
was going to come up and ask you
was going to come up and ask you your
definition
definition of
was going to come up and ask you your
definition of God.
definition of God. But
was going to come up and ask you your
definition of God. But with
definition of God. But with that
question
question is
question is that
question is that I
question is that I did
question is that I did I
question is that I did I do
question is that I did I do miss
question is that I did I do miss the
devotion
devotion and
question is that I did I do miss the
devotion and you
devotion and you have
question is that I did I do miss the
devotion and you have the
devotion and you have the devotional
duality
duality and
duality and and
duality and and I
duality and and I do
duality and and I do miss
duality and and I do miss the
duality and and I do miss the faith
duality and and I do miss the faith of
loving
loving God
duality and and I do miss the faith of
loving God through
loving God through Jesus
duality and and I do miss the faith of
loving God through Jesus Christ
loving God through Jesus Christ the
duality and and I do miss the faith of
loving God through Jesus Christ the the
son
son of
son of God.
son of God. It
son of God. It was
son of God. It was so
son of God. It was so easy
son of God. It was so easy to
son of God. It was so easy to have
son of God. It was so easy to have a
representation
representation the
son of God. It was so easy to have a
representation the Holy
representation the Holy Spirit.
son of God. It was so easy to have a
representation the Holy Spirit. I
representation the Holy Spirit. I knew
the
the faith
>> humbly
>> humbly thankfully
the faith
>> humbly thankfully very
>> humbly thankfully very well
the faith
>> humbly thankfully very well I
>> and
>> and and
>> and and and
>> and and and now
>> and and and now I'm
>> and and and now I'm struggling
>> and and and now I'm struggling to
>> and and and now I'm struggling to get
the
the love
>> and and and now I'm struggling to get
the love of
the love of God.
>> and and and now I'm struggling to get
the love of God. If
the love of God. If the
>> and and and now I'm struggling to get
the love of God. If the love
the love of God. If the love of
>> and and and now I'm struggling to get
the love of God. If the love of God
the love of God. If the love of God is
just
just energy
just energy and
just energy and the
just energy and the unmanifest,
just energy and the unmanifest, it's
hard
hard for
just energy and the unmanifest, it's
hard for me
hard for me to
just energy and the unmanifest, it's
hard for me to to
hard for me to to uh
just energy and the unmanifest, it's
hard for me to to uh and
hard for me to to uh and I
just energy and the unmanifest, it's
hard for me to to uh and I you
hard for me to to uh and I you know
just energy and the unmanifest, it's
hard for me to to uh and I you know it's
hard
hard for
hard for me
hard for me to
hard for me to um
hard for me to um I
hard for me to um I mean
hard for me to um I mean I
hard for me to um I mean I surrender
hard for me to um I mean I surrender I
say
say the
hard for me to um I mean I surrender I
say the prayers
say the prayers that
hard for me to um I mean I surrender I
say the prayers that and
say the prayers that and I
hard for me to um I mean I surrender I
say the prayers that and I have
say the prayers that and I have so
hard for me to um I mean I surrender I
say the prayers that and I have so many
things
things you
things you have
things you have said
things you have said I
things you have said I I'll
things you have said I I'll say
things you have said I I'll say but
things you have said I I'll say but I
things you have said I I'll say but I I
don't
don't I'm
things you have said I I'll say but I I
don't I'm missing
don't I'm missing the
things you have said I I'll say but I I
don't I'm missing the fervor
don't I'm missing the fervor I
things you have said I I'll say but I I
don't I'm missing the fervor I think
don't I'm missing the fervor I think the
enthusiasm
enthusiasm that
enthusiasm that I
enthusiasm that I pray
enthusiasm that I pray for
enthusiasm that I pray for the
enthusiasm that I pray for the the
devotion
devotion the
enthusiasm that I pray for the the
devotion the love
devotion the love not
enthusiasm that I pray for the the
devotion the love not not
devotion the love not not necessarily
it's
it's still
it's still more
it's still more contemplative
it's still more contemplative and
it's still more contemplative and that's
what
what I'm
it's still more contemplative and that's
what I'm blessed
what I'm blessed with
it's still more contemplative and that's
what I'm blessed with and
what I'm blessed with and I'm
it's still more contemplative and that's
what I'm blessed with and I'm thankful
because
because of
because of the
>> So
>> So what's
because of the
>> So what's the
>> So what's the question?
because of the
>> So what's the question? That's
>> So what's the question? That's the
question
question like
question like how
question like how how
question like how how could
question like how how could I
question like how how could I I
question like how how could I I how
question like how how could I I how can
I
I love
question like how how could I I how can
I love energy?
I love energy? How
question like how how could I I how can
I love energy? How can
I love energy? How can I
question like how how could I I how can
I love energy? How can I love
I love energy? How can I love you
question like how how could I I how can
I love energy? How can I love you know
me?
me? How
me? How can
me? How can I
me? How can I get
me? How can I get that
me? How can I get that de
me? How can I get that de the
me? How can I get that de the the
me? How can I get that de the the uh
>> well
>> well you're
me? How can I get that de the the uh
>> well you're looking
>> well you're looking for
>> or
>> or the
>> or the definition
>> or the definition of
>> or the definition of God
>> or the definition of God your
>> or the definition of God your definition
>> you're
>> you're looking
>> or the definition of God your definition
>> you're looking for
>> you're looking for an
>> or the definition of God your definition
>> you're looking for an object
>> you're looking for an object you're
looking
looking for
looking for an
looking for an object
>> an
>> an object
looking for an object
>> an object out
>> an object out there
looking for an object
>> an object out there of
>> an object out there of a
looking for an object
>> an object out there of a god
>> an object out there of a god and
looking for an object
>> an object out there of a god and you
>> an object out there of a god and you you
you
you separate
you separate from
you separate from that
you separate from that it's
you separate from that it's going
you separate from that it's going to
you separate from that it's going to uh
be
be passionate
you separate from that it's going to uh
be passionate about
be passionate about that
you separate from that it's going to uh
be passionate about that see
be passionate about that see one
you separate from that it's going to uh
be passionate about that see one can
be passionate about that see one can be
passionate
passionate about
passionate about one's
passionate about one's spiritual
evolution
uh
uh without
uh without making
uh without making it
uh without making it dualistic
and
and to
uh without making it dualistic
and to search
and to search deeper
uh without making it dualistic
and to search deeper within
and to search deeper within divinity
uh without making it dualistic
and to search deeper within divinity was
not
not something
not something found
not something found without
not something found without it
not something found without it was
something
something that
not something found without it was
something that arose
something that arose from
not something found without it was
something that arose from within
something that arose from within as
not something found without it was
something that arose from within as the
core
core of
core of my
core of my existence,
core of my existence, the
core of my existence, the core
core of my existence, the core of
core of my existence, the core of the
beingness,
beingness, the
core of my existence, the core of the
beingness, the core
beingness, the core of
core of my existence, the core of the
beingness, the core of the
beingness, the core of the capacity
core of my existence, the core of the
beingness, the core of the capacity to
exist.
And
And that
exist.
And that capacity
And that capacity transcends
exist.
And that capacity transcends all
And that capacity transcends all of
time.
So
So you're
time.
So you're doing
So you're doing very
time.
So you're doing very well
So you're doing very well the
time.
So you're doing very well the way
So you're doing very well the way you
are.
are. Don't
are. Don't be
are. Don't be impatient
are. Don't be impatient about
are. Don't be impatient about it.
are. Don't be impatient about it. You're
doing
doing fine
are. Don't be impatient about it. You're
doing fine indeed.
>> Yeah.
Before
Before you
>> Yeah.
Before you leave,
Before you leave, go
>> Yeah.
Before you leave, go and
Before you leave, go and see
>> Yeah.
Before you leave, go and see the
Before you leave, go and see the chapel
of
of the
of the Holy
of the Holy Cross.
of the Holy Cross. Have
of the Holy Cross. Have you
of the Holy Cross. Have you been
of the Holy Cross. Have you been there
yet?
>> No.
>> No. No.
>> Go
>> Go see
>> No. No.
>> Go see it.
>> Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you. I
>> Thank you. I think
>> Okay.
>> Thank you. I think I
>> Thank you. I think I have
>> Okay.
>> Thank you. I think I have a
>> Thank you. I think I have a picture
coming
coming with
coming with this
coming with this high-tech
coming with this high-tech camera
coming with this high-tech camera I
coming with this high-tech camera I got.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I
coming with this high-tech camera I got.
>> Yeah. I went
>> Yeah. I went into
coming with this high-tech camera I got.
>> Yeah. I went into a
>> Yeah. I went into a state
coming with this high-tech camera I got.
>> Yeah. I went into a state of
>> Yeah. I went into a state of ecstasy
coming with this high-tech camera I got.
>> Yeah. I went into a state of ecstasy in
the
the Chapel
the Chapel of
the Chapel of the
the Chapel of the Holy
the Chapel of the Holy Cross.
>> I'm
>> I'm I'm
the Chapel of the Holy Cross.
>> I'm I'm going
>> I'm I'm going to
the Chapel of the Holy Cross.
>> I'm I'm going to go.
>> Yes.
>> I
>> I don't
>> Yes.
>> I don't know
>> I don't know if
>> Yes.
>> I don't know if I'm
>> I don't know if I'm going
>> Yes.
>> I don't know if I'm going in.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> He's
>> He's very
>> He's very passionate
>> He's very passionate about
>> He's very passionate about his
>> He's very passionate about his lack
>> He's very passionate about his lack of
passion,
passion, isn't
>> He's very passionate about his lack of
passion, isn't he?
He
He can
He can make
He can make anybody
He can make anybody enthusiastic.
>> You
>> You guys
He can make anybody enthusiastic.
>> You guys know
>> You guys know so
He can make anybody enthusiastic.
>> You guys know so well.
>> You guys know so well. You
He can make anybody enthusiastic.
>> You guys know so well. You know,
>> You guys know so well. You know, I
He can make anybody enthusiastic.
>> You guys know so well. You know, I have
a
a a
a a video
a a video that
a a video that I
a a video that I watch
a a video that I watch all
a a video that I watch all all
a a video that I watch all all the
a a video that I watch all all the time.
And
And uh
a a video that I watch all all the time.
And uh you
And uh you look
a a video that I watch all all the time.
And uh you look so
And uh you look so much
a a video that I watch all all the time.
And uh you look so much prettier
And uh you look so much prettier in
a a video that I watch all all the time.
And uh you look so much prettier in this
than
than you
than you do
than you do in
than you do in the
than you do in the video.
Oh,
Oh, it's
than you do in the video.
Oh, it's so
Oh, it's so great
than you do in the video.
Oh, it's so great to
Oh, it's so great to be
than you do in the video.
Oh, it's so great to be here.
>> Talk
>> Talk to
>> Talk to my
>> Talk to my cameraman.
>> It's
>> It's so
>> Talk to my cameraman.
>> It's so great
>> It's so great to
>> Talk to my cameraman.
>> It's so great to be
>> It's so great to be here.
>> Talk to my cameraman.
>> It's so great to be here. Christopher,
the
the young
the young man
the young man that
the young man that was
the young man that was just
the young man that was just here,
the young man that was just here, uh,
from
from New
the young man that was just here, uh,
from New York,
from New York, and
the young man that was just here, uh,
from New York, and I
from New York, and I made
the young man that was just here, uh,
from New York, and I made it
from New York, and I made it to
the young man that was just here, uh,
from New York, and I made it to the
front
front row.
front row. I'm
front row. I'm from
front row. I'm from Miami
front row. I'm from Miami and
front row. I'm from Miami and he's
front row. I'm from Miami and he's from
New
New York,
front row. I'm from Miami and he's from
New York, so
New York, so I
front row. I'm from Miami and he's from
New York, so I guess
New York, so I guess it's
>> the
>> the pushy
>> the pushy people,
>> the pushy people, you
>> the pushy people, you know,
>> the pushy people, you know, the
>> the pushy people, you know, the little
pushy
>> h
>> h Jewish
>> h Jewish on
>> h Jewish on top
>> h Jewish on top of
>> h Jewish on top of it.
>> You're
>> You're not
>> h Jewish on top of it.
>> You're not Jewish.
>> You're not Jewish. Yeah.
>> Galatians
>> Galatians 3:29.
>> Galatians 3:29. Yeah.
>> Galatians 3:29. Yeah. Galatians
>> Galatians 3:29. Yeah. Galatians 3:29
that
that if
>> Galatians 3:29. Yeah. Galatians 3:29
that if you're
that if you're in
>> Galatians 3:29. Yeah. Galatians 3:29
that if you're in Christ,
that if you're in Christ, you're
>> Galatians 3:29. Yeah. Galatians 3:29
that if you're in Christ, you're of
Abraham's
Abraham's seed
Abraham's seed and
Abraham's seed and heir
Abraham's seed and heir to
Abraham's seed and heir to the
Abraham's seed and heir to the promise.
>> Uh
>> Uh so
Abraham's seed and heir to the promise.
>> Uh so that
>> Uh so that would
Abraham's seed and heir to the promise.
>> Uh so that would make
>> Uh so that would make me
Abraham's seed and heir to the promise.
>> Uh so that would make me Jewish.
>> My
>> My the
>> My the question
>> My the question I've
>> My the question I've had
>> My the question I've had a
>> My the question I've had a question
>> My the question I've had a question for
a
a long
>> My the question I've had a question for
a long time.
a long time. It's
>> My the question I've had a question for
a long time. It's not
a long time. It's not because
>> My the question I've had a question for
a long time. It's not because I
a long time. It's not because I really
wanted
wanted to
wanted to do
wanted to do it
wanted to do it or
wanted to do it or anything.
wanted to do it or anything. It's
wanted to do it or anything. It's it's
fasting.
>> Yeah.
>> Fasting.
>> Fasting. I
>> Yeah.
>> Fasting. I haven't
>> Fasting. I haven't seen
>> Yeah.
>> Fasting. I haven't seen it
>> Fasting. I haven't seen it in
>> Yeah.
>> Fasting. I haven't seen it in the
material
material and
material and I
material and I didn't
material and I didn't know
material and I didn't know whether
material and I didn't know whether it
calibrated
calibrated positive
material and I didn't know whether it
calibrated positive or
>> I
>> I never
>> I never did
>> I never did calibrate
>> I never did calibrate it.
>> I never did calibrate it. No,
>> like
>> like Mahatma
>> I never did calibrate it. No,
>> like Mahatma Gandhi.
>> like Mahatma Gandhi. Uh,
>> well,
>> well, he
>> well, he did
>> well, he did it
>> well, he did it as
>> well, he did it as a
>> well, he did it as a demonstration
political
political and
>> well, he did it as a demonstration
political and also
political and also as
>> well, he did it as a demonstration
political and also as a
political and also as a form
>> well, he did it as a demonstration
political and also as a form of
confrontation
confrontation of
confrontation of the
confrontation of the British
confrontation of the British Empire.
>> Esther
did
did a
did a ask
did a ask Israel
did a ask Israel for
did a ask Israel for a
did a ask Israel for a three-day
did a ask Israel for a three-day fast
and
and was
did a ask Israel for a three-day fast
and was there
and was there power
did a ask Israel for a three-day fast
and was there power in
and was there power in that?
>> You're
>> You're trying
>> You're trying to
>> You're trying to trans
>> You're trying to trans transcend
>> You're trying to trans transcend the
dominance
dominance of
>> You're trying to trans transcend the
dominance of the
dominance of the sensations.
>> It
>> It is
>> It is um
>> It is um a
>> It is um a whole
>> It is um a whole yoga
>> It is um a whole yoga in
>> It is um a whole yoga in itself.
It
It can
>> It is um a whole yoga in itself.
It can be
It can be done
>> It is um a whole yoga in itself.
It can be done and
It can be done and um
in
in fact
in fact it
in fact it can
in fact it can be
in fact it can be done
in fact it can be done to
in fact it can be done to excess
in fact it can be done to excess you
know
know and
>> I
>> I was
>> I was never
>> I was never tempted.
>> Your
>> Your friends
>> I was never tempted.
>> Your friends tell
>> Your friends tell you
>> I was never tempted.
>> Your friends tell you you
>> Your friends tell you you better
>> I was never tempted.
>> Your friends tell you you better eat
something
something this
something this week.
>> Right.
>> Right. Right.
something this week.
>> Right. Right. Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's
>> Yeah. It's just
>> Yeah. It's just been
>> Yeah. It's just been a
>> Yeah. It's just been a question
>> Yeah. It's just been a question that
>> Yeah. It's just been a question that I
>> Yeah. It's just been a question that I I
didn't
didn't know
>> Yeah. It's just been a question that I I
didn't know whether
didn't know whether it
>> Yeah. It's just been a question that I I
didn't know whether it was
didn't know whether it was positive
>> Yeah. It's just been a question that I I
didn't know whether it was positive or
negative.
>> I
>> I never
negative.
>> I never uh
>> I never uh you
negative.
>> I never uh you know
>> I never uh you know I
negative.
>> I never uh you know I was
>> I never uh you know I was everything
depends
depends on
depends on the
depends on the context.
>> Yeah.
>> Fasting
>> Fasting we
>> Fasting we have
>> Fasting we have permission
>> Fasting we have permission to
>> Fasting we have permission to ask
>> Fasting we have permission to ask God
fasting.
fasting. Fasting
>> Fasting we have permission to ask God
fasting. Fasting in
fasting. Fasting in and
>> Fasting we have permission to ask God
fasting. Fasting in and of
fasting. Fasting in and of itself
>> Fasting we have permission to ask God
fasting. Fasting in and of itself is
neutral.
neutral. Resist.
neutral. Resist. Yeah.
>> Fasting
>> Fasting as
neutral. Resist. Yeah.
>> Fasting as an
>> Fasting as an act
neutral. Resist. Yeah.
>> Fasting as an act of
>> Fasting as an act of devotion
neutral. Resist. Yeah.
>> Fasting as an act of devotion towards
God
God would
God would be
God would be 540
God would be 540 resist
God would be 540 resist as
God would be 540 resist as an
God would be 540 resist as an act
God would be 540 resist as an act of
devotion.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, that's
>> Oh, that's interesting.
>> Oh, that's interesting. Yeah,
>> Oh, that's interesting. Yeah, that's
good
good to
>> Oh, that's interesting. Yeah, that's
good to know.
good to know. Um,
>> Oh, that's interesting. Yeah, that's
good to know. Um, today
good to know. Um, today is
>> Oh, that's interesting. Yeah, that's
good to know. Um, today is my
good to know. Um, today is my fiveyear
birthday
birthday and
uh
uh and
birthday and
uh and aa
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
>> such
>> such a
>> Oh, yeah.
>> such a wonderful
>> such a wonderful such
>> Oh, yeah.
>> such a wonderful such a
>> such a wonderful such a wonderful
So,
So, thank
So, thank you
So, thank you so
So, thank you so much.
So, thank you so much. You've
So, thank you so much. You've become
So, thank you so much. You've become my
mentor
mentor and
So, thank you so much. You've become my
mentor and teacher.
mentor and teacher. I've
So, thank you so much. You've become my
mentor and teacher. I've studied
mentor and teacher. I've studied your
stuff
stuff for
stuff for so
stuff for so much.
stuff for so much. I
stuff for so much. I never
stuff for so much. I never thought
stuff for so much. I never thought I
would
would be
stuff for so much. I never thought I
would be able
would be able to
stuff for so much. I never thought I
would be able to sit
would be able to sit down
stuff for so much. I never thought I
would be able to sit down here
would be able to sit down here like
this.
this. So,
this. So, it's
this. So, it's wonderful.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
this. So, it's wonderful.
>> Thank you. Don't
>> Thank you. Don't forget.
>> There's
>> There's a
>> There's a guy
>> There's a guy a
>> There's a guy a commentator
>> There's a guy a commentator on
>> There's a guy a commentator on TV
>> There's a guy a commentator on TV now.
What's
What's his
>> There's a guy a commentator on TV now.
What's his name?
What's his name? Dennis.
>> There's a guy a commentator on TV now.
What's his name? Dennis. Uh,
>> what's
>> what's his
>> what's his name?
>> I
>> I can't
>> what's his name?
>> I can't remember.
>> I can't remember. He's
>> what's his name?
>> I can't remember. He's at
>> I can't remember. He's at the
>> what's his name?
>> I can't remember. He's at the same
>> I can't remember. He's at the same time
as
as whatchamacall
as whatchamacall but
as whatchamacall but he's
as whatchamacall but he's on
as whatchamacall but he's on 202
>> CNN.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Glenn
>> Yeah. Glenn Beck.
>> Yeah. Glenn Beck. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Glenn Beck. Yeah. Is
>> Yeah. Glenn Beck. Yeah. Is uh
>> Yeah. Glenn Beck. Yeah. Is uh about
>> Yeah. Glenn Beck. Yeah. Is uh about the
same
same political
>> Yeah. Glenn Beck. Yeah. Is uh about the
same political position
same political position but
>> Yeah. Glenn Beck. Yeah. Is uh about the
same political position but he's
same political position but he's comical
about
about it.
about it. Comical
about it. Comical about
about it. Comical about it.
about it. Comical about it. Yeah.
The
The question
about it. Comical about it. Yeah.
The question is
what
what it
what it for?
what
what it
what it is
what it is for
what it is for that
what it is for that creation
what it is for that creation was
what it is for that creation was created
if
if the
what it is for that creation was created
if the creation
if the creation is
what it is for that creation was created
if the creation is going
if the creation is going to
what it is for that creation was created
if the creation is going to return
if the creation is going to return to
its
its source
its source eventually.
its source eventually. So
its source eventually. So why
its source eventually. So why is
its source eventually. So why is it
doing
doing a
its source eventually. So why is it
doing a circle?
>> No,
>> No, that's
>> No, that's not
>> No, that's not that's
>> No, that's not that's a
>> No, that's not that's a linear
>> No, that's not that's a linear way
>> No, that's not that's a linear way of
denoting
denoting it.
>> No, that's not that's a linear way of
denoting it. It's
denoting it. It's not
>> No, that's not that's a linear way of
denoting it. It's not moving
denoting it. It's not moving in
>> No, that's not that's a linear way of
denoting it. It's not moving in any
direction.
direction. That's
direction. That's geometric
direction. That's geometric uh
imaging.
imaging. Um
the
the evolution
the evolution of
of
of um
the evolution of
of um the
of um the universe
the evolution of
of um the universe is
of um the universe is continuous
the evolution of
of um the universe is continuous and
ongoing
ongoing with
ongoing with no
ongoing with no beginning
ongoing with no beginning and
ongoing with no beginning and no
ongoing with no beginning and no end.
And
And it's
ongoing with no beginning and no end.
And it's not
And it's not circuitous.
ongoing with no beginning and no end.
And it's not circuitous. It's
evolutionary.
evolutionary. You
evolutionary. You see,
evolutionary. You see, we
evolutionary. You see, we track
evolutionary. You see, we track the
evolutionary. You see, we track the the
evolutionary
evolutionary level
evolutionary. You see, we track the the
evolutionary level of
evolutionary level of consciousness
evolutionary. You see, we track the the
evolutionary level of consciousness over
great
great expansions
great expansions of
great expansions of time,
great expansions of time, millions
great expansions of time, millions and
millions
millions and
great expansions of time, millions and
millions and trillions
millions and trillions of
great expansions of time, millions and
millions and trillions of years.
millions and trillions of years. And
great expansions of time, millions and
millions and trillions of years. And you
see
see it's
see it's constantly
see it's constantly going
see it's constantly going up.
You
You know,
see it's constantly going up.
You know, if
You know, if I
see it's constantly going up.
You know, if I had
You know, if I had my
see it's constantly going up.
You know, if I had my say
You know, if I had my say about
see it's constantly going up.
You know, if I had my say about it,
You know, if I had my say about it, I'd
say
say when
say when uh
say when uh the
say when uh the consciousness
say when uh the consciousness level
say when uh the consciousness level of
the
the planet
say when uh the consciousness level of
the planet meets
the planet meets uh
say when uh the consciousness level of
the planet meets uh reaches
the planet meets uh reaches 600,
say when uh the consciousness level of
the planet meets uh reaches 600, there'd
be
be no
be no point
be no point to
be no point to the
be no point to the planet
be no point to the planet because
there's
there's a
be no point to the planet because
there's a celestial
there's a celestial realm
be no point to the planet because
there's a celestial realm at
there's a celestial realm at 600.
be no point to the planet because
there's a celestial realm at 600. So,
you
you wouldn't
you wouldn't have
you wouldn't have to
you wouldn't have to incarnate.
you wouldn't have to incarnate. It
you wouldn't have to incarnate. It would
seem
seem that
you wouldn't have to incarnate. It would
seem that it
seem that it serves
you wouldn't have to incarnate. It would
seem that it serves the
seem that it serves the purpose
you wouldn't have to incarnate. It would
seem that it serves the purpose of
becoming
becoming linear.
becoming linear. There's
becoming linear. There's certain
becoming linear. There's certain forms
of
of incarnation
becoming linear. There's certain forms
of incarnation and
of incarnation and evolution
becoming linear. There's certain forms
of incarnation and evolution that
of incarnation and evolution that are
only
only possible
only possible if
only possible if you
only possible if you are
only possible if you are willing
only possible if you are willing to
only possible if you are willing to go
through
through the
only possible if you are willing to go
through the the
through the the linear.
The
The fate
The fate of
The fate of mankind
The fate of mankind is
The fate of mankind is that
The fate of mankind is that you
The fate of mankind is that you fooled
around
around with
The fate of mankind is that you fooled
around with the
around with the linear.
>> So
>> So this
>> So this is
>> So this is a
>> So this is a limitation
>> So this is a limitation of
>> So this is a limitation of the
>> So this is a limitation of the logic.
>> Huh?
>> This
>> This is
>> This is a
>> This is a limitation
>> This is a limitation of
>> This is a limitation of the
>> This is a limitation of the logic
of
of the
>> This is a limitation of the logic
of the intellect
that
that thought
that thought that
that thought that statement
inside.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't understand
>> I don't understand what
>> I don't understand what is
>> I don't understand what is your
question.
question. The
>> I don't understand what is your
question. The statement
question. The statement that
>> I don't understand what is your
question. The statement that that
question. The statement that that has
been
been said
been said is
been said is it
been said is it the
been said is it the limitation
been said is it the limitation of
been said is it the limitation of the
mind
mind the
been said is it the limitation of the
mind the logic
>> limitation
>> limitation of
>> limitation of the
>> limitation of the mind
>> limitation of the mind is
>> limitation of the mind is it
>> limitation of the mind is it the
limitation
limitation of
>> limitation of the mind is it the
limitation of the
limitation of the logic
>> the
>> the circle
>> you're
>> you're in
>> the circle
>> you're in a
>> you're in a circle
>> the
>> the question
>> the question is
>> the question is from
>> the question is from the
>> the question is from the intellect
>> the question is from the intellect what
just
just been
>> the question is from the intellect what
just been asked
>> no
>> what
>> what is
>> no
>> what is the
>> what is the question
>> no
>> what is the question from
>> what is the question from the
>> no
>> what is the question from the intellect
what's
what's the
what's the purpose
what's the purpose of
what's the purpose of the
what's the purpose of the universe
what's
what's the
what's the purpose of the universe
what's the purpose
what's the purpose of
what's the purpose of the universe
what's the purpose of evolution
>> no
>> no the
>> no the question
>> no the question is
>> no the question is that
>> no the question is that that
>> no the question is that that the
question
question was
>> no the question is that that the
question was asked
question was asked did
>> no the question is that that the
question was asked did it
question was asked did it came
>> no the question is that that the
question was asked did it came from
question was asked did it came from the
intellect
intellect or
intellect or it
intellect or it came
>> Did
>> Did the
intellect or it came
>> Did the answer
>> Did the answer come
intellect or it came
>> Did the answer come from
>> Did the answer come from the
intellect or it came
>> Did the answer come from the intellect?
>> Yeah,
>> the
>> the question
>> Yeah,
>> the question comes
>> the question comes from
>> Yeah,
>> the question comes from the
>> the question comes from the intellect.
>> The
>> The question
>> The question Yes.
>> The question Yes. Did
>> The question Yes. Did it
>> The question Yes. Did it came
>> The question Yes. Did it came from
>> The question Yes. Did it came from the
intellect
intellect or
>> the
>> the question
>> the question comes
>> the question comes from
>> the question comes from the
>> the question comes from the intellect?
Yes.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
>> Oh, I see.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
>> Oh, I see.
>> Okay.
>> Because
>> Because you
>> Okay.
>> Because you have
>> Because you have to
>> Okay.
>> Because you have to give
>> Because you have to give a
>> Okay.
>> Because you have to give a definition
>> Because you have to give a definition in
a
a linear
a linear languaging
a linear languaging form,
a linear languaging form, conceptual
form.
>> I
>> I get
>> I get it.
>> I get it. Thank
>> I get it. Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. I
>> I get it. Thank you.
>> Yes. I got
>> Yes. I got it.
>> I get it. Thank you.
>> Yes. I got it. No,
>> Yes. I got it. No, it
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
>> Oh, I see
>> Oh, I see what
>> Oh, I see what he
>> Oh, I see what he was
>> Oh, I see what he was saying.
>> Oh, I see what he was saying. Yeah.
Yeah.
>> I
>> I couldn't
>> I couldn't get
>> I couldn't get it.
grateful
grateful for
>> I couldn't get it.
grateful for the
grateful for the opportunity.
>> I couldn't get it.
grateful for the opportunity. You
grateful for the opportunity. You spoke
about
about prayer
about prayer as
about prayer as a
about prayer as a help
about prayer as a help to
about prayer as a help to the
about prayer as a help to the African
countries.
In
In South
In South Africa,
In South Africa, we
In South Africa, we have
In South Africa, we have about
In South Africa, we have about two
In South Africa, we have about two and
In South Africa, we have about two and a
half
half million
In South Africa, we have about two and a
half million orphans.
half million orphans. We
In South Africa, we have about two and a
half million orphans. We have
half million orphans. We have different
views
views on
views on how
views on how to
views on how to treat
views on how to treat them,
views on how to treat them, those
views on how to treat them, those who
want
want to
views on how to treat them, those who
want to help
want to help them,
views on how to treat them, those who
want to help them, and
want to help them, and those
views on how to treat them, those who
want to help them, and those who
want to help them, and those who say
that
that is
that is their
that is their path,
that is their path, they
that is their path, they just
that is their path, they just die.
Is
Is there
that is their path, they just die.
Is there a
Is there a truth?
>> Wait
>> Wait a
>> Wait a minute.
>> Wait a minute. Tell
>> Wait a minute. Tell me
>> Wait a minute. Tell me what
>> Wait a minute. Tell me what you
>> Wait a minute. Tell me what you said
>> Wait a minute. Tell me what you said of
>> She
>> She says
>> Wait a minute. Tell me what you said of
>> She says in
>> She says in Africa
>> Wait a minute. Tell me what you said of
>> She says in Africa they
>> She says in Africa they have
>> Wait a minute. Tell me what you said of
>> She says in Africa they have two
>> She says in Africa they have two and
>> Wait a minute. Tell me what you said of
>> She says in Africa they have two and a
half
half million
half million orphans.
half million orphans. Yes.
>> And
>> And they
half million orphans. Yes.
>> And they have
>> And they have uh
half million orphans. Yes.
>> And they have uh some
>> And they have uh some people
half million orphans. Yes.
>> And they have uh some people say
>> And they have uh some people say uh
half million orphans. Yes.
>> And they have uh some people say uh this
is
is their
is their path
is their path and
is their path and they
is their path and they die.
>> Um
>> it's
>> it's their
>> it's their karmic
>> it's their karmic karmic
>> it's their karmic karmic faith.
>> it's their karmic karmic faith. Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> it's their karmic karmic faith. Right.
>> Yeah. Okay. So
>> and
>> and those
>> and those who
>> and those who want
>> and those who want to
>> and those who want to assist
>> and those who want to assist and
>> and those who want to assist and help
them.
>> Yes.
>> Is
>> Is there
>> Yes.
>> Is there truth
>> Is there truth to
>> Yes.
>> Is there truth to this
>> Is there truth to this theme?
>> Yes.
>> Is there truth to this theme? And
>> Is there truth to this theme? And can
this
this illness
this illness be
this illness be addressed
this illness be addressed through
collectivity
collectivity and
this illness be addressed through
collectivity and energy?
Can
Can can
Can can this
Can can this um
>> it's
>> it's pandemic
>> the
>> the can
>> the can the
>> the can the um
>> the can the um can
>> the can the um can we
>> the can the um can we can
>> the can the um can we can it
>> the can the um can we can it be
addressed
addressed in
>> the can the um can we can it be
addressed in in
addressed in in some
>> the can the um can we can it be
addressed in in some way
addressed in in some way uh
>> the can the um can we can it be
addressed in in some way uh to
addressed in in some way uh to are
>> the can the um can we can it be
addressed in in some way uh to are you
asking
asking for
asking for help
asking for help of
asking for help of them
asking for help of them or
asking for help of them or are
asking for help of them or are you
asking for help of them or are you I'm
not
not quite
asking for help of them or are you I'm
not quite sure
not quite sure what
>> the
>> the pandemic
>> the pandemic of
>> the pandemic of of
>> the pandemic of of AIDS
>> the pandemic of of AIDS how
>> the pandemic of of AIDS how the
>> the pandemic of of AIDS how the higher
frequency
frequency and
>> the pandemic of of AIDS how the higher
frequency and energy
frequency and energy actually
can
can address
can address this
>> how
>> how in
can address this
>> how in other
>> how in other words
can address this
>> how in other words what
>> how in other words what path
can address this
>> how in other words what path do
>> how in other words what path do we
can address this
>> how in other words what path do we take
to
to address
to address um
to address um the
to address um the uh
to address um the uh orphans
to address um the uh orphans and
to address um the uh orphans and uh
their
their suffering.
to address um the uh orphans and uh
their suffering. I
their suffering. I mean
to address um the uh orphans and uh
their suffering. I mean what's
their suffering. I mean what's the
to address um the uh orphans and uh
their suffering. I mean what's the best
path
path to
path to take
path to take to
path to take to address
path to take to address uh
path to take to address uh and
>> well
>> well you
path to take to address uh and
>> well you you
>> well you you practice
path to take to address uh and
>> well you you practice benevolence
>> well you you practice benevolence and
humanitarianism
humanitarianism in
humanitarianism in whatever
humanitarianism in whatever way
humanitarianism in whatever way you
humanitarianism in whatever way you can
in
in a
humanitarianism in whatever way you can
in a practical
in a practical manner
humanitarianism in whatever way you can
in a practical manner at
in a practical manner at the
humanitarianism in whatever way you can
in a practical manner at the same
in a practical manner at the same time
you
you hold
you hold in
you hold in your
you hold in your mind
you hold in your mind that
you hold in your mind that their
condition
condition is
you hold in your mind that their
condition is is
condition is is somehow
you hold in your mind that their
condition is is somehow of
condition is is somehow of service
and
and that
and that their
and that their suffering
and that their suffering not
and that their suffering not you
and that their suffering not you know
that
that their
and that their suffering not you know
that their suffering
that their suffering serve
and that their suffering not you know
that their suffering serve a
that their suffering serve a higher
higher
higher purpose.
can
can through
higher purpose.
can through our
can through our collectivity
higher purpose.
can through our collectivity towards
can through our collectivity towards a
higher
higher energy
higher energy we
higher energy we actually
higher energy we actually impact
higher energy we actually impact that
illness.
>> Repeat
>> Repeat that
>> Repeat that one
>> Repeat that one more
>> Repeat that one more time.
>> If
>> If we
>> Repeat that one more time.
>> If we are
>> If we are on
>> Repeat that one more time.
>> If we are on a
>> If we are on a higher
>> Repeat that one more time.
>> If we are on a higher energy
>> If we are on a higher energy level,
>> yes,
>> can
>> can that
>> yes,
>> can that impact
>> can that impact on
>> yes,
>> can that impact on this
>> can that impact on this AIDS
>> yes,
>> can that impact on this AIDS illness?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. If
>> Yeah. If it's
>> Yeah. If it's if
>> Yeah. If it's if we're
>> Yeah. If it's if we're if
>> Yeah. If it's if we're if you're
>> Yeah. If it's if we're if you're at
>> Yeah. If it's if we're if you're at say
500,
500, can
>> Yeah. If it's if we're if you're at say
500, can that
500, can that impact
>> Yeah. If it's if we're if you're at say
500, can that impact uh
500, can that impact uh say
>> Yeah. If it's if we're if you're at say
500, can that impact uh say the
500, can that impact uh say the AIDS
illness?
illness? No.
illness? No. because
illness? No. because it's
>> oh
>> oh you're
illness? No. because it's
>> oh you're trying
>> oh you're trying to
illness? No. because it's
>> oh you're trying to lift
>> oh you're trying to lift the
illness? No. because it's
>> oh you're trying to lift the energy
>> oh you're trying to lift the energy of
the
the whole
the whole culture
the whole culture by
the whole culture by holding
the whole culture by holding it
the whole culture by holding it in
the whole culture by holding it in a
different
different way.
the whole culture by holding it in a
different way. First
different way. First of
the whole culture by holding it in a
different way. First of all,
different way. First of all, you
the whole culture by holding it in a
different way. First of all, you see
different way. First of all, you see it
as
as something
as something negative
as something negative that
as something negative that has
as something negative that has to
as something negative that has to be
cured.
cured. That's
as something negative that has to be
cured. That's already
cured. That's already an
as something negative that has to be
cured. That's already an impairment.
It's
It's not
It's not a
It's not a negative.
It's not a negative. It's
It's not a negative. It's only
It's not a negative. It's only a
negative
negative in
It's not a negative. It's only a
negative in your
negative in your view.
>> So
>> So the
>> So the prayer
>> So the prayer for
>> So the prayer for the
>> So the prayer for the African
>> So the prayer for the African country
Yes.
>> is
>> is benevolent.
>> is benevolent. any
>> is benevolent. any kind
>> is benevolent. any kind of
>> is benevolent. any kind of prayer
>> is benevolent. any kind of prayer and
sacrifice
sacrifice in
>> is benevolent. any kind of prayer and
sacrifice in their
sacrifice in their name
>> is benevolent. any kind of prayer and
sacrifice in their name and
sacrifice in their name and any
>> is benevolent. any kind of prayer and
sacrifice in their name and any kind
sacrifice in their name and any kind of
humanitarian
humanitarian effort.
humanitarian effort. Obviously
the
the problem
humanitarian effort. Obviously
the problem is
the problem is to
humanitarian effort. Obviously
the problem is to lift
the problem is to lift the
humanitarian effort. Obviously
the problem is to lift the consciousness
level
level of
level of the
level of the people.
level of the people. You
level of the people. You know
level of the people. You know you
level of the people. You know you don't
know
know what
level of the people. You know you don't
know what the
know what the karmic
precedent
precedent is.
precedent is. Therefore
precedent is. Therefore you
precedent is. Therefore you might
precedent is. Therefore you might be
wishing
wishing to
precedent is. Therefore you might be
wishing to deprive
wishing to deprive them
precedent is. Therefore you might be
wishing to deprive them of
wishing to deprive them of the
precedent is. Therefore you might be
wishing to deprive them of the undoing
of
of great
of great deal
of great deal of
of great deal of negative
of great deal of negative karma.
So
So you
of great deal of negative karma.
So you see
So you see your
of great deal of negative karma.
So you see your perception
So you see your perception of
of great deal of negative karma.
So you see your perception of the
So you see your perception of the world
is
is a
is a projection
and
and the
is a projection
and the world
and the world as
is a projection
and the world as it
and the world as it is
is a projection
and the world as it is is
and the world as it is is perfect.
is a projection
and the world as it is is perfect. So
and the world as it is is perfect. So I
wouldn't
wouldn't try
wouldn't try and
wouldn't try and change
wouldn't try and change the
wouldn't try and change the I
wouldn't try and change the I would
wouldn't try and change the I would pray
for
for the
wouldn't try and change the I would pray
for the suffering
for the suffering of
wouldn't try and change the I would pray
for the suffering of all
for the suffering of all those
uh
uh that
uh that is
uh that is of
uh that is of benefit
uh that is of benefit to
uh that is of benefit to them.
There
There is
uh that is of benefit to them.
There is suffering
There is suffering that
uh that is of benefit to them.
There is suffering that is
There is suffering that is of
uh that is of benefit to them.
There is suffering that is of benefit
and
and then
and then there
and then there is
and then there is suffering
and then there is suffering in
and then there is suffering in which
and then there is suffering in which the
benefit
benefit is
and then there is suffering in which the
benefit is not
benefit is not seen
and then there is suffering in which the
benefit is not seen and
benefit is not seen and not
and then there is suffering in which the
benefit is not seen and not chosen
benefit is not seen and not chosen or
accepted.
But
But there
accepted.
But there is
But there is a
accepted.
But there is a benefit
But there is a benefit in
accepted.
But there is a benefit in all
But there is a benefit in all suffering
and
and when
and when you
and when you find
and when you find it
and when you find it and
and when you find it and surrender
and when you find it and surrender it.
>> Yes.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> The
>> The last
>> Thank you.
>> The last pope
>> The last pope demonstrated
that
that suffering
that suffering as
that suffering as a
that suffering as a sacrifice
that suffering as a sacrifice can
that suffering as a sacrifice can be
surrendered
surrendered to
that suffering as a sacrifice can be
surrendered to God
surrendered to God and
that suffering as a sacrifice can be
surrendered to God and etc.
surrendered to God and etc. And
that suffering as a sacrifice can be
surrendered to God and etc. And um
it's
it's you
it's you have
it's you have to
it's you have to be
it's you have to be pretty
it's you have to be pretty advanced
it's you have to be pretty advanced to
understand
understand the
it's you have to be pretty advanced to
understand the karmic
understand the karmic benefit
it's you have to be pretty advanced to
understand the karmic benefit of
suffering
suffering because
suffering because you
suffering because you can
suffering because you can only
suffering because you can only you
suffering because you can only you only
see
see it
suffering because you can only you only
see it as
see it as a
suffering because you can only you only
see it as a negative.
Can
Can I
Can I see
>> it?
>> it? It
Can I see
>> it? It it
>> it? It it can
Can I see
>> it? It it can be
>> it? It it can be the
Can I see
>> it? It it can be the way
>> it? It it can be the way in
Can I see
>> it? It it can be the way in which
>> it? It it can be the way in which a
forsaken
forsaken uh
forsaken uh u
forsaken uh u a
forsaken uh u a soul
forsaken uh u a soul that
forsaken uh u a soul that is
forsaken uh u a soul that is almost
hopeless
hopeless turns
forsaken uh u a soul that is almost
hopeless turns around
hopeless turns around and
forsaken uh u a soul that is almost
hopeless turns around and earns
hopeless turns around and earns its
forsaken uh u a soul that is almost
hopeless turns around and earns its way
back
is
is through
back
is through suffering.
is through suffering. It
back
is through suffering. It could
is through suffering. It could be
back
is through suffering. It could be that
as
as effect
as effect that
as effect that is
as effect that is a
as effect that is a pathway.
as effect that is a pathway. It's
as effect that is a pathway. It's just
that
that is
as effect that is a pathway. It's just
that is a
that is a pathway.
as effect that is a pathway. It's just
that is a pathway. Suffering
that is a pathway. Suffering can
as effect that is a pathway. It's just
that is a pathway. Suffering can be
that is a pathway. Suffering can be a
path.
path. Oh
path. Oh Lord,
path. Oh Lord, I
path. Oh Lord, I wish
path. Oh Lord, I wish to
path. Oh Lord, I wish to undo
path. Oh Lord, I wish to undo all
path. Oh Lord, I wish to undo all that
which
which I
path. Oh Lord, I wish to undo all that
which I have
which I have done
path. Oh Lord, I wish to undo all that
which I have done to
which I have done to others
path. Oh Lord, I wish to undo all that
which I have done to others and
which I have done to others and I
path. Oh Lord, I wish to undo all that
which I have done to others and I pray
for
for that
for that forgiveness.
for that forgiveness. And
for that forgiveness. And then
for that forgiveness. And then you
earn
earn the
for that forgiveness. And then you
earn the chance
earn the chance to
for that forgiveness. And then you
earn the chance to undo
earn the chance to undo it.
Here
Here we
Here we earn
Here we earn positive
Here we earn positive karma
Here we earn positive karma and
Here we earn positive karma and we
Here we earn positive karma and we undo
negative.
Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> I
>> I would
>> I would like
>> I would like you
>> I would like you know
>> I would like you know if
>> I would like you know if we
>> I would like you know if we could
>> I would like you know if we could change
the
the world
>> I would like you know if we could change
the world there
the world there would
>> I would like you know if we could change
the world there would only
the world there would only be
>> I would like you know if we could change
the world there would only be positive.
>> But
>> But I
>> But I can't
>> But I can't decide.
how
how it
>> But I can't decide.
how it changed.
>> There's
>> There's there's
>> There's there's another
>> There's there's another way
>> There's there's another way of
>> There's there's another way of looking
at
at it.
>> There's
>> There's multiple
>> There's multiple ways
>> There's multiple ways you
>> There's multiple ways you can
>> There's multiple ways you can look
>> There's multiple ways you can look at
it.
it. I
>> There's multiple ways you can look at
it. I tried
it. I tried to
>> There's multiple ways you can look at
it. I tried to give
it. I tried to give her
>> I
>> I mean
>> I mean it's
>> I mean it's like
>> I mean it's like if
>> I mean it's like if you
>> I mean it's like if you all right
>> I mean it's like if you all right as
>> I mean it's like if you all right as a
parent
parent when
>> I mean it's like if you all right as a
parent when your
parent when your child
>> I mean it's like if you all right as a
parent when your child takes
parent when your child takes their
>> I mean it's like if you all right as a
parent when your child takes their first
steps
steps walk
steps walk and
steps walk and No,
steps walk and No, it
steps walk and No, it isn't.
steps walk and No, it isn't. Your
steps walk and No, it isn't. Your child
takes
takes the
steps walk and No, it isn't. Your child
takes the first
takes the first step
steps walk and No, it isn't. Your child
takes the first step and
takes the first step and they
steps walk and No, it isn't. Your child
takes the first step and they walk
takes the first step and they walk and
they
they fall.
they fall. Well,
they fall. Well, do
they fall. Well, do you
they fall. Well, do you run
they fall. Well, do you run and
they fall. Well, do you run and pick
them
them up
they fall. Well, do you run and pick
them up or
them up or do
they fall. Well, do you run and pick
them up or do you
them up or do you let
they fall. Well, do you run and pick
them up or do you let them
them up or do you let them get
they fall. Well, do you run and pick
them up or do you let them get up
them up or do you let them get up on
their
their own?
their own? Yeah.
>> You
>> You know,
their own? Yeah.
>> You know, so
>> You know, so it's
their own? Yeah.
>> You know, so it's the
>> You know, so it's the same
their own? Yeah.
>> You know, so it's the same situation
only
only it's
only it's just
only it's just putting
only it's just putting the
only it's just putting the minor
>> self-discovery
>> self-discovery then
only it's just putting the minor
>> self-discovery then that
>> self-discovery then that I
only it's just putting the minor
>> self-discovery then that I have
>> self-discovery then that I have within
me
me the
me the power
me the power to
me the power to get
me the power to get out
me the power to get out of
me the power to get out of the
me the power to get out of the mud.
Okay.
>> Uh
>> that's
>> that's good.
>> Uh
>> that's good. Very
>> that's good. Very good.
>> I
>> I recently
>> I recently heard
>> I recently heard about
>> I recently heard about a
>> I recently heard about a a
>> I recently heard about a a process
called
called the
>> I recently heard about a a process
called the Sedona
called the Sedona method.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And I
>> Yes.
>> And I noticed
>> And I noticed in
>> Yes.
>> And I noticed in their
>> And I noticed in their promotional
materials
materials they
materials they have an
materials they have an endorsement
materials they have an endorsement from
a
a psychiatrist
materials they have an endorsement from
a psychiatrist named
a psychiatrist named David
materials they have an endorsement from
a psychiatrist named David Hawkins
a psychiatrist named David Hawkins from
Nassau
Nassau County,
Nassau County, New
Nassau County, New York.
Nassau County, New York. I
Nassau County, New York. I was
Nassau County, New York. I was wondering
if
if you
Nassau County, New York. I was wondering
if you were
if you were that
Nassau County, New York. I was wondering
if you were that same
if you were that same David
Nassau County, New York. I was wondering
if you were that same David Hawkins.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. back
>> Yes. back years
>> Yes. back years ago,
>> Yes. back years ago, I
>> Yes. back years ago, I uh
>> Yes. back years ago, I uh favored
>> Yes. back years ago, I uh favored it
>> Yes. back years ago, I uh favored it and
I
I knew
>> Yes. back years ago, I uh favored it and
I knew Lester
I knew Lester very
>> Yes. back years ago, I uh favored it and
I knew Lester very well.
>> Yeah.
>> Is
>> Is that
>> Yeah.
>> Is that process
>> Is that process the
>> Yeah.
>> Is that process the same
>> Is that process the same thing
>> Yeah.
>> Is that process the same thing that
you're
you're describing
you're describing as
you're describing as the
you're describing as the process
you're describing as the process of
surrendering
surrendering things
you're describing as the process of
surrendering things to
surrendering things to God?
>> As
>> As last
>> As last I
>> As last I knew
>> As last I knew it,
>> As last I knew it, it
>> As last I knew it, it was
>> As last I knew it, it was sort
>> As last I knew it, it was sort of
secularized
secularized and
>> As last I knew it, it was sort of
secularized and also
secularized and also became
>> As last I knew it, it was sort of
secularized and also became sort
secularized and also became sort of
monetized
monetized and
monetized and therefore
monetized and therefore I
monetized and therefore I parted
monetized and therefore I parted with
him.
Um
yes
yes I
Um
yes I parted
yes I parted because
Um
yes I parted because he
yes I parted because he became
Um
yes I parted because he became secular
>> with
>> with the
>> with the same
>> with the same techniques
>> with the same techniques still
>> I
>> I would
>> with the same techniques still
>> I would use
>> I would use the
>> with the same techniques still
>> I would use the same
>> I would use the same technique
>> with the same techniques still
>> I would use the same technique but
surrendered
surrendered to
surrendered to God
surrendered to God instead.
>> Okay.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Thank you
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Thank you very
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Lester
>> Lester and
>> Lester and I
>> Lester and I parted
>> Lester and I parted over
>> Lester and I parted over that.
>> He
>> He thought
>> Lester and I parted over that.
>> He thought it
>> He thought it was
>> Lester and I parted over that.
>> He thought it was secular
>> He thought it was secular and
>> Lester and I parted over that.
>> He thought it was secular and should
>> He thought it was secular and should be
used
used for
used for money
used for money and
used for money and business
used for money and business and
used for money and business and I
used for money and business and I said
it's
it's a
used for money and business and I said
it's a pathway
it's a pathway to
used for money and business and I said
it's a pathway to God.
it's a pathway to God. And
used for money and business and I said
it's a pathway to God. And that's
it's a pathway to God. And that's why
used for money and business and I said
it's a pathway to God. And that's why we
parted.
Yeah.
>> You
>> You said
>> You said that
>> You said that some
>> You said that some in
>> You said that some in this
>> You said that some in this audience
>> You said that some in this audience will
attain
attain enlightenment
>> You said that some in this audience will
attain enlightenment and
attain enlightenment and I
>> You said that some in this audience will
attain enlightenment and I wondered
attain enlightenment and I wondered is
it
it necessary
it necessary as
it necessary as they
it necessary as they cross
it necessary as they cross certain
levels
levels 600
it necessary as they cross certain
levels 600 to
um
um pull
um pull away
um pull away from
um pull away from society
um pull away from society to
um pull away from society to become
dysfunctional
dysfunctional for
um pull away from society to become
dysfunctional for a
dysfunctional for a time
>> or
>> or can
>> or can they
>> or can they stay?
>> It's
>> It's frankly
>> or can they stay?
>> It's frankly inevitable.
>> At
>> At 570
>> At 570 and
>> At 570 and up
>> At 570 and up it's
>> At 570 and up it's going to
>> At 570 and up it's going to get
>> At 570 and up it's going to get even
harder.
harder. At
>> At 570 and up it's going to get even
harder. At 580
harder. At 580 it's
>> At 570 and up it's going to get even
harder. At 580 it's get
harder. At 580 it's get gets
>> At 570 and up it's going to get even
harder. At 580 it's get gets quite
harder. At 580 it's get gets quite hard.
590.
590. It's
590. It's tough.
590. It's tough. At
590. It's tough. At 600,
590. It's tough. At 600, forget
590. It's tough. At 600, forget it.
590. It's tough. At 600, forget it. If
the
the body,
590. It's tough. At 600, forget it. If
the body, if
the body, if there's
590. It's tough. At 600, forget it. If
the body, if there's somebody
the body, if there's somebody around
590. It's tough. At 600, forget it. If
the body, if there's somebody around to
make
make sure
make sure you
make sure you eat,
make sure you eat, you
make sure you eat, you do,
make sure you eat, you do, and
make sure you eat, you do, and you
survive.
survive. And
make sure you eat, you do, and you
survive. And if
survive. And if there
make sure you eat, you do, and you
survive. And if there isn't,
survive. And if there isn't, so
make sure you eat, you do, and you
survive. And if there isn't, so you
survive. And if there isn't, so you fall
over.
over. So,
>> thank
>> thank you.
>> You
>> You leave.
>> You have
>> You have the
>> You leave.
>> You have the option
>> You have the option to
>> You leave.
>> You have the option to leave.
>> You have the option to leave. You
>> You leave.
>> You have the option to leave. You have
the
the option
the option to
the option to leave.
the option to leave. You
the option to leave. You don't
the option to leave. You don't know
whether
whether you're
the option to leave. You don't know
whether you're going
whether you're going to
the option to leave. You don't know
whether you're going to leave
whether you're going to leave or
the option to leave. You don't know
whether you're going to leave or not,
but
but you
but you have
but you have the
but you have the option.
but you have the option. And
but you have the option. And it's
but you have the option. And it's quite
attractive.
attractive. So
>> picture
>> picture group
>> picture group hug.
>> It's
at
at that
at that level
at that level of
at that level of 600.
at that level of 600. It's
at that level of 600. It's attractive
at that level of 600. It's attractive to
leave.
leave. There's
at that level of 600. It's attractive to
leave. There's an
leave. There's an attraction
at that level of 600. It's attractive to
leave. There's an attraction camera.
leave. There's an attraction camera. I'm
sorry.
>> Oh
>> Oh no.
>> Is
>> Is that
>> Is that an
>> Is that an iPod
>> Is that an iPod that
>> Is that an iPod that you
>> Is that an iPod that you got
>> Is that an iPod that you got there?
I
I don't
>> Is that an iPod that you got there?
I don't know
I don't know what
>> Is that an iPod that you got there?
I don't know what an
I don't know what an iPod
>> Is that an iPod that you got there?
I don't know what an iPod is.
>> I
>> I bet
>> I bet they
>> I bet they look
>> I bet they look like
>> I bet they look like that.
>> No,
>> No, that's
>> I bet they look like that.
>> No, that's a
>> No, that's a camera
>> I bet they look like that.
>> No, that's a camera camera.
>> No, that's a camera camera. No,
>> I bet they look like that.
>> No, that's a camera camera. No, iPods
are
are these
are these little
are these little things
are these little things like
are these little things like this.
are these little things like this. This
flat
flat disc
are these little things like this. This
flat disc thing.
>> Oh
>> Oh boy.
>> I
>> I know.
>> Oh boy.
>> I know. They've
>> I know. They've come
>> Oh boy.
>> I know. They've come out
>> I know. They've come out with
>> Oh boy.
>> I know. They've come out with all
>> I know. They've come out with all this
new
new stuff.
new stuff. Huh.
>> You
>> You get
new stuff. Huh.
>> You get a
>> You get a picture
new stuff. Huh.
>> You get a picture first.
>> You get a picture first. Sure.
>> So,
So,
So, uh,
>> thank
>> thank you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Hi,
>> Hi, Dr.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Thank
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Thank you.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Thank you. Uh,
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Thank you. Uh, my
question
question was
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Thank you. Uh, my
question was about,
question was about, uh,
>> thank
>> thank you.
>> thank you. Uh,
>> thank you. Uh, spiritual
>> thank you. Uh, spiritual practice.
>> thank you. Uh, spiritual practice. So,
uh,
uh, maybe
>> thank you. Uh, spiritual practice. So,
uh, maybe you
uh, maybe you could
>> thank you. Uh, spiritual practice. So,
uh, maybe you could help
uh, maybe you could help me
>> thank you. Uh, spiritual practice. So,
uh, maybe you could help me understand
uh, maybe you could help me understand a
little
little bit
little bit better
little bit better about
little bit better about you
little bit better about you living
little bit better about you living life
as
as a
little bit better about you living life
as a prayer.
as a prayer. So,
little bit better about you living life
as a prayer. So, you
as a prayer. So, you know,
little bit better about you living life
as a prayer. So, you know, like
as a prayer. So, you know, like the
Lord's
Lord's prayer.
Lord's prayer. How
Lord's prayer. How do
Lord's prayer. How do you
Lord's prayer. How do you how
Lord's prayer. How do you how would
Lord's prayer. How do you how would I
>> well
>> well what
Lord's prayer. How do you how would I
>> well what does
>> well what does the
Lord's prayer. How do you how would I
>> well what does the word
>> well what does the word prayer
Lord's prayer. How do you how would I
>> well what does the word prayer mean?
>> well what does the word prayer mean? Not
a
a specific
a specific prayer.
a specific prayer. What
a specific prayer. What is
a specific prayer. What is a
a specific prayer. What is a prayer?
a specific prayer. What is a prayer? A
prayer
prayer is
a specific prayer. What is a prayer? A
prayer is a
prayer is a it's
a specific prayer. What is a prayer? A
prayer is a it's a
prayer is a it's a I
a specific prayer. What is a prayer? A
prayer is a it's a I don't
prayer is a it's a I don't think
a specific prayer. What is a prayer? A
prayer is a it's a I don't think I
demonstrated
demonstrated it
demonstrated it the
demonstrated it the way
demonstrated it the way I
demonstrated it the way I live
demonstrated it the way I live it.
demonstrated it the way I live it. Uh
demonstrated it the way I live it. Uh a
prayer
prayer is
demonstrated it the way I live it. Uh a
prayer is like
prayer is like a
demonstrated it the way I live it. Uh a
prayer is like a mudra.
prayer is like a mudra. You
demonstrated it the way I live it. Uh a
prayer is like a mudra. You see
prayer is like a mudra. You see and
demonstrated it the way I live it. Uh a
prayer is like a mudra. You see and a
mudra
mudra is
mudra is a
mudra is a hand
mudra is a hand position.
mudra is a hand position. This
mudra is a hand position. This is
mudra is a hand position. This is one
mudra is a hand position. This is one of
radiance
radiance of
mudra is a hand position. This is one of
radiance of benevolence.
radiance of benevolence. This
mudra is a hand position. This is one of
radiance of benevolence. This is
radiance of benevolence. This is one
mudra is a hand position. This is one of
radiance of benevolence. This is one of
supplication.
supplication. Yes.
supplication. Yes. So
supplication. Yes. So when
supplication. Yes. So when your
supplication. Yes. So when your life
becomes
becomes a
supplication. Yes. So when your life
becomes a prayer,
becomes a prayer, you're
supplication. Yes. So when your life
becomes a prayer, you're surrendered
becomes a prayer, you're surrendered to
divinity.
divinity. You're
divinity. You're surrendered
divinity. You're surrendered to
divinity. You're surrendered to God
and
and your
divinity. You're surrendered to God
and your and
and your and your
divinity. You're surrendered to God
and your and your life
and your and your life is
divinity. You're surrendered to God
and your and your life is lived
and your and your life is lived thusly
at
at a
at a yin
at a yin supplication
at a yin supplication opening
at a yin supplication opening to
at a yin supplication opening to the
will
will of
at a yin supplication opening to the
will of God
will of God and
at a yin supplication opening to the
will of God and invitational.
Well,
Well, divinity
Well, divinity can't
Well, divinity can't refuse
Well, divinity can't refuse a
Well, divinity can't refuse a an
invitation.
So
So if
So if you
So if you live
So if you live your
So if you live your life
So if you live your life as
So if you live your life as what
So if you live your life as what is
So if you live your life as what is thy
will
will for
So if you live your life as what is thy
will for me
will for me oh
So if you live your life as what is thy
will for me oh lord
then
then that
then that that
then that that summons
then that that summons forth
then that that summons forth the
awareness
god
god cannot
god cannot refuse
god cannot refuse oh
god cannot refuse oh supplication
resistance.
resistance. Yeah
god cannot refuse oh supplication
resistance. Yeah the
resistance. Yeah the supplication
god cannot refuse oh supplication
resistance. Yeah the supplication see
activates
activates uh
activates uh the
activates uh the divinity
activates uh the divinity within
activates uh the divinity within you
activates uh the divinity within you to
finesse
finesse an
activates uh the divinity within you to
finesse an answer
finesse an answer out
activates uh the divinity within you to
finesse an answer out of
finesse an answer out of the
activates uh the divinity within you to
finesse an answer out of the universe.
Mhm.
>> So
>> So your
Mhm.
>> So your life
>> So your life becomes
Mhm.
>> So your life becomes a
>> So your life becomes a supplication
asking
asking always
asking always for
asking always for God's
asking always for God's will
asking always for God's will for
asking always for God's will for you
asking always for God's will for you and
the
the humility
asking always for God's will for you and
the humility to
the humility to surrender
asking always for God's will for you and
the humility to surrender to
the humility to surrender to God's
asking always for God's will for you and
the humility to surrender to God's will
becomes
becomes a
becomes a way
becomes a way of
becomes a way of being.
becomes a way of being. Yeah.
>> In
>> In every
becomes a way of being. Yeah.
>> In every activity.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You
>> Yeah. Yeah. You can't
>> Yeah. Yeah. You can't have
>> Yeah. Yeah. You can't have it
>> Yeah. Yeah. You can't have it on
>> Yeah. Yeah. You can't have it on and
off,
off, you
>> Yeah. Yeah. You can't have it on and
off, you know.
>> I
>> I think
>> I think I'll
>> I think I'll answer
>> I think I'll answer the
>> I think I'll answer the first
>> I think I'll answer the first three
people
people nicely
>> I think I'll answer the first three
people nicely and
people nicely and next
>> I think I'll answer the first three
people nicely and next three
people nicely and next three them.
>> I think I'll answer the first three
people nicely and next three them. You
know,
>> either
>> either your
know,
>> either your way
>> either your way is
know,
>> either your way is to
>> either your way is to have,
know,
>> either your way is to have, you
>> either your way is to have, you know,
give
give the
give the best
give the best answer
give the best answer you
give the best answer you can
give the best answer you can because
that's
that's who
give the best answer you can because
that's who you
that's who you are.
give the best answer you can because
that's who you are. So
that's who you are. So you
give the best answer you can because
that's who you are. So you become
that's who you are. So you become the
intention.
>> In
>> In the
intention.
>> In the beginning
>> In the beginning there's
intention.
>> In the beginning there's a
>> In the beginning there's a you
intention.
>> In the beginning there's a you that
>> In the beginning there's a you that has
a
a this
a this intention
a this intention for
a this intention for that
a this intention for that goal.
a this intention for that goal. In
a this intention for that goal. In the
end
end all
a this intention for that goal. In the
end all three
end all three merge
a this intention for that goal. In the
end all three merge and
end all three merge and you
a this intention for that goal. In the
end all three merge and you realize
end all three merge and you realize that
you
you are
you are the
you are the very
you are the very thing
you are the very thing you're
you are the very thing you're asking
for.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Thank you
>> Okay. Thank you very
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Thanks.
>> Your
>> Your existence
>> Your existence is
>> Your existence is the
>> Your existence is the supplication.
>> I
>> I get
>> Your existence is the supplication.
>> I get it.
>> Uhhuh.
God,
God, God
>> Uhhuh.
God, God bless
God, God bless you,
>> Uhhuh.
God, God bless you, David
God, God bless you, David Hawkins,
>> Uhhuh.
God, God bless you, David Hawkins, for
all
all you
all you do
all you do and
all you do and all
all you do and all you've
all you do and all you've given
all you do and all you've given us.
>> Um,
I
I was
I was wondering
I was wondering if
I was wondering if you
I was wondering if you would
I was wondering if you would give
I was wondering if you would give me
I was wondering if you would give me a
calculation
calculation of
I was wondering if you would give me a
calculation of this
calculation of this book.
>> Calibration.
>> Calibration. Yeah.
>> What
>> What does
>> What does she
>> What does she want?
>> She
>> She wants
>> What does she want?
>> She wants a
>> She wants a calibration
>> What does she want?
>> She wants a calibration of
>> She wants a calibration of the
>> What does she want?
>> She wants a calibration of the book.
>> What
>> What book
>> What book is
>> What book is this?
I
I don't
>> What book is this?
I don't give
I don't give calibration
>> What book is this?
I don't give calibration on
I don't give calibration on books.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, we
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, we actually
>> Oh, we actually don't.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I
>> Okay. I would
I
I would
>> Okay. I would
I would like
I would like to
>> Okay. I would
I would like to give
I would like to give this
>> to
>> to you.
>> to you. It's
>> to you. It's a
>> to you. It's a It's
>> to you. It's a It's a
>> to you. It's a It's a song
>> to you. It's a It's a song called
Benedictus
Benedictus that
>> to you. It's a It's a song called
Benedictus that um
I
I find
I find very
I find very u
I find very u powerful.
I find very u powerful. And
I find very u powerful. And so
I find very u powerful. And so I'm
I find very u powerful. And so I'm just
giving
giving it
I find very u powerful. And so I'm just
giving it to
giving it to you
I find very u powerful. And so I'm just
giving it to you to
giving it to you to listen
I find very u powerful. And so I'm just
giving it to you to listen to.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. To
>> Oh. To have.
>> Oh. To have. Yes.
>> Oh. To have. Yes. Yeah.
>> Oh. To have. Yes. Yeah. Thank
>> Oh. To have. Yes. Yeah. Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. And
>> Mhm.
I'm
I'm curious
>> Mhm.
I'm curious about
I'm curious about um
>> Mhm.
I'm curious about um human
I'm curious about um human cloning.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh
>> Uh because
>> Yeah.
>> Uh because you
>> Uh because you said
>> Yeah.
>> Uh because you said nothing
>> Uh because you said nothing comes
>> Yeah.
>> Uh because you said nothing comes except
by
by God.
by God. So
by God. So if
by God. So if we
by God. So if we do
by God. So if we do human
by God. So if we do human cloning,
I
I just
by God. So if we do human cloning,
I just like
I just like to
by God. So if we do human cloning,
I just like to have
I just like to have your
by God. So if we do human cloning,
I just like to have your comments
I just like to have your comments on
that.
that. And
that. And would
that. And would the
that. And would the clones
that. And would the clones have
that. And would the clones have souls?
How
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know. So
>> I don't know. So you're
>> I don't know. So you're you're
>> I don't know. So you're you're posing
>> I don't know. So you're you're posing a
hypothetical
hypothetical question
>> I don't know. So you're you're posing a
hypothetical question and
hypothetical question and the
hypothetical
hypothetical has
hypothetical has no
hypothetical has no answer.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Okay.
hypothetical has no answer.
>> Okay. Okay. Can
>> Okay. Okay. Can I
hypothetical has no answer.
>> Okay. Okay. Can I ask
>> Okay. Okay. Can I ask one
hypothetical has no answer.
>> Okay. Okay. Can I ask one more?
>> Okay. Okay. Can I ask one more? What
would
would be
would be the
would be the soul
would be the soul of
would be the soul of a
would be the soul of a test
would be the soul of a test tube,
would be the soul of a test tube, baby?
I
I don't
would be the soul of a test tube, baby?
I don't know.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, I
>> Yeah, I don't
>> Yeah, I don't know.
>> And
>> And your
>> Yeah, I don't know.
>> And your soul
>> And your soul floating
>> Yeah, I don't know.
>> And your soul floating around
>> And your soul floating around without
>> Yeah, I don't know.
>> And your soul floating around without a
body,
body, I
body, I suppose.
body, I suppose. Suck
body, I suppose. Suck right
body, I suppose. Suck right into
body, I suppose. Suck right into that
test
test tube
body, I suppose. Suck right into that
test tube and
test tube and said,
body, I suppose. Suck right into that
test tube and said, "Give
test tube and said, "Give me
body, I suppose. Suck right into that
test tube and said, "Give me give
test tube and said, "Give me give me
>> Could
>> Could you
>> Could you explain
>> Could you explain to
>> Could you explain to me
>> Could you explain to me a
>> Could you explain to me a little
>> Could you explain to me a little bit
more
more about
>> Could you explain to me a little bit
more about Jesus
more about Jesus Christ
>> Could you explain to me a little bit
more about Jesus Christ being
more about Jesus Christ being a
>> Could you explain to me a little bit
more about Jesus Christ being a a
savior?
savior? How
savior? How and
savior? How and what
savior? How and what what
savior? How and what what does
savior? How and what what does that
actually
actually mean?"
>> You're
>> You're not
>> You're not familiar
>> You're not familiar with
>> You're not familiar with Christianity.
>> Pardon?
>> You're
>> You're not
>> You're not familiar
>> You're not familiar with
>> You're not familiar with Christianity.
Well,
Well, I'm
>> You're not familiar with Christianity.
Well, I'm familiar
Well, I'm familiar with
>> You're not familiar with Christianity.
Well, I'm familiar with the
Well, I'm familiar with the orth
orthodox
orthodox Christianity
orthodox Christianity which
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Orthodox
orthodox Christianity which
>> Yes. Orthodox says
>> Yes. Orthodox says that
orthodox Christianity which
>> Yes. Orthodox says that he's
>> Yes. Orthodox says that he's a
orthodox Christianity which
>> Yes. Orthodox says that he's a savior.
Correct.
>> Yeah.
>> He
>> He is
>> He is your
>> He is your advocate
>> He is your advocate before
>> He is your advocate before the
>> He is your advocate before the father.
Those
Those who
uh
uh dedicate
uh dedicate himself
uh dedicate himself to
uh dedicate himself to Jesus
uh dedicate himself to Jesus Christ.
uh dedicate himself to Jesus Christ. He
will
will act
uh dedicate himself to Jesus Christ. He
will act on
will act on their
uh dedicate himself to Jesus Christ. He
will act on their behalf.
uh
uh in
uh in Buddhism
uh in Buddhism there
uh in Buddhism there is
uh in Buddhism there is a
uh in Buddhism there is a similar
uh in Buddhism there is a similar uh
aspect
aspect of
uh in Buddhism there is a similar uh
aspect of the
aspect of the Buddha
who
who acts
who acts as
who acts as your
who acts as your savior
that
that in
who acts as your savior
that in other
that in other words
who acts as your savior
that in other words by
that in other words by aligning
who acts as your savior
that in other words by aligning yourself
with
with that
with that which
with that which calibrates
with that which calibrates at
with that which calibrates at 1,00
with that which calibrates at 1,00 you
then
then you
with that which calibrates at 1,00 you
then you might
then you might say
with that which calibrates at 1,00 you
then you might say karmically
then you might say karmically have
with that which calibrates at 1,00 you
then you might say karmically have the
right
right that
right that he
right that he will
right that he will speak
right that he will speak for
right that he will speak for you
right that he will speak for you speak
for
for you.
So
So you
>> yes
>> those
>> those that
>> those that have
>> those that have align
>> those that have align themselves
>> those that have align themselves with
Jesus
Jesus then
>> those that have align themselves with
Jesus then yes
Jesus then yes they
>> those that have align themselves with
Jesus then yes they don't
Jesus then yes they don't have
>> those that have align themselves with
Jesus then yes they don't have to
Jesus then yes they don't have to go
>> those that have align themselves with
Jesus then yes they don't have to go all
the
the way
the way themselves
the way themselves with
the way themselves with to
the way themselves with to enlightenment
>> it's
>> it's like
>> salvation
>> salvation is
>> salvation is a
>> salvation is a different
>> salvation is a different goal
>> salvation is a different goal than
enlightenment
enlightenment heaven
>> salvation is a different goal than
enlightenment heaven the
enlightenment heaven the he
>> salvation is a different goal than
enlightenment heaven the he heavens
calibrate
calibrate in
calibrate in the
calibrate in the 600
calibrate in the 600 enlightenment
calibrate in the 600 enlightenment at
the
the thousand
calibrate in the 600 enlightenment at
the thousand doesn't
the thousand doesn't say
calibrate in the 600 enlightenment at
the thousand doesn't say you
the thousand doesn't say you have
calibrate in the 600 enlightenment at
the thousand doesn't say you have to
become
become a
become a Jesus
become a Jesus Christ
become a Jesus Christ or
become a Jesus Christ or a
become a Jesus Christ or a Buddha
become a Jesus Christ or a Buddha the
celestial
celestial realms
become a Jesus Christ or a Buddha the
celestial realms are
celestial realms are at
become a Jesus Christ or a Buddha the
celestial realms are at 600
celestial realms are at 600 so
become a Jesus Christ or a Buddha the
celestial realms are at 600 so if
celestial realms are at 600 so if you
calibrate
calibrate 520
where
where you
calibrate 520
where you going
where you going to
calibrate 520
where you going to go
where you going to go when
calibrate 520
where you going to go when you
where you going to go when you get
calibrate 520
where you going to go when you get there
under
under Jesus
under Jesus arm.
under Jesus arm. I
under Jesus arm. I speak
under Jesus arm. I speak for
under Jesus arm. I speak for her.
under Jesus arm. I speak for her. She
under Jesus arm. I speak for her. She is
mine.
mine. You
under Jesus arm. I speak for her. She is
mine. You already
mine. You already raised
under Jesus arm. I speak for her. She is
mine. You already raised your
mine. You already raised your oric
vibration
vibration and
vibration and you
vibration and you now
vibration and you now may
vibration and you now may enter
vibration and you now may enter the
celestial
celestial realm.
vibration and you now may enter the
celestial realm. Yeah,
celestial realm. Yeah, that's
vibration and you now may enter the
celestial realm. Yeah, that's a
celestial realm. Yeah, that's a correct
explanation.
explanation. Resist.
That
That ought
explanation. Resist.
That ought to
That ought to get
explanation. Resist.
That ought to get me
That ought to get me a
explanation. Resist.
That ought to get me a DDD
That ought to get me a DDD something.
Doctor
Doctor of
Doctor of the
Doctor of the church,
Doctor of the church, divinity
Doctor of the church, divinity degree.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
Doctor of the church, divinity degree.
>> Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you
Doctor of the church, divinity degree.
>> Thank you. Thank you for
>> Thank you. Thank you for pushing
Doctor of the church, divinity degree.
>> Thank you. Thank you for pushing me
>> Thank you. Thank you for pushing me over
the
the edge,
the edge, you
the edge, you know.
>> Well,
>> Well, you
the edge, you know.
>> Well, you know
>> Well, you know certain
the edge, you know.
>> Well, you know certain things
>> Well, you know certain things just
the edge, you know.
>> Well, you know certain things just that
you
you haven't
you haven't put
you haven't put them
you haven't put them into
you haven't put them into words,
you haven't put them into words, you
know.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you both.
I
I had
>> Thank you both.
I had a
I had a subjective
>> Thank you both.
I had a subjective experience
I had a subjective experience about
>> Thank you both.
I had a subjective experience about 30
years
years ago
that
that was
years ago
that was a
that was a little
years ago
that was a little hard
that was a little hard to
years ago
that was a little hard to swallow
and
and I
and I just
and I just wanted
to
to tell
and I just wanted
to tell you
to tell you what
and I just wanted
to tell you what it
to tell you what it was
and
and see
and see if
and see if you
and see if you have
and see if you have any
and see if you have any thoughts
and see if you have any thoughts about
it.
Um,
Um, I
Um, I was
Um, I was in
Um, I was in a
Um, I was in a seminar
and
and I
Um, I was in a seminar
and I was
and I was really
Um, I was in a seminar
and I was really really
and I was really really bored
Um, I was in a seminar
and I was really really bored out
and I was really really bored out of
Um, I was in a seminar
and I was really really bored out of my
mind.
today.
I
I have
I have to
I have to turn
I have to turn in
I have to turn in my
I have to turn in my DD
I have to turn in my DD now.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Go
I have to turn in my DD now.
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> And
>> And it
>> And it was
>> And it was very
>> And it was very late
>> And it was very late at
>> And it was very late at night
>> And it was very late at night and
everyone
everyone just
>> And it was very late at night and
everyone just wanted
everyone just wanted to
>> And it was very late at night and
everyone just wanted to leave
>> and
>> and I
>> and I was
>> and I was sitting
>> and I was sitting in
>> and I was sitting in that
>> and I was sitting in that experience
>> and I was sitting in that experience in
my
my seat.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Yeah. And then
>> Yeah. And then all
>> Yeah. And then all of
>> Yeah. And then all of a
>> Yeah. And then all of a sudden
>> Yeah. And then all of a sudden I
>> Yeah. And then all of a sudden I kind
>> Yeah. And then all of a sudden I kind of
shifted
and
and the
and the entire
and the entire room
and the entire room I
and the entire room I had
and the entire room I had the
and the entire room I had the experience
that
that the
and the entire room I had the experience
that the entire
that the entire room
and the entire room I had the experience
that the entire room was
that the entire room was inside
and the entire room I had the experience
that the entire room was inside my
that the entire room was inside my head.
>> Super.
>> And
>> And then
>> Super.
>> And then when
>> And then when someone
>> Super.
>> And then when someone stood
>> And then when someone stood up
>> Super.
>> And then when someone stood up to
>> And then when someone stood up to ask
>> Super.
>> And then when someone stood up to ask a
question,
question, I
question, I knew
question, I knew exactly
question, I knew exactly what
question, I knew exactly what they
question, I knew exactly what they were
going
going to
question, I knew exactly what they were
going to say.
>> Oh
>> Oh yeah.
>> Oh yeah. You're
>> Oh yeah. You're a
>> Oh yeah. You're a psychic
>> Oh yeah. You're a psychic at
>> Oh yeah. You're a psychic at the
>> Oh yeah. You're a psychic at the time,
huh?
huh? Clairvoyant.
>> Oh yeah. You're a psychic at the time,
huh? Clairvoyant. Yeah.
>> And
>> And then
>> And then the
>> And then the answer
>> And then the answer I
>> And then the answer I knew
>> And then the answer I knew exactly
>> And then the answer I knew exactly too.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> And then the answer I knew exactly too.
>> Yeah. Mhm. But
>> Yeah. Mhm. But it
>> And then the answer I knew exactly too.
>> Yeah. Mhm. But it was
>> Yeah. Mhm. But it was the
>> And then the answer I knew exactly too.
>> Yeah. Mhm. But it was the sensation
>> Yeah. Mhm. But it was the sensation that
it
it was
it was like
it was like sitting
it was like sitting in
it was like sitting in my
it was like sitting in my head.
>> Yeah.
>> Like
>> Like my
>> Like my mind.
>> Mhm.
>> And
>> And then
>> And then I
>> And then I said,
>> And then I said, "Well,
if
if I
>> And then I said, "Well,
if I can
if I can do
>> And then I said, "Well,
if I can do this,
if I can do this, I
>> And then I said, "Well,
if I can do this, I can
if I can do this, I can move
>> And then I said, "Well,
if I can do this, I can move outside
if I can do this, I can move outside of
my
my body."
>> Right.
>> So
>> So then
>> So then I
>> So then I moved
>> So then I moved outside
and
and went
>> So then I moved outside
and went to
and went to the
>> So then I moved outside
and went to the window
and went to the window and
>> So then I moved outside
and went to the window and I'm
and went to the window and I'm thinking
I
I knew
I knew there
I knew there was
I knew there was a
I knew there was a street
I knew there was a street out
I knew there was a street out there
because
because I
I knew there was a street out there
because I was
because I was in
I knew there was a street out there
because I was in New
because I was in New York
I knew there was a street out there
because I was in New York City
because I was in New York City with
I knew there was a street out there
because I was in New York City with cars
and
and that's
and that's what
and that's what I
and that's what I was
and that's what I was going
and that's what I was going to
and that's what I was going to see.
and that's what I was going to see. But
when
when I
and that's what I was going to see. But
when I went
when I went outside
and that's what I was going to see. But
when I went outside the
when I went outside the window,
and that's what I was going to see. But
when I went outside the window, it
when I went outside the window, it was
the
the universe.
>> It
>> It was
the universe.
>> It was the
>> It was the night
the universe.
>> It was the night sky
>> It was the night sky with
the universe.
>> It was the night sky with the
>> It was the night sky with the stars.
>> Mhm.
>> And
>> And it
>> Mhm.
>> And it was
>> And it was as
>> Mhm.
>> And it was as if
>> And it was as if this
>> Mhm.
>> And it was as if this room
>> And it was as if this room was
>> Mhm.
>> And it was as if this room was floating
in
in that.
>> Yeah.
>> And
>> And then
>> And then at
>> And then at that
>> And then at that time
>> And then at that time I
>> And then at that time I got
>> And then at that time I got so
incredibly
incredibly scared.
>> Mhm.
>> I
>> I moved
>> Mhm.
>> I moved back
>> I moved back down
>> Mhm.
>> I moved back down into
>> I moved back down into my
>> Mhm.
>> I moved back down into my body
>> I moved back down into my body and
>> Mhm.
>> I moved back down into my body and I
>> I moved back down into my body and I was
again
again sitting
again sitting in
again sitting in my
again sitting in my seat
again sitting in my seat separate
again sitting in my seat separate from
everybody
everybody again.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, that
>> Yeah, that was
>> Yeah, that was great.
>> It
>> It was.
>> Yeah, that was great.
>> It was. But
>> It was. But it
>> Yeah, that was great.
>> It was. But it it
>> It was. But it it makes
>> Yeah, that was great.
>> It was. But it it makes me
>> It was. But it it makes me wonder
>> Yeah, that was great.
>> It was. But it it makes me wonder about
the
the mind
the mind and
the mind and about
the mind and about thoughts.
the mind and about thoughts. I
the mind and about thoughts. I mean
>> about
>> about what
>> about the
>> about the mind?
>> about the mind? What
>> about the mind? What is
>> about the mind? What is the
>> about the mind? What is the mind
>> about the mind? What is the mind and
what
what are
>> about the mind? What is the mind and
what are thoughts?
what are thoughts? You
>> about the mind? What is the mind and
what are thoughts? You know
what are thoughts? You know it
because
because the
because the experience
>> you
>> you had
because the experience
>> you had the
>> you had the experience
because the experience
>> you had the experience since
>> not
>> not like
>> not like that.
>> not like that. No
>> no
>> no out
>> not like that. No
>> no out of
>> no out of body
>> not like that. No
>> no out of body experience.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So
>> Yeah. So out
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So out of
>> Yeah. So out of body
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So out of body experiences
>> Yeah. So out of body experiences are
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So out of body experiences are of
a
a great
a great variety.
a great variety. You
a great variety. You know
a great variety. You know the
a great variety. You know the experience
is
is you
a great variety. You know the experience
is you know
is you know very
a great variety. You know the experience
is you know very different
is you know very different from
a great variety. You know the experience
is you know very different from in
multiple
multiple people.
Um,
Um, it
multiple people.
Um, it can
Um, it can take
multiple people.
Um, it can take a
Um, it can take a great
multiple people.
Um, it can take a great variety
Um, it can take a great variety of
forms.
forms. Traveling
forms. Traveling distances,
forms. Traveling distances, going
forms. Traveling distances, going going
various
various places,
it
it can
it can be
it can be spontaneous
it can be spontaneous or
it can be spontaneous or you
it can be spontaneous or you can
actually
actually learn
it can be spontaneous or you can
actually learn how
actually learn how to
it can be spontaneous or you can
actually learn how to do
actually learn how to do it
valitionally.
valitionally. If
valitionally. If you
valitionally. If you do
valitionally. If you do Monroe
valitionally. If you do Monroe Institute
training,
training, you
valitionally. If you do Monroe Institute
training, you can
training, you can learn
valitionally. If you do Monroe Institute
training, you can learn how
training, you can learn how to
valitionally. If you do Monroe Institute
training, you can learn how to do
training, you can learn how to do it
valitionally. If you do Monroe Institute
training, you can learn how to do it at
will.
will. Um,
will. Um, so
will. Um, so it's
will. Um, so it's one
will. Um, so it's one thing
will. Um, so it's one thing you
will. Um, so it's one thing you learn
about
about it
will. Um, so it's one thing you learn
about it is
about it is you're
will. Um, so it's one thing you learn
about it is you're not
about it is you're not just
will. Um, so it's one thing you learn
about it is you're not just the
about it is you're not just the body.
One
One thing
One thing that
One thing that you
One thing that you learn
One thing that you learn about
One thing that you learn about it
One thing that you learn about it is
that
that you're
One thing that you learn about it is
that you're spirit.
The
The interesting
The interesting thing
The interesting thing I
The interesting thing I always
The interesting thing I always thought
was
was when
The interesting thing I always thought
was when you're
was when you're out
The interesting thing I always thought
was when you're out of
was when you're out of body,
The interesting thing I always thought
was when you're out of body, you
was when you're out of body, you can
think,
think, feel,
think, feel, and
think, feel, and hear.
think, feel, and hear. And
think, feel, and hear. And and
think, feel, and hear. And and there's
think, feel, and hear. And and there's a
sense
sense of
think, feel, and hear. And and there's a
sense of self
sense of self the
think, feel, and hear. And and there's a
sense of self the same
sense of self the same as
think, feel, and hear. And and there's a
sense of self the same as when
sense of self the same as when you're
think, feel, and hear. And and there's a
sense of self the same as when you're in
a
a body.
>> Yeah.
>> So
>> So if
>> Yeah.
>> So if you
>> So if you don't
>> Yeah.
>> So if you don't have
>> So if you don't have any
>> Yeah.
>> So if you don't have any when
>> So if you don't have any when you're
>> Yeah.
>> So if you don't have any when you're out
of
of body,
of body, you
of body, you don't
of body, you don't have
of body, you don't have any
of body, you don't have any eyeballs
of body, you don't have any eyeballs or
ears.
ears. So
of body, you don't have any eyeballs or
ears. So how
ears. So how in
of body, you don't have any eyeballs or
ears. So how in the
ears. So how in the world
of body, you don't have any eyeballs or
ears. So how in the world do
ears. So how in the world do you
of body, you don't have any eyeballs or
ears. So how in the world do you hear
and
and see?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Oh.
and see?
>> Yeah. Oh. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Oh. Yeah. So
and see?
>> Yeah. Oh. Yeah. So those
>> Yeah. Oh. Yeah. So those uh
and see?
>> Yeah. Oh. Yeah. So those uh powers
>> Yeah. Oh. Yeah. So those uh powers are
within
within the
within the spirit
within the spirit and
within the spirit and not
within the spirit and not within
within the spirit and not within the
body.
body. So
within the spirit and not within the
body. So the
body. So the body
within the spirit and not within the
body. So the body is
body. So the body is only
within the spirit and not within the
body. So the body is only the
body. So the body is only the linear
expression
expression of
expression of a
expression of a faculty
expression of a faculty which
expression of a faculty which is
expression of a faculty which is innate
to
to the
expression of a faculty which is innate
to the spirit.
to the spirit. Every
expression of a faculty which is innate
to the spirit. Every time
to the spirit. Every time I've
expression of a faculty which is innate
to the spirit. Every time I've not
to the spirit. Every time I've not a
body
body spontaneous
body spontaneous or
body spontaneous or by
body spontaneous or by training
body spontaneous or by training you
body spontaneous or by training you see
and
and hear
body spontaneous or by training you see
and hear and
and hear and think
body spontaneous or by training you see
and hear and think and
and hear and think and feel
body spontaneous or by training you see
and hear and think and feel the
and hear and think and feel the same
body spontaneous or by training you see
and hear and think and feel the same as
anything.
>> Yep.
>> Right.
>> So
>> So you
>> Right.
>> So you at least
>> So you at least one
>> Right.
>> So you at least one thing
>> So you at least one thing I
>> Right.
>> So you at least one thing I know
>> So you at least one thing I know is
you're
you're not
you're not a
you're not a just
you're not a just a
you're not a just a physical
you're not a just a physical body.
>> So
>> So maybe
you're not a just a physical body.
>> So maybe that
>> So maybe that was
you're not a just a physical body.
>> So maybe that was the
>> So maybe that was the lesson
you're not a just a physical body.
>> So maybe that was the lesson that
>> So maybe that was the lesson that you
were
were to
were to learn.
>> And
>> And you
were to learn.
>> And you can
>> And you can have
were to learn.
>> And you can have wonderful
>> And you can have wonderful uh
were to learn.
>> And you can have wonderful uh wonderful
experiences.
experiences. Susan
experiences. Susan who
experiences. Susan who goes
experiences. Susan who goes out
experiences. Susan who goes out of
experiences. Susan who goes out of body
a
a long
experiences. Susan who goes out of body
a long time
a long time if
experiences. Susan who goes out of body
a long time if you
a long time if you don't
experiences. Susan who goes out of body
a long time if you don't keep
a long time if you don't keep her
experiences. Susan who goes out of body
a long time if you don't keep her tight
tight
tight in
tight in there
making
making a
tight in there
making a frying
making a frying a
tight in there
making a frying a hamburger
making a frying a hamburger in
tight in there
making a frying a hamburger in the
middle
middle she
middle she takes
middle she takes off
middle she takes off and
middle she takes off and what
middle she takes off and what about
hamburg
but
but some
but some people
but some people go
but some people go out
but some people go out of
but some people go out of body
but some people go out of body easily
some
some people
but some people go out of body easily
some people it's
some people it's infrequent
but some people go out of body easily
some people it's infrequent I
some people it's infrequent I think
there's
there's a
there's a spiritual
there's a spiritual lesson
there's a spiritual lesson also
there's a spiritual lesson also it
there's a spiritual lesson also it may
only
only happen
there's a spiritual lesson also it may
only happen a
only happen a couple
there's a spiritual lesson also it may
only happen a couple of
only happen a couple of times
there's a spiritual lesson also it may
only happen a couple of times and
only happen a couple of times and and
you
you got
you got what
you got what it
you got what it means
you got what it means that
you got what it means that that
you got what it means that that which
you
you are
you got what it means that that which
you are is
you are is an
you got what it means that that which
you are is an energy
you are is an energy field
you got what it means that that which
you are is an energy field that
you are is an energy field that you
aren't
aren't just
aren't just a
aren't just a physical
aren't just a physical body
aren't just a physical body that
aren't just a physical body that that
which
which you
aren't just a physical body that that
which you are
which you are is
aren't just a physical body that that
which you are is something
which you are is something beyond
aren't just a physical body that that
which you are is something beyond the
limitation
limitation of
limitation of the
limitation of the physical
limitation of the physical domain.
limitation of the physical domain. It
may
may be
limitation of the physical domain. It
may be that's
may be that's all
limitation of the physical domain. It
may be that's all that
may be that's all that was
limitation of the physical domain. It
may be that's all that was in
may be that's all that was in karmically
uh
uh necessary
uh necessary to
uh necessary to learn
uh necessary to learn from
uh necessary to learn from the
experience.
experience. Yeah.
>> And
>> And then
>> And then in
>> And then in terms
>> And then in terms of
>> And then in terms of thoughts,
>> And then in terms of thoughts, I've
>> And then in terms of thoughts, I've had
the
the experience
>> And then in terms of thoughts, I've had
the experience of
the experience of my
>> And then in terms of thoughts, I've had
the experience of my thoughts
the experience of my thoughts being
>> And then in terms of thoughts, I've had
the experience of my thoughts being a
conversation
conversation outside
conversation outside of
conversation outside of me
conversation outside of me that
conversation outside of me that I
conversation outside of me that I was
observing
observing and
conversation outside of me that I was
observing and listening
observing and listening to.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So
>> Yeah. So that's
>> Yeah. So that's all
>> Yeah. So that's all part
>> Yeah. So that's all part of
>> Yeah. So that's all part of the
>> Yeah. So that's all part of the same
phenomenon.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> And
>> And then
>> And then what
>> And then what you
>> And then what you know
>> And then what you know it's
>> there
>> there cert
>> And then what you know it's
>> there cert what
>> there cert what they
>> And then what you know it's
>> there cert what they call
>> there cert what they call paranormal
phenomena.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. And
phenomena.
>> Okay. And in
>> Okay. And in the
phenomena.
>> Okay. And in the 570s
>> Okay. And in the 570s they're
phenomena.
>> Okay. And in the 570s they're very
common.
common. You
common. You know
common. You know you're
common. You know you're clairvoyant
common. You know you're clairvoyant have
chlor
chlor audience.
common. You know you're clairvoyant have
chlor audience. You
chlor audience. You can
common. You know you're clairvoyant have
chlor audience. You can leave
chlor audience. You can leave the
common. You know you're clairvoyant have
chlor audience. You can leave the body
and
and go
and go down
and go down the
and go down the highway
and go down the highway 50
and go down the highway 50 miles
and go down the highway 50 miles and
and go down the highway 50 miles and see
there's
there's a
and go down the highway 50 miles and see
there's a filling
there's a filling station
and go down the highway 50 miles and see
there's a filling station on
there's a filling station on the
and go down the highway 50 miles and see
there's a filling station on the right
hand
hand side
hand side and
hand side and come
hand side and come back
hand side and come back in
hand side and come back in the
hand side and come back in the body.
hand side and come back in the body. But
so
so some
hand side and come back in the body. But
so some people
so some people are
hand side and come back in the body. But
so some people are born
so some people are born with
hand side and come back in the body. But
so some people are born with that
so some people are born with that are
sort
sort of
sort of innately
sort of innately that
sort of innately that way.
sort of innately that way. Sometimes
even
even runs
sort of innately that way. Sometimes
even runs in
even runs in families.
sort of innately that way. Sometimes
even runs in families. The
even runs in families. The mother's
clairvoyant
clairvoyant and
clairvoyant and the
clairvoyant and the daughter
clairvoyant and the daughter is
clairvoyant and the daughter is also
clairvoyant.
clairvoyant. It's
clairvoyant and the daughter is also
clairvoyant. It's pretty
clairvoyant. It's pretty common.
>> Yeah.
And
And then
>> Yeah.
And then coming
And then coming back
>> Yeah.
And then coming back to
And then coming back to it
>> Yeah.
And then coming back to it being
And then coming back to it being of
surrender
surrender to
surrender to God's
surrender to God's will.
surrender to God's will. So
surrender to God's will. So that
>> anything
that
that I'm
that I'm experiencing
that I'm experiencing or
that I'm experiencing or the
that I'm experiencing or the body
that I'm experiencing or the body or
anything
anything are
that I'm experiencing or the body or
anything are here
anything are here as
that I'm experiencing or the body or
anything are here as a
anything are here as a vehicle
that I'm experiencing or the body or
anything are here as a vehicle to
surrender
surrender to
surrender to his
surrender to his will.
surrender to his will. And
surrender to his will. And it's
>> sometimes
>> sometimes I
surrender to his will. And it's
>> sometimes I question,
>> sometimes I question, okay,
surrender to his will. And it's
>> sometimes I question, okay, I've
surrendered
surrendered to
surrendered to God's
surrendered to God's will.
>> Yes.
>> You
>> You know,
>> You know, or
>> You know, or is
>> You know, or is this
>> You know, or is this just
>> You know, or is this just my
>> You know, or is this just my ego
>> You know, or is this just my ego saying,
hey,
hey, I'm
>> You know, or is this just my ego saying,
hey, I'm just
hey, I'm just going
>> You know, or is this just my ego saying,
hey, I'm just going to
hey, I'm just going to be
>> You know, or is this just my ego saying,
hey, I'm just going to be on
hey, I'm just going to be on the
>> You know, or is this just my ego saying,
hey, I'm just going to be on the side
hey, I'm just going to be on the side of
the
the good
the good guy.
the good guy. Well,
the good guy. Well, you
the good guy. Well, you you
the good guy. Well, you you keep
the good guy. Well, you you keep it
the good guy. Well, you you keep it up
as
as a
the good guy. Well, you you keep it up
as a position
as a position a
the good guy. Well, you you keep it up
as a position a position
as a position a position and
the good guy. Well, you you keep it up
as a position a position and no
as a position a position and no matter
what
what arises
what arises you
what arises you surrender
what arises you surrender to
what arises you surrender to God
what arises you surrender to God and
what arises you surrender to God and ask
you
you know
what arises you surrender to God and ask
you know by
you know by supplication
what arises you surrender to God and ask
you know by supplication that's
you know by supplication that's what
what arises you surrender to God and ask
you know by supplication that's what I
say
say to
say to live
say to live your
say to live your life
say to live your life as
say to live your life as a
say to live your life as a prayer
say to live your life as a prayer is
like
like a
say to live your life as a prayer is
like a mudra
like a mudra in
say to live your life as a prayer is
like a mudra in which
like a mudra in which you
say to live your life as a prayer is
like a mudra in which you are
like a mudra in which you are like
continuously
continuously positioning
continuously positioning yourself
continuously positioning yourself as
asking
>> consistently
>> what
>> what does
>> consistently
>> what does that
>> what does that mean
>> consistently
>> what does that mean oh
>> what does that mean oh lord
>> consistently
>> what does that mean oh lord you
>> what does that mean oh lord you prayer
pray
pray to
pray to god
pray to god for
pray to god for an
pray to god for an understanding
pray to god for an understanding of
pray to god for an understanding of the
meaning
meaning and
pray to god for an understanding of the
meaning and the
meaning and the significance
pray to god for an understanding of the
meaning and the significance of
meaning and the significance of the
experience
experience okay
experience okay do
experience okay do that
>> and
>> and the
experience okay do that
>> and the communication
>> and the communication comes
experience okay do that
>> and the communication comes back
>> and the communication comes back to
experience okay do that
>> and the communication comes back to you
>> the
>> the knowingness
>> the knowingness comes
>> the knowingness comes back
>> the knowingness comes back not
>> the knowingness comes back not like
>> the knowingness comes back not like a
communication
communication it
>> the knowingness comes back not like a
communication it comes
communication it comes to
>> the knowingness comes back not like a
communication it comes to the
communication it comes to the knowing
knowing.
>> You're
>> You're thinking
knowing.
>> You're thinking of
>> You're thinking of it
knowing.
>> You're thinking of it conversationally.
It's
It's conversational.
>> Say
>> Say it.
>> Mhm.
>> No,
>> No, it's
>> Mhm.
>> No, it's a
>> No, it's a knowingness.
>> Mhm.
>> No, it's a knowingness. Yeah.
>> No, it's a knowingness. Yeah. Okay.
>> All
>> All of a
>> All of a sudden,
>> All of a sudden, you're
>> All of a sudden, you're walking
>> All of a sudden, you're walking along,
you're
you're not
>> All of a sudden, you're walking along,
you're not even
you're not even thinking
>> All of a sudden, you're walking along,
you're not even thinking about
you're not even thinking about it.
>> All of a sudden, you're walking along,
you're not even thinking about it. And
what
what it
what it all
what it all means
what it all means is
what it all means is just
what it all means is just obvious.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. We
>> Yes. We got
>> Yes. We got to
>> Yes. We got to get
>> Yes. We got to get moving.
>> All
>> All right.
We
We move
We move as
We move as fast
We move as fast as
We move as fast as we
We move as fast as we can.
>> I'm
>> I'm a
We move as fast as we can.
>> I'm a student.
>> Yeah.
>> Hi,
>> Hi, Dave.
I've
I've been
I've been on
I've been on the
I've been on the path
I've been on the path seeking
I've been on the path seeking peace
I've been on the path seeking peace of
heart
heart and
I've been on the path seeking peace of
heart and peace
heart and peace of
I've been on the path seeking peace of
heart and peace of mind
heart and peace of mind for
I've been on the path seeking peace of
heart and peace of mind for 30
heart and peace of mind for 30 years.
And
And I
And I tried
And I tried it
And I tried it all
And I tried it all from
unionism
unionism to
And I tried it all from
unionism to Cabala
unionism to Cabala to
And I tried it all from
unionism to Cabala to Course
unionism to Cabala to Course of
And I tried it all from
unionism to Cabala to Course of Miracles
and
and everything.
and everything. and
and everything. and and
and everything. and and and
and everything. and and and your
teachings
teachings and
understandings
understandings and
understandings and showing
understandings and showing me
understandings and showing me what
understandings and showing me what the
nature
nature of
understandings and showing me what the
nature of all
nature of all this
understandings and showing me what the
nature of all this is.
nature of all this is. It's
understandings and showing me what the
nature of all this is. It's through
your
your teaching,
your teaching, teaching
your teaching, teaching me
your teaching, teaching me how
your teaching, teaching me how to
recontextualize
my
my so-called
my so-called seeming
my so-called seeming bad,
my so-called seeming bad, evil,
horrendous
horrendous childhood.
>> I've
>> I've gotten
>> I've gotten over
>> I've gotten over that.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. I
>> I've gotten over that.
>> Uhhuh. I don't
>> Uhhuh. I don't hate
>> I've gotten over that.
>> Uhhuh. I don't hate myself
>> Uhhuh. I don't hate myself anymore.
>> I've gotten over that.
>> Uhhuh. I don't hate myself anymore. I
don't
don't hate
don't hate her.
don't hate her. I've
>> I
>> I don't
don't hate her. I've
>> I don't have
>> I don't have a
don't hate her. I've
>> I don't have a grudge.
>> I don't have a grudge. I've
don't hate her. I've
>> I don't have a grudge. I've I've
>> I don't have a grudge. I've I've just
put
put it
put it aside
put it aside and
put it aside and it's
put it aside and it's over.
>> Okay.
>> Is
>> Is Is
>> Is Is all
>> Is Is all that
>> Is Is all that karma
>> Is Is all that karma over
>> Is Is all that karma over because
>> Is Is all that karma over because I
>> Is Is all that karma over because I say
it's
it's over?
>> Is Is all that karma over because I say
it's over? Do
it's over? Do I
>> Is Is all that karma over because I say
it's over? Do I have
it's over? Do I have that
>> Is Is all that karma over because I say
it's over? Do I have that power
it's over? Do I have that power or
>> Yes.
>> Yes. The
>> Yes. The willingness
>> Yes. The willingness the
>> Yes. The willingness the willingness
>> Yes. The willingness the willingness to
totally
totally for
>> Yes. The willingness the willingness to
totally for forgive
totally for forgive it?
>> Undo
>> Undo it.
>> Undo it. That's
>> Undo it. That's all
>> Undo it. That's all that's
>> Undo it. That's all that's necessary.
>> They
>> They don't
>> Undo it. That's all that's necessary.
>> They don't have
>> They don't have all
>> Undo it. That's all that's necessary.
>> They don't have all these
>> They don't have all these other
>> Undo it. That's all that's necessary.
>> They don't have all these other players.
They
They don't
They don't have
They don't have any
They don't have any problem.
They don't have any problem. They've
They don't have any problem. They've got
their
their own
They don't have any problem. They've got
their own problems.
>> But
>> But you're
>> But you're you're
>> But you're you're part
>> But you're you're part of
>> But you're you're part of it.
>> But you're you're part of it. You're
part
part of
>> But you're you're part of it. You're
part of it.
>> My
>> My lesson
>> My lesson and
>> My lesson and my
>> My lesson and my dead
>> My lesson and my dead is
>> My lesson and my dead is over.
>> You're
>> You're done
>> My lesson and my dead is over.
>> You're done with
>> You're done with it.
>> My lesson and my dead is over.
>> You're done with it. You're
>> You're done with it. You're done
>> My lesson and my dead is over.
>> You're done with it. You're done with
it.
>> That's
>> That's what
it.
>> That's what I
>> That's what I wanted
it.
>> That's what I wanted to
>> That's what I wanted to hear.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You're
>> Yeah. You're done.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
I
I need
>> Yeah.
I need to
I need to make
>> Yeah.
I need to make an
I need to make an announcement
>> Yeah.
I need to make an announcement that
somebody
somebody lost
somebody lost a
somebody lost a wallet,
somebody lost a wallet, a
somebody lost a wallet, a Gregory,
somebody lost a wallet, a Gregory, and
it's
it's in
somebody lost a wallet, a Gregory, and
it's in the
it's in the uh
somebody lost a wallet, a Gregory, and
it's in the uh office
it's in the uh office right
somebody lost a wallet, a Gregory, and
it's in the uh office right now.
it's in the uh office right now. If
somebody lost a wallet, a Gregory, and
it's in the uh office right now. If you
and
and it
and it had
and it had no
and it had no money,
and it had no money, when
and it had no money, when it
>> What
>> What are
and it had no money, when it
>> What are they
>> What are they doing?
>> We're
>> We're doing
>> We're doing a
>> We're doing a picture,
>> but
>> but I'm
>> We're doing a picture,
>> but I'm meaning
>> but I'm meaning we're
>> We're doing a picture,
>> but I'm meaning we're waiting
>> but I'm meaning we're waiting a
>> We're doing a picture,
>> but I'm meaning we're waiting a second.
Oh,
Oh, just
Oh, just the
Oh, just the two
Oh, just the two of
Oh, just the two of us.
Oh, just the two of us. I
Oh, just the two of us. I thought
Oh, just the two of us. I thought she
was
was going
Oh, just the two of us. I thought she
was going to
was going to be
Oh, just the two of us. I thought she
was going to be in
was going to be in the
Oh, just the two of us. I thought she
was going to be in the picture.
I
I don't
I don't need
I don't need a
I don't need a picture
I don't need a picture of
I don't need a picture of myself
I don't need a picture of myself by
I don't need a picture of myself by the
way.
That's
That's But
>> I
>> I just
That's But
>> I just wanted
>> I just wanted to
That's But
>> I just wanted to thank
>> I just wanted to thank both
That's But
>> I just wanted to thank both of
>> I just wanted to thank both of you
That's But
>> I just wanted to thank both of you for
all
all of
all of your
all of your work.
all of your work. Your
all of your work. Your uh
all of your work. Your uh books
all of your work. Your uh books and
lectures
lectures have
all of your work. Your uh books and
lectures have really
lectures have really helped
all of your work. Your uh books and
lectures have really helped me
lectures have really helped me to
all of your work. Your uh books and
lectures have really helped me to change
my
my perspective
my perspective and
my perspective and I
my perspective and I wanted
my perspective and I wanted to
my perspective and I wanted to thank
my perspective and I wanted to thank you
both.
>> That
>> That makes
>> That makes me
>> That makes me very
>> That makes me very happy
>> That makes me very happy to
>> That makes me very happy to hear
>> That makes me very happy to hear that.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> My
>> My question
>> Thank you.
>> My question was
>> My question was about
>> Thank you.
>> My question was about how
>> My question was about how you
>> Thank you.
>> My question was about how you had
described
described uh
described uh truth
described uh truth earlier
described uh truth earlier in
described uh truth earlier in the
lecture.
lecture. I
described uh truth earlier in the
lecture. I thought
lecture. I thought that
described uh truth earlier in the
lecture. I thought that you
lecture. I thought that you had
described uh truth earlier in the
lecture. I thought that you had said
that
that truth
that truth did
that truth did not
that truth did not depend
that truth did not depend on
circumstance
but
but I
but I thought
but I thought that
but I thought that you
but I thought that you had
but I thought that you had said
but I thought that you had said um
but I thought that you had said um also
it
it depended
but I thought that you had said um also
it depended on
it depended on context
but I thought that you had said um also
it depended on context and
it depended on context and I
but I thought that you had said um also
it depended on context and I if
it depended on context and I if that's
true
true can
true can you
true can you confirm
>> well
>> well what
true can you confirm
>> well what you
>> well what you understand
true can you confirm
>> well what you understand to
>> well what you understand to be
true can you confirm
>> well what you understand to be the
>> well what you understand to be the truth
would
would be
would be an
would be an expression
would be an expression of
would be an expression of a
would be an expression of a level
would be an expression of a level of
consciousness
consciousness the
would be an expression of a level of
consciousness the truth
consciousness the truth itself
would be an expression of a level of
consciousness the truth itself is
unchanging
unchanging it
unchanging it would
unchanging it would look
unchanging it would look differently
whether
whether this
unchanging it would look differently
whether this is
whether this is a
unchanging it would look differently
whether this is a world
whether this is a world that
unchanging it would look differently
whether this is a world that needs
whether this is a world that needs to
unchanging it would look differently
whether this is a world that needs to be
uh
uh improved
uh improved or
uh improved or whether
uh improved or whether it's
uh improved or whether it's a
uh improved or whether it's a perfect
world
world etc
uh improved or whether it's a perfect
world etc would
world etc would all
uh improved or whether it's a perfect
world etc would all depend
world etc would all depend on
uh improved or whether it's a perfect
world etc would all depend on your
world etc would all depend on your level
of
of consciousness.
of consciousness. You
of consciousness. You see?
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So,
>> Yeah. So, it's
>> Yeah. So, it's true
>> Yeah. So, it's true at
>> Yeah. So, it's true at that
>> Yeah. So, it's true at that level
>> Yeah. So, it's true at that level of
consciousness.
>> Okay.
>> That
>> That the
>> Okay.
>> That the world
>> That the world that
>> Okay.
>> That the world that you
>> That the world that you see
>> Okay.
>> That the world that you see doesn't
>> That the world that you see doesn't even
exist.
Doesn't
Doesn't need
exist.
Doesn't need saving
Doesn't need saving because
exist.
Doesn't need saving because what
Doesn't need saving because what you
exist.
Doesn't need saving because what you see
doesn't
doesn't even
doesn't even exist.
It's
It's all
doesn't even exist.
It's all perception
It's all perception and
doesn't even exist.
It's all perception and projection.
Makes
Makes sense
Makes sense at
Makes sense at consciousness
Makes sense at consciousness level
Makes sense at consciousness level 730
or
or 40.
Makes sense at consciousness level 730
or 40. Sounds
or 40. Sounds nonsensical
Makes sense at consciousness level 730
or 40. Sounds nonsensical to
consciousness
consciousness level
consciousness level 283.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So
consciousness level 283.
>> Okay. So that
>> Okay. So that if
consciousness level 283.
>> Okay. So that if if
>> Okay. So that if if we
consciousness level 283.
>> Okay. So that if if we while
>> Okay. So that if if we while we
consciousness level 283.
>> Okay. So that if if we while we advance
in
in our
in our levels
in our levels of
in our levels of consciousness
in our levels of consciousness something
may
may be
in our levels of consciousness something
may be true
may be true at
in our levels of consciousness something
may be true at one
may be true at one level
in our levels of consciousness something
may be true at one level or
may be true at one level or it
in our levels of consciousness something
may be true at one level or it may
may be true at one level or it may seem
some
some way
>> appropriately
>> appropriately to
some way
>> appropriately to the
>> appropriately to the truth
some way
>> appropriately to the truth as
>> appropriately to the truth as you
understand
understand it
understand it at
understand it at this
understand it at this time.
>> Okay.
>> And
>> And then
>> And then later
>> And then later on
>> And then later on it
>> And then later on it may
>> And then later on it may change
>> And then later on it may change and
>> And then later on it may change and then
you
you understand
>> And then later on it may change and then
you understand it
you understand it now
>> And then later on it may change and then
you understand it now from
you understand it now from this
>> And then later on it may change and then
you understand it now from this level.
Is
Is it
>> okay?
>> Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. Thank you
>> Okay. Thank you very
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Once
>> Once at
>> Once at one
>> Once at one level
>> Once at one level you
>> Once at one level you may
>> Once at one level you may see
>> Once at one level you may see be
>> Once at one level you may see be called
upon
upon to
>> Once at one level you may see be called
upon to feel
upon to feel helpful
>> Once at one level you may see be called
upon to feel helpful towards
upon to feel helpful towards others.
>> Once at one level you may see be called
upon to feel helpful towards others. At
others,
others, you
others, you may
others, you may understand
others, you may understand that
helpfulness
helpfulness is
others, you may understand that
helpfulness is weakening
helpfulness is weakening to
others, you may understand that
helpfulness is weakening to them
helpfulness is weakening to them and
that
that you
that you must
that you must let
that you must let the
that you must let the people
that you must let the people suffer
that you must let the people suffer out
and
and discover
that you must let the people suffer out
and discover their
and discover their own
that you must let the people suffer out
and discover their own inner
and discover their own inner strength.
So
So you
So you see
So you see there'd
So you see there'd be
So you see there'd be different
perceptions
perceptions there.
I'd
I'd like
I'd like to
I'd like to thank
I'd like to thank you
I'd like to thank you for
I'd like to thank you for giving
I'd like to thank you for giving us
I'd like to thank you for giving us the
opportunity
opportunity to
I'd like to thank you for giving us the
opportunity to be
opportunity to be here
I'd like to thank you for giving us the
opportunity to be here today.
opportunity to be here today. And
I'd like to thank you for giving us the
opportunity to be here today. And my
question
question is
question is uh
do
do past
question is uh
do past life
do past life experiences
that
that they
that they that
that they that come
that they that come over
that they that come over into
that they that come over into current
life
life situations?
>> Do
>> Do they
>> Do they have
>> Do they have an
>> Do they have an influence?
>> Do they have an influence? They
>> Do they have an influence? They have
>> Do they have an influence? They have a
karmic
karmic influence.
>> Do they have an influence? They have a
karmic influence. Yes,
karmic influence. Yes, there's
>> Do they have an influence? They have a
karmic influence. Yes, there's a
karmic influence. Yes, there's a karmic
influence
influence and
influence and with
influence and with certain
influence and with certain techniques
you
you can
influence and with certain techniques
you can research
you can research them
influence and with certain techniques
you can research them actually.
you can research them actually. Certain
patterns
patterns may
patterns may come
patterns may come out
patterns may come out of
patterns may come out of previous
lifetimes,
lifetimes, commitments,
patterns may come out of previous
lifetimes, commitments, vows
lifetimes, commitments, vows you've
taken,
taken, etc.
taken, etc. You
taken, etc. You think
taken, etc. You think that
taken, etc. You think that when
taken, etc. You think that when you
taken, etc. You think that when you left
the
the body,
taken, etc. You think that when you left
the body, you're
the body, you're free
taken, etc. You think that when you left
the body, you're free to
the body, you're free to that
taken, etc. You think that when you left
the body, you're free to that vow.
the body, you're free to that vow. you
are
are not
are not etc.
are not etc. So
are not etc. So you
are not etc. So you can
are not etc. So you can discover
are not etc. So you can discover a
are not etc. So you can discover a lot
of
of interesting
are not etc. So you can discover a lot
of interesting things.
Past
Past life
Past life regression
Past life regression recall.
Past life regression recall. I
Past life regression recall. I advise
Past life regression recall. I advise it
only
only if
Past life regression recall. I advise it
only if you're
only if you're stuck
Past life regression recall. I advise it
only if you're stuck in
only if you're stuck in something.
If
If you
If you see
If you see a
If you see a persistent
If you see a persistent pattern
If you see a persistent pattern and
If you see a persistent pattern and you
can't
can't get
If you see a persistent pattern and you
can't get over
can't get over it,
If you see a persistent pattern and you
can't get over it, then
can't get over it, then you
If you see a persistent pattern and you
can't get over it, then you could
can't get over it, then you could try
past
past life
past life recall
past life recall techniques
past life recall techniques auto
past life recall techniques auto hypnos
self
self hypnosis
and
and ask
and ask God
and ask God to
and ask God to to
and ask God to to understand
and ask God to to understand what
and ask God to to understand what does
this
this mean?
and ask God to to understand what does
this mean? And
this mean? And then
and ask God to to understand what does
this mean? And then past
this mean? And then past life
and ask God to to understand what does
this mean? And then past life recall
techniques.
techniques. uh
techniques. uh it
techniques. uh it isn't
techniques. uh it isn't a
techniques. uh it isn't a memory
techniques. uh it isn't a memory of
something
something in
techniques. uh it isn't a memory of
something in the
something in the past.
techniques. uh it isn't a memory of
something in the past. What
something in the past. What happens
techniques. uh it isn't a memory of
something in the past. What happens with
the
the past
the past life
the past life recall
the past life recall is
the past life recall is all
the past life recall is all of
the past life recall is all of a
the past life recall is all of a sudden
you
you are
the past life recall is all of a sudden
you are in
you are in that
the past life recall is all of a sudden
you are in that experience
you are in that experience and
the past life recall is all of a sudden
you are in that experience and the
experience
experience is
experience is happening
experience is happening now.
You're
You're the
experience is happening now.
You're the experiencer
You're the experiencer of
experience is happening now.
You're the experiencer of the
experience,
experience, not
experience, not remembering
experience, not remembering how
experience, not remembering how it
experience, not remembering how it was,
you're
you're experiencing
experience, not remembering how it was,
you're experiencing how
you're experiencing how it
experience, not remembering how it was,
you're experiencing how it was,
>> right?
>> And
>> And there
>> right?
>> And there then
>> And there then comes
>> right?
>> And there then comes an
>> And there then comes an understanding
and
and a
and a comprehension
and a comprehension because
and a comprehension because you
reexperience
reexperience it.
and a comprehension because you
reexperience it. You
reexperience it. You say,
and a comprehension because you
reexperience it. You say, "Oh,
reexperience it. You say, "Oh, yeah.
Uhuh.
Uhuh. I
Uhuh. I see
Uhuh. I see that."
>> Does
>> Does everyone
Uhuh. I see that."
>> Does everyone have
>> Does everyone have that
Uhuh. I see that."
>> Does everyone have that in
>> Does everyone have that in their
subconscious?
subconscious? It's
subconscious? It's just
subconscious? It's just a
subconscious? It's just a matter
subconscious? It's just a matter of
subconscious? It's just a matter of it
being
being brought
subconscious? It's just a matter of it
being brought up.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, most
>> Oh, most people
>> Oh, most people don't
>> Oh, most people don't look
>> Oh, most people don't look at
>> Oh, most people don't look at it.
>> Oh, most people don't look at it. You
know,
know, first,
>> Oh, most people don't look at it. You
know, first, most
know, first, most people
>> Oh, most people don't look at it. You
know, first, most people just
know, first, most people just assume
from
from the
from the viewpoint
from the viewpoint of
from the viewpoint of the
from the viewpoint of the ego
from the viewpoint of the ego that
from the viewpoint of the ego that this
is
is the
from the viewpoint of the ego that this
is the only
is the only life
from the viewpoint of the ego that this
is the only life there
is the only life there is
from the viewpoint of the ego that this
is the only life there is and
is the only life there is and the
from the viewpoint of the ego that this
is the only life there is and the only
one
one time
one time you're
one time you're going
one time you're going to
one time you're going to be
one time you're going to be here,
one time you're going to be here, etc.
No.
No. As
one time you're going to be here, etc.
No. As you
No. As you get
one time you're going to be here, etc.
No. As you get more
No. As you get more evolved,
one time you're going to be here, etc.
No. As you get more evolved, you
No. As you get more evolved, you realize
that
that this
that this is
that this is only
that this is only a
that this is only a chapter
that this is only a chapter in
that this is only a chapter in a
that this is only a chapter in a book.
that
that your
that this is only a chapter in a book.
that your spirit
that your spirit is
that this is only a chapter in a book.
that your spirit is nonlinear
that your spirit is nonlinear and
that this is only a chapter in a book.
that your spirit is nonlinear and it's
been
been evolving
been evolving over
been evolving over great
been evolving over great courses
been evolving over great courses of
time.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Thank
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. We're
>> Okay. We're going
>> Okay. We're going to
>> Okay. We're going to have
>> Okay. We're going to have to
>> Okay. We're going to have to stick
>> Okay. We're going to have to stick to
one
one question.
>> Okay. We're going to have to stick to
one question. We
one question. We have
>> Okay. We're going to have to stick to
one question. We have a
one question. We have a time
>> Okay. We're going to have to stick to
one question. We have a time limit
one question. We have a time limit here,
so
so we're
so we're going
so we're going to
so we're going to answer
so we're going to answer as
so we're going to answer as many
so we're going to answer as many as
so we're going to answer as many as we
can,
can, but
so we're going to answer as many as we
can, but we
can, but we do
so we're going to answer as many as we
can, but we do have
can, but we do have a
so we're going to answer as many as we
can, but we do have a time.
>> They
>> They push
>> They push us
>> They push us out
>> They push us out the
>> They push us out the door
>> They push us out the door at
>> They push us out the door at a
>> They push us out the door at a certain
time.
time. Go
>> They push us out the door at a certain
time. Go ahead,
time. Go ahead, Sarah.
>> They push us out the door at a certain
time. Go ahead, Sarah. Yeah.
>> I've
>> I've been
>> I've been working
>> I've been working with
>> I've been working with a
>> I've been working with a health
challenge
challenge the
>> I've been working with a health
challenge the last
challenge the last three
>> I've been working with a health
challenge the last three years.
>> Health
>> Health challenge.
>> Health challenge. health
>> Health challenge. health with
>> Health challenge. health with a
>> Health challenge. health with a health
challenge.
challenge. She's
>> Health challenge. health with a health
challenge. She's been
challenge. She's been working
>> Health challenge. health with a health
challenge. She's been working with
challenge. She's been working with a
health
health challenge.
>> An
>> An illness.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, an
>> An illness.
>> Oh, an illness.
>> Oh, an illness. That's
>> An illness.
>> Oh, an illness. That's an
>> Oh, an illness. That's an English.
>> An illness.
>> Oh, an illness. That's an English. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Go
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> I've
>> I've been
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> I've been working
>> I've been working spiritually,
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> I've been working spiritually, mentally,
and
and physically.
>> Yeah.
>> Mentally,
>> Mentally, I
>> Mentally, I feel
>> Mentally, I feel like
>> Mentally, I feel like I've
>> Mentally, I feel like I've drawn
>> Mentally, I feel like I've drawn some
parameters
parameters that
>> Mentally, I feel like I've drawn some
parameters that I'm
parameters that I'm not
>> Mentally, I feel like I've drawn some
parameters that I'm not willing
parameters that I'm not willing to
>> Mentally, I feel like I've drawn some
parameters that I'm not willing to do
any
any more
any more work
any more work at
any more work at that
any more work at that level.
any more work at that level. And
physically,
physically, I
any more work at that level. And
physically, I feel
physically, I feel like
any more work at that level. And
physically, I feel like I've
physically, I feel like I've drawn
any more work at that level. And
physically, I feel like I've drawn some
parameters.
parameters. When
parameters. When at
parameters. When at my
parameters. When at my last
parameters. When at my last doctor's
appointment,
appointment, she
parameters. When at my last doctor's
appointment, she was
appointment, she was creating
parameters. When at my last doctor's
appointment, she was creating a
appointment, she was creating a whole
other
other list
other list of
other list of things
other list of things for
other list of things for me
other list of things for me to
other list of things for me to do
other list of things for me to do and
other list of things for me to do and I
said,
said, "I
other list of things for me to do and I
said, "I don't
said, "I don't think
other list of things for me to do and I
said, "I don't think I'm
said, "I don't think I'm going
other list of things for me to do and I
said, "I don't think I'm going to
said, "I don't think I'm going to be
doing
doing those
doing those to
doing those to myself."
>> Yeah.
>> Am
>> Am I
>> Am I hurting
>> Am I hurting myself?
>> Am I hurting myself? I
>> Am I hurting myself? I haven't
>> Am I hurting myself? I haven't given
>> Am I hurting myself? I haven't given up
on
on you
>> Am I hurting myself? I haven't given up
on you and
on you and God,
>> Am I hurting myself? I haven't given up
on you and God, but
on you and God, but am
>> Am I hurting myself? I haven't given up
on you and God, but am I
on you and God, but am I hurting
>> Am I hurting myself? I haven't given up
on you and God, but am I hurting myself
by
by drawing
by drawing these
by drawing these boundaries
by drawing these boundaries for
>> No,
>> No, because
by drawing these boundaries for
>> No, because you
>> No, because you probably
by drawing these boundaries for
>> No, because you probably have
>> No, because you probably have pursued
that
that to
that to its
that to its uh
>> fullest.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. There's
>> Yeah. There's only
>> Yeah. There's only so
>> Yeah. There's only so much
>> Yeah. There's only so much you
>> Yeah. There's only so much you can
>> Yeah. There's only so much you can do
>> Yeah. There's only so much you can do on
the
the physical
>> Yeah. There's only so much you can do on
the physical level,
the physical level, you
>> Yeah. There's only so much you can do on
the physical level, you know.
>> But
>> But then
>> But then you
>> But then you can't
>> But then you can't you
>> But then you can't you just
>> But then you can't you just say,
>> But then you can't you just say, "I
don't
don't want
>> But then you can't you just say, "I
don't want to
don't want to do
>> But then you can't you just say, "I
don't want to do this
don't want to do this anymore.
>> But then you can't you just say, "I
don't want to do this anymore. Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Physical,
>> Physical, mental,
>> Physical, mental, and
>> Physical, mental, and spiritual.
>> Physical, mental, and spiritual. So,
>> Physical, mental, and spiritual. So, you
address
address it
>> Physical, mental, and spiritual. So, you
address it on
address it on all
>> Physical, mental, and spiritual. So, you
address it on all levels.
>> Do
>> Do the
>> Do the best
>> Do the best you
>> Do the best you can.
>> Yes.
>> Hi.
>> Um,
>> Um, I
>> Hi.
>> Um, I just
>> Um, I just wanted
>> Hi.
>> Um, I just wanted to
>> Um, I just wanted to come
>> Hi.
>> Um, I just wanted to come and
>> Um, I just wanted to come and say,
>> Hi.
>> Um, I just wanted to come and say, um,
without
without crying,
without crying, thank
without crying, thank you.
without crying, thank you. I've
been
been through
without crying, thank you. I've
been through what
been through what seemed
without crying, thank you. I've
been through what seemed like
been through what seemed like held
without crying, thank you. I've
been through what seemed like held him
back
>> and,
>> and, um,
you've
you've helped
you've helped me
you've helped me a
you've helped me a great
you've helped me a great deal.
you've helped me a great deal. So,
you've helped me a great deal. So, I
just
just want
you've helped me a great deal. So, I
just want to
just want to say
you've helped me a great deal. So, I
just want to say thank
just want to say thank you.
>> She's
>> She's She
>> She's She says
>> She's She says she's
>> She's She says she's been
>> She's She says she's been through
>> She's She says she's been through hell
and
and back
>> She's She says she's been through hell
and back and
and back and she
>> She's She says she's been through hell
and back and she says
and back and she says that
>> She's She says she's been through hell
and back and she says that you've
and back and she says that you've helped
her
her so
her so much
her so much in
her so much in her
her so much in her growth.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, well,
her so much in her growth.
>> Oh, well, you
>> Oh, well, you came
her so much in her growth.
>> Oh, well, you came back
>> Oh, well, you came back from
her so much in her growth.
>> Oh, well, you came back from hell.
>> Oh, well, you came back from hell. Thank
goodness.
>> You
>> You don't
goodness.
>> You don't want
>> You don't want to
goodness.
>> You don't want to hang
>> You don't want to hang out
goodness.
>> You don't want to hang out there
>> You don't want to hang out there too
long.
long. Few
long. Few eons
long. Few eons and
long. Few eons and then
long. Few eons and then you've
long. Few eons and then you've had
long. Few eons and then you've had it
with
with hell,
long. Few eons and then you've had it
with hell, you
with hell, you know.
long. Few eons and then you've had it
with hell, you know. Fed
with hell, you know. Fed up
long. Few eons and then you've had it
with hell, you know. Fed up with
with hell, you know. Fed up with hell,
you
you know.
>> But
>> But yeah,
you know.
>> But yeah, I
>> But yeah, I No,
you know.
>> But yeah, I No, it's
>> But yeah, I No, it's not
you know.
>> But yeah, I No, it's not going
>> But yeah, I No, it's not going back.
you know.
>> But yeah, I No, it's not going back. No,
you're
you're doing
you're doing you're
you're doing you're going
you're doing you're going to
you're doing you're going to do
you're doing you're going to do fine.
you're doing you're going to do fine. I
can
can tell.
>> Yeah.
>> The
>> The worst
>> Yeah.
>> The worst is
>> The worst is over.
>> Yeah.
>> The
>> The willingness
>> Yeah.
>> The willingness to
>> The willingness to do
>> Yeah.
>> The willingness to do anything
>> The willingness to do anything for
>> Yeah.
>> The willingness to do anything for God,
including
including going
including going to
including going to hell
including going to hell to
including going to hell to undo
including going to hell to undo the
including going to hell to undo the bad
karma,
karma, is
including going to hell to undo the bad
karma, is a
karma, is a great
including going to hell to undo the bad
karma, is a great sacrifice.
>> It's
>> It's a
>> It's a sign.
>> It's a sign. Thank
>> It's a sign. Thank you
>> It's a sign. Thank you for
>> It's a sign. Thank you for being
>> It's a sign. Thank you for being my
teacher.
>> Um,
>> Um, I've
>> Um, I've been
>> Um, I've been blessed
>> Um, I've been blessed with
>> Um, I've been blessed with divine
stupidity.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yes.
>> I
>> I can't
>> Oh, yes.
>> I can't figure
>> I can't figure out
>> Oh, yes.
>> I can't figure out what
>> I can't figure out what it
>> Oh, yes.
>> I can't figure out what it means
>> I can't figure out what it means anyway.
I'm
I'm too
I'm too dumb
I'm too dumb to
I'm too dumb to understand
I'm too dumb to understand it.
Yeah,
>> it's
>> it's my
>> it's my intention
>> it's my intention to
>> it's my intention to um
>> it's my intention to um transcend
>> it's my intention to um transcend the
ego
ego and
attain
attain unconditional
attain unconditional love.
attain unconditional love. In
attain unconditional love. In the
meantime,
meantime, how
attain unconditional love. In the
meantime, how do
meantime, how do I
attain unconditional love. In the
meantime, how do I deal
meantime, how do I deal with
attain unconditional love. In the
meantime, how do I deal with the
day-to-day
day-to-day balance
day-to-day balance between
responsibility
and
and living
and living with
and living with two
and living with two people
and living with two people who
and living with two people who have
and living with two people who have very
strong
strong egos,
and living with two people who have very
strong egos, watching
strong egos, watching them
and living with two people who have very
strong egos, watching them tear
themselves
themselves apart?
>> Well,
>> Well, you
themselves apart?
>> Well, you let
>> Well, you let them
themselves apart?
>> Well, you let them tear
>> Well, you let them tear themselves
apart.
apart. I
apart. I mean,
apart. I mean, what's
apart. I mean, what's it
apart. I mean, what's it to
apart. I mean, what's it to you?
>> You
>> You want
apart. I mean, what's it to you?
>> You want to
>> You want to stop
apart. I mean, what's it to you?
>> You want to stop them
>> You want to stop them from
apart. I mean, what's it to you?
>> You want to stop them from it?
>> I
>> I guess
>> I guess it's
>> I guess it's the
>> I guess it's the pain
>> I guess it's the pain because
>> I guess it's the pain because I
>> I guess it's the pain because I love
them
them both.
>> Well,
>> Well, it
>> Well, it makes
>> Well, it makes you
>> Well, it makes you think
>> Well, it makes you think they're
>> Well, it makes you think they're not
getting
getting something
>> Well, it makes you think they're not
getting something out
getting something out of
>> Well, it makes you think they're not
getting something out of their
getting something out of their suffering
that
that you
that you don't
that you don't want
that you don't want to
that you don't want to deprive
that you don't want to deprive them
that you don't want to deprive them of.
>> You
>> You ever
that you don't want to deprive them of.
>> You ever hear
>> You ever hear of
that you don't want to deprive them of.
>> You ever hear of the
>> You ever hear of the Elanon?
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. First
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. First step
>> Yeah. First step in
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. First step in Elanon.
You
You know
You know the
You know the first
You know the first step
You know the first step in
You know the first step in element,
You know the first step in element, let
go
go to
You know the first step in element, let
go to control
go to control others.
You know the first step in element, let
go to control others. Surrender
go to control others. Surrender them
You know the first step in element, let
go to control others. Surrender them to
God
God because
God because they
God because they have
God because they have their
God because they have their own
God because they have their own karmic
destiny
and
and it
and it doesn't
and it doesn't do
and it doesn't do them
and it doesn't do them any
and it doesn't do them any good
and it doesn't do them any good to
intervene.
intervene. In
and it doesn't do them any good to
intervene. In the
intervene. In the meantime,
and it doesn't do them any good to
intervene. In the meantime, you
intervene. In the meantime, you love
them
them to
them to the
them to the best
them to the best you
them to the best you can
them to the best you can unconditionally
and
and as
them to the best you can unconditionally
and as forgivingly
and as forgivingly as
them to the best you can unconditionally
and as forgivingly as possible
because
because there's
because there's nothing
because there's nothing else
because there's nothing else you
because there's nothing else you can
because there's nothing else you can do.
Especially
Especially these
because there's nothing else you can do.
Especially these involvements.
Especially these involvements. Forget
it.
it. You're
it. You're not
it. You're not going
it. You're not going to
it. You're not going to do
it. You're not going to do them.
Okay,
Okay, thank
it. You're not going to do them.
Okay, thank you.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, you
>> Yeah, you know
>> Yeah, you know what
>> Yeah, you know what the
>> Yeah, you know what the fate
>> Yeah, you know what the fate of
>> Yeah, you know what the fate of the
person,
person, you
>> Yeah, you know what the fate of the
person, you hear
person, you hear a
>> Yeah, you know what the fate of the
person, you hear a couple
person, you hear a couple fighting
>> Yeah, you know what the fate of the
person, you hear a couple fighting down
the
the street,
the street, so
the street, so you
the street, so you run
the street, so you run out,
the street, so you run out, you
the street, so you run out, you run,
the street, so you run out, you run, and
you
you knock
the street, so you run out, you run, and
you knock on
you knock on the
the street, so you run out, you run, and
you knock on the door.
you knock on the door. You
the street, so you run out, you run, and
you knock on the door. You try
you knock on the door. You try to
separate
separate them
separate them and
separate them and uh
separate them and uh and
separate them and uh and you
separate them and uh and you know
separate them and uh and you know what
happens
happens in
separate them and uh and you know what
happens in the
happens in the end?
separate them and uh and you know what
happens in the end? They
happens in the end? They both
separate them and uh and you know what
happens in the end? They both turn
against
against you
against you and
against you and turn
against you and turn you
against you and turn you into
against you and turn you into the
against you and turn you into the cops.
Everybody's
Everybody's learned
against you and turn you into the cops.
Everybody's learned not
Everybody's learned not to
against you and turn you into the cops.
Everybody's learned not to intervene.
Thank
Thank you.
They'll
They'll start
Thank you.
They'll start blaming
They'll start blaming you
Thank you.
They'll start blaming you for
They'll start blaming you for the
Thank you.
They'll start blaming you for the whole
thing.
Hey.
>> Yeah.
>> Um,
>> Um, I'm
>> Yeah.
>> Um, I'm so
>> Um, I'm so happy
>> Yeah.
>> Um, I'm so happy to
>> Um, I'm so happy to be
>> Yeah.
>> Um, I'm so happy to be here
>> Um, I'm so happy to be here and
>> Yeah.
>> Um, I'm so happy to be here and I
>> Um, I'm so happy to be here and I wrote
I
I read
I read Power
I read Power Vers
I read Power Vers I
I read Power Vers I didn't
I read Power Vers I didn't I
I read Power Vers I didn't I didn't
write
write it.
I read Power Vers I didn't I didn't
write it. I
write it. I read
I read Power Vers I didn't I didn't
write it. I read Power
write it. I read Power Versus
I read Power Vers I didn't I didn't
write it. I read Power Versus Force
write it. I read Power Versus Force and
I
I called
I called your
I called your home
I called your home number
I called your home number and
I called your home number and I
I called your home number and I said,
"Thank
"Thank you.
I called your home number and I said,
"Thank you. Why
"Thank you. Why did
I called your home number and I said,
"Thank you. Why did I
"Thank you. Why did I do
I called your home number and I said,
"Thank you. Why did I do that?
"Thank you. Why did I do that? I'm
I called your home number and I said,
"Thank you. Why did I do that? I'm so
naive."
naive." But
naive." But thank
naive." But thank you.
naive." But thank you. So,
naive." But thank you. So, I
naive." But thank you. So, I just
naive." But thank you. So, I just need
to
to ask
naive." But thank you. So, I just need
to ask you
to ask you if
naive." But thank you. So, I just need
to ask you if it's
to ask you if it's for
naive." But thank you. So, I just need
to ask you if it's for the
to ask you if it's for the highest
naive." But thank you. So, I just need
to ask you if it's for the highest and
best
best good.
best good. I
best good. I have
best good. I have a
best good. I have a three-year-old
best good. I have a three-year-old son
and
and a
best good. I have a three-year-old son
and a and
and a and a
best good. I have a three-year-old son
and a and a husband.
and a and a husband. My
best good. I have a three-year-old son
and a and a husband. My husband's
currently
currently a
currently a stay-at-home
currently a stay-at-home dad
currently a stay-at-home dad for
currently a stay-at-home dad for three
years.
>> He's
>> He's really
>> He's really what?
>> He's really what? a
>> He's really what? a stay-at-home
>> He's really what? a stay-at-home dad
>> He's really what? a stay-at-home dad for
three
three years.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yes.
>> And
>> And I'm
>> And I'm in
>> And I'm in um
>> And I'm in um and
>> And I'm in um and I
>> And I'm in um and I want
>> And I'm in um and I want to
>> And I'm in um and I want to be
>> And I'm in um and I want to be a
stay-at-home
stay-at-home mom
>> And I'm in um and I want to be a
stay-at-home mom now.
stay-at-home mom now. And
>> And I'm in um and I want to be a
stay-at-home mom now. And I
stay-at-home mom now. And I want
>> And I'm in um and I want to be a
stay-at-home mom now. And I want my
husband
husband to
husband to go
husband to go back
husband to go back to
husband to go back to work.
>> Okay.
>> And
>> And I
>> And I want
>> And I want to
>> And I want to Well,
>> And I want to Well, if
>> And I want to Well, if that
>> And I want to Well, if that would
>> And I want to Well, if that would be
>> And I want to Well, if that would be for
the
the highest,
>> you
>> you want
>> you want to
>> you want to go
>> you want to go back
>> you want to go back to
>> you want to go back to work
>> you want to go back to work tomorrow.
Give
Give us
>> you want to go back to work tomorrow.
Give us your
Give us your husband.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> You
>> You swap
>> Thank you.
>> You swap roles.
>> You swap roles. What
>> Thank you.
>> You swap roles. What did
>> You swap roles. What did you
>> Thank you.
>> You swap roles. What did you swap
>> You swap roles. What did you swap roles
for?
>> Um
>> Um because
for?
>> Um because we
>> Um because we moved
for?
>> Um because we moved from
>> Um because we moved from Arizona
for?
>> Um because we moved from Arizona to
North
North Carolina
North Carolina to
North Carolina to be
North Carolina to be closer
North Carolina to be closer to
North Carolina to be closer to my
North Carolina to be closer to my family
and
and I
North Carolina to be closer to my family
and I got
and I got a
North Carolina to be closer to my family
and I got a transfer.
and I got a transfer. But
North Carolina to be closer to my family
and I got a transfer. But my
and I got a transfer. But my question
is,
is, is
is, is it
is, is it would
is, is it would it
is, is it would it be
is, is it would it be for
is, is it would it be for the
is, is it would it be for the highest
and
and best
is, is it would it be for the highest
and best good
and best good for
is, is it would it be for the highest
and best good for my
and best good for my family
is, is it would it be for the highest
and best good for my family if
and best good for my family if the
is, is it would it be for the highest
and best good for my family if the roles
were
were reversed?
were reversed? If
were reversed? If we
were reversed? If we could
were reversed? If we could swap,
were reversed? If we could swap, it's
very
very important
were reversed? If we could swap, it's
very important to
very important to me.
>> You
>> You know
>> You know what
>> You know what you're
>> You know what you're saying?
>> She
>> She wants
>> You know what you're saying?
>> She wants the
>> She wants the roles
>> You know what you're saying?
>> She wants the roles reversed
>> She wants the roles reversed again.
>> You know what you're saying?
>> She wants the roles reversed again. She
wants
wants him
wants him to
wants him to go
wants him to go out
wants him to go out and
wants him to go out and get
wants him to go out and get a
wants him to go out and get a job
wants him to go out and get a job and
she
she wants
wants him to go out and get a job and
she wants to
she wants to stay
wants him to go out and get a job and
she wants to stay home
she wants to stay home with
wants him to go out and get a job and
she wants to stay home with her
she wants to stay home with her son.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. So
>> would
>> would you
>> Yes. So
>> would you would
>> would you would you
>> Yes. So
>> would you would you would
>> would you would you would you
>> Yes. So
>> would you would you would you help
>> would you would you would you help me?
>> How
>> How would
>> How would I
>> How would I help
>> How would I help you?
>> He
>> He she
>> How would I help you?
>> He she wants
>> He she wants us
>> How would I help you?
>> He she wants us to
>> He she wants us to do
>> How would I help you?
>> He she wants us to do the
>> He she wants us to do the arm
>> How would I help you?
>> He she wants us to do the arm on
>> He she wants us to do the arm on it
>> How would I help you?
>> He she wants us to do the arm on it and
see
see if
see if that's
see if that's the
see if that's the highest
see if that's the highest good.
>> Well,
>> Well, it's
see if that's the highest good.
>> Well, it's the
>> Well, it's the highest
see if that's the highest good.
>> Well, it's the highest good,
>> Well, it's the highest good, of
see if that's the highest good.
>> Well, it's the highest good, of course,
because
because what
because what you
because what you want,
because what you want, isn't
because what you want, isn't it?
Oh
Oh my
because what you want, isn't it?
Oh my David.
>> Thank
>> Thank you,
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> No,
>> No, it's
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> No, it's because
>> No, it's because it
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> No, it's because it doesn't
>> No, it's because it doesn't make
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> No, it's because it doesn't make any
difference.
difference. It
difference. It really
difference. It really doesn't
difference. It really doesn't make
difference. It really doesn't make any
difference.
difference. Resist.
difference. It really doesn't make any
difference. Resist. It
difference. Resist. It doesn't
difference. It really doesn't make any
difference. Resist. It doesn't really
make
make any
make any difference
make any difference which
make any difference which one
make any difference which one is
make any difference which one is going
to
to do
make any difference which one is going
to do the
to do the parenting.
make any difference which one is going
to do the parenting. It's
to do the parenting. It's just
make any difference which one is going
to do the parenting. It's just a
to do the parenting. It's just a choice
that
that between
that between the
that between the two
that between the two of
that between the two of you,
that between the two of you, you
that between the two of you, you know,
whether
whether you
that between the two of you, you know,
whether you want
whether you want a
that between the two of you, you know,
whether you want a green
whether you want a green drapes
that between the two of you, you know,
whether you want a green drapes or
whether you want a green drapes or blue
drapes
drapes is
drapes is really
drapes is really all
drapes is really all it
drapes is really all it amounts
drapes is really all it amounts to,
drapes is really all it amounts to, you
know.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> You're
>> You're you're
>> You're you're a
>> You're you're a woman.
>> You're you're a woman. You're
>> You're you're a woman. You're allowed
>> You're you're a woman. You're allowed to
change
change your
>> You're you're a woman. You're allowed to
change your mind.
Okay,
>> that's
>> that's okay.
Okay,
>> that's okay. That's
>> that's okay. That's good.
Okay,
>> that's okay. That's good. Thank
>> that's okay. That's good. Thank you.
>> Well,
>> Well, a
>> Well, a man
>> Well, a man should
>> Well, a man should want
>> Well, a man should want want
>> Well, a man should want want his
>> Well, a man should want want his wife
>> Well, a man should want want his wife to
be
be happy
>> Well, a man should want want his wife to
be happy and
be happy and uh
>> Well, a man should want want his wife to
be happy and uh and
be happy and uh and therefore,
>> Well, a man should want want his wife to
be happy and uh and therefore, you
be happy and uh and therefore, you know,
>> you
>> you dedicate
>> you dedicate your
>> you dedicate your your
>> you dedicate your your life
>> you dedicate your your life to
>> you dedicate your your life to the
happiness
happiness of
>> you dedicate your your life to the
happiness of others
happiness of others and
>> you dedicate your your life to the
happiness of others and if
happiness of others and if it
>> you dedicate your your life to the
happiness of others and if it makes
happiness of others and if it makes her
happy,
happy, you're
happy, you're happy
happy, you're happy to
happy, you're happy to do
happy, you're happy to do it.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. I
happy, you're happy to do it.
>> Hello. I um
>> I
>> I could
>> I could never
>> I could never be
>> I could never be a
>> I could never be a mother.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I'm
>> I could never be a mother.
>> Oh, I'm a
>> Oh, I'm a mother
>> I could never be a mother.
>> Oh, I'm a mother of
>> Oh, I'm a mother of three.
I'm
I'm looking
I'm looking um
I'm looking um for
I'm looking um for help.
I'm looking um for help. I
I'm looking um for help. I There's
someone
someone that
I'm looking um for help. I There's
someone that I'm
someone that I'm not
I'm looking um for help. I There's
someone that I'm not having
someone that I'm not having a
I'm looking um for help. I There's
someone that I'm not having a very
someone that I'm not having a very good
time
time forgiving.
time forgiving. There's
time forgiving. There's a
time forgiving. There's a teacher
time forgiving. There's a teacher in
time forgiving. There's a teacher in the
area
area of
time forgiving. There's a teacher in the
area of a
area of a course
time forgiving. There's a teacher in the
area of a course in
area of a course in miracles
time forgiving. There's a teacher in the
area of a course in miracles and
area of a course in miracles and he's
been
been using
been using his
been using his teaching
been using his teaching for
been using his teaching for seducing
women
women for
been using his teaching for seducing
women for affairs
women for affairs and
been using his teaching for seducing
women for affairs and for
women for affairs and for control.
been using his teaching for seducing
women for affairs and for control. And
I'm
I'm very
I'm very dedicated
I'm very dedicated to
I'm very dedicated to a
I'm very dedicated to a course
I'm very dedicated to a course and
I'm very dedicated to a course and it's
hurting
>> and
>> and I
>> and I can't
>> and
>> and I can't forgive
>> and I can't forgive him
>> and
>> and I can't forgive him and
>> and I can't forgive him and I
>> and
>> and I can't forgive him and I know
>> and I can't forgive him and I know I
need
need to
need to for
need to for my
need to for my own
need to for my own sanity.
>> You
>> You you
need to for my own sanity.
>> You you need
>> You you need to
need to for my own sanity.
>> You you need to forgive
>> You you need to forgive what?
a
a a
a a teacher
a a teacher was
a a teacher was an
>> he's
>> he's a
a a teacher was an
>> he's a course
>> he's a course of
a a teacher was an
>> he's a course of miracles
>> he's a course of miracles teacher
a a teacher was an
>> he's a course of miracles teacher which
is
is dear
is dear to
is dear to my
is dear to my heart
>> and
>> and this
is dear to my heart
>> and this morning
>> and this morning his
is dear to my heart
>> and this morning his name
>> and this morning his name came
is dear to my heart
>> and this morning his name came up
>> and this morning his name came up and
is dear to my heart
>> and this morning his name came up and I
got
got tied
got tied up
got tied up in
got tied up in knots
got tied up in knots and
got tied up in knots and he's
got tied up in knots and he's using
got tied up in knots and he's using his
teachings
teachings to
got tied up in knots and he's using his
teachings to bring
teachings to bring people
got tied up in knots and he's using his
teachings to bring people in
teachings to bring people in and
got tied up in knots and he's using his
teachings to bring people in and then
he's
he's seducing
he's seducing women
he's seducing women for
he's seducing women for affairs.
he's seducing women for affairs. Oh
he's seducing women for affairs. Oh yes
and
and he's
he's seducing women for affairs. Oh yes
and he's using
and he's using it
he's seducing women for affairs. Oh yes
and he's using it for
and he's using it for control
he's seducing women for affairs. Oh yes
and he's using it for control and
and he's using it for control and I
can't
can't let
can't let go
can't let go and
can't let go and I'm
can't let go and I'm looking
>> that's
>> that's what
can't let go and I'm looking
>> that's what we
>> that's what we were
can't let go and I'm looking
>> that's what we were talking
>> that's what we were talking about
can't let go and I'm looking
>> that's what we were talking about this
morning
morning weren't
morning weren't we?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
morning weren't we?
>> Yeah. And I'm
>> Yeah. And I'm it's
morning weren't we?
>> Yeah. And I'm it's still
>> Yeah. And I'm it's still tied
morning weren't we?
>> Yeah. And I'm it's still tied up.
>> Yeah. And I'm it's still tied up. It's
this
this I
this I want
this I want I
this I want I don't
this I want I don't know
this I want I don't know why
this I want I don't know why I
this I want I don't know why I want
this I want I don't know why I want to
hold
hold on.
this I want I don't know why I want to
hold on. I
hold on. I think
this I want I don't know why I want to
hold on. I think it's
hold on. I think it's because
this I want I don't know why I want to
hold on. I think it's because it's
hold on. I think it's because it's a
spiritual
spiritual betrayal
spiritual betrayal or
spiritual betrayal or something
>> and
>> and I
spiritual betrayal or something
>> and I don't
>> and I don't know
spiritual betrayal or something
>> and I don't know how
>> and I don't know how I'm
spiritual betrayal or something
>> and I don't know how I'm I'm
>> and I don't know how I'm I'm just
looking
looking for
looking for forgi
looking for forgi forgive
>> to
>> to to
looking for forgi forgive
>> to to the
>> to to the relationship.
>> You
>> You want
>> You want to
>> You want to hold
>> You want to hold on
>> You want to hold on to
>> You want to hold on to the
>> You want to hold on to the relationship?
>> I
>> I want
>> You want to hold on to the relationship?
>> I want to
>> I want to hold
>> You want to hold on to the relationship?
>> I want to hold on
>> I want to hold on I'm
>> You want to hold on to the relationship?
>> I want to hold on I'm trying
>> I want to hold on I'm trying to
>> You want to hold on to the relationship?
>> I want to hold on I'm trying to forgive
the
the the
the the appearance
the the appearance of
the the appearance of the
the the appearance of the spiritual
betrayal
betrayal and
the the appearance of the spiritual
betrayal and I'm
betrayal and I'm having
the the appearance of the spiritual
betrayal and I'm having a
betrayal and I'm having a very
the the appearance of the spiritual
betrayal and I'm having a very hard
betrayal and I'm having a very hard time
doing
doing that.
>> Did
>> Did you
doing that.
>> Did you leave
>> Did you leave them
doing that.
>> Did you leave them yet?
>> Did you leave them yet? Well,
doing that.
>> Did you leave them yet? Well, I
>> Did you leave them yet? Well, I wasn't
one
one of
one of the
one of the students.
one of the students. Um,
one of the students. Um, luckily,
one of the students. Um, luckily, but
one of the students. Um, luckily, but I
was
was tied
one of the students. Um, luckily, but I
was tied in
was tied in with
one of the students. Um, luckily, but I
was tied in with all
was tied in with all of
one of the students. Um, luckily, but I
was tied in with all of it.
was tied in with all of it. So,
>> I'm
>> I'm not
>> I'm not sure
>> I'm not sure I
>> I'm not sure I understand
>> I'm not sure I understand what
>> I'm not sure I understand what you're
what
what you're
>> I'm not sure I understand what you're
what you're saying.
>> Um,
I
I am
>> Um,
I am looking
I am looking for
>> Um,
I am looking for help
I am looking for help to
>> Um,
I am looking for help to forgive
someone.
>> You
>> You just
someone.
>> You just do
>> You just do the
someone.
>> You just do the course
>> You just do the course of
someone.
>> You just do the course of miracles.
>> That's
>> That's what
>> That's what I'm
>> That's what I'm doing.
>> No,
>> No, very
>> That's what I'm doing.
>> No, very true.
>> I'm
>> I'm trying.
>> I'm trying. This
>> I'm trying. This is
>> the
>> the willing
>> I'm trying. This is
>> the willing willingness
>> the willing willingness to
>> I'm trying. This is
>> the willing willingness to forget.
Willing
Willing to
Willing to forget.
Willing to forget. the
Willing to forget. the willingness,
Willing to forget. the willingness, but
it's
it's still
Willing to forget. the willingness, but
it's still all
it's still all tied
Willing to forget. the willingness, but
it's still all tied up
it's still all tied up in
Willing to forget. the willingness, but
it's still all tied up in knots.
it's still all tied up in knots. And
Willing to forget. the willingness, but
it's still all tied up in knots. And it
came
came up
came up this
came up this morning.
>> He
>> He teaches
came up this morning.
>> He teaches it.
>> He
>> He teaches
>> He teaches a
>> He teaches a course
and
and he's
>> He teaches a course
and he's had
and he's had this
>> He teaches a course
and he's had this numerous
and he's had this numerous affairs
>> He teaches a course
and he's had this numerous affairs with
everybody
everybody in
everybody in this
everybody in this whole
everybody in this whole circle,
>> having
>> having everybody
everybody in this whole circle,
>> having everybody in
>> having everybody in a
everybody in this whole circle,
>> having everybody in a group.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Right.
>> Okay. Right. Okay.
>> Okay. Right. Okay. Right.
>> Okay. Right. Okay. Right. So,
>> Okay. Right. Okay. Right. So, what
>> Okay. Right. Okay. Right. So, what it
is,
is, she
>> Okay. Right. Okay. Right. So, what it
is, she feels
is, she feels a
>> Okay. Right. Okay. Right. So, what it
is, she feels a spiritual
is, she feels a spiritual betrayal
>> Okay. Right. Okay. Right. So, what it
is, she feels a spiritual betrayal to
all
all these
all these people
all these people as
I'm
I'm trying
all these people as
I'm trying to
I'm trying to fix
all these people as
I'm trying to fix it,
I'm trying to fix it, but
all these people as
I'm trying to fix it, but I
I'm trying to fix it, but I don't
all these people as
I'm trying to fix it, but I don't and
I'm trying to fix it, but I don't and I
know
know I
know I shouldn't,
know I shouldn't, but
know I shouldn't, but I
know I shouldn't, but I can't
know I shouldn't, but I can't quite
know I shouldn't, but I can't quite let
go.
go. So
know I shouldn't, but I can't quite let
go. So I'm
go. So I'm I
know I shouldn't, but I can't quite let
go. So I'm I think
go. So I'm I think I'm
know I shouldn't, but I can't quite let
go. So I'm I think I'm here
go. So I'm I think I'm here to
know I shouldn't, but I can't quite let
go. So I'm I think I'm here to help
go. So I'm I think I'm here to help see
if
if I
if I could
if I could just
if I could just give
if I could just give the
if I could just give the intention
if I could just give the intention for
forgiveness
forgiveness and
if I could just give the intention for
forgiveness and hope
forgiveness and hope that
if I could just give the intention for
forgiveness and hope that somehow
forgiveness and hope that somehow I
if I could just give the intention for
forgiveness and hope that somehow I can
forgive
forgive him
forgive him for
forgive him for that
forgive him for that which
forgive him for that which is
forgive him for that which is happening.
Um
Um because
forgive him for that which is happening.
Um because I
Um because I can't
forgive him for that which is happening.
Um because I can't set
Um because I can't set it
forgive him for that which is happening.
Um because I can't set it free
Um because I can't set it free for
forgive him for that which is happening.
Um because I can't set it free for some
reason.
reason. It's
reason. It's just
reason. It's just stuck
reason. It's just stuck in
reason. It's just stuck in there.
>> It
>> It takes
reason. It's just stuck in there.
>> It takes a
>> It takes a while
reason. It's just stuck in there.
>> It takes a while to
>> It takes a while to get
reason. It's just stuck in there.
>> It takes a while to get over
>> It takes a while to get over uh
spiritual
spiritual betrayal,
spiritual betrayal, spiritual
spiritual betrayal, spiritual rape.
spiritual betrayal, spiritual rape. See,
and
and um
spiritual betrayal, spiritual rape. See,
and um I
and um I don't
spiritual betrayal, spiritual rape. See,
and um I don't want
and um I don't want his
spiritual betrayal, spiritual rape. See,
and um I don't want his karma.
and um I don't want his karma. Thank
you,
you, Lord.
you, Lord. Anyway,
>> yeah,
>> yeah, his
you, Lord. Anyway,
>> yeah, his car
>> yeah, his car was,
>> you
>> you know,
>> you know, taking
>> you know, taking taking
>> you know, taking taking advantage.
>> you know, taking taking advantage. On
the
the other
>> you know, taking taking advantage. On
the other hand,
the other hand, out
>> you know, taking taking advantage. On
the other hand, out of
the other hand, out of the
>> you know, taking taking advantage. On
the other hand, out of the innocence
the other hand, out of the innocence of
his
his own
his own training,
his own training, he
his own training, he wasn't
his own training, he wasn't trained
his own training, he wasn't trained to
beware,
beware, you
his own training, he wasn't trained to
beware, you know.
beware, you know. So,
his own training, he wasn't trained to
beware, you know. So, it's
beware, you know. So, it's a
his own training, he wasn't trained to
beware, you know. So, it's a natural
phenomena
phenomena unless
phenomena unless you're
phenomena unless you're trained
otherwise.
otherwise. Uh,
phenomena unless you're trained
otherwise. Uh, you
otherwise. Uh, you just
phenomena unless you're trained
otherwise. Uh, you just keep
otherwise. Uh, you just keep working.
You
You you
You you pray
You you pray for
You you pray for God
You you pray for God to
You you pray for God to see
You you pray for God to see it
differently.
differently. You
You you pray for God to see it
differently. You g
differently. You g you
You you pray for God to see it
differently. You g you pray
differently. You g you pray to
You you pray for God to see it
differently. You g you pray to God
differently. You g you pray to God to
see
see it
see it for
see it for see
see it for see it
see it for see it differently.
>> It's
>> It's the
see it for see it differently.
>> It's the way
>> It's the way you're
see it for see it differently.
>> It's the way you're seeing
>> It's the way you're seeing it
see it for see it differently.
>> It's the way you're seeing it is
>> It's the way you're seeing it is is
perpetrator
perpetrator and
perpetrator and victim.
perpetrator and victim. That's
perpetrator and victim. That's why
you're
you're you're
perpetrator and victim. That's why
you're you're hooked.
>> Okay?
>> Okay? You
>> Okay? You got
>> Okay? You got a
>> Okay? You got a dualistic
>> Okay? You got a dualistic view
>> Okay? You got a dualistic view of
>> Okay? You got a dualistic view of it
>> Okay? You got a dualistic view of it as
perpetrator
perpetrator and
>> Okay? You got a dualistic view of it as
perpetrator and victim.
>> Yes.
>> Don't
>> Don't forget
>> Yes.
>> Don't forget the
>> Don't forget the victims
>> Yes.
>> Don't forget the victims are
>> Don't forget the victims are all
perpetrators.
>> Every
>> Every victim
perpetrators.
>> Every victim was
>> Every victim was a
perpetrators.
>> Every victim was a perpetrator.
>> They
>> They all
>> They all said
>> They all said yes
>> They all said yes to
>> They all said yes to go
>> They all said yes to go to,
>> They all said yes to go to, didn't
>> They all said yes to go to, didn't they?
Nobody
Nobody dragged
>> They all said yes to go to, didn't they?
Nobody dragged them
Nobody dragged them in
>> They all said yes to go to, didn't they?
Nobody dragged them in and
Nobody dragged them in and raped
>> They all said yes to go to, didn't they?
Nobody dragged them in and raped them.
>> Well,
>> Well, a
>> Well, a lot
>> Well, a lot of
>> Well, a lot of them
>> Well, a lot of them said
>> Well, a lot of them said no.
>> Well, a lot of them said no. But
>> Well, a lot of them said no. But what
>> Well, a lot of them said no. But what is
my
my heart
still
still out
still out there
still out there teaching?
>> You
>> You can't
still out there teaching?
>> You can't stop.
>> Yeah.
>> But
>> But all
>> Yeah.
>> But all you
>> But all you can
>> Yeah.
>> But all you can do
>> But all you can do is
>> Yeah.
>> But all you can do is is
>> But all you can do is is uh
>> Yeah.
>> But all you can do is is uh you
>> But all you can do is is uh you know
your
your own
your own little
just
just let
your own little
just let it
just let it go
your own little
just let it go and
just let it go and let
your own little
just let it go and let him
just let it go and let him go
your own little
just let it go and let him go on
just let it go and let him go on his
journey.
journey. And
>> well,
>> well, I
>> well, I think
>> there's
>> there's no
>> well, I think
>> there's no harm
>> there's no harm in
>> well, I think
>> there's no harm in people.
>> Lack
>> Lack of
>> Lack of integrity.
>> Lack of integrity. People
>> Lack of integrity. People should
>> Lack of integrity. People should be
called
called on
>> Lack of integrity. People should be
called on it.
called on it. I
>> Lack of integrity. People should be
called on it. I think
called on it. I think it
>> Lack of integrity. People should be
called on it. I think it should
called on it. I think it should they
should
should be
should be called
should be called on
should be called on it.
should be called on it. Confronted
should be called on it. Confronted with
it
>> by
>> by me
>> by me personally.
>> Well,
>> Well, by
>> by me personally.
>> Well, by you
>> Well, by you or
>> by me personally.
>> Well, by you or by
>> Well, by you or by a
>> by me personally.
>> Well, by you or by a committee
>> Well, by you or by a committee of
seduced
seduced victims,
seduced victims, you
seduced victims, you know,
>> maybe
>> maybe that's
seduced victims, you know,
>> maybe that's what
>> maybe that's what I
seduced victims, you know,
>> maybe that's what I was
>> maybe that's what I was looking
seduced victims, you know,
>> maybe that's what I was looking for
then.
then. I'm
then. I'm willing
then. I'm willing to
then. I'm willing to do
then. I'm willing to do it.
then. I'm willing to do it. That's
then. I'm willing to do it. That's what
I
I was
then. I'm willing to do it. That's what
I was looking
I was looking for.
then. I'm willing to do it. That's what
I was looking for. victim
I was looking for. victim committee
then. I'm willing to do it. That's what
I was looking for. victim committee that
you
you know
you know we
you know we resent
you know we resent the
you know we resent the fact
you know we resent the fact he
you know we resent the fact he took
advantage
advantage of
you know we resent the fact he took
advantage of us
advantage of us of
you know we resent the fact he took
advantage of us of our
>> confrontation
>> confrontation that
>> confrontation that was
>> on
>> on the
>> confrontation that was
>> on the other
>> on the other hand
>> confrontation that was
>> on the other hand you
>> on the other hand you see
>> confrontation that was
>> on the other hand you see he
>> on the other hand you see he did
>> confrontation that was
>> on the other hand you see he did he
>> on the other hand you see he did he was
not
not aware
not aware of
not aware of the
not aware of the seduction
not aware of the seduction and
not aware of the seduction and the
not aware of the seduction and the trap
of
of his
not aware of the seduction and the trap
of his own
of his own spiritual
>> exactly
>> and
>> and he
>> exactly
>> and he didn't
>> and he didn't know
>> exactly
>> and he didn't know that
>> and he didn't know that when
>> exactly
>> and he didn't know that when you
>> and he didn't know that when you reach
>> exactly
>> and he didn't know that when you reach a
certain
certain level
certain level you
certain level you become
certain level you become very
magnetically
magnetically attractive
certain level you become very
magnetically attractive to
magnetically attractive to people
certain level you become very
magnetically attractive to people in
magnetically attractive to people in the
other
other I
other I told
other I told you
other I told you there
other I told you there was
other I told you there was a
other I told you there was a time
other I told you there was a time in
other I told you there was a time in my
life
life I
other I told you there was a time in my
life I used
life I used to
other I told you there was a time in my
life I used to get
life I used to get proposition
other I told you there was a time in my
life I used to get proposition a
life I used to get proposition a couple
times
times a
times a day
times a day it
times a day it was
times a day it was unbelievable
times a day it was unbelievable I'd
times a day it was unbelievable I'd walk
into
into a
times a day it was unbelievable I'd walk
into a restaurant
into a restaurant sit
times a day it was unbelievable I'd walk
into a restaurant sit down
into a restaurant sit down and
times a day it was unbelievable I'd walk
into a restaurant sit down and some
into a restaurant sit down and some lady
would
would come
would come over
would come over sit
would come over sit next
would come over sit next to
would come over sit next to me
would come over sit next to me and
would come over sit next to me and say
this
this is
would come over sit next to me and say
this is going
this is going to
would come over sit next to me and say
this is going to strange
this is going to strange sounds
would come over sit next to me and say
this is going to strange sounds strange
but
but I
but I just
but I just feel
but I just feel like
but I just feel like I
but I just feel like I need
but I just feel like I need to
but I just feel like I need to meet
but I just feel like I need to meet you.
I
I mean,
but I just feel like I need to meet you.
I mean, you
I mean, you know,
but I just feel like I need to meet you.
I mean, you know, it's
I mean, you know, it's just
but I just feel like I need to meet you.
I mean, you know, it's just out
I mean, you know, it's just out of
but I just feel like I need to meet you.
I mean, you know, it's just out of the
blue.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Thank
blue.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Thank you. I
blue.
>> Yeah. Thank you. I I
>> Yeah. Thank you. I I think
blue.
>> Yeah. Thank you. I I think I
>> Yeah. Thank you. I I think I I
blue.
>> Yeah. Thank you. I I think I I think
that
that was
that was it
that was it for
that was it for me.
that was it for me. I
that was it for me. I appreciate
that was it for me. I appreciate it.
>> Out
>> Out of
that was it for me. I appreciate it.
>> Out of his
>> Out of his own
that was it for me. I appreciate it.
>> Out of his own innocence,
>> Out of his own innocence, he
that was it for me. I appreciate it.
>> Out of his own innocence, he didn't
>> Out of his own innocence, he didn't know
any
any better
any better either.
>> Yeah.
>> He
>> He didn't
>> He didn't go
>> He didn't go to
>> He didn't go to spiritual
>> He didn't go to spiritual training
school,
school, you
>> He didn't go to spiritual training
school, you know.
>> Let's
>> Let's get
>> Let's get together
>> Let's get together and
>> Let's get together and call
>> Let's get together and call him
>> Let's get together and call him on
>> Let's get together and call him on it.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, good.
>> But
>> But you
>> But you should
>> But you should be
>> But you should be confront.
>> I
>> I will
>> But you should be confront.
>> I will do
>> I will do that.
>> But you should be confront.
>> I will do that. Thank
>> I will do that. Thank you.
>> But you should be confront.
>> I will do that. Thank you. He
>> I will do that. Thank you. He doesn't
deserve
>> Well,
>> Well, he
deserve
>> Well, he doesn't
>> Well, he doesn't know
deserve
>> Well, he doesn't know what
>> Well, he doesn't know what he's
deserve
>> Well, he doesn't know what he's doing
>> Well, he doesn't know what he's doing as
long
long as
long as he
>> goes
>> goes through
long as he
>> goes through the
>> goes through the line.
long as he
>> goes through the line. Um
>> goes through the line. Um I
long as he
>> goes through the line. Um I don't
>> goes through the line. Um I don't know.
>> We
>> We have
>> We have to
>> We have to keep
>> We have to keep moving.
>> We have to keep moving. Come
>> We have to keep moving. Come on.
>> We have to keep moving. Come on. Let's
move.
move. Well,
>> We have to keep moving. Come on. Let's
move. Well, some
move. Well, some people
>> We have to keep moving. Come on. Let's
move. Well, some people stood
move. Well, some people stood in
>> We have to keep moving. Come on. Let's
move. Well, some people stood in line.
>> Got
>> Got to
>> Got to move
>> Got to move a
>> Got to move a little
>> Got to move a little faster.
>> The
>> The line
>> Got to move a little faster.
>> The line is
>> The line is moving
>> Got to move a little faster.
>> The line is moving fast
>> The line is moving fast and
>> Got to move a little faster.
>> The line is moving fast and make
>> The line is moving fast and make it
short.
>> And
>> And that's
short.
>> And that's what
>> And that's what the
short.
>> And that's what the problem
>> And that's what the problem is.
short.
>> And that's what the problem is. Go
ahead.
ahead. And
ahead. And no
ahead. And no one's
ahead. And no one's standing.
ahead. And no one's standing. First
ahead. And no one's standing. First of
all,
all, I
ahead. And no one's standing. First of
all, I want
all, I want to
ahead. And no one's standing. First of
all, I want to thank
all, I want to thank you
ahead. And no one's standing. First of
all, I want to thank you getting
all, I want to thank you getting in
line.
line. So,
>> yeah,
>> yeah, sweetheart.
line. So,
>> yeah, sweetheart. Go
>> yeah, sweetheart. Go ahead.
>> Secondly,
>> Secondly, I
>> Secondly, I want
>> Secondly, I want to
>> Secondly, I want to ask
>> Secondly, I want to ask about
>> Secondly, I want to ask about um
>> Secondly, I want to ask about um milking
guilt.
guilt. You
>> Secondly, I want to ask about um milking
guilt. You know,
guilt. You know, juicing
>> Secondly, I want to ask about um milking
guilt. You know, juicing it
guilt. You know, juicing it as
>> Secondly, I want to ask about um milking
guilt. You know, juicing it as you
guilt. You know, juicing it as you say.
>> I'm
>> I'm having
>> I'm having a
>> I'm having a hard
>> I'm having a hard time
>> I'm having a hard time hearing
>> I'm having a hard time hearing today.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. You've
>> I'm having a hard time hearing today.
>> Okay. You've got
>> Okay. You've got to
>> I'm having a hard time hearing today.
>> Okay. You've got to speak
>> Okay. You've got to speak up
>> I'm having a hard time hearing today.
>> Okay. You've got to speak up real
>> Okay. You've got to speak up real clear.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I
>> Okay. I have
>> Okay. I have a
>> Okay. I have a question
>> Okay. I have a question involved,
>> Okay. I have a question involved, as
>> Okay. I have a question involved, as you
say,
say, juicing
>> Okay. I have a question involved, as you
say, juicing guilt.
say, juicing guilt. Um,
>> Okay. I have a question involved, as you
say, juicing guilt. Um, every
say, juicing guilt. Um, every once
>> Okay. I have a question involved, as you
say, juicing guilt. Um, every once in
say, juicing guilt. Um, every once in a
while
while I'll
while I'll get
while I'll get an
while I'll get an intense
while I'll get an intense feeling
while I'll get an intense feeling all
while I'll get an intense feeling all of
a
a sudden
while I'll get an intense feeling all of
a sudden of
a sudden of guilt.
while I'll get an intense feeling all of
a sudden of guilt. Um,
a sudden of guilt. Um, and
while I'll get an intense feeling all of
a sudden of guilt. Um, and it
a sudden of guilt. Um, and it doesn't
have
have to
have to do
have to do anything
have to do anything that
have to do anything that happened
have to do anything that happened or
have to do anything that happened or is
around.
around. It's
have to do anything that happened or is
around. It's just
around. It's just the
have to do anything that happened or is
around. It's just the intense
around. It's just the intense feeling
and
and it
and it will
and it will come
and it will come on
and it will come on really
and it will come on really hard
and it will come on really hard and
fast.
fast. And
and it will come on really hard and
fast. And I'm
fast. And I'm wondering
and it will come on really hard and
fast. And I'm wondering where's
fast. And I'm wondering where's the
point
point where
point where it's
point where it's just
point where it's just milking?
>> The
>> The question,
point where it's just milking?
>> The question, what's
>> The question, what's the
point where it's just milking?
>> The question, what's the question?
>> Um,
>> Um, can
>> Um, can you
>> Um, can you just
>> Um, can you just tell
>> Um, can you just tell me
>> Um, can you just tell me a
>> Um, can you just tell me a little
>> Um, can you just tell me a little more
about
about like
>> Um, can you just tell me a little more
about like um
about like um juicing
>> Um, can you just tell me a little more
about like um juicing guilt?
>> Guilt.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, guilt.
>> Guilt.
>> Yes, guilt. Guilt
>> Yes, guilt. Guilt is
>> Guilt.
>> Yes, guilt. Guilt is narcissism.
>> Okay,
>> that's
>> that's the
>> Okay,
>> that's the solution
>> that's the solution for
>> Okay,
>> that's the solution for you.
>> that's the solution for you. Give
>> Okay,
>> that's the solution for you. Give up
narcissism.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, guilty
narcissism.
>> Oh, guilty wonderful
>> Oh, guilty wonderful you.
narcissism.
>> Oh, guilty wonderful you. Don't
>> Oh, guilty wonderful you. Don't you
narcissism.
>> Oh, guilty wonderful you. Don't you have
to
to suffer
to suffer and
to suffer and punish
to suffer and punish yourself
to suffer and punish yourself and
to suffer and punish yourself and wear
to suffer and punish yourself and wear a
sack
sack cloth
to suffer and punish yourself and wear a
sack cloth and
sack cloth and ashes
to suffer and punish yourself and wear a
sack cloth and ashes that
sack cloth and ashes that you're
to suffer and punish yourself and wear a
sack cloth and ashes that you're putting
yourself
yourself at
yourself at the
yourself at the center
yourself at the center of
yourself at the center of the
yourself at the center of the dream.
Guilt
Guilt is
yourself at the center of the dream.
Guilt is narcissism.
That's
That's the
That's the teaching
That's the teaching of
That's the teaching of the
That's the teaching of the Buddhists.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. It's
>> all
>> all concerned
>> Thank you very much. It's
>> all concerned about
>> all concerned about me,
>> Thank you very much. It's
>> all concerned about me, my
>> all concerned about me, my guilt,
>> Thank you very much. It's
>> all concerned about me, my guilt, and
how
how important
how important that
how important that is.
You
You can
how important that is.
You can let
You can let all
how important that is.
You can let all that
You can let all that go.
>> The
>> The issue
>> The issue of
>> The issue of the
>> The issue of the world
>> The issue of the world is
>> The issue of the world is not
>> The issue of the world is not even
noticed.
>> And
>> And I
>> And I don't
>> And I don't know
>> And I don't know who
>> And I don't know who was
>> And I don't know who was trying
>> And I don't know who was trying to
>> And I don't know who was trying to do
that.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Almost
>> Almost done.
>> Almost done. Move
>> Almost done. Move on.
>> I
>> I haven't
>> Almost done. Move on.
>> I haven't got
>> I haven't got a
>> Almost done. Move on.
>> I haven't got a clue
>> I haven't got a clue what
>> Almost done. Move on.
>> I haven't got a clue what I'm
>> I haven't got a clue what I'm going
>> Almost done. Move on.
>> I haven't got a clue what I'm going to
ask
ask you.
>> Oh,
I'
I' I've
I' I've thousands
I' I've thousands of
I' I've thousands of miles.
>> It's
>> It's probably
I' I've thousands of miles.
>> It's probably the
>> It's probably the best
I' I've thousands of miles.
>> It's probably the best time
>> It's probably the best time of
I' I've thousands of miles.
>> It's probably the best time of my
>> It's probably the best time of my life.
>> I
>> I haven't
>> I haven't got
>> I haven't got a
>> I haven't got a clue
>> I haven't got a clue what
>> I haven't got a clue what to
>> I haven't got a clue what to ask
>> I haven't got a clue what to ask you.
>> That's
>> That's good.
I
I can't
I can't think
I can't think of
I can't think of a
I can't think of a smart
I can't think of a smart thing
I can't think of a smart thing to
I can't think of a smart thing to say.
>> God
>> God bless
I can't think of a smart thing to say.
>> God bless you,
>> God bless you, brother.
>> You
>> You didn't
>> You didn't have
>> You didn't have to
>> You didn't have to ask
>> You didn't have to ask anything.
>> You didn't have to ask anything. I
already
already got
>> You didn't have to ask anything. I
already got the
already got the question,
>> You didn't have to ask anything. I
already got the question, which
already got the question, which you
don't
don't even
don't even know
don't even know about,
don't even know about, and
don't even know about, and I
don't even know about, and I already
gave
gave you
don't even know about, and I already
gave you the
gave you the answer,
don't even know about, and I already
gave you the answer, which
gave you the answer, which you
don't even know about, and I already
gave you the answer, which you don't
gave you the answer, which you don't yet
know
know about,
know about, but
know about, but you
know about, but you will.
>> I
>> I don't
know.
>> I
>> I got
know.
>> I got it.
>> I got it. I
know.
>> I got it. I got
>> I got it. I got I
know.
>> I got it. I got I got
>> I got it. I got I got it.
know.
>> I got it. I got I got it. I
>> I got it. I got I got it. I got
know.
>> I got it. I got I got it. I got what
>> I got it. I got I got it. I got what he
was
was asking
was asking and
was asking and I
was asking and I also
was asking and I also got
was asking and I also got the
was asking and I also got the answer
was asking and I also got the answer for
him.
>> He'd
>> He'd already
>> He'd already got
>> He'd already got it.
>> He'd already got it. I
>> He'd already got it. I said,
>> He'd already got it. I said, "Thank
>> He'd already got it. I said, "Thank you
very
obvious."
obvious." He
obvious." He was
obvious." He was say,
obvious." He was say, "Oh,
obvious." He was say, "Oh, that's
obvious."
>> I
>> I love
>> I love it
>> I love it that
>> I love it that you're
>> I love it that you're from
>> I love it that you're from the
>> I love it that you're from the upper
Midwest.
Midwest. I
>> I love it that you're from the upper
Midwest. I love
Midwest. I love it
>> I love it that you're from the upper
Midwest. I love it you're
Midwest. I love it you're a
psychotherapist.
psychotherapist. I
psychotherapist. I love
psychotherapist. I love it
psychotherapist. I love it you're
psychotherapist. I love it you're an
alcoholic.
alcoholic. I
psychotherapist. I love it you're an
alcoholic. I just
alcoholic. I just love
psychotherapist. I love it you're an
alcoholic. I just love all
alcoholic. I just love all that.
psychotherapist. I love it you're an
alcoholic. I just love all that. It
alcoholic. I just love all that. It just
makes
makes you
makes you such
makes you such a
makes you such a good
makes you such a good teacher
makes you such a good teacher for
makes you such a good teacher for me.
>> Here's
>> Here's my
makes you such a good teacher for me.
>> Here's my question.
>> Here's my question. You
makes you such a good teacher for me.
>> Here's my question. You say
>> Here's my question. You say that
makes you such a good teacher for me.
>> Here's my question. You say that you
>> Here's my question. You say that you do
better
better in
better in your
better in your growth
better in your growth if
better in your growth if you're
better in your growth if you're near
better in your growth if you're near the
teacher.
teacher. Correct.
>> In
>> In the
>> In the presence
>> In the presence of
>> In the presence of the
>> In the presence of the teacher.
>> In the presence of the teacher. Correct.
>> There
>> There there
>> In the presence of the teacher. Correct.
>> There there is
>> There there is a
>> In the presence of the teacher. Correct.
>> There there is a karmic
>> There there is a karmic uh
>> In the presence of the teacher. Correct.
>> There there is a karmic uh benefit.
>> There there is a karmic uh benefit. Yes.
Yeah.
>> So,
>> So, how
Yeah.
>> So, how big
>> So, how big a
Yeah.
>> So, how big a deal
>> So, how big a deal is
Yeah.
>> So, how big a deal is that?
>> So, how big a deal is that? Should
Yeah.
>> So, how big a deal is that? Should I
>> So, how big a deal is that? Should I be
canceling
canceling my
canceling my schedule
canceling my schedule to
canceling my schedule to show
canceling my schedule to show up
canceling my schedule to show up every
time
time here
canceling my schedule to show up every
time here or
time here or is
canceling my schedule to show up every
time here or is reading
time here or is reading the
canceling my schedule to show up every
time here or is reading the books
time here or is reading the books and
doing
doing the
>> because
>> because all
doing the
>> because all you
>> because all you have
doing the
>> because all you have to
>> because all you have to do
doing the
>> because all you have to do is
>> because all you have to do is experience
the
the energy
the energy once.
>> So,
>> So, you're
the energy once.
>> So, you're done
>> So, you're done deal
>> that
>> that once
>> that once it's
>> that once it's sufficient
>> if
>> if that's
>> that once it's sufficient
>> if that's what
>> if that's what you
>> that once it's sufficient
>> if that's what you want.
>> if that's what you want. But
>> that once it's sufficient
>> if that's what you want. But some
>> if that's what you want. But some people
that
that isn't
that isn't enough
that isn't enough and
that isn't enough and they're
that isn't enough and they're they
that isn't enough and they're they move
to
to Sedona
that isn't enough and they're they move
to Sedona and
to Sedona and they
that isn't enough and they're they move
to Sedona and they have
to Sedona and they have a
that isn't enough and they're they move
to Sedona and they have a whole
>> they
>> they want
>> they want to
>> they want to make
>> they want to make it
>> they want to make it a
>> they want to make it a lifestyle
>> and
>> and they
>> they want to make it a lifestyle
>> and they want
>> and they want to
>> they want to make it a lifestyle
>> and they want to make
>> and they want to make it
>> they want to make it a lifestyle
>> and they want to make it a
>> and they want to make it a lifestyle.
So,
So, it's
>> that
>> that which
So, it's
>> that which I
>> that which I knew
So, it's
>> that which I knew at
>> that which I knew at the
So, it's
>> that which I knew at the final
>> that which I knew at the final gate.
That
That which
That which I
That which I knew
That which I knew all
That which I knew all fear
That which I knew all fear is
That which I knew all fear is illusion.
it
it was
That which I knew all fear is illusion.
it was safe
it was safe to
That which I knew all fear is illusion.
it was safe to surrender
it was safe to surrender my
That which I knew all fear is illusion.
it was safe to surrender my life
it was safe to surrender my life uh
surrender
surrender my
surrender my life
>> and
>> and then
surrender my life
>> and then I
>> and then I experienced
surrender my life
>> and then I experienced myself
>> and then I experienced myself drive
surrender my life
>> and then I experienced myself drive die.
>> Uh
>> Uh that
>> Uh that knowingness
>> Uh that knowingness was
>> Uh that knowingness was silent
>> Uh that knowingness was silent a
>> Uh that knowingness was silent a silent
knowingness
knowingness that
>> Uh that knowingness was silent a silent
knowingness that came
knowingness that came out
>> Uh that knowingness was silent a silent
knowingness that came out of
knowingness that came out of the
vibrations
vibrations of
vibrations of the
vibrations of the aura
vibrations of the aura from
vibrations of the aura from some
vibrations of the aura from some great
guru
guru that
vibrations of the aura from some great
guru that I
guru that I had
vibrations of the aura from some great
guru that I had encountered
guru that I had encountered in
vibrations of the aura from some great
guru that I had encountered in prior
many
many many
many many lifetimes
many many lifetimes along
>> that's
>> that's that's
many many lifetimes along
>> that's that's not
>> that's that's not known
many many lifetimes along
>> that's that's not known by
>> that's that's not known by anybody.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, you
>> Yeah, you need
>> Yeah, you need a
>> Yeah, you need a lot
>> Yeah, you need a lot of
>> Yeah, you need a lot of grace
>> Yeah, you need a lot of grace given
>> Yeah, you need a lot of grace given all
of
of all
>> Yeah, you need a lot of grace given all
of all of
of all of us.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, I
>> Yeah, I mean
>> Yeah, I mean there's
>> Yeah, I mean there's tons
>> Yeah, I mean there's tons of
>> Yeah, I mean there's tons of it
>> Yeah, I mean there's tons of it to
>> Yeah, I mean there's tons of it to get
through
through it.
>> Yeah, I mean there's tons of it to get
through it. would
through it. would think
>> Yeah, I mean there's tons of it to get
through it. would think you
>> Yes.
>> All
>> All right.
>> Yes.
>> All right. Thanks
>> All right. Thanks a
>> Yes.
>> All right. Thanks a lot.
>> You
>> You have
>> You have to
>> You have to have
>> You have to have absolute
>> You have to have absolute certainty.
>> Absolute
>> Absolute certainty
>> You have to have absolute certainty.
>> Absolute certainty only
>> Absolute certainty only comes
>> You have to have absolute certainty.
>> Absolute certainty only comes from
somebody
somebody who's
somebody who's lived
somebody who's lived it
somebody who's lived it and
somebody who's lived it and they
somebody who's lived it and they can
then
then speak
somebody who's lived it and they can
then speak with
then speak with an
somebody who's lived it and they can
then speak with an authority
then speak with an authority that
somebody who's lived it and they can
then speak with an authority that no
then speak with an authority that no one
else
else can
else can speak
else can speak with.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Um
else can speak with.
>> Okay. Um like
>> Okay. Um like that
else can speak with.
>> Okay. Um like that one
>> Okay. Um like that one lady's
else can speak with.
>> Okay. Um like that one lady's thing
>> Okay. Um like that one lady's thing was
guilt.
guilt. Mine
guilt. Mine is
guilt. Mine is self-confidence.
guilt. Mine is self-confidence. And
guilt. Mine is self-confidence. And just
standing
standing and
guilt. Mine is self-confidence. And just
standing and that's
standing and that's why
guilt. Mine is self-confidence. And just
standing and that's why I'm
standing and that's why I'm so
guilt. Mine is self-confidence. And just
standing and that's why I'm so far
standing and that's why I'm so far back
in
in line,
in line, right?
in line, right? And
in line, right? And that
in line, right? And that shows
in line, right? And that shows up
in line, right? And that shows up in
every
every area
in line, right? And that shows up in
every area of
every area of my
in line, right? And that shows up in
every area of my life.
every area of my life. So
in line, right? And that shows up in
every area of my life. So what
every area of my life. So what are
in line, right? And that shows up in
every area of my life. So what are what
are
are some
are some things
are some things you
are some things you can
are some things you can say
are some things you can say to
are some things you can say to me
are some things you can say to me is
are some things you can say to me is how
I
I can
are some things you can say to me is how
I can get
I can get past
are some things you can say to me is how
I can get past this.
I can get past this. Some
are some things you can say to me is how
I can get past this. Some areas
I can get past this. Some areas I'm
perfectly
perfectly confident.
perfectly confident. How
perfectly confident. How you
perfectly confident. How you can
perfectly confident. How you can get
past
past what?
>> Lack
>> Lack of
>> Lack of self-confidence.
>> Lack
>> Lack of
>> Lack of self-confidence.
>> Lack of self-confidence. What
>> Lack of self-confidence. What do
>> Lack of self-confidence.
>> Lack of self-confidence. What do you
want
want self-confidence
want self-confidence for?
>> Well,
>> Well, to
want self-confidence for?
>> Well, to like
>> Well, to like to
want self-confidence for?
>> Well, to like to do
>> Well, to like to do things
want self-confidence for?
>> Well, to like to do things like
>> why
>> why don't
>> why don't you
>> why don't you just
>> why don't you just surrender?
>> why don't you just surrender? You're
>> why don't you just surrender? You're a
weak
weak willy
>> why don't you just surrender? You're a
weak willy with
weak willy with no
>> why don't you just surrender? You're a
weak willy with no will
weak willy with no will of
>> why don't you just surrender? You're a
weak willy with no will of your
weak willy with no will of your own
>> why don't you just surrender? You're a
weak willy with no will of your own and
you're
you're wishywashy.
>> He
>> He said
you're wishywashy.
>> He said surrender.
>> He said surrender. You
you're wishywashy.
>> He said surrender. You have
>> He said surrender. You have no
you're wishywashy.
>> He said surrender. You have no will
>> He said surrender. You have no will of
your
your own
your own and
your own and you're
your own and you're just
your own and you're just weak.
>> It's
>> It's a
your own and you're just weak.
>> It's a wishyw
wishywashy
wishywashy floppy
wishywashy floppy old
wishywashy floppy old nothing.
>> God
>> God have
wishywashy floppy old nothing.
>> God have pity
>> God have pity on
wishywashy floppy old nothing.
>> God have pity on you.
That's
That's it,
That's it, huh?
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, that's
That's it, huh?
>> Yeah, that's it.
>> Yeah, that's it. By
That's it, huh?
>> Yeah, that's it. By acceptance,
>> Yeah, that's it. By acceptance, you
disappear
disappear a
disappear a thing.
disappear a thing. By
disappear a thing. By acceptance,
instead
instead of
disappear a thing. By acceptance,
instead of resisting
instead of resisting and
disappear a thing. By acceptance,
instead of resisting and trying
instead of resisting and trying not
disappear a thing. By acceptance,
instead of resisting and trying not to
be
be that
be that which
be that which you
be that which you experience
be that which you experience yourself
as,
as, then
be that which you experience yourself
as, then you
as, then you tend
be that which you experience yourself
as, then you tend to
as, then you tend to potentiate
be that which you experience yourself
as, then you tend to potentiate it.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, good.
>> Okay, good. I'm
>> Okay, good. I'm only
>> Okay, good. I'm only halfway
>> Okay, good. I'm only halfway through
your
your book,
>> Okay, good. I'm only halfway through
your book, your
your book, your first
>> Okay, good. I'm only halfway through
your book, your first book.
your book, your first book. So,
>> Okay, good. I'm only halfway through
your book, your first book. So, okay.
All right.
>> Weak
>> Weak will
All right.
>> Weak will too,
>> Weak will too, huh?
What
What do
What do you
What do you think
What do you think of
What do you think of that?
What do you think of that? Weak
What do you think of that? Weak willed,
wishy-washy.
>> A
>> A pushover.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
>> A pushover.
>> Oh, I love
>> Oh, I love those.
>> There's
>> There's got
>> There's got to
>> There's got to be
>> There's got to be somebody
>> There's got to be somebody to
>> There's got to be somebody to push
>> There's got to be somebody to push her
out
out of
>> There's got to be somebody to push her
out of this
out of this world
>> There's got to be somebody to push her
out of this world and
out of this world and she
>> There's got to be somebody to push her
out of this world and she jumps
out of this world and she jumps right
>> There's got to be somebody to push her
out of this world and she jumps right in
when
when you
when you need
when you need somebody
when you need somebody to
when you need somebody to push
when you need somebody to push her
when you need somebody to push her in.
>> I'm
>> I'm a
when you need somebody to push her in.
>> I'm a medical
>> I'm a medical doctor
when you need somebody to push her in.
>> I'm a medical doctor and
>> I'm a medical doctor and I
when you need somebody to push her in.
>> I'm a medical doctor and I have
>> I'm a medical doctor and I have about
2,000
2,000 patients
2,000 patients and
2,000 patients and I
2,000 patients and I wonder
2,000 patients and I wonder if
2,000 patients and I wonder if it
2,000 patients and I wonder if it would
be
be appropriate
2,000 patients and I wonder if it would
be appropriate for
be appropriate for me
2,000 patients and I wonder if it would
be appropriate for me to
be appropriate for me to use
2,000 patients and I wonder if it would
be appropriate for me to use muscle
testing
testing in
testing in my
testing in my treatments
testing in my treatments of
testing in my treatments of my
testing in my treatments of my patients.
>> I
>> I use
testing in my treatments of my patients.
>> I use it
>> I use it all
testing in my treatments of my patients.
>> I use it all the
>> I use it all the time.
testing in my treatments of my patients.
>> I use it all the time. I
>> I use it all the time. I find
testing in my treatments of my patients.
>> I use it all the time. I find it
diagnostically
diagnostically extremely
diagnostically extremely useful.
diagnostically extremely useful. Also,
it's
it's a
diagnostically extremely useful. Also,
it's a way
it's a way of
diagnostically extremely useful. Also,
it's a way of cross-checking
it's a way of cross-checking what
diagnostically extremely useful. Also,
it's a way of cross-checking what I
suspect.
suspect. I
suspect. I use
suspect. I use it
suspect. I use it to
suspect. I use it to uh
suspect. I use it to uh uh
suspect. I use it to uh uh choose
suspect. I use it to uh uh choose a
medication
medication and
suspect. I use it to uh uh choose a
medication and the
medication and the dosage
suspect. I use it to uh uh choose a
medication and the dosage of
medication and the dosage of the
medication
and
and it's
medication
and it's a
and it's a way
medication
and it's a way of
and it's a way of cross-checking.
medication
and it's a way of cross-checking. I
wouldn't
wouldn't say
wouldn't say I
wouldn't say I use
wouldn't say I use it
wouldn't say I use it all
wouldn't say I use it all by
wouldn't say I use it all by itself,
wouldn't say I use it all by itself, but
don't
don't forget
wouldn't say I use it all by itself, but
don't forget I've
don't forget I've got
wouldn't say I use it all by itself, but
don't forget I've got enormous
don't forget I've got enormous clinical
experience.
experience. So,
experience. So, what
experience. So, what I
experience. So, what I do
experience. So, what I do is
experience. So, what I do is I
experience. So, what I do is I use
experience. So, what I do is I use it
experience. So, what I do is I use it to
back
back up
experience. So, what I do is I use it to
back up my
back up my clinical
experience. So, what I do is I use it to
back up my clinical impression
back up my clinical impression and
experience. So, what I do is I use it to
back up my clinical impression and I
back up my clinical impression and I use
it
it to
it to check
it to check dosages.
>> But
>> But would
it to check dosages.
>> But would it
>> But would it be
it to check dosages.
>> But would it be appropriate
>> But would it be appropriate for
it to check dosages.
>> But would it be appropriate for me
>> But would it be appropriate for me to
it to check dosages.
>> But would it be appropriate for me to do
that
that is
that is this
that is this time,
>> right?
>> right? Would
that is this time,
>> right? Would it
>> right? Would it be
that is this time,
>> right? Would it be appropriate
>> right? Would it be appropriate for
that is this time,
>> right? Would it be appropriate for me
>> right? Would it be appropriate for me at
this
this time
this time to
this time to do
this time to do it
this time to do it with
this time to do it with my
this time to do it with my patient?
Would
Would it
this time to do it with my patient?
Would it be
Would it be for
this time to do it with my patient?
Would it be for the
Would it be for the highest
this time to do it with my patient?
Would it be for the highest good
Would it be for the highest good for
everybody
everybody concerned?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you
everybody concerned?
>> Oh, you mean
>> Oh, you mean using
everybody concerned?
>> Oh, you mean using the
>> Oh, you mean using the patient
everybody concerned?
>> Oh, you mean using the patient to
>> Oh, you mean using the patient to do
everybody concerned?
>> Oh, you mean using the patient to do the
kinesiology
kinesiology with
kinesiology with the
kinesiology with the patient?
kinesiology with the patient? I
kinesiology with the patient? I use
kinesiology with the patient? I use the
second
second person.
kinesiology with the patient? I use the
second person. See,
second person. See, so
kinesiology with the patient? I use the
second person. See, so if
second person. See, so if the
kinesiology with the patient? I use the
second person. See, so if the patient's
over
over there,
>> you
>> you got
over there,
>> you got to
>> you got to understand.
over there,
>> you got to understand. Let
>> you got to understand. Let me
over there,
>> you got to understand. Let me answer.
>> you got to understand. Let me answer. If
the
the patient's
the patient's over
the patient's over there,
the patient's over there, I
the patient's over there, I don't
the patient's over there, I don't use
the
the patient's
the patient's over there, I don't use
the patient's arm.
the patient's arm. See?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. My
>> I'll
>> I'll say
>> Yeah. My
>> I'll say to
>> I'll say to her,
>> Yeah. My
>> I'll say to her, you
>> I'll say to her, you know,
>> I'm
>> I'm not
>> I'm not using
>> I'm not using it
>> I'm not using it yet.
>> Yes.
>> So
>> So my
>> So my question
>> So my question is,
>> So my question is, is
>> So my question is, is it
>> So my question is, is it for
>> So my question is, is it for the
>> So my question is, is it for the highest
good
good of
>> So my question is, is it for the highest
good of myself
good of myself or
>> So my question is, is it for the highest
good of myself or my
good of myself or my patients
>> So my question is, is it for the highest
good of myself or my patients to
good of myself or my patients to start
using
using muscle
using muscle testing?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You
using muscle testing?
>> Yeah. You don't
>> Yeah. You don't even
using muscle testing?
>> Yeah. You don't even have
>> Yeah. You don't even have to
using muscle testing?
>> Yeah. You don't even have to test
>> Yeah. You don't even have to test it.
>> I've
>> I've been
>> I've been doing
>> I've been doing it
>> I've been doing it for
>> I've been doing it for decades.
>> I've been doing it for decades. You're
asking
asking me
>> I've been doing it for decades. You're
asking me now
asking me now if
>> I've been doing it for decades. You're
asking me now if there's
asking me now if there's any
>> I've been doing it for decades. You're
asking me now if there's any value.
>> It's
>> It's good
>> It's good for
>> It's good for you.
>> It's good for you. But
>> is
>> is it
>> It's good for you. But
>> is it good
>> is it good for
>> It's good for you. But
>> is it good for me?
>> Yes.
>> All
>> All right.
>> Yes.
>> All right. It
>> All right. It would
>> Yes.
>> All right. It would Okay,
>> All right. It would Okay, I
>> Yes.
>> All right. It would Okay, I got
>> All right. It would Okay, I got you.
>> Yes.
>> All right. It would Okay, I got you. It
would
would serve
would serve the
would serve the highest
would serve the highest good
would serve the highest good for
would serve the highest good for her
would serve the highest good for her to
learn
learn about
would serve the highest good for her to
learn about it
learn about it and
would serve the highest good for her to
learn about it and utilize
learn about it and utilize it
would serve the highest good for her to
learn about it and utilize it in
learn about it and utilize it in her
clinical
clinical practice.
clinical practice. Resist.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, because
clinical practice. Resist.
>> Yeah, because you
>> Yeah, because you can
clinical practice. Resist.
>> Yeah, because you can get
>> Yeah, because you can get information
you
you can't
you can't get
you can't get any
you can't get any other
you can't get any other way.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
you can't get any other way.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Diagnosed
>> Diagnosed quickly.
>> Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. like
>> Thank you. like I
>> Thank you. like I I'll
>> Thank you. like I I'll I'll
>> Thank you. like I I'll I'll I'll
>> Thank you. like I I'll I'll I'll get
>> Thank you. like I I'll I'll I'll get the
the
the the
>> Thank you. like I I'll I'll I'll get the
the the dosage,
the the dosage, you
>> Thank you. like I I'll I'll I'll get the
the the dosage, you know,
the the dosage, you know, uh
>> propylure
>> propylure 25
>> propylure 25 milligrams
>> propylure 25 milligrams a
>> propylure 25 milligrams a day,
>> propylure 25 milligrams a day, 50,
>> propylure 25 milligrams a day, 50, 75,
100,
100, and
>> propylure 25 milligrams a day, 50, 75,
100, and I'll
100, and I'll get
>> propylure 25 milligrams a day, 50, 75,
100, and I'll get the
100, and I'll get the exact
>> propylure 25 milligrams a day, 50, 75,
100, and I'll get the exact thing,
100, and I'll get the exact thing, you
know.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, great.
know.
>> Okay, great. Yeah.
>> Okay, great. Yeah. Thank
know.
>> Okay, great. Yeah. Thank you.
>> And
>> And and
>> And and there's
>> And and there's many
>> And and there's many clinical
>> And and there's many clinical tests
>> And and there's many clinical tests that
could
could give
>> And and there's many clinical tests that
could give it
could give it could
>> And and there's many clinical tests that
could give it could fine-tune
could give it could fine-tune it
>> And and there's many clinical tests that
could give it could fine-tune it like
that.
>> That's
>> That's true.
>> Yeah.
>> Thanks.
>> Now,
>> Now, you'll
>> Now, you'll find
>> Now, you'll find it's
>> Now, you'll find it's a
>> Now, you'll find it's a great
>> Now, you'll find it's a great service
>> Now, you'll find it's a great service to
your
your your
>> Now, you'll find it's a great service to
your your patients
your your patients and
>> Now, you'll find it's a great service to
your your patients and to
your your patients and to yourself,
>> Now, you'll find it's a great service to
your your patients and to yourself, too.
Clarification.
>> And
>> And you
Clarification.
>> And you can
>> And you can do
Clarification.
>> And you can do it
>> And you can do it by
Clarification.
>> And you can do it by yourself,
>> And you can do it by yourself, too.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Yeah. And you
>> Yeah. And you can't
>> Yeah. And you can't always
>> Yeah. And you can't always get
>> Yeah. And you can't always get the
diagnostic
diagnostic test
>> Yeah. And you can't always get the
diagnostic test you
diagnostic test you want.
>> Yeah. And you can't always get the
diagnostic test you want. It's
diagnostic test you want. It's too
expensive.
expensive. It's
expensive. It's too
expensive. It's too far
expensive. It's too far to
expensive. It's too far to travel.
>> Yeah.
>> Very.
>> Yeah. You
>> Yeah. You can
>> Very.
>> Yeah. You can check
>> Yeah. You can check out
>> Very.
>> Yeah. You can check out the
>> Yeah. You can check out the electroc
cardiogram
cardiogram without
cardiogram without having
cardiogram without having to
cardiogram without having to put
cardiogram without having to put wires
on
on them.
>> I
>> I want
>> I want to
>> I want to thank
>> I want to thank you
>> I want to thank you for
>> I want to thank you for this
opportunity.
opportunity. It's
>> I want to thank you for this
opportunity. It's great
opportunity. It's great to
>> I want to thank you for this
opportunity. It's great to be
opportunity. It's great to be here
>> I want to thank you for this
opportunity. It's great to be here and
opportunity. It's great to be here and I
have
have a
have a similar
have a similar question.
have a similar question. I
have a similar question. I have
have a similar question. I have I'm
have a similar question. I have I'm a
little
little bit
have a similar question. I have I'm a
little bit confused
little bit confused with
have a similar question. I have I'm a
little bit confused with this
self-ringing
self-ringing test
>> sometimes
>> sometimes oring
self-ringing test
>> sometimes oring test
>> and
>> and is
>> and is it
>> and is it sometimes
>> and is it sometimes it
>> and is it sometimes it works
>> and is it sometimes it works sometimes
yes
>> it
>> it doesn't
>> it doesn't it
>> it doesn't it doesn't
>> it doesn't it doesn't work
>> it doesn't it doesn't work and
>> it doesn't it doesn't work and then
>> it doesn't it doesn't work and then the
question
question is
>> it doesn't it doesn't work and then the
question is can
question is can I
>> it doesn't it doesn't work and then the
question is can I rely
question is can I rely on
>> it doesn't it doesn't work and then the
question is can I rely on it
question is can I rely on it to
>> it doesn't it doesn't work and then the
question is can I rely on it to make
decisions
decisions or
>> you
>> you you
decisions or
>> you you have
>> you you have to
decisions or
>> you you have to practice
>> you you have to practice and
decisions or
>> you you have to practice and and
>> you you have to practice and and you
decisions or
>> you you have to practice and and you the
confidence
confidence you
confidence you put
confidence you put into
confidence you put into it
confidence you put into it uh
confidence you put into it uh depends
confidence you put into it uh depends on
on
on on
confidence you put into it uh depends on
on on experience
uh
>> and
>> and vested
uh
>> and vested interest
>> yes
>> yes you
>> yes you have
>> yes you have to
>> yes you have to clarify
>> yes you have to clarify dested
>> yes you have to clarify dested interest.
That's
That's the
>> yes you have to clarify dested interest.
That's the problem
That's the problem with
>> yes you have to clarify dested interest.
That's the problem with doing
That's the problem with doing it
>> yes you have to clarify dested interest.
That's the problem with doing it by
yourself.
yourself. You
yourself. You see
yourself. You see what
yourself. You see what the
yourself. You see what the reason
yourself. You see what the reason you're
asking
asking it
yourself. You see what the reason you're
asking it is
asking it is because
yourself. You see what the reason you're
asking it is because you
asking it is because you want
yourself. You see what the reason you're
asking it is because you want you
asking it is because you want you really
want
want confirmation
want confirmation of
want confirmation of something.
want confirmation of something. See,
want confirmation of something. See, so
you've
you've already
want confirmation of something. See, so
you've already sort
you've already sort of
want confirmation of something. See, so
you've already sort of biased
you've already sort of biased and
want confirmation of something. See, so
you've already sort of biased and it's
very
very hard
very hard to
very hard to be
very hard to be purely
very hard to be purely objective.
very hard to be purely objective. You
know,
know, it's
very hard to be purely objective. You
know, it's hard
know, it's hard to
very hard to be purely objective. You
know, it's hard to be
know, it's hard to be purely
very hard to be purely objective. You
know, it's hard to be purely objective
and
and and
and and that's
and and that's the
and and that's the the
and and that's the the the
and and that's the the the problem
and and that's the the the problem is
and and that's the the the problem is to
uh
uh pray
and and that's the the the problem is to
uh pray for
uh pray for objectivity.
uh
uh to
uh to not
uh to not interject
uh to not interject your
uh to not interject your your
uh to not interject your your ego
uh to not interject your your ego into
uh
uh having
uh to not interject your your ego into
uh having uh
uh having uh a
uh to not interject your your ego into
uh having uh a favorable
uh having uh a favorable answer
uh to not interject your your ego into
uh having uh a favorable answer one
uh having uh a favorable answer one way
or
or the
or the other.
or the other. You
or the other. You know what
or the other. You know what I'm
or the other. You know what I'm saying?
>> That's
>> That's a
or the other. You know what I'm saying?
>> That's a discipline.
>> And
>> And how
>> And how do
>> And how do you
>> And how do you how
>> And how do you how do
>> And how do you how do you
>> And how do you how do you improve
>> And how do you how do you improve that
discipline?
>> By
>> By be
>> By be learning
>> By be learning how
>> By be learning how to
>> By be learning how to become
>> By be learning how to become detached,
>> detached
>> detached from
>> By be learning how to become detached,
>> detached from the
>> detached from the answer
>> By be learning how to become detached,
>> detached from the answer or
>> detached from the answer or detach
>> By be learning how to become detached,
>> detached from the answer or detach from
the
the question.
>> Detach
>> Detach on
the question.
>> Detach on the
>> Detach on the question
the question.
>> Detach on the question on
>> Detach on the question on the
the question.
>> Detach on the question on the answer.
You
You can't
You can't have
You can't have any
You can't have any stake
You can't have any stake in
You can't have any stake in the
You can't have any stake in the answer.
If
If you're
You can't have any stake in the answer.
If you're going
If you're going to
You can't have any stake in the answer.
If you're going to make
If you're going to make a
You can't have any stake in the answer.
If you're going to make a decision
If you're going to make a decision based
on
on the
on the answer,
on the answer, then
on the answer, then you
on the answer, then you it's
on the answer, then you it's not
possible
possible not
on the answer, then you it's not
possible not to
possible not to have
on the answer, then you it's not
possible not to have a
possible not to have a stake
on the answer, then you it's not
possible not to have a stake in
possible not to have a stake in it.
>> Check
>> Check it
>> Check it with
>> Check it with somebody
>> Check it with somebody else
>> Check it with somebody else then.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, you
>> Check it with somebody else then.
>> Yeah, you could
>> Yeah, you could have
>> Check it with somebody else then.
>> Yeah, you could have somebody
>> Yeah, you could have somebody check
>> Check it with somebody else then.
>> Yeah, you could have somebody check it
for
for you.
for you. Um
for you. Um I
for you. Um I can't
for you. Um I can't tell
for you. Um I can't tell you
for you. Um I can't tell you how
for you. Um I can't tell you how to
detach
detach yourself
for you. Um I can't tell you how to
detach yourself from
detach yourself from willfulness.
for you. Um I can't tell you how to
detach yourself from willfulness. Uh
it's
it's a
it's a practice.
Um
willfulness
willfulness will
willfulness will interfere.
willfulness will interfere. So
to
to become
willfulness will interfere. So
to become detached
to become detached from
willfulness will interfere. So
to become detached from the
to become detached from the answer
willfulness will interfere. So
to become detached from the answer means
first
first I
first I want
first I want to
first I want to know
first I want to know what
first I want to know what the
first I want to know what the truth
first I want to know what the truth is.
then
then I'll
first I want to know what the truth is.
then I'll decide
then I'll decide what
first I want to know what the truth is.
then I'll decide what to
then I'll decide what to do
first I want to know what the truth is.
then I'll decide what to do about
then I'll decide what to do about the
truth.
truth. So
truth. So don't
truth. So don't feel
truth. So don't feel that
truth. So don't feel that getting
truth. So don't feel that getting an
answer
answer now
truth. So don't feel that getting an
answer now forces
answer now forces you
truth. So don't feel that getting an
answer now forces you to
answer now forces you to take
truth. So don't feel that getting an
answer now forces you to take a
answer now forces you to take a certain
path
path because
path because that'll
path because that'll give
path because that'll give you
path because that'll give you a
resistance.
resistance. First
path because that'll give you a
resistance. First I
resistance. First I want
path because that'll give you a
resistance. First I want to
resistance. First I want to know
path because that'll give you a
resistance. First I want to know the
truth
truth of
truth of it
truth of it then
truth of it then I'll
truth of it then I'll decide
truth of it then I'll decide what
truth of it then I'll decide what to
truth of it then I'll decide what to do
about
about it.
truth of it then I'll decide what to do
about it. But
about it. But I
truth of it then I'll decide what to do
about it. But I just
about it. But I just got
truth of it then I'll decide what to do
about it. But I just got through
drinking
drinking had
drinking had poison
drinking had poison in
drinking had poison in it.
drinking had poison in it. Yes.
drinking had poison in it. Yes. No.
drinking had poison in it. Yes. No. Yes.
I
I didn't
drinking had poison in it. Yes. No. Yes.
I didn't want
I didn't want to
drinking had poison in it. Yes. No. Yes.
I didn't want to hear
I didn't want to hear the
drinking had poison in it. Yes. No. Yes.
I didn't want to hear the yes.
I didn't want to hear the yes. Yeah.
drinking had poison in it. Yes. No. Yes.
I didn't want to hear the yes. Yeah. But
now
now that
now that I
now that I got
now that I got the
now that I got the yes,
now that I got the yes, now
now that I got the yes, now I
now that I got the yes, now I can
now that I got the yes, now I can decide
what
what to
now that I got the yes, now I can decide
what to do
what to do about
now that I got the yes, now I can decide
what to do about it.
what to do about it. I
now that I got the yes, now I can decide
what to do about it. I should
what to do about it. I should get
now that I got the yes, now I can decide
what to do about it. I should get my
stomach
stomach pumped.
stomach pumped. I
stomach pumped. I should
stomach pumped. I should commit
stomach pumped. I should commit suicide.
You
You know
stomach pumped. I should commit suicide.
You know what
You know what I'm
stomach pumped. I should commit suicide.
You know what I'm saying?
First,
First, you
First, you want
First, you want to
First, you want to detach
First, you want to detach from
First, you want to detach from the
answer.
answer. First,
First, you want to detach from the
answer. First, I
answer. First, I want
First, you want to detach from the
answer. First, I want to
answer. First, I want to know
First, you want to detach from the
answer. First, I want to know the
answer.
answer. Then,
answer. Then, I
answer. Then, I will
answer. Then, I will figure
answer. Then, I will figure out
answer. Then, I will figure out what
answer. Then, I will figure out what to
do
do about
answer. Then, I will figure out what to
do about it.
do about it. Don't
answer. Then, I will figure out what to
do about it. Don't put
do about it. Don't put what
answer. Then, I will figure out what to
do about it. Don't put what to
do about it. Don't put what to do
answer. Then, I will figure out what to
do about it. Don't put what to do about
it
it on
it on top
it on top of
it on top of the
it on top of the answer.
You
You know,
it on top of the answer.
You know, if
You know, if it's
it on top of the answer.
You know, if it's you
You know, if it's you say
it on top of the answer.
You know, if it's you say yes,
You know, if it's you say yes, you
it on top of the answer.
You know, if it's you say yes, you got
to
to quick
to quick sell
to quick sell your
to quick sell your house
to quick sell your house or
to quick sell your house or get
to quick sell your house or get a
divorce.
divorce. That's
to quick sell your house or get a
divorce. That's putting
divorce. That's putting too
to quick sell your house or get a
divorce. That's putting too much
divorce. That's putting too much on
to quick sell your house or get a
divorce. That's putting too much on it.
You
You could
You could say
You could say would
You could say would serve
You could say would serve the
You could say would serve the highest
good
good to
You could say would serve the highest
good to not
good to not continue
You could say would serve the highest
good to not continue this
good to not continue this relationship.
Yes.
Yes. No.
Yes. No. Okay.
Yes. No. Okay. Now
Yes. No. Okay. Now that
Yes. No. Okay. Now that you
Yes. No. Okay. Now that you got
Yes. No. Okay. Now that you got a
Yes. No. Okay. Now that you got a yes
Yes. No. Okay. Now that you got a yes or
a
a no,
Yes. No. Okay. Now that you got a yes or
a no, you
a no, you can
Yes. No. Okay. Now that you got a yes or
a no, you can decide
a no, you can decide what
Yes. No. Okay. Now that you got a yes or
a no, you can decide what to
a no, you can decide what to do
Yes. No. Okay. Now that you got a yes or
a no, you can decide what to do about
it.
it. But
it. But don't
it. But don't put
it. But don't put one
it. But don't put one contingent
it. But don't put one contingent on
it. But don't put one contingent on the
other.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
Yes.
>> You
>> You don't
>> You don't want
>> You don't want a
>> You don't want a payoff
>> You don't want a payoff on
>> You don't want a payoff on the
>> You don't want a payoff on the answer.
You
You want
>> You don't want a payoff on the answer.
You want the
You want the only
>> You don't want a payoff on the answer.
You want the only payoff
You want the only payoff you
>> You don't want a payoff on the answer.
You want the only payoff you want
You want the only payoff you want is
>> You don't want a payoff on the answer.
You want the only payoff you want is you
want
want the
want the truth.
want the truth. Period.
>> Then
>> Then we'll
want the truth. Period.
>> Then we'll figure
>> Then we'll figure out
want the truth. Period.
>> Then we'll figure out what
>> Then we'll figure out what to
want the truth. Period.
>> Then we'll figure out what to do
>> Then we'll figure out what to do about
it.
it. Once
it. Once you
it. Once you have
it. Once you have the
it. Once you have the truth,
it. Once you have the truth, you
it. Once you have the truth, you can
process
process it.
it. Once you have the truth, you can
process it. Then
>> doctor,
>> doctor, in
>> doctor, in your
>> doctor, in your book,
>> doctor, in your book, Eye
>> doctor, in your book, Eye of
>> doctor, in your book, Eye of the
>> doctor, in your book, Eye of the Eye,
>> doctor, in your book, Eye of the Eye, I
read
read a
>> doctor, in your book, Eye of the Eye, I
read a phrase
read a phrase in
>> doctor, in your book, Eye of the Eye, I
read a phrase in there
read a phrase in there that
>> doctor, in your book, Eye of the Eye, I
read a phrase in there that resonated
with
with me
with me and
with me and I
with me and I didn't
with me and I didn't read
with me and I didn't read any
explanation
explanation of
with me and I didn't read any
explanation of it.
explanation of it. It
with me and I didn't read any
explanation of it. It was
explanation of it. It was a
with me and I didn't read any
explanation of it. It was a radical
humility.
>> Yeah.
Uh
Uh I
Uh I do
Uh I do you
Uh I do you did
Uh I do you did you
Uh I do you did you explain
Uh I do you did you explain that
Uh I do you did you explain that in
Uh I do you did you explain that in any
of
of your
Uh I do you did you explain that in any
of your other
of your other books
Uh I do you did you explain that in any
of your other books because
of your other books because um
>> is
>> is there
>> is there some
>> is there some way
>> is there some way that
>> is there some way that I
>> is there some way that I can
>> is there some way that I can find
>> is there some way that I can find out
just
just the
>> is there some way that I can find out
just the extent
just the extent of
>> the
>> the willingness
>> the willingness to
>> the willingness to of
>> the willingness to of humility
>> the willingness to of humility means
>> the willingness to of humility means the
willingness
willingness to
>> the willingness to of humility means the
willingness to surrender
willingness to surrender one's
>> the willingness to of humility means the
willingness to surrender one's will
willingness to surrender one's will to
God
God is
God is really
God is really what
God is really what it
God is really what it is.
God is really what it is. Um
it's
it's hard
God is really what it is. Um
it's hard to
it's hard to say
God is really what it is. Um
it's hard to say what
it's hard to say what humility
God is really what it is. Um
it's hard to say what humility is.
Humility
Humility is
Humility is the
Humility is the willingness
Humility is the willingness to
Humility is the willingness to surrender
one's
one's will
Humility is the willingness to surrender
one's will to
one's will to God.
Humility is the willingness to surrender
one's will to God. That's
one's will to God. That's what
Humility is the willingness to surrender
one's will to God. That's what it
one's will to God. That's what it is.
uh
uh without
uh without any
uh without any valition
uh without any valition in
uh without any valition in one
uh without any valition in one way
uh without any valition in one way or
the
the other
and
and the
and the presumption
and the presumption of
and the presumption of basic
and the presumption of basic human
ignorance.
ignorance. I
and the presumption of basic human
ignorance. I of
ignorance. I of myself
and the presumption of basic human
ignorance. I of myself know
ignorance. I of myself know nothing
of
of the
of the small
of the small self
of the small self know
of the small self know nothing.
of the small self know nothing. Yeah.
Mhm.
I
I thought
I thought maybe
I thought maybe that
I thought maybe that other
I thought maybe that other than
I thought maybe that other than humility
would
would be
I thought maybe that other than humility
would be a
would be a radical
I thought maybe that other than humility
would be a radical approach
would be a radical approach to
I thought maybe that other than humility
would be a radical approach to pursuing
humility.
humility. But
>> yes,
>> yes, well
humility. But
>> yes, well humility
>> yes, well humility can
humility. But
>> yes, well humility can be
in
in other
in other words
in other words any
in other words any any
in other words any any spiritual
endeavor
endeavor can
in other words any any spiritual
endeavor can be
endeavor can be pursued
in other words any any spiritual
endeavor can be pursued to
endeavor can be pursued to a
in other words any any spiritual
endeavor can be pursued to a certain
endeavor can be pursued to a certain to
certain
certain degrees
like
like dedication
certain degrees
like dedication can
like dedication can be
certain degrees
like dedication can be extreme.
The
The dedication
The dedication to
The dedication to not
The dedication to not swerve
The dedication to not swerve from
The dedication to not swerve from a
The dedication to not swerve from a path
no
no matter
The dedication to not swerve from a path
no matter what.
All right.
All right. So
All right. So when
All right. So when you
All right. So when you get
All right. So when you get to
All right. So when you get to the
All right. So when you get to the end
All right. So when you get to the end of
the
the spiritual
All right. So when you get to the end of
the spiritual evolution,
you've
you've made
you've made a
you've made a commitment
you've made a commitment no
you've made a commitment no matter
you've made a commitment no matter what.
It's
It's the
you've made a commitment no matter what.
It's the no
It's the no matter
you've made a commitment no matter what.
It's the no matter whatness
It's the no matter whatness that
you've made a commitment no matter what.
It's the no matter whatness that makes
the
the power
the power so
powerful.
powerful. No
the power so
powerful. No matter
powerful. No matter what.
>> Great.
>> Great. Thank
>> Great. Thank you.
>> Great. Thank you. Thank
>> Great. Thank you. Thank you.
I
I will
>> Great. Thank you. Thank you.
I will go
I will go through
>> Great. Thank you. Thank you.
I will go through this
I will go through this surgery
>> Great. Thank you. Thank you.
I will go through this surgery without
anesthesia
anesthesia no
anesthesia no matter
anesthesia no matter what.
anesthesia no matter what. No
anesthesia no matter what. No matter
what
what the
anesthesia no matter what. No matter
what the degree
what the degree of
anesthesia no matter what. No matter
what the degree of pain,
what the degree of pain, let's
anesthesia no matter what. No matter
what the degree of pain, let's say.
what the degree of pain, let's say. And
then
then you
then you start
then you start surrendering
then you start surrendering the
then you start surrendering the pain.
>> Yes.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. I
>> Hi. I just
>> Hi. I just wanted
>> Hi. I just wanted to
>> Hi. I just wanted to express
>> Hi. I just wanted to express my
gratitude.
gratitude. Thank
>> Hi. I just wanted to express my
gratitude. Thank you
gratitude. Thank you to
>> Hi. I just wanted to express my
gratitude. Thank you to both
gratitude. Thank you to both of
>> Hi. I just wanted to express my
gratitude. Thank you to both of you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you,
>> Thank you, sweetie.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, thank
>> Thank you, sweetie.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> I
>> I thought
>> I thought she
>> I thought she had
>> I thought she had a
>> I thought she had a question.
>> No,
>> No, she
>> I thought she had a question.
>> No, she just
>> No, she just wanted
>> I thought she had a question.
>> No, she just wanted to
>> No, she just wanted to exchange
energies.
>> Hi,
>> Hi, Doc.
energies.
>> Hi, Doc. I
>> Hi, Doc. I just
energies.
>> Hi, Doc. I just wanted
>> Hi, Doc. I just wanted to
energies.
>> Hi, Doc. I just wanted to say
>> Hi, Doc. I just wanted to say thank
energies.
>> Hi, Doc. I just wanted to say thank you,
too.
too. I
too. I appreciate
too. I appreciate it.
>> God
>> God bless
too. I appreciate it.
>> God bless you.
>> Thanks.
What
What a
>> Thanks.
What a gift
What a gift they
>> Thanks.
What a gift they are
What a gift they are to
>> Thanks.
What a gift they are to me
What a gift they are to me these
>> Thanks.
What a gift they are to me these people.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, we're
>> Okay, we're all
>> Okay, we're all done.
>> Okay, we're all done. They
>> Okay, we're all done. They ask
>> Okay, we're all done. They ask that
>> Okay, we're all done. They ask that you
say
say a
>> Okay, we're all done. They ask that you
say a prayer
say a prayer for
>> Okay, we're all done. They ask that you
say a prayer for the
say a prayer for the audience.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I'm
>> Oh, I'm not
>> Oh, I'm not praying
>> Oh, I'm not praying for
>> Oh, I'm not praying for this
>> Oh, I'm not praying for this audience.
They
They don't
>> Oh, I'm not praying for this audience.
They don't need
They don't need my
>> Oh, I'm not praying for this audience.
They don't need my prayers.
They don't need my prayers. This
audience
audience does
audience does not
audience does not need
audience does not need my
audience does not need my prayers.
audience does not need my prayers. Let
me
me tell
audience does not need my prayers. Let
me tell you
me tell you that.
audience does not need my prayers. Let
me tell you that. This
me tell you that. This audience
audience does not need my prayers. Let
me tell you that. This audience is
already
already such
already such an
already such an incredible
already such an incredible blessing.
This
This audience
already such an incredible blessing.
This audience is
This audience is God's
already such an incredible blessing.
This audience is God's gift
This audience is God's gift to
already such an incredible blessing.
This audience is God's gift to me.
This audience is God's gift to me. I
surrendered
surrendered my
surrendered my life
surrendered my life to
surrendered my life to God
surrendered my life to God and
surrendered my life to God and laid
surrendered my life to God and laid down
my
my life
surrendered my life to God and laid down
my life to
my life to God
surrendered my life to God and laid down
my life to God and
my life to God and all
surrendered my life to God and laid down
my life to God and all of a
my life to God and all of a sudden
surrendered my life to God and laid down
my life to God and all of a sudden look
what
what I
what I get.
So
So this
what I get.
So this group
So this group is
what I get.
So this group is my
So this group is my dessert
what I get.
So this group is my dessert and
So this group is my dessert and my
what I get.
So this group is my dessert and my God
uh
uh God's
uh God's love
uh God's love expresses
uh God's love expresses itself
uh God's love expresses itself toward
towards
towards me.
uh God's love expresses itself toward
towards me. So
towards me. So I
uh God's love expresses itself toward
towards me. So I am
towards me. So I am very
uh God's love expresses itself toward
towards me. So I am very thankful
towards me. So I am very thankful for
your
your presence.
your presence. I'm
your presence. I'm very
your presence. I'm very thankful
your presence. I'm very thankful for
your
your love
your presence. I'm very thankful for
your love and
your love and I
your presence. I'm very thankful for
your love and I do
your love and I do indeed
your presence. I'm very thankful for
your love and I do indeed bless
your love and I do indeed bless thee
your presence. I'm very thankful for
your love and I do indeed bless thee in
the
the name
the name of
the name of the
the name of the Lord
the name of the Lord to
the name of the Lord to the
the name of the Lord to the extent
the name of the Lord to the extent that
I
I am
gifted
gifted to
gifted to do
gifted to do so
gifted to do so and
gifted to do so and I
gifted to do so and I ask
gifted to do so and I ask for
gifted to do so and I ask for thy
blessing
blessing oh
gifted to do so and I ask for thy
blessing oh Lord
blessing oh Lord on
gifted to do so and I ask for thy
blessing oh Lord on this
blessing oh Lord on this thy
gifted to do so and I ask for thy
blessing oh Lord on this thy servants
uh
uh for
uh for whom
uh for whom I
uh for whom I have
uh for whom I have great
uh for whom I have great joy
and
those
those who
those who surrender
those who surrender themselves
those who surrender themselves and
dedicate
dedicate themselves
those who surrender themselves and
dedicate themselves to
dedicate themselves to God
those who surrender themselves and
dedicate themselves to God belong
dedicate themselves to God belong to
those who surrender themselves and
dedicate themselves to God belong to God
those
those who
those who surrendered
those who surrendered themselves.
Krishna
Krishna said
those who surrendered themselves.
Krishna said to
Krishna said to me
those who surrendered themselves.
Krishna said to me become
Krishna said to me become mine.
those who surrendered themselves.
Krishna said to me become mine. In
Krishna said to me become mine. In the
91st
91st psalm,
91st psalm, it
91st psalm, it says
91st psalm, it says those
91st psalm, it says those who
91st psalm, it says those who surrender
and
and serve
91st psalm, it says those who surrender
and serve me
and serve me become
91st psalm, it says those who surrender
and serve me become mine.
and serve me become mine. And
91st psalm, it says those who surrender
and serve me become mine. And I
and serve me become mine. And I declare
thereby
thereby that
thereby that we
thereby that we all
thereby that we all belong
thereby that we all belong therefore
thereby that we all belong therefore to
divinity
divinity by
thereby that we all belong therefore to
divinity by our
divinity by our own
thereby that we all belong therefore to
divinity by our own surrender.
Yeah.
God,
God, we
Yeah.
God, we belong
God, we belong to
Yeah.
God, we belong to God.
God, we belong to God. Yep.
Yeah.
God, we belong to God. Yep. Those
God, we belong to God. Yep. Those who
surrender
surrender to
surrender to God,
surrender to God, those
surrender to God, those who
surrender to God, those who worship
surrender to God, those who worship God,
those
those who
surrender to God, those who worship God,
those who are
those who are devoted
surrender to God, those who worship God,
those who are devoted to
those who are devoted to truth
surrender to God, those who worship God,
those who are devoted to truth become
um
um we
um we belong
um we belong to
um we belong to God.
um we belong to God. So
um we belong to God. So we
um we belong to God. So we claim
um we belong to God. So we claim that
um we belong to God. So we claim that we
belong
belong to
um we belong to God. So we claim that we
belong to the
belong to the old
um we belong to God. So we claim that we
belong to the old Lord.
belong to the old Lord. Wow.
Thank
Thank you
Thank you so
Thank you so much.
We
We all
Thank you so much.
We all come
We all come in
Thank you so much.
We all come in together
We all come in together and
Thank you so much.
We all come in together and we
We all come in together and we all
Thank you so much.
We all come in together and we all stay
together.
together. So
together. So we
together. So we will
together. So we will not
together. So we will not be
together. So we will not be parted
anyway.
anyway. We
together. So we will not be parted
anyway. We are
anyway. We are one
together. So we will not be parted
anyway. We are one flock.
Yeah.
They
They are
Yeah.
They are wonderful
They are wonderful people.
Yeah.
They are wonderful people. I'll
They are wonderful people. I'll tell
Yeah.
They are wonderful people. I'll tell you
what.
>> Get
>> Get your
what.
>> Get your mic
>> Get your mic off.
>> A
>> A bunch
>> A bunch of
>> A bunch of wonderful
>> A bunch of wonderful people.
>> No,
>> No, it's
>> A bunch of wonderful people.
>> No, it's not.
>> And
>> And we'll
>> And we'll come
>> And we'll come right
>> And we'll come right back
>> And we'll come right back here.
>> They're
>> They're greatly
>> And we'll come right back here.
>> They're greatly wonderful
>> They're greatly wonderful people.
>> And we'll come right back here.
>> They're greatly wonderful people. One
after
after another
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.
Halle.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.
Halle.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu