The nearest relationship between the
The nearest relationship between the calibrated level of the 400s and 500s
calibrated level of the 400s and 500s
calibrated level of the 400s and 500s and up is actually quantum mechanics.
and up is actually quantum mechanics.
and up is actually quantum mechanics. And of course, the Heisenberg principle
And of course, the Heisenberg principle
And of course, the Heisenberg principle explains why healings work, why prayer
explains why healings work, why prayer
explains why healings work, why prayer works. It gives some kind of a
works. It gives some kind of a
works. It gives some kind of a scientific respectability.
scientific respectability.
scientific respectability. Uh and this is a we we talk about Henry
Uh and this is a we we talk about Henry
Uh and this is a we we talk about Henry Stamp's uh website is good place to pick
Stamp's uh website is good place to pick
Stamp's uh website is good place to pick it up where the Schroinger
it up where the Schroinger
it up where the Schroinger um early condition is activated by the
um early condition is activated by the
um early condition is activated by the Heisenberg PR principle and the
Heisenberg PR principle and the
Heisenberg PR principle and the collapses the wave function which is the
collapses the wave function which is the
collapses the wave function which is the way we can say in quantum mechanics what
way we can say in quantum mechanics what
way we can say in quantum mechanics what we say in just spiritual teaching that
we say in just spiritual teaching that
we say in just spiritual teaching that potentiality becomes actuality when
potentiality becomes actuality when
potentiality becomes actuality when conditions are appropriate And one of
conditions are appropriate And one of
conditions are appropriate And one of the conditions that is appropriate in in
the conditions that is appropriate in in
the conditions that is appropriate in in the proximate field is intention. So I
the proximate field is intention. So I
the proximate field is intention. So I like Wayne Dyer's book. He picked up on
like Wayne Dyer's book. He picked up on
like Wayne Dyer's book. He picked up on intention
intention
intention to demonstrate its importance by sheer
to demonstrate its importance by sheer
to demonstrate its importance by sheer intention. Then we tend to manifest we
intention. Then we tend to manifest we
intention. Then we tend to manifest we tend to manifest things due to intention
tend to manifest things due to intention
tend to manifest things due to intention because the potentiality actualizes as
because the potentiality actualizes as
because the potentiality actualizes as uh the collapse of the wave function.
uh the collapse of the wave function.
uh the collapse of the wave function. Okay. Next. So that just proves you can
Okay. Next. So that just proves you can
Okay. Next. So that just proves you can be spiritual and also scientific. Right.
be spiritual and also scientific. Right.
be spiritual and also scientific. Right. I know more about the Heisenberg, you
I know more about the Heisenberg, you
I know more about the Heisenberg, you know, quantum mechanics than a lot of
know, quantum mechanics than a lot of
know, quantum mechanics than a lot of physicists do.
physicists do.
physicists do. Why? Because it's it it's like a
Why? Because it's it it's like a
Why? Because it's it it's like a reflection of the spiritual reality
reflection of the spiritual reality
reflection of the spiritual reality which is already second nature, you
which is already second nature, you
which is already second nature, you know, in which you see emergence
know, in which you see emergence
know, in which you see emergence emergence. You don't see causality. You
emergence. You don't see causality. You
emergence. You don't see causality. You say potential. So the world is what
say potential. So the world is what
say potential. So the world is what you're seeing is the emergence of
you're seeing is the emergence of
you're seeing is the emergence of potentiality continuously. It's not
potentiality continuously. It's not
potentiality continuously. It's not cause and effect. There's not a this and
cause and effect. There's not a this and
cause and effect. There's not a this and a that. The this is
a that. The this is
a that. The this is emerging into actuality in the
emerging into actuality in the
emerging into actuality in the three-dimensional expression because on
three-dimensional expression because on
three-dimensional expression because on the level of consciousness it exists
the level of consciousness it exists
the level of consciousness it exists already is potentiality.
already is potentiality.
already is potentiality. Yeah. Sheldrake of course Sheld Drake's
Yeah. Sheldrake of course Sheld Drake's
Yeah. Sheldrake of course Sheld Drake's principle
principle
principle and uh I think it was very important.
and uh I think it was very important.
and uh I think it was very important. Not not too many people quote more
Not not too many people quote more
Not not too many people quote more people should quote Sheldrake than they
people should quote Sheldrake than they
people should quote Sheldrake than they do I think in the world of physics
do I think in the world of physics
do I think in the world of physics because I thought it was very important
because I thought it was very important
because I thought it was very important phenomena. Okay. So the Newtonian
phenomena. Okay. So the Newtonian
phenomena. Okay. So the Newtonian paradigm as you see things are forced
paradigm as you see things are forced
paradigm as you see things are forced cause provable measurable. This is the
cause provable measurable. This is the
cause provable measurable. This is the world of the ego. It is also the world
world of the ego. It is also the world
world of the ego. It is also the world of science. And then quantum mechanics
of science. And then quantum mechanics
of science. And then quantum mechanics we're moving on to a whole different
we're moving on to a whole different
we're moving on to a whole different viewpoint of reality. We see non-local
viewpoint of reality. We see non-local
viewpoint of reality. We see non-local coherence. We see potential. we see the
coherence. We see potential. we see the
coherence. We see potential. we see the time dependent and independent phenomena
time dependent and independent phenomena
time dependent and independent phenomena and the whole world of stochastic or so
and the whole world of stochastic or so
and the whole world of stochastic or so so-called chaotic and in in our work
so-called chaotic and in in our work
so-called chaotic and in in our work those are attractor fields. So in the
those are attractor fields. So in the
those are attractor fields. So in the scale of consciousness each one of those
scale of consciousness each one of those
scale of consciousness each one of those levels represents an attractor field
levels represents an attractor field
levels represents an attractor field from the viewpoint of nonlinear
from the viewpoint of nonlinear
from the viewpoint of nonlinear dynamics. It has an energy to it. Just
dynamics. It has an energy to it. Just
dynamics. It has an energy to it. Just as I say, there's only one orange cat in
as I say, there's only one orange cat in
as I say, there's only one orange cat in the whole universe. That's an attractor
the whole universe. That's an attractor
the whole universe. That's an attractor field of orange catnness
field of orange catnness
field of orange catnness out of which emerges its representations
out of which emerges its representations
out of which emerges its representations as living orange kitties. But all of
as living orange kitties. But all of
as living orange kitties. But all of them are controlled by the same
them are controlled by the same
them are controlled by the same attractor field. Orange kitties don't
attractor field. Orange kitties don't
attractor field. Orange kitties don't bark. You know, they just in the
bark. You know, they just in the
bark. You know, they just in the attractor field of kittiness. They mute.
attractor field of kittiness. They mute.
attractor field of kittiness. They mute. So yeah, so anyway that creates a
So yeah, so anyway that creates a
So yeah, so anyway that creates a certain amount of order. So in nonlinear
certain amount of order. So in nonlinear
certain amount of order. So in nonlinear dynamics, these are called attractor
dynamics, these are called attractor
dynamics, these are called attractor fields. Some of them are very powerful.
fields. Some of them are very powerful.
fields. Some of them are very powerful. This is why I tell people do not fool
This is why I tell people do not fool
This is why I tell people do not fool around.
around.
around. Do not fool around with deviant pathways
Do not fool around with deviant pathways
Do not fool around with deviant pathways just out of curiosity. Get your kicks
just out of curiosity. Get your kicks
just out of curiosity. Get your kicks some other way. Uh people go to um what
some other way. Uh people go to um what
some other way. Uh people go to um what do they call those? New age fairs.
do they call those? New age fairs.
do they call those? New age fairs. People say, "Well, I'm going to spend
People say, "Well, I'm going to spend
People say, "Well, I'm going to spend the weekend with new age fair." people
the weekend with new age fair." people
the weekend with new age fair." people here doing this that and of course I'm
here doing this that and of course I'm
here doing this that and of course I'm not going to be affected by it by
not going to be affected by it by
not going to be affected by it by because I don't believe in it.
because I don't believe in it.
because I don't believe in it. That's amazing illusion. That's how
That's amazing illusion. That's how
That's amazing illusion. That's how you're led over the cliff because when
you're led over the cliff because when
you're led over the cliff because when you come back from that and I've done it
you come back from that and I've done it
you come back from that and I've done it with many people say, "Well, I went
with many people say, "Well, I went
with many people say, "Well, I went there and they're very nice people had
there and they're very nice people had
there and they're very nice people had horrible time and I didn't believe any
horrible time and I didn't believe any
horrible time and I didn't believe any of it. They weren't affected by it
of it. They weren't affected by it
of it. They weren't affected by it except why do I have to clear myself
except why do I have to clear myself
except why do I have to clear myself after I just got through talking to
after I just got through talking to
after I just got through talking to them?" because they picked up so much
them?" because they picked up so much
them?" because they picked up so much weird negative energy vibrations in
weird negative energy vibrations in
weird negative energy vibrations in their aura. Their aura is full of crap
their aura. Their aura is full of crap
their aura. Their aura is full of crap they picked up from all these people
they picked up from all these people
they picked up from all these people because these people are wanderers
because these people are wanderers
because these people are wanderers through the new age forest and they're
through the new age forest and they're
through the new age forest and they're full of it.
If you looked at their aura with a
If you looked at their aura with a spectroscope, you'd say, "Good God
spectroscope, you'd say, "Good God
spectroscope, you'd say, "Good God almighty." You'd wear a mask. You know
almighty." You'd wear a mask. You know
almighty." You'd wear a mask. You know what I mean?
what I mean?
what I mean? You put on gloves when you shake hands
You put on gloves when you shake hands
You put on gloves when you shake hands with them. sterilizer when you do
with them. sterilizer when you do
with them. sterilizer when you do because you pick up all kinds of
because you pick up all kinds of
because you pick up all kinds of energies are looking for your chinks.
energies are looking for your chinks.
energies are looking for your chinks. Now you think you're beyond chinkism.
Now you think you're beyond chinkism.
Now you think you're beyond chinkism. No, I'll tell you why. What did the
No, I'll tell you why. What did the
No, I'll tell you why. What did the Buddha say at the very end? He says, "I
Buddha say at the very end? He says, "I
Buddha say at the very end? He says, "I was beset by demons." You're talking
was beset by demons." You're talking
was beset by demons." You're talking about the Buddha. You're not talking
about the Buddha. You're not talking
about the Buddha. You're not talking about Sedona, a spiritual aspirin.
about Sedona, a spiritual aspirin.
about Sedona, a spiritual aspirin. The Buddha was beset by demons. And you
The Buddha was beset by demons. And you
The Buddha was beset by demons. And you think you're not going to be you're
think you're not going to be you're
think you're not going to be you're going to walk through the muck field
going to walk through the muck field
going to walk through the muck field and then come and visit me. Uh please
because of sophistication and many years
because of sophistication and many years experience I know this phenomena and I'm
experience I know this phenomena and I'm
experience I know this phenomena and I'm aware of what it is. I usually intuit it
aware of what it is. I usually intuit it
aware of what it is. I usually intuit it what it is. Uh there usually appeals to
what it is. Uh there usually appeals to
what it is. Uh there usually appeals to vanity and uh various things like
vanity and uh various things like
vanity and uh various things like anyway. So you know what to clear in
anyway. So you know what to clear in
anyway. So you know what to clear in yourself. You know what to clear in
yourself. You know what to clear in
yourself. You know what to clear in yourself, what to pray for, etc. But the
yourself, what to pray for, etc. But the
yourself, what to pray for, etc. But the average person thinks that they have not
average person thinks that they have not
average person thinks that they have not been affected.
been affected.
been affected. You have to, you know, smudge the house
You have to, you know, smudge the house
You have to, you know, smudge the house after they visit you and they think they
after they visit you and they think they
after they visit you and they think they have been unaffected.
have been unaffected.
have been unaffected. There's those negative spirits and
There's those negative spirits and
There's those negative spirits and demons running all over the place.
So, you're not going to walk through the
So, you're not going to walk through the field and not come out with stickers on
field and not come out with stickers on
field and not come out with stickers on you. Ain't going to happen.
you. Ain't going to happen.
you. Ain't going to happen. If the Buddha had that complaint, what
If the Buddha had that complaint, what
If the Buddha had that complaint, what what's your chance? You're going to go
what's your chance? You're going to go
what's your chance? You're going to go out and hang hang out with people that
out and hang hang out with people that
out and hang hang out with people that all are so surrounded by demons. The
all are so surrounded by demons. The
all are so surrounded by demons. The truth. Yeah. All kinds of white magic
truth. Yeah. All kinds of white magic
truth. Yeah. All kinds of white magic and black magic and god knows what.
and black magic and god knows what.
and black magic and god knows what. That's a tier. Alistister Crowley,
That's a tier. Alistister Crowley,
That's a tier. Alistister Crowley, the Golden Dawn. You think you can read
the Golden Dawn. You think you can read
the Golden Dawn. You think you can read officer Crowley play the tarot deck. The
officer Crowley play the tarot deck. The
officer Crowley play the tarot deck. The Carly deck.
Carly deck.
Carly deck. Let's ask what's the Cly deck at?
Let's ask what's the Cly deck at?
Let's ask what's the Cly deck at? We have permission.
We have permission.
We have permission. Carly deck celebrates over 60
Carly deck celebrates over 60
Carly deck celebrates over 60 55. You're going to play with the
55. You're going to play with the
55. You're going to play with the Crowley deck. Tell me you had a good
Crowley deck. Tell me you had a good
Crowley deck. Tell me you had a good time at the New Age Fair. Had your cards
time at the New Age Fair. Had your cards
time at the New Age Fair. Had your cards read and it didn't affect you, right?
read and it didn't affect you, right?
read and it didn't affect you, right? Of course it affected you.
Of course it affected you.
Of course it affected you. That's why the guides on the other side
That's why the guides on the other side
That's why the guides on the other side do so well
do so well
do so well because your weakness is transparent.
because your weakness is transparent.
because your weakness is transparent. Transparent.
Transparent.
Transparent. Just like a germ knows where to feed on
Just like a germ knows where to feed on
Just like a germ knows where to feed on you. You're transparent to them. These
you. You're transparent to them. These
you. You're transparent to them. These spirit guides on the other side, master
spirit guides on the other side, master
spirit guides on the other side, master poo poo and paba and gaba, they all have
poo poo and paba and gaba, they all have
poo poo and paba and gaba, they all have a fancy name. Intuit from the psychic
a fancy name. Intuit from the psychic
a fancy name. Intuit from the psychic realm what you're thinking has got you.
realm what you're thinking has got you.
realm what you're thinking has got you. The minute you sit down for a reading,
The minute you sit down for a reading,
The minute you sit down for a reading, >> they've already got you. Don't you
>> they've already got you. Don't you
>> they've already got you. Don't you understand? They just read you.
understand? They just read you.
understand? They just read you. They just read you.
They just read you.
They just read you. Got you just where you want to hear.
So, of course, they sound impressive.
So, of course, they sound impressive. They sound impressive because anybody
They sound impressive because anybody
They sound impressive because anybody who's psychic can do that. I've had
who's psychic can do that. I've had
who's psychic can do that. I've had psychic friends over the years. This is
psychic friends over the years. This is
psychic friends over the years. This is intuitive.
intuitive.
intuitive. Susan is very psychic. If I'm holding
Susan is very psychic. If I'm holding
Susan is very psychic. If I'm holding something in mind, I'll say she'll say,
something in mind, I'll say she'll say,
something in mind, I'll say she'll say, "Oh, so and so, she's got it already."
"Oh, so and so, she's got it already."
"Oh, so and so, she's got it already." Not through mental processing, not
Not through mental processing, not
Not through mental processing, not through linear
through linear
through linear cognitive functioning. Just knows it.
cognitive functioning. Just knows it.
cognitive functioning. Just knows it. Why? You get the energy field. And the
Why? You get the energy field. And the
Why? You get the energy field. And the energy field tells you what it is.
energy field tells you what it is.
energy field tells you what it is. That's called women's intuition, right?
That's called women's intuition, right?
That's called women's intuition, right? Men have it in business. See, women have
Men have it in business. See, women have
Men have it in business. See, women have it, but men have it also in business. I
it, but men have it also in business. I
it, but men have it also in business. I just get this deal ain't going to work
just get this deal ain't going to work
just get this deal ain't going to work with this so you know and he's right.
with this so you know and he's right.
with this so you know and he's right. Men don't accept it as intuition. They
Men don't accept it as intuition. They
Men don't accept it as intuition. They think that that's a a womanly thing. The
think that that's a a womanly thing. The
think that that's a a womanly thing. The woman respects it. She respects it. And
woman respects it. She respects it. And
woman respects it. She respects it. And look at all the trouble she say to
look at all the trouble she say to
look at all the trouble she say to herself reading all those dopey books.
herself reading all those dopey books.
herself reading all those dopey books. She didn't have to read the great books
She didn't have to read the great books
She didn't have to read the great books of the western world.
of the western world.
of the western world. I'll say something to her and she'll say
I'll say something to her and she'll say
I'll say something to her and she'll say that's out.
Then we check it. Yeah, it is out
Then we check it. Yeah, it is out instant knowingness. Instant
instant knowingness. Instant
instant knowingness. Instant knowingness. So, we value intuition
knowingness. So, we value intuition
knowingness. So, we value intuition then. It's really a gift. And it's but I
then. It's really a gift. And it's but I
then. It's really a gift. And it's but I I believe uh you know my male brain
I believe uh you know my male brain
I believe uh you know my male brain says, "Yeah, but check it out." So, she
says, "Yeah, but check it out." So, she
says, "Yeah, but check it out." So, she says, "This is what it is." And then I
says, "This is what it is." And then I
says, "This is what it is." And then I say, "Okay, we'll check it out." So, now
say, "Okay, we'll check it out." So, now
say, "Okay, we'll check it out." So, now you got the both the masculine and the
you got the both the masculine and the
you got the both the masculine and the feminine view of how to check out
feminine view of how to check out
feminine view of how to check out reality through intuitive knowingness.
reality through intuitive knowingness.
reality through intuitive knowingness. And then the male brain says, "Yeah, but
And then the male brain says, "Yeah, but
And then the male brain says, "Yeah, but let's check it out through the
let's check it out through the
let's check it out through the intellect. Let's calibrate it. What do
intellect. Let's calibrate it. What do
intellect. Let's calibrate it. What do we just calibrate it for?
we just calibrate it for?
we just calibrate it for? >> Oh, well, the cards.
>> Oh, well, the cards.
>> Oh, well, the cards. >> Oh, yeah. The car. I wasn't going to
>> Oh, yeah. The car. I wasn't going to
>> Oh, yeah. The car. I wasn't going to bring up bring it up, but it just came
bring up bring it up, but it just came
bring up bring it up, but it just came up, so I guess God wanted me to say it.
up, so I guess God wanted me to say it.
up, so I guess God wanted me to say it. Yeah. So, I I say don't fool around with
Yeah. So, I I say don't fool around with
Yeah. So, I I say don't fool around with it.
it.
it. Uh if you want to spend a number of
Uh if you want to spend a number of
Uh if you want to spend a number of lifetimes wandering around the esoteric
lifetimes wandering around the esoteric
lifetimes wandering around the esoteric world, uh you know, I'm not saying you
world, uh you know, I'm not saying you
world, uh you know, I'm not saying you shouldn't. And certainly all of us when
shouldn't. And certainly all of us when
shouldn't. And certainly all of us when we got involved, then it had a
we got involved, then it had a
we got involved, then it had a curiosity. You see the child's curiosity
curiosity. You see the child's curiosity
curiosity. You see the child's curiosity and that's what they play on the child's
and that's what they play on the child's
and that's what they play on the child's curiosity. I want a reading. Please do
curiosity. I want a reading. Please do
curiosity. I want a reading. Please do the cards. Let's do a psychic. Let's go
the cards. Let's do a psychic. Let's go
the cards. Let's do a psychic. Let's go into a trance. Let's throw the runes.
into a trance. Let's throw the runes.
into a trance. Let's throw the runes. Let's throw the stones. Let's throw the
Let's throw the stones. Let's throw the
Let's throw the stones. Let's throw the marbles. Let's throw the dice. Let's
marbles. Let's throw the dice. Let's
marbles. Let's throw the dice. Let's throw the
throw the
throw the Yeah. Look at the attraction of that.
Yeah. Look at the attraction of that.
Yeah. Look at the attraction of that. The attraction of it to the child's
The attraction of it to the child's
The attraction of it to the child's curiosity.
curiosity.
curiosity. So, if you can leave your curious child
So, if you can leave your curious child
So, if you can leave your curious child at home and go to a new age fair, fine.
at home and go to a new age fair, fine.
at home and go to a new age fair, fine. But if it wasn't for your curious child,
But if it wasn't for your curious child,
But if it wasn't for your curious child, you wouldn't even be there. So, you
you wouldn't even be there. So, you
you wouldn't even be there. So, you can't leave them home because that's who
can't leave them home because that's who
can't leave them home because that's who went to the fair in the first place.
We're almost time.
We're almost time. >> She makes threatening gestures when it's
>> She makes threatening gestures when it's
>> She makes threatening gestures when it's time to break.
All right. So, we'll take a break and
All right. So, we'll take a break and then we'll resume at what time?
then we'll resume at what time?
then we'll resume at what time? >> Uh 2 o'clock.
>> Uh 2 o'clock.
>> Uh 2 o'clock. >> We resume at 2 o'clock. And thank you
>> We resume at 2 o'clock. And thank you
>> We resume at 2 o'clock. And thank you very much.
We're going to resume where we left off.
We're going to resume where we left off. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Oh, God. I didn't know there was so many
>> Oh, God. I didn't know there was so many
>> Oh, God. I didn't know there was so many people here all of a sudden.
>> Here we go.
>> Here we go. Uh, we're going to resume now. A lot of
Uh, we're going to resume now. A lot of
Uh, we're going to resume now. A lot of this is familiar territory, but as I
this is familiar territory, but as I
this is familiar territory, but as I say, according to the Kenok principle,
say, according to the Kenok principle,
say, according to the Kenok principle, the more often you hear it, the more it
the more often you hear it, the more it
the more often you hear it, the more it becomes your own natural way of being
becomes your own natural way of being
becomes your own natural way of being just through familiarity. So, one way to
just through familiarity. So, one way to
just through familiarity. So, one way to learn things is through familiarity.
learn things is through familiarity.
learn things is through familiarity. You're so familiar with it that imagine
You're so familiar with it that imagine
You're so familiar with it that imagine getting in a cockpit of one of these
getting in a cockpit of one of these
getting in a cockpit of one of these planes and reading the instructions.
planes and reading the instructions.
planes and reading the instructions. You'd be old and gray before you finish
You'd be old and gray before you finish
You'd be old and gray before you finish the book. No, you've got to be able to
the book. No, you've got to be able to
the book. No, you've got to be able to do it. And uh I do a lot of things
do it. And uh I do a lot of things
do it. And uh I do a lot of things spatially.
spatially.
spatially. I don't really know where they are, but
I don't really know where they are, but
I don't really know where they are, but I know I by reaching this way, I've got
I know I by reaching this way, I've got
I know I by reaching this way, I've got it. So, uh, it's just my orientation of
it. So, uh, it's just my orientation of
it. So, uh, it's just my orientation of life is spatial is, uh, I when I put a
life is spatial is, uh, I when I put a
life is spatial is, uh, I when I put a tool away, I know where it is and next
tool away, I know where it is and next
tool away, I know where it is and next time I'm in the tour room, I just reach
time I'm in the tour room, I just reach
time I'm in the tour room, I just reach there. I don't look at it. See?
there. I don't look at it. See?
there. I don't look at it. See? Uh, which is sort of handy, I guess, for
Uh, which is sort of handy, I guess, for
Uh, which is sort of handy, I guess, for what I don't know.
what I don't know.
what I don't know. But everybody has a different way of
But everybody has a different way of
But everybody has a different way of processing information.
processing information.
processing information. Some people are mainly auditory, some
Some people are mainly auditory, some
Some people are mainly auditory, some people are linear, you know, visual.
people are linear, you know, visual.
people are linear, you know, visual. And uh I just noticed that I when we
And uh I just noticed that I when we
And uh I just noticed that I when we were talking about it that I'm very
were talking about it that I'm very
were talking about it that I'm very spatial. I mean I reach for this cuz I
spatial. I mean I reach for this cuz I
spatial. I mean I reach for this cuz I know where it is but I don't remember
know where it is but I don't remember
know where it is but I don't remember where it is at all. So that's just
where it is at all. So that's just
where it is at all. So that's just familiarity. So that's the easiest way
familiarity. So that's the easiest way
familiarity. So that's the easiest way to learn and um if I had to go through
to learn and um if I had to go through
to learn and um if I had to go through school again I just do the count
school again I just do the count
school again I just do the count principle frankly and save myself all
principle frankly and save myself all
principle frankly and save myself all that memorizing.
Okay
Okay this is the Newtonian paradigm. uh this
this is the Newtonian paradigm. uh this
this is the Newtonian paradigm. uh this is in the 400s. This is the world of
is in the 400s. This is the world of
is in the 400s. This is the world of logic and causality.
logic and causality.
logic and causality. This is the world of science
This is the world of science
This is the world of science and the nearest thing to it is quantum
and the nearest thing to it is quantum
and the nearest thing to it is quantum mechanics which is the next uh
mechanics which is the next uh
mechanics which is the next uh direction. So you can go from Newtonian
direction. So you can go from Newtonian
direction. So you can go from Newtonian science into quantum mechanics
science into quantum mechanics
science into quantum mechanics and advanced theoretical physics and
and advanced theoretical physics and
and advanced theoretical physics and then uh the next emergence is into a
then uh the next emergence is into a
then uh the next emergence is into a different paradigm. said the reason uh
different paradigm. said the reason uh
different paradigm. said the reason uh for the co scopes trial you see
for the co scopes trial you see
for the co scopes trial you see because I'm writing about about that now
because I'm writing about about that now
because I'm writing about about that now and um the scopes trial is not
and um the scopes trial is not
and um the scopes trial is not resolvable the scopes dilemma is not
resolvable the scopes dilemma is not
resolvable the scopes dilemma is not resolvable
resolvable
resolvable because you what you had was the
because you what you had was the
because you what you had was the presentation of two different paradigms
presentation of two different paradigms
presentation of two different paradigms uh two different paradigms so Clarence
uh two different paradigms so Clarence
uh two different paradigms so Clarence Durl was coming from the Newtonian
Durl was coming from the Newtonian
Durl was coming from the Newtonian scientific paradigm of the mid 400s
scientific paradigm of the mid 400s
scientific paradigm of the mid 400s and Bryant was coming from the 500s and
and Bryant was coming from the 500s and
and Bryant was coming from the 500s and up which is a different paradigm. So you
up which is a different paradigm. So you
up which is a different paradigm. So you cannot argue the paradigm of the 400s
cannot argue the paradigm of the 400s
cannot argue the paradigm of the 400s against the 500s or vice versa. So there
against the 500s or vice versa. So there
against the 500s or vice versa. So there was no meeting of minds because they're
was no meeting of minds because they're
was no meeting of minds because they're two different paradigms. So my
two different paradigms. So my
two different paradigms. So my resolution of the scopes paradigm
resolution of the scopes paradigm
resolution of the scopes paradigm confrontation between you know science
confrontation between you know science
confrontation between you know science and faith
and faith
and faith uh is that you have to have a paradigm
uh is that you have to have a paradigm
uh is that you have to have a paradigm that is uh that is large enough to be
that is uh that is large enough to be
that is uh that is large enough to be inclusive of both. See so you don't have
inclusive of both. See so you don't have
inclusive of both. See so you don't have the either or or you have so kind the
the either or or you have so kind the
the either or or you have so kind the the calibrated level of consciousness is
the calibrated level of consciousness is
the calibrated level of consciousness is inclusive of all domains. It goes from
inclusive of all domains. It goes from
inclusive of all domains. It goes from 500 up to 500. So you got something big
500 up to 500. So you got something big
500 up to 500. So you got something big enough and you can just see that they
enough and you can just see that they
enough and you can just see that they were in different positions within this
were in different positions within this
were in different positions within this overall context. So there isn't really a
overall context. So there isn't really a
overall context. So there isn't really a conflict. They're just two different
conflict. They're just two different
conflict. They're just two different paradigms of reality. But you cannot
paradigms of reality. But you cannot
paradigms of reality. But you cannot resolve it because you cannot
resolve it because you cannot
resolve it because you cannot uh resolve it. You cannot apply science
uh resolve it. You cannot apply science
uh resolve it. You cannot apply science to spiritual reality, nor can you apply
to spiritual reality, nor can you apply
to spiritual reality, nor can you apply spiritual reality to science. There is
spiritual reality to science. There is
spiritual reality to science. There is no meaning of the minds there. They're
no meaning of the minds there. They're
no meaning of the minds there. They're two different paradigms. So, as I say,
two different paradigms. So, as I say,
two different paradigms. So, as I say, it's like to try and do so is like uh
it's like to try and do so is like uh
it's like to try and do so is like uh looking for ghosts with a geer counter.
looking for ghosts with a geer counter.
looking for ghosts with a geer counter. You just got the wrong instrument.
Okay. So, we're all familiar with the
Okay. So, we're all familiar with the Newtonian paradigm of course and the
Newtonian paradigm of course and the
Newtonian paradigm of course and the quantum mechanics begins to take us
quantum mechanics begins to take us
quantum mechanics begins to take us beyond that up to the next uh paradigm.
beyond that up to the next uh paradigm.
beyond that up to the next uh paradigm. So, it is sort of an area of transition.
So, it is sort of an area of transition.
So, it is sort of an area of transition. Okay, we'll move on from there. Uh
Okay, we'll move on from there. Uh
Okay, we'll move on from there. Uh and this has to do with the getting rid
and this has to do with the getting rid
and this has to do with the getting rid of the dualities. Um so that you see
of the dualities. Um so that you see
of the dualities. Um so that you see that heat is not the opposite of cold
that heat is not the opposite of cold
that heat is not the opposite of cold and truth is you know falsehood
and truth is you know falsehood
and truth is you know falsehood falsehood is not the opposite of truth.
falsehood is not the opposite of truth.
falsehood is not the opposite of truth. It's the absence of truth and cold is
It's the absence of truth and cold is
It's the absence of truth and cold is the absence of heat. So the mind tends
the absence of heat. So the mind tends
the absence of heat. So the mind tends to create dualities where there are
to create dualities where there are
to create dualities where there are none. There's only gradations. So the
none. There's only gradations. So the
none. There's only gradations. So the calibrated levels of consciousness are
calibrated levels of consciousness are
calibrated levels of consciousness are the same. There's gradations,
the same. There's gradations,
the same. There's gradations, gradations. So we know that boiling is
gradations. So we know that boiling is
gradations. So we know that boiling is at 212 and freezing at 32. Of course, 1
at 212 and freezing at 32. Of course, 1
at 212 and freezing at 32. Of course, 1 to a,000 was arbitrary. And I always
to a,000 was arbitrary. And I always
to a,000 was arbitrary. And I always tell people you can make up your own
tell people you can make up your own
tell people you can make up your own scale, you know, from 1 to 100 or or
scale, you know, from 1 to 100 or or
scale, you know, from 1 to 100 or or from 100 to 10,000 or whatever you want
from 100 to 10,000 or whatever you want
from 100 to 10,000 or whatever you want and then you will end up. So uh we'll
and then you will end up. So uh we'll
and then you will end up. So uh we'll just move on to see that duality is an
just move on to see that duality is an
just move on to see that duality is an artifact of mentation. see
artifact of mentation. see
artifact of mentation. see are effective mentation
are effective mentation
are effective mentation spiritual practices. Uh this I think is
spiritual practices. Uh this I think is
spiritual practices. Uh this I think is valuable
valuable
valuable um because it gives validity to many of
um because it gives validity to many of
um because it gives validity to many of the things we do and it gives
the things we do and it gives
the things we do and it gives recognition to the essence of things uh
recognition to the essence of things uh
recognition to the essence of things uh that we were not aware was there. the
that we were not aware was there. the
that we were not aware was there. the Lord's Prayer, the sound.
Lord's Prayer, the sound.
Lord's Prayer, the sound. And you see the difference between the
And you see the difference between the
And you see the difference between the sound om and a yeah a of course the
sound om and a yeah a of course the
sound om and a yeah a of course the reason I bring this out is because
reason I bring this out is because
reason I bring this out is because that's a that's in the apherisms of
that's a that's in the apherisms of
that's a that's in the apherisms of jelly by sacha and that's an error as I
jelly by sacha and that's an error as I
jelly by sacha and that's an error as I see it
see it
see it shanti shanti shiad
oh boy those are so much fun.
oh boy those are so much fun. Oh money.
Gregorian chance Japa. The Jesus prayer.
Gregorian chance Japa. The Jesus prayer. Sing the rosary.
Sing the rosary.
Sing the rosary. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. I was in the back of a cathedral in uh
I was in the back of a cathedral in uh
I was in the back of a cathedral in uh Ecuador someplace. Going up to uh
Ecuador someplace. Going up to uh
Ecuador someplace. Going up to uh going up to well, I can't think of all
going up to well, I can't think of all
going up to well, I can't think of all these names anymore.
these names anymore.
these names anymore. >> Machipede. Yeah. And there you are
>> Machipede. Yeah. And there you are
>> Machipede. Yeah. And there you are 10,000 ft. They said don't walk around.
10,000 ft. They said don't walk around.
10,000 ft. They said don't walk around. I walked around and shouldn't have
I walked around and shouldn't have
I walked around and shouldn't have walked into a cathedral. It was
walked into a cathedral. It was
walked into a cathedral. It was enchanting.
enchanting.
enchanting. Uh, it was Christmas time and here was
Uh, it was Christmas time and here was
Uh, it was Christmas time and here was this huge cray and the lights were
this huge cray and the lights were
this huge cray and the lights were flickering in the cray and there was a
flickering in the cray and there was a
flickering in the cray and there was a big thing of incense and the incense was
big thing of incense and the incense was
big thing of incense and the incense was rising up through the cathedral and the
rising up through the cathedral and the
rising up through the cathedral and the sunlight was coming through the stained
sunlight was coming through the stained
sunlight was coming through the stained glass windows and uh the the organ there
glass windows and uh the the organ there
glass windows and uh the the organ there in Peru uh was set like uh Peruvian
in Peru uh was set like uh Peruvian
in Peru uh was set like uh Peruvian pipes. So there's the Peruvian pipes
pipes. So there's the Peruvian pipes
pipes. So there's the Peruvian pipes playing hymns and in the background are
playing hymns and in the background are
playing hymns and in the background are these ladies, local ladies, all all
these ladies, local ladies, all all
these ladies, local ladies, all all dressed in black, long black and they
dressed in black, long black and they
dressed in black, long black and they have coins in their finger in their
have coins in their finger in their
have coins in their finger in their hands and they're going like this to the
hands and they're going like this to the
hands and they're going like this to the music to the sound of the flutes and
music to the sound of the flutes and
music to the sound of the flutes and clinking the coins as they go like this.
clinking the coins as they go like this.
clinking the coins as they go like this. It was like unbelievable
It was like unbelievable
It was like unbelievable chanting
chanting
chanting transport you to a different realm.
transport you to a different realm.
transport you to a different realm. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. Uh, pilgrimage is to Mecca. Uh, yogic
Uh, pilgrimage is to Mecca. Uh, yogic
Uh, pilgrimage is to Mecca. Uh, yogic chants, AA is 540.
chants, AA is 540.
chants, AA is 540. It's probably the to me the most
It's probably the to me the most
It's probably the to me the most successful spiritual organization in the
successful spiritual organization in the
successful spiritual organization in the world right now. There's nothing that
world right now. There's nothing that
world right now. There's nothing that surpasses it. Uh, it does not indulge in
surpasses it. Uh, it does not indulge in
surpasses it. Uh, it does not indulge in self gratification. Grandisman, has no
self gratification. Grandisman, has no
self gratification. Grandisman, has no great buildings, has no huge money, no
great buildings, has no huge money, no
great buildings, has no huge money, no coercion, everyone's free to come and go
coercion, everyone's free to come and go
coercion, everyone's free to come and go and represents to me pure spirituality.
and represents to me pure spirituality.
and represents to me pure spirituality. So this was uh born of genius and of
So this was uh born of genius and of
So this was uh born of genius and of course Bill Wilson if you calibrate uh
course Bill Wilson if you calibrate uh
course Bill Wilson if you calibrate uh when he finally gave up in uh what Mclad
when he finally gave up in uh what Mclad
when he finally gave up in uh what Mclad hospital
hospital
hospital uh the room lit up. He was an atheist at
uh the room lit up. He was an atheist at
uh the room lit up. He was an atheist at the time and when he finally surrendered
the time and when he finally surrendered
the time and when he finally surrendered to God the room lit up and he said and
to God the room lit up and he said and
to God the room lit up and he said and he recognized what it was.
He recognized that moment and I
He recognized that moment and I calibrated that moment and he recognized
calibrated that moment and he recognized
calibrated that moment and he recognized the presence of God and uh
the presence of God and uh
the presence of God and uh that got rid of his atheism
that was well up in the 500s and uh but
that was well up in the 500s and uh but out of that moment arose the salvation
out of that moment arose the salvation
out of that moment arose the salvation of millions worldwide.
of millions worldwide.
of millions worldwide. So that is the power spiritual power in
So that is the power spiritual power in
So that is the power spiritual power in one instant out of that arose then
one instant out of that arose then
one instant out of that arose then unfolded what to me is probably the
unfolded what to me is probably the
unfolded what to me is probably the purest spiritual organization in
purest spiritual organization in
purest spiritual organization in existence today extremely powerful
existence today extremely powerful
existence today extremely powerful transformative and it set the paradigm
transformative and it set the paradigm
transformative and it set the paradigm of spiritual purity. It really set the
of spiritual purity. It really set the
of spiritual purity. It really set the paradigm of uh integrity at the golden
paradigm of uh integrity at the golden
paradigm of uh integrity at the golden rule at 405. Uh you never hear the
rule at 405. Uh you never hear the
rule at 405. Uh you never hear the golden rule anymore. I haven't anybody
golden rule anymore. I haven't anybody
golden rule anymore. I haven't anybody quote the golden rule in 20 30 years.
quote the golden rule in 20 30 years.
quote the golden rule in 20 30 years. Are you
Are you
Are you >> have you? I never hear the golden rule.
>> have you? I never hear the golden rule.
>> have you? I never hear the golden rule. No, the the public is all full of
No, the the public is all full of
No, the the public is all full of rights. You know, these are my rights,
rights. You know, these are my rights,
rights. You know, these are my rights, you know, right?
you know, right?
you know, right? TM at 295. Fair JZ.
TM at 295. Fair JZ.
TM at 295. Fair JZ. Walking the labyrinth. They do that at
Walking the labyrinth. They do that at
Walking the labyrinth. They do that at the uh they do that at the Episcopal
the uh they do that at the Episcopal
the uh they do that at the Episcopal church in town. Genulection. You see all
church in town. Genulection. You see all
church in town. Genulection. You see all these acts of devotion are all 540.
these acts of devotion are all 540.
these acts of devotion are all 540. Turning the prayer wheel, kneeling to
Turning the prayer wheel, kneeling to
Turning the prayer wheel, kneeling to prayer, handful, devotional hand flex.
prayer, handful, devotional hand flex.
prayer, handful, devotional hand flex. So that's what's so charming and I
So that's what's so charming and I
So that's what's so charming and I always say that about Korea and being in
always say that about Korea and being in
always say that about Korea and being in Korea is because everybody greets you
Korea is because everybody greets you
Korea is because everybody greets you this. Well, that's 540 to begin with for
this. Well, that's 540 to begin with for
this. Well, that's 540 to begin with for openers. Wow.
openers. Wow.
openers. Wow. Everybody you meet greets you at a
Everybody you meet greets you at a
Everybody you meet greets you at a conscious level of 540. Wow. I mean that
conscious level of 540. Wow. I mean that
conscious level of 540. Wow. I mean that to me is tremendous.
to me is tremendous.
to me is tremendous. Prayerful handcross devotional acts
Prayerful handcross devotional acts
Prayerful handcross devotional acts turning the prayer wheels. Burning of
turning the prayer wheels. Burning of
turning the prayer wheels. Burning of incense the wheeling wall bathing in the
incense the wheeling wall bathing in the
incense the wheeling wall bathing in the Genesis. St. Francis of Aisi is 580. Oh,
Genesis. St. Francis of Aisi is 580. Oh,
Genesis. St. Francis of Aisi is 580. Oh, that's a beautiful prayer. Let me just
that's a beautiful prayer. Let me just
that's a beautiful prayer. Let me just be a channel of thy will, oh Lord. Okay.
be a channel of thy will, oh Lord. Okay.
be a channel of thy will, oh Lord. Okay. So, you see, all of these things become
So, you see, all of these things become
So, you see, all of these things become habitual. When you're around a spiritual
habitual. When you're around a spiritual
habitual. When you're around a spiritual group like this,
group like this,
group like this, you become you remember spiritual
you become you remember spiritual
you become you remember spiritual uh patterns and sayings and chants and
uh patterns and sayings and chants and
uh patterns and sayings and chants and things, they just come to mind. So, you
things, they just come to mind. So, you
things, they just come to mind. So, you tend to do it more automatically on your
tend to do it more automatically on your
tend to do it more automatically on your own. Uh you would think about it. You
own. Uh you would think about it. You
own. Uh you would think about it. You know, you say the Lord's Prayer when you
know, you say the Lord's Prayer when you
know, you say the Lord's Prayer when you go to sleep at night. Maybe you say
go to sleep at night. Maybe you say
go to sleep at night. Maybe you say grace at dinner, but that's pretty much
grace at dinner, but that's pretty much
grace at dinner, but that's pretty much it for the secular day. And a spiritual
it for the secular day. And a spiritual
it for the secular day. And a spiritual group for reasons you don't know because
group for reasons you don't know because
group for reasons you don't know because you don't see you don't see the
you don't see you don't see the
you don't see you don't see the interaction uh spatially
interaction uh spatially
interaction uh spatially um because there are all they're all
um because there are all they're all
um because there are all they're all over the country. But that a group like
over the country. But that a group like
over the country. But that a group like this has a interactive uh what should we
this has a interactive uh what should we
this has a interactive uh what should we call it almost telepathic oneness.
That is so resistant. See, so this group
That is so resistant. See, so this group is is continuous all the time every day.
is is continuous all the time every day.
is is continuous all the time every day. So as you're walking along and you feel
So as you're walking along and you feel
So as you're walking along and you feel a little discouraged and then you
a little discouraged and then you
a little discouraged and then you suddenly get, well, I can turn that over
suddenly get, well, I can turn that over
suddenly get, well, I can turn that over to God. You think that came from your
to God. You think that came from your
to God. You think that came from your mind. It came from the group field. You
mind. It came from the group field. You
mind. It came from the group field. You see, once you ascribe to a field, now
see, once you ascribe to a field, now
see, once you ascribe to a field, now you have the energy of the field.
you have the energy of the field.
you have the energy of the field. That's what they mean in AA when they
That's what they mean in AA when they
That's what they mean in AA when they say just bring the body and the rest you
say just bring the body and the rest you
say just bring the body and the rest you get by osmosis
because by commitment you become one
because by commitment you become one with the field. Now the field serves
with the field. Now the field serves
with the field. Now the field serves you. So you you think your individual
you. So you you think your individual
you. So you you think your individual self is remembering to give thanks.
self is remembering to give thanks.
self is remembering to give thanks. Actually it's the it's the powerful
Actually it's the it's the powerful
Actually it's the it's the powerful upliftment of the field. And that's why
upliftment of the field. And that's why
upliftment of the field. And that's why each one of us as we evolve spiritually
each one of us as we evolve spiritually
each one of us as we evolve spiritually lifts all of mankind because they're all
lifts all of mankind because they're all
lifts all of mankind because they're all part of a field. So it's the field
part of a field. So it's the field
part of a field. So it's the field effect. So to be a member of a group
effect. So to be a member of a group
effect. So to be a member of a group then does have a powerful supportive
then does have a powerful supportive
then does have a powerful supportive effect. Uh by commitment you don't have
effect. Uh by commitment you don't have
effect. Uh by commitment you don't have to physically be actually be there but
to physically be actually be there but
to physically be actually be there but by by mental ascent by inner ascent you
by by mental ascent by inner ascent you
by by mental ascent by inner ascent you have grabbed onto the uh energy field as
have grabbed onto the uh energy field as
have grabbed onto the uh energy field as well as the karma of the field. The
well as the karma of the field. The
well as the karma of the field. The progressive fields of uh realization are
progressive fields of uh realization are
progressive fields of uh realization are very inter uh very useful in meditation
very inter uh very useful in meditation
very inter uh very useful in meditation because in meditation you keep letting
because in meditation you keep letting
because in meditation you keep letting go of this, you keep letting go of this
go of this, you keep letting go of this
go of this, you keep letting go of this and then you realize what's going on is
and then you realize what's going on is
and then you realize what's going on is that you're watching it. And how do you
that you're watching it. And how do you
that you're watching it. And how do you know you're watching it out of
know you're watching it out of
know you're watching it out of awareness? It's relatively easy in in
awareness? It's relatively easy in in
awareness? It's relatively easy in in meditation
meditation
meditation to let all this go and allow yourself to
to let all this go and allow yourself to
to let all this go and allow yourself to be the observer witness. The observer
be the observer witness. The observer
be the observer witness. The observer witness is a very comfortable place to
witness is a very comfortable place to
witness is a very comfortable place to be. Uh you can live in the observer
be. Uh you can live in the observer
be. Uh you can live in the observer witness all the time and a contemplative
witness all the time and a contemplative
witness all the time and a contemplative person tends to um you're the observer
person tends to um you're the observer
person tends to um you're the observer and the witness but you have no reaction
and the witness but you have no reaction
and the witness but you have no reaction to it, no commitment to it. Uh if it
to it, no commitment to it. Uh if it
to it, no commitment to it. Uh if it disappears, it's okay. If it appears
disappears, it's okay. If it appears
disappears, it's okay. If it appears again, it's okay. You don't have any
again, it's okay. You don't have any
again, it's okay. You don't have any stake in what's happening in the world
stake in what's happening in the world
stake in what's happening in the world because you see that all you're doing is
because you see that all you're doing is
because you see that all you're doing is witnessing the phenomena. witnessing the
witnessing the phenomena. witnessing the
witnessing the phenomena. witnessing the phenomena without personal involvement
phenomena without personal involvement
phenomena without personal involvement or identification. So this is a very
or identification. So this is a very
or identification. So this is a very good place to pull back to the observer
good place to pull back to the observer
good place to pull back to the observer witness and from there you really it's
witness and from there you really it's
witness and from there you really it's quite easy uh for the awareness of the
quite easy uh for the awareness of the
quite easy uh for the awareness of the light of consciousness
light of consciousness
light of consciousness to be aware that that is that your
to be aware that that is that your
to be aware that that is that your consciousness is an independent field in
consciousness is an independent field in
consciousness is an independent field in and of itself and the what it's
and of itself and the what it's
and of itself and the what it's conscious of or the content of it is
conscious of or the content of it is
conscious of or the content of it is relatively irrelevant.
relatively irrelevant.
relatively irrelevant. Why? Because if it isn't this, then it's
Why? Because if it isn't this, then it's
Why? Because if it isn't this, then it's going to be that. So what's so special
going to be that. So what's so special
going to be that. So what's so special about that?
about that?
about that? If it isn't this, it's going to be that.
If it isn't this, it's going to be that.
If it isn't this, it's going to be that. You see? All right. So pulling yourself
You see? All right. So pulling yourself
You see? All right. So pulling yourself back and identifying here is not that
back and identifying here is not that
back and identifying here is not that difficult. That can be done. Just to
difficult. That can be done. Just to
difficult. That can be done. Just to know that this is possible already
know that this is possible already
know that this is possible already enables you to do that. And then one day
enables you to do that. And then one day
enables you to do that. And then one day all of this disappears. There's no
all of this disappears. There's no
all of this disappears. There's no observer or witness. There's only
observer or witness. There's only
observer or witness. There's only consciousness being conscious as
consciousness being conscious as
consciousness being conscious as awareness and you realize neither
awareness and you realize neither
awareness and you realize neither there's not a witness or an observer.
there's not a witness or an observer.
there's not a witness or an observer. There is only the awareness of
There is only the awareness of
There is only the awareness of consciousness and as that disappears
consciousness and as that disappears
consciousness and as that disappears uh then you realize itself with a
uh then you realize itself with a
uh then you realize itself with a capital S.
capital S.
capital S. Yeah. Okay. Next one. Thank you very
Yeah. Okay. Next one. Thank you very
Yeah. Okay. Next one. Thank you very much for that one.
important to spiritual evolution and uh
important to spiritual evolution and uh things the world doesn't realize is that
things the world doesn't realize is that
things the world doesn't realize is that spiritual evolution now triggers from
spiritual evolution now triggers from
spiritual evolution now triggers from two consciousness level 200 up um the
two consciousness level 200 up um the
two consciousness level 200 up um the pouring forth of spiritual energy which
pouring forth of spiritual energy which
pouring forth of spiritual energy which gets stronger and stronger. This
gets stronger and stronger. This
gets stronger and stronger. This spiritual energy classically called
spiritual energy classically called
spiritual energy classically called condundolini
condundolini
condundolini uh
uh
uh shifts very physiology. You shift from
shifts very physiology. You shift from
shifts very physiology. You shift from processing things here uh on the animal
processing things here uh on the animal
processing things here uh on the animal level. This is the animal level which is
level. This is the animal level which is
level. This is the animal level which is primarily emotional. Emotional it's only
primarily emotional. Emotional it's only
primarily emotional. Emotional it's only concerned whether it wants to eat you,
concerned whether it wants to eat you,
concerned whether it wants to eat you, attack you or mate with you. You know
from 200 and up then you see the the
from 200 and up then you see the the major jump here is here you develop an
major jump here is here you develop an
major jump here is here you develop an etheric brain below 200
etheric brain below 200
etheric brain below 200 uh one is subject to group karma. I have
uh one is subject to group karma. I have
uh one is subject to group karma. I have permission to ask this one award. Below
permission to ask this one award. Below
permission to ask this one award. Below 200, you're subject to group karma.
200, you're subject to group karma.
200, you're subject to group karma. Resist. Wow.
Resist. Wow.
Resist. Wow. Below consciousness level 200, people
Below consciousness level 200, people
Below consciousness level 200, people will share a group karma. There's no
will share a group karma. There's no
will share a group karma. There's no point then of getting all indignant and
point then of getting all indignant and
point then of getting all indignant and angry, is there? Or seeking revenge or
angry, is there? Or seeking revenge or
angry, is there? Or seeking revenge or something because people are are
something because people are are
something because people are are reflecting a group karma.
reflecting a group karma.
reflecting a group karma. Huh.
Huh.
Huh. They even tend to congregate on the
They even tend to congregate on the
They even tend to congregate on the planet in similar locations sort of
planet in similar locations sort of
planet in similar locations sort of swoop in like
swoop in like
swoop in like birds and settle here and then these
birds and settle here and then these
birds and settle here and then these birds swoop in and settle there. Uh so
birds swoop in and settle there. Uh so
birds swoop in and settle there. Uh so below 200 then which is the animal level
below 200 then which is the animal level
below 200 then which is the animal level you share with the animals that kind of
you share with the animals that kind of
you share with the animals that kind of a karmic propensity that if you are like
a karmic propensity that if you are like
a karmic propensity that if you are like a killer of people for the fun of that
a killer of people for the fun of that
a killer of people for the fun of that then you share the group karma of
then you share the group karma of
then you share the group karma of killers of people for the fun of that
killers of people for the fun of that
killers of people for the fun of that but not an individual karma. Huh?
but not an individual karma. Huh?
but not an individual karma. Huh? Here from 200 up now you have personal
Here from 200 up now you have personal
Here from 200 up now you have personal responsibility because you have an
responsibility because you have an
responsibility because you have an atheric brain which which registers all
atheric brain which which registers all
atheric brain which which registers all your spiritual decisions or your yeses
your spiritual decisions or your yeses
your spiritual decisions or your yeses and your nos and you build begin to
and your nos and you build begin to
and your nos and you build begin to build build a etheric destiny a
build build a etheric destiny a
build build a etheric destiny a spiritual destiny. This brain processes
spiritual destiny. This brain processes
spiritual destiny. This brain processes things differently very fast. You see uh
things differently very fast. You see uh
things differently very fast. You see uh and therefore this experience of the
and therefore this experience of the
and therefore this experience of the world is different than this experience
world is different than this experience
world is different than this experience of the world. Is New York a friendly
of the world. Is New York a friendly
of the world. Is New York a friendly place or a hostile place? It all depends
place or a hostile place? It all depends
place or a hostile place? It all depends on on you.
on on you.
on on you. It all depends on you.
It all depends on you.
It all depends on you. My experience of New York is you can
My experience of New York is you can
My experience of New York is you can stop anybody on the sidewalk anywhere
stop anybody on the sidewalk anywhere
stop anybody on the sidewalk anywhere and start a conversation about anything
and start a conversation about anything
and start a conversation about anything and they'll all have a good time. You
and they'll all have a good time. You
and they'll all have a good time. You can stop anybody and say, "What do you
can stop anybody and say, "What do you
can stop anybody and say, "What do you think of the so and so?" And the guy
think of the so and so?" And the guy
think of the so and so?" And the guy says, "Hey, that's a crocup." You know,
says, "Hey, that's a crocup." You know,
says, "Hey, that's a crocup." You know, and you met the guy and right away
and you met the guy and right away
and you met the guy and right away you're into comedy with the guy. That's
you're into comedy with the guy. That's
you're into comedy with the guy. That's because of who you are. See, this person
because of who you are. See, this person
because of who you are. See, this person would get paranoid and and he's probably
would get paranoid and and he's probably
would get paranoid and and he's probably a pickpocket. You know, she take her
a pickpocket. You know, she take her
a pickpocket. You know, she take her purses. This gentleman accosted me on
purses. This gentleman accosted me on
purses. This gentleman accosted me on the street. She goes, "No, he was just
the street. She goes, "No, he was just
the street. She goes, "No, he was just trying to be friendly." So, your
trying to be friendly." So, your
trying to be friendly." So, your perception of the world changes because
perception of the world changes because
perception of the world changes because you're processing differently. This is
you're processing differently. This is
you're processing differently. This is crucial and therefore it's sort of
crucial and therefore it's sort of
crucial and therefore it's sort of repeated in every book the most recent
repeated in every book the most recent
repeated in every book the most recent books
books
books uh because it explains a lot of
uh because it explains a lot of
uh because it explains a lot of phenomena and it takes it out of uh
phenomena and it takes it out of uh
phenomena and it takes it out of uh other realms that are more difficult to
other realms that are more difficult to
other realms that are more difficult to see. Here you see the everything is
see. Here you see the everything is
see. Here you see the everything is aligned differently than here and
aligned differently than here and
aligned differently than here and uh the consequences of course are quite
uh the consequences of course are quite
uh the consequences of course are quite different because you're putting out
different because you're putting out
different because you're putting out endorphins. A brain that's dominated by
endorphins. A brain that's dominated by
endorphins. A brain that's dominated by endorphins sees things different than a
endorphins sees things different than a
endorphins sees things different than a brain dominated by adrenaline and
brain dominated by adrenaline and
brain dominated by adrenaline and cortisone and the so-called uh stress uh
cortisone and the so-called uh stress uh
cortisone and the so-called uh stress uh hormones. Okay, we'll move on. Um
hormones. Okay, we'll move on. Um
hormones. Okay, we'll move on. Um this has to do with it sort of
this has to do with it sort of
this has to do with it sort of eliminates sociologic theories. There's
eliminates sociologic theories. There's
eliminates sociologic theories. There's all kinds of sociologic theories uh to
all kinds of sociologic theories uh to
all kinds of sociologic theories uh to blame lack of personal responsibility on
blame lack of personal responsibility on
blame lack of personal responsibility on all kinds of factors. And we see that
all kinds of factors. And we see that
all kinds of factors. And we see that the rate of uh unemployment, rate of
the rate of uh unemployment, rate of
the rate of uh unemployment, rate of poverty,
poverty,
poverty, uh rate of happiness and rate of
uh rate of happiness and rate of
uh rate of happiness and rate of criminality are all directly almost
criminality are all directly almost
criminality are all directly almost exactly related to level of
exactly related to level of
exactly related to level of consciousness,
consciousness,
consciousness, level of consciousness.
And therefore,
And therefore, you see why pouring money into Haiti
you see why pouring money into Haiti
you see why pouring money into Haiti does no good. Haiti, which is into
does no good. Haiti, which is into
does no good. Haiti, which is into voodoo and black magic and all this,
voodoo and black magic and all this,
voodoo and black magic and all this, calibrates about 90 or someplace around
calibrates about 90 or someplace around
calibrates about 90 or someplace around there. And pouring money does no good at
there. And pouring money does no good at
there. And pouring money does no good at all. In fact, it makes it worse.
all. In fact, it makes it worse.
all. In fact, it makes it worse. All right. So, we see that happiness
All right. So, we see that happiness
All right. So, we see that happiness then is the automatic accompaniment to
then is the automatic accompaniment to
then is the automatic accompaniment to one's level of consciousness. If you're
one's level of consciousness. If you're
one's level of consciousness. If you're completely if you're very evolved,
completely if you're very evolved,
completely if you're very evolved, almost anything can happen and it's not
almost anything can happen and it's not
almost anything can happen and it's not going to change your state of happiness.
going to change your state of happiness.
going to change your state of happiness. And of course of sociologic import here
And of course of sociologic import here
And of course of sociologic import here is the rate of criminality. The rate of
is the rate of criminality. The rate of
is the rate of criminality. The rate of criminality. And so we see every night
criminality. And so we see every night
criminality. And so we see every night on television how some judge somewhere
on television how some judge somewhere
on television how some judge somewhere has a receivist uh serial killer raper
has a receivist uh serial killer raper
has a receivist uh serial killer raper and has let the guy go because he thinks
and has let the guy go because he thinks
and has let the guy go because he thinks he's suffering from he's going to need
he's suffering from he's going to need
he's suffering from he's going to need rehab.
rehab.
rehab. Gonna need rehab but in a different
Gonna need rehab but in a different
Gonna need rehab but in a different dimension than the human.
dimension than the human.
dimension than the human. If you calibrate a lot of those
If you calibrate a lot of those
If you calibrate a lot of those criminals that you know what's his name
criminals that you know what's his name
criminals that you know what's his name always gets very indignant poed about
always gets very indignant poed about
always gets very indignant poed about that some somebody with a terrible thing
that some somebody with a terrible thing
that some somebody with a terrible thing and this judge let him off with you know
and this judge let him off with you know
and this judge let him off with you know a small fine or something and then two
a small fine or something and then two
a small fine or something and then two days later he kills somebody else and
days later he kills somebody else and
days later he kills somebody else and that just sends a rally up the wall.
It's because they're suffering from a
It's because they're suffering from a mental disorder. Criminality is a mental
mental disorder. Criminality is a mental
mental disorder. Criminality is a mental disorder. A mental disorder. And um it
disorder. A mental disorder. And um it
disorder. A mental disorder. And um it takes more than a couple of rehab
takes more than a couple of rehab
takes more than a couple of rehab classes to recover from it. I treat a
classes to recover from it. I treat a
classes to recover from it. I treat a lot of psychopaths and frankly the
lot of psychopaths and frankly the
lot of psychopaths and frankly the recovery rate was zilch.
recovery rate was zilch.
recovery rate was zilch. Pedophiles the recovery rate was pretty
Pedophiles the recovery rate was pretty
Pedophiles the recovery rate was pretty much zilch.
much zilch.
much zilch. And you know they get arrested for one
And you know they get arrested for one
And you know they get arrested for one crime and I'd have them in the office.
crime and I'd have them in the office.
crime and I'd have them in the office. I'd say how many how many altogether
I'd say how many how many altogether
I'd say how many how many altogether really?
really?
really? Well
Well
Well 350.
350.
350. That's about 350. Why? Because you have
That's about 350. Why? Because you have
That's about 350. Why? Because you have got to have a new boy once a week.
got to have a new boy once a week.
got to have a new boy once a week. That's not too often for sex, right?
That's not too often for sex, right?
That's not too often for sex, right? Once a week. Go to the park, go to the
Once a week. Go to the park, go to the
Once a week. Go to the park, go to the kindergarten, go, you get one kid a
kindergarten, go, you get one kid a
kindergarten, go, you get one kid a week. At the end of the year, that's 50
week. At the end of the year, that's 50
week. At the end of the year, that's 50 kids, right? End of three years, you got
kids, right? End of three years, you got
kids, right? End of three years, you got 150. So the average guy before a judge
150. So the average guy before a judge
150. So the average guy before a judge has done hundreds, hundreds, hundreds.
has done hundreds, hundreds, hundreds.
has done hundreds, hundreds, hundreds. So when the judge releases them, you're
So when the judge releases them, you're
So when the judge releases them, you're just releasing another predator on the
just releasing another predator on the
just releasing another predator on the street. Yeah. So the receivism rate here
street. Yeah. So the receivism rate here
street. Yeah. So the receivism rate here uh is close to 100%. 100%.
uh is close to 100%. 100%.
uh is close to 100%. 100%. Uh they are dominated by a certain
Uh they are dominated by a certain
Uh they are dominated by a certain energy field. That energy field may be
energy field. That energy field may be
energy field. That energy field may be 10, 20 or 30. Uh so dominated by an
10, 20 or 30. Uh so dominated by an
10, 20 or 30. Uh so dominated by an energy field. They have group karma of
energy field. They have group karma of
energy field. They have group karma of 30. All the child serial killers etc.
30. All the child serial killers etc.
30. All the child serial killers etc. calibrate around 30 around in there.
calibrate around 30 around in there.
calibrate around 30 around in there. Okay. Next.
In fact, most of them pedophilia will go
In fact, most of them pedophilia will go to the park the day they're released in
to the park the day they're released in
to the park the day they're released in jail. The day they get out at three, by
jail. The day they get out at three, by
jail. The day they get out at three, by five they're in the park.
five they're in the park.
five they're in the park. Let's see. That's addiction. Craving
Let's see. That's addiction. Craving
Let's see. That's addiction. Craving this. What does an elkie do who's at
this. What does an elkie do who's at
this. What does an elkie do who's at force sobriety? What do you do? You let
force sobriety? What do you do? You let
force sobriety? What do you do? You let him out of jail. He heads for the
him out of jail. He heads for the
him out of jail. He heads for the nearest bar. What do you think he does?
nearest bar. What do you think he does?
nearest bar. What do you think he does? Yeah. Okay.
Yeah. Okay.
Yeah. Okay. This is diagnostic scale. And I think
This is diagnostic scale. And I think
This is diagnostic scale. And I think the usefulness of it is considerable.
the usefulness of it is considerable.
the usefulness of it is considerable. We certainly see see it in today's
We certainly see see it in today's
We certainly see see it in today's world. Let's just do Iran for fun. Let's
world. Let's just do Iran for fun. Let's
world. Let's just do Iran for fun. Let's see if we got permission to do a run. Uh
see if we got permission to do a run. Uh
see if we got permission to do a run. Uh we have permission to do a run.
we have permission to do a run.
we have permission to do a run. Don't have permission to do a run. Okay.
Don't have permission to do a run. Okay.
Don't have permission to do a run. Okay. Uh
Uh
Uh but we have been doing it.
Now people will begin to think that it's
Now people will begin to think that it's due to religion. I see what it's
due to religion. I see what it's
due to religion. I see what it's misconceive. It's got nothing to do with
misconceive. It's got nothing to do with
misconceive. It's got nothing to do with religion. Has to do with the leadership.
religion. Has to do with the leadership.
religion. Has to do with the leadership. The leadership. So you see the three
The leadership. So you see the three
The leadership. So you see the three things we have to get is the leader uh
things we have to get is the leader uh
things we have to get is the leader uh the people and the government. There's
the people and the government. There's
the people and the government. There's the people, there's the government and
the people, there's the government and
the people, there's the government and the leader. And there can be quite a
the leader. And there can be quite a
the leader. And there can be quite a disparity. You can have wonderful people
disparity. You can have wonderful people
disparity. You can have wonderful people who've been taken over by a dictator. Uh
who've been taken over by a dictator. Uh
who've been taken over by a dictator. Uh you can have lovely people, but their
you can have lovely people, but their
you can have lovely people, but their whole government is rotten to the core
whole government is rotten to the core
whole government is rotten to the core and $5 will buy you anything. So you
and $5 will buy you anything. So you
and $5 will buy you anything. So you have to know, you have to put the three
have to know, you have to put the three
have to know, you have to put the three together. But I think this is useful. If
together. But I think this is useful. If
together. But I think this is useful. If I was a diplomat, this is the first
I was a diplomat, this is the first
I was a diplomat, this is the first thing I'd want to know. I've got to talk
thing I'd want to know. I've got to talk
thing I'd want to know. I've got to talk to people from here about this subject
to people from here about this subject
to people from here about this subject here. And this is where I am about it.
here. And this is where I am about it.
here. And this is where I am about it. This is where the Republicans are, the
This is where the Republicans are, the
This is where the Republicans are, the Democrats, the president. Uh this is
Democrats, the president. Uh this is
Democrats, the president. Uh this is where my cabinet is. This is where their
where my cabinet is. This is where their
where my cabinet is. This is where their cabinet is. You know, I would have a
cabinet is. You know, I would have a
cabinet is. You know, I would have a whole book of I mean, I would have a
whole book of I mean, I would have a
whole book of I mean, I would have a staggering amount of information. So,
staggering amount of information. So,
staggering amount of information. So, you don't make any mistakes because you
you don't make any mistakes because you
you don't make any mistakes because you know exactly who you're dealing with and
know exactly who you're dealing with and
know exactly who you're dealing with and what level. And you know what their
what level. And you know what their
what level. And you know what their expectation is on that level and you
expectation is on that level and you
expectation is on that level and you don't make ridiculous comments and make
don't make ridiculous comments and make
don't make ridiculous comments and make a fool out of yourself. Soaps world
a fool out of yourself. Soaps world
a fool out of yourself. Soaps world leaders very often make absolute fools
leaders very often make absolute fools
leaders very often make absolute fools on themselves because they have no uh
on themselves because they have no uh
on themselves because they have no uh idea of credibility. They don't know who
idea of credibility. They don't know who
idea of credibility. They don't know who they're talking to. They don't
they're talking to. They don't
they're talking to. They don't understand the American psyche because a
understand the American psyche because a
understand the American psyche because a lot of things they say, you know, to us
lot of things they say, you know, to us
lot of things they say, you know, to us are ridiculous. And the other hand, we
are ridiculous. And the other hand, we
are ridiculous. And the other hand, we don't understand their their psyche
don't understand their their psyche
don't understand their their psyche either. You know, democracy probably
either. You know, democracy probably
either. You know, democracy probably sounds idiotic to them.
sounds idiotic to them.
sounds idiotic to them. I imagine democracy sounds like the
I imagine democracy sounds like the
I imagine democracy sounds like the stupidest fool idea that you could think
stupidest fool idea that you could think
stupidest fool idea that you could think of and we want them to buy it. Huh? Why
of and we want them to buy it. Huh? Why
of and we want them to buy it. Huh? Why should they buy it when it's stupid? You
should they buy it when it's stupid? You
should they buy it when it's stupid? You know, so the lack of communication is
know, so the lack of communication is
know, so the lack of communication is lack of awareness of where each person
lack of awareness of where each person
lack of awareness of where each person is. You know, as a psychiatrist, when a
is. You know, as a psychiatrist, when a
is. You know, as a psychiatrist, when a new patient walked into my office, it
new patient walked into my office, it
new patient walked into my office, it was up to me to know where they were, up
was up to me to know where they were, up
was up to me to know where they were, up to me to intuit it, to know, to verify.
to me to intuit it, to know, to verify.
to me to intuit it, to know, to verify. uh you've got to know who you're talking
uh you've got to know who you're talking
uh you've got to know who you're talking to and at what stage they are with
to and at what stage they are with
to and at what stage they are with various issues. And if I suggested a a
various issues. And if I suggested a a
various issues. And if I suggested a a to a guy at this point, he would have
to a guy at this point, he would have
to a guy at this point, he would have walked out of the office. And if I wait
walked out of the office. And if I wait
walked out of the office. And if I wait till later and now I've got him softened
till later and now I've got him softened
till later and now I've got him softened up and said, now if I suggested, he
up and said, now if I suggested, he
up and said, now if I suggested, he thinks it's a good idea. So timing
thinks it's a good idea. So timing
thinks it's a good idea. So timing depends on your estimation. And a lot of
depends on your estimation. And a lot of
depends on your estimation. And a lot of political disasters, diplomatic
political disasters, diplomatic
political disasters, diplomatic disaster, it's just very very poor
disaster, it's just very very poor
disaster, it's just very very poor timing. Very poor timing. And you hear
timing. Very poor timing. And you hear
timing. Very poor timing. And you hear it every night. reporting. Okay. With no
it every night. reporting. Okay. With no
it every night. reporting. Okay. With no preparation for the listener. So, you're
preparation for the listener. So, you're
preparation for the listener. So, you're thinking about you. Isn't democracy
thinking about you. Isn't democracy
thinking about you. Isn't democracy wonderful.
wonderful.
wonderful. You know,
You know,
You know, the be all end all of American life is
the be all end all of American life is
the be all end all of American life is democracy.
democracy.
democracy. But a large part of the world thinks
But a large part of the world thinks
But a large part of the world thinks it's stupid
it's stupid
it's stupid and they just don't wave flags with
and they just don't wave flags with
and they just don't wave flags with excitement when we offer them democracy.
excitement when we offer them democracy.
excitement when we offer them democracy. All right. The levels of happiness. Then
All right. The levels of happiness. Then
All right. The levels of happiness. Then we calibrated them here in the percent.
we calibrated them here in the percent.
we calibrated them here in the percent. As you see at the very bottom, the
As you see at the very bottom, the
As you see at the very bottom, the chances of being happy are not too down
chances of being happy are not too down
chances of being happy are not too down at the bottom. I guess the happiness is
at the bottom. I guess the happiness is
at the bottom. I guess the happiness is the thought you're going to be leaving
the thought you're going to be leaving
the thought you're going to be leaving this world soon.
All right. So the rate of happiness even
All right. So the rate of happiness even at pride you get 22%. So you can see why
at pride you get 22%. So you can see why
at pride you get 22%. So you can see why people many people are unwilling to let
people many people are unwilling to let
people many people are unwilling to let go of their anger or their pride because
go of their anger or their pride because
go of their anger or their pride because at least 12 or 22% of people are getting
at least 12 or 22% of people are getting
at least 12 or 22% of people are getting a good deal of feedback from it. But
a good deal of feedback from it. But
a good deal of feedback from it. But then you jump from happiness rate of 22%
then you jump from happiness rate of 22%
then you jump from happiness rate of 22% to 55% the minute you go over level 200.
to 55% the minute you go over level 200.
to 55% the minute you go over level 200. The minute you go over in integrity
The minute you go over in integrity
The minute you go over in integrity and as you go up the rate of happiness
and as you go up the rate of happiness
and as you go up the rate of happiness becomes more and more and more. And over
becomes more and more and more. And over
becomes more and more and more. And over here the reason it's out higher is I
here the reason it's out higher is I
here the reason it's out higher is I think because they are self
think because they are self
think because they are self uh their expectation of self is holding
uh their expectation of self is holding
uh their expectation of self is holding back their sense of happiness that their
back their sense of happiness that their
back their sense of happiness that their spiritual goals have not been reached
spiritual goals have not been reached
spiritual goals have not been reached and they uh are not into a state of
and they uh are not into a state of
and they uh are not into a state of ecstasy and joy yet. Okay, we'll move on
ecstasy and joy yet. Okay, we'll move on
ecstasy and joy yet. Okay, we'll move on now.
now.
now. Uh
Uh
Uh this is important because what we
this is important because what we
this is important because what we started with today are false teachings
started with today are false teachings
started with today are false teachings etc. And in all of them you can see the
etc. And in all of them you can see the
etc. And in all of them you can see the profound gain. The gain the sense of
profound gain. The gain the sense of
profound gain. The gain the sense of power over others, control, uh
power over others, control, uh
power over others, control, uh theatrics, the narcissistic ego just
theatrics, the narcissistic ego just
theatrics, the narcissistic ego just having a wonderful time. Uh titles, you
having a wonderful time. Uh titles, you
having a wonderful time. Uh titles, you know, grandmaster and the grand this and
know, grandmaster and the grand this and
know, grandmaster and the grand this and that. Um
that. Um
that. Um so I think this is very uh for the
so I think this is very uh for the
so I think this is very uh for the safety of students. This is really for
safety of students. This is really for
safety of students. This is really for everyone's safety that whatever you get
everyone's safety that whatever you get
everyone's safety that whatever you get involved with uh see where it lines up
involved with uh see where it lines up
involved with uh see where it lines up and where it might have a defect. An
and where it might have a defect. An
and where it might have a defect. An organization might be good uh except if
organization might be good uh except if
organization might be good uh except if you they if you try to leave it they put
you they if you try to leave it they put
you they if you try to leave it they put a rattlesnake in your mailbox that would
a rattlesnake in your mailbox that would
a rattlesnake in your mailbox that would sort of make you think twice
sort of make you think twice
sort of make you think twice which historically is a fact by the way.
which historically is a fact by the way.
which historically is a fact by the way. Yeah. So
Yeah. So
Yeah. So no requirements or demands, no
no requirements or demands, no
no requirements or demands, no membership, no no oaths, no swearing.
membership, no no oaths, no swearing.
membership, no no oaths, no swearing. You don't have to sign anything, no
You don't have to sign anything, no
You don't have to sign anything, no rules or conditions. Free to come and
rules or conditions. Free to come and
rules or conditions. Free to come and go. The teacher has no interest in in
go. The teacher has no interest in in
go. The teacher has no interest in in the trivia of life, you know, sex lives,
the trivia of life, you know, sex lives,
the trivia of life, you know, sex lives, economics, family patterns. Why? Because
economics, family patterns. Why? Because
economics, family patterns. Why? Because you're talking about level of
you're talking about level of
you're talking about level of consciousness and and not the linear
consciousness and and not the linear
consciousness and and not the linear domain. You're talking about the
domain. You're talking about the
domain. You're talking about the nonlinear
nonlinear
nonlinear uh integrity of purpose, availability,
uh integrity of purpose, availability,
uh integrity of purpose, availability, non-exclusive.
non-exclusive.
non-exclusive. Therefore, many of things that calibrate
Therefore, many of things that calibrate
Therefore, many of things that calibrate negative are secret ancient mysteries.
negative are secret ancient mysteries.
negative are secret ancient mysteries. You see the glamorization of calling it
You see the glamorization of calling it
You see the glamorization of calling it an ancient mystery. Oo, an ancient
an ancient mystery. Oo, an ancient
an ancient mystery. Oo, an ancient mystery.
mystery.
mystery. Oo.
Do you want an ancient vehicle? How
Do you want an ancient vehicle? How about an oxar?
about an oxar?
about an oxar? You want ancient communication? Thump
You want ancient communication? Thump
You want ancient communication? Thump smoke signals.
smoke signals.
smoke signals. You want ancient science?
You want ancient science?
You want ancient science? You want ancient medicine?
You want ancient medicine?
You want ancient medicine? Do you want a medicine man doing brain
Do you want a medicine man doing brain
Do you want a medicine man doing brain surgery on you?
You want an ancient mechanic fixing your
You want an ancient mechanic fixing your car?
car?
car? I'll tell you the truth about ancient
I'll tell you the truth about ancient
I'll tell you the truth about ancient stupid,
stupid,
stupid, uneducated, ignorant. I mean, what is so
uneducated, ignorant. I mean, what is so
uneducated, ignorant. I mean, what is so wonderful about a stone age guy's idea
wonderful about a stone age guy's idea
wonderful about a stone age guy's idea about the universe?
about the universe?
about the universe? He thinks the stars are God. Well,
He thinks the stars are God. Well,
He thinks the stars are God. Well, that's a good start.
But I have to be I wouldn't want to be
But I have to be I wouldn't want to be constrained by his knowledge of
constrained by his knowledge of
constrained by his knowledge of astronomy or anything else. And that's
astronomy or anything else. And that's
astronomy or anything else. And that's why in a lot of classic ancient
why in a lot of classic ancient
why in a lot of classic ancient literature, what you have is the
literature, what you have is the
literature, what you have is the mythology of a primitive culture which
mythology of a primitive culture which
mythology of a primitive culture which itself is extremely ignorant.
itself is extremely ignorant.
itself is extremely ignorant. You're talking about cultures where
You're talking about cultures where
You're talking about cultures where nobody could read, nobody went to
nobody could read, nobody went to
nobody could read, nobody went to school, nobody even hardly knew
school, nobody even hardly knew
school, nobody even hardly knew arithmetic other than the abacus.
arithmetic other than the abacus.
arithmetic other than the abacus. So what can come out of that?
So what can come out of that?
So what can come out of that? What can come come out of that is that
What can come come out of that is that
What can come come out of that is that the the ancient myths and cultural uh
the the ancient myths and cultural uh
the the ancient myths and cultural uh stories uh serve for a sense of
stories uh serve for a sense of
stories uh serve for a sense of solidarity, ethnic identification and
solidarity, ethnic identification and
solidarity, ethnic identification and they subtly have a lesson. Most of them
they subtly have a lesson. Most of them
they subtly have a lesson. Most of them subtly have a lesson within them. So the
subtly have a lesson within them. So the
subtly have a lesson within them. So the purpose is not whether the story is
purpose is not whether the story is
purpose is not whether the story is literally true or not. Whether Jonah was
literally true or not. Whether Jonah was
literally true or not. Whether Jonah was actually swallowed by a whale is
actually swallowed by a whale is
actually swallowed by a whale is actually irrelevant. You see? All right.
actually irrelevant. You see? All right.
actually irrelevant. You see? All right. So
So
So these are the basic requirements of any
these are the basic requirements of any
these are the basic requirements of any uh spiritual organization or teacher and
uh spiritual organization or teacher and
uh spiritual organization or teacher and this is to protect the student from
this is to protect the student from
this is to protect the student from being seduced, savaged than raped,
being seduced, savaged than raped,
being seduced, savaged than raped, spiritually raped. Spiritual rape is far
spiritually raped. Spiritual rape is far
spiritually raped. Spiritual rape is far more painful and devastating than
more painful and devastating than
more painful and devastating than physical rape. Physical rape is nothing
physical rape. Physical rape is nothing
physical rape. Physical rape is nothing compared to spiritual rape. Spiritual
compared to spiritual rape. Spiritual
compared to spiritual rape. Spiritual rape causes an injury, a devastation
rape causes an injury, a devastation
rape causes an injury, a devastation which goes on often for decades.
which goes on often for decades.
which goes on often for decades. Decades. Why? Because the exposure of
Decades. Why? Because the exposure of
Decades. Why? Because the exposure of faith. Faith. To put faith in this
faith. Faith. To put faith in this
faith. Faith. To put faith in this person and treat him almost in a godlike
person and treat him almost in a godlike
person and treat him almost in a godlike way and then find out that you've been
way and then find out that you've been
way and then find out that you've been savaged and raped is devastating.
savaged and raped is devastating.
savaged and raped is devastating. And I've treated people who have had
And I've treated people who have had
And I've treated people who have had that. Because I say the first one I met
that. Because I say the first one I met
that. Because I say the first one I met was by a local teacher who had fallen
was by a local teacher who had fallen
was by a local teacher who had fallen down. And when I met her, she was on six
down. And when I met her, she was on six
down. And when I met her, she was on six Prozac a day to keep her from suicide.
Prozac a day to keep her from suicide.
Prozac a day to keep her from suicide. Six Prozac.
Six Prozac.
Six Prozac. The devastation of spiritual rape is
The devastation of spiritual rape is
The devastation of spiritual rape is horrendous. Consequently, do not take a
horrendous. Consequently, do not take a
horrendous. Consequently, do not take a risk. Do not take a risk. And don't
risk. Do not take a risk. And don't
risk. Do not take a risk. And don't think that because when you find out
think that because when you find out
think that because when you find out your mistake, you're going to be okay.
your mistake, you're going to be okay.
your mistake, you're going to be okay. Because if you were really a devote,
Because if you were really a devote,
Because if you were really a devote, then you deopified the teacher. And it's
then you deopified the teacher. And it's
then you deopified the teacher. And it's like you just gotten raped by God in the
like you just gotten raped by God in the
like you just gotten raped by God in the way. It's so savage disillusionment
way. It's so savage disillusionment
way. It's so savage disillusionment and that's something you want to have
and that's something you want to have
and that's something you want to have happen to you. Yeah. So the simplest way
happen to you. Yeah. So the simplest way
happen to you. Yeah. So the simplest way is to avoid it in the first place by
is to avoid it in the first place by
is to avoid it in the first place by watching all these things which are
watching all these things which are
watching all these things which are predictive. All right.
I don't want the bad karma of having
I don't want the bad karma of having failed to say what I've just said.
Now I feel it my responsibility plus
Now I feel it my responsibility plus I've had personal experience as well as
I've had personal experience as well as
I've had personal experience as well as clinical experience so I know wherever
clinical experience so I know wherever
clinical experience so I know wherever I'm speaking and I've also calibrated of
I'm speaking and I've also calibrated of
I'm speaking and I've also calibrated of course all these various cults and etc.
course all these various cults and etc.
course all these various cults and etc. And therefore to safeguard the students
And therefore to safeguard the students
And therefore to safeguard the students we have the spiritual we have the
we have the spiritual we have the
we have the spiritual we have the spiritual teachers
spiritual teachers
spiritual teachers uh am I supposed to look at my watch?
uh am I supposed to look at my watch?
uh am I supposed to look at my watch? >> We have 10 minutes.
>> We have 10 minutes.
>> We have 10 minutes. >> Huh?
>> Huh?
>> Huh? >> We have 10 minutes.
>> We have 10 minutes.
>> We have 10 minutes. >> I have 10 minutes. Oh my god. So
>> I have 10 minutes. Oh my god. So
>> I have 10 minutes. Oh my god. So here's all the great ones. They're
here's all the great ones. They're
here's all the great ones. They're listed for you.
listed for you.
listed for you. There's over a hundred
There's over a hundred
There's over a hundred over 100 calibrated, verified,
over 100 calibrated, verified,
over 100 calibrated, verified, authenticated. And I know the minute I
authenticated. And I know the minute I
authenticated. And I know the minute I say this, I will get an email. But what
say this, I will get an email. But what
say this, I will get an email. But what about Swami Pucha?
He always calibrates 190. I know what it
He always calibrates 190. I know what it is. wisdom and I see the email come
is. wisdom and I see the email come
is. wisdom and I see the email come through because if he was really
through because if he was really
through because if he was really integrous why would you have a doubt
integrous why would you have a doubt
integrous why would you have a doubt want to know what he calibrates at and
want to know what he calibrates at and
want to know what he calibrates at and where did you get this guy out of a
where did you get this guy out of a
where did you get this guy out of a corner he got over a hund of the
corner he got over a hund of the
corner he got over a hund of the greatest teachers of all time so what do
greatest teachers of all time so what do
greatest teachers of all time so what do you do you go down and you look
you do you go down and you look
you do you go down and you look underneath the mouse hole here's Swami
underneath the mouse hole here's Swami
underneath the mouse hole here's Swami puts
puts
puts give me a break first do this hund then
give me a break first do this hund then
give me a break first do this hund then send me the email about Swami puts
send me the email about Swami puts
send me the email about Swami puts who may well be on the other side to
who may well be on the other side to
who may well be on the other side to make get even worse. God help us.
When you get done with these, then give
When you get done with these, then give me an email.
me an email.
me an email. I mean, I get the weird ones from all
I mean, I get the weird ones from all
I mean, I get the weird ones from all over.
over.
over. Okay, now we go ahead. Uh, I just say
Okay, now we go ahead. Uh, I just say
Okay, now we go ahead. Uh, I just say that because you can see there's
that because you can see there's
that because you can see there's something um resistant in the person. If
something um resistant in the person. If
something um resistant in the person. If I tell you a hundred easy ways to get to
I tell you a hundred easy ways to get to
I tell you a hundred easy ways to get to the North Pole and you telegraph me from
the North Pole and you telegraph me from
the North Pole and you telegraph me from Puchagand Co Manga Rock,
Puchagand Co Manga Rock,
Puchagand Co Manga Rock, I mean, you didn't want to get to the
I mean, you didn't want to get to the
I mean, you didn't want to get to the North Pole, did you? Because I already
North Pole, did you? Because I already
North Pole, did you? Because I already gave you 42 ways to get there. So,
gave you 42 ways to get there. So,
gave you 42 ways to get there. So, you're up to something else. So, you
you're up to something else. So, you
you're up to something else. So, you left to look in yourself and say, "What
left to look in yourself and say, "What
left to look in yourself and say, "What is the something else I'm
is the something else I'm
is the something else I'm into where I'm avoiding the obvious?"
into where I'm avoiding the obvious?"
into where I'm avoiding the obvious?" You're avoiding the obvious. Why are you
You're avoiding the obvious. Why are you
You're avoiding the obvious. Why are you avoiding the obvious, the easy, sure,
avoiding the obvious, the easy, sure,
avoiding the obvious, the easy, sure, established pathway in order to find
established pathway in order to find
established pathway in order to find something unique and exotic? Yeah. So,
something unique and exotic? Yeah. So,
something unique and exotic? Yeah. So, there's probably a karmic proclivity.
there's probably a karmic proclivity.
there's probably a karmic proclivity. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. Here the attraction and aversion.
Here the attraction and aversion.
Here the attraction and aversion. We said that everything sticks where it
We said that everything sticks where it
We said that everything sticks where it sticks because of two sides. One is it
sticks because of two sides. One is it
sticks because of two sides. One is it has a payoff. That's the attraction. And
has a payoff. That's the attraction. And
has a payoff. That's the attraction. And the aversion is what would come up if
the aversion is what would come up if
the aversion is what would come up if you let it go. What would come up if you
you let it go. What would come up if you
you let it go. What would come up if you let it go?
let it go?
let it go? Uh, so here's the attraction. Yeah. And
Uh, so here's the attraction. Yeah. And
Uh, so here's the attraction. Yeah. And here's what you're afraid may come up if
here's what you're afraid may come up if
here's what you're afraid may come up if you let it go. And here again is the
you let it go. And here again is the
you let it go. And here again is the attraction. And here's what's going to
attraction. And here's what's going to
attraction. And here's what's going to come up. One thing that comes up when
come up. One thing that comes up when
come up. One thing that comes up when you let go of level is the one that's
you let go of level is the one that's
you let go of level is the one that's below it. You see, like anger underneath
below it. You see, like anger underneath
below it. You see, like anger underneath anger is somebody just hurt your
anger is somebody just hurt your
anger is somebody just hurt your feelings. And so you're really you're
feelings. And so you're really you're
feelings. And so you're really you're from pride. If you were humble, you
from pride. If you were humble, you
from pride. If you were humble, you wouldn't have had hurt feelings. So now
wouldn't have had hurt feelings. So now
wouldn't have had hurt feelings. So now you wouldn't be angry. So you wouldn't
you wouldn't be angry. So you wouldn't
you wouldn't be angry. So you wouldn't be thinking about revenge. See what I'm
be thinking about revenge. See what I'm
be thinking about revenge. See what I'm saying? And then when all that crashes,
saying? And then when all that crashes,
saying? And then when all that crashes, you feel depressed. So you see the whole
you feel depressed. So you see the whole
you feel depressed. So you see the whole stack. You pull out one toothpick. What
stack. You pull out one toothpick. What
stack. You pull out one toothpick. What was that? Pickup sticks we used to play
was that? Pickup sticks we used to play
was that? Pickup sticks we used to play as kids. You pull out this one st stick
as kids. You pull out this one st stick
as kids. You pull out this one st stick and it all collapses. So the secret of
and it all collapses. So the secret of
and it all collapses. So the secret of rather rapid spiritual evolutions to see
rather rapid spiritual evolutions to see
rather rapid spiritual evolutions to see these are all sticks and that when you
these are all sticks and that when you
these are all sticks and that when you pull one out, uh, a whole bunch of them
pull one out, uh, a whole bunch of them
pull one out, uh, a whole bunch of them will collapse. Uhhuh.
will collapse. Uhhuh.
will collapse. Uhhuh. All right. So, we'll go to the next
All right. So, we'll go to the next
All right. So, we'll go to the next uh diagnostic differential. Oh,
uh diagnostic differential. Oh,
uh diagnostic differential. Oh, infatuation versus love. Uh this is one
infatuation versus love. Uh this is one
infatuation versus love. Uh this is one that was sort of popular with quite a
that was sort of popular with quite a
that was sort of popular with quite a few people. Uh the quality of love
few people. Uh the quality of love
few people. Uh the quality of love itself is attracted to passion. You see
itself is attracted to passion. You see
itself is attracted to passion. You see that passionate attraction calibrates
that passionate attraction calibrates
that passionate attraction calibrates about 145.
about 145.
about 145. Therefore, it's an animal instinct. You
Therefore, it's an animal instinct. You
Therefore, it's an animal instinct. You know, frantic to mate, frantic, frantic,
know, frantic to mate, frantic, frantic,
know, frantic to mate, frantic, frantic, frantic. Like in heat, frantic, frantic,
frantic. Like in heat, frantic, frantic,
frantic. Like in heat, frantic, frantic, frantic. Uh,
frantic. Uh,
frantic. Uh, you see it on the nature nature
you see it on the nature nature
you see it on the nature nature at night. You know, these two animals
at night. You know, these two animals
at night. You know, these two animals killing each other is for the frantic
killing each other is for the frantic
killing each other is for the frantic frantic desire to meet, huh?
frantic desire to meet, huh?
frantic desire to meet, huh? The idea is that so they will see that
The idea is that so they will see that
The idea is that so they will see that their proeny
their proeny
their proeny uh propagate. That's teologic thinking.
uh propagate. That's teologic thinking.
uh propagate. That's teologic thinking. The bull just doesn't isn't interested
The bull just doesn't isn't interested
The bull just doesn't isn't interested in offspring. He just wants the matrix
in offspring. He just wants the matrix
in offspring. He just wants the matrix or anything.
or anything.
or anything. He not trying to establish his genetic
He not trying to establish his genetic
He not trying to establish his genetic line, you know, that's the crap that
line, you know, that's the crap that
line, you know, that's the crap that gets rejected on this. I mean, this bull
gets rejected on this. I mean, this bull
gets rejected on this. I mean, this bull just wants that cow and that's all there
just wants that cow and that's all there
just wants that cow and that's all there is to it. He don't give a damn about
is to it. He don't give a damn about
is to it. He don't give a damn about genes or carrying on his genetic line.
genes or carrying on his genetic line.
genes or carrying on his genetic line. That's all academic uh pulley poo
That's all academic uh pulley poo
That's all academic uh pulley poo predicted on it.
Oh, these are this is shame. Anybody who
Oh, these are this is shame. Anybody who hangs on to shame should be ashamed of
hangs on to shame should be ashamed of
hangs on to shame should be ashamed of themselves.
Give up shame.
Give up shame. Give up all this self-punitive behavior.
Give up all this self-punitive behavior.
Give up all this self-punitive behavior. You see, cuz sometimes what you do is
You see, cuz sometimes what you do is
You see, cuz sometimes what you do is you can't do it to yourself, but you put
you can't do it to yourself, but you put
you can't do it to yourself, but you put yourself into a position where others
yourself into a position where others
yourself into a position where others will do it. You see what I'm saying?
will do it. You see what I'm saying?
will do it. You see what I'm saying? Then you can blame them. Actually,
Then you can blame them. Actually,
Then you can blame them. Actually, you're the one that precipitated that.
you're the one that precipitated that.
you're the one that precipitated that. You dropped the hint. Now the gossip is
You dropped the hint. Now the gossip is
You dropped the hint. Now the gossip is out there. Now you can blame them for
out there. Now you can blame them for
out there. Now you can blame them for being gossip, you know. Okay, we'll move
being gossip, you know. Okay, we'll move
being gossip, you know. Okay, we'll move on. Shame. We'll move on.
on. Shame. We'll move on.
on. Shame. We'll move on. Um,
Um,
Um, guilt and hate. Of course, we see guilt
guilt and hate. Of course, we see guilt
guilt and hate. Of course, we see guilt is um expeditative in our own fantasy
is um expeditative in our own fantasy
is um expeditative in our own fantasy and hatred is self-propagating. Hatred
and hatred is self-propagating. Hatred
and hatred is self-propagating. Hatred is self-propagating. And of course as we
is self-propagating. And of course as we
is self-propagating. And of course as we see one reason the calibration level of
see one reason the calibration level of
see one reason the calibration level of the world has gone down is because
the world has gone down is because
the world has gone down is because hatred has become so widespread
hatred has become so widespread
hatred has become so widespread and socially acceptable and approved
and socially acceptable and approved
and socially acceptable and approved socially acceptable and approved even in
socially acceptable and approved even in
socially acceptable and approved even in our own politics. So you know hatred
our own politics. So you know hatred
our own politics. So you know hatred hatred of uh especially of the leader uh
hatred of uh especially of the leader uh
hatred of uh especially of the leader uh is accepted accepted. So when you accept
is accepted accepted. So when you accept
is accepted accepted. So when you accept hatred as normal and even even uh
hatred as normal and even even uh
hatred as normal and even even uh encourage it uh by all kinds of
encourage it uh by all kinds of
encourage it uh by all kinds of publicity etc. Yeah, you can make
publicity etc. Yeah, you can make
publicity etc. Yeah, you can make millions of dollars in today's world
millions of dollars in today's world
millions of dollars in today's world with hate hatred. You can get yourself
with hate hatred. You can get yourself
with hate hatred. You can get yourself on the cover of anything and make
on the cover of anything and make
on the cover of anything and make millions within a matter of weeks if by
millions within a matter of weeks if by
millions within a matter of weeks if by you know hatred. So naturally people
you know hatred. So naturally people
you know hatred. So naturally people would not want to let go of hatred
would not want to let go of hatred
would not want to let go of hatred because that's their their whole claim
because that's their their whole claim
because that's their their whole claim to fame. Okay. So we'll move on.
to fame. Okay. So we'll move on.
to fame. Okay. So we'll move on. Uh blame of course is the underpinning
Uh blame of course is the underpinning
Uh blame of course is the underpinning of social maladjustment and and uh that
of social maladjustment and and uh that
of social maladjustment and and uh that black comedian who lectures to the kids
black comedian who lectures to the kids
black comedian who lectures to the kids about letting go of blame and taking
about letting go of blame and taking
about letting go of blame and taking responsibility.
responsibility.
responsibility. >> Cosby
>> Cosby
>> Cosby >> Cosby great guy.
>> Cosby great guy.
>> Cosby great guy. Of course you see how how how welcome
Of course you see how how how welcome
Of course you see how how how welcome his message is.
How much more fun it is to be able to
How much more fun it is to be able to blame and hate the supposed cause of
blame and hate the supposed cause of
blame and hate the supposed cause of your problems is out there. and he calls
your problems is out there. and he calls
your problems is out there. and he calls him up calls him up on it and he's got
him up calls him up on it and he's got
him up calls him up on it and he's got the courage to face the flack. He's got
the courage to face the flack. He's got
the courage to face the flack. He's got the courage to face the flack. He knew
the courage to face the flack. He knew
the courage to face the flack. He knew he's going to pull out flack but he
he's going to pull out flack but he
he's going to pull out flack but he doesn't anyway. So you know he's worried
doesn't anyway. So you know he's worried
doesn't anyway. So you know he's worried about his soul and he's worried about
about his soul and he's worried about
about his soul and he's worried about the soul of these kids and uh current
the soul of these kids and uh current
the soul of these kids and uh current popularity he so he's a very de
popularity he so he's a very de
popularity he so he's a very de spiritually intigous kind of guy. Apathy
spiritually intigous kind of guy. Apathy
spiritually intigous kind of guy. Apathy of course is very difficult for people
of course is very difficult for people
of course is very difficult for people to understand and of course as a
to understand and of course as a
to understand and of course as a psychiatrist I saw this in in severe
psychiatrist I saw this in in severe
psychiatrist I saw this in in severe severe
severe
severe expressions of self-pity and
expressions of self-pity and
expressions of self-pity and helplessness and just laying down
helplessness and just laying down
helplessness and just laying down and uh we saw this so much after major
and uh we saw this so much after major
and uh we saw this so much after major catastrophes
catastrophes
catastrophes uh
the major catastrophes people into
the major catastrophes people into helplessness and and then into rage over
helplessness and and then into rage over
helplessness and and then into rage over the fact that uh others didn't do for
the fact that uh others didn't do for
the fact that uh others didn't do for them. The time to plan for catastrophe
them. The time to plan for catastrophe
them. The time to plan for catastrophe is now. And of course, the most recent
is now. And of course, the most recent
is now. And of course, the most recent poll shows that even after that, most of
poll shows that even after that, most of
poll shows that even after that, most of the big cities of the world are still
the big cities of the world are still
the big cities of the world are still not ready for a cast catastrophe. I
not ready for a cast catastrophe. I
not ready for a cast catastrophe. I don't know if they ever will be. You
don't know if they ever will be. You
don't know if they ever will be. You know why? Because you got to use common
know why? Because you got to use common
know why? Because you got to use common sense.
sense.
sense. uh
uh
uh grief grief uh we say we want to get rid
grief grief uh we say we want to get rid
grief grief uh we say we want to get rid of grief and and yet there is of course
of grief and and yet there is of course
of grief and and yet there is of course the classic stages of grief uh by that
the classic stages of grief uh by that
the classic stages of grief uh by that psychiatrist whose name I forgot uh
psychiatrist whose name I forgot uh
psychiatrist whose name I forgot uh anger resentment um
anger resentment um
anger resentment um bargaining etc. Okay quickly the next
bargaining etc. Okay quickly the next
bargaining etc. Okay quickly the next one the dualities of grief next one
one the dualities of grief next one
one the dualities of grief next one dualities of fear they all have a big
dualities of fear they all have a big
dualities of fear they all have a big payoff next one next one Oh,
payoff next one next one Oh,
payoff next one next one Oh, >> you got all them, right? Okay, next one.
>> you got all them, right? Okay, next one.
>> you got all them, right? Okay, next one. Oh,
okay. After pride, what do we got?
okay. After pride, what do we got? Comparative dualities.
Comparative dualities.
Comparative dualities. Oh, yes. They're they're held in place
Oh, yes. They're they're held in place
Oh, yes. They're they're held in place by a desire and also by its opposite of
by a desire and also by its opposite of
by a desire and also by its opposite of a fear if we let them go. If I'm not
a fear if we let them go. If I'm not
a fear if we let them go. If I'm not greedy, won't I be poor? If I'm not
greedy, won't I be poor? If I'm not
greedy, won't I be poor? If I'm not looking to win all the time, won't I
looking to win all the time, won't I
looking to win all the time, won't I lose? So all right, we'll move to the
lose? So all right, we'll move to the
lose? So all right, we'll move to the next one because we're going to have a
next one because we're going to have a
next one because we're going to have a break. The true nature of reality of
break. The true nature of reality of
break. The true nature of reality of divinity
divinity
divinity in today's world. What can the modern
in today's world. What can the modern
in today's world. What can the modern mind believe about religion and
mind believe about religion and
mind believe about religion and spiritual reality? Uh spiritual reality
spiritual reality? Uh spiritual reality
spiritual reality? Uh spiritual reality and modern man is the name of it. And
and modern man is the name of it. And
and modern man is the name of it. And uh if we go back to see what validity is
uh if we go back to see what validity is
uh if we go back to see what validity is available to anyone in today's world, we
available to anyone in today's world, we
available to anyone in today's world, we can see what degree of confidence. So
can see what degree of confidence. So
can see what degree of confidence. So for faith there should be confidence
for faith there should be confidence
for faith there should be confidence that con confidence should be into
that con confidence should be into
that con confidence should be into something verifiably integrous and
something verifiably integrous and
something verifiably integrous and therefore we've published pretty much as
therefore we've published pretty much as
therefore we've published pretty much as close as I can get to the true integrity
close as I can get to the true integrity
close as I can get to the true integrity uh for whatever good next
uh for whatever good next
uh for whatever good next uh
uh
uh does God exist? Well, we use
does God exist? Well, we use
does God exist? Well, we use consciousness research and we see that
consciousness research and we see that
consciousness research and we see that all references to God are infinity. That
all references to God are infinity. That
all references to God are infinity. That sort of does settle the question.
We see that the great avatars calibrate
We see that the great avatars calibrate really at a thousand but in their
really at a thousand but in their
really at a thousand but in their essence at infinity. And therefore we
essence at infinity. And therefore we
essence at infinity. And therefore we verify for a modern man who's scientific
verify for a modern man who's scientific
verify for a modern man who's scientific scientific logical etc. He says why
scientific logical etc. He says why
scientific logical etc. He says why should I believe in this? we say well
should I believe in this? we say well
should I believe in this? we say well this is the verification of the truth of
this is the verification of the truth of
this is the verification of the truth of it. All right. So, we'll move on. Okay.
it. All right. So, we'll move on. Okay.
it. All right. So, we'll move on. Okay. A thousand and the highest here. Here
A thousand and the highest here. Here
A thousand and the highest here. Here are the great spiritual teachers which
are the great spiritual teachers which
are the great spiritual teachers which we've repeated in a couple of books. And
we've repeated in a couple of books. And
we've repeated in a couple of books. And we'll move on so that people don't fall
we'll move on so that people don't fall
we'll move on so that people don't fall into falsehood.
into falsehood.
into falsehood. Uh and this is uh we could spend this
Uh and this is uh we could spend this
Uh and this is uh we could spend this course quite a bit of time on this one.
course quite a bit of time on this one.
course quite a bit of time on this one. Uh other teaching schools and traditions
Uh other teaching schools and traditions
Uh other teaching schools and traditions from body work. This is the kind of
from body work. This is the kind of
from body work. This is the kind of thing most almost everybody has gotten
thing most almost everybody has gotten
thing most almost everybody has gotten involved with. If you're into the
involved with. If you're into the
involved with. If you're into the spiritual world, most of us have checked
spiritual world, most of us have checked
spiritual world, most of us have checked out, you know, agnosticism maybe and uh
out, you know, agnosticism maybe and uh
out, you know, agnosticism maybe and uh archangel channelers, we've looked at
archangel channelers, we've looked at
archangel channelers, we've looked at astrology, bio feedback, body work, uh
astrology, bio feedback, body work, uh
astrology, bio feedback, body work, uh we've done workshops on codependency, we
we've done workshops on codependency, we
we've done workshops on codependency, we played with crystals, we've gotten
played with crystals, we've gotten
played with crystals, we've gotten readings, and we checked out eken car
readings, and we checked out eken car
readings, and we checked out eken car and est and we did all these ethical
and est and we did all these ethical
and est and we did all these ethical culture uh fenchu. We got mirrors and
culture uh fenchu. We got mirrors and
culture uh fenchu. We got mirrors and things all around the house.
things all around the house.
things all around the house. rearranged the garden in different flow
rearranged the garden in different flow
rearranged the garden in different flow lines. We've all done yoga. We tried
lines. We've all done yoga. We tried
lines. We've all done yoga. We tried holotropic. This is all the stuff we
holotropic. This is all the stuff we
holotropic. This is all the stuff we did, isn't it? We did the Iching.
did, isn't it? We did the Iching.
did, isn't it? We did the Iching. Checked out the keys of Eno. I checked
Checked out the keys of Eno. I checked
Checked out the keys of Eno. I checked out curling photography.
out curling photography.
out curling photography. Didn't we do kung fu and numerology?
Didn't we do kung fu and numerology?
Didn't we do kung fu and numerology? Didn't we all do Key Gong? We Everybody
Didn't we all do Key Gong? We Everybody
Didn't we all do Key Gong? We Everybody got rebirth and did Reiki and got Ralph
got rebirth and did Reiki and got Ralph
got rebirth and did Reiki and got Ralph and uh didn't you guys do that? Anybody
and uh didn't you guys do that? Anybody
and uh didn't you guys do that? Anybody here didn't get Ralph?
Check out the White Brotherhood. Check
Check out the White Brotherhood. Check out White Magic and Wu Den. I don't know
out White Magic and Wu Den. I don't know
out White Magic and Wu Den. I don't know what the Wu Den is, but it's one I
what the Wu Den is, but it's one I
what the Wu Den is, but it's one I missed. I knew I'd missed something. I
missed. I knew I'd missed something. I
missed. I knew I'd missed something. I got to do Wuen now. So that I've done
got to do Wuen now. So that I've done
got to do Wuen now. So that I've done Wuen and clear off this whole stack.
Wuen and clear off this whole stack.
Wuen and clear off this whole stack. Okay, one more and then we're done.
Okay, one more and then we're done.
Okay, one more and then we're done. Secularism at 185. 165 is of course the
Secularism at 185. 165 is of course the
Secularism at 185. 165 is of course the threat with relativism.
threat with relativism.
threat with relativism. Relativism is the leading edge by which
Relativism is the leading edge by which
Relativism is the leading edge by which secularism takes over.
secularism takes over.
secularism takes over. Okay. and his marginal spiritual
Okay. and his marginal spiritual
Okay. and his marginal spiritual religious belief system. This is a very
religious belief system. This is a very
religious belief system. This is a very all very interesting. The left behind
all very interesting. The left behind
all very interesting. The left behind apocalyptic ideology is quite popular.
apocalyptic ideology is quite popular.
apocalyptic ideology is quite popular. They sell a lot of books but we see that
They sell a lot of books but we see that
They sell a lot of books but we see that it is uh you know predictions of the
it is uh you know predictions of the
it is uh you know predictions of the future and we've done most of these
future and we've done most of these
future and we've done most of these before. So we'll move on to the next and
before. So we'll move on to the next and
before. So we'll move on to the next and then we'll move on to the next and uh
then we'll move on to the next and uh
then we'll move on to the next and uh move on to the next.
move on to the next.
move on to the next. uh
uh
uh these are merely confirmations of higher
these are merely confirmations of higher
these are merely confirmations of higher spiritual states. As a scientist, I like
spiritual states. As a scientist, I like
spiritual states. As a scientist, I like to see validation of the claims of any
to see validation of the claims of any
to see validation of the claims of any field. I like to see it validated by
field. I like to see it validated by
field. I like to see it validated by another field. I like to see one field
another field. I like to see one field
another field. I like to see one field validated by another discipline that
validated by another discipline that
validated by another discipline that comes in and says yes that is. So that's
comes in and says yes that is. So that's
comes in and says yes that is. So that's why I get a kick out of that uh
why I get a kick out of that uh
why I get a kick out of that uh physicist advanced theoretical physics
physicist advanced theoretical physics
physicist advanced theoretical physics uh when you grasp that time and space
uh when you grasp that time and space
uh when you grasp that time and space etc are all projections. Uh it's like we
etc are all projections. Uh it's like we
etc are all projections. Uh it's like we confirm back and forth. I haven't
confirm back and forth. I haven't
confirm back and forth. I haven't written them yet but I probably will. Do
written them yet but I probably will. Do
written them yet but I probably will. Do we quit now? All right. What what do we
we quit now? All right. What what do we
we quit now? All right. What what do we take a break and then we have questions
take a break and then we have questions
take a break and then we have questions and answers? We get another break. Oh.
wonderful. What a wonderful group.
wonderful. What a wonderful group. >> It's a wonderful group, isn't it?
>> It's a wonderful group, isn't it?
>> It's a wonderful group, isn't it? >> I think they're just fantastic.
>> I think they're just fantastic.
>> I think they're just fantastic. >> I'm very very fortunate.
>> No, folks, uh we tell the Creative Life
>> No, folks, uh we tell the Creative Life Center is having somebody else come in
Center is having somebody else come in
Center is having somebody else come in after we leave. So, we've been requested
after we leave. So, we've been requested
after we leave. So, we've been requested to be prompt when we leave. Uh, so we're
to be prompt when we leave. Uh, so we're
to be prompt when we leave. Uh, so we're going to cut off at five o'clock.
going to cut off at five o'clock.
going to cut off at five o'clock. Consequently, if you have a question,
Consequently, if you have a question,
Consequently, if you have a question, uh, we don't have time to hear your life
uh, we don't have time to hear your life
uh, we don't have time to hear your life story.
Try and distill it to a statement or
Try and distill it to a statement or two.
two.
two. >> Try to distill it to the crux of the
>> Try to distill it to the crux of the
>> Try to distill it to the crux of the matter, you know,
matter, you know,
matter, you know, and that'll save time. Also, you'll
and that'll save time. Also, you'll
and that'll save time. Also, you'll understand the answer better because a
understand the answer better because a
understand the answer better because a lot of times it's a very complicated
lot of times it's a very complicated
lot of times it's a very complicated question. When I've answered it, they I
question. When I've answered it, they I
question. When I've answered it, they I notice they walk away with a day's look.
notice they walk away with a day's look.
notice they walk away with a day's look. So, they didn't get it anyway.
So, they didn't get it anyway.
So, they didn't get it anyway. >> Yes. Ma'am,
>> Yes. Ma'am,
>> Yes. Ma'am, >> a friend of mine is going to India to
>> a friend of mine is going to India to
>> a friend of mine is going to India to see Romesh. And I was wondering
see Romesh. And I was wondering
see Romesh. And I was wondering >> to see what
>> to see what
>> to see what >> Romesh Balsakar
>> Romesh Balsakar
>> Romesh Balsakar Bachar.
Bachar.
Bachar. >> Yes, ma'am.
>> Yes, ma'am.
>> Yes, ma'am. >> And I was wondering if you would
>> And I was wondering if you would
>> And I was wondering if you would calibrate his current level of
calibrate his current level of
calibrate his current level of consciousness. He's going soon.
consciousness. He's going soon.
consciousness. He's going soon. >> You you've been following what's
>> You you've been following what's
>> You you've been following what's happened with him on the internet and
happened with him on the internet and
happened with him on the internet and you're aware of it, correct? Um,
you're aware of it, correct? Um,
you're aware of it, correct? Um, >> yes. Well, that's the answer.
>> yes. Well, that's the answer.
>> yes. Well, that's the answer. >> So, are you saying that you
>> So, are you saying that you
>> So, are you saying that you >> don't need calibration? You don't need a
>> don't need calibration? You don't need a
>> don't need calibration? You don't need a calibration.
calibration.
calibration. >> You You believe he's gone down.
>> You You believe he's gone down.
>> You You believe he's gone down. >> I said the answer's already out there in
>> I said the answer's already out there in
>> I said the answer's already out there in in
in
in E land. WW land.
E land. WW land.
E land. WW land. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. I knew him when
>> and the calibration I had in the book
>> and the calibration I had in the book was was the win.
was was the win.
was was the win. >> Dr. Hawkins, I've been uh studying with
>> Dr. Hawkins, I've been uh studying with
>> Dr. Hawkins, I've been uh studying with an organization whose one of whose
an organization whose one of whose
an organization whose one of whose distinctions is word creates world as
distinctions is word creates world as
distinctions is word creates world as language as a way of manifesting. And I
language as a way of manifesting. And I
language as a way of manifesting. And I was wondering if you could world
was wondering if you could world
was wondering if you could world >> word creates world.
>> word creates world.
>> word creates world. Oh, you think it comes out of the word
>> language?
>> language? >> In the beginning, what does it say in
>> In the beginning, what does it say in
>> In the beginning, what does it say in Genesis?
Genesis?
Genesis? >> In the beginning was the word.
>> In the beginning was the word.
>> In the beginning was the word. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And the word was God.
>> And the word was God.
>> And the word was God. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> And the word was with God.
>> And the word was with God.
>> And the word was with God. >> Okay. So that gives it the background.
>> Okay. So that gives it the background.
>> Okay. So that gives it the background. Yes.
Yes.
Yes. >> Sorry.
>> Sorry.
>> Sorry. >> So what about it?
>> So what about it?
>> So what about it? >> That's it. Word creates world.
The beginning was the word.
The beginning was the word. >> Thank you. I myself don't believe that
>> Thank you. I myself don't believe that
>> Thank you. I myself don't believe that that was the beginning because prior to
that was the beginning because prior to
that was the beginning because prior to the world word
the world word
the world word was
because the word is God
because the word is God expressed as God.
expressed as God.
expressed as God. Prior to that was the Godhead.
Prior to that was the Godhead.
Prior to that was the Godhead. I ask permission. Prior to that was the
I ask permission. Prior to that was the
I ask permission. Prior to that was the godhead.
godhead.
godhead. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Prior to Genesis,
>> Genesis is the expression of the
>> Genesis is the expression of the potentiality of the Godhead into
potentiality of the Godhead into
potentiality of the Godhead into uh
Dr. Hawkins, my question refers to
Dr. Hawkins, my question refers to music.
music.
music. >> When calibrating the right form of music
>> When calibrating the right form of music
>> When calibrating the right form of music to listen to, what are you basing the
to listen to, what are you basing the
to listen to, what are you basing the calibration on? The form, the sound, the
calibration on? The form, the sound, the
calibration on? The form, the sound, the mu musical composer, the notes. You can
mu musical composer, the notes. You can
mu musical composer, the notes. You can break it down if you like.
break it down if you like.
break it down if you like. Uh I just ask what is the overall impact
Uh I just ask what is the overall impact
Uh I just ask what is the overall impact of it. Of course, I've also in truth
of it. Of course, I've also in truth
of it. Of course, I've also in truth versus falsehood calibrated composers.
versus falsehood calibrated composers.
versus falsehood calibrated composers. You can, you know, you can calibrate
You can, you know, you can calibrate
You can, you know, you can calibrate composer and music,
composer and music,
composer and music, etc. I've never broke it down that much.
etc. I've never broke it down that much.
etc. I've never broke it down that much. Like the music we play here calibrates
Like the music we play here calibrates
Like the music we play here calibrates the 700 and uh the author of that is um
the 700 and uh the author of that is um
the 700 and uh the author of that is um >> Robert G.
>> Robert G.
>> Robert G. >> Yeah. Robert Gas. Yeah. Uh so I don't
>> Yeah. Robert Gas. Yeah. Uh so I don't
>> Yeah. Robert Gas. Yeah. Uh so I don't break it down into him as a person or
break it down into him as a person or
break it down into him as a person or individual. What's the what's the
individual. What's the what's the
individual. What's the what's the impact? You know what I mean? What's the
impact? You know what I mean? What's the
impact? You know what I mean? What's the impact of Loam? You know,
impact of Loam? You know,
impact of Loam? You know, >> thank you. Why does Lap Boy make you
>> thank you. Why does Lap Boy make you
>> thank you. Why does Lap Boy make you cry? I don't know. Always makes me cry.
cry? I don't know. Always makes me cry.
cry? I don't know. Always makes me cry. >> We have a gift for you for Father's Day,
>> We have a gift for you for Father's Day,
>> We have a gift for you for Father's Day, Dr. Hawkins from the group.
Dr. Hawkins from the group.
Dr. Hawkins from the group. >> Isn't that nice? Isn't that nice? Hey,
>> Isn't that nice? Isn't that nice? Hey,
>> Isn't that nice? Isn't that nice? Hey, thank you.
thank you.
thank you. >> Tim Russ Ruster is the author and wisdom
>> Tim Russ Ruster is the author and wisdom
>> Tim Russ Ruster is the author and wisdom of our fathers.
of our fathers.
of our fathers. >> Oh, sounds great.
>> Oh, sounds great.
>> Oh, sounds great. >> Thank you, sir.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Thank you, sir. >> Yes, because we're talking about the
>> Yes, because we're talking about the
>> Yes, because we're talking about the wisdom of oligarchy today. Salvation of
wisdom of oligarchy today. Salvation of
wisdom of oligarchy today. Salvation of mankind is in wisdom, not in political
mankind is in wisdom, not in political
mankind is in wisdom, not in political positionality.
The first year that I was coming here,
The first year that I was coming here, everything was wonderful. Insights,
everything was wonderful. Insights,
everything was wonderful. Insights, joyous.
joyous.
joyous. >> And you've been getting worse ever
>> And you've been getting worse ever
>> And you've been getting worse ever since.
since.
since. >> Pretty much progress.
>> Pretty much progress.
>> Pretty much progress. >> How are you getting worse?
>> How are you getting worse?
>> How are you getting worse? >> Well, then I went through
>> Well, then I went through
>> Well, then I went through one issue. My whole life was just about
one issue. My whole life was just about
one issue. My whole life was just about one issue. Very intense, lots of pain,
one issue. Very intense, lots of pain,
one issue. Very intense, lots of pain, prayer, which helped. And then one day
prayer, which helped. And then one day
prayer, which helped. And then one day it just cleared. It was gone. It I felt
it just cleared. It was gone. It I felt
it just cleared. It was gone. It I felt it actually leave the intensity. So is
it actually leave the intensity. So is
it actually leave the intensity. So is that a stack? Is that
that a stack? Is that
that a stack? Is that >> as a stack?
>> as a stack?
>> as a stack? >> What?
>> What?
>> What? >> Yeah. So what we think is you know the
>> Yeah. So what we think is you know the
>> Yeah. So what we think is you know the cause of pain in this lifetime is a
cause of pain in this lifetime is a
cause of pain in this lifetime is a whole stack of the same thing. So what
whole stack of the same thing. So what
whole stack of the same thing. So what what you experience in this lifetime is
what you experience in this lifetime is
what you experience in this lifetime is the uncoring of the whole stack.
the uncoring of the whole stack.
the uncoring of the whole stack. >> Est did a good job of teaching that
>> Est did a good job of teaching that
>> Est did a good job of teaching that >> EST
>> EST
>> EST >> you know emart seminar train. Yeah.
>> you know emart seminar train. Yeah.
>> you know emart seminar train. Yeah. uh that you're pulling up a stack. In
uh that you're pulling up a stack. In
uh that you're pulling up a stack. In fact, I call them what like ones, twos,
fact, I call them what like ones, twos,
fact, I call them what like ones, twos, and threes, you know, depending on how
and threes, you know, depending on how
and threes, you know, depending on how big and bad a stack it is. Sometimes you
big and bad a stack it is. Sometimes you
big and bad a stack it is. Sometimes you you you pull up a stack and what you
you you pull up a stack and what you
you you pull up a stack and what you didn't realize is you pulled up a big
didn't realize is you pulled up a big
didn't realize is you pulled up a big stack
stack
stack >> from other lives.
>> from other lives.
>> from other lives. >> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. >> Okay. Okay. Thank you.
>> You pulled up a big stack.
>> You pulled up a big stack. >> Hello. Hi.
>> Hello. Hi.
>> Hello. Hi. >> Um, sometimes I'm picking up something
>> Um, sometimes I'm picking up something
>> Um, sometimes I'm picking up something from uh the aura of some other persons.
from uh the aura of some other persons.
from uh the aura of some other persons. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And I want to know um how to best uh
>> And I want to know um how to best uh
>> And I want to know um how to best uh protect yourself or clean it up if it
protect yourself or clean it up if it
protect yourself or clean it up if it happens and how careful you
happens and how careful you
happens and how careful you >> uh you can do theic thump. You can do
>> uh you can do theic thump. You can do
>> uh you can do theic thump. You can do prayer. Mhm.
prayer. Mhm.
prayer. Mhm. >> Uh what what I do is I if I'm not aware
>> Uh what what I do is I if I'm not aware
>> Uh what what I do is I if I'm not aware of what something is and I can't quite
of what something is and I can't quite
of what something is and I can't quite put my finger on it, I ask the Holy
put my finger on it, I ask the Holy
put my finger on it, I ask the Holy Spirit for a miracle to reveal to me the
Spirit for a miracle to reveal to me the
Spirit for a miracle to reveal to me the truth of that which I am puzzling about
truth of that which I am puzzling about
truth of that which I am puzzling about and then I leave it alone. Okay.
and then I leave it alone. Okay.
and then I leave it alone. Okay. >> And then in the middle of a peanut
>> And then in the middle of a peanut
>> And then in the middle of a peanut butter sandwich, I suddenly get out.
And how careful should you be um with
And how careful should you be um with other people's um like you said one time
other people's um like you said one time
other people's um like you said one time this lecture don't go to the new age
this lecture don't go to the new age
this lecture don't go to the new age festivals but um in general
festivals but um in general
festivals but um in general >> I mean like normal people or you know
>> I mean like normal people or you know
>> I mean like normal people or you know >> what what is he asking me
>> what what is he asking me
>> what what is he asking me >> you said don't go to the avoid avoid the
>> you said don't go to the avoid avoid the
>> you said don't go to the avoid avoid the new like new age
new like new age
new like new age >> right
>> right
>> right >> because you don't know what you're
>> because you don't know what you're
>> because you don't know what you're getting into
getting into
getting into >> right but other people have also
>> right but other people have also
>> right but other people have also negative karma you know and um how much
negative karma you know and um how much
negative karma you know and um how much you should avoid you know should you
you should avoid you know should you
you should avoid you know should you just stay in your room Yeah. How
just stay in your room Yeah. How
just stay in your room Yeah. How should you avoid it? I mean, should you
should you avoid it? I mean, should you
should you avoid it? I mean, should you just isolate yourself or what? Is that
just isolate yourself or what? Is that
just isolate yourself or what? Is that what you're saying? To isolate yourself
what you're saying? To isolate yourself
what you're saying? To isolate yourself from those I mean cuz a lot of people um
from those I mean cuz a lot of people um
from those I mean cuz a lot of people um >> like even normal normal people, you
>> like even normal normal people, you
>> like even normal normal people, you know, have something
know, have something
know, have something >> have something even normal people have
>> have something even normal people have
>> have something even normal people have something.
something.
something. >> So what is the question?
>> So what is the question?
>> So what is the question? >> How do you protect yourself
>> How do you protect yourself
>> How do you protect yourself >> from what? Other people's negative
>> from what? Other people's negative
>> from what? Other people's negative energies.
energies.
energies. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Oh, because you cleared that in yourself
>> Oh, because you cleared that in yourself
>> Oh, because you cleared that in yourself and transcended it. uh it's no longer so
and transcended it. uh it's no longer so
and transcended it. uh it's no longer so you got to have a hook that they can put
you got to have a hook that they can put
you got to have a hook that they can put it in. So once you've cleared that out
it in. So once you've cleared that out
it in. So once you've cleared that out then there that hook doesn't remain
then there that hook doesn't remain
then there that hook doesn't remain anymore.
anymore.
anymore. >> So I treat it just as myself as my issue
>> So I treat it just as myself as my issue
>> So I treat it just as myself as my issue and
and
and that's it.
>> You can clear the energy quickly by the
>> You can clear the energy quickly by the time right but you still don't know what
time right but you still don't know what
time right but you still don't know what it is. So you can use kinesiology to
it is. So you can use kinesiology to
it is. So you can use kinesiology to find out what it is. You can use
find out what it is. You can use
find out what it is. You can use intuition. You can ask the Holy Spirit
intuition. You can ask the Holy Spirit
intuition. You can ask the Holy Spirit for a miracle that it be revealed to
for a miracle that it be revealed to
for a miracle that it be revealed to you.
you.
you. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yep.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. >> Thank you very much.
>> Hi, Dr. Hopkins.
>> Hi, Dr. Hopkins. >> Hello, Susan.
>> Hello, Susan.
>> Hello, Susan. I wanted to ask what
I wanted to ask what
I wanted to ask what the the nervousness what comes up when
the the nervousness what comes up when
the the nervousness what comes up when you look into somebody's eyes because
you look into somebody's eyes because
you look into somebody's eyes because there's very few people I can look into
there's very few people I can look into
there's very few people I can look into their eyes except for you
their eyes except for you
their eyes except for you >> you know
>> you know
>> you know >> what comes up in people's eyes
>> what comes up in people's eyes
>> what comes up in people's eyes >> yes
>> yes
>> yes >> is that a real strong connection
>> is that a real strong connection
>> is that a real strong connection >> well what comes up is the self reflected
>> well what comes up is the self reflected
>> well what comes up is the self reflected back to you
back to you
back to you >> okay
>> okay
>> okay >> see when I was in psychiatric practice I
>> see when I was in psychiatric practice I
>> see when I was in psychiatric practice I wrote about they would bring in the most
wrote about they would bring in the most
wrote about they would bring in the most pathetic things from all over the world
pathetic things from all over the world
pathetic things from all over the world wrapped in wet sheets writhing on the
wrapped in wet sheets writhing on the
wrapped in wet sheets writhing on the floor grotesque
floor grotesque
floor grotesque hopeless and I would look into their
hopeless and I would look into their
hopeless and I would look into their eyes and
eyes and
eyes and they felt healed in that instant. Yeah.
they felt healed in that instant. Yeah.
they felt healed in that instant. Yeah. Sometimes sometimes the physicality did
Sometimes sometimes the physicality did
Sometimes sometimes the physicality did not socially recover but the person
not socially recover but the person
not socially recover but the person within was recovered because who they
within was recovered because who they
within was recovered because who they really were had been recognized and
really were had been recognized and
really were had been recognized and reciprocated. And that was you know the
reciprocated. And that was you know the
reciprocated. And that was you know the moment of the m the miracle. So many of
moment of the m the miracle. So many of
moment of the m the miracle. So many of the recoveries were miraculous.
the recoveries were miraculous.
the recoveries were miraculous. It's because the self sees the self that
It's because the self sees the self that
It's because the self sees the self that self recognizes the self and um that was
self recognizes the self and um that was
self recognizes the self and um that was the relief of the suffering.
the relief of the suffering.
the relief of the suffering. My only mission was that their suffering
My only mission was that their suffering
My only mission was that their suffering be relieved. You see there soioeconomic
be relieved. You see there soioeconomic
be relieved. You see there soioeconomic recovery was not my problem. That's the
recovery was not my problem. That's the
recovery was not my problem. That's the families.
families.
families. >> Yeah. Thank you.
Happy birthday.
Happy birthday. >> Hey.
>> Hey.
>> Hey. >> I've been having a little bit of
>> I've been having a little bit of
>> I've been having a little bit of troubles juggling the paradox of not
troubles juggling the paradox of not
troubles juggling the paradox of not doing and being completely surrendered
doing and being completely surrendered
doing and being completely surrendered and then not doing enough to be a
and then not doing enough to be a
and then not doing enough to be a diligent follower of the truth.
diligent follower of the truth.
diligent follower of the truth. So, I was wondering if maybe you could
So, I was wondering if maybe you could
So, I was wondering if maybe you could help me clear it up.
help me clear it up.
help me clear it up. Doing this is not a a block.
Doing this is not a a block.
Doing this is not a a block. Doing this has to do with what your mind
Doing this has to do with what your mind
Doing this has to do with what your mind is doing while you're doing this.
If you're doing it from context, it's
If you're doing it from context, it's not going to interfere. If you're doing
not going to interfere. If you're doing
not going to interfere. If you're doing it from content, it's going to be a
it from content, it's going to be a
it from content, it's going to be a constant interruption.
Uh,
Uh, >> I'm going have to sit and chew on that
>> I'm going have to sit and chew on that
>> I'm going have to sit and chew on that for a second.
If you if you're just being who you are,
If you if you're just being who you are, then everything is happening
then everything is happening
then everything is happening spontaneously. It's not interrupting
spontaneously. It's not interrupting
spontaneously. It's not interrupting anything.
anything.
anything. >> If you're trying to do something outside
>> If you're trying to do something outside
>> If you're trying to do something outside of the, you know, that which you really
of the, you know, that which you really
of the, you know, that which you really are, something artificial,
are, something artificial,
are, something artificial, uh, that's going to interrupt you. See?
uh, that's going to interrupt you. See?
uh, that's going to interrupt you. See? >> Okay. I see what you're saying.
>> Okay. I see what you're saying.
>> Okay. I see what you're saying. >> If beheading people all the time is your
>> If beheading people all the time is your
>> If beheading people all the time is your job, as the beheadsman, then chopping
job, as the beheadsman, then chopping
job, as the beheadsman, then chopping off a head doesn't bother you. You see,
off a head doesn't bother you. You see,
off a head doesn't bother you. You see, cuz you're just a routine day for you,
cuz you're just a routine day for you,
cuz you're just a routine day for you, you know?
>> I said experience few shackles will.
>> I said experience few shackles will. >> How do you do it?
>> How do you do it?
>> How do you do it? >> Thank you, doctor.
>> Thank you, doctor.
>> Thank you, doctor. >> You bet.
>> You bet.
>> You bet. >> Thank you, Susan.
>> Always tip the head.
>> Always tip the head. >> Oh, yeah.
>> It's just his job, you know. I tell
>> It's just his job, you know. I tell them, "Don't feel guilty for God's sake.
them, "Don't feel guilty for God's sake.
them, "Don't feel guilty for God's sake. It's just your job." You know,
>> how can one
>> how can one be kind and compassionate and loving and
be kind and compassionate and loving and
be kind and compassionate and loving and yet at the same time not karmically
yet at the same time not karmically
yet at the same time not karmically interfere in other people and other
interfere in other people and other
interfere in other people and other lives?
lives?
lives? >> Good one.
>> Good one.
>> Good one. >> Oh, good.
>> Oh, good.
>> Oh, good. >> How can you be loving and caring and not
>> How can you be loving and caring and not
>> How can you be loving and caring and not interfere with someone else's karma
interfere with someone else's karma
interfere with someone else's karma karma?
karma?
karma? >> How does being loving interfere with
>> How does being loving interfere with
>> How does being loving interfere with their karma? Well, maybe you intervene
their karma? Well, maybe you intervene
their karma? Well, maybe you intervene too much and you changed.
too much and you changed.
too much and you changed. >> Let's say a ch uh you protective. You're
>> Let's say a ch uh you protective. You're
>> Let's say a ch uh you protective. You're talking about being overprotective.
talking about being overprotective.
talking about being overprotective. >> If a child is being beaten and and
>> If a child is being beaten and and
>> If a child is being beaten and and you're there,
you're there,
you're there, >> yeah,
>> yeah,
>> yeah, >> uh you automatically
>> uh you automatically
>> uh you automatically >> want to interfere and
>> want to interfere and
>> want to interfere and >> you automatically respond as
>> you automatically respond as
>> you automatically respond as >> based on your level of consciousness.
>> based on your level of consciousness.
>> based on your level of consciousness. >> You might say from a certain level it's
>> You might say from a certain level it's
>> You might say from a certain level it's not even happening. This is just a
not even happening. This is just a
not even happening. This is just a perceptual illusion, right?
perceptual illusion, right?
perceptual illusion, right? >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You might say karmically this kid
>> You might say karmically this kid
>> You might say karmically this kid deserves it. You know you might say it
deserves it. You know you might say it
deserves it. You know you might say it is not my place to intervene in God's
is not my place to intervene in God's
is not my place to intervene in God's world or you may feel called upon
world or you may feel called upon
world or you may feel called upon uh to intervene in the child's behalf.
uh to intervene in the child's behalf.
uh to intervene in the child's behalf. So it would depend on how you define
So it would depend on how you define
So it would depend on how you define your yourself see yourself in this world
your yourself see yourself in this world
your yourself see yourself in this world and what your function is. See,
and what your function is. See,
and what your function is. See, >> okay.
>> okay.
>> okay. >> My function has always been, you know,
>> My function has always been, you know,
>> My function has always been, you know, therapeutic. You know, as a child, I
therapeutic. You know, as a child, I
therapeutic. You know, as a child, I want to relieve the suffering of a
want to relieve the suffering of a
want to relieve the suffering of a puppy. As a doctor, I want to relieve
puppy. As a doctor, I want to relieve
puppy. As a doctor, I want to relieve suffering. And as a spiritual teacher, I
suffering. And as a spiritual teacher, I
suffering. And as a spiritual teacher, I want to prevent and relieve spiritual
want to prevent and relieve spiritual
want to prevent and relieve spiritual suffering. So, that's always been my
suffering. So, that's always been my
suffering. So, that's always been my orientation. See,
orientation. See,
orientation. See, >> yes, sir.
>> yes, sir.
>> yes, sir. >> That out of that which you are, that
>> That out of that which you are, that
>> That out of that which you are, that which you value, you behave out of that
which you value, you behave out of that
which you value, you behave out of that which you value. And uh I think the
which you value. And uh I think the
which you value. And uh I think the relief of suffering is uh you know what
relief of suffering is uh you know what
relief of suffering is uh you know what I do. That's what I've always done, you
I do. That's what I've always done, you
I do. That's what I've always done, you know.
know.
know. >> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much. >> What do you call them to take care of
>> What do you call them to take care of
>> What do you call them to take care of animals?
animals?
animals? >> What do you call them?
>> What do you call them?
>> What do you call them? >> Veterinarian.
>> Veterinarian.
>> Veterinarian. >> Yeah, vet. It' be the same as a
>> Yeah, vet. It' be the same as a
>> Yeah, vet. It' be the same as a veterinarian. You know, I could equally
veterinarian. You know, I could equally
veterinarian. You know, I could equally be a veterinarian. And because the
be a veterinarian. And because the
be a veterinarian. And because the relief of suffering brings a sense of
relief of suffering brings a sense of
relief of suffering brings a sense of fulfillment with me, whether it's a
fulfillment with me, whether it's a
fulfillment with me, whether it's a puppy, a kitten, human being, or a poor
puppy, a kitten, human being, or a poor
puppy, a kitten, human being, or a poor old lady sitting by herself, you know.
old lady sitting by herself, you know.
old lady sitting by herself, you know. >> Okay. Thank you so much.
My question has been answered but thank
My question has been answered but thank you for being my teacher.
you for being my teacher.
you for being my teacher. >> Thank you for the gift of being my
>> Thank you for the gift of being my
>> Thank you for the gift of being my student. Every student is a
student. Every student is a
student. Every student is a >> thank you
>> thank you
>> thank you >> is a blessing.
>> is a blessing.
>> is a blessing. >> How do I do this here?
>> How do I do this here?
>> How do I do this here? >> Just
>> Just
>> Just >> here.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I was hoping you could help me with a
I was hoping you could help me with a
I was hoping you could help me with a continuous dream that I keep having.
continuous dream that I keep having.
continuous dream that I keep having. >> Dream?
>> Dream?
>> Dream? >> Yeah. Is that all right? I have this
>> Yeah. Is that all right? I have this
>> Yeah. Is that all right? I have this >> Maybe
>> Maybe
>> Maybe >> I have this dream where I'm chewing gum
>> I have this dream where I'm chewing gum
>> I have this dream where I'm chewing gum and I go to spit it out and I can't. So,
and I go to spit it out and I can't. So,
and I go to spit it out and I can't. So, I use my hand and I keep on pulling and
I use my hand and I keep on pulling and
I use my hand and I keep on pulling and pulling and pulling and then
pulling and pulling and then
pulling and pulling and then >> it will finally snap, but there's still
>> it will finally snap, but there's still
>> it will finally snap, but there's still some in my mouth and I just keep pulling
some in my mouth and I just keep pulling
some in my mouth and I just keep pulling and pulling. It's kind of a nightmare
and pulling. It's kind of a nightmare
and pulling. It's kind of a nightmare for me. Yeah, it's a weird dream. Yeah.
>> Give up bubble gum.
>> Give up bubble gum. >> I have.
>> I have.
>> I have. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I don't know what it means.
I don't know what it means.
I don't know what it means. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> See in psychoanalysis you lay on the
>> See in psychoanalysis you lay on the
>> See in psychoanalysis you lay on the couch both of us would ignore this and
couch both of us would ignore this and
couch both of us would ignore this and you know maybe tomorrow the next day
you know maybe tomorrow the next day
you know maybe tomorrow the next day suddenly come to you what it means or I
suddenly come to you what it means or I
suddenly come to you what it means or I would get it. Say it's really a
would get it. Say it's really a
would get it. Say it's really a psychoanalytic question because what do
psychoanalytic question because what do
psychoanalytic question because what do all these things symbolize? I don't
all these things symbolize? I don't
all these things symbolize? I don't know.
know.
know. You'd have to be in s, you know, an
You'd have to be in s, you know, an
You'd have to be in s, you know, an analysis of me and then the two of us
analysis of me and then the two of us
analysis of me and then the two of us would come on what it probably means,
would come on what it probably means,
would come on what it probably means, you know.
you know.
you know. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Something sticky, something oral. Uh,
>> Something sticky, something oral. Uh,
>> Something sticky, something oral. Uh, I'm stuck with my orality.
I'm stuck with my orality.
I'm stuck with my orality. Uh, you know, what is the symbolic
Uh, you know, what is the symbolic
Uh, you know, what is the symbolic language? Dreams are always symbolic.
language? Dreams are always symbolic.
language? Dreams are always symbolic. >> The gums lost its flavor, so I keep on
>> The gums lost its flavor, so I keep on
>> The gums lost its flavor, so I keep on I'm trying to spit it out. I don't know
I'm trying to spit it out. I don't know
I'm trying to spit it out. I don't know if that makes any difference.
if that makes any difference.
if that makes any difference. >> Yeah, that's interesting. You've
>> Yeah, that's interesting. You've
>> Yeah, that's interesting. You've depleted it.
depleted it.
depleted it. Now, it's time to stick it under the
Now, it's time to stick it under the
Now, it's time to stick it under the seat, right, for the next one.
seat, right, for the next one.
seat, right, for the next one. Can I ask one more question since I
Can I ask one more question since I
Can I ask one more question since I didn't really get an answer on that one?
didn't really get an answer on that one?
didn't really get an answer on that one? >> I'm going to ask another question, but
>> I'm going to ask another question, but
>> I'm going to ask another question, but you didn't want to know.
you didn't want to know.
you didn't want to know. >> Is that all right?
>> Is that all right?
>> Is that all right? >> Um,
>> Um,
>> Um, >> I gave you a response. I didn't say I
>> I gave you a response. I didn't say I
>> I gave you a response. I didn't say I was going to answer.
was going to answer.
was going to answer. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Also, I'd like to, you know, remind
>> Also, I'd like to, you know, remind
>> Also, I'd like to, you know, remind people.
people.
people. >> Okay. I was wondering if
>> Okay. I was wondering if
>> Okay. I was wondering if >> I give you what I know, but I'm not I
>> I give you what I know, but I'm not I
>> I give you what I know, but I'm not I don't claim omission. Seriously.
don't claim omission. Seriously.
don't claim omission. Seriously. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Once in a while, people hit me for being
>> Once in a while, people hit me for being
>> Once in a while, people hit me for being not omnicient.
not omnicient.
not omnicient. I don't claim ambitions any more than I
I don't claim ambitions any more than I
I don't claim ambitions any more than I complain omnipresence
complain omnipresence
complain omnipresence >> or omnipotence.
>> or omnipotence.
>> or omnipotence. >> Um I was wondering if you could help me
>> Um I was wondering if you could help me
>> Um I was wondering if you could help me with m uh mudras if you could show me a
with m uh mudras if you could show me a
with m uh mudras if you could show me a couple different mudras and what they
couple different mudras and what they
couple different mudras and what they mean and when to use them.
mean and when to use them.
mean and when to use them. >> Uh I don't know that it's something I
>> Uh I don't know that it's something I
>> Uh I don't know that it's something I necessarily consciously use. Uh mudra
necessarily consciously use. Uh mudra
necessarily consciously use. Uh mudra has a h position each you might say it's
has a h position each you might say it's
has a h position each you might say it's symbolic languaging.
symbolic languaging.
symbolic languaging. uh when I say live your life as a prayer
uh when I say live your life as a prayer
uh when I say live your life as a prayer uh I mean that your configuration the
uh I mean that your configuration the
uh I mean that your configuration the way you relate to God is more or less
way you relate to God is more or less
way you relate to God is more or less thusly
thusly
thusly it's very yin so the yin position you
it's very yin so the yin position you
it's very yin so the yin position you see in the three-dimensional world you
see in the three-dimensional world you
see in the three-dimensional world you have to be very yang and in the
have to be very yang and in the
have to be very yang and in the spiritual world it's like yin you you
spiritual world it's like yin you you
spiritual world it's like yin you you pull by attraction
pull by attraction
pull by attraction so if I live my life as this position to
so if I live my life as this position to
so if I live my life as this position to God. How can he refuse me?
God. How can he refuse me?
God. How can he refuse me? Okay.
Okay.
Okay. Your life is a supplication. To thee, oh
Your life is a supplication. To thee, oh
Your life is a supplication. To thee, oh Lord, do I devote my life.
Lord, do I devote my life.
Lord, do I devote my life. Yeah. And has to be a channel of thy
Yeah. And has to be a channel of thy
Yeah. And has to be a channel of thy will.
will.
will. Uh so that is a powerful yin attraction.
Uh so that is a powerful yin attraction.
Uh so that is a powerful yin attraction. You might say the great beings flock to
You might say the great beings flock to
You might say the great beings flock to your side because they see,
your side because they see,
your side because they see, you know, to thee, oh Lord, do I devote
you know, to thee, oh Lord, do I devote
you know, to thee, oh Lord, do I devote my life. that I that I may be thy
my life. that I that I may be thy
my life. that I that I may be thy servant. Amen.
servant. Amen.
servant. Amen. >> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Okay. Thank you very much. >> It's a very powerful prayer. You see the
>> It's a very powerful prayer. You see the
>> It's a very powerful prayer. You see the very powerful yen pull of it.
very powerful yen pull of it.
very powerful yen pull of it. >> Okay. Thank you very much. Happy
>> Okay. Thank you very much. Happy
>> Okay. Thank you very much. Happy birthday. Can I get a picture real
birthday. Can I get a picture real
birthday. Can I get a picture real quick?
>> Pretend like you like me.
>> Pretend like you like me. >> Oh.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. >> Oh, picture.
Yeah. My pleasure.
Yeah. My pleasure. so much,
so much,
so much, >> Dr. Hawkins. I'm glad you brought up the
>> Dr. Hawkins. I'm glad you brought up the
>> Dr. Hawkins. I'm glad you brought up the list of spiritual myths right at the
list of spiritual myths right at the
list of spiritual myths right at the beginning. I've read some of those books
beginning. I've read some of those books
beginning. I've read some of those books myself. And in the last two weeks, I ran
myself. And in the last two weeks, I ran
myself. And in the last two weeks, I ran into one other book. It's called The
into one other book. It's called The
into one other book. It's called The Impersonal Life by Joseph Benner. And I
Impersonal Life by Joseph Benner. And I
Impersonal Life by Joseph Benner. And I don't know if you've heard of this work.
don't know if you've heard of this work.
don't know if you've heard of this work. It was written a long time ago in 1944
It was written a long time ago in 1944
It was written a long time ago in 1944 or something.
or something.
or something. >> Who wrote it?
>> Who wrote it?
>> Who wrote it? >> Joseph Benner.
>> Joseph Benner.
>> Joseph Benner. >> Benner.
>> Benner.
>> Benner. >> I'm not familiar with the book. Okay.
>> I'm not familiar with the book. Okay.
>> I'm not familiar with the book. Okay. Um the other thing is um I'm a doctor
Um the other thing is um I'm a doctor
Um the other thing is um I'm a doctor and I've been listening to your
and I've been listening to your
and I've been listening to your lectures, the health and healing series
lectures, the health and healing series
lectures, the health and healing series and so what advice would you give me in
and so what advice would you give me in
and so what advice would you give me in my clinic? I'm trying to bring some of
my clinic? I'm trying to bring some of
my clinic? I'm trying to bring some of those principles for my patients. Um and
those principles for my patients. Um and
those principles for my patients. Um and it doesn't seem in context in in where I
it doesn't seem in context in in where I
it doesn't seem in context in in where I am looking at data and talking about
am looking at data and talking about
am looking at data and talking about results and so on. And yet a part of me
results and so on. And yet a part of me
results and so on. And yet a part of me in some situations wants to bring that
in some situations wants to bring that
in some situations wants to bring that into their awareness that they need to
into their awareness that they need to
into their awareness that they need to have inquiry as to why they're sick. So
have inquiry as to why they're sick. So
have inquiry as to why they're sick. So how can I bring your principles in my
how can I bring your principles in my
how can I bring your principles in my practice? What advice would you give?
practice? What advice would you give?
practice? What advice would you give? >> What I did was I started a attitudinal
>> What I did was I started a attitudinal
>> What I did was I started a attitudinal healing center in the clinic of which I
healing center in the clinic of which I
healing center in the clinic of which I was director.
was director.
was director. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Uh so at no charge people with hopeless
>> Uh so at no charge people with hopeless
>> Uh so at no charge people with hopeless diseases could get together and study
diseases could get together and study
diseases could get together and study the course of miracles. So that created
the course of miracles. So that created
the course of miracles. So that created a spiritual context for healing. See,
a spiritual context for healing. See,
a spiritual context for healing. See, and gave them a whole new different idea
and gave them a whole new different idea
and gave them a whole new different idea on how they could approach it. See,
on how they could approach it. See,
on how they could approach it. See, >> I'm passing up the course in miracles in
>> I'm passing up the course in miracles in
>> I'm passing up the course in miracles in my clinic. I've been th I've not been
my clinic. I've been th I've not been
my clinic. I've been th I've not been thrown out of my work yet.
thrown out of my work yet.
thrown out of my work yet. >> No, I do I do tell my patients about a
>> No, I do I do tell my patients about a
>> No, I do I do tell my patients about a course in miracles and many
course in miracles and many
course in miracles and many but actually supporting it.
but actually supporting it.
but actually supporting it. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> See, because you'll say, "Yeah, uh-huh."
>> See, because you'll say, "Yeah, uh-huh."
>> See, because you'll say, "Yeah, uh-huh." And they won't do it. But if they get
And they won't do it. But if they get
And they won't do it. But if they get together one evening a week, pretty soon
together one evening a week, pretty soon
together one evening a week, pretty soon they form a camaraderie,
they form a camaraderie,
they form a camaraderie, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> And then they begin to see the change in
>> And then they begin to see the change in
>> And then they begin to see the change in each other,
each other,
each other, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> And then the miraculous begins to occur.
>> And then the miraculous begins to occur.
>> And then the miraculous begins to occur. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> What do I do with this?
>> What do I do with this?
>> What do I do with this? >> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. >> Sign here.
>> Sign here.
>> Sign here. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Thank you, Susan.
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> Thank you, Susan. >> Oh, thank you.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Oh, thank you. >> Okay. Yes.
>> Okay. Yes.
>> Okay. Yes. >> Sign here.
>> That's science of mind. I forgot I was
>> That's science of mind. I forgot I was even in science of mind.
even in science of mind.
even in science of mind. Oh, yes.
Oh, yes.
Oh, yes. Yes. What?
Yes. What?
Yes. What? >> Um, Dr. Hawkins, we're very grateful for
>> Um, Dr. Hawkins, we're very grateful for
>> Um, Dr. Hawkins, we're very grateful for your teaching. And when we were here
your teaching. And when we were here
your teaching. And when we were here last time, you said a number of things
last time, you said a number of things
last time, you said a number of things that inspired us to put together a bag
that inspired us to put together a bag
that inspired us to put together a bag of gifts of various kinds for you and
of gifts of various kinds for you and
of gifts of various kinds for you and and Susan. And there's a a letter in
and Susan. And there's a a letter in
and Susan. And there's a a letter in there which explains the different gifts
there which explains the different gifts
there which explains the different gifts and and how they might be used depending
and and how they might be used depending
and and how they might be used depending on how kinesiology indicates they might
on how kinesiology indicates they might
on how kinesiology indicates they might or might not be useful for you. Thank
or might not be useful for you. Thank
or might not be useful for you. Thank you.
>> And our birthday wish for you is that
>> And our birthday wish for you is that whatever time you have with us in in in
whatever time you have with us in in in
whatever time you have with us in in in service that it be filled with joy and
service that it be filled with joy and
service that it be filled with joy and health and strength.
health and strength.
health and strength. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> I'm sure everyone in the room shares us.
>> I had a question um about people who are
>> I had a question um about people who are up, you know, we've calibrated someone
up, you know, we've calibrated someone
up, you know, we've calibrated someone like Mother Teresa at 700 or above.
like Mother Teresa at 700 or above.
like Mother Teresa at 700 or above. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> And she was very very against um
>> And she was very very against um
>> And she was very very against um abortion
abortion
abortion >> and preached quite She was a Catholic.
>> and preached quite She was a Catholic.
>> and preached quite She was a Catholic. >> Adamantly she was a Catholic.
>> Adamantly she was a Catholic.
>> Adamantly she was a Catholic. >> Um Yes, I know.
>> The one time I went to hear her speak,
>> The one time I went to hear her speak, she just talked about well how horrible
she just talked about well how horrible
she just talked about well how horrible it was that people had abortions.
it was that people had abortions.
it was that people had abortions. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> And then in your book, you've also said
>> And then in your book, you've also said
>> And then in your book, you've also said that until the third month
that until the third month
that until the third month >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> the fetus.
>> the fetus.
>> the fetus. >> Well, that's the facts,
>> Well, that's the facts,
>> Well, that's the facts, >> right? That's the facts. So I guess I
>> right? That's the facts. So I guess I
>> right? That's the facts. So I guess I get confused and you were talking today
get confused and you were talking today
get confused and you were talking today about who do we know how to trust
about who do we know how to trust
about who do we know how to trust >> is that I admire Mother Teresa a whole
>> is that I admire Mother Teresa a whole
>> is that I admire Mother Teresa a whole lot
lot
lot >> and then admiring her and knowing she's
>> and then admiring her and knowing she's
>> and then admiring her and knowing she's a 700 then do I automatically say she
a 700 then do I automatically say she
a 700 then do I automatically say she must be right about abortion and you
must be right about abortion and you
must be right about abortion and you know we should never have abortions. Do
know we should never have abortions. Do
know we should never have abortions. Do you see the question? I get very
you see the question? I get very
you see the question? I get very confused about
confused about
confused about >> well because you have your own
>> well because you have your own
>> well because you have your own individual spiritual path to evolve
individual spiritual path to evolve
individual spiritual path to evolve through. You see, uh, we we give you the
through. You see, uh, we we give you the
through. You see, uh, we we give you the facts and now what you do with them
facts and now what you do with them
facts and now what you do with them depends on where you're at. See, you may
depends on where you're at. See, you may
depends on where you're at. See, you may be willing to sacrifice the benefits of
be willing to sacrifice the benefits of
be willing to sacrifice the benefits of abortion
abortion
abortion uh in return for
uh in return for
uh in return for uh the positive karma of having chosen
uh the positive karma of having chosen
uh the positive karma of having chosen what you consider to be the spiritually
what you consider to be the spiritually
what you consider to be the spiritually higher track kind of thing.
higher track kind of thing.
higher track kind of thing. >> So, it may not be the abortion itself,
>> So, it may not be the abortion itself,
>> So, it may not be the abortion itself, but the intention by which you make the
but the intention by which you make the
but the intention by which you make the decision. I merely pointed out the facts
decision. I merely pointed out the facts
decision. I merely pointed out the facts that the spirit doesn't enter the fetus
that the spirit doesn't enter the fetus
that the spirit doesn't enter the fetus until the third month of gestation. So
until the third month of gestation. So
until the third month of gestation. So that people who have had abortions maybe
that people who have had abortions maybe
that people who have had abortions maybe wouldn't feel quite as guilty.
wouldn't feel quite as guilty.
wouldn't feel quite as guilty. >> It didn't really kill a spirit, you
>> It didn't really kill a spirit, you
>> It didn't really kill a spirit, you know?
know?
know? >> Right.
>> Right.
>> Right. >> Yeah. Okay. So, I just thought it might
>> Yeah. Okay. So, I just thought it might
>> Yeah. Okay. So, I just thought it might help clarify because I don't have any
help clarify because I don't have any
help clarify because I don't have any position about it. You see, as a
position about it. You see, as a
position about it. You see, as a physician, I myself cannot do it. You
physician, I myself cannot do it. You
physician, I myself cannot do it. You see, but that's just my own as a
see, but that's just my own as a
see, but that's just my own as a position.
position.
position. >> How is that different than relativism
>> How is that different than relativism
>> How is that different than relativism then? Oh, relativism is a whole
then? Oh, relativism is a whole
then? Oh, relativism is a whole different ball game.
different ball game.
different ball game. >> A ball game.
>> A ball game.
>> A ball game. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> So, oh,
>> So, oh,
>> So, oh, >> well, you see, from relativism, you
>> well, you see, from relativism, you
>> well, you see, from relativism, you wouldn't have any problem because from
wouldn't have any problem because from
wouldn't have any problem because from relativism, there is no right and wrong.
relativism, there is no right and wrong.
relativism, there is no right and wrong. Everybody is the author of their own
Everybody is the author of their own
Everybody is the author of their own moral code and they have no obligation
moral code and they have no obligation
moral code and they have no obligation to agree with truth or falsehood. So, a
to agree with truth or falsehood. So, a
to agree with truth or falsehood. So, a relativist wouldn't be worrying about
relativist wouldn't be worrying about
relativist wouldn't be worrying about the question.
>> Okay. And then someone might have a
>> Okay. And then someone might have a different position. safe from you or
different position. safe from you or
different position. safe from you or from Mother Teresa and it not isn't
from Mother Teresa and it not isn't
from Mother Teresa and it not isn't necessarily the wrong one if they're on
necessarily the wrong one if they're on
necessarily the wrong one if they're on their own spiritual path.
their own spiritual path.
their own spiritual path. >> It's their it's their choice. You know,
>> It's their it's their choice. You know,
>> It's their it's their choice. You know, the only the only rule we have right now
the only the only rule we have right now
the only the only rule we have right now is if we calibrate them.
is if we calibrate them.
is if we calibrate them. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> Let's say we calibrate this person has
>> Let's say we calibrate this person has
>> Let's say we calibrate this person has an abortion at this time. What does that
an abortion at this time. What does that
an abortion at this time. What does that calibrate at? Then we say, what does it
calibrate at? Then we say, what does it
calibrate at? Then we say, what does it calibrate uh to reject an abortion from
calibrate uh to reject an abortion from
calibrate uh to reject an abortion from spiritual principles? And now it's up to
spiritual principles? And now it's up to
spiritual principles? And now it's up to you to choose.
you to choose.
you to choose. >> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> Oh, and by the way, I'm it's not because
>> Oh, and by the way, I'm it's not because
>> Oh, and by the way, I'm it's not because I'm thinking of having an abortion. No,
I'm thinking of having an abortion. No,
I'm thinking of having an abortion. No, but you're
but you're
but you're >> that just occurred.
>> that just occurred.
>> that just occurred. >> Not either, but you're having a you're
>> Not either, but you're having a you're
>> Not either, but you're having a you're presenting me with a hypothetical
presenting me with a hypothetical
presenting me with a hypothetical position. How do you resolve it?
position. How do you resolve it?
position. How do you resolve it? >> You try to extract the essence of all of
>> You try to extract the essence of all of
>> You try to extract the essence of all of it. And then from that, depending on
it. And then from that, depending on
it. And then from that, depending on where you are, you will make your
where you are, you will make your
where you are, you will make your choice.
choice.
choice. >> So, so then when you are adopting to
>> So, so then when you are adopting to
>> So, so then when you are adopting to follow someone and have them be your
follow someone and have them be your
follow someone and have them be your teacher, you might not agree with them
teacher, you might not agree with them
teacher, you might not agree with them on everything with everything. Nope.
on everything with everything. Nope.
on everything with everything. Nope. >> Okay. Thank you.
Then you should feel guilty. Of course,
Then you should feel guilty. Of course, don't forget to feel guilty about it.
don't forget to feel guilty about it.
don't forget to feel guilty about it. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Just had to say that.
>> Just had to say that.
>> Just had to say that. >> Well, just you get to the other side and
>> Well, just you get to the other side and
>> Well, just you get to the other side and Mother Teresa greets you and
you discover she's your angel on the
you discover she's your angel on the other side. Sorry, mother.
other side. Sorry, mother.
other side. Sorry, mother. >> Hi, Sus.
>> Hi, Sus.
>> Hi, Sus. >> We do a lot of things we do not out of
>> We do a lot of things we do not out of
>> We do a lot of things we do not out of rationality, but out of love. you. So
rationality, but out of love. you. So
rationality, but out of love. you. So you might forego a convenience out of
you might forego a convenience out of
you might forego a convenience out of love for Mother Teresa, out of love.
love for Mother Teresa, out of love.
love for Mother Teresa, out of love. See, so there your motivation would be
See, so there your motivation would be
See, so there your motivation would be out of my love for this teacher, I will
out of my love for this teacher, I will
out of my love for this teacher, I will follow this teacher's teachings, you
follow this teacher's teachings, you
follow this teacher's teachings, you know, out of love, not out of fear of
know, out of love, not out of fear of
know, out of love, not out of fear of mistake, not out of
mistake, not out of
mistake, not out of >> Can you just read my mind and tell me
>> Can you just read my mind and tell me
>> Can you just read my mind and tell me what my question is?
what my question is?
what my question is? >> Go ahead.
>> Go ahead.
>> Go ahead. >> Okay. Sorry. Um well I was wondering I
>> Okay. Sorry. Um well I was wondering I
>> Okay. Sorry. Um well I was wondering I um I was listening to the lecture today
um I was listening to the lecture today
um I was listening to the lecture today and I had heard you say that for the
and I had heard you say that for the
and I had heard you say that for the pedophilers and things like that there's
pedophilers and things like that there's
pedophilers and things like that there's I'm an alcoholic and I go to the AA and
I'm an alcoholic and I go to the AA and
I'm an alcoholic and I go to the AA and um I see that there's been great help
um I see that there's been great help
um I see that there's been great help but I know the statistics is very low as
but I know the statistics is very low as
but I know the statistics is very low as far as recovery is concerned but you
far as recovery is concerned but you
far as recovery is concerned but you said there was no hope you know for
said there was no hope you know for
said there was no hope you know for those people and I'm just wondering
those people and I'm just wondering
those people and I'm just wondering because I want
because I want
because I want >> no hope for what people
>> no hope for what people
>> no hope for what people >> for like the pet no the pedophilers.
>> for like the pet no the pedophilers.
>> for like the pet no the pedophilers. What's it got to do with a
What's it got to do with a
What's it got to do with a >> Well, because I think that everybody has
>> Well, because I think that everybody has
>> Well, because I think that everybody has a chance and
a chance and
a chance and >> Oh, you you're coming from the
>> Oh, you you're coming from the
>> Oh, you you're coming from the hypothetical idealism.
hypothetical idealism.
hypothetical idealism. >> Well, in in
>> I have to use a dictionary to read some
>> I have to use a dictionary to read some of your books. So, can you
of your books. So, can you
of your books. So, can you >> I'm I'm new at this. This is my first
>> I'm I'm new at this. This is my first
>> I'm I'm new at this. This is my first conference here and um but I mean what I
conference here and um but I mean what I
conference here and um but I mean what I >> I'm just giving you a clinical
>> I'm just giving you a clinical
>> I'm just giving you a clinical experience. Okay. Clinical. That's the
experience. Okay. Clinical. That's the
experience. Okay. Clinical. That's the experience. The only cases I ever saw
experience. The only cases I ever saw
experience. The only cases I ever saw recover from it were people who joined a
recover from it were people who joined a
recover from it were people who joined a 12step group and they were avid members.
12step group and they were avid members.
12step group and they were avid members. And those few guys did recover at least
And those few guys did recover at least
And those few guys did recover at least for the period of time that I continued
for the period of time that I continued
for the period of time that I continued to see them.
to see them.
to see them. >> And there's other groups for people that
>> And there's other groups for people that
>> And there's other groups for people that just aren't alcoholic or drug addicts. I
just aren't alcoholic or drug addicts. I
just aren't alcoholic or drug addicts. I mean, there's other I know there's like
mean, there's other I know there's like
mean, there's other I know there's like fat people groups and um
fat people groups and um
fat people groups and um overeaters anonymous, gambling recovery
overeaters anonymous, gambling recovery
overeaters anonymous, gambling recovery from pedophilia. The only ones I saw had
from pedophilia. The only ones I saw had
from pedophilia. The only ones I saw had joined AA groups and practiced the
joined AA groups and practiced the
joined AA groups and practiced the principles of all their phrases.
principles of all their phrases.
principles of all their phrases. >> Well, I guess what I'm getting at is
>> Well, I guess what I'm getting at is
>> Well, I guess what I'm getting at is that I I'm kind of curious as to how you
that I I'm kind of curious as to how you
that I I'm kind of curious as to how you got started doing this because I wake up
got started doing this because I wake up
got started doing this because I wake up at 3:00 in the morning and you know, my
at 3:00 in the morning and you know, my
at 3:00 in the morning and you know, my husband's like, "What are you doing? Are
husband's like, "What are you doing? Are
husband's like, "What are you doing? Are you high or something?" I mean, because
you high or something?" I mean, because
you high or something?" I mean, because I get these great ideas and I want to
I get these great ideas and I want to
I get these great ideas and I want to write Oprah a letter and be on her show
write Oprah a letter and be on her show
write Oprah a letter and be on her show and, you know, and I get real um, you
and, you know, and I get real um, you
and, you know, and I get real um, you know, interested in in in doing this
know, interested in in in doing this
know, interested in in in doing this kind of work one day, you know, and
kind of work one day, you know, and
kind of work one day, you know, and helping people. But
helping people. But
helping people. But >> yes,
>> yes,
>> yes, >> what?
>> what?
>> what? >> He says, "Yes."
>> He says, "Yes."
>> He says, "Yes." >> What's the question? Oh, I'm
>> What's the question? Oh, I'm
>> What's the question? Oh, I'm >> How did you get started doing this sort
>> How did you get started doing this sort
>> How did you get started doing this sort of stuff and helping so many people?
of stuff and helping so many people?
of stuff and helping so many people? >> You want my life story?
>> You want my life story?
>> You want my life story? >> No, just I mean how do you because I
>> No, just I mean how do you because I
>> No, just I mean how do you because I have all the ideas in my head, but how
have all the ideas in my head, but how
have all the ideas in my head, but how do you manifest that? I mean, you know,
do you manifest that? I mean, you know,
do you manifest that? I mean, you know, to just just
to just just
to just just >> it's too general a question to answer.
>> it's too general a question to answer.
>> it's too general a question to answer. >> Sorry.
>> Sorry.
>> Sorry. >> My own life was quite complex and also
>> My own life was quite complex and also
>> My own life was quite complex and also quite unusual. But there are very
quite unusual. But there are very
quite unusual. But there are very powerful experiences that catapulted me
powerful experiences that catapulted me
powerful experiences that catapulted me into certain states and from that state
into certain states and from that state
into certain states and from that state you saw everything and understood it
you saw everything and understood it
you saw everything and understood it differently. All I can say
differently. All I can say
differently. All I can say >> each level of spiritual evolution you
>> each level of spiritual evolution you
>> each level of spiritual evolution you get a
get a
get a >> it's true
>> it's true
>> it's true >> you get a revolution
>> you get a revolution
>> you get a revolution evolution of uh your worldview it looks
evolution of uh your worldview it looks
evolution of uh your worldview it looks different
different
different >> and many of the most major things that
>> and many of the most major things that
>> and many of the most major things that have come to me came to me out of the
have come to me came to me out of the
have come to me came to me out of the blue I wasn't thinking about it I wasn't
blue I wasn't thinking about it I wasn't
blue I wasn't thinking about it I wasn't contemplating suddenly
contemplating suddenly
contemplating suddenly >> 3 in the morning
>> 3 in the morning
>> 3 in the morning >> right
>> right
>> right >> both
>> both
>> both >> yeah I guess my question is what do you
>> yeah I guess my question is what do you
>> yeah I guess my question is what do you do after that I mean
do after that I mean
do after that I mean >> it becomes it becomes obvious what to do
>> it becomes it becomes obvious what to do
>> it becomes it becomes obvious what to do after that you can't answer it from a
after that you can't answer it from a
after that you can't answer it from a hypothetical you to answer from the
hypothetical you to answer from the
hypothetical you to answer from the real.
real.
real. >> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. >> If it's meant to be about this com
>> uh I found an article uh a couple of
>> uh I found an article uh a couple of months ago in the St. Pete Times
months ago in the St. Pete Times
months ago in the St. Pete Times >> in the
>> in the
>> in the >> in St. Pete Times in Florida and it was
>> in St. Pete Times in Florida and it was
>> in St. Pete Times in Florida and it was kind of apppropo to the subject today.
kind of apppropo to the subject today.
kind of apppropo to the subject today. >> Yeah. And the article reads,
>> Yeah. And the article reads,
>> Yeah. And the article reads, "Scientology nearly ready to unveil
"Scientology nearly ready to unveil
"Scientology nearly ready to unveil superpower."
superpower."
superpower." And the subtitle is, "In the works for
And the subtitle is, "In the works for
And the subtitle is, "In the works for decades, the closely guarded spiritual
decades, the closely guarded spiritual
decades, the closely guarded spiritual training program will be revealed in
training program will be revealed in
training program will be revealed in Clearwater."
Clearwater."
Clearwater." And so
And so
And so >> what's the price?
>> what's the price?
>> what's the price? >> You know what the price is?
>> You know what the price is?
>> You know what the price is? >> It's tens of thousands of dollars. Boy,
>> It's tens of thousands of dollars. Boy,
>> It's tens of thousands of dollars. Boy, >> and uh so I brought you the article.
>> and uh so I brought you the article.
>> and uh so I brought you the article. It's kind of they have it on the front
It's kind of they have it on the front
It's kind of they have it on the front page, but I thought
page, but I thought
page, but I thought >> that's interesting. Yeah,
>> that's interesting. Yeah,
>> that's interesting. Yeah, >> it should be in the entertainment se
>> it should be in the entertainment se
>> it should be in the entertainment se section.
>> So,
>> So, thank you.
thank you.
thank you. >> Scientology is a whole study in itself.
>> Scientology is a whole study in itself.
>> Scientology is a whole study in itself. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> And Dionetics,
>> And Dionetics,
>> And Dionetics, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> And then what happened to him later in
>> And then what happened to him later in
>> And then what happened to him later in life? You know, he stayed he never came
life? You know, he stayed he never came
life? You know, he stayed he never came near the the shores of the US after
near the the shores of the US after
near the the shores of the US after that.
that.
that. >> Yeah. He was on a
>> Yeah. He was on a
>> Yeah. He was on a >> he was paranoid lived on a ship. You
>> he was paranoid lived on a ship. You
>> he was paranoid lived on a ship. You thought the FBI was after him,
thought the FBI was after him,
thought the FBI was after him, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> But you you brought up the the name in
>> But you you brought up the the name in
>> But you you brought up the the name in in the lecture today.
in the lecture today.
in the lecture today. >> Oh, yes. because of uh the
>> Oh, yes. because of uh the
>> Oh, yes. because of uh the anti-sychiatry
anti-sychiatry
anti-sychiatry >> right
>> right
>> right >> uh movement you know
>> uh movement you know
>> uh movement you know >> uh which sounded idealistic but when you
>> uh which sounded idealistic but when you
>> uh which sounded idealistic but when you look what is the consequence it was
look what is the consequence it was
look what is the consequence it was disaster for millions you know
disaster for millions you know
disaster for millions you know >> and their organization
>> and their organization
>> and their organization has worldwide global you know
has worldwide global you know
has worldwide global you know aspirations
aspirations
aspirations and I was wondering you've never in any
and I was wondering you've never in any
and I was wondering you've never in any of your books you never calibrated the
of your books you never calibrated the
of your books you never calibrated the organization
organization
organization >> it's banned in Germany
>> it's banned in Germany
>> it's banned in Germany >> yeah yeah
>> yeah yeah
>> yeah yeah >> there's certain things you'll find uh
>> there's certain things you'll find uh
>> there's certain things you'll find uh missing
missing
missing in the book that you would expect and I
in the book that you would expect and I
in the book that you would expect and I have good reasons to admit them.
have good reasons to admit them.
have good reasons to admit them. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> First of all, I don't want a rattlesnake
>> First of all, I don't want a rattlesnake
>> First of all, I don't want a rattlesnake in my mailbox. That would help.
in my mailbox. That would help.
in my mailbox. That would help. >> They're very ligious.
>> They're very ligious.
>> They're very ligious. >> Secondly, I don't want 50 or 100
>> Secondly, I don't want 50 or 100
>> Secondly, I don't want 50 or 100 lawsuits trying to wear me out just at
lawsuits trying to wear me out just at
lawsuits trying to wear me out just at the cost of defending lawsuits, which is
the cost of defending lawsuits, which is
the cost of defending lawsuits, which is the
the
the >> the tactic of a certain organization,
>> the tactic of a certain organization,
>> the tactic of a certain organization, which is also glaringly missing.
which is also glaringly missing.
which is also glaringly missing. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> But I think any spiritual student would
>> But I think any spiritual student would
>> But I think any spiritual student would get instantly what they're what they
get instantly what they're what they
get instantly what they're what they calibrate. Right.
calibrate. Right.
calibrate. Right. >> Okay. Well,
>> Okay. Well,
>> Okay. Well, >> yeah.
>> yeah.
>> yeah. >> Thought it was perfect.
>> Thought it was perfect.
>> Thought it was perfect. >> I just wouldn't want to be any of them
>> I just wouldn't want to be any of them
>> I just wouldn't want to be any of them at death's door when you think you
at death's door when you think you
at death's door when you think you devoted your whole life to eliminating
devoted your whole life to eliminating
devoted your whole life to eliminating God from the human universe and now you
God from the human universe and now you
God from the human universe and now you realize that you're about to meet him.
realize that you're about to meet him.
realize that you're about to meet him. >> That is a good thought.
>> That is a good thought.
>> That is a good thought. >> Hello. Reality check.
>> Hello. Reality check.
>> Hello. Reality check. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Was mistaken.
>> Was mistaken.
>> Was mistaken. >> And what was the last thought he had
>> And what was the last thought he had
>> And what was the last thought he had before he left the world? Oops.
Oh, I stepped out of the human body
Oh, I stepped out of the human body right into a a banana peel.
right into a a banana peel.
right into a a banana peel. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Um, I love to paint and
>> Um, I love to paint and
>> Um, I love to paint and >> you love what?
>> you love what?
>> you love what? >> I love painting.
>> I love painting.
>> I love painting. >> And I want to steward that love of art
>> And I want to steward that love of art
>> And I want to steward that love of art and be a working artist. And I try to
and be a working artist. And I try to
and be a working artist. And I try to make the work in a spirit of devotion.
make the work in a spirit of devotion.
make the work in a spirit of devotion. Yes.
Yes.
Yes. >> But I'm wondering if you could speak
>> But I'm wondering if you could speak
>> But I'm wondering if you could speak some more about um the spiritual
some more about um the spiritual
some more about um the spiritual significance of art and how it can be of
significance of art and how it can be of
significance of art and how it can be of service. Well, of course, it's a great
service. Well, of course, it's a great
service. Well, of course, it's a great and classic study, you know, from the
and classic study, you know, from the
and classic study, you know, from the from the dome of what you call the
from the dome of what you call the
from the dome of what you call the Vatican. Uh, spirituality, art of course
Vatican. Uh, spirituality, art of course
Vatican. Uh, spirituality, art of course have been so closely relationship
have been so closely relationship
have been so closely relationship and art has played a very important part
and art has played a very important part
and art has played a very important part throughout all the history of religion
throughout all the history of religion
throughout all the history of religion and spirituality. So certainly it could
and spirituality. So certainly it could
and spirituality. So certainly it could um inspire your work, inspire your work,
um inspire your work, inspire your work,
um inspire your work, inspire your work, you know. Mhm.
you know. Mhm.
you know. Mhm. >> Okay. Thanks.
>> Okay. Thanks.
>> Okay. Thanks. >> Cyine Chapel. The ceiling of the
>> Cyine Chapel. The ceiling of the
>> Cyine Chapel. The ceiling of the Systeine Chapel.
Systeine Chapel.
Systeine Chapel. Yep.
Yep.
Yep. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Imagine what it took him to do that.
>> Imagine what it took him to do that.
>> Imagine what it took him to do that. What was it? Four years on his back up
What was it? Four years on his back up
What was it? Four years on his back up there. Four years on his back painting
there. Four years on his back painting
there. Four years on his back painting upside down. Good God. What a
upside down. Good God. What a
upside down. Good God. What a >> what a devotion.
>> what a devotion.
>> what a devotion. >> Okay. Thank you. So,
>> Okay. Thank you. So,
>> Okay. Thank you. So, >> okay. much.
>> okay. much.
>> okay. much. >> Can you imagine?
>> Can you imagine?
>> Can you imagine? >> Four years on your back.
>> Four years on your back.
>> Four years on your back. >> We also wonder if we could take a
>> We also wonder if we could take a
>> We also wonder if we could take a picture with you.
picture with you.
picture with you. >> Paint the ceiling of the Systeine
>> Paint the ceiling of the Systeine
>> Paint the ceiling of the Systeine Chapel. Boy, oh boy.
Chapel. Boy, oh boy.
Chapel. Boy, oh boy. >> You ready, Doc?
>> You ready, Doc?
>> You ready, Doc? >> Oh,
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I was looking at the Sistine Chapel in
I was looking at the Sistine Chapel in
I was looking at the Sistine Chapel in my mind. I'm sorry.
my mind. I'm sorry.
my mind. I'm sorry. Hand out there. Man reaching for him.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins. >> Um, my question is I'm a I'm going into
>> Um, my question is I'm a I'm going into
>> Um, my question is I'm a I'm going into my last year of a psychotherapy program,
my last year of a psychotherapy program,
my last year of a psychotherapy program, a Buddhist based one.
a Buddhist based one.
a Buddhist based one. >> Last year of what?
>> Last year of what?
>> Last year of what? >> Uh, a training in psychotherapy to be a
>> Uh, a training in psychotherapy to be a
>> Uh, a training in psychotherapy to be a psychotherapist.
psychotherapist.
psychotherapist. >> Oh, yes. Yes.
>> Oh, yes. Yes.
>> Oh, yes. Yes. >> And I noticed personally I have a lot of
>> And I noticed personally I have a lot of
>> And I noticed personally I have a lot of self-interest and attraction to your
self-interest and attraction to your
self-interest and attraction to your work, this context.
work, this context.
work, this context. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> And I also noticed kind of two things.
>> And I also noticed kind of two things.
>> And I also noticed kind of two things. um almost like judgment or an aversion
um almost like judgment or an aversion
um almost like judgment or an aversion to working uh outside of it or I have
to working uh outside of it or I have
to working uh outside of it or I have this question if I'm going to you
this question if I'm going to you
this question if I'm going to you mentioned timing and like working with a
mentioned timing and like working with a
mentioned timing and like working with a client and you only mention a at a
client and you only mention a at a
client and you only mention a at a certain point to a certain person
certain point to a certain person
certain point to a certain person >> when they're ready for it. Yeah. Yeah.
>> when they're ready for it. Yeah. Yeah.
>> when they're ready for it. Yeah. Yeah. >> So my question is just and again I
>> So my question is just and again I
>> So my question is just and again I haven't been seeing a lot of clients yet
haven't been seeing a lot of clients yet
haven't been seeing a lot of clients yet so I'm wondering how to bring this
so I'm wondering how to bring this
so I'm wondering how to bring this context in a meaningful way uh working
context in a meaningful way uh working
context in a meaningful way uh working with someone one-on-one.
with someone one-on-one.
with someone one-on-one. What you do is whatever your frame of
What you do is whatever your frame of
What you do is whatever your frame of reference is um you know you incorporate
reference is um you know you incorporate
reference is um you know you incorporate that into yourself and then you merely
that into yourself and then you merely
that into yourself and then you merely explain to the patient how you see it
explain to the patient how you see it
explain to the patient how you see it from this particular context. You see
from this particular context. You see
from this particular context. You see >> and u
>> and u
>> and u with a therapeutic intention. See
with a therapeutic intention. See
with a therapeutic intention. See >> so uh you know I I incorporated
>> so uh you know I I incorporated
>> so uh you know I I incorporated information from a variety of sources.
information from a variety of sources.
information from a variety of sources. Freud Young,
Freud Young,
Freud Young, >> uh, brain chemistry, spiritual reality,
>> uh, brain chemistry, spiritual reality,
>> uh, brain chemistry, spiritual reality, aa, 12 steps.
aa, 12 steps.
aa, 12 steps. Wherever I could find truth, I
Wherever I could find truth, I
Wherever I could find truth, I incorporated it because at some point
incorporated it because at some point
incorporated it because at some point with some patient, that is just what
with some patient, that is just what
with some patient, that is just what they need. That little extra quarter
they need. That little extra quarter
they need. That little extra quarter ounce on the scale is what tips it, you
ounce on the scale is what tips it, you
ounce on the scale is what tips it, you know what I mean?
know what I mean?
know what I mean? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> And then humor, I think, is very
>> And then humor, I think, is very
>> And then humor, I think, is very therapeutic.
therapeutic.
therapeutic. had to see things in a humorous way. And
had to see things in a humorous way. And
had to see things in a humorous way. And pretty soon the patient begins to see
pretty soon the patient begins to see
pretty soon the patient begins to see things in a humorous way and gives up
things in a humorous way and gives up
things in a humorous way and gives up thinking about suicide and considers the
thinking about suicide and considers the
thinking about suicide and considers the whole thing's a stupid joke. Haha.
>> Thank you, doctor.
>> Thank you, doctor. >> I'd say, "Don't kill yourself this week.
>> I'd say, "Don't kill yourself this week.
>> I'd say, "Don't kill yourself this week. You haven't paid your bill yet.
First, pay my bill, then kill yourself."
First, pay my bill, then kill yourself." Oh, you son of a You'd say, "Walk
Oh, you son of a You'd say, "Walk
Oh, you son of a You'd say, "Walk out the door." But I know he's not going
out the door." But I know he's not going
out the door." But I know he's not going to commit suicide tonight.
to commit suicide tonight.
to commit suicide tonight. Thank you.
>> I don't know if I would have gone to see
>> I don't know if I would have gone to see you.
you.
you. >> Well, it's because the timing of the
>> Well, it's because the timing of the
>> Well, it's because the timing of the remark was perfect. You know, I'm taking
remark was perfect. You know, I'm taking
remark was perfect. You know, I'm taking it out of context.
it out of context.
it out of context. >> Taking it out of context. Is it is it
>> Taking it out of context. Is it is it
>> Taking it out of context. Is it is it generally likely that loved ones in our
generally likely that loved ones in our
generally likely that loved ones in our lives, parents, children, siblings are
lives, parents, children, siblings are
lives, parents, children, siblings are people that we have had relationships
people that we have had relationships
people that we have had relationships with or known in prior lives.
with or known in prior lives.
with or known in prior lives. >> Let's ask the question. We can ask it in
>> Let's ask the question. We can ask it in
>> Let's ask the question. We can ask it in a general way. There is a good
a general way. There is a good
a general way. There is a good likelihood. Is this great likelihood?
likelihood. Is this great likelihood?
likelihood. Is this great likelihood? Not a determination, not a one to one.
Not a determination, not a one to one.
Not a determination, not a one to one. But many people have been in and out
But many people have been in and out
But many people have been in and out each other's lives for a long long time.
each other's lives for a long long time.
each other's lives for a long long time. I'd say how long
>> we do and we said we knew each other 11
>> we do and we said we knew each other 11 times.
times.
times. >> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. A lot of timeslu