Just to get out of bed here, dude.
I got to get me one of them.
I look old-fashioned.
Go back down, center to the left.
Hello.
Good morning, Doctor.
Hi, Doctor.
Hello.
Uh-huh.
George.
Yeah.
This way, Doctor.
This way, this way, this way.
Good morning.
All right, it's good to see you again.
Hi.
Uh-huh.
Good morning.
Hello.
Greetings from Ken Watnick.
Oh, hi, thanks.
Nice to meet you.
L.L. Bean Church.
Oh, boy.
How are you?
Hey, Doc, smile over here.
Oh, come over here.
Oh, my, oh, my.
That's a great hat.
Hi.
Great hat, great hat.
Merry Christmas, David.
Merry Christmas.
Gloria in excelsis Deo.
Praise be to thee, O Lord, most high, in whose name we are assembled today.
The 91st Psalm says that those who...
...put their faith in me are mine.
Krishna says, those who believe in me, God said, we need to make a couple of announcements.
There's much literature about the obligation of the student to the teacher.
I turn it around the other way.
I'm concerned about the obligation and the promise and responsibility of the teacher
to the student.
I'm answering the question.
It's not answerable for all of you, so keep that in mind.
You screw up, I'm in trouble, you know what I mean?
Yes, we'll get to...
We have a slide on the obligation of the spiritual teacher to be straightforward, honest, to
try to remain as simple as possible, and to be completely transparent.
Needs nothing, wants nothing from students, has nothing to do with their personal lives,
doesn't try to control them, doesn't tell them what to do.
do, have freedom to come and go, don't have to sign up for anything, no obligations, no
oaths. That's a cheerful start, isn't it? All right, we're going to go through, as you
know, we have by now over a hundred slides from various lectures. So what we're going
to do, how many people here are new? How many people are new? Okay. So I'm going to emphasize
the basics then, the basics, and the charts that are farther along in the lecture series
are in the books, you know, the calibration of the most famous scientists in history,
et cetera. Those are all very interesting. But today I really want to cover the basics
and a few concepts. And once you, they incorporate them, the rest of them become much easier.
A couple of very basic premises. I speak from several different experiential backgrounds
simultaneously. You know, I practiced psychiatry, psychoanalysis, psychology, et cetera, for
fifty years. Had a huge practice. Also had, with the roll calls, rather unusual spiritual
experiences starting very young, age, you know, about a year and a half ago. And I've
been doing a lot of research, three, and very intense throughout my life, that transform,
they enter context of existence and reality. Therefore I saw some things differently than
other people. And some things I thought were quite useful. And they're incorporated into
the lecture series as consciousness research. So we'll also be talking about spiritual reality
and consciousness research.
Okay.
The reason for that is mankind has never had the capacity to tell truth from falsehood.
Here we wander around this planet, for zillions of years, and you can't even tell truth from
falsehood.
Letting a kid loose on the desert with no compass. Good luck.
How we even survived to where we are today is amazing to me. You know, man has been at
war.
93% of the time. 93% of the time. It's been continuous since I've been born. I was born
right after World War I, and it's been one war after another ever since. 7% of the time
man wasn't at war, he was probably too sick to plague, or some great catastrophe kept
him from his usual business. So, we'll discover why that is. Why is man so warlike? He talks
peace, but it's the last straw.
So, we'll, we'll discover why that is. Why is man so warlike? He talks peace, but it's
the last straw.
Man talks peace, but it's the last thing he wants. Man talks peace, but it's the last
thing he wants. Resist. Got that? He talks peace, but he doesn't want it. A threat of
peace crashes the stock market and everything else, right?
Man talks peace, but he lives by war. And we'll see why that is, because we'll cover
that when we discuss the evolution of man.
The evolution of man. The evolution of man. The evolution of man. The evolution of man.
Are the evolution of the ego over evolutionary time. And we'll see what the impact of that
is on man's brain physiology. Spiritual attention alignment absolutely alters your brain physiology
so that you see things and process them differently, understand them differently. At the present
time, you know, on the caliber of consciousness, truth starts at 200 and goes up to 1,000.
That which is not true is 295.
85% of mankind calibrates below 200 at the present time.
That should give you more realistic expectations of earthly life.
So now we have slides.
We'll start with one we always start with.
And yes, now what, do you see the same thing on all three screens?
No.
I thought maybe I'd have to run back and forth between the screens.
That's a lucky break.
I didn't need my kid's gym shoes after all.
Okay.
Well, we'll talk about how this came to be.
I was, as I said, I had a very large clinic.
We had the most hopeless patients from all over the world.
They flew them in from all over the world.
And a thousand, we had a thousand new patients a year.
Extremely hopeless.
And therefore,
I used every modality that could possibly help people.
Acupuncture, nutrition, everything.
And each thing that we added made a difference.
You would take ten hopeless cases and put them on certain kinds of diets.
Seven of them would cure.
That left seven to go.
Those seven, we would test them for cerebral allergy.
Four of them, we would find what it is.
Four would go. We only got three left.
And we used kinesiology.
Kinesiology, which I learned from Diamond, Dr. Diamond.
So, I was giving a lecture one time on kinesiology.
Kinesiology is so simple that if you can't understand it,
you have to leave this audience immediately.
This is Susan, my right arm.
She's done many thousands of calibrations.
She's very quick and fast.
That's why I use her all the time.
She's also inexpensive.
So, I was teaching kinesiology.
Things that I learned with George Diamond.
And I was teaching it to our staff.
And the first thing we...
One of the first things that we demonstrated
was if you take naive subjects
and have them look at fluorescent lights,
they'll go weak.
Now, she's not a naive subject.
So, we can't use her anymore.
She can't use you anymore for that.
But if you take just ordinary people off the street,
we've done it with many large audiences.
We've done it with audiences of a thousand people
in New York City.
And if you take naive people
and have them hold out their arm,
and now I ask them, ask you to resist.
And I push down with two fingers.
I'd say that's about six ounces of pressure, wouldn't you?
Yeah, six ounces.
And I say, resist.
Okay?
All right.
Now, if you take naive people
and have them look at the fluorescent light,
I'll put your arm up.
I'm going to hold something in mind.
Okay.
What I'm holding in mind
calibrates over 200 resist.
Okay.
If you have a person look at fluorescent lights,
their arm will go weak.
If you hold pesticides over the solar plexus,
Sweet and low.
We used to pass it out to the audience
and count it out in twos.
One's a doctor, one's a patient.
Anyway, certain things made everybody go weak,
fluorescent lights especially.
Think of all the people working all day,
all their lives under fluorescent lights
that are making their energies go weak all day long.
Yeah.
So I was demonstrating it.
So that night at the clinic, I said,
you can sit down.
I said, I need some volunteers.
So some people volunteered.
We had an attitudinal healing center.
Jerry Jampolsky came over
and he started the first one on Tiburon
and we had the second one.
So I said, I need some students
to teach a class in kinesiology.
And they were doing the Course in Miracles.
And so I said, okay, kid, look at the fluorescent lights
and they did not go weak.
I said, what?
Look at the lights.
They did not go weak.
They did not go weak with pesticides.
They're sweet and low.
Something had happened.
Something was different about these people
who were spiritual students.
So I started a small research project.
A number of people just starting the Course in Miracles.
And I tested them out at the very beginning of the course
before they started.
They all went weak with pesticides.
They all went weak with fluorescent lights.
And we retested them about once a week.
And by the time they got to less than 75,
around in there, 75, 80, 85,
all of a sudden they would not go weak to anything.
Something had happened to their consciousness
that made them immune
to the adverse effects of negative stimuli.
They were no longer subject to what was out there.
And that was the premise,
you're only subject to what you hold in mind.
It progressed from there then
and we discovered a scale of consciousness
of one to a thousand.
And on the scale of consciousness,
using the same technique we just did,
we calibrated all the major motions.
We have a scale that goes from one to a thousand,
a logarithmic scale.
These numbers are 10.
So this is 10 times 10, 150 times.
This is 10 times 10, 259, 50 times,
which is exponential and logarithmic.
Which is it, logarithmic or exponential?
Anybody know?
It's logarithmic exponential.
It covers it all.
The highest possible calibration in this planet,
earthly human life, is a thousand.
Because that's the way we set up the scale.
The lowest is death at one.
Life begins at one and goes up to one thousand.
We found that anything and everything in this planet
could be calibrated.
And what we discovered we were discovering
is how to tell perception from essence.
How to tell reality from appearance.
Descartes, the great philosopher.
The difference between what a thing looks like
and what it actually is.
The wolf in sheep's clothing, how do you discern it?
And of course, Socrates, my favorite philosopher,
said, all men chooses only the good.
That helps you put in place
the Christian premise of forgiveness.
How can you forgive people that seem so?
When you recall Socrates' teaching,
all men choose what they think and believe to be the good.
The only problem is they cannot discern
the real good from the false good.
Therefore, the basic problem is again ignorance,
not knowing essence from appearance.
So what we had discovered then,
with the calibrated levels of consciousness,
is how to discern essence from appearance
for the first time in human history.
Man goes by appearance and opinion.
All right, so using the same simple arm technique
to hold the thing in mind.
So when we calibrate something,
I'll just calibrate something.
You don't have to do it.
I'm holding something in mind now.
I'm holding something in mind.
I want you to resist.
Resist.
I'm holding something else in mind now.
I want you to resist.
The first thing I was holding in mind
is a fake,
a fake,
a fake Picasso.
Yeah, fake Picasso.
I just was holding a picture of that.
Fake Picasso at home.
And then I also have a couple of legitimate Dali's.
And I have another painting.
Let's see if this is a real one too.
I'm holding this one in mind.
Resist.
Thank God, that's a Miro.
It's a Miro lithograph.
Miro died at age 90.
And suddenly it became very valuable.
So anyway, I keep it out in the garage
so that no harm will come to it.
So there's objections to kinesiology
and it's the problem of the people
who make the objections
because you can see
even a child can do this.
And we did a video,
I think it's called
Wall Power versus Force,
in which we just use a simple child.
And so it's very simplistic.
As you can see, it's not suggestive
because she doesn't know what I'm holding in mind.
The trouble that people ask me sometimes is about dowsing.
Some super experts can do it with dowsing.
The trouble with dowsing is the subject and the answer
are both the same person.
The questioner and the answer are the same person.
And one could have a prejudice,
in one way or the other,
that might influence the answer.
So if it's something really critical,
I don't tell her what I'm holding in mind
because I don't want the slightest chance
of any kind of suggestion taking place.
To be able to do it,
you have to be dedicated to truth,
not to seeking reinforcement
of your favorite positionality.
Understand?
So it's like a compass.
The compass then,
man was without a compass.
He couldn't tell the truth from falsehood.
Now he has a compass that's calibrated
all the way to a thousand.
And so we found that everything below level 200 was false.
Everything above 200 was true.
And we then incorporated from psychoanalysis
also the perennial wisdom,
also the great chain of being.
So this is a very familiar
listing of levels of consciousness
with shame and disgrace
and guilt and apathy.
All the negative ones down here,
Columbia Psychoanalytic,
Shandor Rado taught adaptational psychodynamics,
a variation of Freudian psychoanalysis.
These recall the emergency emotions.
These recall the welfare emotions.
So it also correlates to psychoanalysis.
I spent four years of psychoanalysis.
With Lionel Oversee,
who was a professor at Columbia University,
whose analyst was Abraham Kardiner,
whose analyst was Freud.
So Freud's my great-grandfather.
He was an atheist.
My first analyst and I were both atheists.
We agreed that it was all nonsensical.
And that lasts you a while.
Then, so here we have all the things
that we call the basic feelings.
And of course we wrote a book called
Transcending Levels of Consciousness,
in which we look at the upside and the downside
of what is holding each one of these levels.
What's holding all negative things in place
is one single thing.
You don't have to give up anything
in this whole world
to get off these things here.
All you have to give up is one thing,
repeatedly one thing,
no matter what the one thing is.
Hating your mother-in-law,
feeling guilty about something,
being overcome with greed and lust or what.
The only thing you've got to give up
is the juice that you're getting out of it,
the secret pleasure that you're getting out of it.
Why are people so addicted to hatred?
Because they get such wonderful juice out of it.
It's just so wonderful to get out there
and have a parade and picket and riot
and have a whole hate orgy.
You watch them on TV,
they've got that glee,
it's like an orgy look.
Once you get that look,
you can see it all over the world,
whatever the parade is,
whatever the issue is,
it's all the same look.
I'm right and you're wrong.
So to get off anything then,
you have to just be willing
to give up whatever juice
you're getting off of it.
You say,
oh, I'm not getting any juice out of suffering.
Oh yes, you are.
You're getting less and less of it.
You're getting less and less of the juice.
I know people that are still suffering
over the loss of a family member 30 years ago.
Isn't it time to get over it?
No, it's becoming a lifestyle.
Lifestyle.
And the addictiveness that goes with it,
see it every night on television,
you can't get over it.
What was the eagle?
The eagles had a song.
Let's get over it.
Wasn't that the name of it?
It's time to get over it.
The getting over it
really comes from being willing
to let go the energy
that we get out of the negative positionality.
We finally get up to a level called courage.
Level courage.
Courage is the willingness to tell the truth.
It's the first step in all the 12-step groups.
It's the willingness to take responsibility
and be honest.
Then you move up to neutrality.
Neutrality is a very comfortable place to be.
Neutrality, if you get the job, it's fine.
And if you don't, you'll find another.
So what's the big deal?
We need lots more people
and neutrality in the world.
People worry about the world ending in the year 2012.
What's the next time the world's supposed to end?
The Mayan calendar?
Let's take care of the Mayan calendar.
The world is going to end in 2012.
Folks, it's not going to end in 2012.
Those of you who were counting on it,
I hate to disappoint you.
The Mayan calendar has been wrong
for thousands of years,
and it's going to be wrong for thousands of years.
Why is that?
Because you can't predict the future.
The future is not set.
If the future was set,
there would be no personal responsibility,
no karmic responsibility,
and there would really be no point to evolution itself.
Because this world is optimal
for spiritual evolution.
This world gives you the optimum opportunity
to gain positive karma
and undo negative karma.
Therefore, this world is perfect.
Huh.
This is a perfect world.
Resist.
Zowie.
That's the essence and appearance.
If God wanted a place where your spirit could evolve,
he would create Earth, wouldn't he?
Every moment you have to make a choice.
Every single moment you have to make a choice.
You don't have any choice not to make a choice.
You always have to make a choice.
Constantly.
So, the spirit is like a little iron filing
in the infinite field of consciousness,
which is the light of God out of which arose creation.
Therefore, every choice and every decision you make
alters the energy of this little iron filing
that is within this giant electromagnetic field.
Therefore, everything comes about
as a consequence of karmic choice.
Every time you make a positive choice,
this polarity increases.
A negative choice, a negative polarity.
Therefore, where you are in the overall field
is automatically the consequence of that which you are.
That which you are is determining what is.
There's no point to worry about Judgment Day
because it's happened.
Today is Judgment Day.
Resist.
Today and every day is Judgment Day.
There's no point about worrying about
some horrible god in the future
who's going to beat you up,
throw you into hell because he hits you.
You've done it already.
All right.
So, the justice of God is absolute.
Why?
Because it is based on the reality
of that which you have chosen of your own free choice.
And God's will for us is free choice.
Free choice.
To say such things makes me, again,
in the eyes of a relativist, an absolutist.
I might as well have warned everybody here.
I am an absolutist.
It's the absolutism of absolutism
that makes it so absolute.
You chop off a finger, folks.
It's not relative.
It's gone.
I was going to kick out a relativist
when it comes to money.
You know, these crazy professors and all.
They ridicule everything,
every kind of reality, etc.
When it comes to money, it's amazing
what an absolutist they are.
One man's 50 is another man's 20?
Uh-uh, that does not go.
One man's 50 is everybody's 50.
Every one of these relativists is an absolutist
when it comes down to the reality
of everyday life.
It's a nice game to play politically, philosophically.
All right, so neutrality, willingness,
in the 300s are very powerful.
The 300s are very powerful.
They build great and do wonderful humanitarian beneficial things.
Rick Warren, what he writes is up there in the high 350s.
You get up to the level of 400s,
you're talking about the intellect,
non-emotional, non-emotional.
Reason and logic.
And then the great scientific geniuses,
Einstein and Freud, etc.,
are at calibration level 499.
499 is as far as you can go with reason.
The intellect, you can prove what is so.
The differential calculus, 499.
All right, so the reason and the intellect
then is in the range of the mid 400s.
You're still talking about linear reality.
Linear.
That means content.
Now when you get to level 500,
you bring in context.
Context.
Because now you're moving to the non-linear.
Love at 500 is the emergence of the non-linear.
So from 500 up then, we have love,
and then we move on into the higher levels
of selfless love.
Selfless love,
the 12 step groups,
alcoholics and anomalous,
calibrates at 500 and a 40.
500 and a 40.
That's the top few percentage
of all of mankind, 540.
Only 4% of mankind ever gets beyond level 500.
0.4 gets to 540.
People who have recovered in 12 step programs
or A Course in Miracles, etc.,
belong to 0.4.
0.4% of the world's population, statistically.
So 540 is the beginning of a transformation
and it comes about via illumination.
As you get towards level 600,
at about 570 is sainthood.
The Dalai Lama, the Pope, Father Pio.
The level of 570 is
sainthood.
And from 540 and up,
and especially around 570,
there emerges the miraculous.
The miraculous about which mankind goes ooh and ahh.
But in experiential reality,
the miraculous is nothing but the unfolding
of unnatural phenomena.
When you realize that evolution and creation
are one and the same thing,
right now there's so much controversy
about intelligent design versus creationism, etc.
That which shines forth
in the description of Genesis,
the light of God shone forth
out of which arose all of creation.
One thing that arose was
the energy field of life itself.
And so everything that we calibrate
is in comparison to an infinite field of consciousness.
The infinite field called consciousness,
which is beyond time and place,
beyond time and place,
has no beginning and no ending.
Therefore it's impossible
to prove the existence of God
because that which is infinite,
limitless, has no beginning and ending,
is in a different paradigm of reality than proof.
Proof is the world of the 400s.
Spiritual reality starts at 500 and up.
It has to do with essence.
It has to do with radical subjectivity.
The reason certain things became apparent
was because when I saw kinesiology demonstrated,
they presumed that it was a local phenomena
based on the Newtonian premise of causality.
Causality applies to the energy fields
of the 400s science.
But the way things come about
is not via causality.
That is a mentalization
that you project into the world
like you do with time.
There is no time out there.
There is no space.
There is no distance.
There is no causality.
And there is no before or after.
That's the way it looks to your witnessing.
The fact that you witness things progressively
doesn't mean that they are that way in the universe.
You see the grandiosity of the ego.
If I see it that way,
that's the way it must be in the universe.
The universe has no interest
in the sequence in which you're witnessing here.
So what you're actually watching
is that everything is occurring
of its own spontaneously
as the phenomena of emergence,
potentiality becoming an actuality.
Things do not happen by causality.
That's an impossibility
because you end up in an infinite progressive series.
Everything that happens is happening spontaneously.
There isn't even any personal you
making it happen,
although you think there is.
Duality arises from thinking
that there is a separate personal you
that is the originator of all action,
the motivator, the decider.
In reality, everything is happening spontaneously.
Potentiality, when local conditions are right,
emerges into an actuality.
And that's the same phenomena
we see within the miraculous.
The miraculous is nothing but
the potentiation,
the activation of that potentiation
into an actuality
by virtue of the field of the context.
The higher the spiritual energy of the context,
the greater the likelihood
that what is held in mind will potentiate.
At a certain level of consciousness,
the witnessing of life
is once
one continuous miracle after another.
Everything is happening of its own
by virtue of that which it is.
Hmm.
I don't know what all that meant,
but it certainly sounded good, didn't it?
I know what it means.
Maybe we should go to the next slide.
In this lifetime,
the reason I recognize
what's going on with kinesiology
is because I've had rather astonishing
spiritual experiences throughout life,
starting at a very young age.
People like me didn't talk about it,
so I give it a few minutes.
The rest of it's in the book.
It began at age three,
when out of nothingness,
there came the sudden shock of existence,
out of oblivion,
out of the void,
where I went from previous lifetimes
as a Hinayana Buddhist
into the void.
I would leave that lifetime in the void.
This lifetime, at age three,
suddenly,
there was a shock.
It was like suddenly turned on the Klee lights,
and I realized that I existed.
It was a stunning, terrible shock.
I was not happy about it.
I was not pleased to exist.
Not only was it bad enough to exist,
but with it went this little body.
Ha!
Three-year-old body in a wagon.
First, you exist.
Secondly, you got this body with you.
Oh, my God.
The next thing that arose,
this is all nonverbal,
the next thing that arose
was suddenly the fear of nonexistence.
If I had come into existence,
then it could have arisen
that I would not have come into existence,
which was just a total awareness.
So, there arose the conundrum,
which this life was about for many years.
Was reality existence or nonexistence?
Was reality beyond existence or nonexistence,
which can't be solved
if you go past consciousness level 850.
So, I came in as nothingness,
nothingness was the absolute reality,
nothingness.
From there, a lot of rather profound
spiritual experiences happened.
They were all spontaneous,
in which I experienced
the infinite radiance of the self,
and whether the physical body
continued to exist or not
was totally irrelevant,
because in that state,
it's timeless.
So, in a snowbank somewhere
in the highways of Wisconsin,
I climbed in and out of this blizzard
and this incredible blissful condition
overwhelmed,
and there was no personal self anymore,
just an infinite presence
beyond all description,
beyond all time,
with no beginning and no end.
Its characteristics were power,
power beyond all description.
The power of divine love is invincible.
Its invincibility is based on the fact
that it is absolute.
The absolute power of divinity
is an absolute,
and simultaneously exquisitely soft,
so that what was left of the self,
personal self,
melts,
melted into this infinite beingness.
Then came the knowingness,
the reality,
that that which I am
existed before all time.
That which I am
will exist beyond all universes,
after all universes have disappeared,
resist.
An absolute knowingness.
The thing about spiritual reality
is that it is an absolute,
experientially,
it is an absolute.
It's non-verbal,
no questions can be asked,
none arise,
because they have all been answered.
Because of such experiences
when I saw kinesiology,
I saw that it was not a Newtonian causal,
cause and effect kind of relationship.
What I saw was that
what the person was responding to
was the energy field of consciousness itself,
it's not a linear causality.
When I hold in mind something
and press down her arm,
I'm holding the energy field
of the essence of that,
and what her arm is responding to
is the essence.
If the essence is over 200,
she stays strong.
If the essence is under 200,
she goes weak.
She doesn't even know
why I'm holding in mind.
Everybody got that?
I want to get that very well.
It's non-linear.
It has nothing to do with reason,
argument, logic, etc.
So all comes about then
as a virtue of that which it is,
potentiality,
which is actualized by the field.
So the field is what actualizes
the kinesiologic response.
It's also the field that actualizes
what the world calls the miraculous
from energy field.
540,
the miraculous is common
in 12-step groups,
and Course in Miracles, of course,
is based on that.
570 and up,
the miraculous is almost continuous.
Everything is just in place
the way it's supposed to be,
and everything is perfect.
And so the world doesn't go
from imperfection to perfection.
The world in reality,
when you really see it for what it is,
goes from perfection to perfection.
As a spiritual discipline then,
you make a decision
to see the intrinsic beauty and perfection
of all that exists no matter what.
The mind will make objections.
You don't mean that garbage can
laying over there.
Yes, I mean that garbage can
I remember walking down an alley
in New York City,
and here's two old beautiful garbage cans
and a couple of mice running around,
and I merged into that awareness.
It was like an incredible painting.
It was like an impressionistic painting.
Here's these garbage cans like this,
and little mice like this running all over,
and everything is all collapsed like that,
and the tin can is laying there,
and it's just a stunning,
what do you call it,
montage or whatever the word is in art.
Within everything then is,
because of its perfection,
everything goes from perfection
to perfection.
And so,
everything goes from perfection
to perfection.
You say, well what about this half-grown rose?
Is it an imperfect rose?
No,
it's a perfectly half-grown rose.
Understand?
It can only move from perfection
to perfection.
This is a perfect half-grown rose.
This is a perfect three-quarters.
This is a perfect full.
This is a perfect faded rose.
This is a perfect dyed,
dried up,
old,
crossing rose.
It goes from perfectly almost
to perfectly full,
to perfectly faded,
to perfectly dried up,
and then it blows away into perfect dust.
Do you see its perfection at every second?
Everything is that way.
What the world, what you think is destruction
is the perfection of the
emergence of that potentiality.
As the ship goes over,
they all drown
at the same time.
La la.
Wasn't that a great drowning we did
when they came down the other side?
Man, that really turned on the TV and everybody.
People go out with a dramatic bang,
don't they?
Look at the lengths that people go through
to get out of here, you know?
You don't just simply quietly slump over.
You gotta do a whole big deal out of it,
drive off a cliff, have the police there,
9-11, God all help us.
Alright, so let's go.
Everything then is the perfect
fulfillment of potential. Why?
Because this world is
perfect for the undoing of negative
karma and the gaining of positive
karma. This world is
maximal. Let's see if
that's so. We have permission
to ask that. That is so.
What the Buddha said is truth.
The Buddha wasn't lying, folks.
I told him, I said,
when I get back there, I want to remind everybody
that you were telling the truth, in case they'd forgotten.
They think the Buddha
only applies to the Eastern world.
Oh, okay, right.
Infinite potentiality, then.
These are the scale of the
enlightened states.
I don't know where
the calibrations are. They all calibrate
a thousand and over.
If you ask
the arm what these are, these are all
infinite.
Well, I see.
Then you leave this
experiential universe,
and you get to angels and archangels.
And
my own salvation came about
in this lifetime.
Out of the pits of hell,
I would not advise anybody
to take any risk of going to hell
under any circumstances.
Let me be a witness.
You don't want to take any chances at all.
You just do not want to even
give it a thought.
To risk hell, see.
Because there are levels of hell
far deeper than even Dante
realized.
Dante was extremely correct.
The upper levels of hell.
Because when I hit the pits of hell,
through inner spiritual exploration
and despair,
I was an atheist at the time.
I was a religionist
all my life.
Brought up in a very religious
environment.
I was an acolyte.
I sang in the choir.
I was a boy soprano, sort of.
I sang in the Great Lakes in the old choir.
Eventually, I became an atheist
for the reason that,
how can anybody so religious be an atheist?
I was walking through the woods one day
thinking of nothing at all.
And all of a sudden,
all the great things that have happened to me
came as a revelation.
This was not such a great thing.
This was the opposite.
All of a sudden, out of nothingness,
I grasped the totality
of the suffering
of mankind
throughout all of time.
The totality of the suffering
of all of mankind
throughout all of time.
I was staggered.
In that moment, I became an atheist.
I said, any god that could allow
what I comprehended,
there couldn't be a god.
And I became
an intense atheist,
not an amateur.
In order to be something,
you better become an expert
at what you're going to be.
Catholic theology, et cetera.
So I knew what my enemy was.
I could ridicule
the reasons that prove
the existence of God from
first cause.
Give me a break, first cause.
It still gives me a laugh.
That which is eternal
couldn't possibly have a cause,
much less a first cause.
I was very anti-religious.
Intensely anti-religious.
I didn't hate God.
I was just anti-religious.
Absurd.
So I understand the skeptics
when they ridicule faith in God,
religion and all.
I went through it.
It's sort of an adolescent phase.
If you haven't been an atheist
in one time in adolescence,
you're probably not scheduled
for enlightenment.
Why?
Because you didn't care enough about it.
It's like a person who's never gotten angry
is not going to become heavenly
because if you don't care enough about life
you don't care about the facts.
There was still a drive
to know the truth.
That's why I became an atheist.
I became an atheist because
I was driven like a mania
to discover the truth behind existence,
the truth of reality,
the truth of creation.
And the belief in God didn't serve anymore.
So God went down
as a consequence
of my pursuit for truth.
And
this led to an inner search
and sort of an endless despair.
And I went to
the very bottom,
the serious source of the ego itself,
the source of human existence
and the source of human awareness
of its own existence.
So I dove into the depths
of the inner realm
of the existential self
and in searching I then went into
a state of hell.
Profound hell
of endless spiritual agony.
The upper levels of hell
are people being tortured and all that.
That's jacks for openers.
It's not even getting serious yet.
Beyond
the agony, beyond the
screaming torment and all that
begins the real hell.
The real hell is dread beyond
description.
Because it's characterized by an
absolute hopelessness
and you understand
what hopeless is
and you understand what forever is
because in this hope
you are condemned to this hopeless
agony forever.
And you get what
forever means.
And then the real dread hits.
To abandon all
hope, ye who enter here.
Dante knew that. I don't know how he knew that.
But on that level, that's
annoyingness. Once you pass
this barrier, there
is no hope for all
eternity. All
eternity. All eternity.
Forever. You realize
what that means.
Never ever will you
again have the chance to experience
the light. In the depths of
that absolute despair
which is timeless.
Just like the highest states went on
forever, this state
went on forever.
Eons. In the
bottom of the pit
I said, if there is a God
I ask him for help.
Then I went blank.
When they came to
me, the entire universe
had totally changed.
The exquisite presence of all
that exists as divinity.
What I'm looking at now
is divinity
expressed as all of you
here know.
The divinity of all that
exists shines forth
with a shocking emergence
beyond words, beyond description.
It's as though the
everything radiates out
the essence of that which it is.
The greenness of the flower
shines forth
as a presence.
The essence of all that exists
shines forth via its essence.
And you see
the divinity of all
of creation.
The essence of all
that exists is divine.
So when we lick our attachments
to the linear perception
then you become aware
of the divinity
of the essence of all
that exists.
Therefore,
your life is conducted
at all times
in the presence of God.
At all times you are in
the presence of God.
It's just that you fail to recognize it.
And when you recognize it
you see the divinity of all that exists.
The infinite potential
of creation.
You see that evolution and creation
are one and the same thing.
Evolution is what creation looks like.
Religionists tend to think
there was a God.
First there was nothing.
Then suddenly there was a God.
He rolled out the dice
and then he took off on vacation.
So the bottom-up theory
of creation and the top-down
theories of creation
are still looking at God
and that which is forever
has no beginning.
It has no ending.
It has no start.
It has no source.
It has no cause.
There is no first principle to God.
That which has been forever
has no beginning.
So there's no point to look
for the cause of the beginning
which is bad enough to look
for cause in the Newtonian dimension
of the mid-400s
when spiritual realities don't get serious
over and over.
Alright, so let's go
and you'll have to let me know
when it's break time.
Oh good, alright.
So we were just saying
what got me going on this whole thing
was the archangel.
Sorry, I lost my place here somewhere.
I got up to archangel
and next thing you know
I took off in a different realm.
Archangels calibrate 50,000 and up.
So
in the pit of hell
which I don't know how I got there
but I got there
the prayer went up.
If there is a God I hear him
I ask him for help.
At that level of hell apparently
it takes an archangel to pay attention to you
because an archangel paid attention
to the thought.
That archangel calibrated 50,000.
We're talking a lot of rhythmic.
That's a lot of juice, 50,000.
So I pictured this archangel
I heard this goofball
agonizing
with his karmic watch and said
and out of that came the transformation
that stands before you
this day.
Don't mess with archangels.
Alright, we'll go on to the next slide.
This is just a calibration
of the energy
somebody figured out mathematically
the relative energies
as you go up the scale of consciousness.
We'll go to the next one.
This is the distribution
of the level of consciousness
which helps you understand this world.
There's no point of bemoaning this world
when you see that
approximately 80% of the world's population
calibrates below 200.
Therefore
truth does not prevail
in 80% of mankind.
You want to negotiate
with people who don't believe in honesty or truth?
That's what we're trying to do
all over the world all the time.
They think it'd be good
if mankind is just stupid.
Alright, so
this is the mass of mankind.
So you see the levels
here, how few people there are
even at the level of the intellect, 400.
Certainly the mid-intellect
500 people that are motivated
by lovingness
and you see that enlightenment
is almost an impossibility.
There are only a couple of people on the planet
at any one time
in the higher levels.
Unconditional love
the 12 step groups
0.4%
and only a few
people ever hit 600
which is the level of
divine infinite bliss
Sat Chit Ananda
and half of them leave at that point.
There are very few left
because half leave at 600
and as it goes up, half leave.
One characteristic of those states
is the state of infinite wonderment
and bliss and complete and total
there's nothing you want
there's nothing you need
your condition is complete and total
and fine
and if the body topples over
you have a strange
there's a strange permission to leave
and it recurs every once in a while
sometimes very unexpectedly
suddenly the state of bliss
just becomes overwhelming
and you could leave
I could have left this morning
I'm walking around
and we're all breaking down with tears of joy
I just left
I had permission to leave
I could go
but then what about the people
sitting around waiting for you to talk
it's always something
something
duck pecking at your ankle
okay
well
because of the people's love
you can't leave them
that's what it's about
so
you continue to live
so here's the distribution of mankind
you understand now
the evening paper
and the news
78% of the world population
only 22%
is over the low
is interested in truth
these are the only people
that are interested in truth
the other people are interested in
a reinforcement of their preference
they want you to prove
that what they believe in is true
so people who can't do kinesiology
can't do it
because they cannot seem to detach
and become objective
what they should say is
first let's see what the truth is
and then I'll decide what I want to do about it
but no they don't want to do it that way
they want to rig the bet
so that they find reinforcement
of what they want to believe
alright we'll move on
so you see the power
it's the power of these people here
that counterbalance it
you say why doesn't the world self-destruct
make energy
so these people are numerous
but personally they have very little power
to move things
what keeps the world from destructing them
is what's going on here
what is the consciousness of mankind right now
ah
the consciousness of mankind overall
is over 202
we were up to 207 for a while folks
we went down to 204
we went up to 205
when we spoke in San Francisco
right at the time of the Harmonic Concordance
right during a class
we clocked it
right during the class Harmonic Concordance
remember it went up
and I was a little disappointed
I thought it was going to continue up
no it went back down again
so what's America right now
let's see America right now
is over 421
oops 421
America right now is over 420
it went down again
426 it was 426
well
you bad folks better quit sinning out there
alright so mankind
we'll get to mankind in a while
we'll move on
let's move on to the next one
this is the percent of elapsed time
the level of consciousness
we'll go to the next one
those of us who have been here before
this is tracing the evolution of consciousness over time
over great eons of time
you see the light
of divinity
there's first the Godhead
out of which emerges God
out of which emerges creation
which shines forth as the radiation
the infinite power
of consciousness
and when consciousness
interacts with
any matter
it emerges as life
life itself cannot be destroyed
let's get that one
for sure
life itself cannot be destroyed
resist
so you can quit worrying about death
because there isn't any
life cannot be destroyed
the law of conservation of energy
the law of conservation of matter
and it just amazes me
the law of conservation of life
you can make life
change form
but you cannot kill it
so you can stop feeling guilty
about swatting flies
I was an intensive Buddhist for a long time
and the patient would leave my office
and I had a
butterfly net behind the drapes
as soon as the patient
we did a 50 minute hour
I take this thing out
and I catch these flies in the middle
and I put them out the window
because I didn't want to kill a fly
I didn't want a patient seeing me do that
they didn't know I was a Buddhist
and I didn't believe in killing anything
including flies
well
let's see what actually happens
when you kill a fly
it doesn't even notice it
you kill a fly
it goes right along flying
in its etheric body
and it doesn't realize anything has changed
the fact that you don't see it
is not his problem
those of you who have been out of body
know what I am talking about
you go out of body
it happened to me spontaneously
I never heard about it
I was sick as a dog
and there I am suddenly
ten feet over my body
there is Dave up in the air
no there is Dave down there
there is me
I can hear
when you are out of body
you can see, think, feel, hear
all the senses are operative
how can that be
I am way up here in the room
the body is over there
I can hear, think, feel
everything perfectly
didn't even notice it
one minute you are in the body
the next minute you are out
you have no point of worrying about it
ok
we see how consciousness evolved
over great eons of time
the light of divinity
shining forth as the energy field
consciousness itself
accompanies
enters organic matter
the lowest level of consciousness
is that we can find
what calibrates as one
is that of the bacteria
then you see the evolution of consciousness
through the animal kingdom
over great periods of time
don't let me forget the bacteria
later
now here we go
over millions of earth ages
and we see
we see the reptiles
the dinosaurs
we see the calibrated level of life
in these various epochs
it rises
let's move on to the next one
it rises through the animal kingdom
rises through the animal
we are tracing the evolution of consciousness
the spirit, the soul, the essence
of life itself
goes through these various forms
there is bacteria
etwan
then protozoa, crustaceans, insects
octopuses
those are the most amazing animals
sharks, vipers
can you imagine somebody put his foot in
the pen of a komodo dragon
I think he did it in California
then we get the predatory mammals
alligators
whales
we move up through
what?
we don't want to hear about dolphins
and whales please
we don't want any more emails
one caliber is higher than the other
ask your mother
I don't know
ask God don't ask me
ok so you'll notice
these are primarily predators
are they not
hippopotamuses kill a lot of people
you wouldn't think so
they don't look smart enough
below 200
life is lived by virtue
of the death of others
the dinosaur has to kill others to eat
the tiger has to
so below 200
is predatory
in the animal world
also in the human world
below 200 is predatory
it reacts
like an instinctual animal
game
and if you have to lose your life
too bad
then at consciousness level 200
we see a shift
from that which lives carnivorously
to the herbivore
the zebra
the giraffe
the deer
the bison
piggies, elk, sheep
you see they live
not by the death of others
in fact they fertilize everything
that furnishes the source of life for others
and we move up to
kitties at 240
family kitties
race horses, dogs, family dogs
we move up to the highest levels
the monkeys, the gorilla
chimpanzees
cocos, the trained gorilla
calibrates at 405
you are very safe in a cage
of a gorilla
and you are not safe with 85%
of humans alive today
coco will not hurt you at all
coco will be happy
so you can teach coco words
and the two most
amazing things
are the cats
the cat's purr
is at 500
and the dog's wagging tail is at 500
they are man's best friends
why is that?
because they respond to essence
we've got a new kitty at home
and when I come over
and I merely intend
to start petting the kitty
it instantly starts to purr
it's like you can turn it on a long distance
I come in like this
and I think of kitty
and I think of petting kitty
and the girls in the office will say
he's purring already
and of course the dog
instantly knows
when I treated lots and lots of patients
I had a lot
I practiced 50 years
and I would have depressed people
living alone
and I told them if you don't get a dog or a cat
I can't treat you
no, because that person is so narcissistic
they can't even take care of a pet
there is no way they are going to heal
they are going to sit there and wallow
in their narcissistic self indulgent grief
and resentment and self pity
I said well I'll treat you if you get a dog
one lady said no
she hated dogs
I said you'll have to find another doctor
that's a fact
the incapacity, the refusal to love
and the refusal of love
in its most appealing form
means such a degree of narcissism
and selfishness
that you're not going to be able to relate
so because part of helping a patient
is a positive transference
faith in the energy that you put forth for them
they're not going to form a positive transference
with you
if they're not going to care about a vibing dog
they're not going to care about you
so one of the levers you have to get patients better
is the transference
and of course you use it
and the transference is
one of the things that's non-linear
so
scientific inquiry
is a lot of it is quite skeptical
and frankly rather dumb
and it's because
it confines itself to the
linear domain
it has to do with the non-linear
it has to do with context
so reality has to do with essence
which has to do with context
and the trouble with the scoffer and the skeptic
is they're sticking to low levels of
mentation
and they're sticking to just the
linear pedestrian level
so that's the story on animals
and
I think it's quite interesting
we have an African parrot at home
Dr. Kalmbach gave it to me
where is
Broccoli
Broccoli's consciousness level
is currently over 350
she's up to 365
she ain't the brightest bird on the planet
but
Susan teaches her
funny songs all the time
what are you teaching her now
jingle bells, she's teaching her jingle bells
so we'll go to the next one
the great books of the world
so we were talking about
what is the significance of the level
this is the 400s
I want to watch the time
what time do we have to take a break
this is going to cover centuries
of the world's greatest wisdom
it'll only take us a few minutes
it's called
the great books of the western world
this is what I grew up
to think is a liberal education
a liberal education
is one in which
you discover
this is the content of your college education
that you're at least familiar
with the gist, the thrust
the impact
you get
you get the levels of truth
the levels of
contextualization
and you don't make
foolish statements
the world right now is full of relativists
who all calibrate at 190
and they can't even stay with one single subject
you know
they can't stay
within the same category of thought
so here's the greatest names
in all of
recent history
you see Darwin is at 450
so
this is the level of causality
Descartes
who I quote quite a bit
is at 490
he differentiated
the difference between appearance
and reality
the difference between appearance and essence
Immanuel Kant
all the great names here
are in the mid 400s
this I happen to have
a set which I picked up at a very good buy
there's only two things wrong with it
you see
the average is about 450 to 460
suddenly you see
Karl Marx at 130
there you see the introduction of relativism
and its impact in the modern world
historically we see the impact of
calibrated 130
you know
a million Chinese die of starvation
etc
we see the fallacy of low 130
if you try to institute it as a political
social
legal reality
and he wrote it with Engels
who was at 200
Engels just didn't know any better
at 200 he thought Marx sounded good
so he went along with it
but here's the great minds of history
so
to argue with
absolutism then
arguments would have to start
around the mid 400s
because all the
philosophic discussions of today's
news etc
so called postmodern relativism etc
you know
is about a 190
you can't even argue with
with absolutism
until you start coming from
an argument that calibrates at least
450 or 460
so we'll go to the next slide
most of the arguments
of the modern world
were settled in about 350 BC
I don't know what happened
in schooling that they haven't learned that
everything that they're studying there
was settled
about 350 BC
somehow
they haven't gotten the word
this is the
context
this is the content
this is approximate field
ok one last slide
and then we stop
the content is the ego
it's linear
this is what we call the ego
in scientific world we say
it's Newtonian world
it's placed in time and location
and it's provable
and if we compare that with
context you see
context is the opposite
it's non-linear it's unlimited
it's spiritual
you can verify it but you can't prove it
you can know it by becoming it
and it's non-local
it's enough to give you a headache
just thinking about all that
I'm sorry I went into it so much folks
but I just had to do it
you know because
I have a certain obsessive impulsive
academic trend
that I'm struggling to overcome
but I feel an obligation
there are actually real intellectuals
out there who are actually
legitimately interested in finding truth
for its own sake
and therefore for their sake
I say those things so that I can sleep well
how long do we have for a break?
we'll be back in about
15-20 minutes