So
heaven
The
The phenomena
The phenomena of
The phenomena of paying
The phenomena of paying attention
phenomena
phenomena of
The phenomena of paying attention
phenomena of paying
phenomena of paying attention
The phenomena of paying attention
phenomena of paying attention is
automatic
because
because the
automatic
because the ego
because the ego is
automatic
because the ego is feeding
because the ego is feeding on
automatic
because the ego is feeding on data
because the ego is feeding on data and
it's
it's always
it's always looking
it's always looking for
it's always looking for data
and
and that's
it's always looking for data
and that's a
and that's a con
it's always looking for data
and that's a con that
and that's a con that that's
it's always looking for data
and that's a con that that's a
and that's a con that that's a quality
of
of the
of the ego.
of the ego. You
of the ego. You don't
of the ego. You don't claim
of the ego. You don't claim credit
of the ego. You don't claim credit for
your
your heart
of the ego. You don't claim credit for
your heart beating
your heart beating all
of the ego. You don't claim credit for
your heart beating all the
your heart beating all the time.
of the ego. You don't claim credit for
your heart beating all the time. You
say,
say, "Well,
say, "Well, I'm
say, "Well, I'm making
say, "Well, I'm making my
say, "Well, I'm making my heart
say, "Well, I'm making my heart beat."
You
You don't
say, "Well, I'm making my heart beat."
You don't say
You don't say that,
say, "Well, I'm making my heart beat."
You don't say that, do
You don't say that, do you?
Take
Take the
Take the same
Take the same attitude
Take the same attitude towards
Take the same attitude towards mental
mental
mental phenomena
Take the same attitude towards mental
mental phenomena as
mental phenomena as you
Take the same attitude towards mental
mental phenomena as you do
mental phenomena as you do towards
physical.
Rarely
Rarely do
physical.
Rarely do you
Rarely do you decide
physical.
Rarely do you decide to
Rarely do you decide to do
physical.
Rarely do you decide to do something
physically.
physically. You
physically. You think
physically. You think you
physically. You think you do
physically. You think you do it
physically. You think you do it all
physically. You think you do it all the
time.
time. It's
physically. You think you do it all the
time. It's rare.
time. It's rare. It's
physically. You think you do it all the
time. It's rare. It's so
time. It's rare. It's so rare
physically. You think you do it all the
time. It's rare. It's so rare that
time. It's rare. It's so rare that when
it
it happens,
it happens, you
it happens, you notice
it happens, you notice it.
The
The phenomenon
it happens, you notice it.
The phenomenon are
The phenomenon are happening
autonomously
autonomously in
autonomously in this
autonomously in this ego
autonomously in this ego self
autonomously in this ego self that
autonomously in this ego self that is
called
called I.
autonomously in this ego self that is
called I. What
called I. What it
autonomously in this ego self that is
called I. What it does
called I. What it does is
autonomously in this ego self that is
called I. What it does is constantly
claim
claim credit
claim credit as
claim credit as author.
claim credit as author. It
claim credit as author. It claims
claim credit as author. It claims credit
of
of author.
claim credit as author. It claims credit
of author. It's
of author. It's the
claim credit as author. It claims credit
of author. It's the author
of author. It's the author of
claim credit as author. It claims credit
of author. It's the author of your
experience.
experience. It's
experience. It's who
experience. It's who you
experience. It's who you think
experience. It's who you think you
experience. It's who you think you are.
So
So that's
experience. It's who you think you are.
So that's the
So that's the leading
experience. It's who you think you are.
So that's the leading edge
So that's the leading edge of
experience. It's who you think you are.
So that's the leading edge of the
So that's the leading edge of the ego.
And
And the
And the only
And the only way
And the only way you
And the only way you can
And the only way you can go
And the only way you can go beyond
And the only way you can go beyond it
And the only way you can go beyond it is
to
to realize
And the only way you can go beyond it is
to realize the
to realize the presence
And the only way you can go beyond it is
to realize the presence of
to realize the presence of yourself
with
with a
with a capital
with a capital S
with a capital S as
with a capital S as the
with a capital S as the field
with a capital S as the field in
with a capital S as the field in which
this
this phenomena
with a capital S as the field in which
this phenomena is
this phenomena is happening
spontaneously.
You
You stop
spontaneously.
You stop looking
You stop looking at
spontaneously.
You stop looking at the
You stop looking at the event
spontaneously.
You stop looking at the event and
You stop looking at the event and you
look
look at
look at the
look at the field
look at the field and
look at the field and you
look at the field and you realize
look at the field and you realize you
are
are the
look at the field and you realize you
are the field
and
and that
and that this
and that this sense
and that this sense of
and that this sense of a
and that this sense of a personal
and that this sense of a personal eye
and that this sense of a personal eye is
a
a propensity
and that this sense of a personal eye is
a propensity that
a propensity that is
and that this sense of a personal eye is
a propensity that is arising
a propensity that is arising in
and that this sense of a personal eye is
a propensity that is arising in the
field.
its
its degree
field.
its degree of
its degree of likelihood
field.
its degree of likelihood increases
its degree of likelihood increases the
lower
lower the
lower the level
lower the level of
lower the level of consciousness
lower the level of consciousness and
decreases.
decreases. So
lower the level of consciousness and
decreases. So as
decreases. So as consciousness
lower the level of consciousness and
decreases. So as consciousness evolves,
it
it begins
it begins to
it begins to spontaneously
it begins to spontaneously intuit
it begins to spontaneously intuit it
it begins to spontaneously intuit it and
sense
that
that it
that it is
that it is not
that it is not its
that it is not its own
that it is not its own mother
that it is not its own mother and
father.
There
There would
There would have
There would have to
There would have to be
There would have to be a
There would have to be a mother
There would have to be a mother and
father
father of
There would have to be a mother and
father of the
father of the mother
There would have to be a mother and
father of the mother and
father of the mother and father.
There would have to be a mother and
father of the mother and father. You
father of the mother and father. You see
by
by infinite
by infinite regression
by infinite regression you
by infinite regression you would
by infinite regression you would say
by infinite regression you would say and
then
then and
by infinite regression you would say and
then and then
then and then and
by infinite regression you would say and
then and then and then
then and then and then what
by infinite regression you would say and
then and then and then what and
then and then and then what and so
by infinite regression you would say and
then and then and then what and so how
does
does this
does this sense
does this sense of
does this sense of self
does this sense of self even
does this sense of self even arise?
Enlightenment
Enlightenment is
does this sense of self even arise?
Enlightenment is the
Enlightenment is the dropping
does this sense of self even arise?
Enlightenment is the dropping of
Enlightenment is the dropping of a
does this sense of self even arise?
Enlightenment is the dropping of a sense
of
of personal
of personal self
of personal self as
of personal self as the
of personal self as the determiner
of personal self as the determiner of
behaviors
behaviors and
of personal self as the determiner of
behaviors and decisions
behaviors and decisions and
of personal self as the determiner of
behaviors and decisions and who
behaviors and decisions and who you
of personal self as the determiner of
behaviors and decisions and who you are
and
and you
and you begin
and you begin to
and you begin to see
and you begin to see that
and you begin to see that you
and you begin to see that you are
and you begin to see that you are the
field.
The
The phenomena
The phenomena of
The phenomena of the
The phenomena of the Olympics
The phenomena of the Olympics is
The phenomena of the Olympics is a
The phenomena of the Olympics is a whole
energy
energy field
The phenomena of the Olympics is a whole
energy field is
energy field is it
The phenomena of the Olympics is a whole
energy field is it not?
energy field is it not? People
The phenomena of the Olympics is a whole
energy field is it not? People feel
energy field is it not? People feel that
certain
certain sense
certain sense the
certain sense the minute
certain sense the minute they
certain sense the minute they turn
certain sense the minute they turn the
TV
TV on
certain sense the minute they turn the
TV on to
TV on to the
certain sense the minute they turn the
TV on to the because
TV on to the because they
certain sense the minute they turn the
TV on to the because they picked
TV on to the because they picked up
certain sense the minute they turn the
TV on to the because they picked up the
field.
field. There's
field. There's no
field. There's no no
field. There's no no performers
field. There's no no performers there
yet,
yet, nothing
field. There's no no performers there
yet, nothing happening,
yet, nothing happening, but
field. There's no no performers there
yet, nothing happening, but they've
already
already picked
already picked up
already picked up on
already picked up on the
already picked up on the field.
already picked up on the field. So
already picked up on the field. So you
begin
begin to
already picked up on the field. So you
begin to instead
begin to instead of
already picked up on the field. So you
begin to instead of looking
begin to instead of looking for
specifics,
you
you look
specifics,
you look more
you look more for
specifics,
you look more for a
you look more for a generality,
you
you begin
you begin to
you begin to sense
you begin to sense and
you begin to sense and begin
you begin to sense and begin to
you begin to sense and begin to identify
with
with the
you begin to sense and begin to identify
with the field
with the field with
you begin to sense and begin to identify
with the field with the
with the field with the field.
you begin to sense and begin to identify
with the field with the field. And
with the field with the field. And you
realize
realize that
realize that decisions
are
are made
realize that decisions
are made within
are made within the
realize that decisions
are made within the field
are made within the field and
realize that decisions
are made within the field and then
are made within the field and then the
field
field influences
field influences the
field influences the likelihood
field influences the likelihood of
field influences the likelihood of the
phenomena
phenomena happening
field influences the likelihood of the
phenomena happening uh
phenomena happening uh within
field influences the likelihood of the
phenomena happening uh within the
phenomena happening uh within the linear
domain.
domain. The
domain. The decision
domain. The decision to
domain. The decision to be
domain. The decision to be forgiving
increases
increases the
domain. The decision to be forgiving
increases the likelihood
increases the likelihood of
domain. The decision to be forgiving
increases the likelihood of forgiveness
but
but it
but it doesn't
but it doesn't cause
but it doesn't cause it.
You
You say
but it doesn't cause it.
You say when
You say when you
but it doesn't cause it.
You say when you get
You say when you get up
but it doesn't cause it.
You say when you get up this
You say when you get up this morning,
dear
dear God,
dear God, help
dear God, help please
dear God, help please help
dear God, help please help me
dear God, help please help me to
dear God, help please help me to be
forgiving
forgiving to
dear God, help please help me to be
forgiving to myself
forgiving to myself and
dear God, help please help me to be
forgiving to myself and and
forgiving to myself and and and
everyone.
That
That doesn't
everyone.
That doesn't mean
That doesn't mean you
everyone.
That doesn't mean you haven't
That doesn't mean you haven't just
everyone.
That doesn't mean you haven't just made
it
it happen.
it happen. You
it happen. You haven't
it happen. You haven't determined
it happen. You haven't determined it
happen.
happen. All
it happen. You haven't determined it
happen. All you've
happen. All you've done
it happen. You haven't determined it
happen. All you've done is
happen. All you've done is increased
it happen. You haven't determined it
happen. All you've done is increased the
likelihood
likelihood of
likelihood of this
likelihood of this event
likelihood of this event being
recontextualized
recontextualized in
likelihood of this event being
recontextualized in such
recontextualized in such a
likelihood of this event being
recontextualized in such a way
recontextualized in such a way that
likelihood of this event being
recontextualized in such a way that you
see
see there's
see there's nothing
see there's nothing to
see there's nothing to forgive.
Each
Each thing
see there's nothing to forgive.
Each thing is
Each thing is only
see there's nothing to forgive.
Each thing is only being
Each thing is only being what
see there's nothing to forgive.
Each thing is only being what it
Each thing is only being what it is.
Each
Each thing
Each thing is
Each thing is only
Each thing is only being
Each thing is only being what
Each thing is only being what it
Each thing is only being what it is,
including
including being
Each thing is only being what it is,
including being wrong.
The
The ego
The ego loves
The ego loves to
The ego loves to be
The ego loves to be right.
So
So you
The ego loves to be right.
So you see
So you see the
The ego loves to be right.
So you see the seduction
So you see the seduction of
The ego loves to be right.
So you see the seduction of being
So you see the seduction of being right
and
and you
and you see
and you see how
and you see how the
and you see how the ego
and you see how the ego falls
and you see how the ego falls into
and you see how the ego falls into it.
So
So what
and you see how the ego falls into it.
So what happens
So what happens is
and you see how the ego falls into it.
So what happens is you
So what happens is you become
and you see how the ego falls into it.
So what happens is you become too
sophisticated,
sophisticated, too
sophisticated, too spiritually
sophisticated
and
and irriodite
to
to fall
and irriodite
to fall for
to fall for the
and irriodite
to fall for the ego
to fall for the ego anymore.
and irriodite
to fall for the ego anymore. I
to fall for the ego anymore. I think
that's
that's what
that's what happens.
that's what happens. You
that's what happens. You become
that's what happens. You become so
sophisticated
that
that you've
that you've learned
that you've learned its
that you've learned its nature
that you've learned its nature and
that you've learned its nature and you
then
then refuse
that you've learned its nature and you
then refuse it.
And
And when
And when you
And when you get
And when you get to
And when you get to the
And when you get to the core
And when you get to the core of
And when you get to the core of the
And when you get to the core of the ego,
as
as I've
And when you get to the core of the ego,
as I've told
as I've told you
And when you get to the core of the ego,
as I've told you before,
you've
you've surrendered
you've surrendered all
you've surrendered all the
you've surrendered all the illusions
you've surrendered all the illusions of
causality
causality and
you've surrendered all the illusions of
causality and personal
causality and personal identity
you've surrendered all the illusions of
causality and personal identity and
causality and personal identity and all
these
these things.
You
You then
these things.
You then exist
You then exist in
these things.
You then exist in an
You then exist in an infinite
these things.
You then exist in an infinite silence.
Infinite
Infinite silence.
Infinite silence. The
And
And then
Infinite silence. The
And then the
And then the knowingness
Infinite silence. The
And then the knowingness comes
that
that the
that the one
that the one thing
that the one thing you're
that the one thing you're hanging
that the one thing you're hanging on
that the one thing you're hanging on to.
You
You you
that the one thing you're hanging on to.
You you thought
You you thought you've
that the one thing you're hanging on to.
You you thought you've let
You you thought you've let go
that the one thing you're hanging on to.
You you thought you've let go of
everything.
You
You haven't
everything.
You haven't let
You haven't let go
everything.
You haven't let go of
You haven't let go of everything.
everything.
You haven't let go of everything. You've
let
let go
let go of
let go of life.
let go of life. You
let go of life. You haven't
let go of life. You haven't let
let go of life. You haven't let go
let go of life. You haven't let go of
life.
You
You still
You still think
You still think that
You still think that you
You still think that you are
You still think that you are the
You still think that you are the source
of
of your
You still think that you are the source
of your life.
of your life. And
You still think that you are the source
of your life. And without
of your life. And without you
You still think that you are the source
of your life. And without you being
watchful
watchful of
watchful of it,
watchful of it, your
watchful of it, your life
watchful of it, your life will
disappear.
The
The last
The last great
The last great illusion
The last great illusion experientially
the
the experiential
The last great illusion experientially
the experiential reality
the experiential reality of
The last great illusion experientially
the experiential reality of this
particular
particular speaker
particular speaker was
particular speaker was all
particular speaker was all had
particular speaker was all had been
released.
released. All
particular speaker was all had been
released. All had
released. All had been
particular speaker was all had been
released. All had been surrendered.
There
There was
There was only
There was only infinite
power
power and
There was only infinite
power and knowingness.
There
There came
There came the
There came the temptation
to
to own
There came the temptation
to own the
to own the power.
All
All power
All power is
All power is yours.
All power is yours. Claim
All power is yours. Claim it.
That
That was
All power is yours. Claim it.
That was the
That was the la
All power is yours. Claim it.
That was the la the
That was the la the the
All power is yours. Claim it.
That was the la the the luciferic
temptation
temptation came
temptation came almost
temptation came almost at
temptation came almost at the
temptation came almost at the last
minute.
minute. Silent
temptation came almost at the last
minute. Silent unspoken
minute. Silent unspoken as
temptation came almost at the last
minute. Silent unspoken as a
knowingness.
All
All power
knowingness.
All power is
All power is yours.
knowingness.
All power is yours. Claim
All power is yours. Claim it.
You're
You're not
You're not answerable
You're not answerable to
You're not answerable to anyone.
You're not answerable to anyone. Karma,
you're
you're beyond
You're not answerable to anyone. Karma,
you're beyond karma.
Those
Those are
Those are all
Those are all illusions.
In
In the
Those are all illusions.
In the silence
In the silence came
Those are all illusions.
In the silence came the
In the silence came the knowingness.
All
All power
All power is
All power is yours.
All power is yours. You
All power is yours. You can
All power is yours. You can see
All power is yours. You can see how
All power is yours. You can see how love
once
once you
All power is yours. You can see how love
once you surrender
once you surrender love,
All power is yours. You can see how love
once you surrender love, you
once you surrender love, you could
All power is yours. You can see how love
once you surrender love, you could do
anything
anything to
anything to anybody,
anything to anybody, couldn't
anything to anybody, couldn't you?
anything to anybody, couldn't you? It's
actually
actually that
anything to anybody, couldn't you? It's
actually that innate
actually that innate love
anything to anybody, couldn't you? It's
actually that innate love we
actually that innate love we have
anything to anybody, couldn't you? It's
actually that innate love we have for
our
our fellow
our fellow human
our fellow human being
our fellow human being that
our fellow human being that makes
our fellow human being that makes us
hold
hold back
our fellow human being that makes us
hold back at
hold back at the
our fellow human being that makes us
hold back at the last
hold back at the last moment
unless
unless we're
unless we're way
unless we're way below
unless we're way below 200.
And
And then
unless we're way below 200.
And then when
And then when that
unless we're way below 200.
And then when that was
And then when that was silenced,
unless we're way below 200.
And then when that was silenced, it
And then when that was silenced, it was
as
as I
as I say,
as I say, it
as I say, it was
as I say, it was like
as I say, it was like a
as I say, it was like a high
as I say, it was like a high alpine
space,
space, very
as I say, it was like a high alpine
space, very rarified.
Hardly
Hardly anybody
Hardly anybody had
Hardly anybody had ever
Hardly anybody had ever been
Hardly anybody had ever been there.
Hardly anybody had ever been there. You
could
could see
Hardly anybody had ever been there. You
could see who'd
could see who'd been
Hardly anybody had ever been there. You
could see who'd been there
could see who'd been there and
Hardly anybody had ever been there. You
could see who'd been there and you
could see who'd been there and you could
see
see what
see what they'd
see what they'd said
see what they'd said by
see what they'd said by saying,
see what they'd said by saying, "See,
see what they'd said by saying, "See, I
mean,
mean, knowing
see what they'd said by saying, "See, I
mean, knowing this,
mean, knowing this, you
see what they'd said by saying, "See, I
mean, knowing this, you felt
mean, knowing this, you felt the
see what they'd said by saying, "See, I
mean, knowing this, you felt the energy
of
of those
of those who'
of those who' been
of those who' been there."
of those who' been there." And
of those who' been there." And uh
of those who' been there." And uh so
what
what would
of those who' been there." And uh so
what would a
what would a person
of those who' been there." And uh so
what would a person want
what would a person want power
of those who' been there." And uh so
what would a person want power for?
It
It would
It would be
It would be a
It would be a drag,
It would be a drag, wouldn't
It would be a drag, wouldn't it?
I
I consider
It would be a drag, wouldn't it?
I consider it
I consider it a
It would be a drag, wouldn't it?
I consider it a drag.
There's
There's nothing
There's nothing worse
There's nothing worse than
There's nothing worse than having
There's nothing worse than having power
over
over others.
There's nothing worse than having power
over others. I
over others. I mean,
There's nothing worse than having power
over others. I mean, how
over others. I mean, how would
There's nothing worse than having power
over others. I mean, how would you
over others. I mean, how would you like
to
to have
to have power
to have power over
to have power over everybody?
to have power over everybody? I
to have power over everybody? I mean,
you
you just
to have power over everybody? I mean,
you just think
you just think of
to have power over everybody? I mean,
you just think of the
you just think of the karma
to have power over everybody? I mean,
you just think of the karma of
you just think of the karma of it
to have power over everybody? I mean,
you just think of the karma of it on
you just think of the karma of it on top
of
of it.
So,
So, power
of it.
So, power over
So, power over others
of it.
So, power over others was
So, power over others was practically
the
the last
the last thing.
the last thing. And
the last thing. And when
the last thing. And when it
the last thing. And when it disappeared,
there
there remained
the last thing. And when it disappeared,
there remained only
only
only life
only life itself.
The
The awareness
only life itself.
The awareness arose.
The
The one
The one thing
The one thing you're
The one thing you're clinging
The one thing you're clinging to
The one thing you're clinging to is
life.
life. Life.
The
The ego
The ego thinks
The ego thinks that
The ego thinks that it
The ego thinks that it is
The ego thinks that it is the
The ego thinks that it is the author
The ego thinks that it is the author of
your
your life.
The ego thinks that it is the author of
your life. If
your life. If it's
The ego thinks that it is the author of
your life. If it's the
your life. If it's the author
The ego thinks that it is the author of
your life. If it's the author of
your life. If it's the author of your
thoughts,
thoughts, actions,
thoughts, actions, and
thoughts, actions, and everything
thoughts, actions, and everything else,
it
it naturally
thoughts, actions, and everything else,
it naturally thinks
it naturally thinks it's
thoughts, actions, and everything else,
it naturally thinks it's the
it naturally thinks it's the author
thoughts, actions, and everything else,
it naturally thinks it's the author of
your
your existence.
your existence. So,
your existence. So, the
your existence. So, the very
your existence. So, the very core
your existence. So, the very core of
your existence. So, the very core of the
ego
ego arose.
And
And then
And then came
And then came the
And then came the knowingness
And then came the knowingness to
surrender
surrender life
And then came the knowingness to
surrender life itself.
And
And I
And I and
And I and then
And I and then came
And I and then came a
And I and then came a terror
And I and then came a terror a
And I and then came a terror a terror.
The
The ego's
And I and then came a terror a terror.
The ego's existence
The ego's existence is
And I and then came a terror a terror.
The ego's existence is anchored
The ego's existence is anchored in
And I and then came a terror a terror.
The ego's existence is anchored in a
profound
belief
belief system
profound
belief system that
belief system that has
profound
belief system that has gone
belief system that has gone on
profound
belief system that has gone on for
millennia.
And
And up
millennia.
And up came
the
the eye
the eye as
the eye as the
the eye as the core
the eye as the core and
the eye as the core and essence
the eye as the core and essence and
source
source of
the eye as the core and essence and
source of your
source of your life.
This
This too,
This too, oh
This too, oh Lord,
This too, oh Lord, this
This too, oh Lord, this too
This too, oh Lord, this too must
This too, oh Lord, this too must be
laid.
laid. And
This too, oh Lord, this too must be
laid. And then
laid. And then with
This too, oh Lord, this too must be
laid. And then with terror
laid. And then with terror the
This too, oh Lord, this too must be
laid. And then with terror the dread
came
came up,
came up, the
came up, the fear
came up, the fear came
came up, the fear came up
came up, the fear came up in
came up, the fear came up in droves,
millennia
millennia of
came up, the fear came up in droves,
millennia of time.
And
And the
And the knowingness,
And the knowingness, the
And the knowingness, the frequency,
And the knowingness, the frequency, the
vibration
vibration of
And the knowingness, the frequency, the
vibration of the
vibration of the energy
And the knowingness, the frequency, the
vibration of the energy and
vibration of the energy and the
And the knowingness, the frequency, the
vibration of the energy and the aura
vibration of the energy and the aura of
the
the enlightened
the enlightened being
the enlightened being from
the enlightened being from whom
the enlightened being from whom I'd
picked
picked it
the enlightened being from whom I'd
picked it up
picked it up in
the enlightened being from whom I'd
picked it up in some
picked it up in some lifetime
the enlightened being from whom I'd
picked it up in some lifetime came
through
through as
through as a
through as a knowingness
that
that all
through as a knowingness
that all fear
that all fear is
through as a knowingness
that all fear is illusion.
that all fear is illusion. All
through as a knowingness
that all fear is illusion. All fear
that all fear is illusion. All fear is
illusion.
All
All fear
illusion.
All fear is
All fear is illusion.
Then
Then the
Then the trust
Then the trust in
Then the trust in the
Then the trust in the absoluteness
Then the trust in the absoluteness of
that
that teaching
Then the trust in the absoluteness of
that teaching comes
that teaching comes from
Then the trust in the absoluteness of
that teaching comes from the
that teaching comes from the power
Then the trust in the absoluteness of
that teaching comes from the power of
certainty.
certainty. And
certainty. And that's
certainty. And that's what
certainty. And that's what a
certainty. And that's what a false
teacher
teacher cannot
certainty. And that's what a false
teacher cannot give
teacher cannot give you.
certainty. And that's what a false
teacher cannot give you. It
teacher cannot give you. It has
certainty. And that's what a false
teacher cannot give you. It has to
teacher cannot give you. It has to be
the
the power
the power of
the power of absolute
the power of absolute certainty
that
that you
the power of absolute certainty
that you can
that you can lay
the power of absolute certainty
that you can lay down
that you can lay down your
the power of absolute certainty
that you can lay down your life.
Instantly
Instantly the
Instantly the door
Instantly the door to
Instantly the door to eternity
Instantly the door to eternity opened
Instantly the door to eternity opened up
and
the
the terror
the terror went
the terror went away.
the terror went away. Huh?
the terror went away. Huh? Then
the terror went away. Huh? Then was
the terror went away. Huh? Then was the
infinite
infinite stillness
the terror went away. Huh? Then was the
infinite stillness of
infinite stillness of the
the terror went away. Huh? Then was the
infinite stillness of the infinite
presence
presence of
presence of all
presence of all of
presence of all of of
presence of all of of everythingness
presence of all of of everythingness is
divinity.
divinity. So
presence of all of of everythingness is
divinity. So the
divinity. So the divinity
presence of all of of everythingness is
divinity. So the divinity of
divinity. So the divinity of all
presence of all of of everythingness is
divinity. So the divinity of all of
creation
creation shines
creation shines forth
and
and you're
creation shines forth
and you're unable
and you're unable to
creation shines forth
and you're unable to function
and you're unable to function for
creation shines forth
and you're unable to function for quite
a
a while.
Now
Now what?
Because
Because there
Because there is
Because there is no
Because there is no personal
Because there is no personal self
Because there is no personal self from
which
which to
Because there is no personal self from
which to guide
which to guide the
Because there is no personal self from
which to guide the functioning
which to guide the functioning of
Because there is no personal self from
which to guide the functioning of the
body.
body. Even
body. Even that
body. Even that is
body. Even that is problematic.
body. Even that is problematic. And
body. Even that is problematic. And it
walks
walks about
body. Even that is problematic. And it
walks about spontaneously
walks about spontaneously like
body. Even that is problematic. And it
walks about spontaneously like a
walks about spontaneously like a top.
Like
Like you
Like you see
Like you see it
Like you see it walk
Like you see it walk about
Like you see it walk about like
Like you see it walk about like a
Like you see it walk about like a top
right
right now.
Like you see it walk about like a top
right now. It
right now. It walks
Like you see it walk about like a top
right now. It walks around
right now. It walks around like
Like you see it walk about like a top
right now. It walks around like a
right now. It walks around like a top.
It
It does
It does what
It does what the
It does what the heck
It does what the heck it's
It does what the heck it's going
It does what the heck it's going to
It does what the heck it's going to do.
I
I don't
It does what the heck it's going to do.
I don't know
I don't know anything
It does what the heck it's going to do.
I don't know anything to
I don't know anything to do
It does what the heck it's going to do.
I don't know anything to do with
I don't know anything to do with it.
How
How would
How would I
How would I know
How would I know what
How would I know what it's
How would I know what it's going
How would I know what it's going to
How would I know what it's going to do?
You
You know
How would I know what it's going to do?
You know what I'm
You know what I'm saying?
How would I know what it's going to do?
You know what I'm saying? The
presumption
presumption that
presumption that I
presumption that I know
presumption that I know what
presumption that I know what it's
presumption that I know what it's going
to
to do
presumption that I know what it's going
to do and
to do and I'm
presumption that I know what it's going
to do and I'm determining
to do and I'm determining what
presumption that I know what it's going
to do and I'm determining what it's
going
going to
going to do
going to do would
going to do would reinforce
going to do would reinforce the
going to do would reinforce the belief
that
that I
going to do would reinforce the belief
that I am
that I am the
going to do would reinforce the belief
that I am the decider.
that I am the decider. That's
going to do would reinforce the belief
that I am the decider. That's the
that I am the decider. That's the innate
portion
portion of
portion of the
portion of the ego.
portion of the ego. It's
portion of the ego. It's not
portion of the ego. It's not only
portion of the ego. It's not only the
creator
creator of
portion of the ego. It's not only the
creator of your
creator of your life.
portion of the ego. It's not only the
creator of your life. It's
creator of your life. It's the
portion of the ego. It's not only the
creator of your life. It's the decider
of
of your
of your actions.
of your actions. And
of your actions. And you
of your actions. And you see
of your actions. And you see that
of your actions. And you see that the
ego
ego is
of your actions. And you see that the
ego is the
ego is the inner
of your actions. And you see that the
ego is the inner majesty.
It's
It's a
It's a majesty.
Majesty.
Now
Now you
Now you understand
Now you understand messianic
Now you understand messianic narcissism.
You
You see
Now you understand messianic narcissism.
You see these
You see these crazy
Now you understand messianic narcissism.
You see these crazy rulers.
You see these crazy rulers. I
Now you understand messianic narcissism.
You see these crazy rulers. I will
You see these crazy rulers. I will kill
300 million.
300 million. Saul.
Some
Some have
300 million. Saul.
Some have killed
Some have killed 100
300 million. Saul.
Some have killed 100 million.
Some have killed 100 million. Saul.
300 million. Saul.
Some have killed 100 million. Saul. They
deserved
deserved it.
The
The death
deserved it.
The death of
The death of a
deserved it.
The death of a 100
The death of a 100 million
deserved it.
The death of a 100 million people
The death of a 100 million people means
nothing.
nothing. And
nothing. And when
nothing. And when brought
nothing. And when brought to
nothing. And when brought to court,
nothing. And when brought to court, they
stick
stick out
nothing. And when brought to court, they
stick out their
stick out their tongue,
nothing. And when brought to court, they
stick out their tongue, drop
stick out their tongue, drop their
pants,
pants, and
pants, and show
pants, and show the
pants, and show the rear
pants, and show the rear to
pants, and show the rear to the
pants, and show the rear to the judge
who
who orders
pants, and show the rear to the judge
who orders them
who orders them out
pants, and show the rear to the judge
who orders them out of
who orders them out of court.
pants, and show the rear to the judge
who orders them out of court. Yeah.
The
The value
The value of
The value of these
The value of these uh
The value of these uh trials
is
is that
The value of these uh trials
is that you
is that you see
The value of these uh trials
is that you see the
is that you see the core
The value of these uh trials
is that you see the core of
is that you see the core of the
The value of these uh trials
is that you see the core of the ego
blatantly
blatantly displayed
blatantly displayed for
blatantly displayed for you.
blatantly displayed for you. You
blatantly displayed for you. You say
that's
that's them.
blatantly displayed for you. You say
that's them. No,
that's them. No, that's
blatantly displayed for you. You say
that's them. No, that's your
that's them. No, that's your ego.
Without
Without love,
Without love, you
Without love, you would
Without love, you would also
Without love, you would also slaughter
100 million
100 million people.
Without love, you would also slaughter
100 million people. The
100 million people. The constraint
Without love, you would also slaughter
100 million people. The constraint is
with
with love,
with love, you
with love, you can't
with love, you can't do
with love, you can't do it.
That's
That's why
with love, you can't do it.
That's why the
That's why the luciferic
with love, you can't do it.
That's why the luciferic says,
That's why the luciferic says, "Forget
love.
love. It's
love. It's just
love. It's just a
love. It's just a limitation."
I
I had
love. It's just a limitation."
I had a
I had a teacher
love. It's just a limitation."
I had a teacher actually
I had a teacher actually tell
love. It's just a limitation."
I had a teacher actually tell me
I had a teacher actually tell me that
and
and he
and he became
and he became Lucifer
and he became Lucifer and
and he became Lucifer and he
and he became Lucifer and he was
calibrated
calibrated high
and he became Lucifer and he was
calibrated high and
calibrated high and he
and he became Lucifer and he was
calibrated high and he crashed
calibrated high and he crashed very
and he became Lucifer and he was
calibrated high and he crashed very low.
Love
Love is
Love is just
Love is just an
Love is just an attachment.
Personal
love
love is
love is an
love is an attachment.
Divine
Divine love
love is an attachment.
Divine love is
Divine love is a
love is an attachment.
Divine love is a quality
Divine love is a quality of
love is an attachment.
Divine love is a quality of divinity.
Quality
Quality of
Quality of divinity.
Quality of divinity. So
Quality of divinity. So when
Quality of divinity. So when you
surrender
surrender and
Quality of divinity. So when you
surrender and release
surrender and release on
Quality of divinity. So when you
surrender and release on a
surrender and release on a quality
invalidate
invalidate a
invalidate a quality
invalidate a quality of
invalidate a quality of divinity,
invalidate a quality of divinity, you
just
just rejected
love
love as
love as one
love as one of
love as one of the
love as one of the innate
love as one of the innate qualities
love as one of the innate qualities of
divinity.
And
And therefore
And therefore he
And therefore he crashed.
And therefore he crashed. He
And therefore he crashed. He crashed.
He
He crashed.
And therefore he crashed. He crashed.
He crashed. and
He crashed. and with
And therefore he crashed. He crashed.
He crashed. and with them
He crashed. and with them crash
And therefore he crashed. He crashed.
He crashed. and with them crash lava
students
some
some of
students
some of which
some of which run
students
some of which run five
some of which run five or
students
some of which run five or six
some of which run five or six pro
students
some of which run five or six pro a
some of which run five or six pro a day
that's
that's a
that's a very
that's a very important
that's a very important error
that's a very important error not
that's a very important error not to
make
make all
that's a very important error not to
make all love
make all love emanates
that's a very important error not to
make all love emanates from
make all love emanates from divinity
what
what you
what you want
what you want to
what you want to transcend
what you want to transcend is
what you want to transcend is attachment
I
I can't
what you want to transcend is attachment
I can't live
I can't live without
having
having that
having that person
having that person controlling
having that person controlling that
person
person etc
so
so by
so by becoming
so by becoming acquainted
so by becoming acquainted with
so by becoming acquainted with the
nature
nature of
so by becoming acquainted with the
nature of the
nature of the ego
so by becoming acquainted with the
nature of the ego you're
nature of the ego you're in
so by becoming acquainted with the
nature of the ego you're in You
nature of the ego you're in You begin
so by becoming acquainted with the
nature of the ego you're in You begin to
automatically
automatically transcend
automatically transcend it.
automatically transcend it. Having
automatically transcend it. Having heard
these
these words,
automatically transcend it. Having heard
these words, having
these words, having heard
automatically transcend it. Having heard
these words, having heard these
these words, having heard these words,
you
you are
you are already
you are already transcending
you are already transcending the
personal
personal ego
you are already transcending the
personal ego to
personal ego to a
you are already transcending the
personal ego to a greater
personal ego to a greater degree
you are already transcending the
personal ego to a greater degree than
you
you were.
you were. As
you were. As we
you were. As we said,
you were. As we said, because
you were. As we said, because it's
you were. As we said, because it's in
the
the field
you were. As we said, because it's in
the field now,
the field now, because
you were. As we said, because it's in
the field now, because it's
the field now, because it's in
you were. As we said, because it's in
the field now, because it's in the
field,
field, you
field, you don't
field, you don't have
field, you don't have to
field, you don't have to pay
field, you don't have to pay attention
to
to it
field, you don't have to pay attention
to it all
to it all the
field, you don't have to pay attention
to it all the time.
to it all the time. It
field, you don't have to pay attention
to it all the time. It begins
to it all the time. It begins to
field, you don't have to pay attention
to it all the time. It begins to move
to it all the time. It begins to move to
to
to work
to work on
to work on its
to work on its own.
to work on its own. To
to work on its own. To have
to work on its own. To have heard
to work on its own. To have heard that
within
within the
to work on its own. To have heard that
within the field
within the field with
to work on its own. To have heard that
within the field with absolute
within the field with absolute certainty
already
already changes
already changes outcomes.
already changes outcomes. Do
already changes outcomes. Do you
understand
understand what
already changes outcomes. Do you
understand what I'm
understand what I'm saying?
because
because the
because the overall
because the overall field
because the overall field then
because the overall field then begins
because the overall field then begins to
influence.
influence. So
because the overall field then begins to
influence. So when
influence. So when you're
because the overall field then begins to
influence. So when you're trying
influence. So when you're trying to
change
change a
change a behavior,
change a behavior, counting
change a behavior, counting it
change a behavior, counting it every
time
time that
change a behavior, counting it every
time that it
time that it occurs,
even
even though
even though you
even though you don't
even though you don't attempt
even though you don't attempt to
even though you don't attempt to change
the
the behavior,
even though you don't attempt to change
the behavior, it's
the behavior, it's already
even though you don't attempt to change
the behavior, it's already changing.
It's
It's already
It's already changing.
Just
Just the
It's already changing.
Just the knowingness
Just the knowingness be,
It's already changing.
Just the knowingness be, you
Just the knowingness be, you know,
pervades
pervades one's
pervades one's aura
pervades one's aura and
pervades one's aura and already
pervades one's aura and already you
begin
begin to
pervades one's aura and already you
begin to experience
begin to experience the
pervades one's aura and already you
begin to experience the personal
begin to experience the personal self
differently.
First
First of
differently.
First of all,
First of all, you're
differently.
First of all, you're not
First of all, you're not at
differently.
First of all, you're not at the
First of all, you're not at the effect.
You're
You're not
You're not the
You're not the slave
You're not the slave of
You're not the slave of it.
You're not the slave of it. It's
You're not the slave of it. It's not
You're not the slave of it. It's not who
you
you are.
You're not the slave of it. It's not who
you are. It's
you are. It's an
You're not the slave of it. It's not who
you are. It's an option.
you are. It's an option. It's
You're not the slave of it. It's not who
you are. It's an option. It's an
you are. It's an option. It's an option.
Oh,
Oh, to
Oh, to feel
Oh, to feel that
Oh, to feel that I
Oh, to feel that I am
Oh, to feel that I am who
Oh, to feel that I am who I
Oh, to feel that I am who I am
Oh, to feel that I am who I am is
Oh, to feel that I am who I am is only
an
an option.
Oh, to feel that I am who I am is only
an option. Heck,
an option. Heck, I
Oh, to feel that I am who I am is only
an option. Heck, I thought
an option. Heck, I thought it
Oh, to feel that I am who I am is only
an option. Heck, I thought it was
an option. Heck, I thought it was a
certainty.
certainty. I
certainty. I thought
certainty. I thought you're
certainty. I thought you're born
certainty. I thought you're born with
it.
it. You
certainty. I thought you're born with
it. You know,
it. You know, you
certainty. I thought you're born with
it. You know, you come
it. You know, you come into
certainty. I thought you're born with
it. You know, you come into the
it. You know, you come into the world
and
and blubber
and blubber and
and blubber and carry
and blubber and carry on
and blubber and carry on like
and blubber and carry on like that.
That's
That's the
and blubber and carry on like that.
That's the worst
That's the worst part
and blubber and carry on like that.
That's the worst part of
That's the worst part of getting
and blubber and carry on like that.
That's the worst part of getting reborn.
I
I really
I really wouldn't
I really wouldn't want
I really wouldn't want to
first
first first
I really wouldn't want to
first first 50
first first 50 years
I really wouldn't want to
first first 50 years are
first first 50 years are tough.
I really wouldn't want to
first first 50 years are tough. I
first first 50 years are tough. I tell
you
you life
you life doesn't
you life doesn't get
you life doesn't get better
you life doesn't get better till
you life doesn't get better till you
you life doesn't get better till you at
least
least 50.
you life doesn't get better till you at
least 50. I'll
least 50. I'll tell
you life doesn't get better till you at
least 50. I'll tell you
least 50. I'll tell you how
you life doesn't get better till you at
least 50. I'll tell you how people
least 50. I'll tell you how people get
through
through to
through to 50
through to 50 be
through to 50 be compassion
through to 50 be compassion for
through to 50 be compassion for mankind.
Seeing
Seeing what
through to 50 be compassion for mankind.
Seeing what it
Seeing what it takes
through to 50 be compassion for mankind.
Seeing what it takes to
Seeing what it takes to get
through to 50 be compassion for mankind.
Seeing what it takes to get there
Seeing what it takes to get there before
the
the great
the great heroes
the great heroes of
the great heroes of wisdom
the great heroes of wisdom start
the great heroes of wisdom start keeping
you
you from
the great heroes of wisdom start keeping
you from putting
you from putting your
the great heroes of wisdom start keeping
you from putting your foot
you from putting your foot in
the great heroes of wisdom start keeping
you from putting your foot in the
putting
putting put
putting put your
putting put your foot
putting put your foot in
putting put your foot in the
putting put your foot in the crank
again.
Uh,
Uh, so
Uh, so in
Uh, so in the
Uh, so in the old
Uh, so in the old days,
Uh, so in the old days, the
Uh, so in the old days, the old
Uh, so in the old days, the old model
Uh, so in the old days, the old model A
model
model T
Uh, so in the old days, the old model A
model T for
model T for it,
Uh, so in the old days, the old model A
model T for it, it
model T for it, it had
Uh, so in the old days, the old model A
model T for it, it had a
model T for it, it had a crank,
Uh, so in the old days, the old model A
model T for it, it had a crank, you
know,
know, you
know, you crank
know, you crank it
know, you crank it and
know, you crank it and you
know, you crank it and you had
know, you crank it and you had to
know, you crank it and you had to be
careful
careful because
know, you crank it and you had to be
careful because the
careful because the kickback
know, you crank it and you had to be
careful because the kickback would
careful because the kickback would break
your
your arm.
your arm. So
you
you learn
your arm. So
you learn to
you learn to avoid
your arm. So
you learn to avoid the
you learn to avoid the model
your arm. So
you learn to avoid the model T4s.
All right.
All right. So
All right. So wisdom
is
is wisdom
All right. So wisdom
is wisdom accrs.
Every
Every spiritual
teacher
teacher you
Every spiritual
teacher you listen
teacher you listen to,
Every spiritual
teacher you listen to, every
teacher you listen to, every book
Every spiritual
teacher you listen to, every book you
read,
read, every
read, every spiritual
read, every spiritual person
read, every spiritual person you
encounter
encounter is
read, every spiritual person you
encounter is already
encounter is already advancing
read, every spiritual person you
encounter is already advancing your
field.
field. It's
field. It's advancing
field. It's advancing your
field. It's advancing your field.
field. It's advancing your field. They
say
say hang
field. It's advancing your field. They
say hang out
say hang out with
field. It's advancing your field. They
say hang out with holy
say hang out with holy company.
field. It's advancing your field. They
say hang out with holy company. It
say hang out with holy company. It means
that
that the
that the field
that the field itself
that the field itself is
that the field itself is supportive.
That's
That's the
that the field itself is supportive.
That's the charge
That's the charge you
that the field itself is supportive.
That's the charge you feel.
That's the charge you feel. For
instance,
instance, when
instance, when you
instance, when you turn
instance, when you turn in
instance, when you turn in on
instance, when you turn in on the
Olympics,
Olympics, you're
instance, when you turn in on the
Olympics, you're picking
Olympics, you're picking up
instance, when you turn in on the
Olympics, you're picking up the
Olympics, you're picking up the energy
of
of the
of the Olympics.
of the Olympics. You
of the Olympics. You know,
of the Olympics. You know, you
of the Olympics. You know, you feel
of the Olympics. You know, you feel an
excitement
excitement and
of the Olympics. You know, you feel an
excitement and a
excitement and a certain
of the Olympics. You know, you feel an
excitement and a certain charge
and
and there's
and there's nobody
and there's nobody even
and there's nobody even on
and there's nobody even on the
and there's nobody even on the screen
yet.
yet. It's
and there's nobody even on the screen
yet. It's just
yet. It's just the
and there's nobody even on the screen
yet. It's just the announcer
yet. It's just the announcer and
and there's nobody even on the screen
yet. It's just the announcer and now
tonight
tonight will
tonight will resume
tonight will resume and
tonight will resume and so
tonight will resume and so and
tonight will resume and so and so
tonight will resume and so and so and
already
already you're
tonight will resume and so and so and
already you're feeling
already you're feeling that
tonight will resume and so and so and
already you're feeling that surge
already you're feeling that surge of
tonight will resume and so and so and
already you're feeling that surge of the
sense
sense of
sense of the
sense of the energy.
sense of the energy. Just
sense of the energy. Just the
sense of the energy. Just the same
sense of the energy. Just the same as
when
when you
sense of the energy. Just the same as
when you walk
when you walk into
sense of the energy. Just the same as
when you walk into one
when you walk into one of
sense of the energy. Just the same as
when you walk into one of the
when you walk into one of the great
cathedrals
cathedrals in
cathedrals in the
cathedrals in the world
cathedrals in the world when
cathedrals in the world when you
cathedrals in the world when you look
cathedrals in the world when you look in
the
the pyramids
cathedrals in the world when you look in
the pyramids of
the pyramids of Eg
cathedrals in the world when you look in
the pyramids of Eg in
the pyramids of Eg in pyramids
cathedrals in the world when you look in
the pyramids of Eg in pyramids in
the pyramids of Eg in pyramids in Egypt.
I
I meditated
I meditated in
I meditated in um
I meditated in um most
I meditated in um most people
I meditated in um most people meditate
in
in the
I meditated in um most people meditate
in the first
in the first try
I meditated in um most people meditate
in the first try to
in the first try to meditate
I meditated in um most people meditate
in the first try to meditate in
in the first try to meditate in the
first
first pyramid.
first pyramid. There's
first pyramid. There's too
first pyramid. There's too much
first pyramid. There's too much traffic
in
in the
first pyramid. There's too much traffic
in the first
in the first pyramid
first pyramid. There's too much traffic
in the first pyramid plus
in the first pyramid plus it
first pyramid. There's too much traffic
in the first pyramid plus it smells
in the first pyramid plus it smells bad.
There's
There's a
There's a sarcophagus
There's a sarcophagus that
There's a sarcophagus that people
There's a sarcophagus that people have
peed
peed in
There's a sarcophagus that people have
peed in for
peed in for a thousand
There's a sarcophagus that people have
peed in for a thousand years.
peed in for a thousand years. There's
There's a sarcophagus that people have
peed in for a thousand years. There's no
restroom,
restroom, you
restroom, you know,
restroom, you know, and
restroom, you know, and you
restroom, you know, and you hunt
restroom, you know, and you hunt 400
restroom, you know, and you hunt 400 ft
up
up through
restroom, you know, and you hunt 400 ft
up through this
up through this thing.
restroom, you know, and you hunt 400 ft
up through this thing. You
up through this thing. You aren't
restroom, you know, and you hunt 400 ft
up through this thing. You aren't about
to
to walk
to walk back
to walk back out
to walk back out to
to walk back out to go
to walk back out to go to
to walk back out to go to the
to walk back out to go to the bathroom.
So,
So, I'm
to walk back out to go to the bathroom.
So, I'm sure
So, I'm sure there's
to walk back out to go to the bathroom.
So, I'm sure there's some
So, I'm sure there's some people
to walk back out to go to the bathroom.
So, I'm sure there's some people that
But
But you
But you know
But you know what,
But you know what, too?
Egyptians
Egyptians are
But you know what, too?
Egyptians are funny.
Egyptians are funny. It's,
But you know what, too?
Egyptians are funny. It's, you
Egyptians are funny. It's, you know,
people
people write
people write graffiti
people write graffiti on
people write graffiti on on
people write graffiti on on the
people write graffiti on on the wall
people write graffiti on on the wall and
they
they just
people write graffiti on on the wall and
they just leave
they just leave it.
people write graffiti on on the wall and
they just leave it. Anybody
they just leave it. Anybody else
people write graffiti on on the wall and
they just leave it. Anybody else want
they just leave it. Anybody else want to
erase
erase it,
erase it, you
erase it, you know,
erase it, you know, like
erase it, you know, like remember
erase it, you know, like remember it
said
said in
erase it, you know, like remember it
said in Korean
said in Korean some
erase it, you know, like remember it
said in Korean some guy's
said in Korean some guy's name
erase it, you know, like remember it
said in Korean some guy's name 1937,
said in Korean some guy's name 1937, the
Egyptians
Egyptians just
Egyptians just leave
Egyptians just leave it
Egyptians just leave it there.
Anyway,
Anyway, you
Egyptians just leave it there.
Anyway, you sense
Anyway, you sense the
Egyptians just leave it there.
Anyway, you sense the the
Anyway, you sense the the energy
Egyptians just leave it there.
Anyway, you sense the the energy and
Anyway, you sense the the energy and the
grandeur
grandeur of
grandeur of all
grandeur of all that
grandeur of all that exists
grandeur of all that exists uh
grandeur of all that exists uh despite
superficial
superficial existence.
You
You get
You get the
You get the feeling
You get the feeling of
You get the feeling of the
You get the feeling of the sacrificial
energy.
energy. the
You get the feeling of the sacrificial
energy. the sacrificial
energy. the sacrificial energy.
You get the feeling of the sacrificial
energy. the sacrificial energy. So
energy. the sacrificial energy. So those
who
who make
who make sacrificial
who make sacrificial commitments
who make sacrificial commitments etc
who make sacrificial commitments etc to
further
further the
who make sacrificial commitments etc to
further the evolution
further the evolution of
who make sacrificial commitments etc to
further the evolution of their
consciousness.
consciousness. I
consciousness. I mean
consciousness. I mean like
consciousness. I mean like a
consciousness. I mean like a contender
in
in the
consciousness. I mean like a contender
in the Olympics
in the Olympics certainly
consciousness. I mean like a contender
in the Olympics certainly does
in the Olympics certainly does make
consciousness. I mean like a contender
in the Olympics certainly does make a
commitment
commitment and
commitment and you
commitment and you you
commitment and you you you
commitment and you you you sense
commitment and you you you sense the
sacrificial
sacrificial core
commitment and you you you sense the
sacrificial core of
sacrificial core of it
commitment and you you you sense the
sacrificial core of it as
sacrificial core of it as well.
commitment and you you you sense the
sacrificial core of it as well. I
sacrificial core of it as well. I say
they
they all
they all do
they all do it
they all do it for
they all do it for God
they all do it for God whether
they all do it for God whether they're
consciousness
consciousness conscious
they all do it for God whether they're
consciousness conscious of
consciousness conscious of it
they all do it for God whether they're
consciousness conscious of it or
consciousness conscious of it or not.
And
And of
And of course,
And of course, how
And of course, how many
And of course, how many fall
And of course, how many fall to
And of course, how many fall to their
knees
knees after
And of course, how many fall to their
knees after their
knees after their performance?
That's
That's very
That's very heartwarming
That's very heartwarming too,
That's very heartwarming too, is
That's very heartwarming too, is it
That's very heartwarming too, is it not?
You
You see,
That's very heartwarming too, is it not?
You see, after
You see, after their
That's very heartwarming too, is it not?
You see, after their performance,
You see, after their performance, they
cross
cross themsel
cross themsel and
cross themsel and you
cross themsel and you see
cross themsel and you see great
cross themsel and you see great sports
figures
figures do
cross themsel and you see great sports
figures do that.
figures do that. Gratitude.
So
So one
So one essence
So one essence then
So one essence then is
So one essence then is gratitude,
humility
to
to witness
to witness the
to witness the sacredness
to witness the sacredness of
to witness the sacredness of all
to witness the sacredness of all that
exists.
To
To get
To get a
To get a sense
To get a sense of
To get a sense of the
To get a sense of the eye,
To get a sense of the eye, who
To get a sense of the eye, who the
To get a sense of the eye, who the real
eye
eye is
To get a sense of the eye, who the real
eye is and
eye is and to
To get a sense of the eye, who the real
eye is and to realize
eye is and to realize that
To get a sense of the eye, who the real
eye is and to realize that the
eye is and to realize that the real
To get a sense of the eye, who the real
eye is and to realize that the real eye
is
is the
is the field,
is the field, the
is the field, the entire
is the field, the entire field
is the field, the entire field out
is the field, the entire field out of
which
which the
is the field, the entire field out of
which the sense
which the sense of
is the field, the entire field out of
which the sense of a
which the sense of a personal
is the field, the entire field out of
which the sense of a personal eye
crystallizes.
To
To get
crystallizes.
To get a
To get a jump
crystallizes.
To get a jump on
To get a jump on the
crystallizes.
To get a jump on the experiencer,
you
you have
you have to
you have to be
you have to be quick.
you have to be quick. It
you have to be quick. It happens
you have to be quick. It happens in
you have to be quick. It happens in one
10,000th
10,000th of
you have to be quick. It happens in one
10,000th of a
10,000th of a second.
you have to be quick. It happens in one
10,000th of a second. Within
10,000th of a second. Within 110,000
you have to be quick. It happens in one
10,000th of a second. Within 110,000 of
a
a second,
the
the sense
a second,
the sense of
the sense of I
a second,
the sense of I has
the sense of I has already
a second,
the sense of I has already claimed
credit
credit for
credit for moving
credit for moving the
credit for moving the arm.
credit for moving the arm. It's
credit for moving the arm. It's already
claimed
claimed credit.
It
It all
It all the
It all the time
It all the time believes
It all the time believes that
It all the time believes that it
It all the time believes that it is
It all the time believes that it is the
source
source of
It all the time believes that it is the
source of its
source of its own
It all the time believes that it is the
source of its own existence.
The
The core
The core of
The core of the
The core of the ego
The core of the ego then
is
is we
The core of the ego then
is we call
is we call egoomania
grandiosity.
And
And the
grandiosity.
And the core
And the core of
grandiosity.
And the core of the
And the core of the ego
grandiosity.
And the core of the ego is
And the core of the ego is it
grandiosity.
And the core of the ego is it that
And the core of the ego is it that it
thinks
thinks it
thinks it is
thinks it is God.
thinks it is God. It
thinks it is God. It does
thinks it is God. It does think
thinks it is God. It does think it
thinks it is God. It does think it is
God.
God. It
thinks it is God. It does think it is
God. It does.
God. It does. People
thinks it is God. It does think it is
God. It does. People say
God. It does. People say I
thinks it is God. It does think it is
God. It does. People say I don't
God. It does. People say I don't believe
that.
that. I
that. I said
that. I said who
that. I said who just
that. I said who just said
that. I said who just said that?
Who
Who just
that. I said who just said that?
Who just decided
Who just decided to
that. I said who just said that?
Who just decided to say
Who just decided to say that?
And
And now
And now the
And now the core
And now the core of
And now the core of the
And now the core of the narcissistic
And now the core of the narcissistic ego
is
is God.
And now the core of the narcissistic ego
is God. Therefore,
is God. Therefore, Nero
And now the core of the narcissistic ego
is God. Therefore, Nero and
is God. Therefore, Nero and all
And now the core of the narcissistic ego
is God. Therefore, Nero and all the
great
great egoomaniacs,
great egoomaniacs, iron,
great egoomaniacs, iron, the
great egoomaniacs, iron, the terrible
Henry
Henry VII,
great egoomaniacs, iron, the terrible
Henry VII, right
Henry VII, right down
great egoomaniacs, iron, the terrible
Henry VII, right down to
Henry VII, right down to the
great egoomaniacs, iron, the terrible
Henry VII, right down to the present
time,
time, Alesovich,
people
people on
time, Alesovich,
people on trial
people on trial now,
time, Alesovich,
people on trial now, heads
people on trial now, heads of
time, Alesovich,
people on trial now, heads of certain
nations
nations to
nations to tell
nations to tell the
nations to tell the tell
nations to tell the tell the
nations to tell the tell the whole
nations to tell the tell the whole world
to
to go
nations to tell the tell the whole world
to go to
to go to hell.
nations to tell the tell the whole world
to go to hell. They're
to go to hell. They're just
nations to tell the tell the whole world
to go to hell. They're just going
to go to hell. They're just going to
nations to tell the tell the whole world
to go to hell. They're just going to do
what
what they're
what they're going
what they're going to
what they're going to do.
How
How can
what they're going to do.
How can you
How can you speak
what they're going to do.
How can you speak rationally
How can you speak rationally to
what they're going to do.
How can you speak rationally to that
which
which is
which is coming
which is coming out
which is coming out of
which is coming out of such
which is coming out of such an
incredible
incredible egoomania?
How
How can
How can you
How can you tell
How can you tell somebody
How can you tell somebody who
How can you tell somebody who believes
that
that he's
How can you tell somebody who believes
that he's God
that he's God to
How can you tell somebody who believes
that he's God to be
that he's God to be humble
How can you tell somebody who believes
that he's God to be humble and
that he's God to be humble and deal
How can you tell somebody who believes
that he's God to be humble and deal with
other
other countries
other countries in
other countries in an
other countries in an even-handed
other countries in an even-handed way?
Sounds
Sounds nonsensical,
other countries in an even-handed way?
Sounds nonsensical, does
Sounds nonsensical, does it
other countries in an even-handed way?
Sounds nonsensical, does it not?
He
He goes
He goes home
He goes home and
He goes home and says,
He goes home and says, "Boy,
He goes home and says, "Boy, are
He goes home and says, "Boy, are they
idiots?"
idiots?" You
He goes home and says, "Boy, are they
idiots?" You know
idiots?" You know what
He goes home and says, "Boy, are they
idiots?" You know what I
idiots?" You know what I mean?
All
All right.
All right. So
you're
you're way
All right. So
you're way ahead
you're way ahead of
All right. So
you're way ahead of the
you're way ahead of the game
All right. So
you're way ahead of the game if
you're way ahead of the game if you
realize
realize that
realize that the
realize that the core
realize that the core of
realize that the core of the
realize that the core of the ego
realize that the core of the ego is
realize that the core of the ego is this
egoomaniac
that
that claims
that claims credit
that claims credit for
that claims credit for all
that claims credit for all decisions,
all
all thoughts.
that claims credit for all decisions,
all thoughts. It
all thoughts. It actually
that claims credit for all decisions,
all thoughts. It actually claims
all thoughts. It actually claims credit
for
for your
for your own
for your own existence.
It
It is
for your own existence.
It is because
It is because of
for your own existence.
It is because of I
It is because of I of
for your own existence.
It is because of I of I
that
that you
that you even
that you even exist.
So
So the
that you even exist.
So the fear
So the fear comes
that you even exist.
So the fear comes up.
So the fear comes up. If
that you even exist.
So the fear comes up. If I
So the fear comes up. If I surrender
that you even exist.
So the fear comes up. If I surrender the
source
source of
source of life,
source of life, then
source of life, then I
source of life, then I will
source of life, then I will die.
And
And you
source of life, then I will die.
And you do.
You
You think
You think you
You think you won't
You think you won't die,
You think you won't die, but
You think you won't die, but you
You think you won't die, but you do.
You think you won't die, but you do. The
ego
ego self
You think you won't die, but you do. The
ego self actually
ego self actually experiences
You think you won't die, but you do. The
ego self actually experiences death.
ego self actually experiences death. In
that
that instant,
that instant, you
that instant, you realize
that instant, you realize it
that instant, you realize it never
experienced
experienced death
that instant, you realize it never
experienced death ever.
experienced death ever. It
that instant, you realize it never
experienced death ever. It left
experienced death ever. It left the
that instant, you realize it never
experienced death ever. It left the body
of
of whatever
of whatever it
of whatever it was
of whatever it was at
of whatever it was at the
of whatever it was at the time
of whatever it was at the time from
salamander
salamander to
of whatever it was at the time from
salamander to peacock
to
to to
to to a
to to a sailor
to to a sailor or
to to a sailor or whatever
to to a sailor or whatever you
to to a sailor or whatever you were.
to to a sailor or whatever you were. And
it
it never
to to a sailor or whatever you were. And
it never once
it never once accepted
to to a sailor or whatever you were. And
it never once accepted its
it never once accepted its own
to to a sailor or whatever you were. And
it never once accepted its own the
it never once accepted its own the the
reality.
reality. It
reality. It always
reality. It always made
reality. It always made a
reality. It always made a certain
presumption
beyond
beyond all
beyond all time.
beyond all time. Then
beyond all time. Then the
beyond all time. Then the core
beyond all time. Then the core of
beyond all time. Then the core of the
ego
ego is
beyond all time. Then the core of the
ego is its
ego is its refusal
beyond all time. Then the core of the
ego is its refusal to
ego is its refusal to accept
beyond all time. Then the core of the
ego is its refusal to accept God
ego is its refusal to accept God as
beyond all time. Then the core of the
ego is its refusal to accept God as the
author
author of
author of existence.
It
It will
author of existence.
It will not
It will not accept
author of existence.
It will not accept that
It will not accept that to
author of existence.
It will not accept that to the
It will not accept that to the point
author of existence.
It will not accept that to the point of
death.
death. It
death. It will
death. It will not
death. It will not accept
death. It will not accept it
death. It will not accept it to
death. It will not accept it to the
death
death of
death. It will not accept it to the
death of all
death of all of
death. It will not accept it to the
death of all of its
death of all of its countrymen.
Any
Any one
Any one of
Any one of those
Any one of those that
Any one of those that you
Any one of those that you see
Any one of those that you see will
willingly
willingly slaughter
Any one of those that you see will
willingly slaughter their
willingly slaughter their entire
country.
They
They will
country.
They will willingly
They will willingly slaughter
country.
They will willingly slaughter all
They will willingly slaughter all of
mankind.
They
They will
mankind.
They will willingly
They will willingly let
mankind.
They will willingly let loose
They will willingly let loose a
mankind.
They will willingly let loose a dirty
nuclear
nuclear bomb
nuclear bomb just
nuclear bomb just out
nuclear bomb just out of
nuclear bomb just out of malevolence.
And
And I
nuclear bomb just out of malevolence.
And I scares
And I scares me
nuclear bomb just out of malevolence.
And I scares me when
And I scares me when I
nuclear bomb just out of malevolence.
And I scares me when I see
And I scares me when I see people
tempting
tempting them
tempting them to
tempting them to see
tempting them to see how
tempting them to see how far
tempting them to see how far they
tempting them to see how far they can
tempting them to see how far they can go
before
before they
tempting them to see how far they can go
before they do
before they do that.
They'll
They'll do
They'll do it
They'll do it just
They'll do it just for
They'll do it just for fun.
They'll do it just for fun. They
They'll do it just for fun. They don't
need
need an
They'll do it just for fun. They don't
need an excuse.
need an excuse. If
They'll do it just for fun. They don't
need an excuse. If there
need an excuse. If there is
They'll do it just for fun. They don't
need an excuse. If there is no
conscience,
conscience, then
conscience, then you
conscience, then you wouldn't
conscience, then you wouldn't need
reason,
reason, would
conscience, then you wouldn't need
reason, would you?
reason, would you? or
conscience, then you wouldn't need
reason, would you? or an
reason, would you? or an excuse.
You
You would
You would just
You would just do
You would just do that
You would just do that because
You would just do that because that's
your
your right,
You would just do that because that's
your right, sovereign
your right, sovereign right
You would just do that because that's
your right, sovereign right as
your right, sovereign right as God.
You would just do that because that's
your right, sovereign right as God. So
the
the ego's
problem
problem is
the ego's
problem is its
problem is its inability
the ego's
problem is its inability to
problem is its inability to admit
the ego's
problem is its inability to admit that
it
it is
it is not
it is not God.
That's
That's the
it is not God.
That's the whole
That's the whole core
it is not God.
That's the whole core of
That's the whole core of philosophic
relativism
relativism etc.
relativism etc. is
relativism etc. is the
relativism etc. is the illusion
relativism etc. is the illusion that
relativism etc. is the illusion that it
is
is the
relativism etc. is the illusion that it
is the core
is the core of
relativism etc. is the illusion that it
is the core of the
is the core of the ego
relativism etc. is the illusion that it
is the core of the ego that
is the core of the ego that is
relativism etc. is the illusion that it
is the core of the ego that is divinity.
Therefore,
Therefore, that's
Therefore, that's why
Therefore, that's why enlightenment
Therefore, that's why enlightenment is
so
so difficult
Therefore, that's why enlightenment is
so difficult to
so difficult to achieve
Therefore, that's why enlightenment is
so difficult to achieve because
that
that which
that which assumes
that which assumes it's
that which assumes it's in
that which assumes it's in divin
that which assumes it's in divin it
that which assumes it's in divin it is
divinity
will
will not
will not allow
will not allow for
will not allow for any
will not allow for any infringement.
It
It maintains
will not allow for any infringement.
It maintains its
It maintains its illusion
will not allow for any infringement.
It maintains its illusion of
It maintains its illusion of divinity
will not allow for any infringement.
It maintains its illusion of divinity no
matter
matter all
matter all the
matter all the confronting
matter all the confronting evidence.
matter all the confronting evidence. All
the
the confronting
matter all the confronting evidence. All
the confronting evidence.
It
It has
It has contempt
It has contempt for
It has contempt for confronting
evidence.
evidence. Ignorance
It has contempt for confronting
evidence. Ignorance has
evidence. Ignorance has certain
It has contempt for confronting
evidence. Ignorance has certain forms
evidence. Ignorance has certain forms of
ignorance
ignorance have
ignorance have contempt
ignorance have contempt for
ignorance have contempt for wisdom,
ignorance have contempt for wisdom, have
contempt
contempt for
uh
uh age,
uh age, have
uh age, have contempt
uh age, have contempt for
uh age, have contempt for truth.
uh age, have contempt for truth. A
uh age, have contempt for truth. A great
deal
deal of
uh age, have contempt for truth. A great
deal of the
deal of the world
uh age, have contempt for truth. A great
deal of the world has
deal of the world has contempt
uh age, have contempt for truth. A great
deal of the world has contempt for
truth.
truth. Contempt.
truth. Contempt. They'll
truth. Contempt. They'll go
truth. Contempt. They'll go out
truth. Contempt. They'll go out to
foreign
foreign countries
truth. Contempt. They'll go out to
foreign countries and
and
and heap
and heap contempt
and heap contempt against
and heap contempt against their
and heap contempt against their own
country,
country, their
and heap contempt against their own
country, their own
country, their own countrymen.
Raise
Raise their
Raise their man
Raise their man with
Raise their man with souls
Raise their man with souls who
Raise their man with souls who dead
Raise their man with souls who dead who
himself
himself has
Raise their man with souls who dead who
himself has not
himself has not said.
Raise their man with souls who dead who
himself has not said. This
himself has not said. This is
Raise their man with souls who dead who
himself has not said. This is my
himself has not said. This is my own
Raise their man with souls who dead who
himself has not said. This is my own my
native
native land.
native land. They're
native land. They're out
native land. They're out there.
native land. They're out there. You
native land. They're out there. You can
see
see them
native land. They're out there. You can
see them on
see them on television
native land. They're out there. You can
see them on television with
see them on television with soul
native land. They're out there. You can
see them on television with soul so
see them on television with soul so dead
calibrating
the
the bottom.
calibrating
the bottom. Huh?
The
The ego
The ego therefore
The ego therefore will
The ego therefore will not
The ego therefore will not stop
The ego therefore will not stop at
anything.
anything. You
The ego therefore will not stop at
anything. You can't
anything. You can't count
The ego therefore will not stop at
anything. You can't count the
anything. You can't count the common
sense
sense and
sense and the
sense and the ego
sense and the ego will
sense and the ego will stop
sense and the ego will stop an
sense and the ego will stop an asalent.
You
You cannot
sense and the ego will stop an asalent.
You cannot at
You cannot at all
sense and the ego will stop an asalent.
You cannot at all depend
You cannot at all depend on
sense and the ego will stop an asalent.
You cannot at all depend on that.
You cannot at all depend on that. It's
suicidal.
suicidal. Oh,
suicidal. Oh, at
suicidal. Oh, at the
suicidal. Oh, at the last
suicidal. Oh, at the last minute
suicidal. Oh, at the last minute he
suicidal. Oh, at the last minute he will
see
see the
suicidal. Oh, at the last minute he will
see the fallacy
see the fallacy and
suicidal. Oh, at the last minute he will
see the fallacy and the
see the fallacy and the foolishness
suicidal. Oh, at the last minute he will
see the fallacy and the foolishness of
setting
setting off,
you
you know,
setting off,
you know, destroying
you know, destroying all
setting off,
you know, destroying all of
you know, destroying all of Europe
setting off,
you know, destroying all of Europe or
something.
Don't
Don't count
something.
Don't count on
Don't count on it.
something.
Don't count on it. In
Don't count on it. In fact,
that
that makes
that makes it
that makes it more
that makes it more fun
that makes it more fun than
that makes it more fun than anything.
that makes it more fun than anything. If
you
you can
that makes it more fun than anything. If
you can wipe
you can wipe out
that makes it more fun than anything. If
you can wipe out all
you can wipe out all of
that makes it more fun than anything. If
you can wipe out all of Europe
you can wipe out all of Europe at
that makes it more fun than anything. If
you can wipe out all of Europe at the
same
same time,
same time, the
same time, the better.
That's
That's the
same time, the better.
That's the human
That's the human ego.
same time, the better.
That's the human ego. So,
That's the human ego. So, we
same time, the better.
That's the human ego. So, we see
That's the human ego. So, we see if
same time, the better.
That's the human ego. So, we see if you
can
can see
can see it
can see it out
can see it out there,
can see it out there, that's
can see it out there, that's because
it's
it's already
can see it out there, that's because
it's already within
it's already within you
can see it out there, that's because
it's already within you or
it's already within you or you
can see it out there, that's because
it's already within you or you couldn't
see
see it
see it out
see it out there.
The
The core
see it out there.
The core of
The core of the
see it out there.
The core of the ego
The core of the ego then
see it out there.
The core of the ego then doesn't
The core of the ego then doesn't care
see it out there.
The core of the ego then doesn't care of
anything
anything at
anything at all
anything at all about
anything at all about you.
anything at all about you. It's
anything at all about you. It's out
anything at all about you. It's out to
destroy
destroy you
anything at all about you. It's out to
destroy you so
destroy you so long
anything at all about you. It's out to
destroy you so long as
destroy you so long as it
anything at all about you. It's out to
destroy you so long as it can
destroy you so long as it can maintain
its
its sense
its sense of
its sense of sovereignty.
Radical
Radical reality
its sense of sovereignty.
Radical reality then
Radical reality then means
its sense of sovereignty.
Radical reality then means the
willingness
willingness to
willingness to surrender
willingness to surrender the
willingness to surrender the claim
willingness to surrender the claim to
sovereignty
of
of the
of the inner
of the inner sense
of the inner sense of
of the inner sense of a
of the inner sense of a personal
of the inner sense of a personal eye
of the inner sense of a personal eye and
surrender
surrender to
of the inner sense of a personal eye and
surrender to the
surrender to the field.
of the inner sense of a personal eye and
surrender to the field. Then
surrender to the field. Then ego
of the inner sense of a personal eye and
surrender to the field. Then ego says
surrender to the field. Then ego says if
you
you surrender
you surrender me
you surrender me to
you surrender me to the
you surrender me to the field
you surrender me to the field you'll
become
become nothing.
The
The truth
The truth is
The truth is if
The truth is if you
The truth is if you surrender
The truth is if you surrender me
The truth is if you surrender me to
The truth is if you surrender me to the
field,
field, you
The truth is if you surrender me to the
field, you become
field, you become everything.
>> You
>> You become
>> You become all
>> You become all of
>> You become all of it
>> You become all of it because
>> You become all of it because all
>> You become all of it because all of
>> You become all of it because all of it
and
and what
>> You become all of it because all of it
and what you
and what you are
>> You become all of it because all of it
and what you are are
and what you are are identical.
>> You become all of it because all of it
and what you are are identical. The
sense
sense of
sense of self,
what
what would
sense of self,
what would I
what would I do
sense of self,
what would I do without
what would I do without her?
sense of self,
what would I do without her? I
what would I do without her? I wouldn't
get
get through
get through tomorrow
get through tomorrow night,
get through tomorrow night, I'll
get through tomorrow night, I'll tell
you.
Yeah.
Yeah. What
Yeah. What about
Yeah. What about this
Yeah. What about this reality?
Yeah. What about this reality? Okay.
If
If you
Yeah. What about this reality? Okay.
If you haven't
If you haven't eaten
Yeah. What about this reality? Okay.
If you haven't eaten in
If you haven't eaten in a
Yeah. What about this reality? Okay.
If you haven't eaten in a couple
If you haven't eaten in a couple of
days,
days, she
days, she complains.
days, she complains. Yeah.
Thursday.
Thursday. Last
days, she complains. Yeah.
Thursday. Last day.
Thursday. Last day. Mon
days, she complains. Yeah.
Thursday. Last day. Mon Monday.
Thursday. Last day. Mon Monday. Okay.
So,
So, let's
So, let's see.
So, let's see. Uh
So, let's see. Uh we
So, let's see. Uh we will
So, let's see. Uh we will stop
So, let's see. Uh we will stop and
So, let's see. Uh we will stop and then
we
we will
So, let's see. Uh we will stop and then
we will resume
we will resume at
So, let's see. Uh we will stop and then
we will resume at what
we will resume at what time?
>> 2
>> 2 o'clock.
>> We
>> We will
>> 2 o'clock.
>> We will stop.
>> We will stop. We
>> 2 o'clock.
>> We will stop. We will
>> We will stop. We will then
>> 2 o'clock.
>> We will stop. We will then resume
>> We will stop. We will then resume at
>> 2 o'clock.
>> We will stop. We will then resume at 2
o'clock.
That
That was
o'clock.
That was really
That was really good.
>> Yeah,
>> it
>> it was
>> Yeah,
>> it was superb.
>> it was superb. It
>> Yeah,
>> it was superb. It was
>> it was superb. It was wonderful.
>> Uh
>> Uh Gail,
>> Uh Gail, are
>> Uh Gail, are you
>> Uh Gail, are you going
>> Uh Gail, are you going to
>> Uh Gail, are you going to talk
>> Uh Gail, are you going to talk first?
>> Go
>> Go ahead.
>> Uh Gail, are you going to talk first?
>> Go ahead. Right.
>> Good
>> Good afternoon.
Glad
Glad you're
>> Good afternoon.
Glad you're all
Glad you're all just
>> Good afternoon.
Glad you're all just want
Glad you're all just want to
>> Good afternoon.
Glad you're all just want to uh
Glad you're all just want to uh make
>> Good afternoon.
Glad you're all just want to uh make an
announcement
announcement that
announcement that in
announcement that in March
announcement that in March in
announcement that in March in the
announcement that in March in the second
Wednesday
Wednesday of
announcement that in March in the second
Wednesday of March
Wednesday of March we're
announcement that in March in the second
Wednesday of March we're meeting
Wednesday of March we're meeting here
and
and not
and not where
and not where we
and not where we did
and not where we did before
and not where we did before um
and not where we did before um in
and not where we did before um in terms
of
of having
and not where we did before um in terms
of having a
of having a question
and not where we did before um in terms
of having a question and
of having a question and answer
um
um discussion.
um discussion. So
um discussion. So if
um discussion. So if you
um discussion. So if you want
um discussion. So if you want more
information
information on
um discussion. So if you want more
information on that
information on that go
um discussion. So if you want more
information on that go to
information on that go to the
um discussion. So if you want more
information on that go to the website
information on that go to the website or
call
call the
call the center
call the center but
call the center but it's
call the center but it's not
call the center but it's not at
call the center but it's not at the
Episcopal
Episcopal Church.
call the center but it's not at the
Episcopal Church. It's
Episcopal Church. It's here
call the center but it's not at the
Episcopal Church. It's here at
Episcopal Church. It's here at this
call the center but it's not at the
Episcopal Church. It's here at this um
center.
center. There's
center. There's something
center. There's something else
center. There's something else I'm
supposed
supposed to
center. There's something else I'm
supposed to tell
supposed to tell you.
We'll
We'll come
We'll come back.
>> What'
>> What' you
We'll come back.
>> What' you say?
>> The
>> The rest
>> The rest of
>> The rest of the
>> The rest of the schedule.
>> The rest of the schedule. Oh,
>> The rest of the schedule. Oh, I'm
>> The rest of the schedule. Oh, I'm sorry.
The
The rest
>> The rest of the schedule. Oh, I'm sorry.
The rest of
The rest of the
>> The rest of the schedule. Oh, I'm sorry.
The rest of the schedule
The rest of the schedule is
>> The rest of the schedule. Oh, I'm sorry.
The rest of the schedule is doctor's
going
going to
going to lecture,
going to lecture, Nico
going to lecture, Nico is
going to lecture, Nico is going
going to lecture, Nico is going to
chant,
chant, and
going to lecture, Nico is going to
chant, and then
chant, and then we're
going to lecture, Nico is going to
chant, and then we're going
chant, and then we're going to
going to lecture, Nico is going to
chant, and then we're going to have
chant, and then we're going to have our
final
final break.
final break. Okay.
final break. Okay. Thanks.
>> Yes.
>> Well,
>> Well, the
>> Well, the problem
>> Well, the problem was
>> Well, the problem was we
>> Well, the problem was we overloaded
>> Well, the problem was we overloaded St.
Andrews.
Andrews. We
>> Well, the problem was we overloaded St.
Andrews. We didn't
Andrews. We didn't know
>> Well, the problem was we overloaded St.
Andrews. We didn't know such
Andrews. We didn't know such a
>> Well, the problem was we overloaded St.
Andrews. We didn't know such a crowd
Andrews. We didn't know such a crowd was
going
going to
going to come.
going to come. I
going to come. I originally
going to come. I originally told
going to come. I originally told them
about
about 60
going to come. I originally told them
about 60 70
about 60 70 people.
going to come. I originally told them
about 60 70 people. I
about 60 70 people. I figured,
going to come. I originally told them
about 60 70 people. I figured, you
about 60 70 people. I figured, you know,
people
people around
people around Sedona,
people around Sedona, maybe
people around Sedona, maybe a
people around Sedona, maybe a few
people around Sedona, maybe a few from
Phoenix.
Phoenix. Oh.
people around Sedona, maybe a few from
Phoenix. Oh. So,
Phoenix. Oh. So, we
people around Sedona, maybe a few from
Phoenix. Oh. So, we decided
Phoenix. Oh. So, we decided we
people around Sedona, maybe a few from
Phoenix. Oh. So, we decided we better
move
move back
move back here,
move back here, you
move back here, you know,
move back here, you know, and
move back here, you know, and Nancy
move back here, you know, and Nancy was
very
very gracious
move back here, you know, and Nancy was
very gracious and
very gracious and made
move back here, you know, and Nancy was
very gracious and made the
very gracious and made the arrangement
for
for us.
for us. So,
for us. So, the
for us. So, the dates
for us. So, the dates are
for us. So, the dates are the
for us. So, the dates are the same.
for us. So, the dates are the same. It's
just
just the
for us. So, the dates are the same. It's
just the location
just the location is
for us. So, the dates are the same. It's
just the location is different.
just the location is different. Yeah.
>> I
>> I said
>> I said the
>> I said the second
>> I said the second Wednesday.
>> I said the second Wednesday. Someone
just
just told
>> I said the second Wednesday. Someone
just told me
just told me it's
>> I said the second Wednesday. Someone
just told me it's the
just told me it's the third
>> I said the second Wednesday. Someone
just told me it's the third Wednesday.
>> It
>> It is
>> It is the
>> It is the third
>> It is the third Wednesday.
>> It is the third Wednesday. This
and
and then
>> It is the third Wednesday. This
and then after
and then after this
next
next in
next in March,
next in March, it
next in March, it will
next in March, it will be
next in March, it will be the
next in March, it will be the third
Wednesday.
Wednesday. March
next in March, it will be the third
Wednesday. March it'll
Wednesday. March it'll be
next in March, it will be the third
Wednesday. March it'll be different
Wednesday. March it'll be different but
after
after that
after that it's
after that it's the
after that it's the same
after that it's the same just
after that it's the same just the
location
location is
after that it's the same just the
location is different.
>> However
>> However it
>> However it happens
>> However it happens is
>> However it happens is however
>> However it happens is however it
happens.
I'm
I'm glad
I'm glad that
I'm glad that everything's
I'm glad that everything's happening
spontaneously.
spontaneously. I
I'm glad that everything's happening
spontaneously. I wouldn't
spontaneously. I wouldn't want
I'm glad that everything's happening
spontaneously. I wouldn't want to
spontaneously. I wouldn't want to take
responsibility
responsibility for
responsibility for it.
The
The awareness
responsibility for it.
The awareness that
The awareness that everything
responsibility for it.
The awareness that everything is
happening
happening spontaneously
happening spontaneously gives
happening spontaneously gives you
happening spontaneously gives you a
happening spontaneously gives you a very
rapid
rapid leap
happening spontaneously gives you a very
rapid leap forward
rapid leap forward in
happening spontaneously gives you a very
rapid leap forward in consciousness.
You
You become
You become aware
You become aware that
You become aware that all
You become aware that all phenomena
You become aware that all phenomena are
occurring
occurring as
You become aware that all phenomena are
occurring as a
occurring as a consequence
You become aware that all phenomena are
occurring as a consequence of
occurring as a consequence of the
You become aware that all phenomena are
occurring as a consequence of the field
not
not as
not as a
not as a consequence
not as a consequence of
not as a consequence of a
not as a consequence of a personal
not as a consequence of a personal eye.
For
For instance,
not as a consequence of a personal eye.
For instance, who
For instance, who speaks
not as a consequence of a personal eye.
For instance, who speaks when
For instance, who speaks when the
spiritual
spiritual speech
spiritual speech teacher
spiritual speech teacher speaks?
spiritual speech teacher speaks? Who's
speaking?
speaking? If
spiritual speech teacher speaks? Who's
speaking? If not
speaking? If not the
spiritual speech teacher speaks? Who's
speaking? If not the personal
speaking? If not the personal eye,
spiritual speech teacher speaks? Who's
speaking? If not the personal eye, I
don't
don't want
don't want anything
don't want anything to
don't want anything to do
don't want anything to do with
don't want anything to do with it.
It's
It's happening
don't want anything to do with it.
It's happening of
It's happening of its
don't want anything to do with it.
It's happening of its own.
It's happening of its own. Classically,
that's
that's called
that's called the
that's called the perushia.
that's called the perushia. The
that's called the perushia. The presence
within
within speaks.
So
So you
So you become
So you become you
So you become you become
So you become you become progressively
aware
that
that it's
that it's the
that it's the field
that it's the field and
that it's the field and not
that it's the field and not a
that it's the field and not a personal
self
self that
that it's the field and not a personal
self that uh
self that uh and
that it's the field and not a personal
self that uh and then
self that uh and then phenomena
that it's the field and not a personal
self that uh and then phenomena are
self that uh and then phenomena are a
consequence
consequence of
consequence of the
consequence of the field
consequence of the field and
consequence of the field and of
consequence of the field and of course
part
part of
consequence of the field and of course
part of the
part of the field
consequence of the field and of course
part of the field is
part of the field is intention.
So
So that
So that intention
So that intention increases
So that intention increases the
likelihood
likelihood of
So that intention increases the
likelihood of certain
likelihood of certain responses
and
and but
and but the
and but the responses
and but the responses themselves
and but the responses themselves are
still
still autonomous,
and but the responses themselves are
still autonomous, spontaneous,
still autonomous, spontaneous, occurring
of
of their
of their own.
of their own. The
of their own. The fulfillment
of their own. The fulfillment of
of their own. The fulfillment of a
potential
potential becoming
of their own. The fulfillment of a
potential becoming an
potential becoming an actuality
by
by virtue
by virtue of
by virtue of intention.
The
The Heisenberg
by virtue of intention.
The Heisenberg principle.
The Heisenberg principle. Yeah.
core
core to
core to this
core to this commitment
core to this commitment is
core to this commitment is devotion
core to this commitment is devotion to
it.
it. Devotion
core to this commitment is devotion to
it. Devotion because
it. Devotion because that
core to this commitment is devotion to
it. Devotion because that energizes
it. Devotion because that energizes the
power
power that
power that you
power that you that
power that you that you
power that you that you need
power that you that you need because
you're
you're overcoming,
power that you that you need because
you're overcoming, you
you're overcoming, you know,
power that you that you need because
you're overcoming, you know, really
millennia
millennia of
millennia of limitation
millennia of limitation of
millennia of limitation of the
millennia of limitation of the ego.
millennia of limitation of the ego. As
you
you see,
millennia of limitation of the ego. As
you see, it
you see, it developed
millennia of limitation of the ego. As
you see, it developed over
you see, it developed over great
expanses
expanses of
expanses of time.
expanses of time. The
expanses of time. The ego
expanses of time. The ego didn't
expanses of time. The ego didn't just
arise
arise uh
expanses of time. The ego didn't just
arise uh with
arise uh with man.
expanses of time. The ego didn't just
arise uh with man. It
arise uh with man. It pre-existed
expanses of time. The ego didn't just
arise uh with man. It pre-existed as
arise uh with man. It pre-existed as a
as
as a
as a quality
as a quality of
as a quality of life,
as a quality of life, quality
as a quality of life, quality of
as a quality of life, quality of life
itself
itself and
as a quality of life, quality of life
itself and then
itself and then its
as a quality of life, quality of life
itself and then its manifestation
uh
uh gradually
uh gradually took
uh gradually took us
uh gradually took us away
uh gradually took us away from
uh gradually took us away from the
awareness
awareness of
uh gradually took us away from the
awareness of its
awareness of its source.
uh gradually took us away from the
awareness of its source. And
awareness of its source. And so
uh gradually took us away from the
awareness of its source. And so to
awareness of its source. And so to seek
enlightenment
enlightenment is
enlightenment is to
enlightenment is to seek
enlightenment is to seek to
enlightenment is to seek to return
enlightenment is to seek to return to
the
the source.
We
We said
We said that
We said that the
We said that the experiencer
We said that the experiencer wants
We said that the experiencer wants to
jump
jump ahead
We said that the experiencer wants to
jump ahead at
jump ahead at the
We said that the experiencer wants to
jump ahead at the peak
jump ahead at the peak of
We said that the experiencer wants to
jump ahead at the peak of the
jump ahead at the peak of the prow
We said that the experiencer wants to
jump ahead at the peak of the prow of
the
the ship.
the ship. you
the ship. you might
the ship. you might say
the ship. you might say of
the ship. you might say of the
the ship. you might say of the ego
the ship. you might say of the ego and
take
take credit
the ship. you might say of the ego and
take credit for
take credit for everything
the ship. you might say of the ego and
take credit for everything that
take credit for everything that happens
to
to get
to get ahead
to get ahead of
to get ahead of it
to get ahead of it takes
to get ahead of it takes it
to get ahead of it takes it happens
to get ahead of it takes it happens in
one
one 10,000th
to get ahead of it takes it happens in
one 10,000th of
one 10,000th of a
to get ahead of it takes it happens in
one 10,000th of a second.
one 10,000th of a second. So
to get ahead of it takes it happens in
one 10,000th of a second. So you
one 10,000th of a second. So you can't
valitionally
valitionally jump
valitionally jump it
valitionally jump it by
valitionally jump it by 110,000
valitionally jump it by 110,000 of
valitionally jump it by 110,000 of a
second
second because
valitionally jump it by 110,000 of a
second because your
second because your mind
valitionally jump it by 110,000 of a
second because your mind that's
second because your mind that's trying
to
to jump
to jump to
to jump to 10,000
to jump to 10,000 of
to jump to 10,000 of a
to jump to 10,000 of a second
to jump to 10,000 of a second is
to jump to 10,000 of a second is is
itself
itself moving
to jump to 10,000 of a second is is
itself moving at
itself moving at 10,000
to jump to 10,000 of a second is is
itself moving at 10,000 of
itself moving at 10,000 of a
to jump to 10,000 of a second is is
itself moving at 10,000 of a second.
So
So you'd
So you'd be
So you'd be like
So you'd be like a
So you'd be like a dog
So you'd be like a dog trying
So you'd be like a dog trying to
So you'd be like a dog trying to catch
its
its tail.
So you'd be like a dog trying to catch
its tail. So
its tail. So you
So you'd be like a dog trying to catch
its tail. So you can't
its tail. So you can't do
So you'd be like a dog trying to catch
its tail. So you can't do it
its tail. So you can't do it by
So you'd be like a dog trying to catch
its tail. So you can't do it by specific
logical
logical intention.
You
You do
logical intention.
You do it
You do it by
logical intention.
You do it by by
You do it by by becoming
logical intention.
You do it by by becoming the
You do it by by becoming the field.
logical intention.
You do it by by becoming the field. So
we
we say
to
to dedicate
we say
to dedicate your
to dedicate your life
we say
to dedicate your life so
to dedicate your life so that
we say
to dedicate your life so that your
to dedicate your life so that your life
becomes
becomes the
becomes the prayer.
Who
Who you
becomes the prayer.
Who you are
Who you are becomes
becomes the prayer.
Who you are becomes the
Who you are becomes the prayer.
And
And then
the
the consequences
And then
the consequences of
the consequences of that
And then
the consequences of that is
the consequences of that is that
And then
the consequences of that is that one
the consequences of that is that one day
while
while you're
while you're walking
while you're walking through
while you're walking through the
while you're walking through the woods
thinking
thinking about
while you're walking through the woods
thinking about nothing,
thinking about nothing, you
while you're walking through the woods
thinking about nothing, you become
thinking about nothing, you become the
field.
Yeah,
Yeah, it's
field.
Yeah, it's worth
Yeah, it's worth the
field.
Yeah, it's worth the field.
Yeah, it's worth the field. How
field.
Yeah, it's worth the field. How did
Yeah, it's worth the field. How did you
fail
fail to
fail to notice
fail to notice it?
fail to notice it? Huh?
fail to notice it? Huh? It's
fail to notice it? Huh? It's because
you're
you're you
fail to notice it? Huh? It's because
you're you were
you're you were focused
fail to notice it? Huh? It's because
you're you were focused in
you're you were focused in such
fail to notice it? Huh? It's because
you're you were focused in such a
limited
limited parameter
limited parameter of
limited parameter of the
limited parameter of the linear
dimension.
dimension. you
limited parameter of the linear
dimension. you see
dimension. you see together
limited parameter of the linear
dimension. you see together with
dimension. you see together with you
know
know the
know the belief
know the belief in
know the belief in cause
know the belief in cause and
know the belief in cause and effect.
So
So you
know the belief in cause and effect.
So you become
So you become then
know the belief in cause and effect.
So you become then the
So you become then the field
know the belief in cause and effect.
So you become then the field in
So you become then the field in which
these
these phenomena
um
um become
these phenomena
um become self-revealing.
How
How to
How to discern
the
the linear
How to discern
the linear from
the linear from the
How to discern
the linear from the nonlinear
the linear from the nonlinear is
How to discern
the linear from the nonlinear is you
realize
realize that
realize that your
realize that your reality
realize that your reality is
realize that your reality is the
nonlinear
nonlinear and
realize that your reality is the
nonlinear and your
nonlinear and your expression
realize that your reality is the
nonlinear and your expression your
expression
expression is
expression is in
expression is in the
expression is in the linear
expression is in the linear but
expression is in the linear but your
source
source your
expression is in the linear but your
source your essence
source your essence that
expression is in the linear but your
source your essence that which
source your essence that which you
expression is in the linear but your
source your essence that which you are
is
is nonlinear.
Uhhuh.
All
All right.
The
The core
All right.
The core then
The core then is
All right.
The core then is the
The core then is the dedication.
Now
Now the
Now the heart
Now the heart is
Now the heart is more
Now the heart is more powerful
Now the heart is more powerful than
Now the heart is more powerful than the
mind.
mind. See?
Therefore,
Therefore, devotion
Therefore, devotion to
Therefore, devotion to truth,
Therefore, devotion to truth, devotion
to
to spiritual
Therefore, devotion to truth, devotion
to spiritual evolution
is
is very
is very powerful.
is very powerful. The
is very powerful. The intellect
is very powerful. The intellect alone
can't
can't do
is very powerful. The intellect alone
can't do it.
can't do it. Otherwise,
is very powerful. The intellect alone
can't do it. Otherwise, you
can't do it. Otherwise, you could
is very powerful. The intellect alone
can't do it. Otherwise, you could become
enlightened
enlightened by
enlightened by reading
enlightened by reading a
enlightened by reading a lot
enlightened by reading a lot of
enlightened by reading a lot of books.
You
You take
enlightened by reading a lot of books.
You take a
You take a test
enlightened by reading a lot of books.
You take a test on
You take a test on it,
enlightened by reading a lot of books.
You take a test on it, you
You take a test on it, you get
enlightened by reading a lot of books.
You take a test on it, you get a
You take a test on it, you get a 100
year
year length.
Willy-nilly
Willy-nilly devotion
year length.
Willy-nilly devotion also
Willy-nilly devotion also is
year length.
Willy-nilly devotion also is not
sufficient.
There
There are
sufficient.
There are lots
There are lots of
sufficient.
There are lots of people
There are lots of people that
sufficient.
There are lots of people that are
devoted
devoted and
devoted and they
devoted and they have
devoted and they have been
devoted and they have been for
devoted and they have been for many
devoted and they have been for many a
lifetime.
But
But they
But they get
But they get so
But they get so far
But they get so far and
But they get so far and no
But they get so far and no more
But they get so far and no more because
beyond
beyond that
But they get so far and no more because
beyond that you
beyond that you also
But they get so far and no more because
beyond that you also need
beyond that you also need knowledge.
But they get so far and no more because
beyond that you also need knowledge. You
also
also need
also need certain
also need certain energies
also need certain energies and
frequencies
frequencies in
also need certain energies and
frequencies in your
frequencies in your aura
also need certain energies and
frequencies in your aura so
frequencies in your aura so that
also need certain energies and
frequencies in your aura so that when
you
you get
you get to
you get to that
you get to that point,
you get to that point, it's
you get to that point, it's waiting
you get to that point, it's waiting for
you.
you. Yeah.
Now,
Now, we
Now, we um
Now, we um did
Now, we um did the
Now, we um did the uh
Now, we um did the uh slides
Now, we um did the uh slides because
Now, we um did the uh slides because um
of
of the
Now, we um did the uh slides because um
of the new
of the new people
Now, we um did the uh slides because um
of the new people that
of the new people that were
Now, we um did the uh slides because um
of the new people that were here
of the new people that were here and
Now, we um did the uh slides because um
of the new people that were here and in
in
in the
in the future,
in the future, what
in the future, what I'll
in the future, what I'll probably
in the future, what I'll probably do
in the future, what I'll probably do is
just
just use
in the future, what I'll probably do is
just use the
just use the slides
in the future, what I'll probably do is
just use the slides for
just use the slides for background.
in the future, what I'll probably do is
just use the slides for background. In
other
other words,
other words, when
other words, when I
other words, when I get
other words, when I get through
other words, when I get through talking,
we'll
we'll maybe
other words, when I get through talking,
we'll maybe go
we'll maybe go to
other words, when I get through talking,
we'll maybe go to a
we'll maybe go to a slide
other words, when I get through talking,
we'll maybe go to a slide and
we'll maybe go to a slide and that
other words, when I get through talking,
we'll maybe go to a slide and that will
trigger
trigger a
trigger a new
trigger a new uh
trigger a new uh subject.
trigger a new uh subject. So
trigger a new uh subject. So rather
trigger a new uh subject. So rather than
following
following the
trigger a new uh subject. So rather than
following the slides,
following the slides, we'll
trigger a new uh subject. So rather than
following the slides, we'll use
following the slides, we'll use them
more
more as
more as backup
more as backup or
more as backup or fill
more as backup or fill in,
more as backup or fill in, you
more as backup or fill in, you might
say.
say. And
more as backup or fill in, you might
say. And I
say. And I don't
more as backup or fill in, you might
say. And I don't even
say. And I don't even know
more as backup or fill in, you might
say. And I don't even know what
say. And I don't even know what slide
we're
we're up
we're up to.
we're up to. Do
we're up to. Do you
we're up to. Do you know?
Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Is
>> Okay. Is this
>> Okay. Is this the
>> Okay. Is this the way
>> Okay. Is this the way the
>> Okay. Is this the way the lights
>> Okay. Is this the way the lights were
this
this morning?
>> The
>> The lights
>> The lights seem
>> The lights seem different
>> The lights seem different than
>> The lights seem different than they
>> The lights seem different than they were
this
this morning.
>> Huh?
>> The
>> The lights
>> Huh?
>> The lights are
>> The lights are up.
>> Why
>> Why is
>> Why is that?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
The
The lights
The lights are
The lights are up
The lights are up a
The lights are up a little
The lights are up a little bit
The lights are up a little bit more
The lights are up a little bit more than
they
they were
The lights are up a little bit more than
they were this
they were this morning.
Are
Are you
Are you still
Are you still there?
Are you still there? Yes.
Big
Big black
Are you still there? Yes.
Big black crowd
Big black crowd in
Are you still there? Yes.
Big black crowd in these
Big black crowd in these bright
Are you still there? Yes.
Big black crowd in these bright lights.
Okay.
Maybe
Maybe Robert
Okay.
Maybe Robert can
Maybe Robert can arrange
Okay.
Maybe Robert can arrange to
Maybe Robert can arrange to dim
Okay.
Maybe Robert can arrange to dim the
lights
lights a
lights a little
lights a little bit.
lights a little bit. Okay.
lights a little bit. Okay. All
lights a little bit. Okay. All right.
But
But I
lights a little bit. Okay. All right.
But I think
But I think the
lights a little bit. Okay. All right.
But I think the video
But I think the video oper.
Mhm.
Mhm. All right.
Mhm. All right. I
Mhm. All right. I wanted
Mhm. All right. I wanted to
Mhm. All right. I wanted to pick
Mhm. All right. I wanted to pick up
where
where we
Mhm. All right. I wanted to pick up
where we left
where we left on
Mhm. All right. I wanted to pick up
where we left on the
where we left on the slides.
Mhm. All right. I wanted to pick up
where we left on the slides. We
where we left on the slides. We were
talking
talking about
talking about spiritual
talking about spiritual teaching
and
and uh
talking about spiritual teaching
and uh the
and uh the commitment
talking about spiritual teaching
and uh the commitment of
and uh the commitment of the
talking about spiritual teaching
and uh the commitment of the teacher
and uh the commitment of the teacher uh
should
should be
should be equal
should be equal to
should be equal to that
should be equal to that of
should be equal to that of the
should be equal to that of the student.
You
You can't
should be equal to that of the student.
You can't ask
You can't ask the
should be equal to that of the student.
You can't ask the devotion
You can't ask the devotion of
should be equal to that of the student.
You can't ask the devotion of the
student
student and
student and you're
student and you're supposed
student and you're supposed to
student and you're supposed to be
student and you're supposed to be free
to
to do
student and you're supposed to be free
to do anything
to do anything you
student and you're supposed to be free
to do anything you you
to do anything you you please
including
including exploiting
including exploiting people
exploiting
exploiting their
including exploiting people
exploiting their naivity
exploiting their naivity and
including exploiting people
exploiting their naivity and their
trust.
trust. Why?
trust. Why? Because
trust. Why? Because the
trust. Why? Because the basically
trust. Why? Because the basically the
human
human mind
trust. Why? Because the basically the
human mind is
human mind is innocent
trust. Why? Because the basically the
human mind is innocent is
human mind is innocent is innocent.
Uh
Uh it
Uh it can't
Uh it can't tell
Uh it can't tell truth
Uh it can't tell truth from
Uh it can't tell truth from falsehood
innately.
innately. It
Uh it can't tell truth from falsehood
innately. It cannot
innately. It cannot not
Uh it can't tell truth from falsehood
innately. It cannot not equipped
innately. It cannot not equipped to
Uh it can't tell truth from falsehood
innately. It cannot not equipped to do
that.
that. U
all
all right.
that. U
all right. So
all right. So we
that. U
all right. So we did
all right. So we did spiritual
that. U
all right. So we did spiritual teachers.
We've
We've done
We've done these
We've done these before
We've done these before but
We've done these before but it
We've done these before but it just
We've done these before but it just is
mainly
mainly to
We've done these before but it just is
mainly to recall
mainly to recall to
We've done these before but it just is
mainly to recall to recall
mainly to recall to recall uh
We've done these before but it just is
mainly to recall to recall uh what
mainly to recall to recall uh what is
the
the responsibility
and
and um
the responsibility
and um the
and um the integrity
the responsibility
and um the integrity of
and um the integrity of course
the responsibility
and um the integrity of course the
and um the integrity of course the other
thing
thing you
thing you can
thing you can do
thing you can do is
thing you can do is you
thing you can do is you can
thing you can do is you can calibrate
the
the teacher
thing you can do is you can calibrate
the teacher you
the teacher you can
thing you can do is you can calibrate
the teacher you can calibrate
the teacher you can calibrate the
teacher
teacher if
teacher if there's
teacher if there's a
teacher if there's a doubt
teacher if there's a doubt in
teacher if there's a doubt in your
teacher if there's a doubt in your mind
some
some people
teacher if there's a doubt in your mind
some people sound
some people sound very
teacher if there's a doubt in your mind
some people sound very convincing
some people sound very convincing and
then
then when
then when you
then when you calibrate
then when you calibrate him
then when you calibrate him you
then when you calibrate him you you
realize
realize how
then when you calibrate him you you
realize how could
realize how could I
then when you calibrate him you you
realize how could I been
realize how could I been so
then when you calibrate him you you
realize how could I been so off
realize how could I been so off and
then when you calibrate him you you
realize how could I been so off and you
realize
realize then
realize then you
realize then you realize
realize then you realize what
realize then you realize what the
illusion
illusion was
realize then you realize what the
illusion was usually
illusion was usually it's
realize then you realize what the
illusion was usually it's the
illusion was usually it's the glamour
the
the glamour
and
and the
the glamour
and the projected
and the projected uh
the glamour
and the projected uh what
and the projected uh what you
the glamour
and the projected uh what you project
onto
onto the
onto the teacher.
onto the teacher. Yeah.
onto the teacher. Yeah. But
onto the teacher. Yeah. But very
onto the teacher. Yeah. But very often
it's
it's the
onto the teacher. Yeah. But very often
it's the glamour.
it's the glamour. Yeah.
So
So these
So these are
So these are sp
So these are sp the
So these are sp the great
So these are sp the great spiritual
teachers
teachers of
So these are sp the great spiritual
teachers of time.
teachers of time. We
So these are sp the great spiritual
teachers of time. We I
teachers of time. We I wouldn't
So these are sp the great spiritual
teachers of time. We I wouldn't say
they're
they're everyone,
they're everyone, but
they're everyone, but we
they're everyone, but we tried
they're everyone, but we tried to
they're everyone, but we tried to pick
out
out the
they're everyone, but we tried to pick
out the most
out the most well-known.
Why?
Why? Because
Why? Because it
Why? Because it gives
Why? Because it gives us
Why? Because it gives us an
Why? Because it gives us an orientation
to
to the
Why? Because it gives us an orientation
to the field.
to the field. It
Why? Because it gives us an orientation
to the field. It isn't
to the field. It isn't that
Why? Because it gives us an orientation
to the field. It isn't that we
necessarily
necessarily want
necessarily want to
necessarily want to know
every
every particular
necessarily want to know
every particular one,
every particular one, but
necessarily want to know
every particular one, but how
every particular one, but how does
necessarily want to know
every particular one, but how does the
field
field line
field line up?
field line up? How
field line up? How does
field line up? How does the
field line up? How does the field
field line up? How does the field line
up?
up? You
field line up? How does the field line
up? You see,
up? You see, the
field line up? How does the field line
up? You see, the same
up? You see, the same as
field line up? How does the field line
up? You see, the same as in
up? You see, the same as in sports,
what's
what's the
what's the overall
what's the overall field?
what's the overall field? And
what's the overall field? And then
what's the overall field? And then where
where
where are
what's the overall field? And then where
where are you
where are you in
what's the overall field? And then where
where are you in the
where are you in the field?
what's the overall field? And then where
where are you in the field? But
where are you in the field? But what
does
does the
does the field
does the field itself
does the field itself uh
does the field itself uh look
does the field itself uh look look
does the field itself uh look look like?
You
You see,
does the field itself uh look look like?
You see, and
You see, and sooner
does the field itself uh look look like?
You see, and sooner or
You see, and sooner or later,
does the field itself uh look look like?
You see, and sooner or later, usually
you'll
you'll meet
you'll meet people
you'll meet people who are
you'll meet people who are destined
you'll meet people who are destined for
enlightenment
enlightenment will
you'll meet people who are destined for
enlightenment will meet
enlightenment will meet uh
you'll meet people who are destined for
enlightenment will meet uh one
enlightenment will meet uh one or
you'll meet people who are destined for
enlightenment will meet uh one or two
enlightenment will meet uh one or two of
these
these people.
these people. uh
these people. uh for
these people. uh for what
these people. uh for what reason
these people. uh for what reason I
these people. uh for what reason I don't
know
know but
these people. uh for what reason I don't
know but uh
know but uh you
these people. uh for what reason I don't
know but uh you know
know but uh you know I
these people. uh for what reason I don't
know but uh you know I got
know but uh you know I got to
these people. uh for what reason I don't
know but uh you know I got to read
know but uh you know I got to read the
hear
hear the
hear the Karmapa
hear the Karmapa and
hear the Karmapa and meet
hear the Karmapa and meet Makananda
and
and worked
hear the Karmapa and meet Makananda
and worked with
and worked with Monro's
hear the Karmapa and meet Makananda
and worked with Monro's things.
and worked with Monro's things. So
hear the Karmapa and meet Makananda
and worked with Monro's things. So you
get
get to
get to know
get to know some
get to know some of
get to know some of these
get to know some of these people
get to know some of these people somehow
one
one way
get to know some of these people somehow
one way or
one way or the
get to know some of these people somehow
one way or the other
one way or the other uh
get to know some of these people somehow
one way or the other uh perhaps
and
and then
and then we
and then we were
and then we were at
and then we were at uh
and then we were at uh the
and then we were at uh the headquarters
of
of Unity
and then we were at uh the headquarters
of Unity Church
of Unity Church and
and then we were at uh the headquarters
of Unity Church and uh
of Unity Church and uh and
and then we were at uh the headquarters
of Unity Church and uh and we
of Unity Church and uh and we got
and then we were at uh the headquarters
of Unity Church and uh and we got to
of Unity Church and uh and we got to see
the
the original
the original manuscripts
the original manuscripts of
the original manuscripts of the
the original manuscripts of the film
wars
wars and
the original manuscripts of the film
wars and calibrate
wars and calibrate them.
the original manuscripts of the film
wars and calibrate them. It
wars and calibrate them. It was
the original manuscripts of the film
wars and calibrate them. It was very
very
very interesting
very interesting in
very interesting in their
very interesting in their uh
very interesting in their uh library.
very interesting in their uh library. So
these
these are
very interesting in their uh library. So
these are the
these are the just
very interesting in their uh library. So
these are the just the
these are the just the best
very interesting in their uh library. So
these are the just the best known
these are the just the best known names.
Uh
Uh it
Uh it gives
Uh it gives you
Uh it gives you a
Uh it gives you a sense
Uh it gives you a sense of
Uh it gives you a sense of where
everything
everything is
Uh it gives you a sense of where
everything is at.
everything is at. Now,
Uh it gives you a sense of where
everything is at. Now, this
everything is at. Now, this is
Uh it gives you a sense of where
everything is at. Now, this is not
everything is at. Now, this is not a
Uh it gives you a sense of where
everything is at. Now, this is not a a
way
way of
way of valuing
way of valuing people,
way of valuing people, saying
way of valuing people, saying this
person's
person's worth
way of valuing people, saying this
person's worth more
person's worth more than
way of valuing people, saying this
person's worth more than this.
person's worth more than this. Uh,
that's
that's not
that's not true
that's not true because
that's not true because somebody
that's not true because somebody at
that's not true because somebody at 350
can
can say
that's not true because somebody at 350
can say a
can say a thing,
that's not true because somebody at 350
can say a thing, you
can say a thing, you get
that's not true because somebody at 350
can say a thing, you get it.
can say a thing, you get it. And
that's not true because somebody at 350
can say a thing, you get it. And of
course,
course, it's
course, it's been
course, it's been said
course, it's been said for
course, it's been said for centuries
course, it's been said for centuries by
somebody
somebody at
course, it's been said for centuries by
somebody at 800,
somebody at 800, but
course, it's been said for centuries by
somebody at 800, but at
somebody at 800, but at 800,
course, it's been said for centuries by
somebody at 800, but at 800, it
somebody at 800, but at 800, it doesn't
make
make any
make any sense.
make any sense. So,
I
I always
make any sense. So,
I always tell
I always tell people,
make any sense. So,
I always tell people, first
I always tell people, first digest
make any sense. So,
I always tell people, first digest the
easy
easy ones
easy ones before
easy ones before you
easy ones before you try
easy ones before you try moving
easy ones before you try moving on.
Before
Before you
easy ones before you try moving on.
Before you try
Before you try moving
easy ones before you try moving on.
Before you try moving on.
Before you try moving on. And
easy ones before you try moving on.
Before you try moving on. And we
Before you try moving on. And we pointed
out
out in
out in the
out in the recent
out in the recent book
out in the recent book whatever
out in the recent book whatever one
out in the recent book whatever one it
was
was I
out in the recent book whatever one it
was I forget
was I forget the
out in the recent book whatever one it
was I forget the limitation
was I forget the limitation of
out in the recent book whatever one it
was I forget the limitation of hanging
po
po the
po the you
po the you know
po the you know you
po the you know you read
po the you know you read Wayne
po the you know you read Wayne Po
po the you know you read Wayne Po that's
the
the pathway
po the you know you read Wayne Po that's
the pathway of
the pathway of negation
po the you know you read Wayne Po that's
the pathway of negation and
the pathway of negation and the
po the you know you read Wayne Po that's
the pathway of negation and the pathway
of
of Wang
of Wang Po
of Wang Po will
of Wang Po will take
of Wang Po will take you
of Wang Po will take you to
of Wang Po will take you to 850
of Wang Po will take you to 850 850
of Wang Po will take you to 850 850 is
the
the void
850 is
850 is very
850 is very very
850 is very very impressive
850 is very very impressive the
850 is very very impressive the void
850 is very very impressive the void is
very
very very
850 is very very impressive the void is
very very impressive
there
there is
there is no
uh
uh question
there is no
uh question about
uh question about it
but
but it
but it is
but it is not
but it is not the
but it is not the ultim
but it is not the ultim it
but it is not the ultim it is
but it is not the ultim it is 850.
but it is not the ultim it is 850. So
the
the pathway
but it is not the ultim it is 850. So
the pathway of
the pathway of negation
but it is not the ultim it is 850. So
the pathway of negation to
the pathway of negation to to
but it is not the ultim it is 850. So
the pathway of negation to to negate
the pathway of negation to to negate the
reality
reality of
reality of all
reality of all that
reality of all that is
reality of all that is linear
reality of all that is linear will
reality of all that is linear will take
you
you to
unless
unless you've
unless you've got
unless you've got a
unless you've got a teacher
unless you've got a teacher that
unless you've got a teacher that can
prepare
prepare you
unless you've got a teacher that can
prepare you in
prepare you in advance
unless you've got a teacher that can
prepare you in advance to
prepare you in advance to the
unless you've got a teacher that can
prepare you in advance to the void
prepare you in advance to the void to
nothingness.
nothingness. Nothingness
nothingness. Nothingness is
nothingness. Nothingness is not
nothingness. Nothingness is not the
ultimate
ultimate state
nothingness. Nothingness is not the
ultimate state and
uh
uh Wayne
uh Wayne Po
uh Wayne Po uh
uh Wayne Po uh corrected
uh Wayne Po uh corrected that
uh Wayne Po uh corrected that later
uh Wayne Po uh corrected that later when
he
he wrote
uh
uh his
uh his famous
uh his famous book
uh his famous book Wayne
uh his famous book Wayne Po
uh his famous book Wayne Po uh
uh his famous book Wayne Po uh was
uh his famous book Wayne Po uh was at
after
after writing
after writing the
after writing the book
after writing the book he
after writing the book he never
after writing the book he never wrote
another
another thing
after writing the book he never wrote
another thing he
another thing he realized
after writing the book he never wrote
another thing he realized the
another thing he realized the error
after writing the book he never wrote
another thing he realized the error he
himself
himself went
himself went to
himself went to 980
himself went to 980 or
himself went to 980 or 90
himself went to 980 or 90 or
himself went to 980 or 90 or something
but
but he
himself went to 980 or 90 or something
but he never
but he never wrote
himself went to 980 or 90 or something
but he never wrote anything
but he never wrote anything about
himself went to 980 or 90 or something
but he never wrote anything about it
but he never wrote anything about it so
we
we think
we think that
we think that Wang
we think that Wang Po
we think that Wang Po you
we think that Wang Po you know
we think that Wang Po you know famous
we think that Wang Po you know famous in
the
the Classicist
we think that Wang Po you know famous in
the Classicist in
the Classicist in is
we think that Wang Po you know famous in
the Classicist in is the
the Classicist in is the ultimate
master.
master. He
master. He is
master. He is up
master. He is up to
master. He is up to 850.
master. He is up to 850. But
master. He is up to 850. But then
master. He is up to 850. But then at
master. He is up to 850. But then at 850
you
you enter
master. He is up to 850. But then at 850
you enter the
you enter the void
master. He is up to 850. But then at 850
you enter the void which
you enter the void which is
nonlinear,
nonlinear, infinite,
profound,
profound, silent,
nonlinear, infinite,
profound, silent, unmoving
with
with no
with no beginning
with no beginning and
with no beginning and no
with no beginning and no end,
with no beginning and no end, universal.
And
And one
with no beginning and no end, universal.
And one thinks
And one thinks this
with no beginning and no end, universal.
And one thinks this is
And one thinks this is it.
with no beginning and no end, universal.
And one thinks this is it. This
And one thinks this is it. This is
with no beginning and no end, universal.
And one thinks this is it. This is what
has
has been
has been spoken
has been spoken about
has been spoken about over
has been spoken about over the
centuries.
Went
Went back
Went back into
Went back into it.
Went back into it. Started
Went back into it. Started this
Went back into it. Started this lifetime
back
back at
Went back into it. Started this lifetime
back at that
back at that at
Went back into it. Started this lifetime
back at that at age
back at that at age three.
Went
Went back
Went back to
Went back to the
Went back to the pathway
Went back to the pathway of
Went back to the pathway of negation
again
again later
Went back to the pathway of negation
again later in
again later in life
and
and ended
and ended back
and ended back in
and ended back in the
and ended back in the void
and ended back in the void again.
However,
the
the difference
the difference was
at
at age
the difference was
at age 12
at age 12 or
the difference was
at age 12 or 14,
at age 12 or 14, something
the difference was
at age 12 or 14, something like
at age 12 or 14, something like that,
the difference was
at age 12 or 14, something like that, I
had
had in
had in a
had in a snowbank
had in a snowbank gotten
had in a snowbank gotten out
had in a snowbank gotten out of
had in a snowbank gotten out of the
wind.
I
I got
I got out
I got out of
I got out of the
I got out of the wind.
I got out of the wind. That's
I got out of the wind. That's all
I got out of the wind. That's all I
I got out of the wind. That's all I did
is
is just
I got out of the wind. That's all I did
is just get
is just get out
I got out of the wind. That's all I did
is just get out of
is just get out of the
I got out of the wind. That's all I did
is just get out of the wind
is just get out of the wind and
I got out of the wind. That's all I did
is just get out of the wind and suddenly
the
the presence
the presence of
the presence of infinite
the presence of infinite love
beyond
beyond description
melted
melted the
melted the personal
melted the personal self
melted the personal self into
melted the personal self into the
eternal
eternal beyond
melted the personal self into the
eternal beyond time
eternal beyond time with
melted the personal self into the
eternal beyond time with no
eternal beyond time with no beginning
melted the personal self into the
eternal beyond time with no beginning no
end.
And
And so
end.
And so there
And so there was
end.
And so there was the
experience
experience of
experience of the
experience of the presence
experience of the presence of
experience of the presence of divinity
as
as infinite
experience of the presence of divinity
as infinite love.
Therefore
Therefore at
Therefore at a
Therefore at a later
Therefore at a later life
Therefore at a later life going
Therefore at a later life going back
into
into the
Therefore at a later life going back
into the void
the
the knowingness
the knowingness was
the knowingness was that
the knowingness was that that
the knowingness was that that quality
was
was missing.
So
So that
So that quality
So that quality of
So that quality of divinity
So that quality of divinity of
So that quality of divinity of infinite
love
love was
So that quality of divinity of infinite
love was missing.
Therefore,
Therefore, there
Therefore, there was
Therefore, there was a
Therefore, there was a decision
Therefore, there was a decision to
Therefore, there was a decision to back
out
out of
Therefore, there was a decision to back
out of the
out of the void,
Therefore, there was a decision to back
out of the void, which
out of the void, which was
Therefore, there was a decision to back
out of the void, which was not
out of the void, which was not easy.
In
In as
In as much
In as much as
In as much as there's
In as much as there's nothing
In as much as there's nothing there
In as much as there's nothing there to
back
back out
In as much as there's nothing there to
back out from
back out from or
In as much as there's nothing there to
back out from or with
a
a float
a float did
a float did there
a float did there was
a float did there was a
a float did there was a thought
a float did there was a thought that
floated
floated a
a float did there was a thought that
floated a pass
floated a pass past
a float did there was a thought that
floated a pass past and
floated a pass past and I
a float did there was a thought that
floated a pass past and I grabbed
floated a pass past and I grabbed the
a float did there was a thought that
floated a pass past and I grabbed the I
grabbed
grabbed the
grabbed the thought
grabbed the thought and
grabbed the thought and expanded
grabbed the thought and expanded on
grabbed the thought and expanded on it
and
and focused
grabbed the thought and expanded on it
and focused on
and focused on it.
grabbed the thought and expanded on it
and focused on it. It
and focused on it. It took
grabbed the thought and expanded on it
and focused on it. It took hours
and focused on it. It took hours of
focus
focus and
focus and concentration
and
and then
focus and concentration
and then I
and then I backed
focus and concentration
and then I backed out.
and then I backed out. I
focus and concentration
and then I backed out. I backed
and then I backed out. I backed out
focus and concentration
and then I backed out. I backed out of
the
the void.
later
went
went past
went past the
went past the void.
went past the void. All right.
went past the void. All right. But
went past the void. All right. But Hang
Po
Po never
went past the void. All right. But Hang
Po never wrote
Po never wrote anything
went past the void. All right. But Hang
Po never wrote anything about
Po never wrote anything about that.
went past the void. All right. But Hang
Po never wrote anything about that. So
that's
that's the
that's the warning
that's the warning on
that's the warning on Hang
that's the warning on Hang Poe
that's the warning on Hang Poe because
he's
he's a
that's the warning on Hang Poe because
he's a very
he's a very esteemed
that's the warning on Hang Poe because
he's a very esteemed Zen
he's a very esteemed Zen master
is
is that
is that he
is that he then
is that he then later
is that he then later went
is that he then later went to
is that he then later went to 960
or
or 980
is that he then later went to 960
or 980 or
or 980 or something
is that he then later went to 960
or 980 or something like
or 980 or something like that.
is that he then later went to 960
or 980 or something like that. 960
that's
that's where
that's where he
that's where he went.
But
But that
that's where he went.
But that was
But that was after
that's where he went.
But that was after he
But that was after he wrote
that's where he went.
But that was after he wrote the
But that was after he wrote the book.
that's where he went.
But that was after he wrote the book. So
the
the book
the book just
the book just negating
the book just negating the
the book just negating the linear
the book just negating the linear will
take
take you
the book just negating the linear will
take you to
take you to voidness
the book just negating the linear will
take you to voidness but
take you to voidness but it
the book just negating the linear will
take you to voidness but it won't
take you to voidness but it won't take
you
you to
you to full
you to full realization.
you to full realization. Huh?
you to full realization. Huh? So
you to full realization. Huh? So we
mentioned
mentioned that
you to full realization. Huh? So we
mentioned that before
mentioned that before because
you to full realization. Huh? So we
mentioned that before because it's
mentioned that before because it's a
frequent
frequent error.
frequent error. Once
frequent error. Once in
frequent error. Once in a
frequent error. Once in a while
frequent error. Once in a while I
frequent error. Once in a while I get
frequent error. Once in a while I get a
letter
letter uh
frequent error. Once in a while I get a
letter uh in
letter uh in fact
frequent error. Once in a while I get a
letter uh in fact I
letter uh in fact I got
frequent error. Once in a while I get a
letter uh in fact I got a
letter uh in fact I got a letter
frequent error. Once in a while I get a
letter uh in fact I got a letter this
year
year about
year about somebody
year about somebody who
year about somebody who had
year about somebody who had done
year about somebody who had done the
very
very thing
year about somebody who had done the
very thing the
very thing the path
year about somebody who had done the
very thing the path of
very thing the path of indigation
year about somebody who had done the
very thing the path of indigation landed
in
in the
in the nothingness
in the nothingness of
in the nothingness of the
in the nothingness of the void
in the nothingness of the void wanted
in the nothingness of the void wanted to
know
know if
in the nothingness of the void wanted to
know if that's
know if that's where
in the nothingness of the void wanted to
know if that's where we
know if that's where we should
in the nothingness of the void wanted to
know if that's where we should be.
know if that's where we should be. Okay.
And
And Lisa
And Lisa I
And Lisa I got
And Lisa I got to
And Lisa I got to meet
And Lisa I got to meet too.
So
So anyway,
And Lisa I got to meet too.
So anyway, some
So anyway, some of
And Lisa I got to meet too.
So anyway, some of these
So anyway, some of these people
And Lisa I got to meet too.
So anyway, some of these people you
So anyway, some of these people you get
to
to meet
to meet in
to meet in your
to meet in your present
to meet in your present life
to meet in your present life and
to meet in your present life and there
are
are famous
to meet in your present life and there
are famous names
are famous names and
to meet in your present life and there
are famous names and we
are famous names and we rever
to meet in your present life and there
are famous names and we rever all
are famous names and we rever all of
them
them because
them because each
them because each one
them because each one contributes
something
something unique.
them because each one contributes
something unique. Mother
something unique. Mother Teresa
them because each one contributes
something unique. Mother Teresa demon,
you
you know,
you know, demonstrated
and
and was
you know, demonstrated
and was and
and was and something
you know, demonstrated
and was and something unique
and was and something unique about
you know, demonstrated
and was and something unique about that
particular
particular level
particular level that
particular level that she
particular level that she was
particular level that she was at.
particular level that she was at. And
Vivikananda,
Vivikananda, each
particular level that she was at. And
Vivikananda, each of
Vivikananda, each of these
particular level that she was at. And
Vivikananda, each of these people
contributed
contributed a
contributed a very
each
each one
contributed a very
each one has
each one has a
contributed a very
each one has a unique
each one has a unique piece
contributed a very
each one has a unique piece of
each one has a unique piece of the
overall
overall picture.
Any
Any one
overall picture.
Any one of
Any one of them
overall picture.
Any one of them can
Any one of them can ring
overall picture.
Any one of them can ring true
Any one of them can ring true with
overall picture.
Any one of them can ring true with you.
So
So they
So they say
So they say what
So they say what teacher
So they say what teacher is
So they say what teacher is the
So they say what teacher is the best?
the
the one
So they say what teacher is the best?
the one that
the one that you
So they say what teacher is the best?
the one that you feel
the one that you feel attracted
So they say what teacher is the best?
the one that you feel attracted to
intuitively
attuned.
attuned. Uh
intuitively
attuned. Uh so
attuned. Uh so we'll
intuitively
attuned. Uh so we'll move
attuned. Uh so we'll move to
intuitively
attuned. Uh so we'll move to the
attuned. Uh so we'll move to the next
one.
one. Yes.
Uh
we
we said
we said that
we said that every
we said that every positionality
we said that every positionality is
we said that every positionality is uh
held
held in
we said that every positionality is uh
held in place
held in place by
we said that every positionality is uh
held in place by two
held in place by two things.
we said that every positionality is uh
held in place by two things. There's
held in place by two things. There's an
attraction
attraction and
attraction and there's
attraction and there's also
attraction and there's also an
attraction and there's also an aversion.
So
So all
attraction and there's also an aversion.
So all the
So all the levels
attraction and there's also an aversion.
So all the levels of
So all the levels of consciousness
attraction and there's also an aversion.
So all the levels of consciousness in
the
the book
the book transcending
the book transcending levels
the book transcending levels of
consciousness.
consciousness. Uh
the book transcending levels of
consciousness. Uh each
consciousness. Uh each level
the book transcending levels of
consciousness. Uh each level you
consciousness. Uh each level you can
the book transcending levels of
consciousness. Uh each level you can see
has
has an
has an attraction
has an attraction and
has an attraction and it
has an attraction and it has
has an attraction and it has an
aversion.
aversion. Now
has an attraction and it has an
aversion. Now these
aversion. Now these are
has an attraction and it has an
aversion. Now these are just
aversion. Now these are just the
dualities
dualities of
dualities of attraction
dualities of attraction and
dualities of attraction and aversion
dualities of attraction and aversion but
you
you can
dualities of attraction and aversion but
you can see
you can see how
dualities of attraction and aversion but
you can see how they
you can see how they could
dualities of attraction and aversion but
you can see how they could apply
you can see how they could apply to
dualities of attraction and aversion but
you can see how they could apply to any
level
level of
level of consciousness.
level of consciousness. We're
level of consciousness. We're attracted
to
to that
level of consciousness. We're attracted
to that which
to that which is
level of consciousness. We're attracted
to that which is familiar.
to that which is familiar. Uh
level of consciousness. We're attracted
to that which is familiar. Uh and
to that which is familiar. Uh and we
have
have an
have an aversion
have an aversion to
have an aversion to changing.
have an aversion to changing. Uh
have an aversion to changing. Uh we
have an aversion to changing. Uh we like
the
the comfort
have an aversion to changing. Uh we like
the comfort of
the comfort of the
have an aversion to changing. Uh we like
the comfort of the familiar.
the comfort of the familiar. We
have an aversion to changing. Uh we like
the comfort of the familiar. We like
things
things that
things that are
things that are easy
things that are easy and
things that are easy and we
things that are easy and we feel
things that are easy and we feel that
the
the change
things that are easy and we feel that
the change is
the change is going
things that are easy and we feel that
the change is going to
the change is going to take
things that are easy and we feel that
the change is going to take effort.
Uh
Uh we
Uh we may
Uh we may feel
Uh we may feel pride
Uh we may feel pride that
Uh we may feel pride that uh
Uh we may feel pride that uh we
Uh we may feel pride that uh we we
Uh we may feel pride that uh we we know
what
what we
Uh we may feel pride that uh we we know
what we need
what we need to
Uh we may feel pride that uh we we know
what we need to know
what we need to know whereas
Uh we may feel pride that uh we we know
what we need to know whereas humility
what we need to know whereas humility is
you
you don't
you don't know
you don't know much
you don't know much of
you don't know much of anything.
The
The feeling
you don't know much of anything.
The feeling of
The feeling of anger
you don't know much of anything.
The feeling of anger is
The feeling of anger is a
you don't know much of anything.
The feeling of anger is a false
The feeling of anger is a false sense
you don't know much of anything.
The feeling of anger is a false sense of
strength
strength and
strength and the
strength and the dread
strength and the dread is
strength and the dread is to
strength and the dread is to be
strength and the dread is to be to
appear
appear weak
strength and the dread is to be to
appear weak and
appear weak and passivity.
Uh
Uh so
Uh so this
Uh so this is
Uh so this is puffing
Uh so this is puffing yourself
Uh so this is puffing yourself up
Uh so this is puffing yourself up with
anger
anger and
Uh so this is puffing yourself up with
anger and you
anger and you see
Uh so this is puffing yourself up with
anger and you see that
anger and you see that in
Uh so this is puffing yourself up with
anger and you see that in international
politics.
This
This is
politics.
This is the
This is the drivenness
politics.
This is the drivenness to
This is the drivenness to win
politics.
This is the drivenness to win to
This is the drivenness to win to gain.
So
So this
So this is
So this is the
leading
leading edge
So this is the
leading edge of
leading edge of the
So this is the
leading edge of the ego
leading edge of the ego which
So this is the
leading edge of the ego which is
leading edge of the ego which is always
looking
looking for
looking for gain
looking for gain for
looking for gain for gain.
looking for gain for gain. Therefore
looking for gain for gain. Therefore you
don't
don't want
looking for gain for gain. Therefore you
don't want a
don't want a spiritual
looking for gain for gain. Therefore you
don't want a spiritual teacher
don't want a spiritual teacher who's
looking
looking for
looking for gain.
looking for gain. Says
looking for gain. Says we're
looking for gain. Says we're focusing
looking for gain. Says we're focusing on
throughout
throughout the
looking for gain. Says we're focusing on
throughout the teachers
throughout the teachers a
looking for gain. Says we're focusing on
throughout the teachers a little
throughout the teachers a little bit
again
again today.
The
The teacher
again today.
The teacher has
The teacher has nothing
again today.
The teacher has nothing to
The teacher has nothing to gain.
again today.
The teacher has nothing to gain. Nothing
to
to gain.
to gain. They're
to gain. They're not
to gain. They're not interested
to gain. They're not interested in
signing
signing up
to gain. They're not interested in
signing up followers,
signing up followers, selling
to gain. They're not interested in
signing up followers, selling books,
signing up followers, selling books, uh
multi-level
multi-level merchandising,
signing
signing up
multi-level merchandising,
signing up people,
selling
selling them
selling them courses.
selling them courses. There's
selling them courses. There's no
selling them courses. There's no there's
no
no pitch
selling them courses. There's no there's
no pitch to
no pitch to it.
selling them courses. There's no there's
no pitch to it. So
no pitch to it. So that
selling them courses. There's no there's
no pitch to it. So that which
no pitch to it. So that which has
selling them courses. There's no there's
no pitch to it. So that which has a
pitch
pitch has
pitch has an
pitch has an ulterior
pitch has an ulterior motive.
pitch has an ulterior motive. Yeah.
pitch has an ulterior motive. Yeah. Uh
so
so the
pitch has an ulterior motive. Yeah. Uh
so the attraction
so the attraction is
pitch has an ulterior motive. Yeah. Uh
so the attraction is to
so the attraction is to have
pitch has an ulterior motive. Yeah. Uh
so the attraction is to have money
so the attraction is to have money and
the
the aversion
the aversion is
the aversion is poverty.
the aversion is poverty. Why?
the aversion is poverty. Why? Because
they
they think
the aversion is poverty. Why? Because
they think uh
they think uh these
the aversion is poverty. Why? Because
they think uh these things
they think uh these things will
the aversion is poverty. Why? Because
they think uh these things will bring
you
you happiness.
you happiness. and
you happiness. and these
you happiness. and these things
you happiness. and these things will
not.
not. So
you happiness. and these things will
not. So the
not. So the the
you happiness. and these things will
not. So the the cling
not. So the the cling is
you happiness. and these things will
not. So the the cling is to
not. So the the cling is to the
you happiness. and these things will
not. So the the cling is to the illusion
of
of what
of what will
of what will bring
of what will bring you
of what will bring you happiness.
of what will bring you happiness. You'll
be
be happy
of what will bring you happiness. You'll
be happy if
be happy if you
of what will bring you happiness. You'll
be happy if you can
be happy if you can control
of what will bring you happiness. You'll
be happy if you can control everything
and
and the
and the aversion
and the aversion is
and the aversion is to
and the aversion is to accept
and the aversion is to accept things
and the aversion is to accept things the
way
way they
and the aversion is to accept things the
way they are.
Okay.
The
The attraction
Okay.
The attraction is
The attraction is the
Okay.
The attraction is the egotism
The attraction is the egotism that
you're
you're going
you're going to
you're going to save
you're going to save the
you're going to save the world
you're going to save the world instead
of
of surrendering
you're going to save the world instead
of surrendering it
of surrendering it to
you're going to save the world instead
of surrendering it to God.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So these
All right. So these are
All right. So these are all
All right. So these are all emotional
payoffs
payoffs and
All right. So these are all emotional
payoffs and you
payoffs and you can
All right. So these are all emotional
payoffs and you can see
payoffs and you can see that
All right. So these are all emotional
payoffs and you can see that the
attachment
attachment is
attachment is to
attachment is to the
attachment is to the emotional
attachment is to the emotional payoff.
The
The attachment
attachment is to the emotional payoff.
The attachment is
The attachment is not
attachment is to the emotional payoff.
The attachment is not to
The attachment is not to the
attachment is to the emotional payoff.
The attachment is not to the thing
itself
but
but the
itself
but the juice
but the juice you
itself
but the juice you get
but the juice you get out
itself
but the juice you get out of
but the juice you get out of the
itself
but the juice you get out of the thing
itself.
itself. To
itself. To feel
itself. To feel important
itself. To feel important gives
itself. To feel important gives you
juice.
juice. To
itself. To feel important gives you
juice. To feel
juice. To feel you're
itself. To feel important gives you
juice. To feel you're right
juice. To feel you're right and
itself. To feel important gives you
juice. To feel you're right and that
you're
you're winning
you're winning gives
you're winning gives you
you're winning gives you juice.
you're winning gives you juice. It
you're winning gives you juice. It isn't
the
the winning.
you're winning gives you juice. It isn't
the winning. It
the winning. It isn't
you're winning gives you juice. It isn't
the winning. It isn't the
the winning. It isn't the being
you're winning gives you juice. It isn't
the winning. It isn't the being right.
What
What you're
What you're addicted
What you're addicted to
What you're addicted to is
What you're addicted to is the
What you're addicted to is the juice.
What you're addicted to is the juice. So
the
the ego
What you're addicted to is the juice. So
the ego is
the ego is addicted
What you're addicted to is the juice. So
the ego is addicted to
the ego is addicted to the
What you're addicted to is the juice. So
the ego is addicted to the juice.
So
So you
So you only
So you only have
So you only have to
So you only have to surrender
So you only have to surrender your
attachment
attachment to
So you only have to surrender your
attachment to one
attachment to one thing,
So you only have to surrender your
attachment to one thing, not
attachment to one thing, not all
So you only have to surrender your
attachment to one thing, not all these
hundreds
hundreds of
hundreds of things.
hundreds of things. The
hundreds of things. The juice,
hundreds of things. The juice, no matter
what
what it
hundreds of things. The juice, no matter
what it is,
what it is, it's
hundreds of things. The juice, no matter
what it is, it's the
what it is, it's the juice
hundreds of things. The juice, no matter
what it is, it's the juice of
what it is, it's the juice of the
hundreds of things. The juice, no matter
what it is, it's the juice of the thing
and
and not
and not the
and not the thing
and not the thing itself.
So
So you
and not the thing itself.
So you only
So you only have
and not the thing itself.
So you only have to
So you only have to let
and not the thing itself.
So you only have to let go
So you only have to let go of
and not the thing itself.
So you only have to let go of your
attachment
uh
uh to
attachment
uh to the
uh to the juice
attachment
uh to the juice of
uh to the juice of the
attachment
uh to the juice of the ego's
uh to the juice of the ego's payoffs,
whether
whether they're
whether they're anger,
whether they're anger, winning,
whether they're anger, winning, being
better
better than,
whether they're anger, winning, being
better than, they're
better than, they're all
whether they're anger, winning, being
better than, they're all the
better than, they're all the same.
whether they're anger, winning, being
better than, they're all the same. They
give
give you
give you a
give you a certain
give you a certain feeling,
give you a certain feeling, and
give you a certain feeling, and it's
that
that high
give you a certain feeling, and it's
that high that
that high that you're
give you a certain feeling, and it's
that high that you're looking
that high that you're looking for.
You're
You're looking
You're looking for
You're looking for the
You're looking for the high.
That's
That's what
You're looking for the high.
That's what drives
That's what drives the
You're looking for the high.
That's what drives the gambler
That's what drives the gambler back
You're looking for the high.
That's what drives the gambler back to
the
the casino.
the casino. You're
the casino. You're looking
the casino. You're looking for
the casino. You're looking for the
the casino. You're looking for the high.
The
The person
the casino. You're looking for the high.
The person with
The person with his
the casino. You're looking for the high.
The person with his sexual
The person with his sexual addiction,
it's
it's the
it's the high
it's the high of
it's the high of a
it's the high of a new
it's the high of a new conquest,
it's the high of a new conquest, you
know.
So,
So, it's
So, it's the
So, it's the little
So, it's the little high
So, it's the little high that
So, it's the little high that you
So, it's the little high that you get
out
out of
So, it's the little high that you get
out of these
out of these positions.
So, it's the little high that you get
out of these positions. Being
out of these positions. Being right.
Yeah.
Yeah. It's
Yeah. It's boring
Yeah. It's boring being
Yeah. It's boring being right.
Yeah. It's boring being right. More
Yeah. It's boring being right. More fun
to
to be
Yeah. It's boring being right. More fun
to be wrong.
to be wrong. Why?
Yeah. It's boring being right. More fun
to be wrong. Why? Because
to be wrong. Why? Because they
Yeah. It's boring being right. More fun
to be wrong. Why? Because they feel
to be wrong. Why? Because they feel so
good.
It's
It's easy
good.
It's easy to
It's easy to make
good.
It's easy to make somebody
It's easy to make somebody feel
good.
It's easy to make somebody feel good.
Just
Just let
Just let them
Just let them win
Just let them win and
Just let them win and be
Just let them win and be right
Just let them win and be right up
until
until they
Just let them win and be right up
until they catch
until they catch on
Just let them win and be right up
until they catch on to
until they catch on to what
Just let them win and be right up
until they catch on to what you're
until they catch on to what you're up
to.
We
We all
to.
We all want
We all want to
to.
We all want to be
We all want to be fashionable,
to.
We all want to be fashionable, be
We all want to be fashionable, be right,
be
be superior,
be superior, be
be superior, be famous,
be superior, be famous, be
be superior, be famous, be famous.
be superior, be famous, be famous. So,
you
you don't
be superior, be famous, be famous. So,
you don't want
you don't want a
be superior, be famous, be famous. So,
you don't want a teacher
you don't want a teacher that
be superior, be famous, be famous. So,
you don't want a teacher that wants
anything
anything these
anything these things.
anything these things. Being
anything these things. Being famous,
anything these things. Being famous, uh,
being
being superior,
anything these things. Being famous, uh,
being superior, being
being superior, being right.
anything these things. Being famous, uh,
being superior, being right. save
being superior, being right. save the
world.
Uh
Uh all
world.
Uh all right.
Uh all right. The
world.
Uh all right. The attraction
Uh all right. The attraction is
world.
Uh all right. The attraction is here
Uh all right. The attraction is here to
resist
resist and
resist and to
resist and to the
resist and to the resistance
resist and to the resistance is
resist and to the resistance is to
resist and to the resistance is to be
flexible.
We
We want
We want to
We want to change
We want to change the
We want to change the world.
We want to change the world. We
We want to change the world. We want
We want to change the world. We want to
condemn
condemn others
We want to change the world. We want to
condemn others instead
condemn others instead of
We want to change the world. We want to
condemn others instead of forgive
condemn others instead of forgive them.
We
We want
We want to
We want to hold
We want to hold still
We want to hold still let
We want to hold still let go.
And
And here
content
content versus
content versus field
play
play victim,
content versus field
play victim, play
play victim, play revenge.
content versus field
play victim, play revenge. These
play victim, play revenge. These are
content versus field
play victim, play revenge. These are all
the
the payoffs.
the payoffs. So
the payoffs. So you
the payoffs. So you can
the payoffs. So you can trade
the payoffs. So you can trade them
the payoffs. So you can trade them all
in
in for
the payoffs. So you can trade them all
in for the
in for the same
the payoffs. So you can trade them all
in for the same model
in for the same model because
the payoffs. So you can trade them all
in for the same model because they
in for the same model because they all
are
are just
the
the juice
are just
the juice that
the juice that you
are just
the juice that you get
the juice that you get out
are just
the juice that you get out of
the juice that you get out of it.
are just
the juice that you get out of it. So
the juice that you get out of it. So you
can
can say,
can say, well,
can say, well, gee,
can say, well, gee, how
can say, well, gee, how can
can say, well, gee, how can I
can say, well, gee, how can I undo
can say, well, gee, how can I undo all
the
the ego's
can say, well, gee, how can I undo all
the ego's attachments?
the ego's attachments? You
can say, well, gee, how can I undo all
the ego's attachments? You don't
the ego's attachments? You don't have
to.
to. You
to. You just
to. You just have
to. You just have to
to. You just have to undo
to. You just have to undo the
to. You just have to undo the one
attachment
attachment to
to. You just have to undo the one
attachment to the
attachment to the high
to. You just have to undo the one
attachment to the high of
attachment to the high of the
to. You just have to undo the one
attachment to the high of the payoff.
What
What causes
What causes the
What causes the payoff
What causes the payoff is
What causes the payoff is irrelevant.
If
If you're
What causes the payoff is irrelevant.
If you're losing
If you're losing your
What causes the payoff is irrelevant.
If you're losing your money
If you're losing your money gambling,
what
what difference
what difference does
what difference does it
what difference does it make
what difference does it make what
what difference does it make what casino
you're
you're in?
One's
One's as
One's as good
One's as good as
One's as good as another
One's as good as another as
One's as good as another as another.
One's as good as another as another. Is
that
that you're
One's as good as another as another. Is
that you're addicted
that you're addicted to
One's as good as another as another. Is
that you're addicted to the
that you're addicted to the high.
One's as good as another as another. Is
that you're addicted to the high. You're
addicted
addicted to
addicted to the
addicted to the high.
addicted to the high. All
addicted to the high. All right.
addicted to the high. All right. So,
we'll
we'll move
addicted to the high. All right. So,
we'll move on.
we'll move on. There's
addicted to the high. All right. So,
we'll move on. There's only
we'll move on. There's only one
addicted to the high. All right. So,
we'll move on. There's only one thing
you
you got
you got to
you got to let
you got to let go
you got to let go of.
you got to let go of. That
you got to let go of. That makes
you got to let go of. That makes it
you got to let go of. That makes it very
easy,
easy, doesn't
you got to let go of. That makes it very
easy, doesn't it?
Here
Here you
Here you see
Here you see the
Here you see the quality,
Here you see the quality, the
Here you see the quality, the locust,
Here you see the quality, the locust, uh
the
the balance,
Here you see the quality, the locust, uh
the balance, the
passion
passion and
passion and attraction
passion and attraction versus
passion and attraction versus love.
How
How can
passion and attraction versus love.
How can you
How can you tell
passion and attraction versus love.
How can you tell passion
How can you tell passion and
passion and attraction versus love.
How can you tell passion and attraction
from
from actual
from actual love?
from actual love? And
from actual love? And of
from actual love? And of course
from actual love? And of course that
that's
that's very
from actual love? And of course that
that's very uh
that's very uh interesting
from actual love? And of course that
that's very uh interesting the
comparison
comparison of
comparison of the
comparison of the two.
comparison of the two. Of
comparison of the two. Of course
comparison of the two. Of course the
calibration
calibration levels
comparison of the two. Of course the
calibration levels are
calibration levels are quite
comparison of the two. Of course the
calibration levels are quite different
quite
quite different
quite different but
quite different but you
quite different but you can
quite different but you can see
quite different but you can see passion
about
about which
quite different but you can see passion
about which Hollywood
about which Hollywood loves
quite different but you can see passion
about which Hollywood loves to
about which Hollywood loves to to
glorify
is
is um
glorify
is um actually
is um actually calibrates
glorify
is um actually calibrates below
is um actually calibrates below 200.
glorify
is um actually calibrates below 200. It
actually
actually calibrates
uh
uh at
actually calibrates
uh at the
uh at the animal
actually calibrates
uh at the animal instinct
uh at the animal instinct level.
actually calibrates
uh at the animal instinct level. Uh
uh at the animal instinct level. Uh so
when
when the
when the spiritual
when the spiritual teachers
when the spiritual teachers warn
when the spiritual teachers warn you
about
about uh
when the spiritual teachers warn you
about uh relationship
about uh relationship some
when the spiritual teachers warn you
about uh relationship some even
about uh relationship some even forbid
it
what
what they're
it
what they're really
what they're really warning
it
what they're really warning you
what they're really warning you against
is
is this
is this but
is this but then
is this but then it
is this but then it gets
is this but then it gets misinterpreted
as
as to
is this but then it gets misinterpreted
as to warn
as to warn you
is this but then it gets misinterpreted
as to warn you against
as to warn you against relationship
commitment
commitment or
commitment or love
commitment or love which
commitment or love which can
commitment or love which can flourish
very
very nicely
commitment or love which can flourish
very nicely without
very nicely without all
commitment or love which can flourish
very nicely without all the
very nicely without all the downside
commitment or love which can flourish
very nicely without all the downside of
all
all these
all these animal
all these animal instincts
all these animal instincts animal
instincts.
instincts. Okay,
all these animal instincts animal
instincts. Okay, we'll
instincts. Okay, we'll move
all these animal instincts animal
instincts. Okay, we'll move on
instincts. Okay, we'll move on to
all these animal instincts animal
instincts. Okay, we'll move on to the
next.
next. Mhm.
Uhhuh.
We
We we
We we went
We we went through
We we went through before
We we went through before the
We we went through before the levels
We we went through before the levels of
consciousness
consciousness and
We we went through before the levels of
consciousness and we
consciousness and we we're
We we went through before the levels of
consciousness and we we're just
reviewing
reviewing them
reviewing them again.
reviewing them again. The
reviewing them again. The the
reviewing them again. The the attraction
of
of shame
reviewing them again. The the attraction
of shame then
of shame then is
reviewing them again. The the attraction
of shame then is you
of shame then is you get
reviewing them again. The the attraction
of shame then is you get to
of shame then is you get to punish
yourself.
yourself. Therefore,
yourself. Therefore, you're
yourself. Therefore, you're unwilling
yourself. Therefore, you're unwilling to
get
get forgive
yourself. Therefore, you're unwilling to
get forgive yourself.
The
The shame
The shame leads
The shame leads you
The shame leads you into
The shame leads you into depression
The shame leads you into depression in
which
which you
The shame leads you into depression in
which you negate
which you negate life.
The shame leads you into depression in
which you negate life. There's
which you negate life. There's a
resistance
resistance to
resistance to choosing
resistance to choosing life.
We
We could
resistance to choosing life.
We could see
We could see when
resistance to choosing life.
We could see when the
We could see when the when
resistance to choosing life.
We could see when the when the
performers
performers at
performers at the
performers at the Olympics
performers at the Olympics fell
performers at the Olympics fell to
performers at the Olympics fell to their
fell,
fell, they
performers at the Olympics fell to their
fell, they could
fell, they could have
performers at the Olympics fell to their
fell, they could have grabbed
fell, they could have grabbed on
performers at the Olympics fell to their
fell, they could have grabbed on here.
Instead,
Instead, they
Instead, they choose
Instead, they choose life.
Instead, they choose life. Choose
Instead, they choose life. Choose life
and
and keep
Instead, they choose life. Choose life
and keep on
and keep on going.
Instead, they choose life. Choose life
and keep on going. The
and keep on going. The attraction
Instead, they choose life. Choose life
and keep on going. The attraction here
is
is judgmental.
is judgmental. And
is judgmental. And instead
is judgmental. And instead of
surrendering
surrendering it
is judgmental. And instead of
surrendering it to
surrendering it to God,
is judgmental. And instead of
surrendering it to God, we
surrendering it to God, we cling
is judgmental. And instead of
surrendering it to God, we cling to
negativities.
With
With shame,
negativities.
With shame, one
With shame, one wants
negativities.
With shame, one wants to
With shame, one wants to shrink
negativities.
With shame, one wants to shrink and
hide.
hide. sees
hide. sees yourself
hide. sees yourself as
hide. sees yourself as worthless
instead
instead of
hide. sees yourself as worthless
instead of seeing
instead of seeing yourself
hide. sees yourself as worthless
instead of seeing yourself as
instead of seeing yourself as growing.
Condemn
Condemn yourself
Condemn yourself instead
Condemn yourself instead of
Condemn yourself instead of forgiving.
Uh
Uh makes
Condemn yourself instead of forgiving.
Uh makes make
Uh makes make the
Condemn yourself instead of forgiving.
Uh makes make the self
Uh makes make the self less
Condemn yourself instead of forgiving.
Uh makes make the self less instead
Uh makes make the self less instead of
honoring
honoring the
honoring the self.
honoring the self. Self-hatred
honoring the self. Self-hatred instead
of
of self
honoring the self. Self-hatred instead
of self forgiveness.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So then
the
the practicing
All right. So then
the practicing of
the practicing of the
All right. So then
the practicing of the virtues
the practicing of the virtues which
All right. So then
the practicing of the virtues which is
one
one of
one of the
one of the first
one of the first slides
one of the first slides the
one of the first slides the simple
virtues
virtues most
one of the first slides the simple
virtues most of
virtues most of which
one of the first slides the simple
virtues most of which only
virtues most of which only calibrated
one of the first slides the simple
virtues most of which only calibrated in
the
the mid-200s
the mid-200s are
the mid-200s are sufficient
the mid-200s are sufficient to
the mid-200s are sufficient to undo
the mid-200s are sufficient to undo any
of
of these
the mid-200s are sufficient to undo any
of these negativities.
You
You don't
You don't have
You don't have to
You don't have to be
You don't have to be enlightened
You don't have to be enlightened to
You don't have to be enlightened to to
go
go beyond
You don't have to be enlightened to to
go beyond these
go beyond these list.
You don't have to be enlightened to to
go beyond these list. Uh
go beyond these list. Uh all
You don't have to be enlightened to to
go beyond these list. Uh all you
go beyond these list. Uh all you need
You don't have to be enlightened to to
go beyond these list. Uh all you need is
the
the simple
the simple tools
the simple tools of
the simple tools of being
the simple tools of being gracious.
Um
Um to
the simple tools of being gracious.
Um to realize
Um to realize that
the simple tools of being gracious.
Um to realize that your
Um to realize that your own
the simple tools of being gracious.
Um to realize that your own life
Um to realize that your own life is
the simple tools of being gracious.
Um to realize that your own life is a
gift
gift to
gift to have
gift to have reverence
gift to have reverence for
gift to have reverence for life
gift to have reverence for life in
gift to have reverence for life in its
expression
expression as
gift to have reverence for life in its
expression as yourself.
Therefore,
Therefore, you
Therefore, you have
Therefore, you have an
Therefore, you have an obligation
uh
uh to
Therefore, you have an obligation
uh to be
responsible
responsible for
responsible for your
responsible for your life
responsible for your life as
responsible for your life as a
responsible for your life as a gift.
Your
Your life
responsible for your life as a gift.
Your life as
Your life as a
responsible for your life as a gift.
Your life as a gift.
Your life as a gift. Therefore,
unnecessarily
unnecessarily risking
unnecessarily risking one's
unnecessarily risking one's life.
unnecessarily risking one's life. I
unnecessarily risking one's life. I feel
is
is sort
unnecessarily risking one's life. I feel
is sort of
is sort of a
unnecessarily risking one's life. I feel
is sort of a spiritual
is sort of a spiritual violation.
You've
You've been
You've been given
You've been given the
You've been given the gift
You've been given the gift and
You've been given the gift and now
You've been given the gift and now you
risk
risk it
You've been given the gift and now you
risk it for
risk it for a
You've been given the gift and now you
risk it for a cheap
risk it for a cheap thrill.
You've been given the gift and now you
risk it for a cheap thrill. Uh
risk it for a cheap thrill. Uh that's
not
not really
not really integrous.
not really integrous. You
not really integrous. You see,
not really integrous. You see, God
not really integrous. You see, God gives
you
you a
not really integrous. You see, God gives
you a great
you a great gift.
not really integrous. You see, God gives
you a great gift. You
you a great gift. You say,
not really integrous. You see, God gives
you a great gift. You say, "Well,
you a great gift. You say, "Well, I'll
just
just juice
just juice it
just juice it for
just juice it for the
just juice it for the thrills."
just juice it for the thrills." Uh
just juice it for the thrills." Uh is
not
not being
just juice it for the thrills." Uh is
not being the
not being the steward
just juice it for the thrills." Uh is
not being the steward of
not being the steward of your
just juice it for the thrills." Uh is
not being the steward of your own
assets.
So
So spiritual
assets.
So spiritual responsibility,
So spiritual responsibility, you
assets.
So spiritual responsibility, you accept
that
that you
that you are
that you are the
that you are the steward
that you are the steward of
that you are the steward of your
that you are the steward of your assets.
And
spiritual
spiritual devotion
spiritual devotion is
spiritual devotion is a
spiritual devotion is a tremendous
asset.
asset. The
spiritual devotion is a tremendous
asset. The likelihood
asset. The likelihood we
spiritual devotion is a tremendous
asset. The likelihood we said,
recalibrated,
recalibrated, if
recalibrated, if you
recalibrated, if you stop,
recalibrated, if you stop, how
recalibrated, if you stop, how many
people
people would
recalibrated, if you stop, how many
people would you
people would you have
recalibrated, if you stop, how many
people would you have to
people would you have to stop
recalibrated, if you stop, how many
people would you have to stop uh
people would you have to stop uh on
recalibrated, if you stop, how many
people would you have to stop uh on the
street
street before
street before you
street before you find
street before you find somebody
street before you find somebody whose
primary
primary commitment
street before you find somebody whose
primary commitment is
primary commitment is to
street before you find somebody whose
primary commitment is to enlightenment?
One
One in
One in 10
One in 10 million.
One in 10 million. One
One in 10 million. One in
One in 10 million. One in 10
One in 10 million. One in 10 million
people
people are
One in 10 million. One in 10 million
people are devoted.
people are devoted. What
One in 10 million. One in 10 million
people are devoted. What is
people are devoted. What is my
One in 10 million. One in 10 million
people are devoted. What is my life
devoted
devoted to?
devoted to? What
devoted to? What is
devoted to? What is my
devoted to? What is my go
devoted to? What is my go ultimate
devoted to? What is my go ultimate goal?
One
One in
devoted to? What is my go ultimate goal?
One in 10
One in 10 million
devoted to? What is my go ultimate goal?
One in 10 million we'll
One in 10 million we'll say
devoted to? What is my go ultimate goal?
One in 10 million we'll say to
One in 10 million we'll say to become
enlightened.
Very
Very rare.
enlightened.
Very rare. All
Very rare. All right.
enlightened.
Very rare. All right. So
Very rare. All right. So it's
enlightened.
Very rare. All right. So it's one
Very rare. All right. So it's one reason
it's
it's rare
it's rare is
it's rare is because
it's rare is because only
it's rare is because only one
it's rare is because only one in
it's rare is because only one in 10
million
million even
it's rare is because only one in 10
million even adopted
even
even adopted
even adopted as
even adopted as as
even adopted as as a
even adopted as as a serious
consideration
consideration to
even adopted as as a serious
consideration to become
consideration to become enlightened.
Yes.
All
All right.
Yes.
All right. Dualities
All right. Dualities of
Yes.
All right. Dualities of shame.
All right. Dualities of shame. Let's
Yes.
All right. Dualities of shame. Let's go
to
to the
to the next
to the next one.
to the next one. Guilt
to the next one. Guilt and
to the next one. Guilt and hate.
to the next one. Guilt and hate. We
to the next one. Guilt and hate. We we
see
see this
to the next one. Guilt and hate. We we
see this of
see this of course
to the next one. Guilt and hate. We we
see this of course in
see this of course in public.
to the next one. Guilt and hate. We we
see this of course in public. We
see this of course in public. We see
this
this uh
this uh publicly
this uh publicly projected
this uh publicly projected in
this uh publicly projected in the
everyday
everyday news.
this uh publicly projected in the
everyday news. Uh
everyday news. Uh they
this uh publicly projected in the
everyday news. Uh they enjoy
everyday news. Uh they enjoy their
meanness.
meanness. They
meanness. They get
meanness. They get off
meanness. They get off on
meanness. They get off on it.
meanness. They get off on it. Uh
meanness. They get off on it. Uh they
get
get a
meanness. They get off on it. Uh they
get a kick
get a kick out
meanness. They get off on it. Uh they
get a kick out of
get a kick out of it
meanness. They get off on it. Uh they
get a kick out of it and
get a kick out of it and especially
meanness. They get off on it. Uh they
get a kick out of it and especially if
they
they can
they can get
they can get it
they can get it on
they can get it on television.
they can get it on television. I
they can get it on television. I think
the
the television
they can get it on television. I think
the television and
the television and the
they can get it on television. I think
the television and the media
the television and the media have
they can get it on television. I think
the television and the media have really
had
had a
had a profound
had a profound effect
had a profound effect on
had a profound effect on man's
had a profound effect on man's morality
uh
uh and
had a profound effect on man's morality
uh and uh
uh and uh overall
had a profound effect on man's morality
uh and uh overall level
uh and uh overall level of
consciousness.
consciousness. Let's
consciousness. Let's see
consciousness. Let's see what's
consciousness. Let's see what's the
overall
overall level
consciousness. Let's see what's the
overall level of
overall level of consciousness
mankind
mankind today.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, we
mankind today.
>> Okay, we have
>> Okay, we have 15
mankind today.
>> Okay, we have 15 minutes.
>> Okay, we have 15 minutes. We
mankind today.
>> Okay, we have 15 minutes. We have
>> Okay, we have 15 minutes. We have 15
minutes.
>> What's
>> What's the
minutes.
>> What's the overall
>> What's the overall level
minutes.
>> What's the overall level of
consciousness
consciousness of
consciousness of mankind
consciousness of mankind today?
consciousness of mankind today? It's
over
over 205
consciousness of mankind today? It's
over 205 206
205 206.
It
It was
205 206.
It was 207.
It
It has
It has gone
It has gone down
It has gone down two
It has gone down two points.
It has gone down two points. That's
It has gone down two points. That's what
I
I was
It has gone down two points. That's what
I was afraid.
I was afraid. I
It has gone down two points. That's what
I was afraid. I thought
I was afraid. I thought it
It has gone down two points. That's what
I was afraid. I thought it did.
>> It
>> It did.
>> Oh
>> Oh yes.
>> It did.
>> Oh yes. I
>> Oh yes. I felt
>> It did.
>> Oh yes. I felt it
>> Oh yes. I felt it all
>> It did.
>> Oh yes. I felt it all over.
>> Oh yes. I felt it all over. Mhm.
>> It did.
>> Oh yes. I felt it all over. Mhm. The
very
very severe,
very severe, you
very severe, you see,
very severe, you see, because
very severe, you see, because your
calvary
calvary level
very severe, you see, because your
calvary level can
calvary level can go
very severe, you see, because your
calvary level can go up
calvary level can go up and
very severe, you see, because your
calvary level can go up and down
calvary level can go up and down when
you
you make
you make um
you make um seriously
you make um seriously non-intigorous
decisions.
Speak
Speak them
Speak them out
Speak them out in
Speak them out in public,
get
get the
Speak them out in public,
get the press
get the press to
Speak them out in public,
get the press to follow
get the press to follow you.
Speak them out in public,
get the press to follow you. Uh
get the press to follow you. Uh no,
non-integrity
non-integrity has
non-integrity has been
non-integrity has been given
um
um a
non-integrity has been given
um a wide
um a wide swad
non-integrity has been given
um a wide swad by
um a wide swad by the
non-integrity has been given
um a wide swad by the media.
um a wide swad by the media. Many
non-integrity has been given
um a wide swad by the media. Many of the
media
media themselves
media themselves by
media themselves by lack
media themselves by lack of
media themselves by lack of integrity
have
have given
media themselves by lack of integrity
have given great
have given great support
media themselves by lack of integrity
have given great support to
have given great support to people
media themselves by lack of integrity
have given great support to people who
are
are powerfully
are powerfully non-intigorous
are powerfully non-intigorous speakers.
So
So what
are powerfully non-intigorous speakers.
So what happens
So what happens is
are powerfully non-intigorous speakers.
So what happens is they
So what happens is they glamorize
are powerfully non-intigorous speakers.
So what happens is they glamorize that
which
which is
which is not
which is not integrous
which is not integrous by
which is not integrous by giving
which is not integrous by giving it
which is not integrous by giving it a
lot
lot of
which is not integrous by giving it a
lot of attention.
lot of attention. You've
which is not integrous by giving it a
lot of attention. You've already
glamorized
glamorized it,
glamorized it, right?
glamorized it, right? I
glamorized it, right? I mean
glamorized it, right? I mean it's
glamorized it, right? I mean it's a
nothing.
nothing. It's
glamorized it, right? I mean it's a
nothing. It's another
nothing. It's another idiot
glamorized it, right? I mean it's a
nothing. It's another idiot in
nothing. It's another idiot in the
world.
world. But
world. But they
world. But they capture
world. But they capture the
world. But they capture the camera.
The
The consciousness
world. But they capture the camera.
The consciousness level
The consciousness level of
world. But they capture the camera.
The consciousness level of all
The consciousness level of all of
mankind
mankind has
mankind has gone
mankind has gone down
mankind has gone down two
mankind has gone down two points.
Well,
we
we can
we can say
we can say no
we can say no to
we can say no to it
we can say no to it as
we can say no to it as a
we can say no to it as a person.
we can say no to it as a person. Okay.
The
The dualities
we can say no to it as a person. Okay.
The dualities of
The dualities of guilt
we can say no to it as a person. Okay.
The dualities of guilt and
The dualities of guilt and shame.
right.
right. You
right. You see
right. You see how
right. You see how quickly
right. You see how quickly the
right. You see how quickly the media
jump
jump in
right. You see how quickly the media
jump in to
jump in to to
right. You see how quickly the media
jump in to to cause
jump in to to cause blame
right. You see how quickly the media
jump in to to cause blame and
jump in to to cause blame and they
right. You see how quickly the media
jump in to to cause blame and they don't
mind
mind twisting
mind twisting the
mind twisting the facts
mind twisting the facts to
mind twisting the facts to make
mind twisting the facts to make the
blame
blame sound
mind twisting the facts to make the
blame sound more
blame sound more uh
mind twisting the facts to make the
blame sound more uh viciously
uh
devised.
devised. You
uh
devised. You might
devised. You might say
uh
devised. You might say per
devised. You might say per purposely
purposely
purposely misstate
purposely misstate purposeful
misstatement
misstatement of
purposely misstate purposeful
misstatement of facts.
misstatement of facts. I
purposely misstate purposeful
misstatement of facts. I think
misstatement of facts. I think that's
what
what it
what it is.
what it is. Purposeful
purposeful
purposeful misstatement
what it is. Purposeful
purposeful misstatement of
misinterpretation
misinterpretation of
misinterpretation of facts.
misinterpretation of facts. Yes,
misinterpretation of facts. Yes, that's
what's
what's going
misinterpretation of facts. Yes, that's
what's going on.
what's going on. and
misinterpretation of facts. Yes, that's
what's going on. and the
what's going on. and the media
misinterpretation of facts. Yes, that's
what's going on. and the media are
what's going on. and the media are the
source
source and
source and the
source and the support
source and the support of
source and the support of it.
Let's
Let's take
source and the support of it.
Let's take the
Let's take the idea
of
of uh
uh
uh they
of uh
uh they always
uh they always say
of uh
uh they always say um
uh they always say um you
of uh
uh they always say um you take
uh they always say um you take your
choice.
choice. There's
choice. There's the
choice. There's the pro
choice. There's the pro and
choice. There's the pro and then
choice. There's the pro and then to
choice. There's the pro and then to be
fair
fair you
choice. There's the pro and then to be
fair you got
fair you got to
choice. There's the pro and then to be
fair you got to have
fair you got to have the
choice. There's the pro and then to be
fair you got to have the con.
fair you got to have the con. See?
So
So E
So E equals
So E equals MC²
So E equals MC² then
So E equals MC² then they
So E equals MC² then they have
So E equals MC² then they have the
So E equals MC² then they have the con.
I
I don't
So E equals MC² then they have the con.
I don't think
I don't think E
So E equals MC² then they have the con.
I don't think E equals
I don't think E equals MC²
So E equals MC² then they have the con.
I don't think E equals MC² gets
I don't think E equals MC² gets equal
time.
time. You
time. You know what
time. You know what I'm
time. You know what I'm saying?
time. You know what I'm saying? Because
they're
they're trying
time. You know what I'm saying? Because
they're trying to
they're trying to be
time. You know what I'm saying? Because
they're trying to be fair
they're trying to be fair and
time. You know what I'm saying? Because
they're trying to be fair and balanced.
What
What they
What they do
What they do is
What they do is they
What they do is they give
What they do is they give that
What they do is they give that which
What they do is they give that which is
idiotic
idiotic and
What they do is they give that which is
idiotic and calibrates
idiotic and calibrates about
What they do is they give that which is
idiotic and calibrates about 9
idiotic and calibrates about 9 equal
equal
equal time
equal time with
equal time with something
equal time with something that
calibrates
calibrates at
equal time with something that
calibrates at 450.
calibrates at 450. And
equal time with something that
calibrates at 450. And you
calibrates at 450. And you see
equal time with something that
calibrates at 450. And you see how
calibrates at 450. And you see how the
warp
warp comes
warp comes out
warp comes out of
warp comes out of that
warp comes out of that because
warp comes out of that because the
warp comes out of that because the mind
of
of the
warp comes out of that because the mind
of the child
doesn't
doesn't see
doesn't see the
doesn't see the difference.
doesn't see the difference. See,
doesn't see the difference. See, we
doesn't see the difference. See, we know
that
that physiologically
the
the brain
the brain of
the brain of the
the brain of the child
the brain of the child cannot
differentiate
uh
uh fictional
uh fictional violence
uh fictional violence from
uh fictional violence from true
violence.
violence. A
uh fictional violence from true
violence. A child's
violence. A child's brain
uh fictional violence from true
violence. A child's brain cannot
differentiate
whether
a
a fictional
a fictional character
a fictional character is
a fictional character is getting
a fictional character is getting killed
or
or this
a fictional character is getting killed
or this is
or this is the
a fictional character is getting killed
or this is the news
or this is the news real
a fictional character is getting killed
or this is the news real of
or this is the news real of a
a fictional character is getting killed
or this is the news real of a real
person
person getting
person getting killed.
person getting killed. The
person getting killed. The brain
person getting killed. The brain of
person getting killed. The brain of the
child
child cannot
differentiate.
differentiate. So
differentiate. So the
differentiate. So the downside
differentiate. So the downside then
differentiate. So the downside then of
human
human life
differentiate. So the downside then of
human life is
human life is the
differentiate. So the downside then of
human life is the naivity
human life is the naivity and
differentiate. So the downside then of
human life is the naivity and the
human life is the naivity and the basic
innocence
innocence of
innocence of the
innocence of the child
innocence of the child within
innocence of the child within us.
innocence of the child within us. The
child
child within
innocence of the child within us. The
child within us
child within us to
innocence of the child within us. The
child within us to whom
I
I got
I got it
to
to the
I got it
to the child
to the child within
I got it
to the child within us
to the child within us the
I got it
to the child within us the media
to the child within us the media have
become
become the
become the parent.
become the parent. Resist
become the parent. Resist by
become the parent. Resist by God
become the parent. Resist by God we
become the parent. Resist by God we got
it.
The
The media
The media have
The media have become
The media have become the
The media have become the parent.
Who
Who cares
The media have become the parent.
Who cares what
Who cares what your
The media have become the parent.
Who cares what your mother
Who cares what your mother says
The media have become the parent.
Who cares what your mother says when
Who cares what your mother says when the
media
media says
media says that?
media says that? We
media says that? We got
media says that? We got it.
Okay.
Okay. So
media says that? We got it.
Okay. So the
Okay. So the declination
media says that? We got it.
Okay. So the declination of
Okay. So the declination of integrity
media says that? We got it.
Okay. So the declination of integrity in
the
the world
the world today
the world today is
the world today is part
the world today is part and
the world today is part and parcel
the world today is part and parcel of
the
the media
the world today is part and parcel of
the media and
the media and that
the world today is part and parcel of
the media and that which
the media and that which is
non-integrous
non-integrous likes
non-integrous likes to
non-integrous likes to control
non-integrous likes to control the
non-integrous likes to control the media
and
and so
non-integrous likes to control the media
and so you
and so you see
non-integrous likes to control the media
and so you see the
and so you see the constant
non-integrous likes to control the media
and so you see the constant slant.
Constant
Constant slant.
Ahuh.
Ahuh. Well,
Constant slant.
Ahuh. Well, that
Ahuh. Well, that could
Constant slant.
Ahuh. Well, that could be
Ahuh. Well, that could be the
Constant slant.
Ahuh. Well, that could be the downfall
of
of civilization.
of civilization. Yeah.
Well,
Well, civilization,
of civilization. Yeah.
Well, civilization, you
Well, civilization, you had
of civilization. Yeah.
Well, civilization, you had your
Well, civilization, you had your chance.
No,
No, you
No, you see,
No, you see, it's
No, you see, it's the
No, you see, it's the the
No, you see, it's the the warping
No, you see, it's the the warping of
No, you see, it's the the warping of the
idea
idea of
No, you see, it's the the warping of the
idea of fairness
idea of fairness and
No, you see, it's the the warping of the
idea of fairness and free
idea of fairness and free speech.
No, you see, it's the the warping of the
idea of fairness and free speech. Evil
should
should have
should have equal
should have equal time
should have equal time with
should have equal time with goodness
should have equal time with goodness to
be
be fair,
right?
right? Criminals
right? Criminals should
right? Criminals should have
right? Criminals should have an
right? Criminals should have an equal
vote.
Equal
Equal vote.
Yeah.
Yeah. Okay.
Equal vote.
Yeah. Okay. In
Yeah. Okay. In a
Equal vote.
Yeah. Okay. In a world
Yeah. Okay. In a world in
Equal vote.
Yeah. Okay. In a world in which
Yeah. Okay. In a world in which 85%
calibrate
calibrate below
calibrate below 200,
in
in America
calibrate below 200,
in America it's
in America it's 49%.
you
you now
you now give
you now give the
you now give the media
you now give the media the
you now give the media the power
you now give the media the power over
the
the consciousness
you now give the media the power over
the consciousness of
the consciousness of mankind.
So
So therefore
So therefore the
So therefore the responsibility
So therefore the responsibility there
that
that has
So therefore the responsibility there
that has to
that has to be
So therefore the responsibility there
that has to be looked
that has to be looked at
is
is the
is the responsibility
is the responsibility of
is the responsibility of the
is the responsibility of the media.
Each
Each thing
is the responsibility of the media.
Each thing that
Each thing that occurs
is the responsibility of the media.
Each thing that occurs and
Each thing that occurs and has
is the responsibility of the media.
Each thing that occurs and has its
Each thing that occurs and has its own
responsibility.
responsibility. We
responsibility. We spoke
responsibility. We spoke of
responsibility. We spoke of the
responsibility
responsibility of
responsibility. We spoke of the
responsibility of the
responsibility of the spiritual
responsibility. We spoke of the
responsibility of the spiritual teacher,
the
the responsibility
the responsibility of
the responsibility of the
the responsibility of the student,
responsibility
responsibility of
the responsibility of the student,
responsibility of the
responsibility of the parent.
So
So somehow
So somehow the
So somehow the media
So somehow the media had
So somehow the media had to
So somehow the media had to be
So somehow the media had to be made
aware
aware of
So somehow the media had to be made
aware of their
aware of their responsibility.
Okay.
Uh
Uh guilt
Okay.
Uh guilt and
Uh guilt and hate
Okay.
Uh guilt and hate then
Uh guilt and hate then there's
Okay.
Uh guilt and hate then there's a
Uh guilt and hate then there's a big
payoff
payoff to
payoff to guilt
payoff to guilt and
payoff to guilt and hate.
payoff to guilt and hate. The
payoff to guilt and hate. The media
really
really exploited
payoff to guilt and hate. The media
really exploited to
really exploited to the
payoff to guilt and hate. The media
really exploited to the fullest.
really exploited to the fullest. Exploit
it
it to
it to the
it to the fullest.
it to the fullest. I
it to the fullest. I remember
it to the fullest. I remember when
President
President Ford,
it to the fullest. I remember when
President Ford, I
President Ford, I think
it to the fullest. I remember when
President Ford, I think it
President Ford, I think it was
it to the fullest. I remember when
President Ford, I think it was stumbled
coming
coming out
coming out of
coming out of the
coming out of the stairway
coming out of the stairway of
coming out of the stairway of a
coming out of the stairway of a plane.
The
The media
coming out of the stairway of a plane.
The media just
The media just made
coming out of the stairway of a plane.
The media just made a
The media just made a big
coming out of the stairway of a plane.
The media just made a big deal
The media just made a big deal out
coming out of the stairway of a plane.
The media just made a big deal out of
it.
Think
Think had
it.
Think had the
Think had the media
it.
Think had the media been
Think had the media been like
it.
Think had the media been like that
Think had the media been like that in
World
World War
World War II
World War II with
World War II with all
World War II with all the
World War II with all the cameras
World War II with all the cameras to
World War II with all the cameras to be
focused
focused on
World War II with all the cameras to be
focused on Roosevelt's
paralyzed
paralyzed legs
paralyzed legs and
paralyzed legs and the
paralyzed legs and the wheelchair
paralyzed legs and the wheelchair hidden
behind
behind the
paralyzed legs and the wheelchair hidden
behind the speaking
behind the speaking stand
paralyzed legs and the wheelchair hidden
behind the speaking stand and
behind the speaking stand and the
today's
today's media
today's media would
today's media would just
today's media would just focus
today's media would just focus on
today's media would just focus on his
crippleness,
crippleness, his
today's media would just focus on his
crippleness, his polio,
crippleness, his polio, the
today's media would just focus on his
crippleness, his polio, the paralysis
crippleness, his polio, the paralysis it
left
left him
left him with.
It
It wouldn't
left him with.
It wouldn't focus
It wouldn't focus on,
left him with.
It wouldn't focus on, you
It wouldn't focus on, you know,
left him with.
It wouldn't focus on, you know, he
It wouldn't focus on, you know, he had
left him with.
It wouldn't focus on, you know, he had a
pretty
pretty good
pretty good head
pretty good head on
pretty good head on him,
pretty good head on him, won
pretty good head on him, won the
election
election bunch
pretty good head on him, won the
election bunch of
election bunch of times
pretty good head on him, won the
election bunch of times and
election bunch of times and accomplished
great
great things
great things besides
great things besides he
great things besides he and
great things besides he and Winston
Churchill,
Churchill, you
great things besides he and Winston
Churchill, you know,
Churchill, you know, help
great things besides he and Winston
Churchill, you know, help win
Churchill, you know, help win the
great things besides he and Winston
Churchill, you know, help win the war.
So,
So, but
So, but in
So, but in today's
So, but in today's world,
So, but in today's world, that's
So, but in today's world, that's all
So, but in today's world, that's all you
hear
hear about.
So, but in today's world, that's all you
hear about. Uhhuh.
hear about. Uhhuh. I
So, but in today's world, that's all you
hear about. Uhhuh. I could
hear about. Uhhuh. I could just
So, but in today's world, that's all you
hear about. Uhhuh. I could just hear
them
them now.
Okay.
Okay. So,
them now.
Okay. So, the
Okay. So, the dualities
them now.
Okay. So, the dualities of
Okay. So, the dualities of uh
them now.
Okay. So, the dualities of uh guilt
Okay. So, the dualities of uh guilt and
hate.
hate. Let's
hate. Let's go
hate. Let's go to
hate. Let's go to the
hate. Let's go to the next
hate. Let's go to the next one.
Oh,
apathy.
I
I can't
apathy.
I can't be
I can't be bothered
apathy.
I can't be bothered doing
I can't be bothered doing this
apathy.
I can't be bothered doing this one.
What
What difference
What difference does
What difference does it
What difference does it make
What difference does it make anyway?
It
It didn't
What difference does it make anyway?
It didn't do
It didn't do any
What difference does it make anyway?
It didn't do any good
It didn't do any good anyway.
What difference does it make anyway?
It didn't do any good anyway. What
It didn't do any good anyway. What the
hell
hell did?
It's
It's hopeless
hell did?
It's hopeless anyway.
What
What good
What good is
What good is mankind?
What good is mankind? I
What good is mankind? I can't
What good is mankind? I can't seem
What good is mankind? I can't seem to
What good is mankind? I can't seem to do
anything
anything right.
Poor
Poor you.
Poor you. I
Poor you. I think
Poor you. I think I'll
Poor you. I think I'll just
Poor you. I think I'll just quit.
Either
Either that
Poor you. I think I'll just quit.
Either that maybe
Either that maybe the
Poor you. I think I'll just quit.
Either that maybe the Olympics
Either that maybe the Olympics will
Poor you. I think I'll just quit.
Either that maybe the Olympics will save
us.
us. Huh?
us. Huh? Cuz
us. Huh? Cuz there
us. Huh? Cuz there at
us. Huh? Cuz there at least
us. Huh? Cuz there at least the
us. Huh? Cuz there at least the media
are
are giving
us. Huh? Cuz there at least the media
are giving integrity,
are giving integrity, courage,
us. Huh? Cuz there at least the media
are giving integrity, courage, strength,
stamina,
stamina, self-discipline.
A
A version
stamina, self-discipline.
A version here
A version here of
stamina, self-discipline.
A version here of apathy
A version here of apathy is
stamina, self-discipline.
A version here of apathy is caring
A version here of apathy is caring for
things,
things, taking
things, taking action,
things, taking action, seeing
things, taking action, seeing yourself
as
as capable,
things, taking action, seeing yourself
as capable, hope,
as capable, hope, see
things, taking action, seeing yourself
as capable, hope, see your
as capable, hope, see your self-worth
things, taking action, seeing yourself
as capable, hope, see your self-worth as
a
a gift
a gift from
a gift from God.
a gift from God. All
a gift from God. All right.
a gift from God. All right. So
a gift from God. All right. So in
a gift from God. All right. So in a
a gift from God. All right. So in a way
the
the protection
a gift from God. All right. So in a way
the protection from
the protection from all
a gift from God. All right. So in a way
the protection from all these
the protection from all these things
then
uh
I
I can't
I can't find
I can't find the
I can't find the right
I can't find the right word
I can't find the right word is
um
um it
I can't find the right word is
um it will
um it will come
I can't find the right word is
um it will come to
um it will come to me
selfworth.
Yeah.
Yeah. You
selfworth.
Yeah. You see
Yeah. You see when
selfworth.
Yeah. You see when you're
Yeah. You see when you're the
selfworth.
Yeah. You see when you're the steward
Yeah. You see when you're the steward of
the
the gift
the gift of
the gift of life
the gift of life you're
the gift of life you're acknowledging
God
God as
the gift of life you're acknowledging
God as creator
God as creator and
the gift of life you're acknowledging
God as creator and that
God as creator and that recontextualizes
your
your life.
Recontextualizes
Recontextualizes your
your life.
Recontextualizes your life.
Therefore,
Therefore, devotion,
Therefore, devotion, acknowledgment
Therefore, devotion, acknowledgment of
God
God as
Therefore, devotion, acknowledgment of
God as one's
God as one's creator
is
is an
is an enormous
is an enormous sense
is an enormous sense of
is an enormous sense of empowerment.
So
So when
is an enormous sense of empowerment.
So when we
So when we see
is an enormous sense of empowerment.
So when we see the
So when we see the performers
cross
cross themsel
cross themsel and
cross themsel and thank
cross themsel and thank God
cross themsel and thank God that's
cross themsel and thank God that's very
very
very powerful
and
and of
and of course
and of course that
and of course that is
and of course that is impacting
and of course that is impacting all
and of course that is impacting all the
viewers
viewers who
and of course that is impacting all the
viewers who see
viewers who see that
and of course that is impacting all the
viewers who see that the
viewers who see that the great
and of course that is impacting all the
viewers who see that the great warriors,
the
the great
the great sports
the great sports figures
the great sports figures also
acknowledge
acknowledge divinity
the great sports figures also
acknowledge divinity as
acknowledge divinity as their
the great sports figures also
acknowledge divinity as their creator.
So
So counterbalancing
So counterbalancing the
So counterbalancing the decline
So counterbalancing the decline created
by
by the
So counterbalancing the decline created
by the media
by the media we
So counterbalancing the decline created
by the media we have
by the media we have such
So counterbalancing the decline created
by the media we have such events
uh
uh as
uh as that
uh as that which
uh as that which tend
uh as that which tend to
uh as that which tend to counteract
uh as that which tend to counteract it
you
you know.
uh as that which tend to counteract it
you know. Okay.
you know. Okay. Mhm.
Eventually
Eventually the
Eventually the pathway
Eventually the pathway of
Eventually the pathway of failure
Eventually the pathway of failure brings
a
a reaction
Eventually the pathway of failure brings
a reaction formation
a reaction formation and
Eventually the pathway of failure brings
a reaction formation and therefore
a reaction formation and therefore I'm
counting
counting on
counting on a
counting on a reaction
counting on a reaction formation
counting on a reaction formation that
the
the lack
counting on a reaction formation that
the lack of
the lack of integrity
counting on a reaction formation that
the lack of integrity will
the lack of integrity will eventually
rebound
rebound upon
rebound upon itself.
rebound upon itself. You
rebound upon itself. You will
rebound upon itself. You will eventually
when
when you
rebound upon itself. You will eventually
when you go
when you go too
rebound upon itself. You will eventually
when you go too far,
when you go too far, you
rebound upon itself. You will eventually
when you go too far, you get
when you go too far, you get a
rebound upon itself. You will eventually
when you go too far, you get a kickback.
>> Yeah.
If
If one
>> Yeah.
If one political
If one political party
>> Yeah.
If one political party goes
If one political party goes too
>> Yeah.
If one political party goes too too
If one political party goes too too far
on
on a
on a limb
on a limb to
on a limb to attack
on a limb to attack the
on a limb to attack the other,
on a limb to attack the other, you
on a limb to attack the other, you get
on a limb to attack the other, you get a
reaction.
I
I say
I say Michael,
I say Michael, whatever
I say Michael, whatever his
I say Michael, whatever his name
I say Michael, whatever his name was,
elected
elected Bush.
I say Michael, whatever his name was,
elected Bush. Michael.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Michael
>> Yeah. Michael Moore
>> Yeah. Michael Moore elected
>> Yeah. Michael Moore elected Bush.
Because
Because when
>> Yeah. Michael Moore elected Bush.
Because when you
Because when you attack
>> Yeah. Michael Moore elected Bush.
Because when you attack something,
everybody
everybody wants
everybody wants to
everybody wants to defend
everybody wants to defend it.
everybody wants to defend it. See?
everybody wants to defend it. See? Yeah.
So,
So, I
everybody wants to defend it. See? Yeah.
So, I thought
So, I thought Michael
everybody wants to defend it. See? Yeah.
So, I thought Michael Moore
So, I thought Michael Moore probably
everybody wants to defend it. See? Yeah.
So, I thought Michael Moore probably got
elected
elected him.
All right.
All right. The
elected him.
All right. The dualities
All right. The dualities of
elected him.
All right. The dualities of grief,
All right. The dualities of grief, the
attraction
uh
uh is
attraction
uh is living
uh is living living
attraction
uh is living living in
uh is living living in the
attraction
uh is living living in the past.
uh is living living in the past. Grief
is
is clinging
is clinging to
is clinging to the
is clinging to the past
is clinging to the past instead
is clinging to the past instead of
relinquishing
it
it to
it to God.
it to God. also
it to God. also thinking
it to God. also thinking that
it to God. also thinking that the
it to God. also thinking that the source
of
of happiness
it to God. also thinking that the source
of happiness has
of happiness has been
it to God. also thinking that the source
of happiness has been lost
of happiness has been lost and
it to God. also thinking that the source
of happiness has been lost and the
source
source of
source of happiness
source of happiness cannot
source of happiness cannot be
source of happiness cannot be lost
because
because the
source of happiness cannot be lost
because the source
because the source of
source of happiness cannot be lost
because the source of happiness
because the source of happiness is
source of happiness cannot be lost
because the source of happiness is the
presence
presence of
presence of divinity
presence of divinity within
presence of divinity within oneself
presence of divinity within oneself as
the
the source
presence of divinity within oneself as
the source of
the source of one's
presence of divinity within oneself as
the source of one's existence.
So
So humble
So humble gratitude
So humble gratitude for
So humble gratitude for that
So humble gratitude for that tends
So humble gratitude for that tends to
counter
make
make up
make up for
make up for loss.
make up for loss. The
make up for loss. The aversion
make up for loss. The aversion is
make up for loss. The aversion is to
make up for loss. The aversion is to let
go
go of
make up for loss. The aversion is to let
go of the
go of the past
make up for loss. The aversion is to let
go of the past to
go of the past to accept
make up for loss. The aversion is to let
go of the past to accept the
go of the past to accept the change.
make up for loss. The aversion is to let
go of the past to accept the change. uh
the
the willingness
the willingness to
the willingness to surrender
the willingness to surrender your
willful
willful willfulness
the willingness to surrender your
willful willfulness to
willful willfulness to God.
Every
Every loss
Every loss is
Every loss is also
Every loss is also an
Every loss is also an opportunity
uh
uh of
Every loss is also an opportunity
uh of freedom.
uh of freedom. Every
Every loss is also an opportunity
uh of freedom. Every loss
uh of freedom. Every loss is
Every loss is also an opportunity
uh of freedom. Every loss is also
uh of freedom. Every loss is also a
freedom.
freedom. You're
freedom. You're free
freedom. You're free now
freedom. You're free now to
freedom. You're free now to move
freedom. You're free now to move on.
You
You if
freedom. You're free now to move on.
You if the
You if the body
freedom. You're free now to move on.
You if the body doesn't
You if the body doesn't work
freedom. You're free now to move on.
You if the body doesn't work as
You if the body doesn't work as well
anymore,
anymore, you're
anymore, you're free
anymore, you're free to
anymore, you're free to really
anymore, you're free to really devote
yourself
yourself to
anymore, you're free to really devote
yourself to your
yourself to your spirit
anymore, you're free to really devote
yourself to your spirit and
yourself to your spirit and your
intellect.
intellect. In
intellect. In other
intellect. In other words,
intellect. In other words, there's
intellect. In other words, there's an
upside.
Acceptance
Acceptance then
Acceptance then brings
Acceptance then brings an
Acceptance then brings an awareness
and
and you
Acceptance then brings an awareness
and you see
and you see that
Acceptance then brings an awareness
and you see that the
and you see that the source
Acceptance then brings an awareness
and you see that the source of
and you see that the source of happiness
is
is within.
is within. Okay,
is within. Okay, we'll
is within. Okay, we'll move
is within. Okay, we'll move to
is within. Okay, we'll move to the
is within. Okay, we'll move to the next
one.
All
All negative
All negative feelings
All negative feelings are
All negative feelings are due
All negative feelings are due to
feelings
feelings seeing
All negative feelings are due to
feelings seeing the
feelings seeing the source
All negative feelings are due to
feelings seeing the source of
feelings seeing the source of happiness
as
as outside
as outside yourself.
What
>> you
>> you have
>> h
>> h three
>> you have
>> h three minutes.
>> What?
No.
Next
Next slide.
What
What is
Next slide.
What is the
What is the desire?
Next slide.
What is the desire? I
What is the desire? I want
Next slide.
What is the desire? I want the
What is the desire? I want the next
slide
slide to
slide to be
slide to be up
slide to be up immediately.
slide to be up immediately. I
slide to be up immediately. I want
slide to be up immediately. I want to
control
control it.
slide to be up immediately. I want to
control it. I
control it. I want
slide to be up immediately. I want to
control it. I want to
control it. I want to curve
slide to be up immediately. I want to
control it. I want to curve it.
control it. I want to curve it. I
slide to be up immediately. I want to
control it. I want to curve it. I want
to
to force
to force it.
to force it. I'm
to force it. I'm going
to force it. I'm going to
to force it. I'm going to have
to force it. I'm going to have success.
I'm
I'm going
to force it. I'm going to have success.
I'm going to
I'm going to be
to force it. I'm going to have success.
I'm going to be severally
I'm going to be severally aggressive.
to force it. I'm going to have success.
I'm going to be severally aggressive. I
want
want to
want to defend
want to defend it.
want to defend it. Conquest.
And
And of
want to defend it. Conquest.
And of course,
And of course, these
want to defend it. Conquest.
And of course, these are
And of course, these are the
want to defend it. Conquest.
And of course, these are the aversions.
Loss,
Loss, poverty,
Loss, poverty, etc.
Loss, poverty, etc. If
Loss, poverty, etc. If you
Loss, poverty, etc. If you don't
Loss, poverty, etc. If you don't resist
poverty,
poverty, there's
Loss, poverty, etc. If you don't resist
poverty, there's really
poverty, there's really nothing
Loss, poverty, etc. If you don't resist
poverty, there's really nothing wrong
with
with it.
with it. I
with it. I was
with it. I was happier
with it. I was happier poor.
with it. I was happier poor. I've
with it. I was happier poor. I've been
poor,
poor, I've
with it. I was happier poor. I've been
poor, I've been
poor, I've been rich.
with it. I was happier poor. I've been
poor, I've been rich. And
poor, I've been rich. And uh
with it. I was happier poor. I've been
poor, I've been rich. And uh frankly,
there's
there's no
there's no difference
there's no difference between
there's no difference between the
there's no difference between the two
because
because you
there's no difference between the two
because you either
because you either get
there's no difference between the two
because you either get up
because you either get up that
there's no difference between the two
because you either get up that day,
you're
you're either
you're either happy
you're either happy or
you're either happy or you're
you're either happy or you're not
you're either happy or you're not happy.
And
And um
you're either happy or you're not happy.
And um especially
And um especially when
you're either happy or you're not happy.
And um especially when I
And um especially when I first
you're either happy or you're not happy.
And um especially when I first came
And um especially when I first came out
west,
west, you
west, you know,
west, you know, I
west, you know, I I
west, you know, I I slept
west, you know, I I slept on
west, you know, I I slept on a
west, you know, I I slept on a cot
west, you know, I I slept on a cot I
west, you know, I I slept on a cot I got
in
in the
west, you know, I I slept on a cot I got
in the dime
in the dime store.
west, you know, I I slept on a cot I got
in the dime store. We
in the dime store. We had
west, you know, I I slept on a cot I got
in the dime store. We had an
in the dime store. We had an apple
west, you know, I I slept on a cot I got
in the dime store. We had an apple to
celebrate.
celebrate. It
celebrate. It was
celebrate. It was Saturday
celebrate. It was Saturday night.
I
I tested
celebrate. It was Saturday night.
I tested out
I tested out the
celebrate. It was Saturday night.
I tested out the course
I tested out the course of
celebrate. It was Saturday night.
I tested out the course of miracles
I tested out the course of miracles that
you
you could
you could leave
you could leave without
you could leave without anything.
you could leave without anything. And
sure
sure enough,
you could leave without anything. And
sure enough, I
sure enough, I did.
you could leave without anything. And
sure enough, I did. No
sure enough, I did. No money,
you could leave without anything. And
sure enough, I did. No money, no
sure enough, I did. No money, no food,
nothing.
nothing. Walked
nothing. Walked out
nothing. Walked out the
nothing. Walked out the door.
By
By 11
nothing. Walked out the door.
By 11 o'clock,
By 11 o'clock, somebody
nothing. Walked out the door.
By 11 o'clock, somebody said,
By 11 o'clock, somebody said, "What
nothing. Walked out the door.
By 11 o'clock, somebody said, "What you
doing
doing for
doing for lunch?"
doing for lunch?" I
doing for lunch?" I said,
doing for lunch?" I said, "Oh,
doing for lunch?" I said, "Oh, come
along
along with
doing for lunch?" I said, "Oh, come
along with me."
along with me." Everything
doing for lunch?" I said, "Oh, come
along with me." Everything I
along with me." Everything I needed
doing for lunch?" I said, "Oh, come
along with me." Everything I needed just
appeared.
appeared. I
appeared. I said
appeared. I said when
appeared. I said when we
appeared. I said when we drove
appeared. I said when we drove the
appeared. I said when we drove the old
truck
truck out
appeared. I said when we drove the old
truck out here,
truck out here, there
appeared. I said when we drove the old
truck out here, there was
truck out here, there was something
serious
serious about
serious about it
serious about it that
serious about it that could
serious about it that could only
serious about it that could only be
fixed
fixed with
serious about it that could only be
fixed with a
fixed with a pair
serious about it that could only be
fixed with a pair of
fixed with a pair of pliers.
serious about it that could only be
fixed with a pair of pliers. And
fixed with a pair of pliers. And uh
serious about it that could only be
fixed with a pair of pliers. And uh I
still
still got
still got the
still got the same
still got the same old
still got the same old truck.
still got the same old truck. And
still got the same old truck. And uh
just
just as
still got the same old truck. And uh
just as I
just as I needed
still got the same old truck. And uh
just as I needed a
just as I needed a pair
still got the same old truck. And uh
just as I needed a pair of
just as I needed a pair of pliers,
something
something by
something by the
something by the side
something by the side of
something by the side of the
something by the side of the road,
something by the side of the road, not
only
only was
something by the side of the road, not
only was there
only was there a
something by the side of the road, not
only was there a pair
only was there a pair of
something by the side of the road, not
only was there a pair of pliers,
only was there a pair of pliers, but
they
they were
they were brand
they were brand new
they were brand new pair
they were brand new pair of
they were brand new pair of pliers,
never
never been
they were brand new pair of pliers,
never been used,
never been used, sitting
they were brand new pair of pliers,
never been used, sitting there.
never been used, sitting there. I
they were brand new pair of pliers,
never been used, sitting there. I fixed
what
what I
what I needed
what I needed and
what I needed and we
what I needed and we went
what I needed and we went out.
Everything
Everything went
what I needed and we went out.
Everything went that
Everything went that way.
what I needed and we went out.
Everything went that way. And
Everything went that way. And it's
what I needed and we went out.
Everything went that way. And it's true.
You
You don't
You don't need
You don't need anything
You don't need anything at
You don't need anything at all
You don't need anything at all except
faith.
faith. Okay,
You don't need anything at all except
faith. Okay, we'll
faith. Okay, we'll go
You don't need anything at all except
faith. Okay, we'll go to
faith. Okay, we'll go to the
You don't need anything at all except
faith. Okay, we'll go to the next
faith. Okay, we'll go to the next and
then
then we'll
then we'll be
then we'll be uh
then we'll be uh I
then we'll be uh I want
then we'll be uh I want to
then we'll be uh I want to get
then we'll be uh I want to get out
then we'll be uh I want to get out of
the
the 200s
then we'll be uh I want to get out of
the 200s here
the 200s here so
then we'll be uh I want to get out of
the 200s here so that
the 200s here so that we
then we'll be uh I want to get out of
the 200s here so that we can
the 200s here so that we can start
then we'll be uh I want to get out of
the 200s here so that we can start out
upbeat
upbeat next
upbeat next time.
upbeat next time. I
upbeat next time. I don't
upbeat next time. I don't want
upbeat next time. I don't want to
upbeat next time. I don't want to look
at
at any
upbeat next time. I don't want to look
at any more
at any more negative
upbeat next time. I don't want to look
at any more negative feelings.
uh
uh pride.
Uh
this
this one
this one we're
this one we're all
this one we're all pretty
this one we're all pretty uh
this one we're all pretty uh familiar
with
with the
this one we're all pretty uh familiar
with the pride
with the pride of
this one we're all pretty uh familiar
with the pride of being
with the pride of being an
this one we're all pretty uh familiar
with the pride of being an insider,
important,
important, etc.
important, etc. And
important, etc. And this
important, etc. And this is
important, etc. And this is of
important, etc. And this is of course
what
what runs
important, etc. And this is of course
what runs the
what runs the media.
important, etc. And this is of course
what runs the media. And
what runs the media. And the
important, etc. And this is of course
what runs the media. And the aversion
what runs the media. And the aversion is
to
to be
to be nobody,
to
to not
to be nobody,
to not be
to not be noticed.
People
People would
People would do
People would do anything
People would do anything rather
People would do anything rather than
People would do anything rather than not
be
be noticed.
People would do anything rather than not
be noticed. Okay.
be noticed. Okay. So
People would do anything rather than not
be noticed. Okay. So we'll
be noticed. Okay. So we'll go
People would do anything rather than not
be noticed. Okay. So we'll go one
be noticed. Okay. So we'll go one more
time
time and
time and then
time and then we're
time and then we're quitting.
time and then we're quitting. Yes.
Okay.
Okay. All
time and then we're quitting. Yes.
Okay. All right.
uh
uh comparative
uh comparative dualities.
uh comparative dualities. We'll
uh comparative dualities. We'll start
here
here next
uh comparative dualities. We'll start
here next time.
here next time. See,
uh comparative dualities. We'll start
here next time. See, because
here next time. See, because all
uh comparative dualities. We'll start
here next time. See, because all the
dualities
dualities are
dualities are an
dualities are an attraction
dualities are an attraction and
dualities are an attraction and an
aversion
aversion and
dualities are an attraction and an
aversion and therefore
aversion and therefore you
dualities are an attraction and an
aversion and therefore you can
aversion and therefore you can apply
them
them to
them to anything.
them to anything. All right?
them to anything. All right? So,
them to anything. All right? So, we're
trying
trying to
them to anything. All right? So, we're
trying to come
trying to come up
them to anything. All right? So, we're
trying to come up today
trying to come up today with
generalities
generalities that
generalities that you
generalities that you can
generalities that you can apply
generalities that you can apply to
anything
anything and
generalities that you can apply to
anything and everything.
Um,
Um, and
Um, and what
Um, and what I
Um, and what I really
Um, and what I really want
Um, and what I really want you
Um, and what I really want you to
Um, and what I really want you to get
out
out of
Um, and what I really want you to get
out of it
out of it is
Um, and what I really want you to get
out of it is the
out of it is the sense
Um, and what I really want you to get
out of it is the sense of
out of it is the sense of it.
Um, and what I really want you to get
out of it is the sense of it. to
out of it is the sense of it. to get
Um, and what I really want you to get
out of it is the sense of it. to get the
sense
sense of
sense of it.
sense of it. The
sense of it. The specifics
sense of it. The specifics will
sense of it. The specifics will come
sense of it. The specifics will come to
mind
mind in
sense of it. The specifics will come to
mind in your
mind in your spiritual
sense of it. The specifics will come to
mind in your spiritual commitment
identifying
identifying with
identifying with the
identifying with the field
identifying with the field instead
identifying with the field instead of
the
the content
identifying with the field instead of
the content of
the content of the
identifying with the field instead of
the content of the field.
the content of the field. What
identifying with the field instead of
the content of the field. What you
the content of the field. What you need
will
will appear
will appear as
will appear as you
will appear as you need
will appear as you need it.
will appear as you need it. There's
will appear as you need it. There's no
point
point of
will appear as you need it. There's no
point of worrying.
point of worrying. You're
will appear as you need it. There's no
point of worrying. You're worrying
already
already that
already that I
already that I won't
already that I won't have
already that I won't have what
already that I won't have what I
already that I won't have what I need
over
over here
already that I won't have what I need
over here when
over here when it
already that I won't have what I need
over here when it isn't
over here when it isn't even
already that I won't have what I need
over here when it isn't even here
over here when it isn't even here yet.
When
When you
When you get
When you get there,
When you get there, by
When you get there, by intention,
When you get there, by intention, it
will
will arise,
When you get there, by intention, it
will arise, you
will arise, you know.
When you get there, by intention, it
will arise, you know. So,
will arise, you know. So, whatever
When you get there, by intention, it
will arise, you know. So, whatever you
need,
need, spiritual
need, spiritual information,
need, spiritual information, uh,
need, spiritual information, uh, will
arise
arise when
need, spiritual information, uh, will
arise when the
arise when the need
need, spiritual information, uh, will
arise when the need for
arise when the need for it
need, spiritual information, uh, will
arise when the need for it is
arise when the need for it is there.
Yes.
What
What now?
>> What
>> What happens
>> What happens now?
>> Well,
>> Well, Nico's
>> What happens now?
>> Well, Nico's going
>> Well, Nico's going to
>> What happens now?
>> Well, Nico's going to chant.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> And
>> And then
>> Oh, okay.
>> And then we're
>> And then we're going
>> Oh, okay.
>> And then we're going to
>> And then we're going to go
>> Oh, okay.
>> And then we're going to go to
>> And then we're going to go to break.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
In
In that
>> Oh, okay.
In that case,
In that case, Nico's
>> Oh, okay.
In that case, Nico's going
In that case, Nico's going to
>> Oh, okay.
In that case, Nico's going to chant
In that case, Nico's going to chant and
we
we got
we got to
we got to change
we got to change this
we got to change this around
we got to change this around a
we got to change this around a bit.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, I'll
we got to change this around a bit.
>> Yes, I'll do
>> Yes, I'll do that.
>> We'll
>> We'll come
>> We'll come back
>> We'll come back after
>> We'll come back after that
>> We'll come back after that and
>> We'll come back after that and do
questions
questions and
>> We'll come back after that and do
questions and answers
questions and answers later.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. We'll
>> Okay. We'll take
>> Okay.
>> Okay. We'll take this
>> Okay. We'll take this out
>> Okay.
>> Okay. We'll take this out of
>> Okay. We'll take this out of the
>> Okay.
>> Okay. We'll take this out of the way.
Take
Take this
Take this cool
Take this cool one
Take this cool one out
Take this cool one out of
Take this cool one out of the
Take this cool one out of the way.
Take this cool one out of the way. Get
this
this out
Take this cool one out of the way. Get
this out of
this out of the
Take this cool one out of the way. Get
this out of the way.
Nico's
Nico's going
Nico's going to
Nico's going to chat
Nico's going to chat and
So
So just
Nico's going to chat and
So just relax.
And
And uh
And uh I
And uh I would
And uh I would suggest
And uh I would suggest after
And uh I would suggest after what
And uh I would suggest after what doctor
just
just said,
you
you might
you might want
you might want to
you might want to hold
you might want to hold your
you might want to hold your attention
you might want to hold your attention in
mind.
I
I hope
I know.
Fore
Home
Day
home.
foreign.
Okay.
Foreign
speech. Foreign speech. Foreign speech.
for
me.
They
They go
no.
No.
Hing
going.
Where
Where we
going.
Where we go?
Deep
Deep breath.
Uhhuh.
>> Do
>> Do you
>> Do you have
>> Do you have your
>> Do you have your pen?
Yes.
>> Hello.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I
>> Hello.
>> Okay. I have
>> Okay. I have a
>> Hello.
>> Okay. I have a question.
>> Okay. I have a question. Oh,
>> Hello.
>> Okay. I have a question. Oh, it's
>> Okay. I have a question. Oh, it's not
on,
on, is
on, is it?
on, is it? Hello.
on, is it? Hello. Hello.
>> It's
okay.
In
In the
okay.
In the slides
In the slides um
okay.
In the slides um the
In the slides um the progressive
okay.
In the slides um the progressive fields
of
of realization
there
there is
of realization
there is experiencer
there is experiencer between
of realization
there is experiencer between experiencer
and
and weakness
and weakness there
and weakness there is
and weakness there is awareness.
and weakness there is awareness. Can
and weakness there is awareness. Can you
please
please explain
and weakness there is awareness. Can you
please explain what
please explain what awareness
and weakness there is awareness. Can you
please explain what awareness is?
Awareness
Awareness is
Awareness is an
Awareness is an automatic
Awareness is an automatic consequence
Awareness is an automatic consequence of
consciousness.
consciousness. the
Awareness is an automatic consequence of
consciousness. the presence
consciousness. the presence of
consciousness
consciousness itself.
It's
It's a
consciousness itself.
It's a registration.
There's
There's no
There's no person.
Although
Although the
There's no person.
Although the the
Although the the witness
There's no person.
Although the the witness thinks
Although the the witness thinks there's
a
a person,
u
u consciousness
a person,
u consciousness does
u consciousness does it
a person,
u consciousness does it automatically
as
as a
as a consequence
as a consequence as
as a consequence as a
as a consequence as a as
as a consequence as a as an
as a consequence as a as an innate
quality.
Now
Now below
Now below 200
organisms
organisms are
Now below 200
organisms are but
organisms are but they
Now below 200
organisms are but they don't
organisms are but they don't realize
they
they are.
200 and
200 and over
they are.
200 and over they're
200 and over they're aware
they are.
200 and over they're aware but
200 and over they're aware but they
they are.
200 and over they're aware but they also
know
know that
know that they
know that they are
know that they are big
know that they are big difference.
So
So in
know that they are big difference.
So in those
So in those fields
know that they are big difference.
So in those fields of
So in those fields of realization
where
where does
where does the
where does the individual
where does the individual ego
where does the individual ego arise?
You
You call
where does the individual ego arise?
You call talking
You call talking about
where does the individual ego arise?
You call talking about the
You call talking about the calibrated
levels
levels of
levels of consciousness.
>> Uh
>> Uh the
levels of consciousness.
>> Uh the the
>> Uh the the the
levels of consciousness.
>> Uh the the the realization
>> Uh the the the realization progressive
fields
fields of
fields of realization
fields of realization the
fields of realization the experiencer
the
the awareness
fields of realization the experiencer
the awareness and
the awareness and the
fields of realization the experiencer
the awareness and the weakness.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. What
>> Yes. What was
>> Yes. What was the
>> Yes. What was the question?
>> Yes. What was the question? Does
ego
ego arise
>> Yes. What was the question? Does
ego arise in
ego arise in through
>> Yes. What was the question? Does
ego arise in through the
ego arise in through the experiencer
>> Yes. What was the question? Does
ego arise in through the experiencer or
through
through the
through the awareness
through the awareness or
through the awareness or through
through the awareness or through the
weakness?
>> The
>> The ego
>> The ego claims
>> The ego claims to
>> The ego claims to be
>> The ego claims to be the
>> The ego claims to be the author
>> The ego claims to be the author of
>> The ego claims to be the author of the
experience.
experience. The
>> The ego claims to be the author of the
experience. The author
experience. The author and
>> The ego claims to be the author of the
experience. The author and the
experience. The author and the subject
of
of it.
It
It sees
of it.
It sees itself
It sees itself as
of it.
It sees itself as central.
It sees itself as central. In
of it.
It sees itself as central. In reality,
it's
it's not
it's not necessary,
it's not necessary, nor
it's not necessary, nor is
it's not necessary, nor is it
it's not necessary, nor is it central.
The
The phenomena
it's not necessary, nor is it central.
The phenomena happens
The phenomena happens without
it's not necessary, nor is it central.
The phenomena happens without the
The phenomena happens without the ego.
The
The ego
The ego claims
The ego claims ownership.
The ego claims ownership. Yeah.
The ego claims ownership. Yeah. to
The ego claims ownership. Yeah. to the
experience.
>> It
>> It like
>> It like sees
>> It like sees the
>> It like sees the sunrise
>> It like sees the sunrise every
>> It like sees the sunrise every day
>> It like sees the sunrise every day and
thinks
thinks it's
>> It like sees the sunrise every day and
thinks it's making
thinks it's making the
>> It like sees the sunrise every day and
thinks it's making the sunrise.
>> So
>> So to
>> So to transcend
>> So to transcend the
>> So to transcend the ego,
>> So to transcend the ego, is
>> So to transcend the ego, is it
>> So to transcend the ego, is it more
>> So to transcend the ego, is it more like
aligning
aligning to
>> So to transcend the ego, is it more like
aligning to the
aligning to the awareness
>> So to transcend the ego, is it more like
aligning to the awareness and
aligning to the awareness and the
weakness
realization?
>> No,
>> No, it's
>> No, it's you're
>> No, it's you're not
>> No, it's you're not phrasing
>> No, it's you're not phrasing the
question
question right.
The
The ego
when
when it
The ego
when it disintegrates
when it disintegrates no
The ego
when it disintegrates no longer
when it disintegrates no longer claims
to
to be
to be the
to be the author
to be the author or
to be the author or the
to be the author or the subject
>> central.
>> central. It
to be the author or the subject
>> central. It sees
>> central. It sees itself
to be the author or the subject
>> central. It sees itself as
>> central. It sees itself as the
to be the author or the subject
>> central. It sees itself as the star
>> central. It sees itself as the star of
the
the program.
the program. When
the program. When you
the program. When you remove
the program. When you remove it,
the program. When you remove it, he
the program. When you remove it, he sees
it.
it. It's
the program. When you remove it, he sees
it. It's the
it. It's the field
the program. When you remove it, he sees
it. It's the field itself.
>> So
>> So then
>> So then comes
>> So then comes humility.
>> I
>> I guess
>> So then comes humility.
>> I guess my
>> I guess my question
>> So then comes humility.
>> I guess my question is
>> I guess my question is is
>> So then comes humility.
>> I guess my question is is there
>> I guess my question is is there ego
>> So then comes humility.
>> I guess my question is is there ego in
the
the field
the field of
the field of witnessing?
>> Is
>> Is there
the field of witnessing?
>> Is there ego
>> Is there ego in
the field of witnessing?
>> Is there ego in the
>> Is there ego in the field
the field of witnessing?
>> Is there ego in the field of
>> Is there ego in the field of witnessing?
Is
Is there
Is there Does
Is there Does the
Is there Does the does
Is there Does the does the
Is there Does the does the ego
Is there Does the does the ego identify
with
with all?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Because
>> Yes. Because the
>> Yes. Because the ego
>> Yes. Because the ego claims
>> Yes. Because the ego claims that
>> Yes. Because the ego claims that I
>> Yes. Because the ego claims that I am
the
the witness.
>> I
>> I see.
>> It
>> It does
>> I see.
>> It does not
>> It does not see
>> I see.
>> It does not see the
>> It does not see the witnessing
>> I see.
>> It does not see the witnessing is
happening
happening spontaneously
happening spontaneously autonomously
because
because I
happening spontaneously autonomously
because I am
because I am the
happening spontaneously autonomously
because I am the I
because I am the I am
happening spontaneously autonomously
because I am the I am the
because I am the I am the witness.
happening spontaneously autonomously
because I am the I am the witness. I
because I am the I am the witness. I am
the
the the
the the observer
with
with a
the the observer
with a little
with a little contemplation.
One
One sees
One sees that
One sees that the
One sees that the phenomena
One sees that the phenomena occurring
One sees that the phenomena occurring of
their
their own.
>> It's
>> It's not
>> It's not I
>> It's not I that
>> It's not I that I'm
>> It's not I that I'm the
>> It's not I that I'm the witness.
Witnessing
Witnessing is
>> It's not I that I'm the witness.
Witnessing is witnessing
Witnessing is witnessing because
>> It's not I that I'm the witness.
Witnessing is witnessing because it
Witnessing is witnessing because it does
that
that independently,
>> right?
>> Without
>> Without a
>> Without a personal
>> Without a personal self.
>> Without a personal self. Yeah.
>> Got
>> Got it.
>> Without a personal self. Yeah.
>> Got it. Thank
>> Got it. Thank you.
>> Sophisticated
>> Sophisticated question.
>> Sophisticated question. Yeah.
>> Sophisticated question. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Sophisticated question. Yeah. Yeah. Good
question.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. He
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. He was
>> Yeah. He was trying
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. He was trying to
>> Yeah. He was trying to figure
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. He was trying to figure out
>> Yeah. He was trying to figure out where
the
the ego
the ego came.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, I
the ego came.
>> Yes, I I
>> Yes, I I see.
Took
Took me
Took me a
Took me a minute
Took me a minute to
Took me a minute to understand
Took me a minute to understand the
question.
>> Uh
>> Uh Dr.
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins.
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins. I
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins. I have
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins. I have been
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins. I have been wearing
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins. I have been wearing a
silent
silent vibrating
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins. I have been wearing a
silent vibrating alarm
silent vibrating alarm watch
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins. I have been wearing a
silent vibrating alarm watch to
silent vibrating alarm watch to remind
me
me periodically
me periodically during
me periodically during the
me periodically during the day
me periodically during the day to
me periodically during the day to stop,
give
give thanks,
me periodically during the day to stop,
give thanks, and
give thanks, and surrender
me periodically during the day to stop,
give thanks, and surrender my
give thanks, and surrender my will
me periodically during the day to stop,
give thanks, and surrender my will to
God.
God. Would
God. Would you
God. Would you say
God. Would you say one
God. Would you say one should
God. Would you say one should not
God. Would you say one should not become
overly
overly reliant
God. Would you say one should not become
overly reliant on
overly reliant on a
God. Would you say one should not become
overly reliant on a physical
overly reliant on a physical reminder?
I
I don't
I don't know
I don't know what
I don't know what is
I don't know what is overly
I don't know what is overly reliant.
We
We rely
I don't know what is overly reliant.
We rely on
We rely on something
I don't know what is overly reliant.
We rely on something all
We rely on something all the
I don't know what is overly reliant.
We rely on something all the time.
We rely on something all the time. You
know,
know, we
know, we have
know, we have a
know, we have a prop
know, we have a prop that
know, we have a prop that is
know, we have a prop that is always
holding
holding a
know, we have a prop that is always
holding a separate.
holding a separate. If
know, we have a prop that is always
holding a separate. If it
holding a separate. If it takes
know, we have a prop that is always
holding a separate. If it takes a
physical
physical expression,
physical expression, I
physical expression, I see
physical expression, I see nothing
physical expression, I see nothing wrong
with
with it.
You
You know,
You know, in
You know, in a
You know, in a in
You know, in a in a
You know, in a in a monastery,
You know, in a in a monastery, the
You know, in a in a monastery, the gong
gong
gong gong
You know, in a in a monastery, the gong
gong gong calls
gong gong calls you
You know, in a in a monastery, the gong
gong gong calls you to
gong gong calls you to prayer.
>> Would
>> Would you
>> Would you say
>> Would you say it
>> Would you say it would
>> Would you say it would be
>> Would you say it would be preferable
>> Would you say it would be preferable to
remove
remove the
>> Would you say it would be preferable to
remove the physical
remove the physical reminder
>> Would you say it would be preferable to
remove the physical reminder and
remove the physical reminder and be
>> Would you say it would be preferable to
remove the physical reminder and be able
to
to do
to do thus
to do thus without
to do thus without it?
>> I
>> I don't
to do thus without it?
>> I don't think
>> I don't think it's
to do thus without it?
>> I don't think it's of
>> I don't think it's of any
to do thus without it?
>> I don't think it's of any importance
because
because the
because the intention
because the intention would
because the intention would determine
the
the consequence.
the intention
the intention behind
the intention behind it.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
the intention behind it.
>> Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Devotional
>> Devotional attention
>> Devotional attention is
>> Devotional attention is what
>> Devotional attention is what is
important.
Like
Like to
Like to make
Like to make a
Like to make a note
Like to make a note to
Like to make a note to myself
Like to make a note to myself about
4:00.
>> Hello,
>> Hello, doctor.
>> Hello, doctor. Hi,
>> Hello, doctor. Hi, Susan.
>> Hello, doctor. Hi, Susan. Hello.
>> Um,
>> Um, how
>> Hello, doctor. Hi, Susan. Hello.
>> Um, how are
>> Um, how are you?
>> Hello, doctor. Hi, Susan. Hello.
>> Um, how are you? Uh,
>> Um, how are you? Uh, uh,
>> Hello, doctor. Hi, Susan. Hello.
>> Um, how are you? Uh, uh, listening
>> Um, how are you? Uh, uh, listening to
you
you this
you this morning
you this morning talking
you this morning talking about
you this morning talking about tabulate
to
to tabulate
you this morning talking about tabulate
to tabulate your
to tabulate your behavior,
it
it made
it made me
it made me think
it made me think about
it made me think about the
it made me think about the mechanics
it made me think about the mechanics of
the
the 10th
it made me think about the mechanics of
the 10th step.
Uh,
Uh, if
Uh, if I,
Uh, if I, um,
Uh, if I, um, just
Uh, if I, um, just observe
Uh, if I, um, just observe my
Uh, if I, um, just observe my behavior,
uh,
uh, it'll
Uh, if I, um, just observe my behavior,
uh, it'll change
uh, it'll change and
Uh, if I, um, just observe my behavior,
uh, it'll change and I
uh, it'll change and I don't
Uh, if I, um, just observe my behavior,
uh, it'll change and I don't have
uh, it'll change and I don't have to
force
force it.
>> And,
>> And, uh,
force it.
>> And, uh, also
>> And, uh, also uh,
force it.
>> And, uh, also uh, it's
>> And, uh, also uh, it's amazing.
force it.
>> And, uh, also uh, it's amazing. I
>> And, uh, also uh, it's amazing. I I
force it.
>> And, uh, also uh, it's amazing. I I just
I
I just
I just want
I just want to
I just want to express
I just want to express my
I just want to express my gratitude
because
because um
I just want to express my gratitude
because um uh
because um uh well
I just want to express my gratitude
because um uh well your
because um uh well your books
I just want to express my gratitude
because um uh well your books before
having
having your
having your your
having your your your
having your your your uh
having your your your uh anything
having your your your uh anything about
consciousness
consciousness I
having your your your uh anything about
consciousness I was
consciousness I was stuck
having your your your uh anything about
consciousness I was stuck with
consciousness I was stuck with step
having your your your uh anything about
consciousness I was stuck with step six
and
and seven
and seven because
and seven because well
and seven because well how
and seven because well how am
and seven because well how am I
and seven because well how am I just
turn
turn this
lack
lack of
lack of powerless
lack of powerless or
lack of powerless or lack
lack of powerless or lack of
lack of powerless or lack of power
lack of powerless or lack of power and
all
all these
lack of powerless or lack of power and
all these character
all these character defects
lack of powerless or lack of power and
all these character defects how
all these character defects how I
lack of powerless or lack of power and
all these character defects how I turn
them
them over
them over and
them over and how
them over and how I
them over and how I get
them over and how I get rid
them over and how I get rid of
them over and how I get rid of them
them over and how I get rid of them and
uh
uh I
them over and how I get rid of them and
uh I was
uh I was really
them over and how I get rid of them and
uh I was really I
uh I was really I felt
them over and how I get rid of them and
uh I was really I felt really
uh I was really I felt really um
uh
uh I
uh I didn't
uh I didn't know
uh I didn't know what
uh I didn't know what to
uh I didn't know what to do
uh I didn't know what to do with
uh I didn't know what to do with them.
But
But now
uh I didn't know what to do with them.
But now with
But now with this
uh I didn't know what to do with them.
But now with this uh
But now with this uh this
uh I didn't know what to do with them.
But now with this uh this is
But now with this uh this is like
uh I didn't know what to do with them.
But now with this uh this is like a
But now with this uh this is like a map
a
a key
a key map
a key map to
a key map to go
a key map to go through
a key map to go through the
a key map to go through the steps
a key map to go through the steps for
a key map to go through the steps for me
and
and I
a key map to go through the steps for me
and I really
and I really appreciate
a key map to go through the steps for me
and I really appreciate it.
and I really appreciate it. Appreciate
it.
>> We
>> We ask
it.
>> We ask God
>> We ask God to
it.
>> We ask God to remove
>> We ask God to remove these
it.
>> We ask God to remove these defects
>> We ask God to remove these defects of
character.
>> In
>> In the
character.
>> In the meantime,
>> In the meantime, we
character.
>> In the meantime, we stay
>> In the meantime, we stay busy.
That's
That's how
That's how God
That's how God removes
That's how God removes the
That's how God removes the defective
character.
character. He
That's how God removes the defective
character. He gets
character. He gets you
That's how God removes the defective
character. He gets you busy
character. He gets you busy working
That's how God removes the defective
character. He gets you busy working on
them.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
them.
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> All
>> All right.
>> All right. There's
>> All right. There's a
>> All right. There's a Sharpie
>> All right. There's a Sharpie right
>> All right. There's a Sharpie right now.
>> I
>> I I
>> All right. There's a Sharpie right now.
>> I I don't
>> I I don't have
>> All right. There's a Sharpie right now.
>> I I don't have Thank
>> I I don't have Thank you,
>> Susan.
>> Dr.
>> Dr. Hawkins.
>> Susan.
>> Dr. Hawkins. Hi.
in
in the
in the book
in the book uh
in the book uh transcending
in the book uh transcending the
in the book uh transcending the levels
of
of consciousness
um
through
through consciousness
um
through consciousness research
through consciousness research uh
um
through consciousness research uh found
that
that most
that most of
that most of this
that most of this physical
that most of this physical incarnation
that most of this physical incarnation I
was
was at
that most of this physical incarnation I
was at 75
up
up until
up until the
up until the last
up until the last couple
up until the last couple of
up until the last couple of years
and
and um
I
I was
I was addicted
I was addicted to
I was addicted to mentalization
And
And in
I was addicted to mentalization
And in the
And in the section
I was addicted to mentalization
And in the section on
And in the section on reason,
you
you say
you say that
you say that one
you say that one of
you say that one of the
a
a good
you say that one of the
a good method
a good method to
you say that one of the
a good method to help
a good method to help one
you say that one of the
a good method to help one get
a good method to help one get over
mentalization
mentalization is
mentalization is creative
mentalization is creative visualization.
Could
Could you
mentalization is creative visualization.
Could you say
Could you say give
mentalization is creative visualization.
Could you say give an
Could you say give an example
mentalization is creative visualization.
Could you say give an example of
Could you say give an example of that
mentalization is creative visualization.
Could you say give an example of that or
say
say something
say something more
say something more on
say something more on that?
>> The
>> The likelihood.
say something more on that?
>> The likelihood. Don't
>> The likelihood. Don't forget
say something more on that?
>> The likelihood. Don't forget we're
talking
talking about
talking about likelihoods.
talking about likelihoods. the
likelihood
likelihood because
talking about likelihoods. the
likelihood because there's
likelihood because there's karmic
factors
factors and
factors and everything
factors and everything else
factors and everything else factors
involved,
involved, timing,
factors and everything else factors
involved, timing, etc.
involved, timing, etc. Um,
factors and everything else factors
involved, timing, etc. Um, to
involved, timing, etc. Um, to hold
factors and everything else factors
involved, timing, etc. Um, to hold in
mind
mind that
mind that which
mind that which you
uh
uh would
mind that which you
uh would would
uh would would like
mind that which you
uh would would like to
uh would would like to see
mind that which you
uh would would like to see happen
uh would would like to see happen in
your
your own
your own life
your own life greatly
your own life greatly in
your own life greatly in increases
your own life greatly in increases the
likelihood
likelihood of
your own life greatly in increases the
likelihood of its
likelihood of its materialization.
And
And I've
And I've used
And I've used it
And I've used it practically.
And I've used it practically. Every
place
place I've
And I've used it practically. Every
place I've ever
place I've ever lived
And I've used it practically. Every
place I've ever lived has
place I've ever lived has been
And I've used it practically. Every
place I've ever lived has been uh
place I've ever lived has been uh the
consequence
consequence of
consequence of a
consequence of a visualization.
place
place I
consequence of a visualization.
place I live
place I live now,
consequence of a visualization.
place I live now, the
place I live now, the place
consequence of a visualization.
place I live now, the place I
place I live now, the place I live
consequence of a visualization.
place I live now, the place I live back
east.
Um,
Um, just
east.
Um, just held
Um, just held in
east.
Um, just held in mind
Um, just held in mind that
east.
Um, just held in mind that which
Um, just held in mind that which I
east.
Um, just held in mind that which I wish
to
to be.
Yeah.
>> Do
>> Do you
>> Do you fill
>> Do you fill in
>> Do you fill in the
>> Do you fill in the details
>> Do you fill in the details of
>> Do you fill in the details of the
visualization
visualization or
>> Do you fill in the details of the
visualization or you
visualization or you just
>> Do you fill in the details of the
visualization or you just sort
visualization or you just sort of
>> No,
>> No, the
>> No, the general
>> No, the general setting,
>> No, the general setting, you
>> No, the general setting, you know,
>> No, the general setting, you know, the
general
general setting.
>> No, the general setting, you know, the
general setting. I'll
general setting. I'll leave
>> No, the general setting, you know, the
general setting. I'll leave the
general setting. I'll leave the details
up
up to
up to God.
up to God. thought
up to God. thought it
up to God. thought it would
up to God. thought it would be
up to God. thought it would be so
presumptive
>> but
>> but you
>> but you can
>> but you can picture
>> but you can picture you
>> but you can picture you know
>> but you can picture you know uh
>> but you can picture you know uh uh
pristine
pristine woods
>> but you can picture you know uh uh
pristine woods and
pristine woods and uh
>> but you can picture you know uh uh
pristine woods and uh the
pristine woods and uh the sounds
>> but you can picture you know uh uh
pristine woods and uh the sounds of
animals
animals uh
animals uh the
animals uh the sound
animals uh the sound of
animals uh the sound of water
animals uh the sound of water maybe
going
going by
animals uh the sound of water maybe
going by and
going by and uh
animals uh the sound of water maybe
going by and uh then
going by and uh then it
animals uh the sound of water maybe
going by and uh then it materializes
suddenly
suddenly somebody
suddenly somebody calls
suddenly somebody calls you
suddenly somebody calls you and
suddenly somebody calls you and says
suddenly somebody calls you and says I
want
want you
suddenly somebody calls you and says I
want you to
want you to live
suddenly somebody calls you and says I
want you to live next
want you to live next door
suddenly somebody calls you and says I
want you to live next door to
want you to live next door to me
suddenly somebody calls you and says I
want you to live next door to me that's
how
how it happens
>> and
>> and that
how it happens
>> and that helps
>> and that helps one
how it happens
>> and that helps one get
>> and that helps one get over
how it happens
>> and that helps one get over the
>> and that helps one get over the habit
how it happens
>> and that helps one get over the habit of
mentalization
>> what
>> what would
mentalization
>> what would you
>> what would you mentalize
mentalization
>> what would you mentalize about
>> what would you mentalize about oh
mentalization
>> what would you mentalize about oh see
mentalization would
mentalization would be
mentalization would be uh
mentalization would be uh trying
mentalization would be uh trying to
figure
figure out
mentalization would be uh trying to
figure out how
figure out how to
mentalization would be uh trying to
figure out how to make
figure out how to make it
mentalization would be uh trying to
figure out how to make it happen,
>> right?
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. I'll
>> right?
>> Mhm. I'll search
>> Mhm. I'll search the
>> right?
>> Mhm. I'll search the wani
>> Mhm. I'll search the wani ads.
>> right?
>> Mhm. I'll search the wani ads. I'll
travel
travel the
travel the side
travel the side roads.
travel the side roads. I'll
travel the side roads. I'll look
travel the side roads. I'll look for
travel the side roads. I'll look for it.
I'll
I'll call
travel the side roads. I'll look for it.
I'll call on
I'll call on real
travel the side roads. I'll look for it.
I'll call on real estate
I'll call on real estate agents.
>> That
>> That would
>> That would be
>> That would be the
>> That would be the metal
>> That would be the metal mentalization.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, that's
>> That would be the metal mentalization.
>> Yeah, that's your
>> Yeah, that's your rock.
>> That's
>> That's that's
>> That's that's a
addiction
addiction of
>> That's that's a
addiction of mine,
addiction of mine, you
>> That's that's a
addiction of mine, you know,
addiction of mine, you know, kind
>> That's that's a
addiction of mine, you know, kind of
figuring
figuring out
figuring out all
figuring out all the
figuring out all the details.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, figuring
figuring out all the details.
>> Oh, figuring out
>> Oh, figuring out the
figuring out all the details.
>> Oh, figuring out the details.
>> Oh, figuring out the details. Yeah.
figuring out all the details.
>> Oh, figuring out the details. Yeah. Left
braining
braining it.
braining it. Yeah.
>> Right.
>> So,
>> So, just
>> So, just a
>> So, just a general
>> So, just a general visualization
>> So, just a general visualization and
leave
leave the
>> So, just a general visualization and
leave the rest
leave the rest to
>> So, just a general visualization and
leave the rest to God.
>> That's
>> That's right.
Perfect.
Perfect. Thank
>> That's right.
Perfect. Thank you.
>> Hello.
>> Hi.
Um,
of
of late
Um,
of late I've
of late I've been
Um,
of late I've been experience
of late I've been experience finding
myself
myself in
myself in different
myself in different states
myself in different states like
myself in different states like um
a
a state
myself in different states like um
a state of
a state of beauty,
myself in different states like um
a state of beauty, of
a state of beauty, of gratitude,
myself in different states like um
a state of beauty, of gratitude, of
nurturing.
Um,
Um, but
nurturing.
Um, but there's
Um, but there's one
nurturing.
Um, but there's one state
Um, but there's one state that
nurturing.
Um, but there's one state that I
Um, but there's one state that I find
myself
myself on
myself on the
myself on the edge
myself on the edge of
myself on the edge of sometimes
where
where it
myself on the edge of sometimes
where it I
where it I feel
myself on the edge of sometimes
where it I feel a
where it I feel a bit
myself on the edge of sometimes
where it I feel a bit of
where it I feel a bit of fear
myself on the edge of sometimes
where it I feel a bit of fear because
where it I feel a bit of fear because I
feel
feel if
feel if I
feel if I go
feel if I go into
feel if I go into it
feel if I go into it that
feel if I go into it that I'll
feel if I go into it that I'll explode.
And
And that's
>> You'll
>> You'll go
>> You'll go into
>> You'll go into what?
>> Explode.
>> Go
>> Go into
>> Go into what?
>> Go into what? You'll
>> Go into what? You'll explode.
>> What?
>> Well,
>> Well, it
>> Well, it feels
>> Well, it feels like
>> Well, it feels like my
>> Well, it feels like my It's
>> Well, it feels like my It's a
>> Well, it feels like my It's a state
>> Well, it feels like my It's a state of
ecstasy.
ecstasy. Like
>> Well, it feels like my It's a state of
ecstasy. Like a
ecstasy. Like a communion.
>> It
>> It feels
>> It feels like
>> It feels like my
>> It feels like my body
>> It feels like my body won't
>> It feels like my body won't be
>> It feels like my body won't be able
>> It feels like my body won't be able to
take
take it.
>> It feels like my body won't be able to
take it. Like
take it. Like it
>> It feels like my body won't be able to
take it. Like it would
take it. Like it would just
>> It feels like my body won't be able to
take it. Like it would just explode.
Yeah.
Yeah. Okay,
Yeah. Okay, that's
Yeah. Okay, that's fine.
>> Does
>> Does that
Yeah. Okay, that's fine.
>> Does that mean
>> Does that mean it's
Yeah. Okay, that's fine.
>> Does that mean it's going
>> Does that mean it's going to
Yeah. Okay, that's fine.
>> Does that mean it's going to or
>> Does that mean it's going to or not?
>> Explode
>> Explode a
>> Explode a body.
>> Explode a body. What's
>> Explode a body. What's your
>> Explode a body. What's your problem
about
about exploding
>> Explode a body. What's your problem
about exploding your
about exploding your body?
>> Well,
>> Well, is
>> Well, is that
>> Well, is that a
>> Well, is that a good
>> Well, is that a good thing?
>> Well,
>> Well, that
>> Well, is that a good thing?
>> Well, that means
>> Well, that means you're
>> Well, is that a good thing?
>> Well, that means you're attached
>> Well, that means you're attached to
>> Well, is that a good thing?
>> Well, that means you're attached to the
body
body the
body the way
body the way it
body the way it is,
body the way it is, right?
>> Okay.
>> Will
>> Will you
>> Will you surrender
>> Will you surrender your
>> Will you surrender your body
>> Will you surrender your body to
>> Will you surrender your body to God?
>> You
>> You better,
>> Will you surrender your body to God?
>> You better, cuz
>> You better, cuz in
>> Will you surrender your body to God?
>> You better, cuz in the
>> You better, cuz in the end,
>> Will you surrender your body to God?
>> You better, cuz in the end, he's
>> You better, cuz in the end, he's going
to
to take
to take it
to take it back.
>> He's
>> He's going
to take it back.
>> He's going to
>> He's going to take it
to take it back.
>> He's going to take it back.
>> He's going to take it back. Yeah.
to take it back.
>> He's going to take it back. Yeah. Okay.
Are
Are are
Are are those
Are are those what
Are are those what you
Are are those what you called
Are are those what you called in
Are are those what you called in your
book
book called?
Are are those what you called in your
book called? Are
book called? Are those
Are are those what you called in your
book called? Are those Satator
book called? Are those Satator states,
>> right?
>> Satori
>> Satori states.
>> right?
>> Satori states. Did
>> Satori states. Did I
>> right?
>> Satori states. Did I get
>> Satori states. Did I get that
>> right?
>> Satori states. Did I get that right?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Are
>> Yeah. Are they
>> Yeah. Are they the
>> Yeah. Are they the sis?
>> Yeah. Are they the sis? The
>> Yeah. Are they the sis? The cities.
>> I
No.
>> What's
>> What's Okay.
No.
>> What's Okay. Can
>> What's Okay. Can you
No.
>> What's Okay. Can you talk
>> What's Okay. Can you talk about
No.
>> What's Okay. Can you talk about what
that
that is?
>> It's
>> It's just
that is?
>> It's just the
>> It's just the rapid
that is?
>> It's just the rapid rising
>> It's just the rapid rising of
that is?
>> It's just the rapid rising of the
energy.
energy. That's
energy. That's all.
energy. That's all. If
energy. That's all. If you
energy. That's all. If you let
energy. That's all. If you let go
resisting
resisting it,
energy. That's all. If you let go
resisting it, it
resisting it, it cools
energy. That's all. If you let go
resisting it, it cools itself
resisting it, it cools itself out.
energy. That's all. If you let go
resisting it, it cools itself out. Mhm.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> Let
>> Let it
>> Oh, okay.
>> Let it explode.
>> Let it explode. Let's
>> Oh, okay.
>> Let it explode. Let's see
>> Let it explode. Let's see if
>> Oh, okay.
>> Let it explode. Let's see if it
explodes.
cameras
cameras everyone.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> You
>> You let
>> Thank you.
>> You let go
>> You let go of
>> Thank you.
>> You let go of resisting
>> You let go of resisting it
>> Thank you.
>> You let go of resisting it and
>> You let go of resisting it and we'll
>> Thank you.
>> You let go of resisting it and we'll all
catch
catch it.
>> Good
>> Good job.
>> Now
>> Now it's
>> Now it's a
>> Now it's a subjective
>> Now it's a subjective sensation,
physiologic
physiologic sensation.
>> Now it's a subjective sensation,
physiologic sensation. And
physiologic sensation. And just
constantly
constantly surrender
constantly surrender it
constantly surrender it to
constantly surrender it to God.
constantly surrender it to God. Just
surrendered.
surrendered. Surrender.
constantly surrender it to God. Just
surrendered. Surrender. Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Many
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. Many peculiar
>> Yeah. Many peculiar resistances
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. Many peculiar resistances come
>> Yeah. Many peculiar resistances come up
physically
physically and
physically and otherwise
physically and otherwise you
physically and otherwise you know
trying
trying to
physically and otherwise you know
trying to hang
trying to hang on
physically and otherwise you know
trying to hang on to
trying to hang on to one's
physically and otherwise you know
trying to hang on to one's identity.
>> Dr.
>> Dr. Hawkins.
>> Good.
>> Good. I
>> Dr. Hawkins.
>> Good. I recently
>> Good. I recently visited
>> Dr. Hawkins.
>> Good. I recently visited a
>> Good. I recently visited a friend
>> Dr. Hawkins.
>> Good. I recently visited a friend of
mine
mine who's
mine who's just
mine who's just turned
mine who's just turned turning
mine who's just turned turning 99
but
but for
mine who's just turned turning 99
but for the
but for the last
mine who's just turned turning 99
but for the last 10
but for the last 10 years
mine who's just turned turning 99
but for the last 10 years she's
there's
there's not
there's not much
there's not much to
there's not much to connect
there's not much to connect to
there's not much to connect to the
physical
>> but
>> but in
>> but in being
>> but in being with
>> but in being with her
>> but in being with her in
>> but in being with her in the
>> but in being with her in the stillness
to
to connect
>> but in being with her in the stillness
to connect to
to connect to the
>> but in being with her in the stillness
to connect to the spirit.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. And
>> Yes. And when
>> Yes. And when I
>> Yes. And when I asked
>> Yes. And when I asked uh
>> Yes. And when I asked uh one
>> Yes. And when I asked uh one of
>> Yes. And when I asked uh one of her
grandchildren
if
if they
if they had
if they had been
if they had been visiting
if they had been visiting her,
if they had been visiting her, they
said,
said, "Well,
if they had been visiting her, they
said, "Well, why
said, "Well, why bother?
if they had been visiting her, they
said, "Well, why bother? She's
said, "Well, why bother? She's not
there."
>> Yes.
>> But
>> But as
>> But as long
>> But as long as
>> But as long as the
>> But as long as the form's
>> But as long as the form's there,
>> But as long as the form's there, the
spirit's
spirit's there.
>> But as long as the form's there, the
spirit's there. Is
spirit's there. Is that
>> But as long as the form's there, the
spirit's there. Is that true?
>> Not
>> Not necessarily.
>> Not necessarily. The
>> Not necessarily. The spirit
>> Not necessarily. The spirit may
>> Not necessarily. The spirit may have
>> Not necessarily. The spirit may have u
not
not have
>> Not necessarily. The spirit may have u
not have much
not have much to
>> Not necessarily. The spirit may have u
not have much to do
not have much to do with
>> Not necessarily. The spirit may have u
not have much to do with the
physicality,
>> right?
>> What
>> What you're
>> What you're saying
>> What you're saying is
>> What you're saying is sort
>> What you're saying is sort of
intuitively,
>> yes,
>> person's
>> person's aware
>> yes,
>> person's aware of
>> person's aware of the
>> yes,
>> person's aware of the presence
>> person's aware of the presence of
>> yes,
>> person's aware of the presence of the
family.
family. I
family. I don't
family. I don't know.
family. I don't know. I'd
family. I don't know. I'd have
family. I don't know. I'd have to
family. I don't know. I'd have to use
the
the arm
family. I don't know. I'd have to use
the arm on
the arm on that.
>> Right.
>> Right. Um,
so
so I
>> Right. Um,
so I I
so I I when
>> Right. Um,
so I I when I'm
so I I when I'm in
>> Right. Um,
so I I when I'm in senior
so I I when I'm in senior homes
>> Right. Um,
so I I when I'm in senior homes and
so I I when I'm in senior homes and many
other
other people
other people are
other people are in
other people are in wheelchairs
other people are in wheelchairs or
there's
there's not
other people are in wheelchairs or
there's not much
uh
uh movement
uh movement in
uh movement in their
uh movement in their bodies.
>> Yes.
Is
Is the
Is the essence
Is the essence of
Is the essence of them
Is the essence of them the
Is the essence of them the spirit
is
is it
Is the essence of them the spirit
is it still
working
>> working
>> in
>> in like
>> in like is
>> in like is it
>> is
>> is the
>> in like is it
>> is the spirit
>> is
>> is it
>> is it still
>> is it still accomplishing
>> is it still accomplishing something?
>> Okay
>> Okay the
>> is it still accomplishing something?
>> Okay the spirit
>> Okay the spirit leaves
>> is it still accomplishing something?
>> Okay the spirit leaves the
>> Okay the spirit leaves the body
progressively
progressively can
progressively can be
progressively can be 99%
progressively can be 99% gone.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
Thank
Thank you.
Thank you. Yeah,
>> it
>> it makes
Thank you. Yeah,
>> it makes it
>> it makes it easier.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Oh,
>> Yes. Oh, wait.
>> Yes. Oh, wait. You're
>> Yes. Oh, wait. You're welcome.
>> Yes. Oh, wait. You're welcome. Thank
you.
>> I
>> I used
>> I used to
>> I used to go
>> I used to go to
>> I used to go to all
>> I used to go to all the
>> I used to go to all the nursing
>> I used to go to all the nursing homes
>> I used to go to all the nursing homes in
the
the county.
>> I used to go to all the nursing homes in
the county. You
the county. You know,
>> I used to go to all the nursing homes in
the county. You know, nobody
the county. You know, nobody else
>> I used to go to all the nursing homes in
the county. You know, nobody else would
go
go to
go to them,
>> right?
>> And
>> And uh
>> And uh they
>> And uh they the
>> And uh they the family
>> And uh they the family don't
>> And uh they the family don't be
>> And uh they the family don't be worried
about
about Granny
>> And uh they the family don't be worried
about Granny doesn't
about Granny doesn't remember
>> And uh they the family don't be worried
about Granny doesn't remember who
about Granny doesn't remember who I
>> And uh they the family don't be worried
about Granny doesn't remember who I am
anymore.
>> So,
>> So, I'd
anymore.
>> So, I'd visit
>> So, I'd visit them
anymore.
>> So, I'd visit them and
>> So, I'd visit them and I'd
anymore.
>> So, I'd visit them and I'd say,
>> So, I'd visit them and I'd say, "How
anymore.
>> So, I'd visit them and I'd say, "How are
you,
you, Granny?"
you, Granny?" "Fine."
you, Granny?" "Fine." I
you, Granny?" "Fine." I said, "How
you, Granny?" "Fine." I said, "How are
they
they treating
you, Granny?" "Fine." I said, "How are
they treating you
they treating you here?"
you, Granny?" "Fine." I said, "How are
they treating you here?" "Fine."
they treating you here?" "Fine." "You
got
got any
got any complaints?"
got any complaints?" No,
>> they
>> they all
got any complaints?" No,
>> they all said
>> they all said the
got any complaints?" No,
>> they all said the same
>> they all said the same thing.
>> Yes,
>> it's
>> it's only
>> Yes,
>> it's only the
>> it's only the family
>> Yes,
>> it's only the family that's
>> it's only the family that's disturbed.
>> Good
>> Good news.
>> If
>> If you
>> Good news.
>> If you have
>> If you have no
>> Good news.
>> If you have no desires
>> If you have no desires or
>> Good news.
>> If you have no desires or wants,
>> If you have no desires or wants, how
>> Good news.
>> If you have no desires or wants, how can
you
you be
you be frustrated?
you be frustrated? You
you be frustrated? You know,
you be frustrated? You know, right?
>> Um
>> maybe
>> maybe they
>> maybe they forget
>> maybe they forget that
>> maybe they forget that they
>> maybe they forget that they are.
>> maybe they forget that they are. Huh.
My
My question
>> maybe they forget that they are. Huh.
My question was
My question was about
>> maybe they forget that they are. Huh.
My question was about the
My question was about the Native
American
American pipe
American pipe ceremony
American pipe ceremony and
American pipe ceremony and sweat
American pipe ceremony and sweat lodges
and
and how
American pipe ceremony and sweat lodges
and how they
and how they calibrate.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, they
>> Yeah, they calibrate
>> Yeah, they calibrate uh
>> Yeah, they calibrate uh very
>> Yeah, they calibrate uh very well.
>> Does
>> Does it
>> Yeah, they calibrate uh very well.
>> Does it depend
>> Does it depend on
>> Yeah, they calibrate uh very well.
>> Does it depend on the
>> Does it depend on the persons
>> Yeah, they calibrate uh very well.
>> Does it depend on the persons that
>> Does it depend on the persons that are
actually
actually doing
>> I
>> I don't
actually doing
>> I don't know.
>> Okay.
>> Uh
>> Uh we
>> Okay.
>> Uh we did
>> Uh we did uh
>> Okay.
>> Uh we did uh sweatline
>> Uh we did uh sweatline ceremony.
>> Okay.
>> Uh we did uh sweatline ceremony. It's
>> Uh we did uh sweatline ceremony. It's in
the
the book.
the book. Truth
the book. Truth versus
the book. Truth versus false.
>> I'm
>> I'm sorry.
>> It's
>> It's over
>> It's over uh
>> It's over uh 500
550.
550. It's
>> It's over uh 500
550. It's over
550. It's over 500.
>> It's over uh 500
550. It's over 500. It's
550. It's over 500. It's five
>> because
>> because of
>> because of the
>> because of the uh
>> because of the uh commitment.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Thank
>> because of the uh commitment.
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> You
>> You guys
>> You guys send
>> You guys send these
>> You guys send these things?
>> Yep.
>> Okay.
I
I don't
>> Okay.
I don't see
I don't see where
>> Okay.
I don't see where to
I don't see where to sign
>> Okay.
I don't see where to sign here.
I don't see where to sign here. Okay.
All right.
All right. Hello.
Instead
Instead of
All right. Hello.
Instead of a
Instead of a question,
All right. Hello.
Instead of a question, may
Instead of a question, may I
All right. Hello.
Instead of a question, may I ask
Instead of a question, may I ask for
All right. Hello.
Instead of a question, may I ask for a
blessing
blessing for
blessing for Argentina,
blessing for Argentina, please?
>> Blessing
>> Blessing for
blessing for Argentina, please?
>> Blessing for Argentina.
>> Blessing for Argentina. She
blessing for Argentina, please?
>> Blessing for Argentina. She wants
>> Blessing for Argentina. She wants a
blessing
blessing for
blessing for her
blessing for her country.
blessing for her country. That's
blessing for her country. That's very
nice.
>> Uh,
>> Uh, she
>> Uh, she wants
>> Uh, she wants a
>> Uh, she wants a blessing
>> Uh, she wants a blessing for
>> Uh, she wants a blessing for her
country,
country, Argentina.
>> It
>> It is
>> It is a
>> It is a great
>> It is a great country.
>> He
>> He was
>> It is a great country.
>> He was there
>> He was there once.
>> We're
>> We're having
>> We're having some
>> We're having some difficulties.
like
like everybody
>> We're having some difficulties.
like everybody else.
like everybody else. I'm
>> We're having some difficulties.
like everybody else. I'm sorry.
like everybody else. I'm sorry. We're
having
having some
having some difficulties
having some difficulties like
having some difficulties like everybody
else.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Howdy.
>> Howdy. Um
>> Yeah.
>> Howdy. Um okay
>> Howdy. Um okay could
>> Yeah.
>> Howdy. Um okay could you
>> Howdy. Um okay could you please
>> Yeah.
>> Howdy. Um okay could you please explain
to
to me
to me uh
to me uh what
to me uh what is
to me uh what is the
to me uh what is the difference
to me uh what is the difference between
living
living in
to me uh what is the difference between
living in in
living in in meditation
to me uh what is the difference between
living in in meditation and
living in in meditation and living
to me uh what is the difference between
living in in meditation and living in
contemplation?
>> Yes.
>> Living
>> Living in
>> Living in meditation
>> yeah
>> yeah I
>> Living in meditation
>> yeah I got
>> yeah I got it.
>> Living in meditation
>> yeah I got it. Meditation
>> yeah I got it. Meditation I've
>> Living in meditation
>> yeah I got it. Meditation I've spoken
about
has
has its
about
has its place
has its place has
about
has its place has its
has its place has its place.
about
has its place has its place. Uh
the
the trouble
the trouble with
the trouble with meditation
the trouble with meditation is
the trouble with meditation is it
the trouble with meditation is it tends
to
to get
the trouble with meditation is it tends
to get segregated
to get segregated from
the trouble with meditation is it tends
to get segregated from the
to get segregated from the rest
the trouble with meditation is it tends
to get segregated from the rest of
to get segregated from the rest of your
life
life and
life and eventually
life and eventually it
life and eventually it diminishes.
Contemplation
Contemplation is
life and eventually it diminishes.
Contemplation is a
Contemplation is a way
life and eventually it diminishes.
Contemplation is a way of
Contemplation is a way of being
life and eventually it diminishes.
Contemplation is a way of being in
Contemplation is a way of being in the
world
world which
world which is
world which is continuous
world which is continuous around
world which is continuous around the
clock.
clock. Meditation
world which is continuous around the
clock. Meditation is
clock. Meditation is very
world which is continuous around the
clock. Meditation is very focused
but
but you
but you can't
but you can't meditate
but you can't meditate and
but you can't meditate and drive
but you can't meditate and drive at
but you can't meditate and drive at the
same
same time.
but you can't meditate and drive at the
same time. So
same time. So but
but you can't meditate and drive at the
same time. So but it
same time. So but it means
but you can't meditate and drive at the
same time. So but it means you
same time. So but it means you got
but you can't meditate and drive at the
same time. So but it means you got to
take
take out
take out time
take out time from
take out time from life.
take out time from life. Well,
take out time from life. Well, after
take out time from life. Well, after a
while,
while, the
take out time from life. Well, after a
while, the novelty
while, the novelty of
take out time from life. Well, after a
while, the novelty of meditation
while, the novelty of meditation wears
off
off and
off and pretty
off and pretty soon
off and pretty soon instead
off and pretty soon instead of
off and pretty soon instead of doing
off and pretty soon instead of doing it
for
for an
off and pretty soon instead of doing it
for an hour,
for an hour, you
off and pretty soon instead of doing it
for an hour, you do
for an hour, you do it
off and pretty soon instead of doing it
for an hour, you do it half
for an hour, you do it half an
off and pretty soon instead of doing it
for an hour, you do it half an hour
for an hour, you do it half an hour and
then
then you
then you do
then you do it
then you do it for
then you do it for 40
then you do it for 40 minutes
then you do it for 40 minutes and
then you do it for 40 minutes and then
you
you miss
then you do it for 40 minutes and then
you miss it
you miss it when
then you do it for 40 minutes and then
you miss it when you
you miss it when you go
then you do it for 40 minutes and then
you miss it when you go to
you miss it when you go to vis
then you do it for 40 minutes and then
you miss it when you go to vis visit
your
your mother-in-law
your mother-in-law and
your mother-in-law and eventually
your mother-in-law and eventually it
tends
tends to
your mother-in-law and eventually it
tends to fade
tends to fade away
your mother-in-law and eventually it
tends to fade away with
tends to fade away with dedication.
However,
However, it
However, it doesn't.
However, it doesn't. I
However, it doesn't. I meditated
However, it doesn't. I meditated two
hours
hours in
However, it doesn't. I meditated two
hours in the
hours in the morning
However, it doesn't. I meditated two
hours in the morning an
hours in the morning an hour
However, it doesn't. I meditated two
hours in the morning an hour in
hours in the morning an hour in the
morning,
morning, hour
morning, hour at
morning, hour at night
morning, hour at night for
morning, hour at night for well
morning, hour at night for well over
morning, hour at night for well over 20
years.
But
But I
But I found
But I found that
But I found that in
But I found that in the
But I found that in the long
But I found that in the long run
But I found that in the long run the
contemplation
contemplation is
But I found that in the long run the
contemplation is like
contemplation is like making
But I found that in the long run the
contemplation is like making your
contemplation is like making your life
But I found that in the long run the
contemplation is like making your life a
meditation
meditation turning
meditation turning it
meditation turning it into
meditation turning it into a
meditation turning it into a meditation.
You
You know
it's
it's useful
it's useful for
uh
uh you
it's useful for
uh you can
uh you can go
it's useful for
uh you can go deeply
uh you can go deeply into
it's useful for
uh you can go deeply into the
consciousness
consciousness through
consciousness through meditation.
consciousness through meditation. So
consciousness through meditation. So I
don't
don't want
consciousness through meditation. So I
don't want to
don't want to diminish
consciousness through meditation. So I
don't want to diminish its
don't want to diminish its importance
either.
either. There's
either. There's certain
either. There's certain realizations
that
that can
either. There's certain realizations
that can only
that can only come
either. There's certain realizations
that can only come about
that can only come about in
either. There's certain realizations
that can only come about in meditation.
And
And an
And an example
And an example of
And an example of a
And an example of a contemplation,
And an example of a contemplation, an
exp.
exp. Could
And an example of a contemplation, an
exp. Could you
exp. Could you please
And an example of a contemplation, an
exp. Could you please give
exp. Could you please give me
And an example of a contemplation, an
exp. Could you please give me one?
>> Contemplative
>> Contemplative means
>> Contemplative means to
>> Contemplative means to identify
>> Contemplative means to identify with
>> Contemplative means to identify with the
field
field and
>> Contemplative means to identify with the
field and not
field and not the
>> Contemplative means to identify with the
field and not the content
field and not the content of
>> Contemplative means to identify with the
field and not the content of the
field and not the content of the field.
Like
Like when
Like when I
Like when I watch
Like when I watch the
Like when I watch the Olympics,
Like when I watch the Olympics, I'm
feeling
feeling the
Like when I watch the Olympics, I'm
feeling the totality
feeling the totality of
Like when I watch the Olympics, I'm
feeling the totality of the
feeling the totality of the Olympics
Like when I watch the Olympics, I'm
feeling the totality of the Olympics and
its
its place
its place in
its place in human
its place in human evolution
its place in human evolution and
its place in human evolution and its
place
place throughout
its place in human evolution and its
place throughout history.
and
and the
and the how
and the how it's
and the how it's inspirational,
how
how it
and the how it's inspirational,
how it demonstrates
uh
uh strength
uh strength and
uh strength and integrity
uh strength and integrity and
uh strength and integrity and power.
uh strength and integrity and power. I'm
also
also sort
uh strength and integrity and power. I'm
also sort of
also sort of interested
uh strength and integrity and power. I'm
also sort of interested in
also sort of interested in the
individual
individual performer,
individual performer, but
individual performer, but not
individual performer, but not really
because
because if
individual performer, but not really
because if it
because if it isn't
individual performer, but not really
because if it isn't him,
because if it isn't him, it's
individual performer, but not really
because if it isn't him, it's somebody
else.
>> That's
>> That's right.
>> The
>> The individual
>> The individual is
>> The individual is is
>> The individual is is different.
>> The individual is is different. That's
like
like looking
>> The individual is is different. That's
like looking for
like looking for credit.
>> The individual is is different. That's
like looking for credit. Anybody
like looking for credit. Anybody who's
there
there and
there and puts
there and puts himself
there and puts himself out
there and puts himself out there
there and puts himself out there has
already
already got
there and puts himself out there has
already got all
already got all the
there and puts himself out there has
already got all the credit
already got all the credit he
there and puts himself out there has
already got all the credit he needs.
See,
See, and
See, and trying
See, and trying to
See, and trying to be
See, and trying to be number
See, and trying to be number one
See, and trying to be number one to
See, and trying to be number one to me
is
is the
See, and trying to be number one to me
is the downside
is the downside of
See, and trying to be number one to me
is the downside of the
is the downside of the Olympics.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> I
>> I think
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> I think they're
>> I think they're all
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> I think they're all great.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> Who's
>> Who's number
>> Thank you very much.
>> Who's number one?
>> Who's number one? Who's
>> Thank you very much.
>> Who's number one? Who's number
>> Who's number one? Who's number two
>> Thank you very much.
>> Who's number one? Who's number two is
sort
sort of
sort of childish.
Like,
Like, who's
sort of childish.
Like, who's got
Like, who's got more
sort of childish.
Like, who's got more marbles?
I
I got
I got six
I got six marbles,
I got six marbles, you
I got six marbles, you got
I got six marbles, you got five,
I got six marbles, you got five, I
I got six marbles, you got five, I win.
You
You know,
I got six marbles, you got five, I win.
You know, it's
You know, it's sort
I got six marbles, you got five, I win.
You know, it's sort of
You know, it's sort of like
I got six marbles, you got five, I win.
You know, it's sort of like back
You know, it's sort of like back to
childhood.
Yeah.
>> Dr.
>> Dr. Hawkins,
you
you teach
>> Dr. Hawkins,
you teach that
you teach that life
>> Dr. Hawkins,
you teach that life is
you teach that life is a
>> Dr. Hawkins,
you teach that life is a gift
you teach that life is a gift and
>> Dr. Hawkins,
you teach that life is a gift and and
you teach that life is a gift and and I
get
get that.
get that. Um,
get that. Um, I'm
get that. Um, I'm a
get that. Um, I'm a hospice
get that. Um, I'm a hospice volunteer
and
and I
get that. Um, I'm a hospice volunteer
and I see
patients
patients handling
patients handling death
>> very
>> very differently.
patients handling death
>> very differently. Some
>> very differently. Some rage
patients handling death
>> very differently. Some rage against
>> very differently. Some rage against the
light.
>> Mhm.
>> I
>> I judge
>> I judge that
>> I judge that to
>> I judge that to be
>> I judge that to be very
>> I judge that to be very fearful.
>> Mhm.
>> I
>> I see
>> I see others
letting
letting go
>> I see others
letting go and
letting go and allowing
>> I see others
letting go and allowing it
letting go and allowing it to
>> I see others
letting go and allowing it to happen.
>> Yeah.
>> What's
>> What's the
>> Yeah.
>> What's the difference
>> What's the difference between
>> Yeah.
>> What's the difference between giving
>> What's the difference between giving up
and
and letting
and letting go
and letting go in
and letting go in in in
and letting go in in in death?
and letting go in in in death? Well,
surrendering
means
means to
means to surrender
means to surrender one's
means to surrender one's life
means to surrender one's life to
means to surrender one's life to God.
You
You see,
and
and not
and not trying
and not trying to
and not trying to control
and not trying to control it,
and not trying to control it, that's
all.
So,
So, when
>> surrendering
>> surrendering to
So, when
>> surrendering to God's
>> surrendering to God's will
So, when
>> surrendering to God's will instead
>> surrendering to God's will instead of
So, when
>> surrendering to God's will instead of uh
the
the personal
the personal will,
we
we we
the personal will,
we we die
we we die as
the personal will,
we we die as a
we we die as a result
the personal will,
we we die as a result of
we we die as a result of spiritual
choices
choices and
choices and karma.
I
I have
choices and karma.
I have seen
I have seen patients
choices and karma.
I have seen patients who
one
one in
one in particular
one in particular lost
one in particular lost control
one in particular lost control of
one in particular lost control of his
bodily
bodily functions.
>> Yep.
>> Said,
>> Said, "I'm
>> Yep.
>> Said, "I'm not
>> Said, "I'm not going
>> Yep.
>> Said, "I'm not going to
>> Said, "I'm not going to live
>> Yep.
>> Said, "I'm not going to live like
>> Said, "I'm not going to live like this."
And
And died
And died within
And died within 18
And died within 18 hours.
>> Good
>> Good idea.
>> I
>> I used
>> I used to
>> I used to persuade
>> I used to persuade them
>> I used to persuade them to
>> I used to persuade them to leave.
I'd
I'd say,
>> I used to persuade them to leave.
I'd say, "You
I'd say, "You don't
>> I used to persuade them to leave.
I'd say, "You don't have
I'd say, "You don't have to
>> I used to persuade them to leave.
I'd say, "You don't have to hang
I'd say, "You don't have to hang on."
>> I used to persuade them to leave.
I'd say, "You don't have to hang on." I
don't.
don't. They
don't. They think
don't. They think they
don't. They think they got
don't. They think they got to
don't. They think they got to hang
don't. They think they got to hang on
for
for all
don't. They think they got to hang on
for all kinds
for all kinds of
don't. They think they got to hang on
for all kinds of reasons.
for all kinds of reasons. I
don't. They think they got to hang on
for all kinds of reasons. I said,
for all kinds of reasons. I said, "You
can
can let
can let go.
can let go. God,
can let go. God, you
can let go. God, you know,
can let go. God, you know, God's
can let go. God, you know, God's love
forgives
forgives all
can let go. God, you know, God's love
forgives all things.
forgives all things. You
can let go. God, you know, God's love
forgives all things. You know,
forgives all things. You know, they
can let go. God, you know, God's love
forgives all things. You know, they say,
"Oh,
it's
it's okay
"Oh,
it's okay to
it's okay to leave."
"Oh,
it's okay to leave." You
it's okay to leave." You know,
"Oh,
it's okay to leave." You know, they
cling
cling because
cling because of
cling because of the
cling because of the family.
cling because of the family. They
cling because of the family. They cling
for
for all
cling because of the family. They cling
for all kinds
for all kinds of
cling because of the family. They cling
for all kinds of reasons,
but
but what
but what what
but what what is
but what what is the
but what what is the gain
but what what is the gain of
but what what is the gain of that
clinging
clinging to
but what what is the gain of that
clinging to the
clinging to the last
but what what is the gain of that
clinging to the last breath?
clinging to the last breath? And
but what what is the gain of that
clinging to the last breath? And I
order,
order, you
order, you know,
order, you know, there's
order, you know, there's no
order, you know, there's no gain
order, you know, there's no gain to
that.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
I
I remember
I remember telling
I remember telling somebody,
I remember telling somebody, "It's
I remember telling somebody, "It's okay
to
to leave.
I remember telling somebody, "It's okay
to leave. It's
to leave. It's okay
I remember telling somebody, "It's okay
to leave. It's okay to
to leave. It's okay to leave."
I remember telling somebody, "It's okay
to leave. It's okay to leave." She
to leave. It's okay to leave." She She
left.
>> It's
>> It's okay
left.
>> It's okay to
>> It's okay to leave.
>> Huh?
>> Huh? And
>> Huh? And she
>> Huh? And she left.
>> Man,
>> Man, I
>> Huh? And she left.
>> Man, I hope
>> Man, I hope for
>> Huh? And she left.
>> Man, I hope for other
>> Man, I hope for other people's
>> Huh? And she left.
>> Man, I hope for other people's sake,
>> Man, I hope for other people's sake, you
know.
>> Yeah.
>> I
>> I hope
>> I hope it's
>> I hope it's okay
>> I hope it's okay to
>> I hope it's okay to ask
>> I hope it's okay to ask questions
>> I hope it's okay to ask questions then
that
that you're
>> I hope it's okay to ask questions then
that you're afraid
that you're afraid to
>> I hope it's okay to ask questions then
that you're afraid to ask.
that you're afraid to ask. Mhm.
>> Because
>> Because I
>> Because I thought
>> Because I thought this
>> Because I thought this might
>> Because I thought this might sound
>> Because I thought this might sound like
a
a challenge,
>> Because I thought this might sound like
a challenge, but
a challenge, but in
>> Because I thought this might sound like
a challenge, but in in
a challenge, but in in uh
several
several of
several of your
several of your talks,
several of your talks, you
several of your talks, you talk
several of your talks, you talk about
how
how someone
several of your talks, you talk about
how someone who
how someone who calibrates
several of your talks, you talk about
how someone who calibrates 10,000
how someone who calibrates 10,000 can
calibrate
calibrate all
calibrate all the
calibrate all the negativity
calibrate all the negativity of
calibrate all the negativity of mankind
and
>> counterbalances.
>> counterbalances. It
>> counterbalances. It counterbalances
doesn't
doesn't negate
>> counterbalances. It counterbalances
doesn't negate it.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> And
>> And another
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> And another point,
>> And another point, you
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> And another point, you said
>> And another point, you said that
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> And another point, you said that four
and
and 700
and 700 plus
and 700 plus achieves
and 700 plus achieves the
and 700 plus achieves the same
and 700 plus achieves the same effect.
>> I
>> I I
and 700 plus achieves the same effect.
>> I I don't
>> I I don't know.
and 700 plus achieves the same effect.
>> I I don't know. You're
>> I I don't know. You're getting
and 700 plus achieves the same effect.
>> I I don't know. You're getting into
stuff
stuff that's
stuff that's in
stuff that's in the
stuff that's in the book.
stuff that's in the book. I
stuff that's in the book. I don't
remember
remember now.
>> Okay.
Uh
Uh and
>> Okay.
Uh and then
>> it's
>> it's not
>> it's not mathematical.
>> it's not mathematical. See,
>> it's not mathematical. See, you're
you're
you're attacking
>> it's not mathematical. See, you're
you're attacking it
you're attacking it from
>> it's not mathematical. See, you're
you're attacking it from the
you're attacking it from the logical
mathematical
>> okay
>> viewpoint.
>> viewpoint. It's
>> viewpoint. It's not
>> viewpoint. It's not that
energy
energy fields
>> viewpoint. It's not that
energy fields which
energy fields which are
>> viewpoint. It's not that
energy fields which are not
>> mathematically
>> mathematically equivalent.
>> mathematically equivalent. See,
>> mathematically equivalent. See, because
I
I think
>> mathematically equivalent. See, because
I think you're
I think you're answering
>> mathematically equivalent. See, because
I think you're answering Calgary
I think you're answering Calgary level
is
is a
is a range.
>> How
>> How can
is a range.
>> How can I
>> How can I explain
is a range.
>> How can I explain it?
>> How can I explain it? It's
is a range.
>> How can I explain it? It's not
>> How can I explain it? It's not like
numerical
numerical separateness
numerical separateness and
numerical separateness and you
numerical separateness and you put
numerical separateness and you put the
separate
separate blocks
numerical separateness and you put the
separate blocks together.
separate blocks together. It's
numerical separateness and you put the
separate blocks together. It's more
separate blocks together. It's more like
the
the totality
uh
uh the
the totality
uh the totality
uh the totality of
the totality
uh the totality of the
uh the totality of the whole
the totality
uh the totality of the whole is
uh the totality of the whole is greater
than
than the
than the sum
than the sum of
than the sum of the
than the sum of the parts.
than the sum of the parts. You
understand
understand what
than the sum of the parts. You
understand what I'm
understand what I'm saying?
>> Yes.
>> So
>> So at
>> So at the
>> So at the one
>> So at the one in
>> So at the one in the
>> So at the one in the in
>> So at the one in the in the
>> So at the one in the in the video
>> So at the one in the in the video you
tested
tested uh
>> So at the one in the in the video you
tested uh with
tested uh with your
>> So at the one in the in the video you
tested uh with your wife
tested uh with your wife and
>> So at the one in the in the video you
tested uh with your wife and and
tested uh with your wife and and found
that
that there
that there was
that there was one
that there was one on
that there was one on earth
that there was one on earth who
calibrated
calibrated over
that there was one on earth who
calibrated over 1,000.
>> Remember
>> Remember your
>> Remember your reaction?
>> Remember your reaction? Oh,
>> Remember your reaction? Oh, you
>> Remember your reaction? Oh, you said
that.
that. I
>> Remember your reaction? Oh, you said
that. I saw
that. I saw it
>> Remember your reaction? Oh, you said
that. I saw it on
that. I saw it on the
>> Remember your reaction? Oh, you said
that. I saw it on the video
that. I saw it on the video and
>> Remember your reaction? Oh, you said
that. I saw it on the video and you
that. I saw it on the video and you said
>> and
>> and then
>> and then Okay.
>> What
>> What video?
>> It's
>> It's um
I
I wish
>> It's um
I wish I
I wish I brought
>> It's um
I wish I brought it
I wish I brought it with
>> It's um
I wish I brought it with me
I wish I brought it with me here.
>> It's um
I wish I brought it with me here. We'll
have
have to
>> but
>> but I
have to
>> but I definitely
>> but I definitely have
have to
>> but I definitely have it
>> but I definitely have it and
have to
>> but I definitely have it and and
>> but I definitely have it and and I
have to
>> but I definitely have it and and I and
it
it that
it that jumped
it that jumped out
it that jumped out at
it that jumped out at me
it that jumped out at me when
it that jumped out at me when you
it that jumped out at me when you did
that
that and
it that jumped out at me when you did
that and and
that and and said
it that jumped out at me when you did
that and and said that
that and and said that because
it that jumped out at me when you did
that and and said that because you
that and and said that because you seem
to
to be
to be a
to be a surprise
to be a surprise like
to be a surprise like before
to be a surprise like before you
to be a surprise like before you had
said
said that
to be a surprise like before you had
said that that's
said that that's not
to be a surprise like before you had
said that that's not possible.
>> Yeah.
>> And
>> And then
>> Yeah.
>> And then there's
>> And then there's one
>> Yeah.
>> And then there's one that
>> And then there's one that did
>> Yeah.
>> And then there's one that did and
>> And then there's one that did and and
you
>> I
>> I don't
you
>> I don't remember.
>> I don't remember. No.
>> Well,
>> Well, anyway,
>> Well, anyway, let's
>> Well, anyway, let's get
>> Well, anyway, let's get past
>> Well, anyway, let's get past that
>> Well, anyway, let's get past that then
because
because it
>> Well, anyway, let's get past that then
because it doesn't
because it doesn't matter.
>> Well, anyway, let's get past that then
because it doesn't matter. Um
because it doesn't matter. Um that
>> Well, anyway, let's get past that then
because it doesn't matter. Um that the
related
related question
related question was
related question was that
related question was that the
related question was that the zero
related question was that the zero point
field
field is
related question was that the zero point
field is responsible
field is responsible for
related question was that the zero point
field is responsible for inertia
field is responsible for inertia and
related question was that the zero point
field is responsible for inertia and I
haven't
haven't been
haven't been able
haven't been able to
haven't been able to test
haven't been able to test that
haven't been able to test that with
kinesiology
kinesiology and
haven't been able to test that with
kinesiology and I
kinesiology and I will
haven't been able to test that with
kinesiology and I will somehow
>> just
>> just asking
>> just asking complicated
>> just asking complicated questions.
>> What
>> What is
>> just asking complicated questions.
>> What is your
>> What is your question
>> just asking complicated questions.
>> What is your question again?
>> The
>> The the
>> The the zero
>> The the zero point
>> The the zero point field
>> The the zero point field is
>> The the zero point field is responsible
for
for inertia
>> what
>> what the
>> what the zero
>> what the zero point
>> what the zero point field
>> what the zero point field is
>> what the zero point field is responsible
for
for inertia.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know
>> I don't know the
>> I don't know the term
>> I don't know the term zero
>> I don't know the term zero point
>> I don't know the term zero point field.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Um
>> did
>> did you
>> did you use
>> did you use that
>> did you use that term?
>> No.
>> No. then
>> did you use that term?
>> No. then I
>> No. then I can't
>> did you use that term?
>> No. then I can't ask
>> No. then I can't ask that
>> did you use that term?
>> No. then I can't ask that question
>> No. then I can't ask that question I
guess
but
but uh
guess
but uh questions
but uh questions relating
guess
but uh questions relating to
but uh questions relating to the
guess
but uh questions relating to the zero
point
point field
point field I
point field I guess
point field I guess I
point field I guess I can't
point field I guess I can't uh
point field I guess I can't uh do
point field I guess I can't uh do I
thought
thought perhaps
point field I guess I can't uh do I
thought perhaps you
thought perhaps you had
point field I guess I can't uh do I
thought perhaps you had read
thought perhaps you had read because
it's
it's deals
it's deals with
it's deals with quantum
it's deals with quantum physics
it's deals with quantum physics what
you're
>> saying
>> saying yeah
>> saying yeah you
>> saying yeah you have
>> saying yeah you have to
>> saying yeah you have to speak
>> saying yeah you have to speak up
>> saying yeah you have to speak up he
can't
can't hear
>> saying yeah you have to speak up he
can't hear you
>> okay
>> okay uh
>> okay uh I
>> okay uh I just
>> okay uh I just thought
>> okay uh I just thought that
>> okay uh I just thought that that
>> okay uh I just thought that that because
it
it deals
>> okay uh I just thought that that because
it deals with
it deals with quantum
>> okay uh I just thought that that because
it deals with quantum physics
it deals with quantum physics and
>> okay uh I just thought that that because
it deals with quantum physics and you
mentioned
mentioned that
mentioned that in
mentioned that in there
mentioned that in there and
mentioned that in there and especially
in
in the
mentioned that in there and especially
in the appendix
in the appendix of
mentioned that in there and especially
in the appendix of the
in the appendix of the one
mentioned that in there and especially
in the appendix of the one where
in the appendix of the one where you
said
said that
said that uh
said that uh the
said that uh the ultimate
said that uh the ultimate context
said that uh the ultimate context is
said that uh the ultimate context is God
which
which was
said that uh the ultimate context is God
which was one
which was one of
said that uh the ultimate context is God
which was one of those
which was one of those things
said that uh the ultimate context is God
which was one of those things that
jumped
jumped out.
jumped out. So
jumped out. So I
jumped out. So I guess
jumped out. So I guess I
jumped out. So I guess I just
jumped out. So I guess I just don't
jumped out. So I guess I just don't have
a
a clear
jumped out. So I guess I just don't have
a clear formulated
a clear formulated question
jumped out. So I guess I just don't have
a clear formulated question in
a clear formulated question in there.
jumped out. So I guess I just don't have
a clear formulated question in there. So
I
I apologize.
>> God
>> God is
I apologize.
>> God is the
>> God is the infinite
I apologize.
>> God is the infinite context.
>> God is the infinite context. Yes.
>> Pardon?
>> God
>> God is
>> Pardon?
>> God is the
>> God is the ultimate
>> Pardon?
>> God is the ultimate infinite
>> God is the ultimate infinite context.
>> Yeah.
>> I'll
>> I'll have
>> Yeah.
>> I'll have to
>> I'll have to try
>> Yeah.
>> I'll have to try to
>> I'll have to try to recall
>> Yeah.
>> I'll have to try to recall if
>> I'll have to try to recall if there
>> Yeah.
>> I'll have to try to recall if there was
anybody
anybody over
anybody over a
anybody over a thousand.
Not
Not that
anybody over a thousand.
Not that I
Not that I know
anybody over a thousand.
Not that I know of,
Not that I know of, but
anybody over a thousand.
Not that I know of, but I
Not that I know of, but I may
anybody over a thousand.
Not that I know of, but I may have
alluded
alluded to
alluded to something
alluded to something that
alluded to something that I've
alluded to something that I've forgotten
since.
>> It
>> It might
>> It might have
>> It might have been
>> It might have been an
>> It might have been an archangel.
>> It might have been an archangel. It
could
could have
>> It might have been an archangel. It
could have been
could have been something
>> It might have been an archangel. It
could have been something else
could have been something else we
>> It might have been an archangel. It
could have been something else we were
asking.
asking. They
asking. They are
asking. They are the
asking. They are the archangel.
asking. They are the archangel. Yeah.
But
>> you
>> you specifically
>> you specifically asked
>> you specifically asked how
>> you specifically asked how many
>> you specifically asked how many the
question
question came
>> you specifically asked how many the
question came from
question came from the
>> you specifically asked how many the
question came from the audience
question came from the audience is
>> you specifically asked how many the
question came from the audience is you
know
know about
know about how
know about how many
know about how many people
know about how many people calibrate
know about how many people calibrate at
a
a thousand
know about how many people calibrate at
a thousand and
a thousand and and
know about how many people calibrate at
a thousand and and you
>> I
>> I think
>> I think understood
>> I think understood as
>> I think understood as far
>> I think understood as far as
>> I think understood as far as I
>> I think understood as far as I know
nobody
nobody ever
>> I think understood as far as I know
nobody ever calibrate
nobody ever calibrate over
>> I think understood as far as I know
nobody ever calibrate over a thousand.
Um
>> physical
>> physical body
Um
>> physical body won't
>> physical body won't physical
Um
>> physical body won't physical body
>> physical body won't physical body won't
handle
handle it
handle it very
handle it very long.
>> Unless
>> Unless you
handle it very long.
>> Unless you were
>> Unless you were calibrating
handle it very long.
>> Unless you were calibrating archangels
that's
that's the
that's the only
that's the only thing
that's the only thing that
that's the only thing that goes
that's the only thing that goes over
that's the only thing that goes over a
thousand.
>> Is
>> Is is
>> Is is there
>> Is is there some
>> Is is there some place
>> Is is there some place I
>> Is is there some place I can
>> Is is there some place I can send
>> Is is there some place I can send when
>> Is is there some place I can send when I
look
look at
>> Is is there some place I can send when I
look at get
look at get the
>> Is is there some place I can send when I
look at get the title
look at get the title send
>> Is is there some place I can send when I
look at get the title send it
look at get the title send it to
>> Is is there some place I can send when I
look at get the title send it to you
look at get the title send it to you and
show
show you.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You
show you.
>> Yeah. You can
>> Yeah. You can email
show you.
>> Yeah. You can email us.
>> Yeah. You can email us. I'll
show you.
>> Yeah. You can email us. I'll see
>> Yeah. You can email us. I'll see if
show you.
>> Yeah. You can email us. I'll see if I
can
can recall
can recall the
can recall the question
can recall the question of
can recall the question of the
can recall the question of the answer
because
because right
can recall the question of the answer
because right now
>> okay
>> okay because
>> okay because that
>> okay because that that
>> okay because that that would
>> okay because that that would be
important
important in
>> okay because that that would be
important in the
important in the meantime.
So
So but
So but the
So but the but
So but the but the
So but the but the field
So but the but the field is
So but the but the field is when
So but the but the field is when you
So but the but the field is when you say
it's
it's logarithmic
So but the but the field is when you say
it's logarithmic you're
it's logarithmic you're not
So but the but the field is when you say
it's logarithmic you're not speaking
specifically
specifically mathematically
>> so
>> so that
specifically mathematically
>> so that if
>> so that if the
specifically mathematically
>> so that if the if
>> so that if the if you
specifically mathematically
>> so that if the if you let's
>> so that if the if you let's say
specifically mathematically
>> so that if the if you let's say at
>> so that if the if you let's say at one
time
time you
time you had
time you had 12
time you had 12 calibrated
time you had 12 calibrated over
time you had 12 calibrated over 700
time you had 12 calibrated over 700 and
mankind
mankind wouldn't
time you had 12 calibrated over 700 and
mankind wouldn't necessarily
mankind wouldn't necessarily be
time you had 12 calibrated over 700 and
mankind wouldn't necessarily be coined
out
out right
out right okay
>> tools
>> tools these
out right okay
>> tools these are
>> tools these are not
out right okay
>> tools these are not the
>> tools these are not the correct
out right okay
>> tools these are not the correct tools
for
for understanding
for understanding it
>> good
>> good uh
for understanding it
>> good uh how
>> good uh how how
>> using
>> using arithmetic
>> how
>> how do
>> using arithmetic
>> how do I
>> how do I get
>> using arithmetic
>> how do I get past
>> how do I get past this
>> just
>> just decide
>> just decide it's
>> just decide it's irrelevant
>> just decide it's irrelevant take
>> just decide it's irrelevant take my
>> just decide it's irrelevant take my word
for
for it
>> I'll
>> I'll do
>> I'll do just
>> I'll do just All
>> I'll do just All right,
>> I'll do just All right, thank
>> I'll do just All right, thank you.
>> That's
>> That's nonlinear.
>> That
>> That takes
>> That takes courage.
>> That
>> That is
>> to
>> to abandon
>> to abandon the
>> to abandon the left
>> to abandon the left brain.
>> Yeah.
>> Hi,
>> Hi, Dr.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Abandon
>> Abandon that
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Abandon that left
>> Abandon that left brain.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Abandon that left brain. All
>> Abandon that left brain. All ye
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Abandon that left brain. All ye who
>> Abandon that left brain. All ye who are
have
have lost
have lost all
have lost all hope.
>> Hi.
>> I
>> I know
>> I know what
>> I know what he's
>> I know what he's doing.
>> I know what he's doing. any
>> I know what he's doing. any kind
>> I know what he's doing. any kind of
comprehend
comprehend and
>> I know what he's doing. any kind of
comprehend and he's
comprehend and he's trying
>> I know what he's doing. any kind of
comprehend and he's trying the
comprehend and he's trying the harder
>> I know what he's doing. any kind of
comprehend and he's trying the harder he
tries
tries the
tries the more
tries the more obscure
tries the more obscure it
tries the more obscure it gets.
>> Yes.
>> Um
>> Um I
>> Um I have
>> Um I have a
>> Um I have a question.
>> Um I have a question. Um
>> Um I have a question. Um other
>> Um I have a question. Um other than
thanking
thanking you
>> Um I have a question. Um other than
thanking you for
thanking you for everything
>> Um I have a question. Um other than
thanking you for everything you've
thanking you for everything you've done.
Thank
Thank you
Thank you very
Thank you very much.
>> Um
>> Um oh
Thank you very much.
>> Um oh in
>> Um oh in this
Thank you very much.
>> Um oh in this one
>> Um oh in this one or
Thank you very much.
>> Um oh in this one or this
>> Um oh in this one or this one?
>> Just
>> Just lean
>> Just lean forward.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Um,
>> I'm
>> I'm wondering
>> I'm wondering about,
>> I'm wondering about, you
>> I'm wondering about, you mentioned
>> I'm wondering about, you mentioned today
about
about how
>> I'm wondering about, you mentioned today
about how we
about how we went
>> I'm wondering about, you mentioned today
about how we went from
about how we went from 207
>> I'm wondering about, you mentioned today
about how we went from 207 to
about how we went from 207 to 205
>> and
>> and I
>> and I was
>> and I was wondering,
>> you
>> you mentioned
>> and I was wondering,
>> you mentioned today
>> you mentioned today what
>> how
>> how we
>> how we went
>> how we went from
>> how we went from 207
>> how we went from 207 to
>> how we went from 207 to 205
>> how we went from 207 to 205 level
>> how we went from 207 to 205 level of
consciousness.
>> And
>> And I'm
>> And I'm wondering
>> And I'm wondering if
>> And I'm wondering if um
>> And I'm wondering if um other
>> And I'm wondering if um other than
working
working on
>> And I'm wondering if um other than
working on our
working on our own
>> And I'm wondering if um other than
working on our own spirituality,
>> um,
>> um, if
>> um, if there's
>> um, if there's any
>> um, if there's any actions
>> um, if there's any actions that
>> um, if there's any actions that we
>> um, if there's any actions that we could
be
be taking.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, certainly
>> Yeah, certainly the
>> Yeah, certainly the world
>> Yeah, certainly the world to
>> Yeah, certainly the world to God
>> as
>> as Okay.
>> Yeah, certainly the world to God
>> as Okay. Okay.
>> as Okay. Okay. All right.
>> Yeah, certainly the world to God
>> as Okay. Okay. All right. We'll
do
>> if
>> if exit
do
>> if exit is
>> if exit is going
do
>> if exit is going down
>> if exit is going down doesn't
do
>> if exit is going down doesn't mean
>> if exit is going down doesn't mean it
needs
needs saving.
>> All
>> All right.
needs saving.
>> All right. Right.
>> All right. Right. I
needs saving.
>> All right. Right. I see
>> All right. Right. I see that.
needs saving.
>> All right. Right. I see that. And
>> All right. Right. I see that. And then
needs saving.
>> All right. Right. I see that. And then I
was
was wondering
was wondering if
>> the
>> the road
was wondering if
>> the road may
>> the road may have
was wondering if
>> the road may have to
>> the road may have to hit
was wondering if
>> the road may have to hit bottom
>> the road may have to hit bottom before
it
it comes
it comes around
>> in
>> in the
it comes around
>> in the 12step
>> in the 12step program.
>> Yes.
>> Being
>> Being an
>> Yes.
>> Being an enabler
>> Being an enabler is
>> Yes.
>> Being an enabler is preventing
>> Being an enabler is preventing the
person
person from
person from hitting
person from hitting the
person from hitting the bottom,
person from hitting the bottom, right?
>> At
>> At which
person from hitting the bottom, right?
>> At which they
>> At which they would
person from hitting the bottom, right?
>> At which they would completely
>> At which they would completely and
totally
totally abandon
totally abandon themselves.
>> So
>> So trying
totally abandon themselves.
>> So trying to
>> So trying to save
totally abandon themselves.
>> So trying to save the
>> So trying to save the world
totally abandon themselves.
>> So trying to save the world maybe
prolonging
prolonging its
prolonging its agony.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Thank
prolonging its agony.
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Would
>> Yeah. Would could
>> Yeah. Would could we
>> Yeah. Would could we have
>> Yeah. Would could we have a
>> Yeah. Would could we have a picture?
>> He's
>> He's the
>> Yeah. Would could we have a picture?
>> He's the picture.
>> Only
>> Only in
>> Only in war
>> Only in war you
>> Only in war you learn
>> Only in war you learn certain
>> Only in war you learn certain things.
>> Only in war you learn certain things. I
hate
hate to
>> Only in war you learn certain things. I
hate to say
hate to say it,
>> Only in war you learn certain things. I
hate to say it, but
hate to say it, but it's
>> Only in war you learn certain things. I
hate to say it, but it's a
hate to say it, but it's a fact.
>> It's
>> It's only
>> It's only when
>> It's only when you're
>> It's only when you're facing
>> It's only when you're facing a
>> It's only when you're facing a canyon
that
that you
>> It's only when you're facing a canyon
that you can
that you can hit
>> It's only when you're facing a canyon
that you can hit that
that you can hit that bottom.
>> It
>> It has
>> It has to
>> It has to be
>> It has to be a
>> It has to be a real
>> It has to be a real cannon.
>> It has to be a real cannon. Can't
>> It has to be a real cannon. Can't be
>> It has to be a real cannon. Can't be a
shave
shave one.
>> It has to be a real cannon. Can't be a
shave one. Yes.
Very
Very good.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, no.
Very good.
>> Oh, no. You
>> Oh, no. You shut
Very good.
>> Oh, no. You shut it
>> Oh, no. You shut it off.
>> I
>> I shut
>> I shut it
>> I shut it off.
>> Hold
>> Hold on.
>> I shut it off.
>> Hold on. Hold
>> Hold on. Hold on.
>> Other
>> Other other
>> Other other one.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> There
>> There we
>> Yeah.
>> There we go.
>> I
>> I get
>> I get the
>> I get the kind
>> I get the kind at
>> I get the kind at Walgreens
>> I get the kind at Walgreens when
>> I get the kind at Walgreens when you're
done
done with
>> I get the kind at Walgreens when you're
done with them,
done with them, you
>> I get the kind at Walgreens when you're
done with them, you turn
done with them, you turn them
>> I get the kind at Walgreens when you're
done with them, you turn them in
done with them, you turn them in and
they
they give
they give you
they give you back
they give you back the
they give you back the printouts.
they give you back the printouts. And
then
>> Oh,
>> Oh, she
>> Oh, she dropped
>> Oh, she dropped something.
>> It's
>> It's just
>> Oh, she dropped something.
>> It's just got
>> It's just got on,
>> Oh, she dropped something.
>> It's just got on, off,
on,
on, off.
That's
That's as
on, off.
That's as complicated
That's as complicated as
on, off.
That's as complicated as I
That's as complicated as I can
on, off.
That's as complicated as I can handle.
Yes.
Yeah.
>> Hello.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Um,
>> Yes. Um, first
>> Yes. Um, first of
>> Yes. Um, first of all,
>> Yes. Um, first of all, I
>> Yes. Um, first of all, I just
>> Yes. Um, first of all, I just wanted
>> Yes. Um, first of all, I just wanted to
say
say thank
>> Yes. Um, first of all, I just wanted to
say thank you
say thank you very
>> Yes. Um, first of all, I just wanted to
say thank you very much.
say thank you very much. I've
>> Yes. Um, first of all, I just wanted to
say thank you very much. I've been
say thank you very much. I've been a
student
student of
student of your
student of your work
student of your work for
student of your work for a
student of your work for a few
student of your work for a few years
now,
now, and
student of your work for a few years
now, and it's
now, and it's been
student of your work for a few years
now, and it's been a
now, and it's been a great
student of your work for a few years
now, and it's been a great blessing
now, and it's been a great blessing to
my
my life,
my life, as
my life, as I'm
my life, as I'm sure
my life, as I'm sure it
my life, as I'm sure it has
my life, as I'm sure it has to
my life, as I'm sure it has to literally
thousands,
thousands, if
my life, as I'm sure it has to literally
thousands, if not
thousands, if not hundreds
my life, as I'm sure it has to literally
thousands, if not hundreds of
thousands, if not hundreds of thousands
in
in the
in the world,
and
and you
in the world,
and you teach,
and you teach, I
in the world,
and you teach, I know,
and you teach, I know, uh,
in the world,
and you teach, I know, uh, selfless
service
service and
service and selfless
service and selfless love.
service and selfless love. And
service and selfless love. And here
service and selfless love. And here I
service and selfless love. And here I am
and
and I
service and selfless love. And here I am
and I have
and I have a
service and selfless love. And here I am
and I have a kind
and I have a kind of
service and selfless love. And here I am
and I have a kind of a
and I have a kind of a selfish
service and selfless love. And here I am
and I have a kind of a selfish question.
Uh
Uh and
Uh and uh
Uh and uh the
Uh and uh the first
Uh and uh the first question
Uh and uh the first question is
Uh and uh the first question is uh
Uh and uh the first question is uh I've
already
already spoken
Uh and uh the first question is uh I've
already spoken briefly
already spoken briefly to
Uh and uh the first question is uh I've
already spoken briefly to Susan.
already spoken briefly to Susan. Uh
Uh and uh the first question is uh I've
already spoken briefly to Susan. Uh it
would
would be
would be an
would be an invitation
would be an invitation to
would be an invitation to bring
would be an invitation to bring you
would be an invitation to bring you to
Madison,
Madison, Wisconsin
would be an invitation to bring you to
Madison, Wisconsin uh
Madison, Wisconsin uh to
would be an invitation to bring you to
Madison, Wisconsin uh to speak.
>> Well,
>> Well, it
>> Well, it would
>> Well, it would be
>> Well, it would be uh
>> Well, it would be uh nice
>> Well, it would be uh nice if
>> Well, it would be uh nice if I
>> Well, it would be uh nice if I was
traveling.
traveling. I
>> Well, it would be uh nice if I was
traveling. I love
traveling. I love Madison.
>> Mhm.
>> And
>> And I
>> Mhm.
>> And I survived
>> And I survived a
>> Mhm.
>> And I survived a homecoming.
>> And I survived a homecoming. Mhm.
>> My
>> My father
>> My father uh
>> My father uh was
>> My father uh was a
>> My father uh was a well-known
>> My father uh was a well-known musician,
Madison.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Yeah. And uh
>> so
>> so University
>> Yeah. And uh
>> so University of
>> so University of Wisconsin
>> Yeah. And uh
>> so University of Wisconsin uh
>> so University of Wisconsin uh of
>> Yeah. And uh
>> so University of Wisconsin uh of course
I
I thank
I thank you
I thank you for
I thank you for the
I thank you for the uh
I thank you for the uh invitation.
Second
Second question,
I thank you for the uh invitation.
Second question, um
Second question, um I
I thank you for the uh invitation.
Second question, um I don't
Second question, um I don't know
I thank you for the uh invitation.
Second question, um I don't know if
Second question, um I don't know if you
still
still have
still have it
still have it or
still have it or not,
still have it or not, but
still have it or not, but in
still have it or not, but in an
still have it or not, but in an old
video,
video, uh
still have it or not, but in an old
video, uh power
video, uh power versus
still have it or not, but in an old
video, uh power versus forest
video, uh power versus forest video,
still have it or not, but in an old
video, uh power versus forest video, I
believe,
believe, done,
believe, done, I
believe, done, I think,
believe, done, I think, by
believe, done, I think, by yourself,
believe, done, I think, by yourself, uh
at
at your
believe, done, I think, by yourself, uh
at your ranch,
at your ranch, if
believe, done, I think, by yourself, uh
at your ranch, if I'm
at your ranch, if I'm not
believe, done, I think, by yourself, uh
at your ranch, if I'm not mistaken.
at your ranch, if I'm not mistaken. I
might
might be
might be mistaken
might be mistaken about
might be mistaken about that.
>> But
>> But I
might be mistaken about that.
>> But I noticed
>> But I noticed there
might be mistaken about that.
>> But I noticed there was
>> But I noticed there was a
might be mistaken about that.
>> But I noticed there was a blue
>> But I noticed there was a blue Baraka
lounger,
lounger, I
lounger, I think.
>> Blue
>> Blue chair.
>> Could
>> Could be.
>> Could be. Yeah.
>> I
>> I just
>> Could be. Yeah.
>> I just wondered
>> I just wondered if
>> Could be. Yeah.
>> I just wondered if you
>> I just wondered if you still
>> Could be. Yeah.
>> I just wondered if you still had
>> I just wondered if you still had it
>> Could be. Yeah.
>> I just wondered if you still had it and
if
if I
if I might
if I might buy
if I might buy it
if I might buy it from
if I might buy it from you.
It
>> actually
>> actually I
>> actually I think
>> actually I think had
>> actually I think had blue
>> actually I think had blue duct
>> actually I think had blue duct tape
>> actually I think had blue duct tape on
it
it too
>> actually I think had blue duct tape on
it too at
it too at that
>> actually I think had blue duct tape on
it too at that time.
>> Uh
>> Uh I
>> Uh I already
>> Uh I already stole
>> Uh I already stole I
>> Uh I already stole I already
>> Uh I already stole I already sold
>> Uh I already stole I already sold it
>> Uh I already stole I already sold it for
over
over a
>> Uh I already stole I already sold it for
over a million
over a million dollars.
>> That
>> That doesn't
>> That doesn't surprise
>> That doesn't surprise me.
>> I
>> I would
>> That doesn't surprise me.
>> I would have
>> I would have given
>> That doesn't surprise me.
>> I would have given it
>> I would have given it to
>> That doesn't surprise me.
>> I would have given it to you
>> I would have given it to you for
>> That doesn't surprise me.
>> I would have given it to you for 20.
Well,
Well, from
Well, from from
Well, from from what
Well, from from what I
Well, from from what I understand
Well, from from what I understand about
how
how you
Well, from from what I understand about
how you value
how you value your
Well, from from what I understand about
how you value your stewardship
how you value your stewardship of
possessions
possessions that
>> Well,
>> Well, at
possessions that
>> Well, at any
>> Well, at any rate,
possessions that
>> Well, at any rate, um
>> Well, at any rate, um also
possessions that
>> Well, at any rate, um also lastly,
>> Well, at any rate, um also lastly, I
would
would ask
would ask for
would ask for your
would ask for your blessing.
>> Yes.
>> Thank
>> Thank you,
>> Madison.
>> Madison. Yes.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> And
>> And thank
>> Thank you.
>> And thank you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you for
>> Thank you for inviting
>> Thank you for inviting us
>> Thank you for inviting us to
>> Thank you for inviting us to Madison.
>> You're
>> You're welcome.
>> Thank you for inviting us to Madison.
>> You're welcome. Thank
>> You're welcome. Thank you.
>> Thank you for inviting us to Madison.
>> You're welcome. Thank you. And
>> You're welcome. Thank you. And I
>> Thank you for inviting us to Madison.
>> You're welcome. Thank you. And I I
>> You're welcome. Thank you. And I I will
send
send you
send you an
send you an email.
>> The
>> The student
send you an email.
>> The student the
>> The student the student
send you an email.
>> The student the student union,
>> The student the student union, the
send you an email.
>> The student the student union, the rat
killer
killer there
killer there was
killer there was a
killer there was a famous
>> one
>> one of
killer there was a famous
>> one of my
>> one of my favorite
killer there was a famous
>> one of my favorite hangouts
>> one of my favorite hangouts to
killer there was a famous
>> one of my favorite hangouts to play
bridge
bridge years
bridge years ago.
>> We
>> We used
bridge years ago.
>> We used to
>> We used to go
bridge years ago.
>> We used to go there
for
for homecoming,
for homecoming, you
for homecoming, you know.
for homecoming, you know. Homecoming.
Yes,
Yes, I've
for homecoming, you know. Homecoming.
Yes, I've been
Yes, I've been to
for homecoming, you know. Homecoming.
Yes, I've been to many.
>> Yes.
Thank
Thank you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.