Well, I knew Helen, who did the interdictation on the course, and I knew Bill Thepford, and Steinbergs, Saul, who published it for the Foundation for Inner Peace, and his brother, and his brother lost a leg.
And when I lost my thumb, his brother came out to be with me, because he thought I'd probably be grieving the loss of an amputation, and he'd already been through it.
So I thought that was a very loving thing to do. It was Paul, who was not deceased, and so it's all, you know. Yep.
Earlier you said that sometimes people will willingly agree to take on the karma of others.
Yes.
Is that just high-level teachers, people of high levels of consciousness?
I was also wondering, you said that...
I think we saw the Pope do it to some extent.
The Pope did that to some extent.
In the name of all sinners, he was doing it. I could read his mind, you know.
In the name of all sinners, he was doing that as a sacrifice to the Lord Jesus Christ.
And he was obviously a saint.
You said that women are more non-linear than men.
Does that mean that they calibrate higher?
No.
Well, recently there was some research about the IQs of men and women, alleging that men were higher than women or something.
Yeah.
And we instantly, I intuited that.
They weren't as good as science.
That's completely false. No, it wasn't that. It was IQ.
Oh.
And it's false. Their IQs are the same.
The last time I asked you a question, it was about surrendering thoughts.
Because one day it just came to me. I'm not going to follow my mind all over the place.
And you told me about staying on the razor's edge, and so I went home, and I tried to do it, and you're right.
There were some amazing states of joy, like the more you love God, the more you feel it, and then there was this feeling of insanity.
It felt like I was going backwards.
Wait a minute now. You've got to go slower. I'm talking to the microphone. Don't give me a batch of confusion. Straighten it out. Linear, please.
There were these feelings of feeling like I was going backwards, like I was headed in the wrong direction, because it almost felt like insanity.
You mean you used to be insane, and you're going backwards into it again? What do you mean backwards?
I felt all this lower, like that joy wasn't there. It was, it was...
Oh, you mean lowered state, lowered state of consciousness. Yeah.
Right. It felt like I was headed in the wrong direction with the surrendering.
I was surrendering every...
Oh, you were just allowing some negative, negative material to come up, to get cleared. I told you that. When you get high, when you're above your karma, you feel high.
Because you're now above your karma, you've earned the karmic credit to handle a bigger stack. So what comes up then is a bigger stack.
You think that you're going backwards, but you're not. You're just handling what would have been too much for you to handle prior.
I think I'd do it.
Well, if you read the lives of the Christian saints, especially the women, many of them are saints.
They wrote their biographies. They would go into a high state, and then they would lose it because the next stack would come up.
And they would go into mourning and feel deserted by God. So many of the great famous, especially women mystic saints, you really, really, you've got to read about it.
Then you won't, you know, think that you're unusual or something.
Can you recommend?
Well, we have a list of spirits.
Okay.
We have a list of spiritual teachers. In that spiritual teachers, you see several.
In Encyclopedia Britannica, look up mystics.
Okay.
You'll see some of the famous women mystics, a number of whom really were proclaimed to be saints, who would reach a high state and then crash.
And how can you have deserted me, my beloved?
Yeah.
Feeling so.
That is far and parcel of the mystic course.
The inner road.
Do that now.
You're going to promise me.
You're going to look it up in Encyclopedia Britannica.
Look up mystics, and you'll see there's about half a dozen.
And most of all of them, you can read them.
Magdeburg, many, many famous ones, German ones, Austrian ones.
It's par for the course.
Thank you.
You've earned the right to say how awful you've been.
My God, I have been awful.
Dr.
Thank you for.
The Christmas miracle of your presence here today.
For all of us.
I'm basically up here to step through a fear today.
Yeah.
All's well.
Look in the presence of love.
Thank you.
She's afraid to come up here.
She said she had a.
She's okay.
She's come to see us since 2002.
Yeah.
Yes.
Hi.
For two years.
Two years.
There's been an impetus to come and kneel and acknowledge all that I'm grateful for.
And here I am.
I didn't want a year to pass again.
Oh.
Before I did that.
May I?
You've got to be courage.
Yeah.
Yep.
Good for you.
Yeah.
God bless you, sweetheart.
I understand.
I know exactly what you're saying.
Thank you.
And I know exactly how you feel.
I know exactly how you feel.
Sometimes people cry for a couple of years.
And monastic orders, that's very well known.
Reach a certain level, you cry all the time.
Can't help it.
I used to only cry when I saw love expressed in one way or another.
A loving glance, and I couldn't stop crying.
A kitten looking up with trust.
I couldn't stop crying.
Beautiful.
Crying lasted for, I don't know, a year or two.
My question is about love.
I had an experience a few years ago where I was in an accident,
and it changed my whole, it seemed like I lost my identity.
And a couple days after the accident, when I was recuperating,
I had this overwhelming, incredible experience of love.
Like, there was so much love.
And it seemed that at that time that I couldn't handle it.
Like, it was just way too much love.
And so it's almost as if I just shut it off.
And I noticed recently a recurring belief or pattern within myself
that if I allow the love that I feel inside,
the lovingness that I feel inside to be expressed,
or shown, or revealed, or all of those whatever,
that I'll get, it's like I would be crushed.
And so that pattern, it seems to have reared its head recently,
so there's a tendency to want to withdraw.
What I would be crushed.
The personal I would be crushed, wouldn't I?
You would disappear into that energy.
Yes, it's true, you would.
My body might just topple over.
No, it's nothing serious, it's okay.
Yeah, it seems like that's kind of where I want to go.
So basically the ego is worrying about its survival,
and that's the resistance.
That's what's happening.
So just if you surrender to dying, it'll disappear.
Because pretty much every day I say I surrender my existence.
You're disappointed that it didn't happen.
You're right about that.
Okay, so I can just let it rip?
Yes.
So to speak.
If you have family or friends or associates,
somebody who knows what you're doing,
so they realize that it's a spiritual state.
There's also been the desire over the last year to go away.
Like just, I want to go and be in seclusion,
and just be one with God,
because there's nothing else that really appeals.
I don't want to be in seclusion anymore.
Yes.
I mean, what do you think about that?
That's the stage you may well go through, yeah.
So regardless of response, I mean, I'm single, I don't have a cat,
I don't have any plants, you know.
You know, I have financial responsibilities, that's about it.
So I just...
So take advantage of it.
So take advantage of the fact that I'm single,
I don't have a cat or any plants.
What about the financial responsibilities?
No.
Well, that you have to make do as best you can.
You could sell manure, all kinds of things you can do.
Yeah.
Okay.
Forty bucks a load.
I have a truck.
Probably up to sixty by now.
Okay. Thank you very much.
I'll rent you my manure truck for 25% of the profit.
Your old truck? Your old truck?
I don't know, that thing sounds scary to drive.
There's no power steering.
Oh, I had one of those.
Doesn't that power anything though?
I had a Chevy like that.
Whoa.
No, you're doing all right.
Okay.
It's just the process.
You keep telling me I'm doing all right,
so I guess I'm just going to have to take you for your word on that.
And you may not be able to function,
and they'll put you in the poorhouse.
So what?
And we'll all support you.
Thanks, Doc.
Love you very much.
Love you too, Susan.
I don't know.
You can't even find a poorhouse anymore.
Dickens days, they had poorhouses and workhouses and stuff.
Yeah, they do, and they have a poorhouse.
Chino Valley has houses that they maybe retreat in.
You might contact them.
It's amazing to me that there's a person that does work here.
Yeah, they have that, too.
Yeah, the monastic life sometimes comes up as an option in people's lives.
Hi.
Yes.
Thank you so much.
It's such an amazing gift to be here.
I love you both so much.
My question is, when I'm here, Dr. Hawkins,
I feel the presence of God through you, and I feel so happy,
and it feels so easy to have that faith.
It's just natural.
And then when I go home, I pray and try to do the Course in Miracles,
and I have this intellectual knowing that God is real,
and I have faith because I hear what you say,
and I have such faith in you.
But it's hard for me to really feel God a lot of the time,
and it's really painful.
What do I do?
Yeah, no, that's normal, see?
Okay.
And then after a while, it gets stronger and stronger.
Sometimes you can envision the group or the teacher or, you know,
high moment with the group to sort of recapture it.
But it becomes more and more predominant as time goes on.
The separation feeling?
No, no, the feeling of the presence of God that becomes more strong.
Okay.
In a group like this, of course, it's very strong.
Yeah.
And then after you leave the group, your memory of the group,
your vision of the group, et cetera, will carry you through.
Because the group affiliation doesn't require a geographic location,
you know what I'm saying?
You can be in the middle of the Pacific,
and if you're a member of some great group like AA or something,
you know, that carries you through because your commitment is one of commitment.
That's geographic.
So hold the group in mind to reconnect with the feeling here of God.
Yes, yes, to hold it in mind.
Hold it in your heart.
Hold the whole group in your heart.
Thank you.
Hey, Dr. Hawkins, Susan.
One thing that I've noticed every time I come to ask a question
is an awareness of, like, that black spot on your soul thing you talked about.
You got any black spots?
I feel like when I sit with you...
I don't know what you're talking about.
You got a black spot on your soul.
Well, more like just a subtle, like, nervousness or guilt or something.
Yeah, unconscious guilt.
And I know I'm, okay, I'm juicing it, it's narcissistic, but it's just like...
No, it's unconscious guilt.
Yeah, so that's what it is.
Yeah.
I don't know if I have a question.
I just wanted to admit that to you.
Well, you should feel guilty about having unconscious guilt.
I used to feel guilty about worrying about a black spot on my soul.
So, scrupulosity.
Thank you, Doc.
I told her I had to go for counseling with the priest about scrupulosity.
Hello?
Yes.
Oh, there's a guy.
I was just wondering if there's any kind of technique to, like, clear energies
that you pick up in your chakras or your aura throughout the day?
That you pick up when?
Like, throughout the day?
You may pick up certain energies from people or different things that get stuck in your
aura or your chakras?
Well, yes.
That's why.
That's right.
That's one.
You know that one?
Yeah.
Thump the thymus and think of God or Jesus or some divine figure.
Mm-hmm.
Yep.
Is there anything else, like prayer or anything?
Yes.
I think the Holy Spirit revealed to you what the energy, negative energy, is about.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
I asked for a miracle.
I asked the Lord to impress upon my mind the awareness, the knowingness of what kind of
energy is out.
Yeah.
And then from that, you can assume which chakra and maybe what kind of an archetype
within.
Is it the boy?
The man?
And then you said, too, that, like, these energies that come from out here.
Instead of within, we've got the, I guess you could say the karmic right to demand that
they leave now.
Yes.
Oh, yes.
In the name of the Holy Spirit.
The royal money.
Oh, yes.
You have the karmic power.
In the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, I hereby order you to leave.
Hmm.
All right, thank you.
By the power of the Lord Jesus Christ within me, I order you to leave.
That's what you tell the dark spirit.
Yeah.
You're the dark spirit, not me.
You say that to the dark spirit.
I've thanked you both many times in my consciousness, but never face to face, in protoplasm, so from
the depths of my heart, thank you.
Please accept this gift of love and appreciation from myself and Elinda.
Thank you.
Were you the one that hollered out, get a second opinion?
No, that was Jack.
Oh!
I knew it came from that corner.
And the previous guy kind of took my question.
But the thymus thump I found to be incredibly useful, you know, for spiritual first aid.
Yes, yes, yes.
Just throughout the day.
For a quick thumper, yeah.
Yeah, and I don't know if people realize how useful that is.
As I ask people, do you do that?
And most people say no.
It works amazingly well.
Yeah, it's a quick fix.
Yeah.
I was curious about the energetics of that.
What's going on when you do that?
Well, the thymus is right behind the breastbone of a breastbone.
The thymus controls the level of killer cells in the immune system.
And it has to do with the balance of the acupuncture system.
So if something negative comes along, it can blow out that acupuncture meridian.
And so it was John Diamond taught.
I think it was the thymic thump, yes.
You can activate the thymus.
It then pours out more killer cells.
It pours out more good neurotransmitters and gets you out of a negative fix.
Let's say you're angry at somebody.
You can't seem to get off it.
You just smile.
Say, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
And now you'll feel better.
Yep.
Works great.
Thank you so much.
I'm glad you brought it up because I tend to forget mentioning it.
My mistake.
Go ahead.
Hi.
You mentioned depression.
And that you gave up sugar and things.
And that's when my friend elbowed me.
And I have been diagnosed with depression.
I do.
And that took a long time to admit that and to have a crisis that it actually,
I got medication for it.
So I am on medication.
I don't particularly want to give up sugar.
You are hereby ordered to surrender your willfulness, choose the purity of God's help as your reality.
Do you do so?
Yes.
Yes, I do.
The only problem is you got to go withdraw from the sugar.
But do it after Christmas.
Do it after Christmas.
I'm very scrupulous.
If you tell me to do it, I will do it tonight.
I'll tell you things you shouldn't do.
But any words you can use instead of sugar, that works.
Ok.
Have peanut butter for dessert.
Peanut butter, peanut butter and crackers, you'll find that it knocks out the desire
for sweets.
It does.
It works.
What's the other thing that I used to do?
Peanut butter and, oh, pickles.
Pickles.
Yes.
Pickles, well for some reason you feel like you got to have something sweet.
And what are they?
Sweet and sour pickles, is that the one?
Bread and butter.
Ah, yeah.
Bread and butter kind of pickles.
Oh, bread and butter pickles.
and you'll find it works
and it works
it works for pregnancy too
so this doesn't include
like giving up bread
and that kind of stuff
no that's more severe
I did that one year and it was really difficult
yeah that's more severe
you give up all white starch
if you're trying to get off sugar and sweets
if you can avoid white starch on an empty stomach
that's advisable
in other words anything that releases
insulin
your blood sugar is going to go up like this
and then you eat sugar and sweets
your blood sugar goes up
then you pour out insulin
now the blood sugar skyrockets it down
normal people let's say their blood sugar
starts at 95 they eat something sweet
goes up to 114
slowly comes back down to 95
people like yourself
they eat sugar and sweets suddenly it shoots up to 160
then it rockets down the insulin pours out
it goes down to 90
85 by 85 you've got the shakes
and you're psychotic
and thinking about suicide
and we used to do serial electro EEGs
you know I had a big clinic
we would do a five hour glucose tolerance test
they'd take a big dose of sugar
you know
and then we would do an electroencephalogram
periodically every half hour or so
for six hours
and chart the blood sugar
and as it came down
you'd see the EEG
go right into dysfunction
at one time we had a lady
I had a little job
that told the group once before
that her blood sugar skyrocketed down
in the meantime the medical profession
is boo-pooing this
anyway so
as it came down
she got more and more psychotic
and her EEG became very desynchronized
and when her blood sugar got down to about 70
she tore all her clothes off
and ran down the street
and man has it
the traffic was pulled over to the curb
on all sides
and the lab director was about 6 foot 4
like Ichabod Crane
big tall skinny guy with a long white coat
and he's running down the sidewalk after her
come back Ms. Connors
and she's running naked down the street
and the traffic is all piled up
and people are telling me they don't believe
in hypoglycemia
and I say yeah right
so I have been tested before a long time ago
but not for five hours
but they didn't come up with anything
so while I'm doing this
I should stay on my medication
it's empirical
just cut out sugar and sweets
and see if it doesn't help the need
depression
sometimes that's all that's necessary sometimes
yeah but she should stay on her medication
I should stay on my medication
yeah I would stay on my medication
you can try tapering that later
but first try and get hold of the dietary aggravation
it's no problem
no it's no problem
get lots of peanut butter and pickles
okay
and do what I say
and stop being rebellious
all right
then you can have your toys back again
I'm putting it where her teddy bear and her scooter
so she can be complies
is this your water
water water
whose water is this
someone forgot it
yeah there you go
someone forgot their water
okay
here
yes
hello
the last time I was here
was a year ago October
and you had bagpipes playing
and they played Amazing Grace
and we all experienced 535 energy
which was wonderful
we did it Sunday at St. Andrews this week
oh did you do that
last week yeah
my brother has arranged
an Amazing Grace for four part acapella
and we did it with male voices
and it sounded just wonderful
and I'd like to give the two of you
that version
oh Amazing Grace yeah thank you
and just a warning
I was part of singing this
and just hearing it the first time
brought me to tears
it was just so wonderful beautiful
oh thank you
I want to say thank you very much
for all of your teachings
thank you so much
and the question I have is
you taught about hypoglycemia
and then had to stop teaching about hypoglycemia
because it came back for you I believe
and
yes I gave it up you know see
and then I was giving lectures on hypoglycemia
well that re-established it as a reality
operative reality
and then I had
to change my course
because I was
psyching myself back into it myself
because the average person
is subject to it
but a person more advanced in consciousness
will begin to cancel it out
but if you keep reaffirming it
as an existing reality
you'll begin to experience it out again
okay
you had to quit it
I've done 12 step groups
and that was my first foray into personal growth
and then I did a personal growth workshop
which was really
the next step for me
and helped me an awful lot
and then I came to your teachings
and that's the third step for me
and I'm in the process of learning how to teach
the personal growth course
and I'm wondering because it's
a bit different than your teaching
and your teaching is of course higher level than that
by teaching that
would it have some sort of impact in
my work in working with this information
I don't know
I don't see why it should
okay
truth is the truth no matter what
exactly
thank you very much
can I get a picture with my wife and my mother and father with you
sure
that would be wonderful
they're all here
yeah they're all here
mom and dad can you come up
oh
I need your arm quick
what I'm holding on my calvary is over 200
personal growth is over 300
it's 350, 360
okay
personal growth is not going to change
I think I'll grade as high as the course of miracles or AA
are y'all in there
here we go
and five
I get that it's great for positive attitude
enthusiasm
benevolence
thank you
happy
working on about ten to four
and the line is still quite long
yeah okay we'll move along
I just wanted to say thank you so much
and how much I love you
and appreciate everything you've done
thank you
thank you very much
door number one or door number two
or door number three
good to meet you
thank you
doctor is good to meet you
Susan good to meet you
your work is fabulous
I just started into it recently
since my divorce two years ago
I seem to have difficulty
attracting a woman into my life
from a romantic heart to heart standpoint
give it up
now he's still got a negative camera left
go ahead yeah
so what's the story about it
well that's probably the answer right there
She said that's probably the answer right there.
Surrender. Oh, he comes celibate.
How can you tell me that?
I'm telling him, not me.
So what is the problem about it?
Oh, kidding aside, what is the problem about it?
It seems to be paradoxical intent.
It seems what?
Paradoxical.
Paradoxical intent.
Intent.
How is it paradoxical?
If I'm interested in the gal, she's not interested in me.
Or if she's interested in me, then it doesn't work for my end.
It's a one-way relationship?
Right.
Well, it'll agonize its way out.
You know, the right one doesn't come along every day.
Stay in circulation.
When it does.
Stay in circulation, that's my advice.
Yeah.
Okay, hooked up on one frustration.
Makes sense.
Thanks, appreciate it.
Yes, you appreciate the right one.
It does come along.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Now, all you ladies out there that are single.
He's a neat-looking specimen, too.
Call me Mark and Ansel.
This time, I thought I'd reverse the process.
Since I wrote this book, I decided to autograph it and present it to you for Christmas.
It's about the Cajuns, my people in South Louisiana.
The healers, the traitors.
My grandfather was a traitor.
And I spent about 10 years researching the book and throwing it away and writing it again.
And finally, it was published about eight years ago.
So, I want to read the autograph to you.
It's okay.
It says, to Dr. David Hawkins and all his miracles, Cajun miracles included.
Thank you very much.
Speak a little bit of Cajun for us.
Vous parlez français, Dr. Hawkins?
Vous parlez pas français?
You don't speak French.
No.
I'll have mine with toast on the side.
With toast.
And I don't have a question, but I do have a witness.
For the previous speaker, you know, like you said, you get into this spiritual path and look out and things might happen in your family, in your marriage and things.
I was married to a woman after five years.
We had a great relationship.
Everything was fine.
We studied with you for the last three or four years.
And then about eight weeks ago, she said,
She had a paradigm change.
Our marriage ended, and our separation and divorce, and living by myself in a little cabin in a Cajun country now.
And there's a lot of freedom to that.
There's a lot of freedom to that, living by yourself.
You said I could choose to suffer, or I could choose freedom.
I mean, your book says that so much.
Enjoy the freedom, yeah.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Okay, we got another one here.
Thank you.
We're raffling them off.
A dollar a raffle.
Another one.
Thank you.
Can I hold that down?
Got it.
Uh-oh.
No, it didn't go.
Here we go.
Again.
Oh, beautiful.
You got it.
Yeah.
Bye.
Hello.
Bless you so much.
Yes.
God bless both of you.
From all my...
From the depth of my heart.
Thank you.
I don't have a question.
You answered so many questions already, but a friend asked me to ask you, would that be
okay?
A friend asked me?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
Well, this friend of mine is Reverend Jack Blackman.
He's a religious science minister in Albuquerque, and he's been having some experiences where
he starts seeing the presence of God in other people.
And he gets a little overwhelmed, well, a lot overwhelmed sometimes, and he wondered
if he would stop being overwhelmed, or if it would progress in a certain way, or what
would...
It can't be answered, but that is a certain state of consciousness.
I was in it myself one time when I was a little girl.
You see, the divinity of all, everything shines forth, including its perfection and its beauty,
and you often start to cry quite a bit for a couple of years.
He does.
He does cry.
Yeah.
In the last few years.
It's perfectly fine.
It's perfectly okay.
Okay.
Thank you so much.
Yeah.
I used to have it in airports.
I'd see the people look at each other, and I'd start to cry.
Yes.
Hi.
Dr. Hawkins, the community of your students who are gathering here in Sedona to live,
does this serve a group purpose or another purpose?
What did she say?
The people that are gathering here, where we live, does that serve a group purpose?
Yeah.
I think they're just attracted to each other, you know, because of commonality of goal,
you know, having a commonality of goal, and they naturally form their own,
they form a spiritual community is what they do, you know.
Yeah.
That's common throughout history.
Spiritual groups tend to congregate in certain places, and often from there,
it then spreads forth again back into the world again.
Thank you.
Could I get a picture with you?
Can't you get a picture?
Yes.
Of course.
Oh.
There's Susan.
There she is.
No.
Oh, the on switch.
Oh.
We're more non-linear.
Non-linear.
Women are more non-linear, right?
Yeah.
So that's not something that had been done in time but.
And you're seeing the
Can you see the printing?
I can't see anything.
Yeah, that's right.
Hello.
Dr. Hawkins.
I want to thank you and Susan and your staff for all the fine work that you do.
Very appreciative of it.
Question I have is you mentioned again today that we as a group swoop in
and leave together.
Yep.
And I know you mentioned that in Dayton, I think, a couple of years ago.
So that means then what?
We're all going to do, complete our work in unison that we need to do?
That means we have a saree and then we both do that.
A loose affiliation of camarade, of commonality, of intention
that tends to bring us in and out collectively, yeah.
Okay.
Like ice ages, et cetera, tend to favor, you know,
all the blackbirds coming at a certain time,
and now it's not going to be favorable for blackbirds
for another couple hundred years, you know,
so they tend to flock in when times are propitious.
Maybe to uphold the level of consciousness of mankind
under difficult times.
Hmm, I didn't think of that.
It could be so that a group like this is here now
to help uphold mankind under difficult and trying times.
It's just, aha, aha.
Purpose.
Oh, wow.
When things are rosy and swell, they don't need us here,
so we go back and rest on the other side.
That's right.
We're the cheer-up squad.
So that means we have some additional work
to do.
I do, yeah, that sounds like it.
Okay, all right.
Thank you very much.
I think perhaps a sustaining function
so as to prevent human despair worldwide, yes.
I think to offset human despair worldwide, yes,
because cataclysmic events could bring about
pretty widespread despair.
But, yeah, you've mentioned, I know, in the past
that with the end times sort of things,
that that relates to the lower ground.
No, no.
Those are all the prophecies.
So?
Yeah.
Okay.
Now, this has nothing to do with prophecies.
It has to do with the unfoldment of the potential of humankind.
And the higher power uses anything in its own service.
Well, it's willing to sacrifice the small self
for the sake of the large self, or the capital S.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Man's calamity is God's opportunity, yes?
How many people turn to God as a result of Katrina?
Because you've got nothing left.
But God, sometimes that's what it takes to find God.
This question is about my son's allergy to nuts and eggs.
And this is my first lecture,
and I realize there could be a miracle
that he won't be allergic anymore.
But will following the recommended diet here
increase his health
and strengthen his body against allergic reaction?
Yes.
What is it you want to know?
Could you test it to see if following this diet will help?
I don't think it could do that.
You can't calibrate?
The book, even?
That's not relevant,
because I'm talking about a spiritual calibration.
It's not a spiritual problem.
Wouldn't it be true or not true?
What is his problem, again?
He's allergic to nuts and eggs.
That's physical allergy to nuts and eggs.
So what has it got to do with consciousness and God?
Well, I realize that.
But in my world right now, I want my son to be healthy.
Yes.
So is this a good diet for him to strengthen his body?
Oh, I see she's asking a general question.
Except he can't eat the nuts.
That's an X recommended in the diet.
I know, but it's a blood-type diet.
So following the...
Yeah, but this isn't a good book, then, if he can't even do that.
Well...
You want to know if this book's going to...
It is.
Wait a minute.
Let's get straight.
You want to know if this diet is going to help him?
Yes.
Well, for God's sake, woman, just put him on it,
and he'll either get better or he won't.
What do you mean?
No, well, I want to know if I'm on the right track.
I...
You're going around...
Well, I don't...
Try to be linear in your thinking.
I don't want to spend time explaining the book,
but supposedly certain blood types react differently to certain foods.
I don't want to listen to all that stuff.
They tell you that the blood...
What to do to get better.
Just do it.
Take him off the eggs and nuts.
Yeah.
Well, there's another philosophy to that in a certain calibration of people.
Do you want him well, or do you want him sick?
Yeah, no, he is well.
I know he is.
He is well, so I don't get what your question is.
Okay, if he eats nuts, you know, he needs...
Epinephrine, right?
Because he's swallowed up.
All right, so he should not eat nuts.
That's simple enough.
Correct.
What's the problem now?
There is a philosophy in this book...
No, it's not good.
Just forget it.
He's allergic to nuts.
He's allergic to eggs.
Deal with it.
He'll maybe outgrow it if he's young enough.
Yeah.
Okay.
See, I don't believe that.
All right, then we can't help you.
Okay.
This is all BS resistance.
This book is BS.
No way.
I'm totally...
I totally believe it.
I can't...
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
I'm not leaving.
You're just going blah, blah, blah.
You're not even talking sense.
I really think that this book...
You're not making any sense.
This book isn't about avoiding nuts.
It's not just for people with an egg allergy.
What do you want to know about the book?
I don't get the book.
I want to know if it's...
Okay, say for someone that doesn't have a nut or egg allergy.
Is this a good...
That's a hypothetical question.
I cannot answer it.
Okay.
I don't get it.
Is it a good book for me then to follow?
I don't have any allergies.
Is it a good book to keep?
Well, what would you want to follow?
A non-allergy book if you don't have any allergies?
It's not a nut allergy book.
I can't answer your question.
You're not asking a sensible question.
Okay.
It's not answerable the way you're presenting it.
Could I ask one more question?
No.
Yeah, talk to Colin Vaughn.
He knows all about it.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'll be there.
You can go there.
Well, thank you.
Yeah.
Okay.
Oh, that's you.
🎵
Okay.
It's just too complicated that decipher and entangle in front of the audience.
Well, thank you, Susan.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins, for all your work.
It really helped me a lot.
My question today is about karma.
Today you spoke about how actions and facilitators get results.
we take may have positive or negative karma and it's actually regarding the
Bhagavad Gita where Krishna talks to Arjuna and he says that you have to
fight and you have to kill your enemies and Arjuna is actually in a he feels
sad for his but then Krishna tells him that it's his duty yes could you maybe
explain more about that why is the duty to kill I don't agree with it you don't
agree with Krishna I don't agree with that battle scene I never have pretty
high from the viewpoint of Christianity how would you interpret it I'm sure I
don't know huh now shall not kill is one of the commandments is it not yes so now
you're saying under what conditions is it okay to kill it's okay to kill if God
tells me to kill
how do you explain that?
how do you know it was God that told you to kill there's a whole crowd of people on the
other side of the planet think God told them to kill I don't pay attention to
that but then it's an unfortunate chapter I never cared for it there's
much truth in the Bhagavad Gita but not that particular one but it's also
calibrated at 900 I think you calibrated pretty high not that chapter oh but but
it's in the Bhagavad Gita all about the battle scene what is the battle scene
got to do with your life?
you're just giving me an academic question well it's like nothing to do
with your life what does it mean to you it's about asking me the question it's
about you're not on the battlefield you're not belonging to either side so
why are you asking me the question it's about doing a duty what is my duty about
my life it would depend on what your level of consciousness is at one level
of consciousness your duty would be to take up arms and fight for what you
think is right in another level of consciousness it would be your duty to
not participate
so it would depend on what your level of consciousness so my objection to that
chapter is is that what level of consciousness are you talking to see
what's correct at this level to back off from your duty to be brave to stand to
stand for what is right etc at another level would be wrong then at another
level it becomes right again so the context changes with the level of
consciousness another level of consciousness is idiotic the whole story
take my word for it's idiotic
got it
ok thank you very much you have your blessings
i'm glad glad that it confused you it's a good sign
everybody reads the Bhagavad Gita if that doesn't bother you the whole
battlesin and you wonder what the hell's it talking about
it's not very serious seriously yeah because there is no actual personal self
doing that so there are various levels you can interpret that there is no
personal
self-killing enemy that's all in your mind it's okay it is a miracle to be in your presence
dr hawkins yeah i want to thank you for being my teacher thank you my pleasure thank you too
yeah the first chapter of the bhagavad-gita boggles everybody's mind what in hell they're
talking about everybody says hello dr hawkins yeah thank you for all that you give us
thank you um i'd like to ask for your blessings on my life you have it thank you and um i'm on
the precipice of a very large life-changing decision and i would just like to ask is it
truly in the highest and greatest good to end my marriage highest good to what and your marriage
and my marriage i don't know if i'm allowed to ask it yeah i'm not allowed to ask it or just
no
because i'm robbing you of the karmic significance and impact and earning earning about it
some things i can't all i very often personal things i gotta know because it interferes with
the person's karma if i'm feeling say 99 complete i should probably go with that feeling
and trust my inner the problem is one of doubt huh i'm talking about a relationship there is
no certainty in a relationship because it's whatever the two of you make it to be
you can start out awful and get fantastic or you can start out fantastic and get awful you know so
uh it's a whole training program so learn my lessons it's a whole it's you know
it helps mature people i think relationship like that because when you're married now you're up
against it for real you've got to really make peace or you're really going to have war and you
can't just play around with it you've got to really face it and do what you can and you can
be centered in love and part lovingly if that serves the highest part lovingly no not always
yeah thank you it's a big casino in this world isn't it yes yeah roll the dice you take the
chances big casino okay thank you bless you yeah it has big lessons though too big benefits thank you
big upset
and big downside risk yes um i don't have a question i just wanted to be in your presence
thank you thank you very much uh-huh gives me herself as a gift huh yeah yeah
here's one of the mad elves
you can tell by the mad look in his eye
actually all questions uh basically well they did dissolve on the way up here but i didn't want to
i missed aodeshia's vision Wow
the opportunity to say thanks and uh it influenced this life greatly and uh my privilege and a
beautiful group here in sedona i've had the privilege of living here for a short time
and a very inspiring amazing group all the way around and uh yeah i once uh you kind of
influenced me when i lived in flagstaff i got a job for the catholic church cleaning the priest
and a Newman Center, and this shirt right here
was hanging on the wall, and I immediately thought of you
when I saw it.
I love God.
But actually, the students, the Catholic students at NAU
wear this, it's one of their shirts.
But yeah, I was like, that's Dr. Hawkins.
As I always said, the greatest job on the planet
is being a verger in a Greek cathedral,
so to be the verger at Church Cathedral,
you have to be careful not to keep saying that again.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
To serve God.
Yes?
I just want to say thank you.
I do not have a question,
and I just love being in the presence of both of you.
Oh.
And I also came across this CD,
which...
It's a tenor, and the sound, music,
just transcends and transports,
and I'd like for the two of you to have that.
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
You know we love music.
Yes.
Thank you so much.
And then to ask if I can have a picture
with my brother and the two of you.
Sure.
Thank you.
Which reminds me, the second edition
of Celtic Woman is out now.
Hey, Doc.
I was out of focus, I'm sorry.
Robert, you're better at this.
Thank you.
You need somebody with a more linear mind to do this.
Are you happy?
I should talk.
So, Dr. Hawkins, you've given us a lot to contemplate,
and when you were in Long Beach, I asked you the same question.
I think you blew my circuits, and I couldn't remember.
And I couldn't remember what you said.
And I haven't received your DVD yet.
So my question is, can you expand on contemplation
and how to use it?
Contemplation?
Contemplation, yeah.
Contemplation is a lifestyle where you identify
with context instead of content.
It's your life becomes like a mudra.
Your life becomes invitational to God's revelation.
Instead of yang, like, I must get that,
and you've already defined in a linear design what it is you want.
A contemplative lifestyle is more accepting.
It's more yin.
It's more like, reveal to me, O Lord, that which...
So it's more thus.
Excellent.
It's a way of being in the world
in which you notice the beauty and perfection of everything.
You notice the beauty and perfection of everything.
The beauty and perfection of all that exists.
Great, thank you.
It's beautiful.
I forget the miracle of the rattlesnake
on the top of Shinnebly Hill.
Yes, hi.
Hi.
Let's see if I can put this into words.
I was reading your latest book.
I got towards the end of it where you were talking about
the final doorway and that type of thing.
The thought that came into my head wasn't so much about that,
but it was the idea that any separate, independent thought
was the separation that holds back the progress.
Can you...
It doesn't really hold it.
It doesn't necessarily hold it back.
It would just be reflective of where you're at with it.
It doesn't necessarily hold you back.
Doesn't necessarily stop it.
No.
It was an interesting thought that it was the,
I can't think of a good word,
the belligerence that separates
by having an independent thought from God himself.
Well, it's an illusion that it's an independent thought.
If you get over that, then you don't have a problem.
Yeah, of course.
It's a thought, but it's not your thought.
It's yours.
That's true.
If it's not yours, why worry about it?
Yes.
You're a free man.
You're not shackled to the thought, you know.
It's not you.
It's not me.
That's true.
It's a passing bird in the sky.
Yeah.
Thank you so much.
Passing bird.
Thank you.
You bet.
Oh, yes.
I didn't know.
Yes.
Uh-huh.
I didn't tell them the rattlesnake miracle.
I'll tell them sometime.
Yes.
Hi.
You look great.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I have a question about the alcoholic.
A couple questions, and it's probably-
About the what?
The alcoholic.
Oh, yes.
Yeah.
Okay.
In general.
And it's probably non-linear.
In fact, it's very non-linear.
Just sit here.
Okay.
Very non-linear.
So, you said that guilt is one of the locks to the miraculous, and it's self-indulgence.
Any attachments, yeah.
Right.
And also, in one of your early lectures, I remember you saying when someone says they
can't do something because they won't, and they won't do it because it's too much effort-
I'm not hearing what you're saying.
That someone won't do something because they can't-
They can't do it because they won't.
Oh, yes.
Right.
It isn't that they can't.
It's just that they won't.
Right.
Because it says too much effort, because they're holding something back, and-
Willingness, yeah.
Okay.
And so, my question is, I do healing work, and one of my clients, her mother, was a really
bad alcoholic.
Yeah, back off.
Just a hair.
Okay.
Because he can't hear you when you-
Willingness.
It has to do with willingness, right?
Okay.
Yeah.
So, what I'm trying to understand is, the alcoholic who drinks, and the next morning,
they're very angry and enraged, and there's some that'll drink, and there's some that'll
drink, and they don't get angry.
And so, what I'm trying to understand, what makes one alcoholic really angry and furious
after they drink the night before?
And they're very abusive to their children, like, I hate you, you ruined my life, and
all those negative things.
So, what makes one alcoholic angry the next day, and one not?
Well, that's a very general question.
It would depend on their level of consciousness, and their emotional condition, and their relationship.
It's a-
Yeah.
I can't answer a question on that level.
Okay.
Because in one of your earlier videos, one of the very first ones-
It's not due to the alcohol, it's due to who the person is.
That's what I'm trying to understand.
In one of your earlier, very first videos that I had watched, you had explained something
about it, but it was so long ago, I didn't remember, and I thought, maybe-
We have, in our A-B series, which is archival, we have a whole CD devoted to alcoholism.
I don't know.
Okay.
Oh, yeah.
So, if you wanted to add, that is something you probably should get.
Okay.
I think it's 19-something.
But it's a whole CD, and it's devoted to alcoholism.
And then all my questions will probably-
A good majority of them will be answered in that CD.
Okay, great.
Okay.
Thank you.
It's a puzzler.
Yeah.
I think that's all the time we have.
Thank you.
Thank you for sharing your story.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you.
Okay.
Yes. Okay. Thank you very much.
And you're welcome.
I'm not trying to push it, but I think that that would answer a lot of your questions.
It would, definitely. Right. Because, like I said, one of his earlier,
it was one of the very first ones I ever watched.
He explained the difference between someone who gets angry after they drink
and someone who doesn't. And I just couldn't remember.
There were so many CDs of him.
If you look at that CD, that's a very good one on that.
On the alcohol. Okay, thanks.
He's devoted strictly to that. It's about an hour and 20 minutes or so.
That's great. Okay, thanks. Thank you.
I left my magnifying glass. I guess they took it in the bag.
Oh, I took it. I put it in your bag.
Oh, that's okay. All right.
Hi. Hi.
Something here for a minute.
My question is about karma.
Many years ago, I was in an abusive marriage and had a child.
And he got involved in drugs.
And so, I left when my daughter was five, came to America.
She's just about to turn 32. And I might cry in a minute.
I'm going to.
She, I raised her spiritually with the same teachings that you have.
And she's always followed that.
Last year, she had a friend who was...
into drugs.
And she decided that she would need to try the drug
so that she could help him get through it.
And has been addicted to meth for the last 18 months.
Because I brought her out of that relationship,
was she, did she need that experience karmically?
And by me taking her out of it,
she's managed to find...
almost...
almost the same situation and duplicate it.
It could be the lesson wasn't learned.
It has to be repeated until it's learned, yes.
Now, with her being...
That's why the first step in Al-Anon
is to let go and to control the other person.
Say, let go and to save them and control them.
You're just depriving them of a karmic opportunity.
And they're just going to have to go keep doing it.
Well, the thing that complicates it with her is because she still has the same...
spiritual understandings.
She...
I gave her your consciousness and addiction CDs.
Mm-hmm.
Um...
She's not ready for them?
She's...
She knows them off by heart.
She's not ready for them?
She...
She quotes them every day.
She knows exactly what it is.
So what's the question?
Um...
What else can she do is what she wants to save in China?
She didn't answer.
She didn't answer the question.
It's...
I don't know what to do at this point with her.
Don't.
Do me a favor.
Join Al-Anon.
Take step one.
Thank you.
Me?
Me take it?
Al-Anon is for...
Al-Anon is for, like, children and alcoholics, um...
Wives, spouses, family members.
Spouses, family members that have a problem.
You need to join Al-Anon and follow the program.
Especially step one.
Okay?
Can I just ask one more thing about it?
Yeah.
Is this karma...
Is she healing old karma at this point?
Or...
You're asking an academic question.
It's irrelevant.
Go to S...
Go to Al-Anon and take step one.
Let her worry about her karma.
Don't you worry about it.
And just let it go.
You've got to worry about her karma.
Let her worry about her karma.
The hardest thing for parents to do is stand by and watch your children understand.
You know, because you're taking on that which is beyond you and not controllable by you
anyway.
So I should just let her get on with it and, and back out of it?
Go to Al-Anon and take step one.
Repeat back to me.
Don't talk to me again until you do that.
You have to report back to this group that you went to Al-Anon and took step one.
Okay.
You make a promise?
I will make a promise.
Go to your sweetheart.
It's hard to let go of controlling her, see?
Yeah.
It's hard to let go.
It is.
But you'll free her that way.
Okay.
Thank you.
Sometimes you hit the bottom quicker and harder.
Get it over with.
Yeah.
Okay.
You're just helping them limp along.
Yeah.
I asked you a while ago about defenselessness and-
About what?
Defenselessness?
Yeah.
From the course.
And after that, for about three days I felt nothing but love.
And then fears kind of came back and it went away.
So, I want to know what to do.
I'd like to have it come back.
She wants to know what to do about what?
I don't really know.
So, I'm going to tell her that.
She wants to know what to do about what?
I don't know.
I don't know what to do.
do? I'd like to come back. She wants to know what to do about what? She wants that. Oh. I felt nothing but love. I've never experienced that before. I felt nothing but love for three days. I had no anxiety. Oh yes. I don't think anything. You see all spiritual evolution tends to be evanescent. Rarely do you go into a certain state and stay there permanently. It begins to fluctuate. And just accept that that's par for the course.
That's why it's par for the course. And just keep. It's normal. Yeah, it's normal. You'll get states of bliss coming back and then states of discouragement and then moments of renewed enthusiasm. And that's normal. That's normal. I'd just like it to come back. It was wonderful. It was wonderful. If you would just let go wanting it to come back, you would give the space to recur. Don't you get it? It filled you to the brim.
Let go of it. Okay, I got it. Do what you tell you or else. I'm the Dutch uncle, the spiritual teacher, I'll tell you. Because it's more painless. Yes? I actually got up here without crying this time. Now you're going to cry. No.
The question that I have is about a very negative energy that came to me during the night. It's happened before. And I've always used your words that you said in the name of Jesus Christ.
Yeah, right, right. Yeah. And it's always been very effective. These episodes seem to happen after I'm in a very high state. And what I'm wondering is there something in me that's drawing this energy to me?
Oh, no, I just hate you because you're in a high state. Okay. It's envious. It was as if this last time that this energy came to me with a knowingness that I could choose this state. And there was in fact an attractiveness to the evil or whatever it was. There was an attractive to my ego recognized the attractiveness of it. But I... That's being called being beset by demons.
Yes.
Immediately, immediately rejected it and pushed, you know, rejected it.
Yeah, because they don't know any better. See, and they're trapped in their domain. They're trapped in their realm.
Yeah.
They're trapped in their realm. And they're unwilling to do what it takes to get out of that realm.
Therefore, all you can do is have compassion for them.
Okay.
I think the denial of the divinity of God is what keeps them there.
I don't resist. It's the denial of the divinity of God. And you can't force the entity because you will have robbed it of the right to leave hell.
It was hellish.
It was hell, yes.
And I saw, I could see that it was hell.
Those are the demons from hell, yeah.
Yeah.
Lower astral planes.
Yeah. I felt like I was almost visiting there. I don't know why, but it was during a dream or something. Or maybe it came to me. I wasn't sure. But when I woke, it woke me.
Yeah.
It was very intense.
And I found somebody else to bother.
Yeah. I did. And your words, your words helped me a great deal.
Yeah.
Thank you so much. I love you guys.
Yes.
I love this field.
Get the hell, hence demon, to your own domain. Accept Jesus Christ as your savior, and you will be free. It's his choice.
Hi, Doc.
Hi, Susan.
Could you say something for us about something you spoke about?
Something you've spoken about before, vertically aligned relationships?
Yes. Vertically, you see, the trouble with relationships is they tend to be horizontal. Solar plexus, interacting with solar plexus chakras. Control, control, control, control. Or seduction, seduction, seduction. Or right and wrong, better than you, you know, win, lose. All right. So that's the way, it's solar plexus, horizontal. Push, pull, control.
All right.
Relationship that's aligned like this is parallel. You're both aligned with the same ultimate goal. Therefore, you're always aligned no matter what you do. I hate you. I'm sorry I said that. Why did I say I'm hating you? You don't have to wonder if I forgive you. I understand, etc. See, they're both aligned to spiritual perfection, so they're willing to forgive anything. These people are going to carry a grudge. She got to choose what movie we're watching. Okay.
I get to stay up later to watch television later. See, it's record keeping and score keeping. So most relationships end up in squabble score keeping. Struggles over money and all those things. Control, in-laws. If you're both aligned in the same direction, you automatically find ways to heal that. I'm sorry I said that. I wasn't even thinking right. I don't know where my mind was at the time. And the other person is willing to forgive them because you're both aligned with forgiveness and growth.
And supporting each other's spiritual growth and development. You know, I'm interested in winning and losing. There's no winning and losing in a relationship. Because if you win, you're just lost. If you win, you're just lost. It's just a matter of getting even. All right, you had mashed pumpkin tonight. Wait till tomorrow, baby. You're getting fried squash. You know what I'm saying?
So any two people in a relationship who are committed to spiritual perfection.
Right. So a company can be very, very aligned and very, very powerful. And they're all aligned with each other.
Right.
Most companies are struggling for, you know, he wants to be vice president, he wants to be comptroller, and this one's jealous of that one, and he's got a corner office with two windows, and I only have the one window.
Yeah.
But if you can get any organization aligned like that, it's going to be successful.
Right. And so then any group of people or any two people are capable of a vertically aligned relationship, provided they have that commitment.
Any relationship is possible that way.
To serve each other's highest purpose.
This is another way of saying, you know, serve the highest good.
Thank you.
That gets you out of power struggles. Most people in a relationship get caught up in power struggles.
Yeah. So serving the highest good and serving each other's highest good is the way to get past that.
That makes you parallel.
So you're never crisscrossing each other. You may strain each other, be short-tempered or something, but that doesn't change your goal.
Your goal is not to be a short-tempered person. I mean, that's not your goal.
So it doesn't change your goal.
Right.
Temporary blip on the screen.
Yeah. So if you're both vertical, you're not going to change your goal.
Yeah.
Right.
Tell a story.
I once knew a lady who was in a relationship, and every time her husband and her had a fight, she'd take his toothbrush and clean the toilet bowl with it.
So whenever you have a fight with your husband, change toothbrushes.
Buy a new one.
That is a funny story.
Thank you, Susan. I knew there was a reason I came here today.
She is now suffering in hell. You didn't forget.
You better change yours when you get home.
I thank God for you two and for your work.
And I have a very simple question.
For whatever reason, I'm not able to muscle test reliably, and I don't personally know anyone who is able to do that.
Although I've heard of it.
I know a few professionals who use it.
I'm unable to muscle test their integrity.
How do I go about using that as a tool for truth in my life?
Can you do this?
Mm-mm.
I've tried it with the heavy books.
I've tried it with the two-person.
I've tried it with this thing.
Oh, I see. Yeah.
I've tried that.
Well, there's also karmic reasons sometimes.
Yeah.
And just maybe it's not the best thing.
Maybe you're not supposed to be using it right now or something.
I've wondered about that.
Yeah.
It could be a shame.
It's because you're going to short-circuit a greater spiritual understanding that you're trying to bypass by quick answers.
I've wondered about that.
I think that's the sense of it I'm getting.
That's the sense that I'm getting.
She's going to use it to bypass spiritual understandings.
Yeah.
Damn.
Back to the books.
Back to the books or something.
Thank you so much.
Yeah.
Wait, your books?
My books, thank you.
Yeah.
Whose book is that?
It's been there a while.
Okay.
Hello, Dr. Kockes.
Hello, Susan.
We came from cold, cold Canada.
Blowing wind, minus 30 just to be here.
Came from where?
Canada, minus 30.
Oh, yeah.
It's getting chilly.
I have no question.
I only wanted to say thank you for the continuous miraculous.
Uh-huh.
A million times a day, every corner I turn around, every minute of the day, looking in my daughter's eyes, in my pet's eyes, outside, in my clients, in the world, there is, I cannot say anymore because words are useless.
Just...
Thank you so much.
I have a question.
What's your favorite animal?
Oh, tough one.
Tough one?
I'm hoping you like horses.
I like horses and dinosaurs.
Unicorns are wonderful, and dinosaurs I'd love, and kitties, of course.
Because I drew you a picture of a horse and a dinosaur.
Oh, great.
Susan.
Oh, great artist.
Oh, lovely.
Thank you so much.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Monkeys, huh?
No, it's a dinosaur.
Oh, a dinosaur.
I see.
She's got a cute face.
I know that's a cute dinosaur.
It's a dinosaur with consciousness.
It's a cute dinosaur.
Aw.
Oopsie.
I brought something for Christmas.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you, ladies.
Whereabouts in Canada?
Kamloops.
It's only four hours away north from Vancouver.
Vancouver, yeah.
We were in Vancouver area this summer.
A couple months ago, yeah.
And it was beautiful.
Absolutely beautiful.
We fell in love with it.
Yes.
Oh, don't forget about it.
We did the Inland Passageway.
The Inland Passageway was stunning, stunning.
Stunning, stunning.
All the way up here.
Amazing, amazing.
God, miraculous.
Incredibly beautiful.
Continuous miraculous.
Thank you.
It was gorgeous.
It was incredibly beautiful.
Mystical.
Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
It's an honor to finally meet you.
And you as well, Susan.
Thank you.
Hey, good afternoon.
Good afternoon.
Thank you.
Well, can I ask a few questions?
So I know you believe in them.
And what you're telling me is about eternal radio waves,
am I in a position to believe that?
Well, I don't think I'm in a position in that direction.
But I definitely want to ask you a question.
Yes.
Can you tell me, can you tell me a little bit more about I
believe if I could type Glas Creature into
your brain?
And I'm going to try it.
OK.
it's going to come up by itself anyway because your intention is going to set
you know the instruction so when you try to be unconditionally loving you're
automatically attracting energy up to the heart chakra pranayama calibrates at
190 so there's a lot of yoga tricks that are actually injurious and you know I
would perhaps picture the ideal of what you would like so spiritual energy wise
what's the ideal for you at this moment what do you want it to do go where the
sensation I guess it's the physical sensation that there's a tangible
immediate spiritual effect or reward the buzzing in your fingertips you feel like
you've raised your body to a higher pitch a higher octet
you know in the moment that goes out this is the same thing if you show up
Is your body going to go to heaven?
No.
No, that's what I'm saying.
Naturally, the body will respond to it.
But the body is not going to become enlightened,
nor will it take you to heaven.
I would picture the energy more into energizing
that which you wish to become,
the heart and the universal heart, see?
Yeah.
I do as well.
You know, up to the third eye, if you wish.
You know, you picture the energy rising up to the third eye
to open the third eye of discernment,
which is really, you know, the third eye of the Buddhic body.
So I would not use any artificial means, no.
Because your intention is sufficient power.
The kundalini energy will flow up
based on your intention and your dedication.
I suppose where this stems from is
when I'm...
When I'm still, when I'm being,
I don't feel like I'm making progress spiritually.
I mean...
When you're not making progress?
But when I'm doing, then I'm not being,
if that makes sense.
I feel like I have to be proactive.
I have to have a dedicated routine,
a dedicated practice, you know,
and meditation, and those are...
Yes, well, dedication is...
Meditation is something you can do
until you get past the point of...
doingness.
It's what you have become.
What you have become doesn't need to meditate.
Thank you.
That which you are is all that is already.
No, you're well aligned.
Don't worry about that.
Just be patient, you know.
Allow yourself to be attracted
instead of trying to propel.
Allow yourself to be attracted by your destiny
instead of trying to propel yourself.
That makes sense.
Let go of resistance.
The immense gravity of divinity
is like pulling you,
and you allow yourself to let go of resisting it.
You don't have to propel yourself.
Can I get a hug?
You're moving fast enough.
You're going bald already from a lot of effort.
I get bald slower.
Hello.
All that effort, yeah.
I wanted to start off by saying
I'm from Lubbock, Texas,
my friend who has been coming here with me
asked me to tell you hi,
and he wishes he could be here.
Yeah.
So, okay.
My question is,
I have trouble discerning
whether I'm standing up for truth
or engaging in, like,
some sort of justified resentment ego juice.
Resentment?
Not so much, well,
not so much resentment, but frustration.
Well, it's more like you stand for
what you believe in.
That doesn't require you to do that.
It doesn't require aggression.
And I'll usually do that, like,
in the act of standing up for truth,
but then afterwards,
I start reliving it in my mind
and kind of reworking it over and over again.
Should have said something different,
should have done something different.
Well, you stand for what you understand
at the moment.
At other times, you may see it differently.
Mm-hmm.
Also, you've become a different person by then,
and you should take a different stance.
Yeah.
At one stance, it's wrong not to slay the enemy.
At another level,
that's why we were talking about the Bhagavad Gita.
Yeah, I'd never understood that either.
Yeah.
Should he slay the enemy,
or should he refuse?
Which is his highest principle?
Poor Lord, Juna.
Yeah.
So, at each level,
at each,
period of spiritual development,
you would have a different answer
of what's appropriate.
So, is it kind of whatever I go through
is appropriate unless I see it differently?
Well, no.
No.
Because you may see it in a certain way
for many years,
and then slowly or suddenly
you can change your mind about it all.
So, then I can just accept the way I handle it
the way it is?
That's the way it is,
you know,
because it's all transitory.
So, why worry about something
when it's already a was,
not an is?
Yeah.
All right, thank you.
It's already a was.
Give up regretting the wuzzies.
The wuzzies?
Well, it was that way,
and it was that the way I tell you.
Yeah.
Hi.
I had a couple of questions for you.
First, you guys talked about the
other people picking up karma for other folks,
and I was wondering if I could drop off a bunch of mine.
Yes, you could put them in the depository box.
The depository box.
Right on.
It would have a chute on it.
I'm wondering what I can do to get away from the desire
to ask you the right or the perfect question.
Ask me the perfect question?
Yeah.
You already asked me the perfect question once,
so why do you want to ask it again?
All right.
Well, thank you.
Perfect question.
Yeah, that's perfect.
Yeah.
We're satisfied with your question.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
We're doing good.
I know.
That's a treat.
Oh, thank you.
You'll see.
First.
You want me to sign this?
Yes, please.
Thank you.
Thank you for your presence here in this lifetime, both of you.
Thank you for all of us who can be here and not be here.
Yes.
I'm grateful.
And I'd like to know two things.
If you could give us an om, sing an om for us.
Om.
To bless me and those that I love for this new life that has started in part due to my
presence.
I don't hear anything you're saying now.
Okay.
I'd like you to bless me and those that I love.
We just got through doing that.
Oh, okay.
I missed it.
It was the om.
Oh.
Thank you.
Thank you both.
All right.
Thank you.
Okay.
Can I have a hug?
I see that.
What?
She wants a hug.
Oh, yeah.
I really am afraid to hug people.
All right.
Okay.
Yeah.
The doctor said no hugs.
Oh.
I have two things.
First off, Maria, the Mexican who's been coming here for many years, she asked me to say
hello from Canada where she's now living.
Oh, wow.
And Kamloops, actually.
And she wanted to know if you have written, have a book of poetry.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
That's right.
Oh, yeah.
She wants to have a book of poetry that you've written.
Nope.
No.
Because she reads your prose and she says, oh, you've gotta have a poetry
book.
Nope.
That's for sissies.
I'm realing then.
Oh, them poetry types.
Those guys don't go over poetry thing.
I played violin.
Isn't that good enough?
I'll ask her.
Yeah.
The other thing is, I've been re-reading Transcending the Levels, and what I've noticed
in reading the first, the lower levels, that I see in myself still, where there's times
when I say, I can't, and where I am still, those things, those aversions and those attractions
are there.
Yeah, of course.
You wrote the book, yeah.
For you.
Oh, good.
And so the thing that I saw for myself, because you go, oh my God, where am I?
And I said, okay, really, I'm witnessing and observing this, I just need to step back and
not be identified.
There, you got it.
With that, and just say, oh, there you go.
Yep.
Okay.
Good.
Thank you.
And just, I find, then, just something else that's been in my head was the whole, the
thing of surrender, like, I, all my life, I have felt a thing of surrendering, and I've,
there's been times when I just go out and I lay on the earth and just, you know, raise
my hands, like, and just, there's never been a feeling that it is enough, and I'm wonder,
um.
Is this enough?
It's enough.
Just to keep surrendering, and.
Yeah, that's enough.
Okay.
Otherwise, you start crawling on your knees all the way to the palace.
You know, you know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
Thank you.
You're doing well.
No problem.
Thank you.
Hello, Doctor.
I was led here just a little over a year ago to discover you and your work, and have
been coming to your seminars as the ones I could get into ever since.
Thank you.
dining in.
And reading your books, um, and re-reading them, as part of my daily practice, I guess,
is we're, virtually every day I read some of your, or re-read some of your work.
And it's been so powerful that, um, after about six months, and then about right around
my 60th birthday, I experienced what I felt was truly a rebirth.
A spiritual rebirth.
And uh, so I get, in a, in a sort of a reversal state.
Uh huh.
adoption, I guess I've discovered that you're my spiritual father, and with all the love
and honor and respect that that accords. And so I feel that I've really, through both your
efforts and the grace of God, I feel I've at least saved a few lifetimes of effort,
and made this one immeasurably more pleasurable, enjoyable. And so I thank you for that.
And I have two questions, a small one and a large one. The small one is, in a couple of your books,
as it was mentioned today, you mentioned the fact that beings are born with a
calibratable consciousness level. I suppose that entails, then, that we come into this world
with a calibratable consciousness level. And I suppose that entails, then, that we
come into this world with the consciousness level that we had when we left the last life.
That's the implication. But there's other inner fields where we could go in the meantime,
and you may have made the progress there, too.
Ah, I see. And the larger question that concerns me is that about a month or two after this,
what I call a rebirth, my wife went back into rehab, alcoholic rehab, for the fourth time.
And has been there five months. And after stage two, which is supposed to get into deeper issues,
she came back and failed immediately, and so went back. And by that time, I had the confidence in
your kinesiology approach that I, for the first time, used that method to explore the possible
underlying issues that would have caused that failure.
And discovered a sexual transgression at the age of three and a half. And what I'm bothered with is that
if with this, what I consider truth, because of what I've read, from a moral standpoint, am I morally
obligated to do anything with this truth, or to not do anything with this truth?
No.
No? Do nothing? I mean, I shouldn't make this...
I mean, I shouldn't make this so-called truth available to my wife, or...
I doubt it's going to be of any benefit. It's not going to be of any benefit.
If she's in psychoanalysis, that's something different. And the memory comes up, the repressed unconscious.
But to hear it from an external source, there's a principle in psychoanalysis, an interpretation made outside of the therapeutic relationship is always taken as an attack.
Ah.
Right?
And if she's laying on your couch paying you to interpret back, it'll be acceptable.
But as a spontaneous presentation from you, she'll probably give you some bad words about it.
And that would be true of the perpetrator as well?
Yeah, sure.
Sure. Okay. Thank you very much.
Yeah. Other forces are going to have to deal with that.
Hmm.
You, I think.
Yeah. That helps me a great deal. Thank you.
Thank you.
It's sort of a grave situation.
Yeah. And it's, you know, there's children involved in the suffering process.
Ah, yeah. I'll give you a...
That's what I was wondering, if there's something I should do.
I'm trying to say, keep as clear of it as you can.
Okay.
You can't reveal everything you know in this world. If I did, I wouldn't be here now.
You'd be put away as bad long ago.
Okay, yeah.
That's the other thing I enjoy. The spirituality with humor is just remarkable.
Thank you.
I think humor is a very great spiritual benefit. It allows you to accept things that you would never accept otherwise.
Yeah.
You can detach and accept it. Yes?
I just want to take a picture, if I could, of you and Susan.
Yes. Yeah.
One, two, three, two. Thank you very much.
You bet.
Okay.
Yeah. We're done?
One more question.
That's it.
Here is the end.
Yeah.
We have five minutes.
Thank you so much, David and Susan.
This is a little, I feel almost selfish asking a question, but along my travels, I'm part Native American,
and in the sweat ceremony in this one place we've been going from time to time, year to year,
we dipped into a spring beside us.
It's an ancient ground by the people in Canada.
And this one time that I still am looking for an explanation of what happened, it was as if my consciousness,
when I dipped in the water, my consciousness left my body, and I was as if suspended in the clouds,
and it brought a sense of panic at first.
Then I asked my wife, am I still alive?
Is my heart beating?
She said, yes.
And so I just laid back and spent, I don't know how long, drifting in what appeared as clouds, very peaceful.
And then calmly came back, and we went on our way, actually went back in the sweat again.
So my question is, what happens when these kind of things happen?
Well, you know, you could say it's generally out of body experience.
Because you went to a different location, correct?
Yes.
Yes, it's a vital location.
So it's an out-of-body experience, and it sounds like a rather pleasant and beautiful one, yes?
Mm-hmm.
And the world around seems to change as a consequence.
Actually, it's you that's changed, you know?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, that's a lovely experience.
Great, great.
That's it.
I mean, it's a fine experience.
Thank you for the beautiful day.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Great question.
That was a great one.
Yeah, it was.
There was one miracle I forgot to mention, and he just brought it up, actually.
I was on the top of Schnebly Hill when I first came out west here.
There was a place there for sale, the top of Schnebly Hill.
And 90 acres for sale, and I think there was a lake and all, and some buildings.
Anyway, I looked at it several times.
And one night I had a dream of stepping over a serpent.
That was several months prior.
Anyway, I was on top of Schnebly Hill, and I'm looking through these buildings, and there's
nobody up there.
I mean, it's 90 acres of nobody, and just a couple of buildings.
And as I stepped over a step, there was a huge rattlesnake.
I mean, a great big rattlesnake.
And he's pulled back, and he's ready to strike.
In that instant, I surrendered to God, like in an instant.
In a state of profound peace, the state of peace is enormously powerful, enormously soft,
and enormously powerful.
Time stopped.
The snake was totally suspended by the energy, and I was suspended.
We were both outside of time.
In clock time, we looked at each other.
I'd never seen a rattlesnake before.
And he'd never seen a human being.
So we looked into each other's souls and felt completely safe with each other.
It's because we were both suspended by this infinite power of peace, prevailing peace.
This lasted for minutes.
Minutes, two of us suspended in time in complete and utter safety with each other.
And I was taking in the beingness of the snake,
and he was taking in the beingness of this human.
He'd never seen a human before.
And this went on for a considerable length of time,
this enormous state of peace and safety, absolute safety.
And then the snake was satisfied, and he went away and shook his little tail as he went away.
And it was like he had the camera on stop, and then somebody pushed the start button,
and then life sort of started again.
Yeah, that was an interesting experience.
I had to recalibrate it.
Let me see.
The field that surrounded us was over 600, 700, 610.
It was exactly 600.
Okay, so it's like when I was sitting on the rock one time.
Yes.
The state of 600.
Anyway, that was a very interesting experience
because we're just corroborating the experiential reality of the miraculous.
And if we all started joining in experiences now and did a workshop on it,
we would recall all kinds of events that when you realized what it was,
it was actually the miraculous.
Anyway, the snake didn't change his mind, and neither did I,
so that's why we both lived to tell the tale.
I also saw that an instant of fear, one instant of fear would have cost me my life.
He was struck just like that.
He would have sensed one flicker of fear.
And so the presence of God prevailed as the infinite peace.
So the dream that I had now was fulfilled.
Here I am stepping over the serpent just like it happened in the dream.
I don't believe in prophetic dreams in general.
I think that's the only one that ever came near by that.
So anyway, it's been a wonderful day.
Here it is, Christmas almost.
And therefore,
I give thanks, O Lord,
for these thy gifts,
for these thy gifts that sit before me.
What more greater gift could a teacher have than such wondrous students?
God bless you all.
And thank you for your presence because you're God's gift to me.
So I wish you Merry Christmas,
and I accept your presence as your gift to me.
And I feel well loved by you all.
Amen.
Thank you for being here today.
We'll get together for a satsang next time.
The blessing of Almighty God be on you now,
now and forever.
Amen.
My blessing goes with you.
Until next time.
Thank you so much for being here.
Be careful not to trip on this.
Okay, yes.
All right.
They're not...
They can't get off.
They're like the serpent under the energy field.
You see?
You see, they cannot move.
You see them?
They cannot move.
The same energy field that held the serpent holds all of you right now.
How are we going to get loose?
.
with us. The Christ child is within the heart of all of us. Christmas is the rebirth of the
Christ child within each one of us. God bless you. Let's get your mic off. Let's take you
electronically off. Okay. Isn't that adorable? Look at this. Thank you so much. You can take
my microphone off. This bear was the finisher. If my child wasn't up before, it was up now.
Right after the child and me, I'll tell you. Everything's lit up at Christmas time. We have
Christmas lights all around everything. All the little buildings are lit up, you know,
sort of fun. What do we got here? What's this green thing? We've got quite a few praying
mantises in the greenhouse right now. We've got some big praying mantises in the greenhouse.
I thought it was a leaf and I was going to brush it off. It's a great big praying mantis.
As big as they get. She looks like this, you know. I scared her. It's all right.