the big ones in the rear so they don't block traffic. Are we going this way? I guess we are.
Follow me. Okay. Hello, hello. We can do both sides at once
maybe, yeah? We can do both sides at once, yeah?
Good morning. Don't miss anybody?
Have a hand or else pay a dollar.
Hi. How's it going?
Hi. Hi.
That was Daniel Lyons. You remember the guy with the graph?
Which one is Daniel? Daniel Lyons.
Yeah, we're showing his graph this morning.
Oh, really? I met you. Why didn't you say that?
Oh, boy.
Hi. Hi.
Hi. Good morning. Good morning.
Hi.
Thanks again.
Did I say hello to everybody? Did I miss anybody?
Oh, my God. Here's the whole roll.
Oh, hi.
Oh, hello, hello.
Anybody else?
God bless.
Good morning.
Hi.
Here's people my size.
We put the big ones in the back so they don't block the...
We put the big ones in the back and they don't block vision.
All right, we'll go around the other side anyway.
John, how are you?
This way, Doc. Good morning, Doc.
Yeah. Oh, he gets another one.
Hope you're around that way.
Ah, good morning.
No fear to make me cry.
She'll save the day.
Good morning.
Just a few announcements before we begin.
The typical cell phone's off, please.
Use the main entrance only, not the side doors all day, just in and out.
And please save your picture-taking, snapshots,
until the Q&A, which is from 3 to 5, and no video-taking at any time.
And real quickly, the schedule, the doctor's going to talk until 11.15,
and then we have our first 15-minute break.
And there's refreshments served in the universal room,
which is straight out that way to the left.
And then we'll be back here from 11.30 to 12.30.
This is serious business.
All right.
Be back here at 2 until 2.45, and then we have our last 15-minute break,
and the bookstore closes at 3.
And there you have it.
Amber Susan.
Nice to have you all here with us.
We appreciate you all showing your opening.
It's important in the word.
It means not only to me and myself.
One thing, we do have a cell phone right now with the 2002 series.
The 2002 is really good.
basis of all the work, and so we have it in, only in VHS and audio tape, so this is on
sales, I think it's 25% off at this point, but it is the basis of the work, so if you're
interested in that, the bookstore has it, and we are going to have power versus force
on CPU, and that will be coming out, hopefully within about the next two to three weeks,
so please check the website, so we've been working very hard on that for you, I know
that's something that everybody's been waiting for, so, okay, and with that, I'd like to
present Dr. Dewey.
An Excelsior's deal, if anybody complains about something in one of the books, I say,
didn't you read the first page?
You were forewarned, and I figure people who shouldn't read the book won't get past the
first page, so I say, go in.
Excelsior's deal, Jesus, throw it out.
Well, today we're talking about, we're talking about perception versus essence, perception
versus essence, yeah, perception versus essence, on the one hand, very simple, on the other
hand, very subtle, and difficult to describe, but we'll do it anyway.
No problem, the impossible just takes a little longer, that's all.
Does everyone have a fair idea of what that means, the difference between perception and
essence?
Anybody, who thinks it seems somewhat familiar?
Oh dear, thank you.
How many people here are new today, new?
Uh-huh, all right, so, what we do is we sort of do a survey of all the, you know, the
material that's been brought up before, in the beginning, and then we go on to the new
material, so there's something for the people who've been here before, and something new,
something new for the people who've been here before, and a quick review, and a representation.
The material is rather unique, because it came out of research, which had not been done
elsewhere.
It came about as a result of an observation.
Okay.
Of a Course in Miracles class, came as a result of an observation of, I was doing kinesiology
on people, and I needed somebody to demonstrate it that evening, and things that made everybody
go weak, like looking at fluorescent lights, or holding pesticides against your solar plexus,
various things like that, all of a sudden, here was a few students on this Course in
Miracles, and they did not know what it was.
They did not go weak.
I said, what is this?
Hundreds and hundreds of people all went weak, and these people didn't go weak.
And that led to the realization that there had been a movement in consciousness, and
we then discovered, by following new students in the Course, we would test them before they
took the Course, then we'd test them periodically, once a month.
And after about the third month, all the stimuli that make everybody go weak did not make them
go weak.
So we had to do a little bit of a test.
We discovered a rather amazing discovery.
That's clinical science, not academic science.
Academic science, it doesn't even make sense.
So we then discovered the whole scale of consciousness, and that launched all the research.
So we'll start with slide one, and that's the one that's so familiar.
It seems to have started out of focus.
Is that in focus?
It's there.
Yeah? Well, maybe it's those spotlights up there, huh?
I don't know if we can reduce the spotlights.
It's sort of fuzzed out. Isn't that fuzzed out?
Yeah.
Could be the spotlights, or maybe it's the focus on it.
Janice, is there a focus on the...
Oh, okay.
That's how things look as you get older, folks.
That, to me, is normal.
This is a 1927 model here.
We have more recent models on the road now.
When I grew up, the Model T was the car.
The Model T was the car.
And then along came an amazing invention, the Model A.
Wow.
So that's just to warn you.
Anyway, we don't need to see that.
I don't know.
Maybe the spots could be...
So let's focus as well as we can.
Is that as good as we can focus?
Oh, this sun that we normally have.
Oh, oh, this sun, huh?
I thought maybe it was these spots.
Okay, well, anyway, everybody's familiar with the consciousness.
Anyway, it follows the chain of being.
On the left-hand side, what you really see is the levels here
come from psychoanalysis.
They come from the psychoanalysis.
These are the welfare emotions.
These are emergency emotions.
And this is the great chain of being, Ken Wilber,
the perennial philosophy.
It's repetitious throughout history,
that hatred is near the bottom and despair is near the bottom,
and that joy and happiness are up here.
The important thing is that God is up here.
At this end.
He's not at the end of hate.
Some people in the world seem to be at the end of hate.
Some people in the world seem to have this whole map turned around.
Love and trust is weakness and to be despised,
and hate is masculine and good, you know?
Okay.
So, anyway, the map of consciousness allows us now a way of discerning essence.
A way of discerning essence.
So what the map really does is give a calibrated level to the field.
The person says, I come here out of friendship,
and you calibrate him, he's 190.
He's 190.
Better search him, you know?
He says one thing and he looks one way,
but he's up to something else.
All right.
So sometime it's subliminal.
Our intuition, we call it our intuition,
picks up the essence, subliminal, body language,
little subtle hints.
If you had to put your finger on it, you can't, you know,
and women are supposedly better at this than men.
Do we think that's true?
No, that's sexist.
You can't say anything in this world.
Traditionally, women were better at intuition than men.
I would say traditionally women were better at intuition in certain fields of life,
and men were intuitive in other fields of life.
In business, they can pick up, he's good for another grand easy.
So I think women are intuitive in their world,
and men we describe as intuitive in their world, you know?
You know, just...
So I used to, you know, I was trained as a boxer.
I was a mosquito weight,
because I didn't weigh 90 pounds to make flyweight.
And we learned, to some degree,
you learn to intuit the other person's moves.
And never telegraph your punches.
I can't understand these interventions,
because they're international megalomaniac people
that get up and telegraph their punches.
They tell the whole world what they're planning
and where they've got it hidden and what they're going to do.
You wouldn't have made mosquito weight, I'll tell you.
Never telegraph your punches.
You know, with the right cross, you know?
Looks like you're going to come with a left jab,
but you were really planning a right cross.
But you don't let them know that.
You don't hold the right cross where you can see you're getting it already.
I mean, that's dumb, you know?
So dumb is the rule.
That's the rule in today's world.
It's a competition.
Dumb between dumb and dumber.
Dumb and dumber.
Dumb get up there and threaten everything,
and the dumber don't even complain.
They can't even get them to vote to complain
about this guy who's threatening to blow up the world.
That's dumb and dumber.
All right.
There is a perception in essence.
So we'll move on quickly,
because we're going to publish an atlas of all these slides eventually.
We're up to 89.
I thought 100 is a neat number,
so I got to manufacture 11 more out of something.
I figured by the end of the year, we'll have 100, you know?
And so there will be an atlas with the slide,
and then at least a page of explanation, you know?
So you get a quick run of what it's all about
without having to read a lot of material.
So the scale of my calibrating,
the level of consciousness confirms spiritual realities.
Confirms spiritual realities, and that is a focus of interest,
like the Templeton group and people like that.
How can you verify spiritual realities?
Generally, people don't, you can't.
It's purely a subjective experience,
and until we had the calibrated levels of consciousness,
there was no way to verify a spiritual reality.
Everybody, just the fact that everybody believes in it,
everybody believes in it, everybody believes in it, everybody believes in it.
If you believe something, it doesn't make it a spiritual reality,
it makes it something that everybody believes.
So spiritual reality, then, has never been confirmable.
It's purely a subjective state, consequently.
It is outside the field of academic science.
There's no way academic science can confirm spiritual reality,
because it would be transcending its own parameters,
its own paradigm.
So the difficulty in confirming spiritual reality
is the judgment.
You have to move from one paradigm to another.
The spiritual dimension is a different paradigm.
It doesn't operate according to the Newtonian cause and effect,
or mathematical models.
So perception has to do with projecting
onto that which is really linear.
And essence, then, is non-linear.
It's the field.
You intuit the field,
and despite that,
despite your perception.
So the Enlightened states, then,
so as far as atheists,
they have a difficult time with all this.
And if they go past page one,
they're going to run into this.
And unfortunately, God turns out to be infinite.
Calibrates as infinite.
Well, I spent many years as a devout atheist,
so I have sympathy for the atheist.
And I have sympathy for genuine doubt,
because it's intellectual honesty.
So it calibrates as honesty.
If, honestly, I cannot say that I can confirm
the believability of a divinity,
I'm at least being honest.
And being honest is the first requirement.
So perhaps the best way to become enlightened
is first being an honest atheist.
Or at least a skeptic, you know.
Then I move from atheist to,
what's the next one,
whether you can't say yes or no?
Agnostic.
Yeah, yeah.
Anyway, first I was an atheist,
then I became more sophisticated
and became agnostic.
And I said it's not something that can be confirmed
one way or the other,
which made me a formal skeptic.
Because a skeptic says you cannot arrive at truth
by reason or the mind,
which is something that we reconfirmed.
It is a fact.
You cannot arrive at truth by the mind itself.
Because of the construction of the mind.
Okay, so we'll move on then.
That's a good enough start.
We notice that the world's population,
here's the world's population,
the majority are less than 200.
I want to recalibrate the world today.
The consciousness level of humanity at this point
is over 200, 204, 205.
206, 207, 206.
Okay.
206.
It was at 205 for a long time.
Then it went up briefly to 207.
Now it's 206.
206, eh?
All right, so the majority of the world then
are below 200.
That means non-integrity is the rule
by which they live.
This is what America and our government doesn't get.
80% of the world lives,
by completely different rules.
Being nice to them doesn't mean a thing.
It means you're stupid.
Any of you who've been in that part of the world, you know.
If you haven't skewed the customer really good,
you're a failure and you get beaten when you get home.
You could have gotten so much for the carpet
and you only got so much.
All right, so the difficulty with the world today
is the communication then
between the two different levels.
So what is integrous here is ridiculous here.
And what's re...
Hmm, so.
All right, we'll move to the next slide.
That's enough of the world.
It's too depressing a subject.
Anyway, here are the people over 200.
And as you see, because of their power,
they counterbalance all the rest of the world.
And that is a very, very significant factor.
People in a group like this are counterbalancing,
uh, you know,
probably millions on the planet.
A group like this probably counterbalances
hundreds of millions of people below people over here.
Okay, we move next up.
Percent of elapsed time.
Daniel Lyon, who's here today, did this.
People ask, what do you think about the future of mankind?
Well, when you calibrate the consciousness over time,
percent of elapsed time,
you see that it's almost yesterday that it started
to shoot up, and if this continues,
it would be quite rapid.
So right now, we're at 205, 206, okay.
Okay, we'll move on.
Yeah, I think this is very interesting,
from a religious-spiritual viewpoint.
The evolution of consciousness throughout time on the planet.
At the age of the oldest rocks, we go back billions of years,
and then we see the emergence of life.
And then, it's the calibrated level of consciousness
of life on the planet moved ever so slowly,
millions and millions of years.
Three million years ago, Lucy appeared someplace.
Lucy.
The first real human about three million years ago,
which is very recent, in Earth time.
Three million years ago is like yesterday in Earth time,
so we humans are very,
newly emerged just hatched on this planet time-wise we're just hatched and
barely got here okay then we'll move on next and we see the progression of the
evolution of consciousness throughout the animal kingdom on up to Coco and our
kitty at home let's see our kitty at home let's do kitty our kitty our kitty
is over 200 220 250 260 270 280 to 75 kitties at 275 alright then kitties per
let's do kitties fur kitties purrs over five hundred five ten kitties purrs at
500 and that's the most amazing thing the heart of the kitty then
you
It's the essence out of which he's coming, isn't it?
You get the lovingness.
So the cat and the dog, just like some other animals,
mainly cat and dog,
radiate a certain energy that is quite different from any other animal.
The dog sees you coming and he just loves you up.
He just goes crazy over you, doesn't he?
You see a dog come up, he just goes out of his mind with happiness.
There's a lot there we don't know.
And broccoli, let's see how broccoli is doing.
Broccoli is our African gray.
Broccoli is over 300, 320, 340, 380, 400, 390, 395.
Broccoli is up to 390, coming right along.
She's speaking Spanish.
Gabe is teaching her Spanish.
I'm in my study that the bird answers the phone,
rings the phone, answers the phone, and hangs up the phone and says goodbye.
He makes a buzzing sound like the phone,
then says, hello, hello, has this conversation,
says, I've got to go now, and then makes a click sound.
And I go out in the other room, I think somebody's there.
Whole conversation.
Bye now, I've got to go now, click.
So that's, what did she calibrate? I forget.
380? What was it, 380?
Well, we've done her in class before.
And when we first got her, I forget what she was at, 285 or something.
Anyway, she's moving along, so.
All right, so we'll move on.
We just wanted to reconfirm a few things.
For those who are more intellectual, I think this is very interesting,
and the implications of this slide are profound.
And the academic world really needs this information.
Anyway, these are the great minds throughout history.
And you see, they're all about the mid-400s.
Some get as high as 499, Freud, and who else?
Einstein, yeah?
Newton, yeah.
Anyway, 499, yeah, Plotinus is over.
But 499 is really the peak of what the intellect
and reason are.
And what reason can do.
So it defines a paradigm, then, a region in which it's applicable.
It's not applicable elsewhere.
This is not applicable once you get over 500.
Once you get over 500, you're talking about a different dimension
in which reason and logic and the linear constructs
are no longer meaningful, appropriate, or applicable.
Yeah?
So we cannot prove the existence of God by the intellect,
which is one of the reasons I was an atheist.
You know, I studied theology at a Jesuit university.
And classical theology, I said, that's ridiculous.
First cause, the argument for first cause.
I mean, how absurd.
God's infinite.
If you're infinite, you got no beginning and no end.
So how can there be a first cause?
You know what I'm saying?
So goodbye, theology.
Although I got an A in it.
I got an A in all those courses.
You got to be smart.
You got to know what you're arguing about.
That's something new in today's world.
The world I grew up in.
You had to know what you're complaining about.
Now we get emails, and when we do the arm on it,
I said, did this guy read the book?
I get no.
He's complaining he hasn't even read the book.
You open the page, you didn't like it, and send off an email.
I don't like emails.
In the old days, you had to sit down,
and write a letter.
Get out stationery, put a stamp on it,
spend three cents.
And that...
They were three cents.
And therefore...
That took care of about 90% of the emails.
If they had to sit down and write a long-end letter
and put three cents on it,
they wouldn't be doing it.
Anyway, not knowing anything about anything
does not stop them at all.
We'll move on to the next.
We've got to move on.
We've got to move on fast today.
Now this becomes applicable, you see,
because here is perception focusing here.
And here is essence out here, is the field.
So when we talk about essence,
we're talking about a field,
which is often intuited, subliminal.
And the more evolved consciousness gets,
the more you identify with the field.
You have less and less identification with this,
and less than that,
and greater and greater identification,
with life itself,
with the essence of life itself.
You eventually end up identifying with consciousness,
consciousness itself,
rather than the content of consciousness.
Because bodies come and go,
and if you think you're a body,
then you're going to die when your body topples over.
So it's good to realize you're something other than the body
before it topples over.
Although you find out quick enough.
So we'll move to the next.
Yes.
So here we talk about the field
as compared to the content of the field.
The content, which is perception,
is the ego, it's linear, predictable, measurable, objective,
deals with force, time, causality.
The proximate field has an influence on it,
but the infinite field,
is one of the spirit out of which all knowingness arises.
Even the knowingness of that which is linear
comes out of the non-linear.
Okay, we'll go on to the next.
Spiritual foundation of virtues.
This is called,
this was the world that I grew up in,
the 1927 model.
It went with the Model Ts and the Model As.
These were all considered normality.
Heh heh.
This is the way your friends were,
your friends were.
This was what life was.
And we didn't know that anything else existed
except John Dillinger, Machine Gun Kelly,
Babyface Nelson.
There was Mob Barker,
and the criminal gangs,
and then there were these people.
And these people were all the people.
That's what's called traditional America.
Everybody was friendly.
If you moved into a neighborhood,
your neighbors came over and brought some tea to meet you,
and everybody returned your lawn mower,
if you lend it to them.
It was a sane, orderly world,
and people were friendly.
There were some weird people,
but we just avoided them.
Heh heh heh.
The old crab that lived down in the corner.
Walk around her lawn.
Okay.
But generally, everybody followed a certain model of normality.
That's what was called normal.
The interesting thing about the mind is that
it likes to dramatize everything.
The mind is actually 99% silent.
This is helpful when you're meditating.
It's just helpful to know it.
People become, they despair that they can't get their mind to stop
when they're meditating.
It just goes right on talking.
And that's because they're looking at the content of mind,
and not the mind itself.
The mind itself is that in which all this talkingness is going on.
The mind itself is silent.
The only reason you can hear a sound in the forest
is because of the silence of the forest.
The mind is 99% silent.
Everybody here right now,
99% of your mind is doing nothing at all.
It's just being there.
It's the infinite field in which the story goes on.
The story is only 1%.
What happens is for entertainment,
we become hypnotized by the 1%.
We focus on the content of the 1%.
And think that's the mind.
That's not the mind.
That's what's going on in the mind.
That's the action in the mind.
But that is not the mind.
Obviously.
To see something, it has to be an empty space.
To know what you're thinking,
it would have to occur in a vacant field.
Look at the sun shining right on this poor man's face.
Good God.
Can we lend him a cap or something?
Can you want to move?
Are you blinded by the sun?
He looks like he's blinded by the sun.
Alright, so we'll move on from this field.
The formula of causality then
is that a oneness spreads out into its components
and looks like causality.
Looks like causality.
We'll go to the next one.
There is no such thing as causality in reality.
When you're dealing with reality,
what you see is emergence.
When you see the understanding that creation and evolution
are one and the same thing
is the secret to understanding it.
Out of the infinite potentiality of the Godhead arises
God manifests as the universe.
Which is eternally evolving and advancing
at the speed of light.
The universe is expanding at the speed of light.
Wow.
Had to get a franchise on that one.
What we think is causality
is merely the way things emerge.
Alright, so if creation was constructed right from the beginning
to be evolutionary in nature,
and from the preceding slides it's very obvious,
the intrinsic nature of creation
and physical reality is evolutionary.
Each thing is emerging.
Each thing is transforming and emerging.
Nothing is causing anything else.
And what we see is the sequence.
The sequence is going on in your mind.
There's no sequence in the world anymore
than there's causality in the mind, in the world.
What you see is emergence.
Emergence is a potentiality becoming an actuality
when local conditions are favorable and facilitated.
The seed sits there until everything is just right.
The sun doesn't cause the seed to sprout.
The water doesn't cause it.
The person who plants it there doesn't cause it.
Its intrinsic nature is under certain
the potentiality becomes an actuality.
It's very simple to see.
Anybody have any problem with that?
I'll explain it again if you do.
Evolution and creation are one and the same thing.
They were having a big argument about it in the paper,
intelligent design and all the BS that goes on with that.
So I sent a letter to the editor,
which I knew wouldn't get published,
and it says, obviously,
evolution and creation are one and the same thing.
But nobody wants to give up the argument, do they?
They're all getting too much out of it.
Of course they didn't publish it.
Anyway, lower mind, then,
calibrates at about 150.
So the locus on the energy fields,
like the chakra system,
lower mind calibrates at about 155.
It's concrete and literal.
And higher mind calibrates,
what does it say, 275.
So perception, then, first has to
transcend lower mind,
which projects out there its own narcissistic needs.
Its own narcissistic needs.
And the value of everything is based on
its narcissistic gratification.
If you agree with that idea,
if that idea agrees with you, you like it,
because that's narcissistically gratifying.
If it doesn't agree with you, you hate it,
because that's not narcissistically gratifying.
As you move up, you begin to accept
that the end of reason may or may not
agree with how you view it,
and you're more mature and you accept
that that's a likelihood.
Down here, it's not considered to be a likelihood.
It's just simply that you're wrong
and probably should be killed or something.
Burned at the stake.
The trouble with...
Well, that was the world.
How about let's do you in the United States?
Calibrated low in the United States right now.
It's over 420.
421.
422.
Okay, it's holding up pretty good.
Holding up pretty good despite the media.
See, because the media have sort of a
naive, simplistic school child idea of fairness
that the alternate view should always have equal time.
So the whole program's about the fact
the world is round.
Now they're going to give equal time
to some idiot who lives somewhere
in boo-boo land who thinks it's still flat.
The viewer's mind is naive, thinks that,
gee, this must be so.
So that which is not true, you see,
gets equal exposure in the media
with that which is true.
And that's the downside of society,
which I think is its undoing eventually, frankly.
I think the undoing of society is by iteration,
iteration meaning constant repetition
of a small error.
By iteration, you eventually destroy
a social structure.
Until the lie becomes equally okay with the truth.
And in many areas of the media,
that is already so.
The lie is equally valued as the truth.
That's the downside of democracy.
Most democracies only last two or three hundred years.
And it's because,
I call them the great unwashed ones,
that's what I used to call them.
You call them the great unwashed,
have an equal vote.
So if they have equal time,
fair and balanced,
that's fair and balanced.
So falsehood has equal time
and equal emphasis,
and it's equally glamorized.
In fact, it's even more glamorized
because it's more dramatic.
The crazy professor gets more time
than the sane person.
Okay, so the lore of mind then.
We'll move on.
The Newtonian paradigm,
we're all familiar with that.
That's the world of science.
And quantum mechanics, then,
is a way out from the linear domain
of the Newtonian paradigm
via the Heisenberg principle,
in which we have the interesting discovery
that to observe a thing
is already to change the outcome.
You've already changed it.
You've introduced something else.
You've introduced the impact
of consciousness itself.
Quantum mechanics, of course,
didn't know anything about
calibrating level of consciousness.
So my intuition is that
the level of consciousness
of the observer
has a profound effect.
Not only does observing it
change the outcome,
collapse the wave function,
potentiality to anaxiality,
but the power of observation
of the observer
can have a very profound effect.
And such things, then,
can result in fallacious
research.
The Templeton Foundation
spent one million dollars
to study the efficacy of prayer.
All right.
The recent study
that got a lot of publicity out of it,
the Journal of Cardiology,
calibrates over 190, 195.
Calibrates at 190.
One million dollars,
five or ten years' worth of research,
published in Cardiology.
Hit all the newspapers
in the last couple of weeks, right?
All the media.
Prayer doesn't work for healing.
The research calibrates
at 190.
Fallacious,
to begin with,
fallacious by design.
Just as Crick's experiment
that led to the discovery
of the DNA
calibrated 440.
His last experiment
before he left the planet,
he left the planet
at a good time, I'd say.
Calibrated at 170.
That was to prove
that consciousness
is nothing but
the product of neuronal activity.
I mean, mechanistic reductionism
is so important
and so primitive
and stupid
you wouldn't think anybody
with a good IQ
could fall for it anymore.
But it's still
a big argument in the world.
Intelligent design,
components and all such.
I don't see what the opposition is
to intelligent design.
It doesn't say
God's intelligence,
it just says intelligence.
Even a little bug
has intelligence.
How niggardly can you be
that you don't want to
allow intelligence
to play any part?
The little bug goes like this,
he goes like this,
now he gets that
this is where you eat it.
Isn't that intelligence?
Oh well.
Okay, we'll move on.
The linear gradations,
you see,
there's no long end
of the yardstick
because from where
you're observing it,
now this is the long side,
now this is the short side.
Now if I move from here,
this is the long side
and this is the short side.
So you see that
what you see out there
is a function of
the point of observation.
The point of observation
determines what you see.
Alright, so we'll move on,
you know.
Spiritual practices,
this is verifying
spiritual realities,
verifying spiritual realities.
Things that we presume
to be so,
but this is like
confirmatory,
confirmatory.
The Lord's Prayer,
650, yeah?
Om pronounced
om, not om
or a-u-m,
this is the incorrect
pronunciation.
Om namah shivaya,
shanti shanti,
om mana padme hum.
We'll resume later.
Anyway,
Gregorian chants.
I love Gregorian chants.
You know, I said I wanted
to be a diverger
in a great cathedral
and you sit there
and you hear the choir
practicing all day Saturday,
Gregorian chants.
I mean, wow.
You know,
boy, I was a boy soprano.
Boy soprano.
Yeah.
And it was a wonderful life.
Practice Wednesday night,
practice all day Saturday,
and then practice Sunday morning.
Then you get a bowl like that
and the kata, you know.
Yeah.
So that's the religious upbringing,
which has a favorable effect,
as you know,
on neuronal connections.
The best thing you can do
for a child
is classical music,
a spiritual or religious upbringing.
And if you had playing chess,
you'd get an extra note,
one more point.
Sing the rosary,
pilgrimage to Mecca,
12 steps of AA.
12 steps are very powerful,
the 540.
540 is unconditional love
that's reached by 0.4%
of the people on the planet.
0.4.
Unconditional love.
570 is saintliness.
Current Pope, the last Pope was 570.
This Pope's about the same, 567 or something like that.
That's perfect for the head of a world church.
If you get beyond 570, the whole thing becomes idiotic
and you want to deal with it.
And you keep saying, what?
As soon as he's used to that.
What?
And TM, prayer of Jebez, walking in the labyrinth.
We do that here in Sedona at St. Andrews, St. Andrews, yeah.
Genuflection.
Now, all these things here at 540 are all acts of devotion,
acts of devotion.
So I always get spoiled when I go to Korea
because in Korea, everyone greets each other
in what I consider the only civilized manner.
They meet each other.
Even if you're walking through,
the clerks and everybody, complete strangers,
greet each other with a certain reverence,
which I find very, very meaningful.
Prayer of St. Francis of Assisi,
bathing in the Ganges at the Wailing Wall,
devotional burning, turning prayer reels,
devotional acts, hand clasps.
So that's very interesting.
All these are really contributory.
You know, we say how ignorant, turning a prayer reel.
It calibrates at 540.
Why?
Because of the intention.
So the intention is the field.
The intention is the field.
It's the field that elevates it.
We'll move to the next.
Progressive fields of realization, then,
are from form, which registers a recognition.
And how do you know that?
Because part of consciousness is the watcher,
the experiencer, which comes out of awareness,
the observer-witness, the light of consciousness.
So in meditation,
in meditation and in evolution as your consciousness progresses,
you identify farther and farther back into this field.
You begin to know and to it that you are this here.
It's pretty easy to get to the watcher, experiencer.
It's pretty easy to grasp that.
And we'll move to the observer-witness.
You can let go identifying with that and without much effort,
move back and realize that it's not you.
You realize observing and witnessing is a phenomenon of consciousness.
You don't decide to observe or witness.
Your say-so, you don't have no say-so whether you're going to observe or witness.
You open your eyes, you're observing and witnessing already.
It's an automatic phenomenon of consciousness.
So it's easy to let go of a personal eye here.
And you don't have to be a genius to realize the observer,
observing, witnessing is an automatic phenomenon of consciousness itself.
And how do you know?
You have to know that, because of the light of consciousness.
And therefore, with a little contemplation,
you can move and realize that what is of significance,
the core of your reality, is the light of consciousness itself.
We'll move on.
Am I going to take a break? What time?
I drink. I give up drinking.
I spit it all on booze and women and the rest are wasted.
Spirituality, you see.
And where we grew up in traditional America was sort of piety, piety.
Long robes, monks' cowls, crucifixes, saying the rosary,
giving up meat for Fridays, giving it up for Lent.
It was penance and piety and confession.
Spirituality has to do with joy.
Joy has to do with laughter, seeing the humor of life.
If you don't see the humor of life, it's going to be hard to get through it.
You chop off your thumb, you say,
what the hell, I didn't need it anyway.
It's this one I use.
Poor Susie.
Anyway, she said she was going to tie me down today, but I got loose.
No.
Spiritual evolution has to do with joy, joy.
Piety has its place, but beyond piety is joy, and beyond joy is ecstasy.
It's an overwhelming ecstasy with enormous energy, enormous non-stop energy.
You can dance 24 hours a day without ever stopping.
All physiologic functions stop, and you're in a very exalted, ecstatic state.
Oh, I don't know how you get out of it, I forgot.
And then it comes to you that that, too, has to be surrendered to God.
That's what came in that state of ecstasy.
This, too, had to be surrendered to God.
And as the ecstasy was surrendered, then a great peace, peace beyond all description,
the peace of God descends.
So beyond joy is ecstasy.
And beyond ecstasy is an infinite peace, sat-chit-ananda, non-linear, with no content.
It's just the core of one's existence.
It is bliss and forever.
At that point, you can leave the body, 50% too.
And I remember, the door is open.
There's no point to continue on.
The physicality.
And therefore, there was a surrender to what?
Divine will of whether the body would continue on or not.
It was irrelevant.
It gets up and walks around, that's great.
If it doesn't get up and walk around, that's great.
It's equal, of no significance.
And it's God's problem.
That's the solution.
It's God's problem, it's not yours.
Thank God.
So, the spiritual energy, then, comes up as the kundalini energy,
as your consciousness evolves, the kundalini energy rises,
and creates certain phenomena.
One of the first phenomena it creates is,
the outflowing of this kundalini energy then,
occurs, starts to flow at level 200, and advances very strongly.
It creates the etheric brain, creates the etheric brain.
And it modifies the physical brain.
So, as the kundalini energy rises,
then, you experience things differently,
with a different side, a different dominance.
The right brain is now dominant, instead of the left.
So, 80% of the world, or whatever it is,
the majority of the world, live here out of the animal brain.
Greed, hatred, anger, narcissistic self-indulgence.
Exploitation of others, there's nothing wrong with that.
That's business, they call it.
Over here, it starts to bother you.
Over here is where it bothers you,
when you walk by the little black beetle,
I always use him as an example.
Down here, you see a black beetle, you go,
give him another swoosh.
Over 200, you see the black beetle, but you're busy,
you walk by, now it grabs you.
Oh, heck.
You go over and you turn him over.
Now you walk, you're happier, you're happier.
Little beetle walks away, he's happy too, you know.
Life serving life, out of love of life,
all life becomes equally valuable.
So his little dilemma, you know, grabs you.
Under 200, his dilemma doesn't, you call the exterminator.
Okay.
We see that the level of consciousness determines the rate of happiness,
the rate of poverty, criminality,
and the happiness rate, the rate of criminality,
is directly aligned with the level of consciousness.
Directly at the consequence,
it's not due to some environmental out there in this,
but the level of consciousness.
And the way you come out of it is by taking responsibility.
So I agree with that comedian who gets people annoyed
by pointing out that you're the people that created the crime here,
you're the people that created the poverty here.
Bill Crosby.
Bill Crosby, yeah.
Bill Crosby, you know, is trying to get them to come out of that.
Take responsibility for your own actions,
stop blaming it on others.
And you see what happens to the rate of employment,
the rate of poverty.
The minute you do that,
the rate of criminality drops way down.
Down at the bottom, you see,
it's a lifestyle of a whole society.
The whole society lives here, yeah.
All right, so we'll move on.
The level of consciousness as related to international affairs,
of great significance.
If we know, I call this us and them.
This is us, and this is them.
Now, us can be our company, it can be our community,
it can be our family, it can be our,
in this case, it's our country.
And then we calibrate the consciousness level
of who we're dealing with diplomatically,
and you can see that you've got to change your languaging,
you've got to change what carrots you hold out to,
something that's a carrot here is meaningless down here.
The carrot works up here.
Same carrot doesn't work down here.
They don't eat carrots.
We hang the same carrot in front of everybody,
in front of the rabbit and in front of the lion.
Lions don't like carrots, folks.
Lions down here, at calibrated level 90 or something,
don't like carrots.
Isn't that simple?
And meat doesn't appeal to these people here.
So, all right.
To be effective and successful,
we have to change our languaging based on our awareness
of the consciousness level,
the field in which these people live.
Otherwise, we're just talking into a mirror.
And we spend most of our time talking into a mirror.
What time have we gone?
Oh, we've got 20 minutes.
Okay.
All right, I want to see where we are
because I want to save a good deal of time for what's new.
Oh, okay, wonderful, okay.
Because we have three new slides.
As I say, we've got 89 slides altogether.
And we've got three new ones for today.
So we wanted to do first for the people that are new
a quick review and add a few comments as we go.
This I consider to be of profound importance
in world affairs.
It's the only possible way to pace, as far as I can see.
It's the science of international diplomacy
based on calibrating the consciousness level
of the leader, the people, and the government.
You have to know all three.
You can have great people,
but they've been taken over by a terrible ruler.
You can have wonderful people and a good ruler,
but the government, the economy is rotten through and through.
You know, it's payola wherever you go.
Payola wherever you go.
So the whole economy and the government,
so life doesn't get better there.
The people are wonderful people, we love them all.
And the president is a wonderful guy.
But the structure in between doesn't work, it's horrible.
So you get all kinds of admixtures of the three.
And therefore, you'd have a really realistic expectation
of what you can deal with.
If we calibrate the level of a visiting ruler,
we know how to talk to him.
We know what they value, what's meaningful,
what is the field of reality in which they live.
What's the field of reality in which they live?
Getting a free alligator would not tempt me
to get into a deal.
Hey, doc, you do as you get a free alligator,
it would not attract me.
So we offer free alligators to a lot of people
who are not interested in them.
And we say, how come we can't make a deal with them?
We can't get a deal on, what, Iran right now, right?
You can't even get people to agree
that they don't like the idea
of being blown up by an atomic bomb.
They can't even agree they don't like that idea.
You cannot get the governments of the world to agree
that it's not a great idea and they should say so.
Can you believe that?
You can't get the governments to agree
that blowing people up with atomic bombs is not a good idea.
That's why you can't take the world seriously.
I mean, it's bizarre.
Oh, golly.
Here we just see the level of evolution of consciousness
and the rate of happiness.
Percent of people who are happy,
and you see a huge jump at level 200.
Below level 200,
people find gratification and fulfillment.
Take that, you.
I'm sure Dillinger and Babyface Nelson felt good
as they pumped them full of lead and grabbed the money and ran.
But that's not the same thing as happiness.
That's instant gratification.
Plunging the dagger into somebody you hate,
I'm sure it feels good.
Take that, you bastard.
Boy, that feels good. I should have done that.
Snicker snack.
Which lifetime am I in right now?
Let's see, where are they?
That was a different lifetime, boy.
We put each other away.
Did we ever put each other away?
I did it for Jesus, he did it for Allah.
We both left the body at the same time.
And both broke out laughing.
We were good, we were good.
You were the best.
I put it right through him and he put it right through me.
The bodies fell over and we both went out in the spirit
and just laughed. It's hysterical.
I did it for Jesus, he did it for Allah.
So we never had to repeat that one again.
We've helped each other periodically over a great deal of time.
Alright, so we'll move on to the next.
How to identify spiritual truth and integrity as teachers.
We're going to have another lecture later in the year
in which we cover most of this again.
So I'm thinking of constructing a new religion.
We need a whopper of a good name for it, let's recall.
The truth whether you like it or not, religion.
Truth for nickel biters.
Nickel biters, how do you know it's true, huh?
Alright, so is this, no, we've got to go back one.
Yeah, identification of spiritual truth.
Because there's so much that is not spiritual truth.
50% of what's in the spiritual bookstore is fallacious.
Over 50%.
Some bookstores that are just all in the way, just 90% BS.
But the average spiritual bookstores are about 50%, you know?
Everything from the Da Vinci Code to, what's the newest one?
The Jesus thing. No, Judas, Judas Gospel.
Judas Gospel.
If we can discern essence, what would we guess the essence of that is, huh?
I'm going to guess 160.
Let's see.
It's over 130, 140, 150, 150, 155.
Gospel according to the Jews is about 155.
It's total BS, right?
If you write a fiction in the year, you wrote a fiction thousands of years ago,
it's not truer because it's on an old piece of papyrus.
It was BS then and it's BS now.
And the Da Vinci Code is BS when it was written and it's BS now, you know?
If I can make a movie out of it, I'm going to make it true, you know?
Yeah.
Mary, what was it, Jesus and Mary got married and had kids,
and I mean, the whole thing goes boom, boom, boom.
Makes a great story.
And the reason there's so many books going to come out like that,
there's a whole bunch of them about to come out,
is because it made millions of dollars.
So, you can see the spiritual intention there.
Let's warp history.
Let's throw in some big names like Jesus, Mary,
the 12 apostles, right?
Put some big names in there.
Beats, who's the guy, the Scientologist that had a kid?
Tom Cruise, right. Beats Tom Cruise, you know?
All right.
All right, so universally, truth is true at all times and all places.
And the fact that it's on television and has, you know, music in the background.
The other way that falsity enters the media is music.
You can't understand what's being said on the program because of the music.
You get the History Channel.
This is the history of the British Crown, let's say.
And the music drums up like that.
And then the music drowns out.
I'm trying to get what Edward III said about the thing.
And the guy on the music thing thinks that it's all about music.
People getting killed and dying.
People being beheaded.
Crowns are falling.
Europe is changing.
And this guy is, I can see him in his circuit board here.
You know those big boards they have on a rock band?
And he's like, the music is rising up and rising up.
And just then, and just then,
and just then, what for Christ's sake?
I write the History Channel all the time.
Will you stop drowning out the story?
There's a guy that gives the history of Britain,
an incredibly smart guy, I forget his name,
Shalm or something.
And just when he gets to a critical point, you want to know,
the music swells on you.
Truth is always true.
It's available to everyone.
Its purpose is integrity.
Nobody owns it. Nobody sells it.
No requirements.
Non-controlling.
Free of force and intimidation.
Next slide.
What did you say?
Oh.
What number slide are we at now, by the way?
Forty-two.
Okay.
You can't get to heaven without a program grad, folks.
They ask you right at the entrance.
How many slides did you get through?
Forty-two?
Under forty-two.
Got to go back to earth and go from forty-two through to eighty-nine.
All right, so truth is beyond opinion.
Perception has to do with rejecting an opinion, an evaluation, a judgment.
It's beyond that.
And truth does not do anything, it just is.
Truth doesn't try to promote itself, it just stands there.
That which is power does so out of the quality of its essence.
It transforms things
as a consequent of that which it is.
Not that which it says, not that which it does.
Because that which it does and says
is merely an expression of its essence.
When you experience the joy of life,
the joy of life is joyful.
Can't help it.
Stop it. Stop it.
You have to sit on yourself.
Otherwise, Susie comes and says,
we'll just stop.
Non-operative, does not do anything, it just is.
It's invitational, so it grows by attraction rather than promotion.
That's also characteristic of the 12-step groups.
They are not promotional, they don't have any opinions on what's out there,
and they grow by attraction, by attraction of their integrity.
Non-sentimental.
Non-authoritarian.
Non-egoistic.
Educational.
Self-supporting.
Free-standing.
And natural.
We'll go back and finish a little of these up again after the break.
Well, then I'll finish it up now.
We'll go back to it.
No, we can't go back to it.
We'll take a break now.
And I don't want any laughing during intermissions.
I want piety.
I want everybody to be really spiritual.
We haven't started yet.
We don't start until I say we start.
Spiritual teachers are not controlling.
We'll start when I say we start.
Anybody else can leave the congregation.
Now it's up to a group vote.
All in favor of our starting, say aye.
Okay, group vote.
All right, the confirmation of spiritual realities is really the, you know,
a great benefit of calibrating levels of consciousness.
It's hard to tell because perception precludes awareness of essence.
The capacity to discern essence doesn't really arise.
Classically, it's called the opening of the third eye of the Buddhic body.
In other words, the etheric bodies, the etheric body,
at a certain level of consciousness,
the third eye of the Buddhic body opens.
I think it starts to open around 200, I don't know.
I think it starts to open.
The third eye of the Buddhic body begins to open at level 200.
Okay, good enough.
Yeah, it starts opening at 200,
and then its capacity grows over time.
So eventually, you know, you can tell.
The minute you hear,
the minute we heard the Gospel of Judas and this old papyrus,
and they're all going about the reality of this old papyrus,
it's got nothing to do with, I don't give a crap
what this million years old piece of papyrus,
I mean, what's written on there, that's what I want to know.
So you instantly get that you're being hyped, you know.
They're trying to up the viewership, you know,
and then they can increase their advertising rates, etc.
It's got nothing to do with truth, it has to do with hype.
So you get the difference between hype and truth.
Truth doesn't need hype, it stands on its own.
Truth stands on its own.
But it may not be recognizable as truth
until consciousness does evolve to certain levels.
So we've relied over time, am I blocking somebody's view?
So, I don't want you, yeah.
So, anyway.
We've relied then on people who have evolved more spiritually,
and we understand from their writings and their teachings.
Now that in itself causes confusion,
because you see there's disparity between
the literal teachings of the various teachers,
and therefore the naive person gets confused.
It helps to clarify what is being explained by the teacher
if you know the calibrated level of consciousness.
So this person here is not telling you the ultimate truth,
he's telling you what truth looks like at consciousness level 500.
He's telling you what consciousness level 575 looks like.
Confucius, of course, Socrates, etc.
They're telling you what the world looks like,
what reality looks like from that particular level.
So, if I was a starting student,
I would start from the lowest levels and first
become familiar with the lower, you know, the teachings.
Be kind to black beetles on their back.
You see what I'm saying?
Read Chinese fortune cookies and take them seriously.
We told you that fortune, Chinese fortune cookies
calibrate around 350.
Well, a Chinese fortune cookie is far beyond
the consciousness level of mankind.
You understand that?
Mankind is at 205.
Chinese fortune cookies are at 350.
Gail and Robert brought us Chinese food the other night.
The fortune cookie calibrated over 300, 350, 360, 380.
375.
The fortune cookie calibrates at 375.
You know, it'll say something like that.
The wise man knows how far to go and when to stop.
You know what I mean?
And other people, the fool, lunges ahead.
First, make sure you've got fortune cookies mastered.
Move on from fortune cookies.
When the fortune cookie life describes what your life is like,
you are making good progress.
You are way ahead of most of the world.
Be kind to your neighbors.
Be thoughtful of people.
You know?
I mean, this is kindness and wisdom.
So, what it teaches is wisdom and, I think, wonderful sayings.
I don't know how fortune cookies got to be so fortunate.
We have to come back in this world.
We'll come back as a Chinese fortune cookie.
We've got a good start.
Take off from 350, you've got a running start.
You know, what most people want to do,
I'll show you what a 90 person does.
They look for the highest number here.
Quickly, they scan this.
They find 950.
Okay, we'll start there.
Starts with, you don't exist.
Oh.
Existence versus non-existence.
That's where I started out at age three.
For a three year old, that was a conundrum, I'll tell you.
Out of nothingness.
Out of the oblivion of nothingness.
Because my prior spiritual commitments had been to the pathway of negation.
And every time I'd leave the body, I'd go into nothingness.
And so, nothingness is not the ultimate reality.
Or you could stay there.
One thing about nothingness is that it's painless.
And you no longer exist.
You haven't got any problems.
So, I was not happy to suddenly come into conscious awareness of physical existence again.
I remember the shock.
It's still vivid to this day.
At age three or three and a half, whatever it was.
Sitting in this little wooden wagon.
The body's probably about this long.
Sitting there, this little body.
Suddenly aware of existence, that I existed.
It was like a shock.
It was like coming out of the dark to Klieg lights.
Blinding.
Suddenly aware that I existed.
I was not pleased.
Not pleased.
Not only did I exist, but this body went with it.
Oh, God.
Bad enough to exist, but to exist as a physicality, I was not happy.
Not happy.
All right.
So, that's starting out at 8.50.
Most kids don't start at 8.50.
Anyway, that was the conundrum that faced this lifetime.
What's the resolve and go past 8.50?
Because 8.50 is the void.
8.50 is the void.
And it is where the pathway of negation will take you.
And the pathway of negation is taught by some of these teachers at U of C.
That that which is linear and which has form,
which is tangible and physical,
is transitory.
Therefore, you devalue it.
You don't become attached to it.
Now, to not become attached does not mean to devalue.
That's another mistake that's made.
To devalue it because it's linear is the same mistake as pricing it because it's linear.
To sacrifice your life to pile up diamonds at home is an idiocy.
To say that diamonds are worthless is also idiocy.
Because they're not worthless at all.
Plus, they have an intrinsic beauty, do they not?
They have an intrinsic beauty.
Alright, so it's a delicate balance then.
So, I advise people to start with Chinese fortune cookies.
And when you've got that mastered,
when you've got that mastered,
be kind to everyone, you will never regret it.
You will never regret having been kind.
And remember, I told the headsman,
look,
don't worry about it.
It's just a job.
Don't feel bad about it.
I gave him a heavy tip.
Neat job.
Back in the void.
He was stuck in the world.
I was in the void.
So, once you've gone past fortune cookies,
then the next thing to do would be to pick out
those that calibrate the lowest, not the highest.
Start from the lowest, you know.
You start, when you learn anything,
Is it going to be pyramider or is it a primer?
I never did know.
Is it a primer or a primor?
Isn't there a kindergarten teacher here?
Alright, so I would start out until this becomes comprehensible.
Until it becomes concen
No, go back, back.
Ah, yeah.
Okay.
There are very popeular, you know, eirick butterworth,
the writings of butterworth are very, very solid.
very solid so all these that you know are the lower numbers are very very
solid and their value is that they are readily comprehensible you know if you
read my amount of a harsh he says don't you know the people try to fix the world
don't lie by the fixing the world the world you see doesn't even exist they're
all ready for a peace parade let's have a peace parade the police are there the
dogs are there ready for a peace parade so you open Ramana Maharishi and they
say the world that you want to fix doesn't even exist don't bother her
surrender it to God why because everything that's occurring is
fulfilling its current confidentiality how can it grow unless it goes through
stages so you want to fix what is actually other people's salvation what
you want to fix is that is the way in which they are undoing that particular
karma
after you've killed a lot of people how are you going to undo that folks you're
gonna get yourself killed quite a few times most likely I think they even keep
tabbing him I don't think we'll have permission on this one is it a life for
a lucky I have permission to ask this it's okay to ask it in front of this
group today right now it is not okay to ask it not okay to ask it we get knows
so we teach canadians the odds by demonstration you don't always get a yes
because there are such things as God's mercy and many non-linear factors so you
can't count it you know as a decisive question and a decisive answer why
because it defends on the field the field is the infinite mercy and benevolence of Almighty God
in which probably killing a thousand people could be excused like that but one contrition who knows
yeah all right so anyway we started out at the bottom until we feel that we understand uh people
who are have been common and popular and popular preachers I think and uh who's the biggest selling
book in the world today in America uh the um the minister yeah purpose-driven life okay so the
purpose-driven life is the best-selling book in America
isn't that amazing and the values the values that he describes are solid and if I was a candidate for
political office that's the first book I'd read if you're going to speak to the voting populace
you know isn't that important what they consider to be the most popular book in America I mean what
are the people that you want to vote for you what are they thinking what are their values
and I discovered that when we were making we used to travel all around
and speak all over the United States and Canada and various places and we would stop in a truck
stop and all the books in the truck stop were uh was were religious all these truckers pulling in
with their big rigs and all what are they reading they were reading all these religious books isn't
that amazing huh you think this guy with all these tattoos and all these big muscles and all you think
he'd be thinking about football or something
he's out
in his truck it's you can hear the diesel going and he's reading his Rick Warren book he's reading
religious books amazing huh those are the people whose vote I'd be looking for if I was running for
office so more books than any other book isn't that incredible all right so first you you you
master those in the 400s is what I would say the fact that they're in the 400s means that they're
intelligent and comprehensible the intellect can grab them as you get more and more exotic it's
less and less possible to grab it with the intellect so Eric Butterworth is still comprehensible those
within the 400s are still comprehensible uh with it with just the intellect alone Ernest Holmes is
one of our favorites and it all makes good sense so that's the rock solid foundation rock solid foundation
right before you grab a text that calibrates at 800 or 900 and then I would take those that are
now addressing including now the reality of love in the 500s and if I was starting over frankly I
would just put these in order and I'd start at the bottom and start reading my way up to the top
does that make sense well you know as a medical student I had to be very organized in my study I
just grab any old book, because I like the cover, you know what I mean? So if I was doing
it again, if I was a theology student in an advanced theology course, I would start at
the bottom and read my way right through this list, read my way right through the list,
read my way right through the list, until I comprehended all that, comprehended all
that. And of course, as you do that, you become motivated to apply it to your own life,
and automatically you begin to absorb it, you automatically begin to absorb it, by sure
familiarity, by sure familiarity. So constantly, it isn't like you have to intellectually
comprehend every move on the road, but if you keep going over the same road over and
over again, it becomes obvious, it becomes obvious that to be kind to all living creatures
all the time is an expression of wisdom, and if you keep doing that, you become wise,
you become a black turtle turner over. So these are very popular, Thomas Merton, so
these are very well-known names. Now it becomes more difficult to comprehend as you get into
the 700s, Ramana Maharshi, Nisargadatta Maharaj, because now you're getting into Vedanta,
and non-duality, which is the next book we're coming, we're having printed, is devotional
non-duality. So those who have read up through the 700s, it will make sense. So I'm not telling
anybody what to do, except what you should do is, being a obsessive-compulsive physician,
you can't get through medical school unless you're obsessive-compulsive and driven. So,
I would arrange these, you know, all according to the numbers. I know how my mind would
do this. I would put them all according to the numbers, and I would first read, what,
440, and then 450, and then 455, and I would spend a year, a couple of years, what difference
does it take, how long it takes to read them, but I would first master that. So, first
master the 400s, and then the 500s, and as you go up. Of course, the motivation to even
be spiritually involved is usually already over 500, or people wouldn't be at a lecture
like this. I mean, people are already motivated because the spiritual seeker within you, which
is an archetype, is already very involved, and people like this, the archetype of the
spiritual seeker is already quite evolved, and therefore you'll comprehend things that
are beyond the intellectual.
You need to intuit it. So, these are very famous names, Ourobindo, or Charles and Myrtle
Fillmore, the Unity, Emmett Fox, these are all people we all know very well, Meister
Eckhart, and some of these are not well-known here in this country, but certainly Martin
Luther, and we know all these names. So, Robert Monroe is very interesting, Journey's
Out of the Body. If you haven't read that, it's just a fun book to read.
He's an engineer, and he starts having simultaneously out-of-body experiences, and he's never heard
of it before. He gets back in the body, and he writes in his diary, and he starts compiling
for people who have never been out of the body. It's really interesting.
Okay, so we'll go ahead, and these are more in the list, and they go all the way up, probably,
to Huang Po, which I've spoken about before. Now, Huang Po is the Pathway of Negation.
The Pathway of Negation will take you to the Void. The Void is at about 850. The Pathway
of Negation is what he, Huang Po wrote about that, and the Pathway of Negation, Huang Po's
writings are lower than Huang Po's personal calibration, because when he wrote his aphorisms
of, when he wrote the, what do you call it, of Huang Po? What's the name of the book?
It's such a famous book.
Yeah? Anyway, what he was writing about was 850. Then after writing that, Huang Po discovered
the error. He himself went to a higher level. He actually went to 960, although his book,
see, this is Huang Po, the person at 960, but the book, which is famous, I can't think
of it at the moment, takes you to 850. But then he discovered that there was more, that
nothingness is not the ultimate, that allness.
Allness is the ultimate, which I discovered, because at 850, there I was back in the nothingness
of the Void again, and then suddenly back into physicality. Later in life, I re-followed
the Pathway of Negation, and when I negated, I mean it's negated, you know what I mean?
And it's back in the Void again, but, and the Void, as I've said in previous lectures,
is extremely impressive.
This is enlightenment. It matches everything you've ever heard, read, and it usually comes
as a result of a long stretch of spiritual endeavor. And suddenly, there's nothingness.
No you, no person, no nothing linear, and it's eternal. And it's infinite peace and
infinite calm and infinite.
The only thing that's wrong with it is it's devoid of the warmth of the power of the presence
of God as infinite.
It's infinite love.
In this lifetime, that had come out at age, I don't know, 14 or something, in which I
climbed out, as I've said before, out of a storm into a snowbank. And there, the infinite
bliss, the infinite presence, as infinite love.
So in that infinite Void at 850, that's what was missing, was that I already experienced
the incredible bliss.
The incredible state, the condition of love, which is beyond all beginning and all endings.
And it's not different than that which you are.
That which you are is not different than that love.
So that knowingness was already there, and therefore, I refused the Void this time, and
didn't get stuck there.
So anyway, that's how I'd go about starting over.
I'd start right at the bottom.
And so this takes you five or ten years.
I'm not sure how long it takes.
I don't know.
Maybe ten years.
Maybe it takes you twenty years.
What's the difference?
You know?
Because it's so delightful, the whole trip.
And of course, it's very fascinating reading, and you become transformed just by exposure
to the material.
Okay, so that's enough about all that.
What holds the level of consciousness is the dualities of attraction and aversion.
That level of consciousness has a certain attraction to it.
And there's all sorts of things.
There's also an associated aversion.
So this is just general attractions and aversions that keep people fixated at any particular
level of consciousness.
They get a thrill out of it.
They get a kick.
They get a payoff.
So what holds anybody at any particular level of consciousness is that level of consciousness
has payoffs in it.
And what you're unwilling to give up is the payoffs.
The feeling of vindictiveness when you're right and they're wrong.
I mean, what's more fun than being right and having other people wrong?
That's a hard one to beat, isn't it?
Even chocolate is hard to...
Would you rather have chocolate and let go of chocolate or being right?
That's a hard one, isn't it?
Alright, so we get addicted.
Everybody at any level of consciousness means you're already addicted to the payoffs.
Addicted to the payoff of a certain positionality.
You don't have to let go of the positionality.
You have to let go of the addiction to the juice, the payoff of that positionality.
You don't have to give up being right.
You can be right all the time.
Who cares?
What do you mean, who cares?
Yeah, who cares?
It's the narcissistic gratification.
Alright.
So all these dualities then...
Yield a narcissistic gratification, look how people cling to being the victim.
The gender card, the race card, the poverty card.
I mean, you know, they play it to death, you know what I mean?
The tragedy card.
I've lost a member of my family.
I've lost every member of my family.
Everybody's going to lose all the members of your family.
None of us are staying here, folks.
Everybody's going to lose everybody.
All of us.
the time, eventually. Does that get you a 20-minute spot on TV? Lately it does. I have
to just blubber and cry and make a big calamity out of it. That's really juicing it, isn't
it? Juicing it. So you can see the narcissistic ego of these people getting up there juicing
it. I mean, it's nauseating. They just juice it and juice it. Night after night, the same
people juicing the same story. They lost one person in their family. Christ, I've lost
half a dozen already. I mean, so what's a dozen? Probably a dozen. All right. The attraction
then is you cling to it because you get juice out of it. And the aversion is to let go of
the juice. The aversion is letting go of the juice. The attraction is the payoff. And the
aversion is to letting it go. It's much more fun to blame people than to let them go. Yeah.
Blame.
As soon as there's...
As soon as there's a sad story on television, the very next person, the next talking head
that comes out, and we're looking for who to blame. Katrina. Who should we blame for
Katrina? How about the weather?
Next slide.
George Bush. Poor old George. Everything. Everything's George. Katrina's George. The
war's George. The weather's George. Economy's George. The price of gasoline is George. Poor
old George.
But we need George to beat up on. So, he serves the function.
Whoever's president gets beat up by. It used to be Clinton, you know. Whoever's president,
you beat up on him. That's why you can't get people of a certain caliber to be president.
What's his name, the former actor, was...
Reagan.
Reagan was over 500.
But that's very unusual. Very unusual. Usually by 500 you know what the score is.
They're going to beat you up to death, spit on you, and who needs it, and pay you a lousy 200 grand a year.
That's what the President used to get paid, 200,000. I thought it was outrageous.
I mean, you can run a pizza parlor and make 200,000, you know.
The President of the United States gets paid 200,000.
Now he gets 400, yeah. He's a what?
The President of some corporation just got paid off, what, 400 million to exit. 400 million to exit.
The President of the United States gets 400,000.
Alright, so the attraction then, we cling to it because it's familiar, it's got a guaranteed payoff.
So we'll move to the next slide. Yep.
Oh, this is love versus infatuation. People are not interested in that.
Infatuation, of course, is what's sold as love.
And, you know, it's really a madness, it's a mental illness.
Passionate attraction, it calibrates 145.
It's the mating animal in heat. The mating animal in heat.
You can see it on the nature, nature.
All the animals humping away.
There's stuff that if I...
When I was a kid, they would tear the page out of the book in the library.
Elephants doing it.
Menasres is doing it.
I don't want to know about it.
145. So it's instinctual, it's left brain.
It's hormonal, as everybody knows.
And it drives you to murder and suicide.
Other than that, it's great.
Yeah, uh-huh.
So that's passion, 145.
All right, so let's go to the next one.
Love is something else, you see.
So love at 500 and over has to do with concern for the other person's happiness.
And it doesn't need something from the other.
You don't need it.
You appreciate it, you appreciate it, you value it.
But it's not a cravingness.
All right, the dualities of shame, then.
You see, the attraction...
We sing self-punitive.
Isn't that awful?
But no, that's what is sought.
What's sought is to punish yourself.
The child makes a mistake, now you've got to go sit in the corner.
So the child gets...
Be bad, get punished.
So the way you get absolution is by punishment.
Self-flagellation and all the things...
Sing the rosary, all the various things that religion does with it.
The attraction is...
And the aversion.
So the duality is the shame.
So in the book, the most recent one, what is the name of that one?
Oh, yeah, Transcending Levels.
We go into each level, then, and examine each level.
What holds you there?
What's its attraction?
Why do people get stuck in it?
And what do you have to let go of to get off it?
What do you have to let go of to see is that really a sacrifice or not?
So we'll move on out of shame and more shame.
Oh, God, I'm ashamed of this chart.
Pleasure.
Shame, you like beating on yourself instead of blaming it on the ego.
So I don't think you should do spiritual work without holding Socrates' dictum in mind,
that all men choose only the good.
That gets you out of hatred and blame and self-condemnation
because the human mind is so constructed that it craves that which...
Its cravingness is based on perception.
A projected value.
And all men choose only the good.
What Socrates says is you can't choose anything else
except what you conceive of as being the good at the time.
It might be killing somebody.
He deserves it, so the good is to stab him to death.
The good might be blowing up infidels.
That's very popular nowadays.
Straps and bombs on yourself and blow up a busload of infidels.
It's cool, you know, in certain cultures.
All right.
So because the person conceives that that is the way to please God,
therefore Jesus Christ said,
forgive them and they know now what they do.
So instead of trying to follow religious dictum,
which is hard to do,
forgiving those SOBs who don't deserve it,
just as Jesus said it.
You know, it's okay for Jesus to say that.
But he didn't have somebody parking in his place.
You know what I'm saying?
.
I don't know how Jesus would make out in today's world!
We know that the Christ is an energy,
an energy, you know.
It became embodied in the personage of Jesus Christ of Nazareth.
Okay, next.