[music]
Here
he [music]
>> [music]
[music]
>> Now the rate of happiness this is a
little bit different way of doing it. Uh
the the log of the uh calibrated level
of consciousness
what is the percent of happiness?
So you see that happiness is a
consequence of level of consciousness
not a consequence of what you own in the
world or what titles you have or whether
you're pretty or famous. Uh if you uh
are here at 250 which is comfortable the
chances are about 60% 60% of people
there are going to be happy. So the way
to achieve happiness is not through out
there but in here. You can't achieve
happiness by acquisition. You can only
achieve it through advancing your level
of consciousness. You see that people at
the bottom their rate of happiness is
zero. The rate of happiness down here
below consciousness level. So 200 again
is the critical line. Above 200 55% of
the people are happy. The minute you go
below the line it drops to 22%.
There's no way to make these people
happy.
They will say that
there's no way and nothing you can do
that will make people who calibrate
below 200 happy.
Nothing.
Give up your life. Give up your
property. Turn over your country. Turn
over your wife. Turn over your children.
Enslave everybody and you will not make
them happy.
[laughter]
here. I thought we were going to make
thy world happy. Huh?
You cannot make these people happy.
You cannot live and hate etc. and be
happy. Okay? So for the sake of your own
happiness and but because as you as your
level of consciousness rises, you see
you're lifting the world. The only
chance of these people being happy is by
you being happier.
That's the only thing you can do.
As you become enlightened and happy, you
radiate out an energy. And I've walked
through dangerous places. I mean,
dangerous like I don't want to tell you
with complete safety. And all the guys
just looked at me in amazement. A
cutthroat gang with whips, knives, guns,
and chains. And here's this short little
shrimp walking right through the middle
of them. And they all just went
and I walked through absolutely
untouched.
A 6'6 professional Natalie would never
even tackle this crowd. All them whips,
knives, guns, and malice and tattoo from
head to tent and roaring their
motorcycles and just waiting for a rough
something to start up. And I went right
through all them.
I thought they were great looking guys,
you know.
Remind me my lifetime as a pirate. They
were just my buddies on the ship, you
know, cutthroats. Everybody was a
cutthroat. I mean, what's wrong?
[laughter]
Now I've been in very unsafe places and
and and come out of it alive, you know,
in San Pan outside of Shanghai and
various places where I should have been
killed, robbed, and tattooed, but uh I
they delivered me home and put me on the
doorstep, you know. So,
okay. So, it's what you become and not
what you do. All right, we'll move to
the next.
I just put this in for fun.
Uh this is the Louve.
There's the Lou, which is 700 years old
or something. Uh, and in the middle of
it is an abomination.
[laughter]
Here's this crystal and glass
abomination which calibrates at 180.
And I don't know if any of you remember
the contention with with France and who
was the premier of France at the time.
Anyway, they think they were being very
very modern. very very modern. Anyway,
it's of course a disgrace when 180. It's
very functional. No doubt about it. I
mean, it's great. You walk in the
basement and you go up to everything. Uh
it's just aesthetically in the middle of
the Lou. I don't suppose I would have
put that there myself.
[laughter]
Chrome steel and glass in the middle of
the feudal beauty. You know what I mean?
[laughter]
Brussels, you know, the main square in
Brussels in cobblestone and around you
are all these incredible feudal
buildings. I don't know if any of you
have been there, but it's worth a trip
to just to experience that. I said,
yeah, and to picture a modernistic
building would be an abomination anyway.
Okay, we'll just move that in there. I
put that in for my own personal fun.
Now, we're going to talk about spiritual
truth.
See, first we need a science of truth.
Then we need to apply it to the world.
Truth versus falsehood, which was not
everybody's favorite book, and that's
too bad
because man says he's interested in the
truth, but he ain't. I mean, nothing
makes him mad. Then you present it with
the truth. Indignant. Indignant. How can
you say? I didn't say. First of all, I
didn't say, as you can see this morning,
when we do kinesiology, I don't say
anything. She doesn't say anything. We
just come up with a number. What do we
care? It's only just a number. Nobody's
saying anything about anything. Then the
number clues you into whether you're
really delusional or you ought to look
at this or pray for help or what call
your therapists.
There are many false teachers in the uh
world and I was myself quite amazed when
I discovered how many there were. I mean
lots lots who are quite world famous
also.
lots and they calibrated well at one
time
and then crashed very often severely,
you know, not just coming down from 570
to 540 or something, but all the way
down to 180 or something. And of course,
a number of them have been on the
internet of these recent times of the
scandals. So because you're putting the
your eternal soul in the hands of a
teacher, you better know who that
teacher is. I mean, I wouldn't be so
careless. You really you're talking
about your eternal soul, the karmic
perpetuation
throughout all time.
And you're going to put this in some
flashy ad, go and get your orura read by
master so and so on. On the other side,
uh, of course, you have turned over all
all your property to
[laughter]
You get a reading from master so and so
through him on the other side only cost
you 5,000 for your granddaughter except
you don't have a granddaughter
that was in the internet a local one
local guru for five grand a guy reading
on a non-existent felicia is yeah all
right
so I want everybody that I I'm a teacher
of I want to be responsible you know to
tell them the downside. Apparently these
gurus fell because nobody their
instructors did not instruct them of the
downside. So in our lectures we
constantly go over what is the downside
of each level of consciousness. Where is
the trap?
Um people say I'm beyond that. You're
not beyond that at all. The Buddha at
the last from 850 and up is very
difficult. And the Buddha acknowledged
it. He said I felt like my bones are
being broken because the demons are
looking for erony weakness uh in your
psyche.
There are characteristics of spiritual
truth that will carry you through if you
know them. You don't need a list of who
they are and what they calibrate. That's
very handy. But if you know certain
basics, it's more important to
understand the basics. Truth is true at
all times and places independent of the
culture, personalities or circumstances.
Truth is always true no matter what. So
if we calibrate
the
cathedral. It's Shark Cathe Cathedral.
It it it is that calibration is so no
matter what truth is true at all times
and places,
non-exclusionary.
It's all inclusive, nonsecritive, and
non sectarian.
Nobody owns truth. What?
>> What?
>> It's 12:30. You're lying to me.
She said, "It's 12:30 and I have to
stop."
>> Okay, get one more. Not an exclusive.
It's It's not secret. Okay, thanks. Oh,
stop there.
>> [applause]
>> Now, uh, what time is left?
>> Be back at 2:00.
>> You have to be back at 2:00 or else
or else you'll be late.
It's bad to be late.
>> What number side are we up to?
>> 40.
>> Huh?
>> 40. 40. Oh my god. We better move along.
>> Okay, we'll go back to where we were.
>> Oh, 39.
>> Okay, so if you have the basic
principles,
uh you won't fall into the soup. And uh
so we're giving the basics of uh
integrity of teachers and teaches
[laughter]
and as you as yourself evolves in
consciousness
there are certain traps each level has
its trap and uh with forewarning you
won't fall into it. A group like this,
your biggest uh one of the biggest traps
coming up is unconditional love and
love. As you reach the energy of love,
you become quite attractive to other
people and they will interpret it as
personal love. People will fall in love
with you all over the place. There was a
period of time when I got propositioned
a couple times a day.
[laughter]
And I didn't have a teacher to warn me,
but I just
I mean I knew the integrity of it was up
up for you know being tested. So I
intuited it. But uh many fall for that
one there. And uh then glamour the
glamour and uh we were we weren't
allowed to use the title guru in the
book. Every time we'd ask it said no.
The word word has come to mean something
different than what it what originally
meant because it was being exploited.
Uh wealth, fame, having lots of
followers,
uh
having millions of followers across the
globe, etc., world fame. So all those
things are temptations to the spiritual
ego to consider yourself important. And
you see how the the spiritual ego throws
you right back into a personal self
right away. So the minute you think it's
you, you just lost it. [laughter]
It was it was but it was not not
anymore. Uh so spiritual pride
uh vanity
uh the agilation of many followers
being world famous all those things and
seduction and glamour of wealth and fame
and possessions. Yeah.
And uh the glamorization of the the
glamorization of the spiritual teacher
with robes and music and edififices and
pageantry and parades and all that uh is
uh seduction.
All right. So we were talking about
spiritual truth and teachers.
Uh truth is true everywhere. It excludes
no one. Available
open to all. There are no secrets to be
revealed, hidden, sold or magical
formulas or mysteries. Let me just
confirm
that which I spoke is the truth. Oh
Lord, resist that is the truth. When you
see a secret, an ancient secret being
pedal is always for a price, you know
that you're being had by a spiritual
comment.
[laughter]
Truth to be truth is truth all the time.
Foreverness. And how could it be the
exclusive property of someone? Yeah.
Uh available. It's open to all.
[clears throat] Integrity of purpose.
There's nothing to gain or lose. Non
sectarian.
Truth is not the exposition of a
limitation. Independent of opinion.
Truth is nonlinear. Therefore, not
subject to limitations of intellect or
form. independent of opinion, devoid of
positionality. Truth is not anti-
anything. Why is that? Because truth has
no opposite.
It only has it. The you might say the
opposite of truth is is absence.
You understand what I'm saying? The
falsehood has no reality. There's truth
and then there's the absence of truth.
The absence of truth. So there's only
truth and the absence. And we call the
absence of truth falsehood.
Uhhuh.
Just like light and darkness. See, light
and darkness. Light is either present or
not present. Yeah. No requirements or
demands. No required memberships, dues,
fees, regulations, oaths, rules,
conditions, and we don't uh circul
circularize everybody asking for
donations. [laughter]
Non-controlling spiritual purity has no
interest in the personal lives of the
aspirants in their clothing, their
dress, their style, their sex life,
their economics, their family patterns,
their lifestyle or their dietary habits.
So the controlling pseudo guru, you
know, is always telling you have to have
his approval to get married. You have to
etc.
And of course,
sign over your wealth and your ownings,
your possessions to them. [laughter]
That's an important part.
And some are local. There's some local
people here who violate every single
sentence. Every single sentence. Every
single sentence. They want to control
your lifestyle. Now, why would anybody
who was interested in an infinite truth
be interested in your sex life, your
dress life, your or what the hell you do
with your personal life? I mean, why
would he be interested in it except
there's something in it for him? You
know, control.
So, you would have no interest in that
which is linear and personal and
obviously karmic etc. What would you
care about such things? Free of force or
intimidation. We, you know, people are
threatened. There are spiritual groups
including locally where you belong to
the sect and if you try to get out of it
there are uh recriminations
sometimes quite severe
uh no force or intimidation there's no
brainwashing
agilation of the leaders no training
rituals watch out for training rituals
that's a call the brainwash indoctrin by
which you're indoctrinated
indoctrination anything called the
training watch
training.
If you know the truth, what do you need
to be trained?
People a relic occasionally has one on
this program. There's a guy from I think
it's the Islamic world or what and he
gets on you can you can tell
brainwashing it has a sound and a sight
to it. You can tell the instant you hear
it. It's almost like a mechanicalness
and and he's like reciting a program
that he's been programmed with. Once I
tell you that, you'll you'll pick up
programming instantly. They have a
certain style and a mechanicalness to
their dissertation. And you can hear
it's a whole program that they're
reading out of their poor poor mind.
All right. What's next? Uh any more to
this? Oh, nonbinding.
Do not take any oaths.
Do not pledge anything.
And if I fail to break these vows, may
such and such happen to me. Never take
such a vow. It'll cost you lifetimes
later.
I know.
See, you forgot that in life, that
lifetime, you made that commitment and
swore to it by blood, etc. You've
forgotten that, but it's still you're
still held to it. Just all right.
Non-binding freedom. Free to come and go
without persuasion, coercion,
intimidation, or consequences. There's
no hierarchy. Instead, there is
voluntary fulfillment of practical
necessities and duties. Everybody we
work with does what they go do because
that's what needs to be done. [laughter]
Commonality
ah recognition. Let's say if you do have
a leader or people who that you honor,
it's because of what one has become
rather than as a result of some title
or trapping the great Baham you know you
know bam because he's the great Baham
you know what do you mean he's the great
Baham who said he's the great Baham he
say he's the great bah oh
you recognize truth when you see it and
so I respect all that exists because of
the essence of that which they are,
which I sense right away. Therefore, you
give respect to the the little beetle
walking along. You give respect to the
animals. You give respect to the polar
bear. You give respect to all that
exists by virtue of that which it is.
Huh. Mhm.
The essence of the thing is that which
it is, you know. And what does a thing
mean? What a thing means is what it is.
What it is is what it means.
That's hard to see, but then you get the
essence of it. You see, what this thing
means is what it is. You don't have to
add adjectives, adverbs,
languaging.
It speaks for itself by virtue of its
existence. So, a teacher should be will
speak for himself because of the reality
of that which it is. That which it is.
Yeah.
not not that which is spoken about it.
Okay. Nonmaterialistic
neediness of worldly wealth and all this
stuff that goes with it. Uh
so
inspirational truth avoids
glamorization, seduction and theatrics.
Theatrics the glamorization of the
theatrics. And I've been to so-called
spiritual events that were like a
Broadway production, you know.
3D videos and bombing music and
orchestras and flashing lights and holy
god you know
am I being programmed or I mean what is
this
you no need for worldly wealth you see
today's uh this week's what is it time
magazine I think
[clears throat] Frank cover has an issue
on the religious argument about wealth
isn't that Time magazine has it been?
Yeah. Uh wealth etc. And the
promulgation of the idea that God's will
for us is abundance. And then of course
there's an ancient one of uh poverty.
And so what is the truth? Does God mean
for you to have lots of stuff or no
stuff or hardly any stuff or just a
little stuff? [laughter]
So there's evangelicals out there
telling you God's will for you is
abundance. I'm all for that.
And then there's people saying out
there, you don't need anything. Uh and
and it's better to be devoid of
possessions. And I'm all for that.
Best thing to do is be completely
povertystricken and have a lot of money.
Well, it's because they don't define
what is wealth.
See wealth is a is the difference
between your desires and that which you
have. So when you don't want anything
now wantingness is one of the greatest
things if you want to transcend quickly
to let go of wantingness. Letting
wanting this wanting admiration wanting
possessions wanting control wanting all
the wantingness. When you finally let go
all the wantingness you've got more than
what you need.
You get more than what you need. When I
first came to Sedona, I lived in a ready
place. I didn't have a bed, so I went
and bought a cot at the darn store. I
bought some blankets at the Goodwill.
I got a nice wooden box
and put a candlestick next to it. And I
was complete. What What more do you
need? [laughter]
And uh I put an apple in the
refrigerator and save that for dinner.
So what more do you need?
>> Life space. You got nutrition when you
want it. And of course, God will provide
for you if you need. So I tested that
out, too. Of course, a miracle said
that. So I walked out with no money or
no food and wandered around Sedona. I
got invited for breakfast. I got invited
for lunch and invited for dinner.
[laughter]
People would just say, "Do you have
breakfast yet?" "No, I'm going over to
so and so." I said, "I haven't got any
money. It's not It's not the house."
So anyway, um, what you need is
provided. Therefore, if you need
nothing, you already have abundance. You
understand? I already have abundance.
Why am I going to seek abundance when
I've got tons of abundance? Can I live
without a sport jacket? Yeah. I mean, do
I need all this stuff? Frankly, no. I
need a pair of shoes, pair of pants,
shirt. So, what else do you need?
[laughter]
I am rich and fulfilled and complete as
I stand here now. That which I am right
now is complete and total and needs
nothing.
[clears throat] That is a statement of
the truth.
As I stand here, I am complete and total
and need nothing.
>> What more could you add to me that would
not become a burden?
>> She's giving away my secret.
She comes from an old-fashioned middle
class value system
that says if a thing is raggy and worn
out, you should throw it away. And I
my favorite shirts and clothes at home
are all raggy and worn out, and I love
them.
But it has a hole in the elbow. Well, so
what?
Raggy old clothes. There was the the the
the black doctor who who did all the
work with peanuts. It was a very
wonderful all kinds of inventions.
>> Carver. Carver. Yeah.
>> Well, he was a comp
like I am. He he wore raggedy old
clothes and that was his favorite. So,
if you have a new shirt and an old
raggedy shirt, I always take the old
raggedy shirt. I don't know what it is.
So therefore,
um,
you have wealth. It's just you don't
realize it. And almost all Americans
have more than they need despite
whatever they may think about it. Uh
because if you don't have any money, you
can go someplace where they give out
free food for those that are homeless
and have no money. So again, you got
abundance, right?
Uh [clears throat]
so the recognition is that what you
become, not your trappings. Uh the
teacher should be inspirational rather
than depending on seduction and
theatrics and um
devoid of worldly affairs and uh the
these things are okay if they're part of
what the world demands that you have.
I'm sure there are spiritual positions
and religious ones where you more or
less got to have whatever goes with it
because that's the cultural expectation.
Uh you don't have to sign up anybody
prosize gain followers sign up members
non-involvement in world affairs truth
is benign
and has no opposites and therefore no
enemies and no enemies non-intentional
does not have an agenda does not wish to
promulgate anything does not interfere
and try to change the world
non-dualistic all transpires by virtue
of the propensity
within the field by which potentiality
manifests as actuality
rather than by cause and effect. All
right, we've already said that. Okay.
So, there's no way to make things happen
by magic potions. Magic potions and
magic spells and incantations and magic
ruins and marbles and magic toebones
throwing the toebones. You know what I
mean? [laughter]
Tranquility. There are no issues of
partialism.
Not dependent on propagation of effort.
God doesn't need help other than any
more than gravity needs the help of of
an apple falling off the tree.
Yeah. Here to help God. That's a very
nice intention. But God doesn't really
need help. [laughter]
If you want to change the world, you
feel that God needs help. And uh, of
course, you can convert people easily by
cutting their heads off if they don't.
[laughter]
Except the folks say that don't count.
So I don't know what you can say about
that.
So So God doesn't need help. All right.
Equality expressed in reverence for all
of life and all of its expressions and
avoids that which is dilitterious rather
than opposing it. So you don't have an
enemy. Uh you just refuse it. And I
think that's what Jesus Christ
recommended. Do not oppose evil. Avoid
it. Withdraw from it. Uh rather than
doing battle with it.
Beyond proof that which is provable is
linear, limited and a product of
intellectualization and mentation. It's
within the linear domain.
Reality needs no agreement. Reality is
not an acquisition and is spontaneous
because it is nonlinear.
Mystical. The origination of truth is a
spontaneous eulgence, a radiance and
illumination which is the revelation
that replaces the illusion of separate
individual self the ego and its
mentation.
So what happens is as you drop the
barriers to elimination
the all lights up from within not as an
acquisition not as something you've
gotten or done or earned.
As you let go of the blocks, the
resistances,
the truth stands forth of its own. You
don't have to get it, pursue it. You
only have to remove the blocks to it.
That makes the whole work very easy to
merely constantly surrender. So to walk
about in a contemplative way with the
attitude of surrendering to God. So um
your position then as a spiritual
aspirant within the world
is
your contemplative lifestyle is thus
to achieve in the world you're very yang
but to reach enlightenment
you let Let go of this. You let go of
it. I let go of this. Let go of this. If
I don't have wealth and food, I'll start
the death. If I start to death and then
you keep surrendering it. So you start
to death. Got to go one way or the
other. You know what I'm saying?
I don't want to go now. Who cares when
you go?
Reality is outside of time. So what
difference? You drop dead this instant,
next month, a year from now, it's all
irrelevant. You know, so as you
constantly let go then the truth
replaces that which was falsehood. So
you don't have to acquire truth. You
only have to remove the blocks to it.
The blocks to it. We have slides later
on the blocks. Each level of
consciousness has its blocks.
Uh okay. Equality
reverence for all of life. non-temporal.
Life is realized to be eternal and
physicality is temporal. We all suffer
from an incurable disease called
mortalism.
All of us here a 100% fatal condition.
[laughter]
What's nice about it is we all share it
equally.
So we're all equal from the get-go.
all have the same karmic fate to be
transitorially in the linear domain and
then on to the nonlinear okay
we said that proof is truth is not
provable mystical is a spontaneous
revelation I gave you the just an
example I haven't spoken before this
group before so I'll repeat a few I've
said in other lectures the first re
first came as a complete Revelation H3.
Out of nothingness, out of complete and
total oblivion, there was suddenly the
awareness of existence. Existence as
such.
Out of nothingness, there was something
the somethingness of existence. It came
as a incredible shock. I didn't like it.
Now I have that. That was bad enough.
But on top of it, a body went with it. I
looked in the little wooden trailer and
here's this little body. Good God. First
of all, you exist. Now you got a body on
top of it. It was a very bad moment.
[laughter]
Having come out of the lifetimes of the
pathway of negation into nothingness
which is around 850
that void uh to come out of the void
again. See if the void was a reality I
would have stayed there. Void is not a
reality. It's an illusion. It's an
illusory. It's not a reality.
uh 850 is not reality [clears throat]
of nothingness.
Out of nothingness coming into existence
was a terrible shock. No sooner that I
recovered from that shock then suddenly
the polarity of it if I exist and then
the possibility would be that it could
come to pass that I would not exist.
Then came the fear of the loss of
existence. So at age Siri is presented
with a conundrum of is infinite reality
existence or non-existence.
Yeah, it starts at 850. So you know is
reality existence or non-existence? That
is a very advanced thing. It took some
40 years to solve. Anyway, so that was
three. Then as a child I was
compulsively uh religious.
I had to go for the therapy. [laughter]
Uh I did. So
the priest said that uh your soul is
visible to God. See, I pictured it like
a big uh too late glass or something.
And when you sinned, they made a spot on
your soul. Jesus Christ. God's looking
down on you. And every time you sin,
there's a spot there. Jeez, I was scared
to death of spots on my soul.
So I became uh
overly religious and uh what do you call
that? Compulsively scrupulous. Scrupul
severed from scrupulosity.
So I had to see a priest for counseling,
you know, about scrupulosity.
Uh but I can remember going to Saturday
afternoon you went to confession in high
Episcopal
and like Catholicism you went to and
then you weren't supposed to sin before
you took communion the next morning. So,
we're in a 29 model Ford with a top down
and we drive by this huge 30 foot uh
what do you call it? Advertisement and
there's a something rather swimming suit
ad with this big blonde 40 foot long
blonde and my god almost an almost a
sinful thought went into my mind and
terror hit me. [laughter]
Terror hit me
that it might have been a sinful
thought. So now I got to go to church. I
can't tell my parents with the thought
that I've had. My god, I was bad enough
to have it. It's related. So now I got
to go to communion. The whole family's
going to communion. I kneel down there
and I'm praying to God for forgiveness
because I'm not going to take communion.
If you take communion with a sin on your
soul, God knows what would happen.
Lightning would strike or something. So
I held my breath expecting maybe
lightning would strike me or something.
And I sipped from the chalice and all
and I survived it.
So God won't strike you dead. I was
afraid God was going to strike me dead
on the spot.
Just a couple of the funny things that
happen in your life, you know. So I was
very religious and uh one day I was
walking through the woods as a young man
by then. I forget when.
And uh uh suddenly out of nothingness
with no thought about it at all just
looking and enjoying a beautiful fall
day in the woods uh suddenly the
awareness of the totality of the
suffering of all mankind
uh throughout all time
revealed itself.
unasked
and uh
in that moment I became an atheist. I
thought any god who could allow that its
its extent and its duration and its
dimension was
and then I became uh a very dedicated
atheist [laughter]
which was sort of fun because I was
going to a Jesuit university at the time
and I got straight A in theology ethics
I got I mean I knew my theology you
can't argue with thing unless you're a
master of it. So I became a master of
theology. St. Thomas Aquinas and
Aristotle and the whole deal. The the
arguments of the proof of God's
existence are still stupid. [laughter]
How can that be which is eternal have a
first cause? You know what I mean?
Forget it. How could it have a first
cause? So the argument for the existence
of God about a first cause and all
intellectually is dumb because that
which is forever. So in the snowbank I
got the foreverness. That which is
forever has no beginning and no end. So
there can't be a first cause because
that which has no beginning has can't
have a possible first cause. It's
ridiculous. So intellectually I was
correct. But uh later on life got worse.
[laughter]
And uh I forget what the circumstances
were. Oh I know what it was. Uh I was
still dedicated to truth the core of
truth. I had like a session to find out
well what is the truth then God doesn't
exist God does exist
and so I went within I
dove into the depth of consciousness
itself
and confronted all the demons and the
dragons and I went down and I entered
the higher levels of hell
and the higher levels of hell which
people call hell is really just the
higher levels it's just jacks for
openers That's just torture and tearing
your tongue out and putting daggers in
your eyes and crap like that. So, which
is child's play. It's all physical
horribleness,
grotesque horrible. And then it gets
worse. And then I wouldn't accept that
as truth either. And then the the horror
got deeper. And then the horror became
nonlinear. See the higher levels of hell
Dante and all predicting higher levels
artists over time. That's the linear.
The linear is the top of hell and then
it becomes progressively nonlinear. It
just becomes a progressive nameless
hopelessness and agony of dread and
isolation of being cut cut off from
anything forever. And then you walk
through the the level give up all hope
ye who enter here and you've entered a
new domain of hell which is
indescribable. It's eternal eternal
hopelessness. Eternal hopelessness with
no possibility of appeal or escape or
change your condition. A black despair
which is forever God. And when the
foreverness, the horror of foreverness
gets you, that your fate is to forever
be
irretrievably, hopelessly
lost into nothing.
And in the depths of hell uh the agony
came up and
I was presented with that which is the
core of what you consider your life
itself. The narcissistic core of the ego
finally came up
and had to be surrendered to the god.
Then later I went into extreme the
opposite extremely high state and in the
highest state there was nothingness
beyond nothingness at 850 there was
nothingness
and in that realm which is extremely
rare again no one there there's no other
people saying about saints and people
archangels talking to them and all
there's nothing in that realm it's realm
beyond of of anythingness anythingness
in that realm I had surrendered
everything to God all along the way
there was nothing left to surrender to
God nothing left
yes there was one thing in the back of
the mind there came a a sentence it said
now that you realize you're all beyond
all art karma all power belongs to you
own it claim it all power belongs to you
if you no longer love people which is a
constraint
if you no longer have any conditions if
the ego is dead then you have know
uh you are completely free
and your power is infinite. It's a
knowingness that comes to you. And I saw
who had been through that pass. I saw
the few individuals and I saw there what
where they either passed the gate or had
not passed the gate. And I saw J
[clears throat] those who had passed
through the gate. And uh because I
already was the infinite power out of
which radiates the universe, there was
no need to claim that which I already
was. So I refused it. That's the last
luciferic temptation. The last luciferic
temptation.
own power over others. That left nothing
at all. All is infinite silence. There
is no other entities to consult with.
You're beyond all. Remember, teachers
are such things because the mind is
silent.
The last thing left it was life itself.
There was only life, the energy of life.
Sans's
linearity, Sans's thought, Sans's
meaning, Sans's all that the human mind
considers it valuable.
And then I got that this too must be
laid down to thee, oh Lord.
And so
[clears throat] out of eternal life
itself, then I surrendered life itself
to Almighty God. And then there was the
agony of dying because it's the only
time you can die. You can't die just
when the physical dies. The ego goes on
forever and and I surrendered life to
God. It then
became oblivion and then the radiance
of the infinite as everything has shown
forth. the world in such stunning beauty
I couldn't operate for a long time and I
left the world
so uh
just thought I'd share with you some of
the experiences which are nonlinear and
which are uh
signed called the world of the mystic I
guess
all right So beyond proof see you can
calibrate the energy of the fields that
I was describing to you but that is the
world of the mystic. It's a spontaneous
eulgence. None of this was sought. It
came forth as a spontaneous radiance. It
came as an illumination and a
revelation.
Uh any idea of separateness was gone and
mentation stopped.
ineffable, not capable of definition.
Radical truth is experiential
and the condition replaces the former.
One doesn't become enlightened at all.
Uh the old condition disappears and
instead a new a new condition prevails.
And uh so let's see if there's anything
else on this list. I want to make sure
everybody's able to recognize truth.
simplistic uh one sees the uh intrinsic
beauty and perfection of all that
exists. So as a contemplative lifestyle
by merely wish uh desiring and choosing
to be aware of it, you become aware of
the absolute beauty and perfection of
everything that exists. I remember the
first time that came upon me. I was
walking down an alley in New York City
and there was garbage cans and mice and
all and trash and suddenly like a
seralistic painting the stunning beauty
artistic beauty of the creation. I saw
the absolute perfection of it. You could
call this alleyway
aloneess whatever. But here it was the
old garbage can sitting there like this.
All wonderful old garbage cans. A
wonderful beat up old garbage can.
>> [laughter]
>> and little mouse running around. So what
many people would think was a horrible,
filthy looking, dangerous, scary alley,
I saw it stunning beauty as only an
artist would see it. So if an artist
wished to depict and bring forth your
awareness the beauty that's intrinsic to
everything, I would pick my garbage
cans. And I have a a slide of the
garbage can somewhere. [laughter]
uh
nonoperative truth does not do anything.
It is anything and its influence is by
virtue of what it is as the as the as an
expression of that which it is.
Therefore, that which you become is what
changes the world.
Don't try I mean why waste effort on
doing this? You're not going to change
the world uh at all. And um but what you
become the world can't do anything about
it. You understand? The world cannot do
anything about the fact that you become
that which transforms the world. They
don't even know that you're secretly
doing that.
As you're kind to as you're kind to
every beetle and try not to step on it,
your devotion to the value and worth of
life is influencing all of life and
nobody can do anything about it.
[laughter]
Uh trees do not do anything. It's
invitational, non-predictive.
Uh truth does not um predict the future,
nor are there any hidden codes in
anything.
Would you like to tell me why God would
want to hide a code code hide a code in
the scales on a fish or the nostril
hairs of a camel?
[laughter]
You see that code is something you
project into stuff. If I can find a code
in anything, I can count the threads in
your shirt. I can count this, you know,
the holes in your socks. I can make I
can line it with ancient calendars and
you will end up with illusion. Why is
that illusion? Because the future is not
reality. The future is the product of
the evolution of consciousness. And
consequently, you can't predict the
future because it isn't here yet. Nor is
it a linear manifestation. It's
nonlinear.
There's no way for the future to know
how much you're willing to sacrifice of
your ego to evolve. And once
collectively we all do the ch the future
already changes. So you can't p you
can't predict the future now because it
hasn't become a reality as yet and its
reality is not predetermined. Its
reality depends on karmic propensities.
Otherwise there'd be no point to human
existence if you weren't earning good
karma and undoing bad karma. You're
wasting your time on this planet. You
know what I mean? Because this is on in
a way purgatorial. Here you get to undo
bad karma and gain new karma. Let's see
if that's the intention of human life.
I have permission to ask this old one.
Oh, the intention is as I've described
it resist.
>> You have about three minutes.
>> Huh?
>> You have three minutes.
>> Three minutes.
>> Good God. Got to save the world in three
minutes.
No problem.
[cheering]
[applause]
Now the other thing we you notice we
check oursel all the time about the
truth especially if we feel that there
could be some difficulty in acceptance
by the audience. Uh it's really an
affirmation. One time somebody said why
do you always do that? because it
transforms that which may sound
intellectual into that which is
experiential
and it's a technique you can use
yourself and it's so spiritual reality
is educational is self-supporting you
know we don't ask anything of anybody
except the cost of it putting something
on freestanding it's complete without
dependence on historical I don't have to
say I'm the 13th
um humpy of the sixth humpy of hapa
Well, like Buddhism, a lot of doesn't
get into that. He's the sixth descendant
of the seventh matriarch of the seventh
patriarch of the sixth cycle of and they
get into like numerology. They're always
counting the 12 ways to God, the 12 ways
to enlightenment, the 14 ways to purity
and truth.
I only got there with one. How did you
get there with the other 12?
Another thing is the way to go is is
void of induced unnatural states of
consciousness which are which is like
parasychological states. Uh abnormal
breathing patterns, abnormal positions,
postures, ways to try and force the
condundolini. When the condolini is
ready to rise, it does so automatically
because of its own truth. As you become
loving, the the condundolini energy
rises. It's not going to rise because
you cross your legs and sit in front of
a picture of the Buddha ga and and burn
incense and do all kinds of mystical
incantation and crap.
Just try to be kindly and loving and and
and step over the beetle and you can
save yourself all that stuff and you
save all kinds of money on incense and
mystical music and gongs.
[applause]
Well, you see the theatricalization of
it all. Uh you get these spiritual
magazines from whereabouts in the
country and and on the front there's
always a a beautiful blonde. She's
always
flowing hair.
[laughter]
I mean you want to do it with me or what
is it? You know,
[laughter]
sex will allure pathway to God or what
is it? You never get a middle-aged
looking guy who was a little chunky who
looks like a truck driver. Do you ever
see a chunky guy,
you know,
on on the front page of one of these
magazines? Not a one.
Where's all the regular guys? Huh?
Hey, wife. Regular guys. Let's heaven
with the guys. Hey.
Oh, golly. I thought for a while we were
going to get to heaven without long
blonde hair. And [laughter]
magical things. And they always do a
mystical yoga posture.
You see what that what I'm saying?
That's the glamorization of it. It's the
theatricalization.
It's the uh rape of the natural. Okay.
So, we'll go on. So avoid unnatural
things and especially trainings that are
going to teach you mystical powers.
Trainings that's that teach you m
mystical powers. Uh go on to the next
slide. All of them calibrate about 205.
First of all look at the seduction to
the spiritual ego. Oh, I'm going to be
special and I'm going to have super
superpowers.
If you had superpowers, they wouldn't be
selling them, would they?
You got superpowers. You're so rich and
powerful and complete within yourself.
What would you be selling it for?
You'd be selling it because you're
needy. Needy of what? More power and
wealth.
Give me a break.
spiritual teachers throughout time.
You'll find that in the book, I think,
truth versus falsehood is being
reprinted in the new one because people
will always send me emails about some
weird guru somewhere, Tasmania or
someplace, Junky Boohoo to whom who
wants his all his material wealth and
wants him to leave his wife and all. And
I calibrate the guy's about 180. So I
said, why don't you look at the list
here? You know, you've got Walmarts,
you've got gimbals, you got Shusters,
you've got [laughter]
Why do you ask me about Hanky Dink
Hardware in Tunville?
[laughter]
There's enough gurus here to last you a
lot of lifetimes. You can spend a whole
lifetime with just one of them, right?
Uh any one of them will take you a whole
lifetime. Just follow one of them.
I had to laugh. Somebody uh was telling
me about meeting the Daly Lama and of
course I'm on a conversation with her.
She'd been done all the spiritual trips
and met all the people, you know, and
I'm laughing of a storm with her and and
she got confused by that and said, "I
don't know. You're just like the Daly
Lama. He laughed all the time. What is
he laughing at?
You got to explain to her what what he's
laughing at. She isn't going to get it."
The comparison between essence and
appearance is is endlessly comical, you
know. So the Dalai Lama, of course, he
laughs all the time.
Anyway, all these are the great teachers
of time and they've all been
corroborated a number of them. You've
all, I'm sure, studied many of them.
You've all, we are familiar with all of
them. So why look for something offbeat?
Well, I look for something weird and
offbeat and unverified. Not that they
couldn't exist. Not that they couldn't
exist, but you know, I wouldn't say that
it's something you should do now. Okay,
next we go. And then
one more.
Here's some more of them.
>> What more do you want? Hey,
>> what?
>> I hear.
What is that?
>> When she says your time's up, she means
it. Huh? [laughter]
>> Don't fool around with this lady. I
mean, things move in space and
telekinesis.
Little telekinesis will get him to pay
attention to the clock, I guess. Huh.
So, do we have to stop now?
>> No, we're fixing it. Just go ahead.
>> How much more time we got?
>> Well, it's time.
>> It's time. What?
>> It's time. It's time for
>> Oh, we're going to take a break. Uh what
we're going to do is take a break and
then after the break, we'll have
questions and answers.
Individual [clears throat] people, you
remain anonymous and
[laughter]
>> Okay. Wait. Okay. How we do?
>> You see when whatever you need is taken
care of by you. I didn't ask her to do
anything, did I?
>> [applause]
>> When you're just your natural self, all
your needs are fulfilled. You see, uh,
is that the last of the teachers? We'll
go one more line and then we'll we'll
exit.
>> Oh, the this gets to I told you each
level of consciousness has an attraction
and it has an aversion. Attraction and
aversion. Each level of consciousness.
That's of course I think in the book
transcending levels of consciousness.
Each one will have its attraction.
And uh you know, you want the thrill,
the excitement. What's the fear? Oh,
you're going to miss out. You're going
to miss out. Uh-oh, you're going to be
bored. Uh-oh. Uh you want to be right,
the fear is you're going to be wrong. Uh
so, we'll do one more and then I'll
we'll go on. You'll see that the basic
core uh behind all of almost all these
ego positions is actually narcissism.
Narcissism in the current society. The
reason it's going down in consciousness
level is because man now worships
narcissism rather than God.
The narcissistic core of the ego. Oh, I
might be offended. So,
the world must stop. Did anybody ask you
to be offended? I don't remember anybody
asking you to be offended. [laughter]
Or they project the narcissism onto the
world. They might be offended.
If you can't handle being called shorty,
forget reaching enlightenment because
[laughter]
you have to own the truth of yourself
and not want to change it. Why would you
want to change that which you've
karmically inherited is obviously a
positive value or you wouldn't have
reincarnated. So we're all in this
together. We'll do one more thing before
we take a break. After that we have
questions and answers. Um
all of us swoop in here together and
swoop out together onto this planet.
Believe that
>> we come as a karmically like a a flock.
We all tend to reincarnate about the
same time. We all know each other and
then we fulfill this one. We go on the
other side. We do what we can there and
then when we group decides we all sort
of come back again like a bunch of swans
whistling swans or something let's see
that which uh I just spoke is the truth
many in this group are tend to be
enlightened
and many in this group destined to be
enlightened that's why we hang in
together back and forth because as a
group we constantly move and quite a few
in this group uh either now sitting or
due to going back and forth are destined
for enlightenment. Where does
enlightenment arise? It doesn't arise
elsewhere except in extremely
spiritually dedicated people such as a
group like this. Therefore, I'm honored
by your presence to have such wonderful
students.
[applause]
>> [applause]
>> So, you are God's gift to me.
>> Thank you, Lord.
>> We'll take a break and then we'll have
questions and answers.
>> Thank you. Um when we come back from
break um if you want books signed please
over here. If you want books and
questions answered
on this wall
>> talk
say something.
>> Say something.
>> Say one more time. Say, say one thing,
boy.
>> You ready?
>> Am I ready? I am ready.
>> We are ready.
>> Oh, boy.
>> Ke,
we're ready.
>> What's reassuring if you travel around
America by by car, you stop at truck
stops. And when you look at the books
and the racks and the truck stops for
all the truckers, there's the left
behind series. There's Rick Warren. You
see truck drivers out there. When I said
they never put a truck driver on the
front of a spiritual magazine, you know,
I was reading it truck drivers. Every
truck stop you notice in the books,
they're all Rick War and this and
everybody's into spirituality. It's very
enheartening. Yeah.
So, we don't have to worry about America
if all the truck drivers are reading
spiritual work.
>> Is this thing writing? It doesn't seem
to right. I can't see very well. Okay.
>> Yes.
First, I would like to thank you. Um, a
month ago, I listened to your CD about
conquering illness about how you throw
away your glasses.
>> Yes.
>> And after 48 years of wearing glasses
and contacts since I was two. I just
took them and went
>> I threw them away and I couldn't see a
thing.
>> That's right.
>> And I got to tell y'all, it was the
scariest thing I've ever done to go to
work the next day.
>> It's ready.
>> Is it ready?
>> Yeah. And that's been a month ago. I'm
about to 80% vision and I just want to
thank you.
>> 80%
>> 80%. Thank you so much. And I do have a
question. I I deal with dogs and I
rehabilitate dogs and I work with
aggressive dogs and over the last four
months I've started calibrating the dogs
before I work with
>> That's very interesting.
>> And I have found a large range
of of the calibration in the dogs.
>> That's very interesting. And I've gotten
to the point where if it doesn't
calibrate over 200, I don't deal with it
because I don't think I can fix it.
>> Yeah. It's got some karmic u difficulty.
>> Is that the right track?
>> I think that's correct. And that's a
wonderful application.
>> Yeah.
>> Can I email you with questions about it?
>> You can email me blessings anytime.
[laughter]
>> Thank you.
>> Or whatever you found out about it. You
know, that's very interesting cuz
>> Yeah, your research is always
>> I mean, so much of what we talk about,
you know, I could spend a lifetime
investigating any sentence of it. Any
sentence of it because one thing leads
to the other. Yes. You understand? You
know.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And I try not to calibrate the people or
I wouldn't be working with them.
>> That's right. [laughter]
>> Thank you so much. Should have said
that.
>> Yeah. If the if it wasn't for the dog,
the love of dogs and cats, people would
the suicide rate would be at least twice
what it is. It's really the love of
one's pets that keeps many lonely old
people by themselves alive.
>> Okay.
>> To think of something other than than
their condition. Oops. Sorry.
>> Do one more here.
>> Yeah.
>> Doc.
>> Yes.
You can't see now, but thanks.
>> Thanks for nothing.
>> All right.
Thanks for the question. That's very
interesting. She calibrates the various
dogs, you know.
>> That's very interesting.
>> Yeah.
Well, we know that prison the prisoners
who are training the the seeing eye dogs
have shown a extremely high recovery
rate. Some will actually stay in prison
to finish the training of a specific
dog.
>> So I think that is so beautiful to learn
how to love hopeless prisoners become
model citizens after training seeing eye
dogs. That's incredible, isn't it?
>> Yes. My question for you is uh I think
about a year and a half ago or two years
ago I I experienced um
basically a three-week period where uh I
did not have it was kind of linked with
when I started to read this type of
material. You said what?
>> I had a 3-w week period or so
>> closer to the mic.
>> A 3W week to a month period where uh I
would literally not have any negative
emotion. It was a period where um
>> yeah,
>> you know, you would be driving down the
highway to work and and see a sunset or
a sunrise and and literally be
overwhelmed with tears
>> and then a month later
>> I like right now my current
understanding of everything in the books
is higher than it's ever been, but I
don't have that
feeling of uh
>> that it's almost like a a happy type
state.
>> I know what you mean. Now those states
come and go. See, because you let go of
a big you work your way through a big
stack. Now you go into your you're above
your karma. So now you go into a state
of like, you know, semi bliss or
euphoria, happiness, etc. Now
you've earned the right to handle the
next big stack that comes up. See, from
this level, you're entitled to handle
this. From this hand title, you're
entitled to Don't forget how far down in
hell I went. Okay.
>> How far down in hell I went to uh
unearth that which was blocking uh that
which was most extremely high. So don't
don't you're just rising above your
karma. You you'll see the Christian
saints say I forget the names of all the
saints will tell you uh how they went
from belated states to states of
despair. Oh my beloved, how could you
have deserted me? uh states of great
anguish. See?
>> Okay.
>> And don't worry about the states of
great anguish. Just surrender the
anguish itself to God and constantly
surrender all of it. See, don't resist
the anguish if it should come up because
if you're serious, it very likely will
come up again.
>> I never knew anybody just went into a
state of happiness and stayed there all
the way to enlightenment. See,
>> the the Buddha was the Buddha was beset
by demons. Jesus Christ sweat blood in
the garden of Gethsemane. So there's
anguish along the way.
>> Thank you Dr. H.
picture
>> picture
>> I don't like to say that because it
sounds like a program like
but that experientially is what goes on
and you say this this too I'm willing to
go through oh lord whatever this anguish
may mean or whatever it's signified
oh gosh that's okay
>> thank you so much
>> yes I'd like to Thank the creator for
this moment manifested through you. Uh
my question
>> you got to come close to the mic.
>> Yeah, he can't hear you.
>> Sorry. I just like to thank
>> Yes.
>> our creator for this moment manifested
through you right now.
>> Yes.
>> And
I've done a calibration of uh myself, my
wife, and my two 11-year-old twin boys,
and we currently are at 540.
Uh my question to you is
to go to the next level 600. Do you have
any advice other than what's in your
book? Do I have a
>> whatever you're doing just keep doing
it.
>> Do I have a responsibility to my
children to
>> No, become all that you can become. And
uh you see because you go from love to
conditional love, then you move to
unconditional love. Uh beyond that uh
the states beyond 540 around 570 are
states of Sandwood
uh field etc. Also when you get over 540
you get into 570 around in there uh the
so-called cities the paranormal the
miraculous phenomena begin to occur
u spontaneously of their own that which
you hold in mind manifests right in
front of your eyes. So the miraculous
tends to occur. Uh there's a whole
section I wrote in one of the books
about the cities
and um they can be quite a they can well
no they're not a distraction they're a
delight but uh after that then come
states of uh joy which you find may find
it hard to function. uh states of
ecstasy,
states of extremism, joy and ecstasy in
which it's very hard to function also.
Then when you realize this ecstasy too
must be surrendered to the old lord uh
this the ecstasy disappears
and in place of the ecstasy
uh is an infinite peace and stillness.
Seth Chiran Landanda calibrates at 600
and at that point a state of infinite
bliss and serenity and peace and you may
or may not stay in the world because you
have the option to leave.
>> Is that karmatic or my choice?
>> It's not anybody's any person like you
there. it. Yeah.
>> And in terms of doing this in my house,
do I need to leave my house, leave my
children to achieve?
>> No, you just have to follow however your
inspiration goes. It may sometimes
result in that.
>> Yeah, I have before. I just
there's no way of predicting what the
world's response will be.
>> So, it is what it is. Okay.
>> I thank you.
Thank you.
>> Mhm.
>> Hello.
>> Yes.
>> I just wanted to say thank you for
everything.
>> Well, I thank you for your thanks.
>> Thank you.
>> Now, you got to thank me for my thanking
your thank you.
>> [laughter]
>> Yes.
>> Hello. I just I just wanted to come up
here and say hello. [laughter]
>> That's great.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> It's a wonderful group we have here
today. They m They're sort of magical.
>> A great group, I'll tell you.
What do you got in there? Peanut butter
sandwiches for
[laughter]
>> Did you want that?
>> No, I don't want a peanut butter
sandwich.
>> I have a small gift for you in
appreciation, Susan.
>> Yes.
>> And uh something for you also.
>> Ah, thank you so much.
>> Indian
buds.
>> Put this with her. Thanks.
>> Thank you.
>> And I have a
question. I have two in fact.
And this is an individuated question
applying to myself. Uh what importance
does the treatment of form the body hold
in the face of a devoted practice to
non-duality.
Um a little over a year ago a healer by
the name of Dr. Robert Fry has been
treating me through nutrients. And my
intention was and still is to help the
body keep aligned with some uh condalini
creas which were quite violent
>> to keep the what
>> the condalini
>> you got to speak slow to get the
>> keep the condalini ka
>> you want to control the condundalini
energy
>> yeah there were too many kas you know I
just couldn't meditate there's ancient
traditions to do that I don't recommend
it but nevertheless yeah
>> but through a friend I got to know that
this u chiropractor and healer was would
be able to do it by nutrients
>> do what by nutrients
>> help in the not control but facilitate
the
>> facilitate the condundolini
>> yeah not not to make it move but to to
uh ease the creas
>> ease the creas you know the
>> clear the blockages flow of the
condalini energy
>> uh like
>> just stand right here
>> well that sounds like a good intention
My question to you um
>> that's certain kinds of yoga. Yes,
certain kind of kinds of yoga.
>> Uh
>> yeah,
>> the question is um would would it help
to continue in this line of treatment?
>> Would it help?
>> What do you call treatment?
>> He uh No, I'm not sick.
He just gives me nutrients. He
prescribes nutrients for me.
>> Supplements. Yeah.
>> Oh, no. That's just a nice thing to do
anyway, you know.
>> It won't It won't get you to
>> So, do I need the nice thing? Do I need
Do I
>> need the nice thing? We got to ask if
she needs that nice thing.
>> We got to ask if she needs the nutrients
or whatever the vitam
she is needful of these nutrients
resistant.
Yes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> So, it's okay. It isn't hurting you at
all. Okay. I'm sorry.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you. I have another small
question.
>> You see, everything is physical, mental,
and spiritual. So, it's it's fine to to
approach things from all three
simultaneously.
>> In fact, that's the reason why I took
this treatment because I saw your in
your DVD that you had mentioned that it
must be holistic it and we can treat it
bodily also.
>> Everything's physical, mental and
spiritual. So you do what you can on all
on all scores. Yes.
>> Thank you. Uh now in the Hindu tradition
which I'm sure you're aware of um the
spiritual seeker bends his head down in
>> and and touches the feet of the
spiritual teacher.
>> Yes.
>> Um I wish to do that with you. And
normally the spiritual teacher touches
the head of the seeker.
>> Right. So may I request you please to
>> she's going to touch your feet and she
wants you to touch the top of her head.
>> Oh that's a tradition. Yes.
>> I have permission to do that uh in the
present circumstances. Resist.
>> Yes. Acknowledging the self within both
of us you know.
>> Thank you.
>> It's not acknowledging the personality
of the teacher. It's acknowledging the
divinity.
>> Yeah. And your teachings which have
helped me so much.
>> I pray to to you
for the same reason.
Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> So we pray
for each other.
>> Thank you.
[applause]
>> Look in your eyes.
>> That's of India
>> and Hinduism
>> and
>> this the course
>> one acknowledges the presence of
divinity within the teacher. It's not
the teacher personality personally
just as we do in Korea.
We recognize the divinity within within
each other.
>> I would like to thank you for being such
a powerful influence in my life.
>> I am glad it's useful to you. Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> My prayer is to be thy servant, the
servant of thy soul and the devotion of
thy soul. Amen.
Can you transmit no mind to me?
>> Can you transmit no mind to her?
>> I already did. [laughter]
>> It's automatic.
That's the purpose of being in the
presence of the teacher. It's your aura
already picks it up. Let's see if this
you're already aura already picked up.
She she already picked up the guru. The
radiance of the guru, the grease of the
guru. It was just it was already picked
up. Yes.
>> Otherwise, I wouldn't let you touch my
feet.
>> I love you. [laughter]
>> Thank you.
>> Each teacher has his own style.
>> Yeah. And I visited a number you know
and one I got the biggest kick out of
was uh
>> Mkananda you know and Makananda after
you met him and he you know he ought to
gave you his car his energy I would
touch you with a peacock feather
[laughter]
>> and then he would wear an orange knit
cap and periodically during the lecture
he would take his cap off and throw it
out in the audience and they would all
everybody would rush to grab it you know
because it had his energy in it you know
but he would have a whole pile of orange
hats By the end of lecture, [laughter]
you throw them everywhere.
Oh, yeah. So, if I had an orange hat to
give you, I'll give you one.
>> Thank you so much.
>> My books are done.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Thank you.
>> I took care of it.
>> Each culture has its own unique beauty
and styles.
Each one is charming in its own. Each
one is charming.
>> I've been charmed by the spiritual
practices of all the cultures.
[clears throat]
>> Mhm.
>> Yes.
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes. The other evening he had advised me
to um pray to God
to um have a real deep understanding of
the perfection and beauty in everything.
>> What did she say?
>> She said you advised her um last
Wednesday
>> to pray to God.
>> To pray to God.
>> Yes.
>> To have a deeper and complete
understanding
of the perfection and beauty in
everything.
And what I would like to ask you today
is if you could um
>> you have to keep it short.
>> Teach me a little bit more about prayer.
>> It's too long. I can't. What are you
saying?
>> She wants you to teach her a little bit
more about
>> prayer.
>> About prayer.
>> Yeah.
>> And if it might be possible, if you
think it's in the highest good.
>> Well, um yes, because
prayer is a form of supplication.
uh prayer itself calibrates quite high
because it's a statement of declaration
of intention
as well as an intreaty. Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> I think the prayer of St. Francis of
Aisi pretty much sums it all up and the
91st psalm sums it all up. So all you
need is one prayer and one psalm. You
can go the whole way on that.
>> You would
>> you only need one canoe. You don't need
42 canoes to get across the river.
You don't have to change canoes every 20
ft. You know,
one spiritually inspired teaching.
Lord, let me be a servant, thy servant.
Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> 91st Psalm. Those who place their faith
in me are mine.
Krishna said the same thing. Those who
devote themselves to me are mine
and I will own them as mine.
>> Thank you.
>> That's one of the greatest declarations.
You don't have to hear any more than
that.
>> Jesus said those who believe in my name.
I will speak for them to the father in
heaven.
>> If it's
>> so you don't need much more than all of
that. You know,
>> I have [clears throat] a request if it's
if it's for the highest good of
everybody. Could we ask you to lead us
in prayer later?
>> They want you to lead them. Would it be
for the highest good to meet him in
prayer later? He usually does that at
the end.
>> That would be lovely.
>> Thank you.
>> At the very end after everybody's gone
or after everyone's done, he does that.
>> Everyone is blessed by the intention of
their being here. Forget the teacher.
These are these are these are bladders
for him for pens.
>> Oldfashioned ones.
>> He found oldfashioned bladders for you.
>> No. No. [laughter]
>> No such thing.
>> Yes.
>> My god he did. The calendar's from 1940.
So don't use that.
>> That's amazing.
>> Oh, thank you that he's been wanting
one.
>> That's funny how people remember some of
the remark I
>> Yeah.
>> Um I just had a a
Maybe a dualistic conundrum question
come up from the slide that talked about
universality of truth
>> regard regardless of time and culture.
>> Oh yes. Yes.
>> But then I thought that um a statement
can be true in one time or culture and
then be totally false in another.
So I was a little confused at how
>> No, it really can't. That's a
misperception.
Uh
Maybe
>> let's say if I divinity is the source of
all existence
not as a consequence of causality
but because God is not a cause but a
source. Now that's true in all cultures
in all times throughout all millennia.
God is not the cause of existence. He's
the source. Yeah. Yeah. Because the
source is everlasting. The cause would
have a beginning and an end. And the
the source is forever there and it's
within you
as the self with the capital S. The
source is within you. Otherwise, you
wouldn't have life.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you. And thank you for the
>> Oh, you're welcome.
>> I understand what you mean though, but
that would be provisional truth and it
would be linear. Yeah.
>> A linear truth see
>> within a different context. A linear
context can change.
>> Yeah. Yeah. But uh universal truth is
not dependent on on uh circumstances.
>> Uhhuh.
The alternate would be facts. Now facts
are not the same thing as truth. Fact a
fact is one thing. Truth signifies
meaning, significance and inference.
Hi,
>> I was curious as to how the calibration
levels can vary from day to day, same
person or year to year. How do they
change?
>> Calibration levels are constantly
fluctuating
uh of individuals because every moment
your mind is choosing
uh changing, agreeing with, disagreeing
with
uh your mind is constantly changing. So,
if you could do it on a
uh electronic equipment, you know, you'd
see it's it's it's a jittering loose and
then you make a bad mistake. Boing.
[laughter]
Then you forgive forgive them even
though they don't deserve forgiving and
you go up a little bit. Then you decide,
but if I'm honest with my self, I'll
face the fact I hate them. Now you
figure you just admitted hate. You
should go down. No, you were just honest
with yourself and you just came up. I
admit that I hate that person and I ask
Almighty God to change the way I'm
perceiving them. So I see them
differently in a different light. And
when you do that, you see the intrinsic
innocence of all the intrinsic innocence
of all beings who may be acting out in a
way that the world would call evil. But
you see that they cannot help being that
which they are at the moment they're
being that they really can't be any
other way because if they could they
would. Everybody is exactly what they
are because that's the only way they can
be at that moment. And if we had the
option of being other than that which we
are you could see how that would negate
any question in the first place.
>> Thank you.
>> Sign where
I can't see where it is. Okay.
>> Put your hand.
>> This pen is a very bubble pen. I don't
know.
>> I know.
>> Mhm.
>> I think I switch on you. [clears throat]
>> Yes.
>> Hi. I'm very happy to be here and it's
very nice to meet you.
And my question is,
how can I um or what's the best way to
learn to do the kinesiology and muscle
testing? Do you need a partner to do it
with?
>> There's a number of ways to do it. See,
we could give a short lecture on that.
There's the O-ring technique. I hold uh
uh Abraham Lincoln and I go like that
and I try to break this. Now I hold uh
someone evil um serial killer. I hold
bit of louden in mind and I go like this
and it breaks easily. Yeah.
>> Okay. So you can do it on your own. You
need to have someone.
>> There's other ways you simpler ways you
do it. Take a stack of books. Take a
stack of books at this level here and
you think of Jesus Christ and you lift
it. See? See how much?
Then you picture Adolf Hitler and you
lift it and you see it's much the books
are much heavier with Adolf Hitler than
the way they are with Jesus. So then
there's other people who have learned to
use their body as a pendulum where you
move.
>> There are people that will fall forward
with the truth and fall backward with
falsehood.
>> Okay.
>> So many people have learned various
systems, you know, various systems and
techniques that work for them.
>> And what about a pendulum?
>> You should get the same results with a
pendulum. The other thing I'll tell you
about a pendulum is don't start
investigating and calibrating negatives.
Don't don't calibrate binom with a
pendulum. Okay.
>> Okay. Thank you. And
>> don't investigate the negatives with a
pendulum.
>> Okay.
>> So just ask in the highest
>> the pendulum will get contaminated.
You'll get false answers from in because
these are all powerful energies. You're
not just fooling with uh idol.
>> Thank you. I'd like to get a picture of
you with my
>> You could say, you know, this is over
200. See?
>> Mhm.
>> But you don't want to know. In other
words, I would I would avoid that which
is obviously uh negative.
>> Okay.
>> But people get the same results.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> Mhm.
Smile.
>> Okay. Look at the Look at
>> smile.
He's trying to control me, isn't he?
I hate people who try to control me.
But I forgive.
>> Yeah.
We couldn't operate without Robert. I'll
tell you that.
>> I'd like to ask for a blessing.
>> Yes.
>> There's a program that provides
employment for developmentally disabled
adults at the Lawrence Liver at
[clears throat] the Lawrence Livermore
National Laboratory. And I'd like a
blessing for the program and the lives
of all the people that are affected by
it.
>> Livermore.
>> Uh the Lawrence Livermore National
Laboratory.
>> Lawrence Livermore National.
>> Where is that? in Liverour, California.
>> Okay, let's see if we have that. Uh, we
have permission to do that.
>> Let's see. We have permission to do
that.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Sometimes we could know. We don't know
why.
>> Then we have to
>> We'd have to research to find out the
reason for it. Okay. And the other
question is, would you be my teacher?
>> Uh, the teacher is up to the student.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Let's see. And then the teacher is
obligated, you know. Mhm. Okay. Good. So
if you choose uh this way then I've
become automatically by your consent.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> The Buddha can't do anything about it.
If I decide the Buddha is my teacher, he
can't he can't do anything about it, can
he? [laughter]
Yeah. See, it would take five minutes of
questioning to find out where why we
weren't allowed it. Maybe because it's
setting a precedent or, you know, a
pattern or you don't know the reason
why.
>> We could check it out, though.
>> Um, my question is about my
seven-year-old grandson
who had was born with microia.
>> Who has what?
>> Microchia.
>> He has only one ear that he hears out of
>> and and uh he also has some autism. Yes.
>> And Asberger syndrome and
>> oh boy
>> hyperactivity.
>> Oh my goodness. But he is very
intelligent and um
>> I just want to know how to handle him
when he needs discipline
and he reacts a lot of the time by
um crying and throwing things and
hitting and frustrated
>> and it's uh I know he's frustrated but
it all I don't know how to handle it.
>> You what's your relationship to him?
>> Grandson. He's I'm his grandmother.
>> Yes. Does he live with you?
>> No, but I see him very frequently.
>> Oh, yeah. Everything's physical, mental,
and spiritual. So, you pray about the
matter. You get whatever psychological
help you can for it, and you use
whatever psychopharmacologic
u uh cures might be out there and
they're developing all the time, of
course, and neurologic research on these
uh on these conditions is quite intense.
So they keep coming up with new
information about the neurohysiology of
it and there'll be
psychopharmarmacology.
There's already psychopharmarmacology
that's quite helpful but I'm sure
they'll become even better things.
>> He's not on any medications.
>> Well, that that's peculiar right there.
>> Oh, really? Okay.
>> I just said everything's physical,
mental, and spiritual. And there are
many far psychopharmarmacological
uh things that are helpful for all three
of the conditions.
>> Okay?
>> And I've treated many myself. There's,
you know, asparagus syndrome, there's
autism,
uh ADHD, there's there's a whole
spectrum of they're mainly neurologic.
See, and because they're neurologic,
they they're also biochemical. A lot of
them can be ameliorated.
Well, you want to emilate it for a
number of conditions. Not just to
improve their performance, but for their
own sake because if they can control
their own behavior better, they they
they get less negativity from their
environment and they get greater
self-confidence. So, I would help them
pharmacologically as well.
[clears throat]
>> Okay. Can I ask one more thing? You you
talk about over 200 integrous people or
etheric brain is the right their right
brain. No, they're two different things.
They they operate neur neurologically
via the right brain instead of the left
brain. Uh the other thing I forgot to
mention is at level 200 the condundolini
energy rises and you form an atheric
brain.
>> Right?
>> All right. Before below 200 people do
not have an atheric body. Would you
believe that? It's a fact.
>> Right?
>> They do not. And they have a group karma
like the animals do. Over 200 you have
an individual karma. And there's the
formation of the atheric body and the
atheric brain. So
what happens with a spiritual oriented
person is the perception goes right
through is processed by the atheric
brain by the atheric prefrontal cortex
because at about level I forget what
level the level I'm thinking about is
600. Yes, at about 600 the beginning of
the the third eye of the Buddha body you
begin to see essence. You see past
appearance and you begin to pick up
essence.
>> Okay. So whether you're right-handed or
left-handed has nothing to do with this.
>> No. Well, you would have to make it the
opposite in a left-handed person.
>> That's what I've wondered.
>> Dominant versus non-dominant. Yeah.
>> Like a picture.
Now I believe you should help people uh
physical, mental and spiritual because
uh
>> you might say psychopharmarmacology is
also a gift from God. Is it not?
>> The relief of pain and suffering and
disability is a gift. Is it not?
Leave no stone unturned.
>> Yes.
>> What is the best way? That's
>> I'm good. All right. Good. What is the
best way to concept um transcend do
what am I I wrote it down here.
Causality in in trying to surrender
everything to God. Love with all my
heart. What is the best way to transcend
the concept of causality? I still get
stuck in
>> Yes. All right. Because the linear
domain predominates in our society and
especially scientific mindedness.
Um and the mind thinks in terms of
causality.
It also projects time out there. There
isn't any time in the universe. Uh nor
is their position. All these are
conceptual projected onto the world.
Uh what was it you asked me?
>> Transcend causality.
>> Oh, transcending causality. Yes. Well,
we can start out through the intellect.
That which has existed forever obviously
has no beginning.
Right.
>> Right.
>> If if it has no end, it has no
beginning.
So it cannot be subject to cause. Cause
would be subject to the linear world
only of circum. So you could
circumscribe. This is uh cause and this
is effect. You see that's a
mentalization.
The way things come happen is they
is they manifest out of potentiality.
Um Sheldrick had um concept of formative
causation.
Uh Sheldrick a very brilliant guy and uh
formative causation and it's somewhat
represented by the Heisenberg principle.
It's also represented by that which you
hold and mind tends to manifest.
Uh because the nonlinear
then is a vision. You hold the vision
and that tends to materialize. You would
not be able to figure out any way to
make that happen within the world but
via causality.
Uh so the last number of places I've
lived in, I only I pictured what I
wanted ideally. Uh, I just pictured it
and the next thing you know somebody
call up and say, "Hey, the place next
door to me is for sale right in the
middle of the woods, right on the creek
and etc." I said, "What do you know
about that?" So, [laughter]
the place I had back east was also
idyllic and I just pictured, you know,
deserted woods and all and build a house
in the middle of 100 acres of woods. So,
um, let me see if if there's a better
way I can show you how it is. Um
um
the nonlinear you might say is like a
picture and then this picture tends to
manifest tends to emerge. So things
don't happen by causality but by
emergence.
So the potentiality for this hand to
move here actualizes when local
conditions are appropriate such as my
saying yes to it. uh and but then it
moves on from there to there. So the
unfolding of the hand is the opening of
a potentiality.
Think of it more like emerges. Think it
like a like a crystis and the and and
the pupa there emerges. It has the
potentiality becoming a butterfly, but
nothing is causing anything. It can only
fulfill its potentiality when local
conditions are favorable. If they're not
favorable, it will collapse. And
karmically was never destined to man to
manifest.
Uh it's a more of a meditative thing.
You're contemplative. You're walking
around, you begin to notice that
everything is happening of its own.
Nothing is causing anything at all in
the universe. That's a limiting concept.
Okay.
>> In our society, it's hard to transcend
because of science and you know,
accountability and all such you know.
Thank you very much.
>> But you can get beyond it.
>> Okay.
>> If you you know why? Why? Why can you
get beyond it?
>> Prayer and intention.
>> Because that's your potentiality.
If your intention is to transcend it,
then you're obviously going to transcend
it.
>> Or you wouldn't be asking the question.
That's guaranteed that he's going to
transcend causality. Everybody in favor?
>> [applause]
>> He's going to do it for all of us.
[music]
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
[music]
Halle.
Hallelujah.
[music]