[music]
So
heal.
heal. [music]
>> [music]
>> Hello.
>> Good
>> Good morning.
>> Hello.
>> Good morning. Good
>> Good morning. Good morning.
>> I'll
>> I'll be
>> I'll be around
>> I'll be around there.
I'll
I'll be
>> I'll be around there.
I'll be around.
Good
Good morning.
Good morning. Good
Good morning. Good morning.
Good morning. Good morning. Good
Good morning. Good morning. Good morning
everyone.
>> Good
>> Good morning
>> Good morning everyone.
Good
Good morning.
>> Good
>> Good morning.
Good
Good morning.
>> Good
>> Good morning.
It's
It's so
>> Good morning.
It's so nice
It's so nice to
>> Good morning.
It's so nice to see
It's so nice to see you.
>> Good
>> Good morning
>> Good morning everyone.
>> Hello
>> Hello doctor.
>> Good morning everyone.
>> Hello doctor. Listen
>> Hello doctor. Listen to
>> Good morning everyone.
>> Hello doctor. Listen to me.
>> Good
>> Good morning,
>> Good morning, Mrs.
>> Good morning, Mrs. Sarah.
>> Wendy
>> Wendy D
>> Good morning, Mrs. Sarah.
>> Wendy D Merritt.
[laughter]
[music]
>> Hello.
>> Hello. How
>> Hello. How are
>> Hello.
>> Hello. How are you?
>> [music]
>> Good
>> Good morning.
I'm
I'm going
I'm going to
I'm going to be
I'm going to be around
I'm going to be around here
I'm going to be around here this
I'm going to be around here this side.
We're
We're going
I'm going to be around here this side.
We're going to
We're going to go
I'm going to be around here this side.
We're going to go around
We're going to go around this
I'm going to be around here this side.
We're going to go around this side.
We're going to go around this side. This
side.
>> Yeah.
>> Well,
>> Well, you're
>> Well, you're back.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. I
>> Well, you're back.
>> Yes. I was
>> Yes. I was afraid
>> Well, you're back.
>> Yes. I was afraid I
>> Yes. I was afraid I wouldn't.
>> Good
>> Good God.
>> Good God. I
>> Good God. I was
>> Good God. I was in
>> Good God. I was in a
>> Good God. I was in a coffee
>> Good God. I was in a coffee panic.
Okay.
>> All
>> All right.
>> All right. Worried
>> All right. Worried about
>> All right. Worried about coffee
>> All right. Worried about coffee in
>> All right. Worried about coffee in here.
>> Ms.
>> Ms. Combo
>> All right. Worried about coffee in here.
>> Ms. Combo at
>> Ms. Combo at home.
>> Isn't
>> Isn't that
>> Isn't that marvelous?
>> Good
>> Good morning.
>> Uh,
>> Uh, just
>> Uh, just a
>> Uh, just a few
>> Uh, just a few announcements
>> Uh, just a few announcements before
>> Uh, just a few announcements before we
begin.
begin. Um,
>> Uh, just a few announcements before we
begin. Um, please
begin. Um, please make
>> Uh, just a few announcements before we
begin. Um, please make sure
begin. Um, please make sure your
>> Uh, just a few announcements before we
begin. Um, please make sure your cell
phones
phones are
phones are off
phones are off and
phones are off and no
phones are off and no audio
phones are off and no audio or
phones are off and no audio or video
recording
recording at
phones are off and no audio or video
recording at any
recording at any time.
phones are off and no audio or video
recording at any time. And
recording at any time. And if
phones are off and no audio or video
recording at any time. And if you
recording at any time. And if you could
save
save your
save your picture
save your picture taking
save your picture taking um
save your picture taking um for
save your picture taking um for the
save your picture taking um for the Q&A
from
from 3:00
save your picture taking um for the Q&A
from 3:00 to
from 3:00 to 5:00
save your picture taking um for the Q&A
from 3:00 to 5:00 and
from 3:00 to 5:00 and oh
save your picture taking um for the Q&A
from 3:00 to 5:00 and oh please
from 3:00 to 5:00 and oh please only
save your picture taking um for the Q&A
from 3:00 to 5:00 and oh please only use
the
the front
the front entrance.
Don't
Don't use
the front entrance.
Don't use any
Don't use any of
the front entrance.
Don't use any of the
Don't use any of the side
the front entrance.
Don't use any of the side entrances
Don't use any of the side entrances and
the
the creative
the creative Sonic
the creative Sonic creative
the creative Sonic creative lesson
the creative Sonic creative lesson would
appreciate
appreciate that.
the creative Sonic creative lesson would
appreciate that. And
appreciate that. And hopefully
the creative Sonic creative lesson would
appreciate that. And hopefully you've
been
been watching
been watching our
been watching our little
been watching our little movie
been watching our little movie that
been watching our little movie that had
the
the schedule
been watching our little movie that had
the schedule and
the schedule and all
been watching our little movie that had
the schedule and all other
the schedule and all other kind
been watching our little movie that had
the schedule and all other kind of
details
details so
details so that
details so that um
details so that um we
details so that um we can
details so that um we can move
details so that um we can move ahead.
details so that um we can move ahead. Is
there
there anything
details so that um we can move ahead. Is
there anything else
there anything else since
details so that um we can move ahead. Is
there anything else since I
there anything else since I we've
details so that um we can move ahead. Is
there anything else since I we've lost?
We've
We've lost
We've lost the
We've lost the name.
>> Well,
>> Well, that
We've lost the name.
>> Well, that we
>> Well, that we went
We've lost the name.
>> Well, that we went through
>> Well, that we went through you.
We've lost the name.
>> Well, that we went through you. You
>> Well, that we went through you. You You
got
got Did
got Did you
got Did you Did
got Did you Did you
got Did you Did you ask
got Did you Did you ask Did
got Did you Did you ask Did anybody
got Did you Did you ask Did anybody read
the
show
show of
show of hands?
show of hands? Did
show of hands? Did anybody
show of hands? Did anybody not
show of hands? Did anybody not read
show of hands? Did anybody not read the
movie?
I
I told
I told you.
I told you. It
I told you. It is
I told you. It is my
I told you. It is my blessing
I told you. It is my blessing to
I told you. It is my blessing to welcome
the
the fabulous
I told you. It is my blessing to welcome
the fabulous and
the fabulous and wonderful
I told you. It is my blessing to welcome
the fabulous and wonderful Dr.
the fabulous and wonderful Dr. David
Hopkins.
Hopkins. [applause]
>> [applause]
[applause]
>> Gloria
>> Gloria Exosius.
That
That means
That means glory
That means glory to
That means glory to God
That means glory to God in
That means glory to God in the
That means glory to God in the highest.
If
If that
That means glory to God in the highest.
If that makes
If that makes you
That means glory to God in the highest.
If that makes you nervous,
If that makes you nervous, it's
That means glory to God in the highest.
If that makes you nervous, it's the
wrong
wrong lecture
wrong lecture to
wrong lecture to be
wrong lecture to be at.
First
First page
wrong lecture to be at.
First page of
First page of all
wrong lecture to be at.
First page of all the
First page of all the books
wrong lecture to be at.
First page of all the books gives
First page of all the books gives the
reader
reader warning.
[laughter]
If
If they
If they write
If they write complaints,
If they write complaints, I
If they write complaints, I say
If they write complaints, I say you
If they write complaints, I say you were
warned
warned on
If they write complaints, I say you were
warned on the
warned on the first
If they write complaints, I say you were
warned on the first page.
Well,
Well, today
Well, today we're
Well, today we're going
Well, today we're going to
Well, today we're going to um
Well, today we're going to um we
Well, today we're going to um we have
Well, today we're going to um we have a
lot
lot of
Well, today we're going to um we have a
lot of people
lot of people who
Well, today we're going to um we have a
lot of people who have
lot of people who have never
Well, today we're going to um we have a
lot of people who have never been
lot of people who have never been to
Well, today we're going to um we have a
lot of people who have never been to a
lecture
lecture before
lecture before and
lecture before and uh
lecture before and uh that's
lecture before and uh that's why
lecture before and uh that's why we
lecture before and uh that's why we put
this
this lecture
lecture before and uh that's why we put
this lecture on
this lecture on is
lecture before and uh that's why we put
this lecture on is because
this lecture on is because uh
lecture before and uh that's why we put
this lecture on is because uh when
this lecture on is because uh when we
put
put the
put the lectures
put the lectures on
put the lectures on very
put the lectures on very often
put the lectures on very often they're
sold
sold out
put the lectures on very often they're
sold out within
sold out within 24
put the lectures on very often they're
sold out within 24 hours
sold out within 24 hours for
put the lectures on very often they're
sold out within 24 hours for the
sold out within 24 hours for the year
put the lectures on very often they're
sold out within 24 hours for the year or
so.
so. Uh
so. Uh we
so. Uh we put
so. Uh we put uh
so. Uh we put uh a
so. Uh we put uh a special
so. Uh we put uh a special one
so. Uh we put uh a special one on
so. Uh we put uh a special one on for
people
people that
so. Uh we put uh a special one on for
people that couldn't
people that couldn't get
so. Uh we put uh a special one on for
people that couldn't get in
people that couldn't get in and
so. Uh we put uh a special one on for
people that couldn't get in and we'll
probably
probably continue
probably continue to
probably continue to do
probably continue to do that
probably continue to do that so
probably continue to do that so that
people
everyone
everyone can
everyone can get
everyone can get to
everyone can get to be
everyone can get to be here.
everyone can get to be here. Um
so
so today
everyone can get to be here. Um
so today uh
so today uh how
everyone can get to be here. Um
so today uh how many
so today uh how many people
everyone can get to be here. Um
so today uh how many people here
so today uh how many people here uh
everyone can get to be here. Um
so today uh how many people here uh are
new?
[laughter]
Thank
Thank you.
Thank you. All
Thank you. All right.
Usually
Usually we
Thank you. All right.
Usually we say
Usually we say how
Thank you. All right.
Usually we say how many
Usually we say how many are
Thank you. All right.
Usually we say how many are new
Usually we say how many are new so
Thank you. All right.
Usually we say how many are new so we
know
know whether
know whether to
know whether to go
know whether to go over
know whether to go over the
know whether to go over the basics
know whether to go over the basics or
not.
not. And
know whether to go over the basics or
not. And um
not. And um well
know whether to go over the basics or
not. And um well we're
not. And um well we're up
know whether to go over the basics or
not. And um well we're up to
not. And um well we're up to a
know whether to go over the basics or
not. And um well we're up to a hundred
slides
slides now.
So
So we'll
slides now.
So we'll probably
So we'll probably get
slides now.
So we'll probably get out
So we'll probably get out of
slides now.
So we'll probably get out of here
So we'll probably get out of here around
1 this
1 this morning.
But
But we're
1 this morning.
But we're going
But we're going to
1 this morning.
But we're going to at
But we're going to at least
1 this morning.
But we're going to at least cover
But we're going to at least cover the
gist
gist of
gist of things.
gist of things. And
gist of things. And eventually
gist of things. And eventually we're
going
going to
gist of things. And eventually we're
going to we're
going to we're going
gist of things. And eventually we're
going to we're going to
going to we're going to put
gist of things. And eventually we're
going to we're going to put together
going to we're going to put together an
index
index of
index of slides.
index of slides. A
index of slides. A book
index of slides. A book of
index of slides. A book of slide.
index of slides. A book of slide. The
book
book of
index of slides. A book of slide. The
book of slides.
book of slides. [laughter]
Book
Book of
Book of slides.
Book of slides. That
Book of slides. That sounds
Book of slides. That sounds good.
The
The book
Book of slides. That sounds good.
The book of
The book of phenomenal
Book of slides. That sounds good.
The book of phenomenal slides.
The book of phenomenal slides. How?
The
The book
The book of
The book of God's
The book of God's wonderful
The book of God's wonderful miraculous
light.
light. [laughter]
Anyway,
Anyway, my
Anyway, my obligation
Anyway, my obligation is
Anyway, my obligation is to
Anyway, my obligation is to share
Anyway, my obligation is to share with
the
the world
Anyway, my obligation is to share with
the world that
the world that which
Anyway, my obligation is to share with
the world that which I
the world that which I came
Anyway, my obligation is to share with
the world that which I came to
the world that which I came to realize
it
it came
it came out
it came out of
it came out of uh
it came out of uh the
it came out of uh the essence
it came out of uh the essence of
it came out of uh the essence of that
which
which we
it came out of uh the essence of that
which we are
which we are as
it came out of uh the essence of that
which we are as a
which we are as a knowingness
it came out of uh the essence of that
which we are as a knowingness when
which we are as a knowingness when the
mind
mind stopped
mind stopped talking
many
many years
mind stopped talking
many years ago
many years ago uh
mind stopped talking
many years ago uh after
many years ago uh after sort
mind stopped talking
many years ago uh after sort of
many years ago uh after sort of a
phenomenal
phenomenal inner
phenomenal inner experiences
phenomenal inner experiences is
phenomenal inner experiences is uh
phenomenal inner experiences is uh the
mind
mind became
phenomenal inner experiences is uh the
mind became silent
mind became silent and
phenomenal inner experiences is uh the
mind became silent and instead
mind became silent and instead there
phenomenal inner experiences is uh the
mind became silent and instead there was
an
an infinite
an infinite knowingness
in
in the
an infinite knowingness
in the prevalence
in the prevalence of
an infinite knowingness
in the prevalence of a
in the prevalence of a condition.
an infinite knowingness
in the prevalence of a condition. So
in the prevalence of a condition. So I
call
call it
call it a
call it a condition
a
a state
call it a condition
a state a
a state a state
call it a condition
a state a state or
a state a state or a
call it a condition
a state a state or a condition
well
well in
well in which
well in which the
well in which the the
well in which the the personal
well in which the the personal self
well in which the the personal self is
no
no longer
well in which the the personal self is
no longer relevant
no longer relevant or
well in which the the personal self is
no longer relevant or of
no longer relevant or of any
well in which the the personal self is
no longer relevant or of any interest
and
and is
and is sort
and is sort of
and is sort of historical
and is sort of historical historical
phenomena
phenomena rather
and is sort of historical historical
phenomena rather than
phenomena rather than a
and is sort of historical historical
phenomena rather than a current
phenomena rather than a current reality.
Therefore,
in
in as
Therefore,
in as much
in as much as
Therefore,
in as much as there's
in as much as there's no
Therefore,
in as much as there's no person
in as much as there's no person speaking
to
to you,
you'll
you'll be
to you,
you'll be tolerant
you'll be tolerant of
to you,
you'll be tolerant of uh
you'll be tolerant of uh the
to you,
you'll be tolerant of uh the way
you'll be tolerant of uh the way I
to you,
you'll be tolerant of uh the way I l
you'll be tolerant of uh the way I l the
things
things are
things are languaged.
All
All right.
things are languaged.
All right. So
All right. So this
things are languaged.
All right. So this phenomena
All right. So this phenomena occurred
and
and of
and of course
and of course I've
and of course I've shared
and of course I've shared it
and of course I've shared it in
and of course I've shared it in the
about
about the
and of course I've shared it in the
about the author
about the author section
and of course I've shared it in the
about the author section in
about the author section in the
and of course I've shared it in the
about the author section in the back
about the author section in the back of
the
the books
and
and that
the books
and that le
and that le led
the books
and that le led to
and that le led to leaving
the books
and that le led to leaving the
and that le led to leaving the world
the books
and that le led to leaving the world and
spending
spending some
spending some years
spending some years in
spending some years in silence
spending some years in silence and
meditation
meditation and
spending some years in silence and
meditation and then
I
I don't
I don't I
I don't I forget
I don't I forget how
I don't I forget how oh
I don't I forget how oh yes
I don't I forget how oh yes through
kinesiology
kinesiology then
I don't I forget how oh yes through
kinesiology then I
kinesiology then I uh
discovered
discovered a
discovered a phenomena
discovered a phenomena and
discovered a phenomena and that
phenomena
phenomena then
discovered a phenomena and that
phenomena then allowed
phenomena then allowed for
discovered a phenomena and that
phenomena then allowed for calibrating
the
the levels
the levels of
the levels of consciousness.
the levels of consciousness. Now
the
the phenomena
the levels of consciousness. Now
the phenomena is
the phenomena is innate
the levels of consciousness. Now
the phenomena is innate to
the phenomena is innate to uh
the levels of consciousness. Now
the phenomena is innate to uh life.
the phenomena is innate to uh life. Life
in
in order
in order to
in order to survive
in order to survive in
in order to survive in its
in order to survive in its earliest
in order to survive in its earliest form
the
the pro
in order to survive in its earliest form
the pro protozoa.
See
See the
See the animal
See the animal kingdom
See the animal kingdom has
See the animal kingdom has no
See the animal kingdom has no source
See the animal kingdom has no source of
energy
energy within
See the animal kingdom has no source of
energy within itself.
energy within itself. It
See the animal kingdom has no source of
energy within itself. It has
energy within itself. It has to
See the animal kingdom has no source of
energy within itself. It has to go
outside
outside of
outside of itself.
outside of itself. This
outside of itself. This is
outside of itself. This is very
fundamental.
fundamental. As
outside of itself. This is very
fundamental. As you
fundamental. As you see
outside of itself. This is very
fundamental. As you see the
fundamental. As you see the evolution
outside of itself. This is very
fundamental. As you see the evolution of
the
the ego
the ego starts
the ego starts let's
the ego starts let's say
the ego starts let's say with
the ego starts let's say with the
prozzoa
prozzoa or
the ego starts let's say with the
prozzoa or the
prozzoa or the amoeba.
And
And how
And how can
And how can it
And how can it tell
And how can it tell how
And how can it tell how can
And how can it tell how can it
And how can it tell how can it survive?
It
It doesn't
And how can it tell how can it survive?
It doesn't have
It doesn't have chlorophyll
And how can it tell how can it survive?
It doesn't have chlorophyll like
It doesn't have chlorophyll like a
And how can it tell how can it survive?
It doesn't have chlorophyll like a plant
that
that just
that just sits
that just sits in
that just sits in the
that just sits in the sun
that just sits in the sun and
that just sits in the sun and thrives.
that just sits in the sun and thrives. I
if
if it
that just sits in the sun and thrives. I
if it doesn't
if it doesn't get
that just sits in the sun and thrives. I
if it doesn't get energy
if it doesn't get energy from
that just sits in the sun and thrives. I
if it doesn't get energy from out
if it doesn't get energy from out there,
nutrition
nutrition out
nutrition out there,
nutrition out there, it
nutrition out there, it dies.
Consequently,
Consequently, one
nutrition out there, it dies.
Consequently, one principle
Consequently, one principle of
nutrition out there, it dies.
Consequently, one principle of life
Consequently, one principle of life is
you
you have
you have to
you have to be
you have to be able
you have to be able to
you have to be able to sample
you have to be able to sample what's
you have to be able to sample what's out
there
there and
you have to be able to sample what's out
there and recognize
there and recognize it
you have to be able to sample what's out
there and recognize it for
there and recognize it for what
you have to be able to sample what's out
there and recognize it for what it
there and recognize it for what it is.
And
And if
And if you
And if you make
And if you make a
And if you make a mistake,
And if you make a mistake, you
And if you make a mistake, you don't
survive.
survive. So
And if you make a mistake, you don't
survive. So the
survive. So the organisms
And if you make a mistake, you don't
survive. So the organisms still
survive. So the organisms still alive
And if you make a mistake, you don't
survive. So the organisms still alive in
the
the animal
the animal kingdom
the animal kingdom are
the animal kingdom are have
the animal kingdom are have a
the animal kingdom are have a basic
intelligence
intelligence that
the animal kingdom are have a basic
intelligence that they've
intelligence that they've learned
the animal kingdom are have a basic
intelligence that they've learned what
is
is beneficial
is beneficial to
is beneficial to life
is beneficial to life and
is beneficial to life and they've
avoided
avoided that
is beneficial to life and they've
avoided that which
avoided that which will
is beneficial to life and they've
avoided that which will poison
avoided that which will poison you.
So
So that
So that innate
So that innate quality
So that innate quality to
So that innate quality to discern
So that innate quality to discern is
So that innate quality to discern is the
discernment
discernment of
So that innate quality to discern is the
discernment of essence.
discernment of essence. Essence.
So that innate quality to discern is the
discernment of essence. Essence. If
discernment of essence. Essence. If you
make
make the
make the mistake
make the mistake and
make the mistake and eat
make the mistake and eat the
make the mistake and eat the wrong
looking
looking flower,
make the mistake and eat the wrong
looking flower, you
looking flower, you die.
Mankind
Mankind learned
Mankind learned that.
Mankind learned that. You
Mankind learned that. You eat
Mankind learned that. You eat the
Mankind learned that. You eat the wrong
kind
kind of
Mankind learned that. You eat the wrong
kind of mushrooms,
kind of mushrooms, you're
Mankind learned that. You eat the wrong
kind of mushrooms, you're dead.
So
So even
So even man
So even man had
So even man had to
So even man had to learn.
Uh
Uh so
So even man had to learn.
Uh so the
Uh so the value
So even man had to learn.
Uh so the value of
Uh so the value of the
So even man had to learn.
Uh so the value of the kinesiologic
testing
testing was
testing was that
testing was that we
testing was that we discovered
testing was that we discovered that
testing was that we discovered that the
response
response is
testing was that we discovered that the
response is to
response is to the
testing was that we discovered that the
response is to the essence
response is to the essence and
testing was that we discovered that the
response is to the essence and not
response is to the essence and not to
the
the appearance.
Mankind's
Mankind's dilemma
the appearance.
Mankind's dilemma throughout
Mankind's dilemma throughout all
the appearance.
Mankind's dilemma throughout all of
Mankind's dilemma throughout all of time
is
is he's
is he's been
is he's been unable
is he's been unable to
is he's been unable to discern
is he's been unable to discern essence
from
from appearance.
is he's been unable to discern essence
from appearance. And
from appearance. And it
is he's been unable to discern essence
from appearance. And it isn't
from appearance. And it isn't until
is he's been unable to discern essence
from appearance. And it isn't until the
opening
opening of
opening of the
opening of the third
opening of the third eye
opening of the third eye of
opening of the third eye of the
opening of the third eye of the Buddha
body
body consciousness
opening of the third eye of the Buddha
body consciousness level
body consciousness level 600
opening of the third eye of the Buddha
body consciousness level 600 or
body consciousness level 600 or up
that
that the
that the human
that the human has
that the human has the
that the human has the capacity
that the human has the capacity to
that the human has the capacity to look
at
at a
that the human has the capacity to look
at a thing
at a thing and
that the human has the capacity to look
at a thing and tell
at a thing and tell what
that the human has the capacity to look
at a thing and tell what is
at a thing and tell what is it
that the human has the capacity to look
at a thing and tell what is it is
at a thing and tell what is it is it
that the human has the capacity to look
at a thing and tell what is it is it uh
a
a Trojan
a Trojan horse
a Trojan horse or
a Trojan horse or or
a Trojan horse or or is
a Trojan horse or or is it
a Trojan horse or or is it a
a Trojan horse or or is it a piece
a Trojan horse or or is it a piece peace
[laughter]
that
that a
that a peace
that a peace parade
that a peace parade or
that a peace parade or are
that a peace parade or are they
that a peace parade or are they all
carrying
carrying bombs?
that a peace parade or are they all
carrying bombs? You
carrying bombs? You know
that a peace parade or are they all
carrying bombs? You know what
carrying bombs? You know what I
that a peace parade or are they all
carrying bombs? You know what I mean?
Well,
Well, we
Well, we can
Well, we can tell
Well, we can tell but
Well, we can tell but the
Well, we can tell but the world
Well, we can tell but the world can't
tell
tell as
Well, we can tell but the world can't
tell as you
tell as you can
Well, we can tell but the world can't
tell as you can see
tell as you can see by
Well, we can tell but the world can't
tell as you can see by the
tell as you can see by the daily
Well, we can tell but the world can't
tell as you can see by the daily news.
[laughter]
The
The way
[laughter]
The way I'd
The way I'd screen
[laughter]
The way I'd screen him
The way I'd screen him is
[laughter]
The way I'd screen him is Sus
The way I'd screen him is Sus and
[laughter]
The way I'd screen him is Sus and I'd
just
just go,
just go, "Okay,
just go, "Okay, he's
just go, "Okay, he's okay."
just go, "Okay, he's okay." He's
just go, "Okay, he's okay." He's not
okay.
okay. Take
just go, "Okay, he's okay." He's not
okay. Take about
okay. Take about 8
just go, "Okay, he's okay." He's not
okay. Take about 8 seconds
okay. Take about 8 seconds to
just go, "Okay, he's okay." He's not
okay. Take about 8 seconds to tell
okay. Take about 8 seconds to tell you
[laughter]
who's
who's safe
[laughter]
who's safe and
who's safe and who's
[laughter]
who's safe and who's not
who's safe and who's not safe.
[laughter]
who's safe and who's not safe. You
who's safe and who's not safe. You know
what
what I'm
what I'm saying?
what I'm saying? All
what I'm saying? All right.
what I'm saying? All right. So,
out
out of
what I'm saying? All right. So,
out of this
out of this rose,
what I'm saying? All right. So,
out of this rose, a
out of this rose, a calibrated
what I'm saying? All right. So,
out of this rose, a calibrated map
out of this rose, a calibrated map of
consciousness,
consciousness, a
consciousness, a logarithmic
consciousness, a logarithmic scale
consciousness, a logarithmic scale 1
consciousness, a logarithmic scale 1 to
a,000.
Yeah.
Yeah. Which
Yeah. Which includes
Yeah. Which includes all
Yeah. Which includes all possibility
within
within this
Yeah. Which includes all possibility
within this domain.
Um
Um 1,00
Um 1,00 is
Um 1,00 is the
Um 1,00 is the level
Um 1,00 is the level of
Um 1,00 is the level of the
Um 1,00 is the level of the great
avatars
avatars Jesus
Um 1,00 is the level of the great
avatars Jesus Christ,
avatars Jesus Christ, Buddha,
Um 1,00 is the level of the great
avatars Jesus Christ, Buddha, Krishna,
Zuraster.
It's
It's as
Zuraster.
It's as high
It's as high as
Zuraster.
It's as high as you
It's as high as you can
Zuraster.
It's as high as you can go
It's as high as you can go in
Zuraster.
It's as high as you can go in this
It's as high as you can go in this do
Zuraster.
It's as high as you can go in this do in
this
this domain.
this domain. Why?
this domain. Why? Because
this domain. Why? Because human
protoplasm
protoplasm can't
this domain. Why? Because human
protoplasm can't handle
protoplasm can't handle energies
this domain. Why? Because human
protoplasm can't handle energies uh
beyond
beyond that.
beyond that. In
beyond that. In fact,
beyond that. In fact, uh
beyond that. In fact, uh from
beyond that. In fact, uh from about
beyond that. In fact, uh from about 800
up,
up, it's
beyond that. In fact, uh from about 800
up, it's very
up, it's very difficult
beyond that. In fact, uh from about 800
up, it's very difficult to
up, it's very difficult to handle
beyond that. In fact, uh from about 800
up, it's very difficult to handle the
for
for the
for the nervous
for the nervous system
for the nervous system to
for the nervous system to handle
for the nervous system to handle that
kind
kind of
for the nervous system to handle that
kind of energy.
kind of energy. Gets
for the nervous system to handle that
kind of energy. Gets very
kind of energy. Gets very uncomfortable
in
in the
in the 800s.
in the 800s. Often
in the 800s. Often quite
in the 800s. Often quite painful
in the 800s. Often quite painful and
agonizing.
And
And it
And it only
And it only goes
And it only goes up
And it only goes up to
And it only goes up to a
And it only goes up to a thousand.
[clears throat]
If
If your
If your consciousness
If your consciousness goes
If your consciousness goes beyond
If your consciousness goes beyond a
thousand,
thousand, you
If your consciousness goes beyond a
thousand, you belong
thousand, you belong on
If your consciousness goes beyond a
thousand, you belong on a
thousand, you belong on a different
realm
realm and
realm and you
realm and you leave
realm and you leave here.
realm and you leave here. [laughter]
You
You can
realm and you leave here. [laughter]
You can hear
You can hear your
realm and you leave here. [laughter]
You can hear your protoplasm
You can hear your protoplasm sizzling
realm and you leave here. [laughter]
You can hear your protoplasm sizzling in
the
the sun.
the sun. And
it's
it's time
the sun. And
it's time to
it's time to let
the sun. And
it's time to let go
it's time to let go of
the sun. And
it's time to let go of the
it's time to let go of the protoplasmic.
So
So because
So because of
So because of the
So because of the limitation
So because of the limitation of
So because of the limitation of the
human
human nervous
So because of the limitation of the
human nervous system
human nervous system and
So because of the limitation of the
human nervous system and protoplasm,
human nervous system and protoplasm, it
only
only goes
only goes up
only goes up to
only goes up to a
only goes up to a thousand.
only goes up to a thousand. And
only goes up to a thousand. And as
only goes up to a thousand. And as we
say,
say, archangels
only goes up to a thousand. And as we
say, archangels calibrated
say, archangels calibrated such
only goes up to a thousand. And as we
say, archangels calibrated such high
frequencies.
frequencies. The
frequencies. The one
frequencies. The one who
frequencies. The one who once
frequencies. The one who once noticed
frequencies. The one who once noticed me
uh
uh calibrated
frequencies. The one who once noticed me
uh calibrated 50,000
uh calibrated 50,000 and
frequencies. The one who once noticed me
uh calibrated 50,000 and a
uh calibrated 50,000 and a passing
notice
notice totally
notice totally changed
notice totally changed this
notice totally changed this life
completely.
completely. Uh
notice totally changed this life
completely. Uh and
completely. Uh and it
notice totally changed this life
completely. Uh and it was
completely. Uh and it was like
notice totally changed this life
completely. Uh and it was like a
devastating
devastating shot
devastating shot of
devastating shot of a
devastating shot of a lightning.
devastating shot of a lightning. So
uh
uh just
devastating shot of a lightning. So
uh just pray
uh just pray the
devastating shot of a lightning. So
uh just pray the arch
uh just pray the arch angel
devastating shot of a lightning. So
uh just pray the arch angel really
thinks
thinks about
thinks about you
thinks about you too
thinks about you too much.
thinks about you too much. [laughter]
Smoke
Smoke and
thinks about you too much. [laughter]
Smoke and steam
Smoke and steam going
thinks about you too much. [laughter]
Smoke and steam going up
Smoke and steam going up and
thinks about you too much. [laughter]
Smoke and steam going up and a
Smoke and steam going up and a little
cinder
cinder laying
cinder laying there.
cinder laying there. [laughter]
So
So better
cinder laying there. [laughter]
So better isn't
So better isn't always
cinder laying there. [laughter]
So better isn't always higher
So better isn't always higher isn't
always
always better.
It's
It's only
always better.
It's only okay
It's only okay within
always better.
It's only okay within okay
It's only okay within okay range.
All right.
All right. So
All right. So we're
All right. So we're going to
All right. So we're going to cover
All right. So we're going to cover the
basics.
basics. So
All right. So we're going to cover the
basics. So the
basics. So the first
All right. So we're going to cover the
basics. So the first thing
basics. So the first thing of
All right. So we're going to cover the
basics. So the first thing of course
basics. So the first thing of course is
the
the map
the map of
the map of consciousness
the map of consciousness which
the map of consciousness which is
the map of consciousness which is known
worldwide.
worldwide. All
the map of consciousness which is known
worldwide. All these
worldwide. All these books
the map of consciousness which is known
worldwide. All these books we've
worldwide. All these books we've written
are
are in
are in all
are in all the
are in all the world's
are in all the world's languages
are in all the world's languages and
study
study groups
are in all the world's languages and
study groups utilize
study groups utilize them
are in all the world's languages and
study groups utilize them throughout
study groups utilize them throughout the
world.
world. We've
world. We've used
world. We've used it
world. We've used it to
world. We've used it to solve
international
international conflicts
world. We've used it to solve
international conflicts right
international conflicts right on
world. We've used it to solve
international conflicts right on the
edge
edge of
edge of ballistic
edge of ballistic uh
edge of ballistic uh war
edge of ballistic uh war and
edge of ballistic uh war and uh
edge of ballistic uh war and uh nip
edge of ballistic uh war and uh nip that
war
war in
edge of ballistic uh war and uh nip that
war in the
war in the bud
edge of ballistic uh war and uh nip that
war in the bud only
war in the bud only by
edge of ballistic uh war and uh nip that
war in the bud only by knowing
war in the bud only by knowing the
absolute
absolute truth.
So
So how
absolute truth.
So how to
So how to tell
absolute truth.
So how to tell truth
So how to tell truth from
absolute truth.
So how to tell truth from falsehood
So how to tell truth from falsehood is
of
of course
of course as
of course as Decart
of course as Decart said
of course as Decart said you
of course as Decart said you know
of course as Decart said you know uh
of course as Decart said you know uh man
doesn't
doesn't know
of course as Decart said you know uh man
doesn't know whether
doesn't know whether reality
of course as Decart said you know uh man
doesn't know whether reality is
doesn't know whether reality is what
of course as Decart said you know uh man
doesn't know whether reality is what he
perceives
perceives as
perceives as reality
perceives as reality there's
perceives as reality there's rest
internal
internal and
perceives as reality there's rest
internal and then
internal and then there's
perceives as reality there's rest
internal and then there's rest
internal and then there's rest external
the
the world
the world the
the world the way
the world the way it
the world the way it is
the world the way it is or
the world the way it is or nature
the world the way it is or nature itself
and
and of
the world the way it is or nature itself
and of course
and of course Socrates
the world the way it is or nature itself
and of course Socrates is
and of course Socrates is my
the world the way it is or nature itself
and of course Socrates is my favorite
old
old teacher
old teacher uh
old teacher uh said
old teacher uh said the
old teacher uh said the same
old teacher uh said the same thing
uh
uh all
old teacher uh said the same thing
uh all men
uh all men are
old teacher uh said the same thing
uh all men are innocent
uh all men are innocent by
old teacher uh said the same thing
uh all men are innocent by virtue
uh all men are innocent by virtue of
old teacher uh said the same thing
uh all men are innocent by virtue of the
fact
fact that
fact that they're
fact that they're unable
fact that they're unable to
fact that they're unable to discern
appearance
appearance from
fact that they're unable to discern
appearance from essence,
appearance from essence, truth
fact that they're unable to discern
appearance from essence, truth from
falsehood,
falsehood, and
falsehood, and that
falsehood, and that they
falsehood, and that they pursue
illusion.
illusion. They
falsehood, and that they pursue
illusion. They always
illusion. They always pursue
falsehood, and that they pursue
illusion. They always pursue what
illusion. They always pursue what they
perceive
perceive to
perceive to be
perceive to be the
perceive to be the good
perceive to be the good that
perceive to be the good that helps
perceive to be the good that helps us
put
put in
perceive to be the good that helps us
put in place
put in place then
perceive to be the good that helps us
put in place then forgiveness
put in place then forgiveness or
Christ's
Christ's statement
Christ's statement that
Christ's statement that the
Christ's statement that the only
Christ's statement that the only human
error
error is
Christ's statement that the only human
error is one
error is one of
Christ's statement that the only human
error is one of ignorance
error is one of ignorance is
Christ's statement that the only human
error is one of ignorance is the
realization
realization because
realization because of
realization because of limitation
realization because of limitation people
make
make errors
realization because of limitation people
make errors and
make errors and the
realization because of limitation people
make errors and the innocence
make errors and the innocence of
realization because of limitation people
make errors and the innocence of the
child
child is
child is still
child is still resides
child is still resides within
child is still resides within all
child is still resides within all of
child is still resides within all of us
and
and that's
child is still resides within all of us
and that's why
and that's why mankind
child is still resides within all of us
and that's why mankind is
and that's why mankind is dupable
dupable
dupable and
dupable and programmable
dupable and programmable because
dupable and programmable because like
the
the that
dupable and programmable because like
the that the
the that the mind
dupable and programmable because like
the that the mind tends
the that the mind tends to
dupable and programmable because like
the that the mind tends to believe
everything
everything that
everything that it
everything that it hears.
All
All right?
everything that it hears.
All right? So,
All right? So, unless
everything that it hears.
All right? So, unless it's
All right? So, unless it's truth,
everything that it hears.
All right? So, unless it's truth, in
which
which case
which case they
which case they reject
which case they reject it,
which case they reject it, but
[laughter]
you
you you'll
you you'll omit
you you'll omit that
you you'll omit that from
you you'll omit that from you
you you'll omit that from you omit
you you'll omit that from you omit that
one.
one. Okay.
you you'll omit that from you omit that
one. Okay. [laughter]
Okay.
Okay. Love,
Okay. Love, let's
Okay. Love, let's have
Okay. Love, let's have a
Okay. Love, let's have a credit
Okay. Love, let's have a credit line
one.
[cough]
[clears throat]
Of
Of course,
Of course, what
Of course, what you
Of course, what you what
Of course, what you what we
Of course, what you what we what
Of course, what you what we what we
learn
learn through
Of course, what you what we what we
learn through this
learn through this technique
Of course, what you what we what we
learn through this technique is
devastating.
uh
uh what
devastating.
uh what what
uh what what actually
devastating.
uh what what actually goes
uh what what actually goes on
devastating.
uh what what actually goes on in
uh what what actually goes on in the
world
world uh
world uh and
world uh and as
world uh and as compared
world uh and as compared to
world uh and as compared to his
appearance
appearance of
world uh and as compared to his
appearance of course
appearance of course is
world uh and as compared to his
appearance of course is quite
appearance of course is quite remarkable
and
and uh
and uh although
and uh although the
and uh although the world
and uh although the world doesn't
and uh although the world doesn't know
what's
what's going
and uh although the world doesn't know
what's going on
what's going on we
and uh although the world doesn't know
what's going on we do
what's going on we do within
and uh although the world doesn't know
what's going on we do within a
what's going on we do within a matter
and uh although the world doesn't know
what's going on we do within a matter of
seconds.
seconds. [laughter]
[laughter]
All
All right.
All right. So
[laughter]
it
it is
it is sort
it is sort of
it is sort of funny.
it is sort of funny. The
it is sort of funny. The whole
it is sort of funny. The whole world
it is sort of funny. The whole world uh
studies
studies a
it is sort of funny. The whole world uh
studies a thing
studies a thing and
it is sort of funny. The whole world uh
studies a thing and doesn't
studies a thing and doesn't know
it is sort of funny. The whole world uh
studies a thing and doesn't know what
the hell
the hell it's
the hell it's about.
the hell it's about. And
the hell it's about. And I
the hell it's about. And I say
the hell it's about. And I say to
the hell it's about. And I say to Susie,
that's
that's over
the hell it's about. And I say to Susie,
that's over 220.
that's over 220. It
the hell it's about. And I say to Susie,
that's over 220. It said
that's over 220. It said 220,
the hell it's about. And I say to Susie,
that's over 220. It said 220, man.
that's over 220. It said 220, man. It's
like
like so
like so simple.
like so simple. So
the
the only
like so simple. So
the only thing
the only thing is
like so simple. So
the only thing is only
the only thing is only people
like so simple. So
the only thing is only people who
themselves
themselves calibrate
themselves calibrate over
themselves calibrate over 200
themselves calibrate over 200 can
themselves calibrate over 200 can use
the
the technique
themselves calibrate over 200 can use
the technique and
the technique and then
themselves calibrate over 200 can use
the technique and then they
the technique and then they can
themselves calibrate over 200 can use
the technique and then they can only
the technique and then they can only use
it
it if
it if their
it if their intention
it if their intention is
it if their intention is integrous.
it if their intention is integrous. You
can't
can't use
it if their intention is integrous. You
can't use the
can't use the technique
it if their intention is integrous. You
can't use the technique to
can't use the technique to try
it if their intention is integrous. You
can't use the technique to try and
can't use the technique to try and prove
a
a point
a point to
a point to try
a point to try and
a point to try and get
a point to try and get the
a point to try and get the world
a point to try and get the world to
a point to try and get the world to uh
agree
agree with
a point to try and get the world to uh
agree with you.
agree with you. So
a point to try and get the world to uh
agree with you. So you
agree with you. So you have
a point to try and get the world to uh
agree with you. So you have to
agree with you. So you have to be
dedicated
dedicated to
dedicated to truth
dedicated to truth for
dedicated to truth for its
dedicated to truth for its own
dedicated to truth for its own sake.
dedicated to truth for its own sake. And
then
then when
dedicated to truth for its own sake. And
then when you
then when you find
dedicated to truth for its own sake. And
then when you find out
then when you find out the
dedicated to truth for its own sake. And
then when you find out the truth
then when you find out the truth you
dedicated to truth for its own sake. And
then when you find out the truth you can
worry
worry about
worry about what
worry about what to
worry about what to do
worry about what to do about
worry about what to do about it
worry about what to do about it later.
But
But the
worry about what to do about it later.
But the first
But the first thing
worry about what to do about it later.
But the first thing is
But the first thing is you
worry about what to do about it later.
But the first thing is you don't
But the first thing is you don't know
what
what what
what what what
what what what the
what what what the problem
what what what the problem is
what what what the problem is until
what what what the problem is until you
ask
ask what
what what what the problem is until you
ask what is
ask what is the
what what what the problem is until you
ask what is the truth
ask what is the truth of
what what what the problem is until you
ask what is the truth of the
ask what is the truth of the matter.
what what what the problem is until you
ask what is the truth of the matter. So
our
our dedication
our dedication is
our dedication is to
our dedication is to truth
our dedication is to truth and
our dedication is to truth and the
our dedication is to truth and the basis
is
is the
our dedication is to truth and the basis
is the truth
is the truth is
our dedication is to truth and the basis
is the truth is the
is the truth is the straight
our dedication is to truth and the basis
is the truth is the straight way
is the truth is the straight way to
our dedication is to truth and the basis
is the truth is the straight way to god
and
and nonlinear
and nonlinear duality
and nonlinear duality means
and nonlinear duality means uh
and nonlinear duality means uh to
and nonlinear duality means uh to let
and nonlinear duality means uh to let go
of
of the
and nonlinear duality means uh to let go
of the linear
of the linear appearance
and nonlinear duality means uh to let go
of the linear appearance of
of the linear appearance of things
and nonlinear duality means uh to let go
of the linear appearance of things and
to
to align
to align with
to align with the
to align with the essence
to align with the essence which
to align with the essence which is
to align with the essence which is the
fastest
fastest way
to align with the essence which is the
fastest way uh
fastest way uh to
to align with the essence which is the
fastest way uh to enlightenment.
fastest way uh to enlightenment. Yeah.
All right.
All right. Now
All right. Now we
All right. Now we have
All right. Now we have this
All right. Now we have this here
All right. Now we have this here and
this
this is
All right. Now we have this here and
this is a
this is a poker
All right. Now we have this here and
this is a poker poker
this is a poker poker thing.
To
To be
To be a
To be a professor
To be a professor you
To be a professor you have
To be a professor you have to
To be a professor you have to have
To be a professor you have to have a
poker.
[laughter]
You
You see
[laughter]
You see the
You see the the
[laughter]
You see the the view
You see the the view of
[laughter]
You see the the view of God
You see the the view of God then
[laughter]
You see the the view of God then depends
on
on your
on your level
on your level of
on your level of consciousness.
on your level of consciousness. Whether
you
you see
on your level of consciousness. Whether
you see God
you see God as
on your level of consciousness. Whether
you see God as punitive
you see God as punitive or
on your level of consciousness. Whether
you see God as punitive or frightening
or
or whether
or whether you're
or whether you're an
or whether you're an atheist
or whether you're an atheist and
or whether you're an atheist and don't
believe
believe in
or whether you're an atheist and don't
believe in God
believe in God at
or whether you're an atheist and don't
believe in God at all.
believe in God at all. um
your
your view
your view of
your view of yourself
your view of yourself depends
your view of yourself depends on
your view of yourself depends on your
level
level of
your view of yourself depends on your
level of consciousness.
level of consciousness. It
your view of yourself depends on your
level of consciousness. It doesn't
depend
depend on
depend on sociologic
depend on sociologic conditions,
depend on sociologic conditions, poverty
or
or wealth
depend on sociologic conditions, poverty
or wealth or
or wealth or any
depend on sociologic conditions, poverty
or wealth or any of
or wealth or any of these
depend on sociologic conditions, poverty
or wealth or any of these things.
or wealth or any of these things. Your
view
view of
view of yourself
view of yourself then
view of yourself then is
view of yourself then is a
view of yourself then is a consequence
of
of your
view of yourself then is a consequence
of your own
of your own level
view of yourself then is a consequence
of your own level of
of your own level of consciousness.
And
And these
And these levels
And these levels uh
And these levels uh we
And these levels uh we gave
And these levels uh we gave these
And these levels uh we gave these useful
names
names uh
And these levels uh we gave these useful
names uh the
names uh the spiritualization
And these levels uh we gave these useful
names uh the spiritualization of
names uh the spiritualization of these
from
from all
from all the
from all the way
from all the way from
from all the way from enlightenment
uh
uh down
from all the way from enlightenment
uh down through
uh down through the
from all the way from enlightenment
uh down through the high
uh down through the high levels.
from all the way from enlightenment
uh down through the high levels. 600
uh down through the high levels. 600 is
a
a phenomenal
a phenomenal level.
uh
uh in
a phenomenal level.
uh in the
uh in the human
a phenomenal level.
uh in the human domain,
uh in the human domain, very
a phenomenal level.
uh in the human domain, very few
uh in the human domain, very few people
uh
uh really
uh really get
uh really get past
uh really get past uh
uh really get past uh well,
uh really get past uh well, very
uh really get past uh well, very few
uh really get past uh well, very few get
to
to 500
and
and fewer
and fewer yet
and fewer yet get
and fewer yet get to
and fewer yet get to unconditional
and fewer yet get to unconditional love
at
at 540.
In
In the
In the world's
In the world's population,
In the world's population, 0.4%
of
of the
In the world's population, 0.4%
of the world's
of the world's population
In the world's population, 0.4%
of the world's population ever
of the world's population ever reaches
unconditional
unconditional love.
People
People say,
unconditional love.
People say, "How
People say, "How can
unconditional love.
People say, "How can I
People say, "How can I reach
unconditional
unconditional love?"
unconditional love?" I
unconditional love?" I said,
unconditional love?" I said, "Well,
become
become an
unconditional love?" I said, "Well,
become an alcoholic
become an alcoholic and
unconditional love?" I said, "Well,
become an alcoholic and join
become an alcoholic and join AA.
unconditional love?" I said, "Well,
become an alcoholic and join AA. It's
become an alcoholic and join AA. It's at
540.
>> [applause]
>> do
>> do the
>> do the course
>> do the course of
>> do the course of miracles.
>> do the course of miracles. The
>> do the course of miracles. The W
>> do the course of miracles. The W the
workbook
workbook is
>> do the course of miracles. The W the
workbook is at
workbook is at 600.
>> do the course of miracles. The W the
workbook is at 600. The
workbook is at 600. The textbook
>> do the course of miracles. The W the
workbook is at 600. The textbook I
workbook is at 600. The textbook I would
ignore.
ignore. It's
ignore. It's at
ignore. It's at 550
ignore. It's at 550 and
ignore. It's at 550 and it's
ignore. It's at 550 and it's got
everything.
everything. Just
ignore. It's at 550 and it's got
everything. Just do
everything. Just do the
ignore. It's at 550 and it's got
everything. Just do the workbook.
everything. Just do the workbook. That's
all
all you
all you got
all you got to
all you got to do.
all you got to do. Keep
all you got to do. Keep it
all you got to do. Keep it simple.
all you got to do. Keep it simple. So
any
any of
all you got to do. Keep it simple. So
any of those
any of those ways
all you got to do. Keep it simple. So
any of those ways all
any of those ways all depend
all you got to do. Keep it simple. So
any of those ways all depend on
simplicity.
the
the willingness
simplicity.
the willingness to
the willingness to be
simplicity.
the willingness to be forgiving,
the willingness to be forgiving, the
willingness
willingness to
willingness to live
willingness to live one
willingness to live one day
willingness to live one day at
willingness to live one day at a
willingness to live one day at a time.
And
And at
willingness to live one day at a time.
And at a
And at a 12step
willingness to live one day at a time.
And at a 12step meeting,
And at a 12step meeting, a
willingness to live one day at a time.
And at a 12step meeting, a guy
And at a 12step meeting, a guy comes
willingness to live one day at a time.
And at a 12step meeting, a guy comes in,
he's
he's blubbering
he's blubbering and
he's blubbering and crying
he's blubbering and crying all
he's blubbering and crying all over
he's blubbering and crying all over the
place.
place. They
he's blubbering and crying all over the
place. They said,
place. They said, "What's
he's blubbering and crying all over the
place. They said, "What's the
place. They said, "What's the problem?"
He
He said,
He said, "Well,
He said, "Well, my
He said, "Well, my mother
He said, "Well, my mother got
He said, "Well, my mother got run
He said, "Well, my mother got run over
yesterday
yesterday and
He said, "Well, my mother got run over
yesterday and my
yesterday and my wife
He said, "Well, my mother got run over
yesterday and my wife got
yesterday and my wife got shot
He said, "Well, my mother got run over
yesterday and my wife got shot and
yesterday and my wife got shot and and
and
and the
and the dog
and the dog died."
and the dog died." And
and the dog died." And you
and the dog died." And you say
and the dog died." And you say to
and the dog died." And you say to him,
"Well,
"Well, that
and the dog died." And you say to him,
"Well, that was
"Well, that was yesterday.
That
That was
That was yesterday.
What
What are
That was yesterday.
What are you
What are you grinding
That was yesterday.
What are you grinding about
What are you grinding about today,
idiot?
So
So there's
idiot?
So there's a
So there's a group
idiot?
So there's a group discipline
So there's a group discipline to
idiot?
So there's a group discipline to apply
spiritual
spiritual principles.
spiritual principles. Other
spiritual principles. Other people
spiritual principles. Other people read
about
about them
spiritual principles. Other people read
about them and
about them and talk
spiritual principles. Other people read
about them and talk about
about them and talk about them.
spiritual principles. Other people read
about them and talk about them. But
about them and talk about them. But in
self-help
self-help groups,
self-help groups, you're
self-help groups, you're expected
self-help groups, you're expected to
self-help groups, you're expected to do
them,
them, to
self-help groups, you're expected to do
them, to put
them, to put them
self-help groups, you're expected to do
them, to put them into
them, to put them into your
self-help groups, you're expected to do
them, to put them into your life
them, to put them into your life in
daily
daily application
daily application to
daily application to make
daily application to make them
daily application to make them part
daily application to make them part of
your
your life.
Uh
Uh so
Uh so that
Uh so that means
Uh so that means you
Uh so that means you have
Uh so that means you have to
Uh so that means you have to give
Uh so that means you have to give up
Uh so that means you have to give up the
pleasure
pleasure of
Uh so that means you have to give up the
pleasure of condemning
pleasure of condemning people.
Uh so that means you have to give up the
pleasure of condemning people. A
[laughter]
>> [laughter]
>> I
>> I thought
>> I thought we're
>> I thought we're going
>> I thought we're going to
>> I thought we're going to pick
>> I thought we're going to pick on
>> I thought we're going to pick on the
Pope
Pope today.
He's
He's in
He's in hot
He's in hot water,
He's in hot water, isn't
He's in hot water, isn't he?
He's in hot water, isn't he? Something
about
about the
He's in hot water, isn't he? Something
about the Pope.
Did
Did something
Did something wrong.
Did something wrong. He's
okay.
okay. So,
Did something wrong. He's
okay. So, uh
okay. So, uh I'm
Did something wrong. He's
okay. So, uh I'm sure
okay. So, uh I'm sure what
Did something wrong. He's
okay. So, uh I'm sure what the
okay. So, uh I'm sure what the Pope
Did something wrong. He's
okay. So, uh I'm sure what the Pope was
doing
doing is
doing is rational.
doing is rational. Anyway,
reason
reason is
doing is rational. Anyway,
reason is in
reason is in the
doing is rational. Anyway,
reason is in the 400s.
reason is in the 400s. Uh
doing is rational. Anyway,
reason is in the 400s. Uh love
reason is in the 400s. Uh love is
doing is rational. Anyway,
reason is in the 400s. Uh love is 500.
Unconditional
Unconditional love
Unconditional love and
Unconditional love and beyond
unconditional
unconditional love.
Unconditional love and beyond
unconditional love. So
unconditional love. So these
Unconditional love and beyond
unconditional love. So these states
unconditional love. So these states we
start
start out
start out with
start out with shame,
start out with shame, disaster,
start out with shame, disaster, guilt,
uh
uh apathetic,
start out with shame, disaster, guilt,
uh apathetic, fearful,
angry.
We
We get
angry.
We get up
We get up this
angry.
We get up this level
We get up this level of
angry.
We get up this level of 200
We get up this level of 200 is
angry.
We get up this level of 200 is very
critical.
critical. It's
critical. It's very
critical. It's very critical
critical. It's very critical because
we'll
we'll see
critical. It's very critical because
we'll see at
we'll see at level
critical. It's very critical because
we'll see at level 200
we'll see at level 200 the
critical. It's very critical because
we'll see at level 200 the willingness
to
to be
to be honest.
Selfhonesty
Selfhonesty is
to be honest.
Selfhonesty is the
Selfhonesty is the only
to be honest.
Selfhonesty is the only requirement
Selfhonesty is the only requirement of
any
any of
any of these
any of these spiritual
any of these spiritual programs.
any of these spiritual programs. Self
honesty
honesty automatically
any of these spiritual programs. Self
honesty automatically is
honesty automatically is put
any of these spiritual programs. Self
honesty automatically is put you
honesty automatically is put you above
level
level 200.
level 200. And
level 200. And this
level 200. And this from
level 200. And this from here
level 200. And this from here up
level 200. And this from here up you're
interested
interested in
level 200. And this from here up you're
interested in the
interested in the truth
level 200. And this from here up you're
interested in the truth for
interested in the truth for its
level 200. And this from here up you're
interested in the truth for its own
sake.
sake. And
sake. And what
sake. And what happens
sake. And what happens here
sake. And what happens here is
sake. And what happens here is extremely
important
important because
sake. And what happens here is extremely
important because the
important because the brain
sake. And what happens here is extremely
important because the brain chemistry
shifts.
shifts. You
shifts. You shift
shifts. You shift from
shifts. You shift from leftbrain
shifts. You shift from leftbrain animal
instinctual
instinctual dominance
shifts. You shift from leftbrain animal
instinctual dominance of
instinctual dominance of the
shifts. You shift from leftbrain animal
instinctual dominance of the ego.
The
The condundolini
The condundolini energy
The condundolini energy arises
The condundolini energy arises and
The condundolini energy arises and you
now
now shift
The condundolini energy arises and you
now shift to
now shift to right
The condundolini energy arises and you
now shift to right brain
now shift to right brain which
The condundolini energy arises and you
now shift to right brain which sees
things
things in
things in a
things in a benign
uh
uh processes
things in a benign
uh processes information
uh processes information differently
things in a benign
uh processes information differently and
we'll
we'll have
we'll have a
we'll have a slide
we'll have a slide on
we'll have a slide on that.
we'll have a slide on that. It
we'll have a slide on that. It also
releases
releases neurotransmitters
we'll have a slide on that. It also
releases neurotransmitters and
releases neurotransmitters and neuro
hormones
hormones that
hormones that alter
hormones that alter the
hormones that alter the way
hormones that alter the way your
hormones that alter the way your brain
physiology
physiology works.
hormones that alter the way your brain
physiology works. So
physiology works. So people
hormones that alter the way your brain
physiology works. So people hoping
physiology works. So people hoping that
all
all the
all the world
all the world are
all the world are going
all the world are going to
all the world are going to everybody
all the world are going to everybody in
the
the world
all the world are going to everybody in
the world is
the world is going
all the world are going to everybody in
the world is going to
the world is going to get
all the world are going to everybody in
the world is going to get together
the world is going to get together and
sing
sing songs
sing songs and
sing songs and dance
sing songs and dance around
sing songs and dance around the
sing songs and dance around the maple
sing songs and dance around the maple or
I'm
I'm going
sing songs and dance around the maple or
I'm going to
I'm going to be
sing songs and dance around the maple or
I'm going to be happy
I'm going to be happy is
sing songs and dance around the maple or
I'm going to be happy is forgetting
I'm going to be happy is forgetting that
the
the people
the people below
the people below 200
the people below 200 have
the people below 200 have a
the people below 200 have a different
brain
brain physiology
the people below 200 have a different
brain physiology and
brain physiology and frankly
the people below 200 have a different
brain physiology and frankly to
brain physiology and frankly to them
the people below 200 have a different
brain physiology and frankly to them you
sound
sound like
sound like an
sound like an idiot.
sound like an idiot. [laughter]
So
So all
sound like an idiot. [laughter]
So all the
So all the do
sound like an idiot. [laughter]
So all the do [clears throat]
So all the do [clears throat] good
sound like an idiot. [laughter]
So all the do [clears throat] good or
peace
peace that
peace that want
peace that want to
peace that want to envision
peace that want to envision a
peace that want to envision a new
peaceful
peaceful world
peace that want to envision a new
peaceful world are
peaceful world are forgetting
peace that want to envision a new
peaceful world are forgetting that
peaceful world are forgetting that 85%
of
of the
of the world
of the world calibrates
of the world calibrates below
of the world calibrates below 200
in
in America
of the world calibrates below 200
in America approximately
in America approximately 50%.
of the world calibrates below 200
in America approximately 50%. And
in America approximately 50%. And these
people
people have
people have a
people have a different
people have a different brain
people have a different brain physiology
brain
brain physiology
in
in which
in which what
in which what you're
in which what you're saying
in which what you're saying to
in which what you're saying to them
in which what you're saying to them is
nonsensical
nonsensical meaningless
in which what you're saying to them is
nonsensical meaningless and
nonsensical meaningless and probably
absurd
absurd and
absurd and for
absurd and for which
absurd and for which you
absurd and for which you actually
deserve
deserve to
absurd and for which you actually
deserve to be
deserve to be killed.
absurd and for which you actually
deserve to be killed. [laughter]
That
That makes
That makes it
That makes it a
That makes it a little
That makes it a little tacky.
That makes it a little tacky. How
That makes it a little tacky. How you
going
going to
That makes it a little tacky. How you
going to turn
going to turn this
That makes it a little tacky. How you
going to turn this into
going to turn this into a
That makes it a little tacky. How you
going to turn this into a one
going to turn this into a one peaceful
world?
[laughter]
People
People are
People are always
People are always saying,
People are always saying, you
People are always saying, you know,
People are always saying, you know, what
can
can I
People are always saying, you know, what
can I do
can I do to
People are always saying, you know, what
can I do to help
can I do to help the
People are always saying, you know, what
can I do to help the world?
can I do to help the world? Well,
People are always saying, you know, what
can I do to help the world? Well, to
can I do to help the world? Well, to be
quiet,
quiet, nine-year-old
quiet, nine-year-old business
quiet, nine-year-old business is
quiet, nine-year-old business is a
quiet, nine-year-old business is a good
start.
[laughter]
Why?
Why? Because
[laughter]
Why? Because what
Why? Because what actually
[laughter]
Why? Because what actually helps
Why? Because what actually helps the
world
world uh
world uh uh
world uh uh and
world uh uh and with
world uh uh and with research
world uh uh and with research we
world uh uh and with research we can
prove
prove this
world uh uh and with research we can
prove this is
prove this is true.
world uh uh and with research we can
prove this is true. What
prove this is true. What helps
world uh uh and with research we can
prove this is true. What helps the
prove this is true. What helps the world
is
is your
is your personal
is your personal spiritual
is your personal spiritual evolution.
That's
That's what
is your personal spiritual evolution.
That's what helps
That's what helps the
is your personal spiritual evolution.
That's what helps the world.
That's what helps the world. Your
kindness
kindness to
kindness to others
kindness to others begins
kindness to others begins to
kindness to others begins to lift
kindness to others begins to lift the
overall
overall level
kindness to others begins to lift the
overall level of
overall level of consciousness
kindness to others begins to lift the
overall level of consciousness of
mankind
mankind which
mankind which unfortunately
mankind which unfortunately was
mankind which unfortunately was was
mankind which unfortunately was was up
very
very high
mankind which unfortunately was was up
very high was
very high was up
mankind which unfortunately was was up
very high was up high
very high was up high and
mankind which unfortunately was was up
very high was up high and now
very high was up high and now it's
mankind which unfortunately was was up
very high was up high and now it's come
down
down again.
down again. So
down again. So the
down again. So the consciousness
down again. So the consciousness level
of
of mankind
down again. So the consciousness level
of mankind was
of mankind was at
down again. So the consciousness level
of mankind was at 190
of mankind was at 190 for
down again. So the consciousness level
of mankind was at 190 for many
of mankind was at 190 for many many
down again. So the consciousness level
of mankind was at 190 for many many many
thousands
thousands of
thousands of years.
thousands of years. Well,
thousands of years. Well, it
thousands of years. Well, it was
thousands of years. Well, it was at
thousands of years. Well, it was at 90
at
at the
thousands of years. Well, it was at 90
at the time
at the time of
thousands of years. Well, it was at 90
at the time of the
at the time of the Buddha.
thousands of years. Well, it was at 90
at the time of the Buddha. Conscious
level
level mankind
level mankind at
level mankind at the
level mankind at the time
level mankind at the time of
level mankind at the time of Jesus
Christ
Christ was
level mankind at the time of Jesus
Christ was about
Christ was about 100.
level mankind at the time of Jesus
Christ was about 100. It
Christ was about 100. It slowly
level mankind at the time of Jesus
Christ was about 100. It slowly came
Christ was about 100. It slowly came up
to
to 190
to 190 and
to 190 and it
to 190 and it stayed
to 190 and it stayed at
to 190 and it stayed at 190
to 190 and it stayed at 190 over
to 190 and it stayed at 190 over the
centuries.
centuries. Over
to 190 and it stayed at 190 over the
centuries. Over the
centuries. Over the centuries,
to 190 and it stayed at 190 over the
centuries. Over the centuries, the
1800s,
early
early 1900s,
1800s,
early 1900s, in
early 1900s, in this
1800s,
early 1900s, in this lifetime,
early 1900s, in this lifetime, it
1800s,
early 1900s, in this lifetime, it was
still
still at
still at 190.
still at 190. And
still at 190. And then
still at 190. And then in
still at 190. And then in uh
still at 190. And then in uh late
still at 190. And then in uh late 80s
still at 190. And then in uh late 80s at
the
the time
still at 190. And then in uh late 80s at
the time of
the time of the
still at 190. And then in uh late 80s at
the time of the harmonic
the time of the harmonic concordance
still at 190. And then in uh late 80s at
the time of the harmonic concordance or
convergence
convergence whatever
convergence whatever it's
convergence whatever it's called
convergence whatever it's called uh
convergence whatever it's called uh it
suddenly
suddenly jumped
convergence whatever it's called uh it
suddenly jumped to
suddenly jumped to 205
and
and it
and it stayed
and it stayed at
and it stayed at 205.
and it stayed at 205. Then
and it stayed at 205. Then the
and it stayed at 205. Then the the
and it stayed at 205. Then the the the
next
next time
and it stayed at 205. Then the the the
next time there
next time there was
and it stayed at 205. Then the the the
next time there was a
next time there was a harmonic
concordance
concordance or
concordance or convergence
concordance or convergence on
concordance or convergence on which
concordance or convergence on which is
which
which uh
concordance or convergence on which is
which uh we
which uh we were
concordance or convergence on which is
which uh we were giving
which uh we were giving a
concordance or convergence on which is
which uh we were giving a lecture
which uh we were giving a lecture in
concordance or convergence on which is
which uh we were giving a lecture in San
Francisco
Francisco and
Francisco and uh
Francisco and uh at
Francisco and uh at the
Francisco and uh at the exact
Francisco and uh at the exact time
Francisco and uh at the exact time of
this
this event
Francisco and uh at the exact time of
this event uh
this event uh the
Francisco and uh at the exact time of
this event uh the consciousness
this event uh the consciousness level
Francisco and uh at the exact time of
this event uh the consciousness level of
mankind
mankind went
mankind went from
mankind went from 205
mankind went from 205 to
mankind went from 205 to 207.
mankind went from 205 to 207. In
mankind went from 205 to 207. In fact
it's
it's documented
mankind went from 205 to 207. In fact
it's documented and
it's documented and on
mankind went from 205 to 207. In fact
it's documented and on and
it's documented and on and recorded
mankind went from 205 to 207. In fact
it's documented and on and recorded went
to
to 207.
And
And since
to 207.
And since that
And since that time,
to 207.
And since that time, I
And since that time, I forget
to 207.
And since that time, I forget what
And since that time, I forget what year
that
that was.
that was. It
that was. It was
that was. It was four
that was. It was four years
that was. It was four years ago
that was. It was four years ago or
that was. It was four years ago or 5
years
years ago,
that was. It was four years ago or 5
years ago, uh
years ago, uh it
that was. It was four years ago or 5
years ago, uh it stayed
years ago, uh it stayed steady
that was. It was four years ago or 5
years ago, uh it stayed steady and
years ago, uh it stayed steady and then
it
it slowly
it slowly started
it slowly started to
it slowly started to decrease
it slowly started to decrease again.
it slowly started to decrease again. So
what
what did
it slowly started to decrease again. So
what did I
what did I say
it slowly started to decrease again. So
what did I say it
what did I say it was
it slowly started to decrease again. So
what did I say it was now?
>> 204
>> 204.
>> 204. So
>> 204
>> 204. So it
>> 204. So it was
>> 204
>> 204. So it was at
>> 204. So it was at 207,
>> 204
>> 204. So it was at 207, then
>> 204. So it was at 207, then it
>> 204
>> 204. So it was at 207, then it came
>> 204. So it was at 207, then it came down
to
to 206,
to 206, 205,
to 206, 205, and
to 206, 205, and now
to 206, 205, and now it's
to 206, 205, and now it's come
to 206, 205, and now it's come down
to 206, 205, and now it's come down to
204.
204,
204, which
204, which is
204, which is a
204, which is a little
204, which is a little close
204, which is a little close to
204, which is a little close to the
204, which is a little close to the line
because
because 200
204, which is a little close to the line
because 200 is
because 200 is really
204, which is a little close to the line
because 200 is really the
because 200 is really the critical
204, which is a little close to the line
because 200 is really the critical line.
Uh
Uh anyway,
Uh anyway, uh
Uh anyway, uh because
Uh anyway, uh because of
Uh anyway, uh because of two
Uh anyway, uh because of two things,
Uh anyway, uh because of two things, two
things
things both
Uh anyway, uh because of two things, two
things both of
things both of which
Uh anyway, uh because of two things, two
things both of which really
things both of which really the
Uh anyway, uh because of two things, two
things both of which really the pope
addressed.
addressed. Um
addressed. Um the
addressed. Um the the
addressed. Um the the effect
addressed. Um the the effect of
addressed. Um the the effect of uh
addressed. Um the the effect of uh the
philosophy
philosophy of
addressed. Um the the effect of uh the
philosophy of relativism
philosophy of relativism and
addressed. Um the the effect of uh the
philosophy of relativism and all
philosophy of relativism and all of
addressed. Um the the effect of uh the
philosophy of relativism and all of its
uh
uh invasion
uh invasion of
uh invasion of integrity
uh invasion of integrity and
uh invasion of integrity and truth
together
together with
uh invasion of integrity and truth
together with uh
the
the people
the people dedicated
the people dedicated to
the people dedicated to violence
violence.
violence. So
the people dedicated to violence
violence. So between
violence. So between violence
the people dedicated to violence
violence. So between violence on
violence. So between violence on one
side
side and
side and apologies
side and apologies for
side and apologies for the
side and apologies for the violent
people
people on
side and apologies for the violent
people on the
people on the other
side and apologies for the violent
people on the other side,
people on the other side, the
side and apologies for the violent
people on the other side, the world
people on the other side, the world has
come
come down.
come down. So
come down. So uh
come down. So uh that's
come down. So uh that's not
come down. So uh that's not really
come down. So uh that's not really our
concern.
concern. We'll
come down. So uh that's not really our
concern. We'll let
concern. We'll let God
come down. So uh that's not really our
concern. We'll let God wor
concern. We'll let God wor about
come down. So uh that's not really our
concern. We'll let God wor about worry
about
about it.
Um
because
because uh
because uh this
because uh this is
because uh this is this
because uh this is this world
because uh this is this world is
perfect.
perfect. The
because uh this is this world is
perfect. The world
perfect. The world is
because uh this is this world is
perfect. The world is perfect
perfect. The world is perfect as
because uh this is this world is
perfect. The world is perfect as it
perfect. The world is perfect as it is.
I
I don't
I don't want
I don't want any
I don't want any world
I don't want any world improvers
I don't want any world improvers here.
The
The world
I don't want any world improvers here.
The world evol
The world evol is
I don't want any world improvers here.
The world evol is perfect.
The world evol is perfect. Why
I don't want any world improvers here.
The world evol is perfect. Why is
The world evol is perfect. Why is it
perfect?
perfect? Because
perfect? Because it
perfect? Because it offers
perfect? Because it offers maximum
karmic
karmic potential
perfect? Because it offers maximum
karmic potential of
karmic potential of choice.
You
You the
You the spirit
You the spirit cannot
You the spirit cannot evolve
You the spirit cannot evolve unless
You the spirit cannot evolve unless it
has
has choice.
You the spirit cannot evolve unless it
has choice. If
has choice. If you're
You the spirit cannot evolve unless it
has choice. If you're forced
has choice. If you're forced to
You the spirit cannot evolve unless it
has choice. If you're forced to always
be
be a
be a certain
be a certain way,
be a certain way, there's
be a certain way, there's no
be a certain way, there's no karmic
miracle.
So
So because
So because you
So because you take
So because you take the
So because you take the responsibility
for
for the
So because you take the responsibility
for the evolution
for the evolution of
So because you take the responsibility
for the evolution of your
for the evolution of your own
consciousness
consciousness and
consciousness and every
consciousness and every every
consciousness and every every second
consciousness and every every second you
are
are making
consciousness and every every second you
are making a
are making a choice
consciousness and every every second you
are making a choice and
are making a choice and the
consciousness and every every second you
are making a choice and the human
are making a choice and the human spirit
is
is sort
is sort of
is sort of like
is sort of like a
is sort of like a karmic
is sort of like a karmic track
is sort of like a karmic track leaves
is sort of like a karmic track leaves a
karmic
karmic track
is sort of like a karmic track leaves a
karmic track and
karmic track and I
is sort of like a karmic track leaves a
karmic track and I always
karmic track and I always picture
is sort of like a karmic track leaves a
karmic track and I always picture that
it's
it's like
it's like a
it's like a little
it's like a little tiny
it's like a little tiny iron
it's like a little tiny iron filing
it's like a little tiny iron filing and
the
the infinite
it's like a little tiny iron filing and
the infinite field
the infinite field of
it's like a little tiny iron filing and
the infinite field of consciousness
the infinite field of consciousness is
like
like an
like an infinitely
like an infinitely powerful
electromagnetic
electromagnetic field.
like an infinitely powerful
electromagnetic field. So
electromagnetic field. So that
like an infinitely powerful
electromagnetic field. So that by
electromagnetic field. So that by virtue
of
of that
of that which
of that which you
of that which you have
of that which you have become,
of that which you have become, you
position
position yourself
of that which you have become, you
position yourself within
position yourself within the
of that which you have become, you
position yourself within the field.
position yourself within the field. So
there's
there's no
judgmental
judgmental God
there's no
judgmental God who
judgmental God who says
there's no
judgmental God who says you're
judgmental God who says you're being
there's no
judgmental God who says you're being bad
and
and you're
and you're being
and you're being good.
and you're being good. If
and you're being good. If you're
and you're being good. If you're good,
we'll
we'll reward
and you're being good. If you're good,
we'll reward you,
we'll reward you, move
and you're being good. If you're good,
we'll reward you, move you
we'll reward you, move you here.
and you're being good. If you're good,
we'll reward you, move you here. If
you're
you're bad,
you're bad, we'll
you're bad, we'll put
you're bad, we'll put you
you're bad, we'll put you down
you're bad, we'll put you down here.
you're bad, we'll put you down here. You
of
of your
you're bad, we'll put you down here. You
of your own
of your own choice.
Nobody
Nobody steered
Nobody steered your
Nobody steered your canoe
Nobody steered your canoe but
Nobody steered your canoe but you.
Nobody steered your canoe but you. You
by
by your
Nobody steered your canoe but you. You
by your own
by your own choices
Nobody steered your canoe but you. You
by your own choices and
by your own choices and by
Nobody steered your canoe but you. You
by your own choices and by your
by your own choices and by your own
agreement
agreement more
agreement more or
agreement more or less
agreement more or less change
agreement more or less change the
charges
charges on
agreement more or less change the
charges on yourself.
charges on yourself. Let's
agreement more or less change the
charges on yourself. Let's say
charges on yourself. Let's say this
agreement more or less change the
charges on yourself. Let's say this is
positive
positive and
positive and negative.
positive and negative. I
positive and negative. I say
positive and negative. I say you're
positive and negative. I say you're an
SOP
SOP and
positive and negative. I say you're an
SOP and I
SOP and I hate
positive and negative. I say you're an
SOP and I hate you.
SOP and I hate you. And
positive and negative. I say you're an
SOP and I hate you. And then
SOP and I hate you. And then you
positive and negative. I say you're an
SOP and I hate you. And then you get
SOP and I hate you. And then you get a
little
little more
little more negative
little more negative and
little more negative and then
little more negative and then you
little more negative and then you say
but
but but
little more negative and then you say
but but I
but but I forgive
little more negative and then you say
but but I forgive you
but but I forgive you and
little more negative and then you say
but but I forgive you and then
but but I forgive you and then you
little more negative and then you say
but but I forgive you and then you go
but but I forgive you and then you go a
little
little more
little more positive
little more positive [laughter]
because
because you
little more positive [laughter]
because you probably
because you probably don't
little more positive [laughter]
because you probably don't know
because you probably don't know what
little more positive [laughter]
because you probably don't know what you
were
were doing
were doing like
were doing like Socrates
were doing like Socrates said.
were doing like Socrates said. On
were doing like Socrates said. On the
other
other hand,
were doing like Socrates said. On the
other hand, you
other hand, you ought
were doing like Socrates said. On the
other hand, you ought to
other hand, you ought to by
were doing like Socrates said. On the
other hand, you ought to by now
other hand, you ought to by now and
were doing like Socrates said. On the
other hand, you ought to by now and then
you
you move
you move down
you move down a
you move down a little
you move down a little bit.
you move down a little bit. So
you move down a little bit. So you
you move down a little bit. So you see
you're
you're like
you move down a little bit. So you see
you're like a
you're like a little
you move down a little bit. So you see
you're like a little thing
you're like a little thing like
you move down a little bit. So you see
you're like a little thing like this
fluctuating
fluctuating in
fluctuating in the
fluctuating in the electromagnetic
spectrum.
spectrum. And
fluctuating in the electromagnetic
spectrum. And the
spectrum. And the spirit
fluctuating in the electromagnetic
spectrum. And the spirit is
spectrum. And the spirit is what
survives
survives when
survives when it
survives when it leaves
survives when it leaves the
survives when it leaves the body.
survives when it leaves the body. It
survives when it leaves the body. It it
it
it goes
survives when it leaves the body. It it
it goes to
it goes to that
survives when it leaves the body. It it
it goes to that which
it goes to that which it
survives when it leaves the body. It it
it goes to that which it is.
it goes to that which it is. It
survives when it leaves the body. It it
it goes to that which it is. It goes
it goes to that which it is. It goes to
that
that which
that which it
that which it is
that which it is happily
that which it is happily and
that which it is happily and there
that which it is happily and there are
multiple
multiple heavens
that which it is happily and there are
multiple heavens which
multiple heavens which was
that which it is happily and there are
multiple heavens which was another
multiple heavens which was another fun
discovery
which
which we
discovery
which we suspected
which we suspected because
discovery
which we suspected because of
which we suspected because of many
religious
religious sects
religious sects will
religious sects will tell
religious sects will tell you
religious sects will tell you theirs
religious sects will tell you theirs is
the
the only
religious sects will tell you theirs is
the only way
the only way to
religious sects will tell you theirs is
the only way to God
the only way to God only
religious sects will tell you theirs is
the only way to God only way
the only way to God only way to
religious sects will tell you theirs is
the only way to God only way to heaven
rather
rather and
rather and we
rather and we found
rather and we found out
rather and we found out that's
rather and we found out that's true.
Heaven
Heaven has
rather and we found out that's true.
Heaven has multiple
Heaven has multiple neighborhoods
sections
sections divisions
sections divisions etc.
sections divisions etc. So
sections divisions etc. So there's
sections divisions etc. So there's not
just
just one
sections divisions etc. So there's not
just one heaven
just one heaven for
sections divisions etc. So there's not
just one heaven for one
just one heaven for one kind
sections divisions etc. So there's not
just one heaven for one kind of
just one heaven for one kind of people.
There's
There's multiple
There's multiple heavens.
There's multiple heavens. So
There's multiple heavens. So some
churches
churches then
There's multiple heavens. So some
churches then are
churches then are the
There's multiple heavens. So some
churches then are the the
churches then are the the the
There's multiple heavens. So some
churches then are the the the track
churches then are the the the track to
that
that section
that section of
that section of heaven.
that section of heaven. You
that section of heaven. You know
that section of heaven. You know what
that section of heaven. You know what I
mean?
mean? You
that section of heaven. You know what I
mean? You don't
mean? You don't get
that section of heaven. You know what I
mean? You don't get into
mean? You don't get into their
that section of heaven. You know what I
mean? You don't get into their section
of
of heaven
of heaven unless
of heaven unless you
of heaven unless you got
of heaven unless you got 13
of heaven unless you got 13 wives
of heaven unless you got 13 wives and
etc.
This
This section
This section of
This section of heaven,
This section of heaven, you
This section of heaven, you don't
This section of heaven, you don't get
This section of heaven, you don't get in
there
there if
This section of heaven, you don't get in
there if you
there if you got
This section of heaven, you don't get in
there if you got any
there if you got any wives.
This section of heaven, you don't get in
there if you got any wives. You
what
what I
what I mean?
what I mean? Each
what I mean? Each one
all
all women
what I mean? Each one
all women are
all women are evil.
what I mean? Each one
all women are evil. You
all women are evil. You know,
therefore,
therefore, divine
therefore, divine justice
therefore, divine justice is
therefore, divine justice is absolutely
perfect
perfect at
therefore, divine justice is absolutely
perfect at at
perfect at at all
therefore, divine justice is absolutely
perfect at at all times.
perfect at at all times. And
therefore, divine justice is absolutely
perfect at at all times. And you
perfect at at all times. And you don't
need
need an
need an anthropomorphic,
need an anthropomorphic, angry,
need an anthropomorphic, angry, jealous
God,
God, uh,
need an anthropomorphic, angry, jealous
God, uh, such
God, uh, such as
need an anthropomorphic, angry, jealous
God, uh, such as the
God, uh, such as the Old
need an anthropomorphic, angry, jealous
God, uh, such as the Old Testament
God, uh, such as the Old Testament tends
to
to bring
to bring forth,
to bring forth, which
to bring forth, which is
to bring forth, which is really
anthropomorphic.
anthropomorphic. anthropomorphic
to bring forth, which is really
anthropomorphic. anthropomorphic and
anthropomorphic. anthropomorphic and the
human
human characteristics
human characteristics are
human characteristics are projected
human characteristics are projected on
to
to some
human characteristics are projected on
to some kind
to some kind of
human characteristics are projected on
to some kind of to
to some kind of to a
human characteristics are projected on
to some kind of to a god
to some kind of to a god who
human characteristics are projected on
to some kind of to a god who has
to some kind of to a god who has a
personality
personality and
personality and you
personality and you notice
personality and you notice a
personality and you notice a very
personality and you notice a very human
kind
kind of
personality and you notice a very human
kind of personality
shows
shows favoritism
shows favoritism these
shows favoritism these people
shows favoritism these people will
shows favoritism these people will get
favored
favored and
shows favoritism these people will get
favored and these
favored and these people
shows favoritism these people will get
favored and these people will
favored and these people will get
punished
punished and
punished and so
punished and so this
punished and so this is
punished and so this is man's
punished and so this is man's uh
projection
projection so
punished and so this is man's uh
projection so I
projection so I agree
punished and so this is man's uh
projection so I agree with
projection so I agree with Freud
punished and so this is man's uh
projection so I agree with Freud that
the
the negative
the negative depictions
the negative depictions of
the negative depictions of God
the negative depictions of God are
projections
projections from
the negative depictions of God are
projections from the
projections from the human
the negative depictions of God are
projections from the human unconscious
uh
uh however
uh however Freud
uh however Freud then
uh however Freud then went
uh however Freud then went on
uh however Freud then went on and
uh however Freud then went on and made
uh however Freud then went on and made a
mistake
mistake He
uh however Freud then went on and made a
mistake He went
mistake He went further
uh however Freud then went on and made a
mistake He went further than
mistake He went further than that.
uh however Freud then went on and made a
mistake He went further than that. He
said, "Therefore,
said, "Therefore, a
said, "Therefore, a true
said, "Therefore, a true God
said, "Therefore, a true God doesn't
exist."
exist." No,
said, "Therefore, a true God doesn't
exist." No, because
exist." No, because a
said, "Therefore, a true God doesn't
exist." No, because a false
exist." No, because a false god
said, "Therefore, a true God doesn't
exist." No, because a false god doesn't
exist
exist doesn't
exist doesn't mean
exist doesn't mean a
exist doesn't mean a true
exist doesn't mean a true one
exist doesn't mean a true one doesn't.
So
So that's
exist doesn't mean a true one doesn't.
So that's why
So that's why Freud
exist doesn't mean a true one doesn't.
So that's why Freud calibrated
So that's why Freud calibrated 499.
We
We get
We get to
We get to in
We get to in our
We get to in our society
We get to in our society the
We get to in our society the is
the
the 400s
We get to in our society the is
the 400s are
the 400s are extremely
We get to in our society the is
the 400s are extremely uh
the 400s are extremely uh powerful
We get to in our society the is
the 400s are extremely uh powerful and
important.
important. Uh
important. Uh let's
important. Uh let's check
important. Uh let's check what
important. Uh let's check what USA
important. Uh let's check what USA is
today.
today. Um
important. Uh let's check what USA is
today. Um we
today. Um we have
important. Uh let's check what USA is
today. Um we have permission
today. Um we have permission to
important. Uh let's check what USA is
today. Um we have permission to do
today. Um we have permission to do this.
The
United
United States
The
United States the
United States the consciousness
The
United States the consciousness level
United States the consciousness level is
over
over 420.
over 420. 421.
over 420. 421. Jesus.
over 420. 421. Jesus. It
over 420. 421. Jesus. It went
over 420. 421. Jesus. It went down
over 420. 421. Jesus. It went down too.
It's
It's only
over 420. 421. Jesus. It went down too.
It's only at
It's only at 420.
over 420. 421. Jesus. It went down too.
It's only at 420. 421.
You
You sure
You sure you
You sure you hear
You sure you hear that
You sure you hear that line?
You sure you hear that line? Let
You sure you hear that line? Let me
know.
>> It
>> It was
>> It was at
>> It was at 426.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. That
>> It was at 426.
>> Okay. That is
>> Okay. That is the
>> It was at 426.
>> Okay. That is the impact
>> Okay. That is the impact of
>> It was at 426.
>> Okay. That is the impact of what
>> Okay. That is the impact of what I'm
thinking
thinking of.
thinking of. Okay.
So,
So, to
thinking of. Okay.
So, to get
So, to get a
thinking of. Okay.
So, to get a positive
So, to get a positive test,
thinking of. Okay.
So, to get a positive test, uh,
So, to get a positive test, uh, I
thinking of. Okay.
So, to get a positive test, uh, I don't
need
need to
need to tell
need to tell her
need to tell her what
need to tell her what I'm
need to tell her what I'm holding
need to tell her what I'm holding in
mind.
And,
And, um,
And, um, actually,
And, um, actually, we
And, um, actually, we prefer
And, um, actually, we prefer not
And, um, actually, we prefer not to
because
because neither
And, um, actually, we prefer not to
because neither one
because neither one of
And, um, actually, we prefer not to
because neither one of us
because neither one of us wants
And, um, actually, we prefer not to
because neither one of us wants the
question
question to
question to influence
question to influence the
question to influence the answer
question to influence the answer in
question to influence the answer in any
way.
way. It
question to influence the answer in any
way. It doesn't,
way. It doesn't, especially
question to influence the answer in any
way. It doesn't, especially if
way. It doesn't, especially if you're
question to influence the answer in any
way. It doesn't, especially if you're an
expert
expert at
expert at kinesiology.
It
It doesn't
expert at kinesiology.
It doesn't have
It doesn't have any
expert at kinesiology.
It doesn't have any influence.
It doesn't have any influence. But
expert at kinesiology.
It doesn't have any influence. But to
make
make sure
make sure that
make sure that it
make sure that it doesn't,
make sure that it doesn't, I
make sure that it doesn't, I don't
make sure that it doesn't, I don't even
tell
tell her
make sure that it doesn't, I don't even
tell her what
tell her what I
make sure that it doesn't, I don't even
tell her what I have
tell her what I have in
make sure that it doesn't, I don't even
tell her what I have in mind.
tell her what I have in mind. Uh,
make sure that it doesn't, I don't even
tell her what I have in mind. Uh, let's
see.
Uh
Uh I
see.
Uh I have
Uh I have a
see.
Uh I have a painting
Uh I have a painting in
see.
Uh I have a painting in mind
Uh I have a painting in mind uh
see.
Uh I have a painting in mind uh that
Uh I have a painting in mind uh that is
that
that is
that is real
that is real true
that is real true resist
that is real true resist authentic
resist.
resist. Okay.
that is real true resist authentic
resist. Okay. Um
I
I have
I have another
I have another one
I have another one in
I have another one in mind.
I have another one in mind. Uh
I have another one in mind. Uh this
I have another one in mind. Uh this one
is
is authentic
I have another one in mind. Uh this one
is authentic resist.
The
The first
The first one
The first one is
The first one is a
authentic
authentic uh
I
I forget
I forget the
I forget the uh
I forget the uh artist
I forget the uh artist now.
The
The second
I forget the uh artist now.
The second was
The second was a
I forget the uh artist now.
The second was a fake
The second was a fake Picasso.
And
And the
And the first
And the first one
And the first one is
And the first one is what
And the first one is what are
And the first one is what are all
And the first one is what are all those
ones
ones in
>> Salvador
>> Salvador Doll.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, Salvador
>> Salvador Doll.
>> Oh, Salvador Dolly.
>> Oh, Salvador Dolly. Yeah,
>> Salvador Doll.
>> Oh, Salvador Dolly. Yeah, I
>> Oh, Salvador Dolly. Yeah, I held
>> Salvador Doll.
>> Oh, Salvador Dolly. Yeah, I held a
Salvador
Salvador Dolly
Salvador Dolly that's
Salvador Dolly that's on
Salvador Dolly that's on hanging
Salvador Dolly that's on hanging in
Salvador Dolly that's on hanging in in
Itho
and
and she
and she went
and she went strong.
and she went strong. And
and she went strong. And I
and she went strong. And I also
and she went strong. And I also have
and she went strong. And I also have a
Picasso.
Picasso. It's
and she went strong. And I also have a
Picasso. It's exactly
Picasso. It's exactly four
and she went strong. And I also have a
Picasso. It's exactly four lines
Picasso. It's exactly four lines and
extremely
extremely clever
extremely clever and
extremely clever and beautiful.
And
And uh
extremely clever and beautiful.
And uh however,
And uh however, it's
extremely clever and beautiful.
And uh however, it's a
And uh however, it's a fake
extremely clever and beautiful.
And uh however, it's a fake [laughter]
Now
that
that demonstrates
Now
that demonstrates how
that demonstrates how kinesiology
Now
that demonstrates how kinesiology works.
She
She doesn't
She doesn't know
She doesn't know what
She doesn't know what I'm
She doesn't know what I'm holding
She doesn't know what I'm holding in
mind.
mind. What
She doesn't know what I'm holding in
mind. What I'm
mind. What I'm holding
She doesn't know what I'm holding in
mind. What I'm holding in
mind. What I'm holding in mind
She doesn't know what I'm holding in
mind. What I'm holding in mind isn't
even
even here.
And
And yet
even here.
And yet the
And yet the accuracy
even here.
And yet the accuracy is
And yet the accuracy is 100%.
even here.
And yet the accuracy is 100%. How
And yet the accuracy is 100%. How can
you
you see?
you see? You
you see? You see
you see? You see how
you see? You see how we
you see? You see how we would
you see? You see how we would do
screening
screening in
you see? You see how we would do
screening in an
screening in an airport,
you see? You see how we would do
screening in an airport, right?
[laughter]
We
We wouldn't
[laughter]
We wouldn't waste
We wouldn't waste time
[laughter]
We wouldn't waste time on
We wouldn't waste time on all
[laughter]
We wouldn't waste time on all the
We wouldn't waste time on all the people
that
that make
that make Aaron
that make Aaron strong.
that make Aaron strong. Somebody
that make Aaron strong. Somebody makes
you
you weak,
that make Aaron strong. Somebody makes
you weak, we'd
you weak, we'd say,
that make Aaron strong. Somebody makes
you weak, we'd say, "Step
you weak, we'd say, "Step over
that make Aaron strong. Somebody makes
you weak, we'd say, "Step over here.
We'd
We'd like
We'd like to
We'd like to ask
We'd like to ask you
We'd like to ask you a
We'd like to ask you a few
We'd like to ask you a few questions."
You
You got
We'd like to ask you a few questions."
You got any
You got any bombs
We'd like to ask you a few questions."
You got any bombs in
You got any bombs in your
We'd like to ask you a few questions."
You got any bombs in your purse?
Now,
Now, you
Now, you take
Now, you take your
Now, you take your shoes
Now, you take your shoes off
Now, you take your shoes off for
Now, you take your shoes off for God's
sake.
sake. I'm
Now, you take your shoes off for God's
sake. I'm tired
sake. I'm tired of
Now, you take your shoes off for God's
sake. I'm tired of taking
sake. I'm tired of taking my
Now, you take your shoes off for God's
sake. I'm tired of taking my shoes
sake. I'm tired of taking my shoes off
for
for fear
for fear I
for fear I might
for fear I might hurt
for fear I might hurt his
for fear I might hurt his feelings.
He's
He's blowing
for fear I might hurt his feelings.
He's blowing us
He's blowing us up
for fear I might hurt his feelings.
He's blowing us up by
He's blowing us up by the
for fear I might hurt his feelings.
He's blowing us up by the thousands
He's blowing us up by the thousands and
I've
I've got
I've got to
I've got to worry
I've got to worry about
I've got to worry about hurting
I've got to worry about hurting his
narcissistic
narcissistic ego.
My
My solution
My solution is
My solution is to
My solution is to stop
My solution is to stop being
narcissistic.
narcissistic. Don't
My solution is to stop being
narcissistic. Don't worry
narcissistic. Don't worry about
My solution is to stop being
narcissistic. Don't worry about it.
Oh
Oh golly.
Oh golly. All
Oh golly. All right.
Oh golly. All right. So,
see
see that's
Oh golly. All right. So,
see that's reason.
see that's reason. I
Oh golly. All right. So,
see that's reason. I was
see that's reason. I was just
explaining,
explaining, you
explaining, you know,
explaining, you know, reason.
explaining, you know, reason. Love
explaining, you know, reason. Love is
500.
500. Uh
explaining, you know, reason. Love is
500. Uh joy
500. Uh joy is
explaining, you know, reason. Love is
500. Uh joy is 540.
500. Uh joy is 540. You
explaining, you know, reason. Love is
500. Uh joy is 540. You get
500. Uh joy is 540. You get up
explaining, you know, reason. Love is
500. Uh joy is 540. You get up to
500. Uh joy is 540. You get up to 600.
And
And as
And as you
And as you reach
And as you reach the
And as you reach the higher
And as you reach the higher levels
And as you reach the higher levels as
we'll
we'll discuss
And as you reach the higher levels as
we'll discuss later
we'll discuss later um
And as you reach the higher levels as
we'll discuss later um unconditional
love
love I
love I think
love I think is
love I think is the
love I think is the best
love I think is the best um
love I think is the best um goal
love I think is the best um goal to
love I think is the best um goal to aim
for
for in
love I think is the best um goal to aim
for in human
for in human life.
love I think is the best um goal to aim
for in human life. It
for in human life. It is
love I think is the best um goal to aim
for in human life. It is reachable
within
within the
within the human
within the human domain.
within the human domain. The
within the human domain. The states
within the human domain. The states of
enlightenment
enlightenment are
within the human domain. The states of
enlightenment are very
enlightenment are very difficult
within the human domain. The states of
enlightenment are very difficult to
reach
reach and
reach and uh
reach and uh in
reach and uh in today's
reach and uh in today's world.
Uh
Uh but
reach and uh in today's world.
Uh but unconditional
Uh but unconditional love,
reach and uh in today's world.
Uh but unconditional love, unconditional
love
love uh
love uh then
love uh then means
love uh then means that
love uh then means that you
love uh then means that you leave
love uh then means that you leave and
you
you move
love uh then means that you leave and
you move into
you move into celestial
love uh then means that you leave and
you move into celestial heavenly
you move into celestial heavenly and
celestial
celestial realms
celestial realms and
celestial realms and uh
celestial realms and uh it's
celestial realms and uh it's certainly
uh
uh better
celestial realms and uh it's certainly
uh better than
uh better than Brooklyn.
celestial realms and uh it's certainly
uh better than Brooklyn. Yeah.
Now
Now these
Now these are
Now these are the
Now these are the emotions.
Now these are the emotions. I'm
Now these are the emotions. I'm also
Now these are the emotions. I'm also I
practice
practice psychiatry
Now these are the emotions. I'm also I
practice psychiatry for
practice psychiatry for 50
Now these are the emotions. I'm also I
practice psychiatry for 50 years.
practice psychiatry for 50 years. Uh
these
these are
these are the
these are the emotions
these are the emotions that
these are the emotions that go
these are the emotions that go with
these
these and
these are the emotions that go with
these and this
these and this explains
these are the emotions that go with
these and this explains the
these and this explains the process
going
going on
going on in
going on in consciousness
going on in consciousness itself.
And
And you'll
going on in consciousness itself.
And you'll see
And you'll see here
going on in consciousness itself.
And you'll see here inflation
And you'll see here inflation narcissism
the
the reason
the reason it
the reason it brings
the reason it brings down
the reason it brings down the
the reason it brings down the reason
relativism
relativism is
the reason it brings down the reason
relativism is so
relativism is so devastating
the reason it brings down the reason
relativism is so devastating is
relativism is so devastating is this
the reason it brings down the reason
relativism is so devastating is this a
prideful
prideful arrogant
prideful arrogant u
prideful arrogant u what
prideful arrogant u what do
prideful arrogant u what do they
prideful arrogant u what do they call
prideful arrogant u what do they call it
um
um culturally
prideful arrogant u what do they call it
um culturally correct
um culturally correct or
prideful arrogant u what do they call it
um culturally correct or philosophically
elite
elite or
elite or something
>> politically
>> politically correct
>> whatever
>> whatever it
>> whatever it is
>> whatever it is politically
>> whatever it is politically yeah
>> whatever it is politically yeah okay
anyway
anyway it's
>> whatever it is politically yeah okay
anyway it's it's
anyway it's it's at
>> whatever it is politically yeah okay
anyway it's it's at about
anyway it's it's at about 190
>> whatever it is politically yeah okay
anyway it's it's at about 190 but
anyway it's it's at about 190 but you
can
can see
can see it's
can see it's pride
can see it's pride and
can see it's pride and it
can see it's pride and it means
can see it's pride and it means I'm
better
better than
can see it's pride and it means I'm
better than you
better than you and
can see it's pride and it means I'm
better than you and it's
better than you and it's and
can see it's pride and it means I'm
better than you and it's and what
happens
happens here
happens here is
happens here is the
happens here is the ego
happens here is the ego inflation.
happens here is the ego inflation. The
ego
ego becomes
happens here is the ego inflation. The
ego becomes inflated.
ego becomes inflated. So
happens here is the ego inflation. The
ego becomes inflated. So even
ego becomes inflated. So even though
people
people don't
people don't know
people don't know anything
people don't know anything about
people don't know anything about a
subject,
subject, they
people don't know anything about a
subject, they don't
subject, they don't mind
people don't know anything about a
subject, they don't mind getting
subject, they don't mind getting on
television
television and
television and expounding
television and expounding it
television and expounding it and
removing
removing all
television and expounding it and
removing all doubt
removing all doubt about
television and expounding it and
removing all doubt about whether
removing all doubt about whether they're
ignorant
ignorant or
ignorant or not.
ignorant or not. But
then
then you
ignorant or not. But
then you release
then you release on
ignorant or not. But
then you release on it.
then you release on it. So
ignorant or not. But
then you release on it. So if
then you release on it. So if you
ignorant or not. But
then you release on it. So if you want
to
to save
to save the
to save the world,
to save the world, I
to save the world, I would
to save the world, I would suggest
to save the world, I would suggest the
first
first thing
to save the world, I would suggest the
first thing you
first thing you do
to save the world, I would suggest the
first thing you do is
first thing you do is let
to save the world, I would suggest the
first thing you do is let go
first thing you do is let go and
surrender
surrender the
surrender the world
surrender the world to
surrender the world to God,
surrender the world to God, which
surrender the world to God, which is
surrender the world to God, which is the
same
same thing
surrender the world to God, which is the
same thing that
same thing that the
surrender the world to God, which is the
same thing that the great
same thing that the great teachers
surrender the world to God, which is the
same thing that the great teachers have
said
said because
said because the
said because the world
said because the world that
said because the world that you
said because the world that you see
doesn't
doesn't even
said because the world that you see
doesn't even exist.
doesn't even exist. It's
said because the world that you see
doesn't even exist. It's all
doesn't even exist. It's all a
projection
projection of
projection of your
projection of your own
projection of your own perception.
projection of your own perception. So
you
you can
projection of your own perception. So
you can let
you can let go
projection of your own perception. So
you can let go to
you can let go to change
projection of your own perception. So
you can let go to change it
you can let go to change it because
projection of your own perception. So
you can let go to change it because all
you're
you're changing
you're changing is
you're changing is your
you're changing is your own
you're changing is your own projections
that
that you
you're changing is your own projections
that you projected
that you projected out
you're changing is your own projections
that you projected out there.
that you projected out there. You're
you're changing is your own projections
that you projected out there. You're not
changing
changing anything
changing anything in
changing anything in the
changing anything in the world
changing anything in the world at
changing anything in the world at all.
Unless
Unless a
changing anything in the world at all.
Unless a man
Unless a man has
changing anything in the world at all.
Unless a man has a
Unless a man has a choice
changing anything in the world at all.
Unless a man has a choice between
Unless a man has a choice between good
and
and evil,
and evil, how
and evil, how is
and evil, how is he
and evil, how is he going
and evil, how is he going to
and evil, how is he going to transcend?
You
You want
and evil, how is he going to transcend?
You want if
You want if you
and evil, how is he going to transcend?
You want if you don't
You want if you don't have
and evil, how is he going to transcend?
You want if you don't have any
You want if you don't have any enemies,
who
who you
who you got
who you got left
who you got left to
who you got left to forgive?
who you got left to forgive? You
who you got left to forgive? You know,
[laughter]
I'm
I'm a
I'm a failure.
I'm a failure. I
I'm a failure. I haven't
I'm a failure. I haven't got
I'm a failure. I haven't got anybody
left
left to
I'm a failure. I haven't got anybody
left to forgive.
left to forgive. Now
I'm a failure. I haven't got anybody
left to forgive. Now what
left to forgive. Now what do
I'm a failure. I haven't got anybody
left to forgive. Now what do I
left to forgive. Now what do I got
I'm a failure. I haven't got anybody
left to forgive. Now what do I got to
left to forgive. Now what do I got to do
in
in the
in the course
in the course of
in the course of miracles?
>> [laughter]
>> All
>> All right.
>> All right. You
>> All right. You you
>> All right. You you so
>> All right. You you so you
>> All right. You you so you you
>> All right. You you so you you surrender.
You
You let
>> All right. You you so you you surrender.
You let go
You let go to
>> All right. You you so you you surrender.
You let go to change
You let go to change or
>> All right. You you so you you surrender.
You let go to change or control
You let go to change or control things.
And
And as
And as you
And as you do,
And as you do, you
And as you do, you you
And as you do, you you finally
And as you do, you you finally uh
And as you do, you you finally uh move
into
into states
And as you do, you you finally uh move
into states of
uh
spiritual
spiritual work
uh
spiritual work is
spiritual work is primarily
um
um yin.
um yin. Primarily
um yin. Primarily yin.
um yin. Primarily yin. It's
um yin. Primarily yin. It's yang
um yin. Primarily yin. It's yang by
um yin. Primarily yin. It's yang by its
intention,
intention, but
um yin. Primarily yin. It's yang by its
intention, but it's
intention, but it's yin
um yin. Primarily yin. It's yang by its
intention, but it's yin by
intention, but it's yin by its
operation.
by
by means
operation.
by means of
by means of where
operation.
by means of where you
by means of where you I
operation.
by means of where you I ask
by means of where you I ask God
operation.
by means of where you I ask God what
by means of where you I ask God what is
the
the answer
the answer to
the answer to a
the answer to a thing
the answer to a thing and
the answer to a thing and then
the answer to a thing and then I
the answer to a thing and then I step
back
back and
the answer to a thing and then I step
back and allow
back and allow the
the answer to a thing and then I step
back and allow the space
back and allow the space for
the answer to a thing and then I step
back and allow the space for revelation.
Okay.
Okay. So
Okay. So progress
Okay. So progress is
Okay. So progress is often
Okay. So progress is often through
without
without even
Okay. So progress is often through
without even thinking
without even thinking you
Okay. So progress is often through
without even thinking you just
without even thinking you just have
Okay. So progress is often through
without even thinking you just have a
feeling
feeling a
feeling a knowing
feeling a knowing or
feeling a knowing or an
feeling a knowing or an intuition
feeling a knowing or an intuition and
then
then if
feeling a knowing or an intuition and
then if you
then if you know
feeling a knowing or an intuition and
then if you know kinesiology
then if you know kinesiology you
feeling a knowing or an intuition and
then if you know kinesiology you can
just
just check
just check it
just check it out
just check it out for
just check it out for affirmation.
just check it out for affirmation. So
that's
that's the
just check it out for affirmation. So
that's the map
that's the map of
just check it out for affirmation. So
that's the map of consciousness
that's the map of consciousness which
just check it out for affirmation. So
that's the map of consciousness which as
I
I said
I said is
I said is all
I said is all over
I said is all over the
I said is all over the world
I said is all over the world and
I said is all over the world and uh
I said is all over the world and uh has
been
been very
I said is all over the world and uh has
been very very
been very very useful.
I said is all over the world and uh has
been very very useful. Okay,
been very very useful. Okay, we'll
I said is all over the world and uh has
been very very useful. Okay, we'll move
on.
on. Any
on. Any questions
on. Any questions about
on. Any questions about it
on. Any questions about it before
on. Any questions about it before we
on. Any questions about it before we go?
Any
Any questions?
on. Any questions about it before we go?
Any questions? We're
Any questions? We're going
on. Any questions about it before we go?
Any questions? We're going to
Any questions? We're going to have
questions
questions and
questions and answers
questions and answers later,
questions and answers later, but
questions and answers later, but I
questions and answers later, but I don't
mind
mind a
questions and answers later, but I don't
mind a general
mind a general question.
questions and answers later, but I don't
mind a general question. The
mind a general question. The enlightened
and
and divine
and divine states.
and divine states. Uhhuh.
The
The supreme
and divine states. Uhhuh.
The supreme godhead.
The supreme godhead. All
and divine states. Uhhuh.
The supreme godhead. All these
The supreme godhead. All these things
calibrate
calibrate at
calibrate at 1,000
calibrate at 1,000 or
calibrate at 1,000 or over
calibrate at 1,000 or over teacher
calibrate at 1,000 or over teacher like
eyes.
eyes. I
calibrate at 1,000 or over teacher like
eyes. I don't
eyes. I don't know
calibrate at 1,000 or over teacher like
eyes. I don't know why
eyes. I don't know why this
calibrate at 1,000 or over teacher like
eyes. I don't know why this is
eyes. I don't know why this is up
calibrate at 1,000 or over teacher like
eyes. I don't know why this is up here.
Um,
we
we traveled.
Um,
we traveled. We
we traveled. We went
Um,
we traveled. We went to
we traveled. We went to Archangel.
Um,
we traveled. We went to Archangel. Let's
get
get rid
get rid of
get rid of all
get rid of all these
get rid of all these people.
get rid of all these people. Let's
get rid of all these people. Let's take
them
them off.
We
We know
We know who
We know who they
We know who they are,
We know who they are, don't
We know who they are, don't we?
This
This is
We know who they are, don't we?
This is the
This is the uh
We know who they are, don't we?
This is the uh power
This is the uh power in
We know who they are, don't we?
This is the uh power in microwatts.
uh
uh as
uh as you
uh as you the
uh as you the levels
uh as you the levels of
uh as you the levels of consciousness
uh as you the levels of consciousness go
up
up and
uh as you the levels of consciousness go
up and the
up and the originator
uh as you the levels of consciousness go
up and the originator of
up and the originator of that
uh as you the levels of consciousness go
up and the originator of that is
up and the originator of that is with
uh as you the levels of consciousness go
up and the originator of that is with us
today.
today. Okay,
today. Okay, we'll
today. Okay, we'll move
today. Okay, we'll move on.
This
This is
today. Okay, we'll move on.
This is the
This is the world's
today. Okay, we'll move on.
This is the world's population.
Uh
Uh these
Uh these have
Uh these have to
Uh these have to be
Uh these have to be brought
Uh these have to be brought up
Uh these have to be brought up today.
Uh these have to be brought up today. Um
below
below level
Uh these have to be brought up today. Um
below level 200.
Uh
Uh let's
Uh let's see.
Uh let's see. We
Uh let's see. We have
Uh let's see. We have permission
Uh let's see. We have permission to
Uh let's see. We have permission to ask
this
this in
Uh let's see. We have permission to ask
this in front
this in front of
Uh let's see. We have permission to ask
this in front of this
this in front of this group.
Uh let's see. We have permission to ask
this in front of this group. Uh
this in front of this group. Uh we
Uh let's see. We have permission to ask
this in front of this group. Uh we have
permission
permission to
permission to ask
permission to ask this
permission to ask this in
permission to ask this in front
permission to ask this in front of
permission to ask this in front of this
group.
group. Resist.
No,
No, we
No, we do
No, we do not
No, we do not have
No, we do not have permission
No, we do not have permission today.
Wow.
Wow. Okay.
No, we do not have permission today.
Wow. Okay. I
Wow. Okay. I don't
No, we do not have permission today.
Wow. Okay. I don't don't
Wow. Okay. I don't don't know
No, we do not have permission today.
Wow. Okay. I don't don't know why.
Uh
Uh anyway,
Uh anyway, the
Uh anyway, the majority
Uh anyway, the majority of
Uh anyway, the majority of the
Uh anyway, the majority of the world's
population,
population, we'll
Uh anyway, the majority of the world's
population, we'll move
population, we'll move on
Uh anyway, the majority of the world's
population, we'll move on to
population, we'll move on to the
Uh anyway, the majority of the world's
population, we'll move on to the next
slide.
slide. The
slide. The majority
slide. The majority of
slide. The majority of the
slide. The majority of the world's
population,
population, here's
slide. The majority of the world's
population, here's a
population, here's a better
slide. The majority of the world's
population, here's a better way
population, here's a better way to
demonstrate
demonstrate it.
demonstrate it. Uh
demonstrate it. Uh calibrates
demonstrate it. Uh calibrates below
demonstrate it. Uh calibrates below 200.
Huh?
Huh? Uh
demonstrate it. Uh calibrates below 200.
Huh? Uh why
Huh? Uh why doesn't
demonstrate it. Uh calibrates below 200.
Huh? Uh why doesn't the
Huh? Uh why doesn't the world
demonstrate it. Uh calibrates below 200.
Huh? Uh why doesn't the world go
Huh? Uh why doesn't the world go to
pieces
pieces and
pieces and just
pieces and just destroy
pieces and just destroy itself?
pieces and just destroy itself? It
pieces and just destroy itself? It gets
close
close to
pieces and just destroy itself? It gets
close to it
close to it periodically.
pieces and just destroy itself? It gets
close to it periodically. You
close to it periodically. You know,
mankind
mankind has
mankind has been
mankind has been at
mankind has been at war
mankind has been at war 93%
mankind has been at war 93% of
mankind has been at war 93% of recorded
time.
time. 93%.
The
The other
The other 7%
The other 7% he
The other 7% he was
The other 7% he was too
The other 7% he was too sick
The other 7% he was too sick or
The other 7% he was too sick or too
poor.
poor. Probably
The other 7% he was too sick or too
poor. Probably the
poor. Probably the plague
The other 7% he was too sick or too
poor. Probably the plague was
poor. Probably the plague was on
The other 7% he was too sick or too
poor. Probably the plague was on him.
Couldn't
Couldn't get
Couldn't get his
Couldn't get his butt
Couldn't get his butt together
Couldn't get his butt together to
Couldn't get his butt together to get
out
out there
Couldn't get his butt together to get
out there and
out there and kill
Couldn't get his butt together to get
out there and kill somebody.
God
God help
God help me
God help me get
God help me get together
God help me get together so
God help me get together so I
God help me get together so I can
God help me get together so I can go
God help me get together so I can go out
and
and kill
God help me get together so I can go out
and kill the
and kill the enemy.
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, why
All right. So, why doesn't
All right. So, why doesn't the
All right. So, why doesn't the world
just
just self-destruct?
All right. So, why doesn't the world
just self-destruct? uh
just self-destruct? uh it's
All right. So, why doesn't the world
just self-destruct? uh it's because
just self-destruct? uh it's because the
it's
it's a
it's a logarithmic
it's a logarithmic scale.
it's a logarithmic scale. So
logarithmically
logarithmically the
it's a logarithmic scale. So
logarithmically the advance
logarithmically the advance of
it's a logarithmic scale. So
logarithmically the advance of a
logarithmically the advance of a few
point
point is
point is enormously
point is enormously powerful.
point is enormously powerful. Just
point is enormously powerful. Just these
few
few people
point is enormously powerful. Just these
few people here
few people here in
point is enormously powerful. Just these
few people here in fact
few people here in fact in
point is enormously powerful. Just these
few people here in fact in the
few people here in fact in the United
States
States even
States even just
States even just a
States even just a couple
States even just a couple of
States even just a couple of people
calibrate
calibrate so
States even just a couple of people
calibrate so high
calibrate so high and
States even just a couple of people
calibrate so high and logarithmically
the
the power
the power is
the power is so
the power is so great
the power is so great that
the power is so great that it
the power is so great that it totally
next
next slide
the power is so great that it totally
next slide totally
next slide totally counterbalances
the power is so great that it totally
next slide totally counterbalances the
negativity
negativity of
negativity of mankind
negativity of mankind which
negativity of mankind which would
self-destruct.
self-destruct. So
negativity of mankind which would
self-destruct. So those
self-destruct. So those who
negativity of mankind which would
self-destruct. So those who are
self-destruct. So those who are 200
negativity of mankind which would
self-destruct. So those who are 200 and
up
up uh
up uh who
up uh who are
up uh who are all
up uh who are all here
up uh who are all here today
up uh who are all here today [laughter]
are
are keeping
up uh who are all here today [laughter]
are keeping the
are keeping the world
up uh who are all here today [laughter]
are keeping the world from
are keeping the world from going
up uh who are all here today [laughter]
are keeping the world from going down
the
the tubes.
So
So the
the tubes.
So the relative
So the relative power
the tubes.
So the relative power because
So the relative power because it's
logarithmic
logarithmic is
logarithmic is so
logarithmic is so enormous
logarithmic is so enormous that
logarithmic is so enormous that it
counterbalances
counterbalances the
logarithmic is so enormous that it
counterbalances the negativity.
counterbalances the negativity. We'll
move
move on
move on to
move on to the
move on to the next
move on to the next sense.
move on to the next sense. the
move on to the next sense. the evolution
of
of consciousness
move on to the next sense. the evolution
of consciousness over
of consciousness over time
move on to the next sense. the evolution
of consciousness over time as
of consciousness over time as we
move on to the next sense. the evolution
of consciousness over time as we said
of consciousness over time as we said n
it
it was
it was at
it was at 90
it was at 90 at
it was at 90 at the
it was at 90 at the time
it was at 90 at the time of
it was at 90 at the time of the
it was at 90 at the time of the Buddha
100 at
100 at the
it was at 90 at the time of the Buddha
100 at the time
100 at the time of
it was at 90 at the time of the Buddha
100 at the time of Jesus
100 at the time of Jesus Christ
it was at 90 at the time of the Buddha
100 at the time of Jesus Christ and
100 at the time of Jesus Christ and then
you
you see
you see here's
you see here's where
you see here's where we
you see here's where we are
you see here's where we are on
you see here's where we are on the
you see here's where we are on the curve
now
now so
you see here's where we are on the curve
now so here
now so here it
you see here's where we are on the curve
now so here it was
now so here it was 100
you see here's where we are on the curve
now so here it was 100 at
now so here it was 100 at the
you see here's where we are on the curve
now so here it was 100 at the time
now so here it was 100 at the time of
Jesus
Jesus Christ
Jesus Christ and
Jesus Christ and you
Jesus Christ and you can
Jesus Christ and you can see
Jesus Christ and you can see that
Jesus Christ and you can see that the
consciousness
consciousness level
Jesus Christ and you can see that the
consciousness level of
consciousness level of mankind
Jesus Christ and you can see that the
consciousness level of mankind is
consciousness level of mankind is on
Jesus Christ and you can see that the
consciousness level of mankind is on a
very
very rapid
very rapid so
very rapid so it's
very rapid so it's like
very rapid so it's like it
very rapid so it's like it didd
very rapid so it's like it didd around
here
here for
very rapid so it's like it didd around
here for couple
here for couple million
very rapid so it's like it didd around
here for couple million years
here for couple million years and
very rapid so it's like it didd around
here for couple million years and then
suddenly
suddenly got
suddenly got busy
And
And now
suddenly got busy
And now it's
And now it's moving
suddenly got busy
And now it's moving up
And now it's moving up at
suddenly got busy
And now it's moving up at a
And now it's moving up at a rapid
suddenly got busy
And now it's moving up at a rapid rate.
Although
Although we
Although we have
Although we have it's
Although we have it's been
Although we have it's been going
Although we have it's been going down
the
the last
Although we have it's been going down
the last uh
the last uh couple
Although we have it's been going down
the last uh couple of
the last uh couple of months.
Although we have it's been going down
the last uh couple of months. Right.
Okay.
Uh-huh.
Now
Now the
Now the uh
Now the uh we
Now the uh we just
Now the uh we just want
Now the uh we just want to
Now the uh we just want to show
Now the uh we just want to show the
source
source of
Now the uh we just want to show the
source of the
source of the evil
Now the uh we just want to show the
source of the evil of
source of the evil of the
Now the uh we just want to show the
source of the evil of the ego.
[laughter]
The
The evil.
The ego.
The ego. The
The ego. The uh
The ego. The uh ego.
The ego. The uh ego. [laughter]
All
All right,
The ego. The uh ego. [laughter]
All right, we'll
All right, we'll clarify
The ego. The uh ego. [laughter]
All right, we'll clarify you
All right, we'll clarify you know
The ego. The uh ego. [laughter]
All right, we'll clarify you know um
evil
evil because
evil because you
evil because you see
evil because you see consciousness
evil because you see consciousness began
at
at a
evil because you see consciousness began
at a very
at a very primitive
evil because you see consciousness began
at a very primitive level.
at a very primitive level. The
consciousness
consciousness level
consciousness level uh
consciousness level uh over
consciousness level uh over billions
billions
billions and
consciousness level uh over billions
billions and billions
billions and billions of
consciousness level uh over billions
billions and billions of years.
billions and billions of years. The
consciousness
consciousness level
consciousness level uh
consciousness level uh slowly
consciousness level uh slowly arose
consciousness level uh slowly arose over
um
um great
consciousness level uh slowly arose over
um great earth
um great earth epics.
And
And as
And as you
And as you can
And as you can see
And as you can see the
And as you can see the consciousness
level
level of
And as you can see the consciousness
level of life
level of life itself
And as you can see the consciousness
level of life itself the
level of life itself the total
consciousness
consciousness level
consciousness level of
consciousness level of life
consciousness level of life on
consciousness level of life on the
planet
planet has
consciousness level of life on the
planet has evolved
planet has evolved over
consciousness level of life on the
planet has evolved over uh
planet has evolved over uh millions
consciousness level of life on the
planet has evolved over uh millions and
millions
millions and
millions and millions
millions and millions of
millions and millions of years
millions and millions of years very
millions and millions of years very very
slowly.
slowly. This
millions and millions of years very very
slowly. This is
slowly. This is the
millions and millions of years very very
slowly. This is the duration
slowly. This is the duration and
millions and millions of years very very
slowly. This is the duration and this
slowly. This is the duration and this is
the
the consciousness
the consciousness level
the consciousness level and
the consciousness level and we
the consciousness level and we can
the consciousness level and we can see
it.
it. These
the consciousness level and we can see
it. These numbers
it. These numbers are
the consciousness level and we can see
it. These numbers are so
it. These numbers are so big
the consciousness level and we can see
it. These numbers are so big I
it. These numbers are so big I don't
know
know what
know what they
know what they mean.
know what they mean. And
know what they mean. And anyway,
know what they mean. And anyway, it's
know what they mean. And anyway, it's a
big
big lot
know what they mean. And anyway, it's a
big lot of
big lot of zeros.
know what they mean. And anyway, it's a
big lot of zeros. Over
big lot of zeros. Over that
know what they mean. And anyway, it's a
big lot of zeros. Over that amount
big lot of zeros. Over that amount of
time,
time, it
time, it only
time, it only went
time, it only went from
time, it only went from one
time, it only went from one to
time, it only went from one to two.
And
And over
time, it only went from one to two.
And over a
And over a whole
time, it only went from one to two.
And over a whole bunch
And over a whole bunch more
time, it only went from one to two.
And over a whole bunch more zeros
And over a whole bunch more zeros of
centuries,
centuries, it
centuries, it only
centuries, it only went
centuries, it only went up
centuries, it only went up to
centuries, it only went up to 12.
centuries, it only went up to 12. And
centuries, it only went up to 12. And so
you
you can
centuries, it only went up to 12. And so
you can see
you can see extremely
centuries, it only went up to 12. And so
you can see extremely slowly
you can see extremely slowly the
consciousness
consciousness level
consciousness level of
consciousness level of life
consciousness level of life overall
consciousness level of life overall on
the
the planet.
consciousness level of life overall on
the planet. Life
the planet. Life overall
consciousness level of life overall on
the planet. Life overall on
the planet. Life overall on the
consciousness level of life overall on
the planet. Life overall on the planet.
Sometimes
Sometimes the
Sometimes the animal
Sometimes the animal the
Sometimes the animal the consciousness
level
level of
Sometimes the animal the consciousness
level of the
level of the animals
Sometimes the animal the consciousness
level of the animals has
level of the animals has what
Sometimes the animal the consciousness
level of the animals has what kept
level of the animals has what kept it
has
has kept
has kept it
has kept it up.
has kept it up. So
has kept it up. So we'll
has kept it up. So we'll move
has kept it up. So we'll move to
has kept it up. So we'll move to the
next
next one.
Even
Even though
Even though man
Even though man has
Even though man has been
Even though man has been lower
Even though man has been lower than
Even though man has been lower than 200
many
many times
Even though man has been lower than 200
many times you
many times you see
Even though man has been lower than 200
many times you see there
many times you see there are
Even though man has been lower than 200
many times you see there are many
animals
animals on
animals on the
animals on the planet
animals on the planet there
animals on the planet there are
animals on the planet there are over
200.
Aha.
Somebody
Somebody said
Aha.
Somebody said well
Somebody said well the
Aha.
Somebody said well the consciousness
level
level of
level of man
level of man is
level of man is at
level of man is at 204
level of man is at 204 or
level of man is at 204 or something.
level of man is at 204 or something. How
come
come you
level of man is at 204 or something. How
come you got
come you got life
level of man is at 204 or something. How
come you got life is
come you got life is at
level of man is at 204 or something. How
come you got life is at 212?
Because
Because we
Because we got
Because we got kitties,
Because we got kitties, doggies.
[laughter]
A
A dog
A dog wagon
A dog wagon tail
A dog wagon tail is
A dog wagon tail is at
A dog wagon tail is at 500.
What
What does
A dog wagon tail is at 500.
What does the
What does the What
A dog wagon tail is at 500.
What does the What did
What does the What did the
A dog wagon tail is at 500.
What does the What did the shoe
What does the What did the shoe bomber
calibrate
calibrate at?
calibrate at? I
calibrate at? I think
calibrate at? I think about
calibrate at? I think about 70
calibrate at? I think about 70 to
calibrate at? I think about 70 to 90
calibrate at? I think about 70 to 90 or
something
something like
calibrate at? I think about 70 to 90 or
something like that.
something like that. So,
I
I don't
I don't want
I don't want to
I don't want to say
I don't want to say anything
that
that might
I don't want to say anything
that might hurt
that might hurt people's
I don't want to say anything
that might hurt people's feelings,
but
but cats
but cats and
but cats and dogs
but cats and dogs do
but cats and dogs do better
but cats and dogs do better in
chimpanzees
chimpanzees and
but cats and dogs do better in
chimpanzees and gorillas.
chimpanzees and gorillas. You're
but cats and dogs do better in
chimpanzees and gorillas. You're safer
with
with uh
with uh Coco
with uh Coco the
with uh Coco the gorilla
with uh Coco the gorilla than
with uh Coco the gorilla than you
with uh Coco the gorilla than you are
with
with most
with uh Coco the gorilla than you are
with most of
with most of the
with uh Coco the gorilla than you are
with most of the people
with most of the people on
with uh Coco the gorilla than you are
with most of the people on the
with most of the people on the subway.
with uh Coco the gorilla than you are
with most of the people on the subway. I
find
find [laughter]
Coco
Coco won't
find [laughter]
Coco won't steal
Coco won't steal your
find [laughter]
Coco won't steal your person,
Coco won't steal your person, right?
monkeys,
monkeys, the
monkeys, the family
monkeys, the family dogs,
uh
uh family
monkeys, the family dogs,
uh family cats.
uh family cats. Uh,
monkeys, the family dogs,
uh family cats. Uh, of
uh family cats. Uh, of course,
monkeys, the family dogs,
uh family cats. Uh, of course, the
uh family cats. Uh, of course, the more
cats
cats you
cats you have,
cats you have, the
cats you have, the higher
cats you have, the higher your
cats you have, the higher your level
cats you have, the higher your level of
consciousness.
Our
Our cats
Our cats support
Our cats support our
Our cats support our level
Our cats support our level of
consciousness
consciousness at
Our cats support our level of
consciousness at home.
consciousness at home. Without
Our cats support our level of
consciousness at home. Without the
consciousness at home. Without the cats,
we
we would
we would probably
we would probably collapse.
we would probably collapse. And
we would probably collapse. And horses
and
and elephants.
we would probably collapse. And horses
and elephants. And
and elephants. And of
we would probably collapse. And horses
and elephants. And of course,
and elephants. And of course, elephants
get
get mad,
get mad, too.
get mad, too. And
get mad, too. And dairy
get mad, too. And dairy cows.
get mad, too. And dairy cows. You
get mad, too. And dairy cows. You see
these
these are
get mad, too. And dairy cows. You see
these are all
these are all uh
get mad, too. And dairy cows. You see
these are all uh primarily
these are all uh primarily her
herbivores.
And
And when
herbivores.
And when you
And when you see
herbivores.
And when you see how
And when you see how life
herbivores.
And when you see how life starts
And when you see how life starts out
herbivores.
And when you see how life starts out at
the
the lowest
the lowest level
the lowest level uh
the lowest level uh we
the lowest level uh we come
the lowest level uh we come up
the lowest level uh we come up through
the
the fish,
the lowest level uh we come up through
the fish, the
the fish, the octopus,
the lowest level uh we come up through
the fish, the octopus, the
the fish, the octopus, the komodo
the lowest level uh we come up through
the fish, the octopus, the komodo dragon
and
and predatory
and predatory mammals.
and predatory mammals. You
and predatory mammals. You see
and predatory mammals. You see uh
and predatory mammals. You see uh life
is
is voracious.
and predatory mammals. You see uh life
is voracious. Below
is voracious. Below conscious
and predatory mammals. You see uh life
is voracious. Below conscious level
is voracious. Below conscious level 200
uh
uh it
uh it only
uh it only can
uh it only can survive
uh it only can survive by
uh it only can survive by eating
uh it only can survive by eating others,
eating
eating others,
uh it only can survive by eating others,
eating others, killing
eating others, killing others.
uh it only can survive by eating others,
eating others, killing others. And
eating others, killing others. And then
as
as consciousness
as consciousness level
as consciousness level get
as consciousness level get goes
as consciousness level get goes higher
uh
uh you
as consciousness level get goes higher
uh you get
uh you get to
as consciousness level get goes higher
uh you get to the
uh you get to the herbivores
you
you get
you get to
you get to the
you get to the herbivores.
So
So you
you get to the herbivores.
So you see
So you see at
you get to the herbivores.
So you see at consciousness
So you see at consciousness level
you get to the herbivores.
So you see at consciousness level 200.
So
So here
So here we
So here we have
So here we have havalina
So here we have havalina and
So here we have havalina and here
So here we have havalina and here we
have
have wolves
So here we have havalina and here we
have wolves and
have wolves and foxes.
So here we have havalina and here we
have wolves and foxes. And
have wolves and foxes. And then
So here we have havalina and here we
have wolves and foxes. And then all
have wolves and foxes. And then all of a
sudden
sudden at
sudden at the
sudden at the level
sudden at the level 200
sudden at the level 200 you
sudden at the level 200 you shift
sudden at the level 200 you shift to
zebras,
zebras, giraffes,
sudden at the level 200 you shift to
zebras, giraffes, deer,
zebras, giraffes, deer, bison,
sudden at the level 200 you shift to
zebras, giraffes, deer, bison, even
domestic
domestic pigs,
domestic pigs, uh
domestic pigs, uh the
domestic pigs, uh the elk,
domestic pigs, uh the elk, deer,
domestic pigs, uh the elk, deer, dairy
cows,
cows, sheep,
domestic pigs, uh the elk, deer, dairy
cows, sheep, range
cows, sheep, range cattle.
domestic pigs, uh the elk, deer, dairy
cows, sheep, range cattle. You
cows, sheep, range cattle. You see
domestic pigs, uh the elk, deer, dairy
cows, sheep, range cattle. You see the
shift?
shift? You
shift? You eat
shift? You eat grass
shift? You eat grass and
shift? You eat grass and you're
shift? You eat grass and you're not
killing
killing anybody.
shift? You eat grass and you're not
killing anybody. U
killing anybody. U whereas
shift? You eat grass and you're not
killing anybody. U whereas the
killing anybody. U whereas the dinosaur
has
has to
has to kill.
has to kill. He
has to kill. He has
has to kill. He has to
has to kill. He has to kill
has to kill. He has to kill in
has to kill. He has to kill in order
has to kill. He has to kill in order to
eat.
eat. So
has to kill. He has to kill in order to
eat. So his
eat. So his nature
has to kill. He has to kill in order to
eat. So his nature is
eat. So his nature is to
has to kill. He has to kill in order to
eat. So his nature is to kill.
He's
He's not
He's not being
He's not being bad
He's not being bad or
He's not being bad or evil.
He's not being bad or evil. That's
He's not being bad or evil. That's just
his
his nature.
He's not being bad or evil. That's just
his nature. is
his nature. is reflecting
He's not being bad or evil. That's just
his nature. is reflecting the
his nature. is reflecting the level
He's not being bad or evil. That's just
his nature. is reflecting the level of
consciousness.
consciousness. So
consciousness. So many
consciousness. So many people
consciousness. So many people on
consciousness. So many people on the
planet
who
who seem
who seem to
who seem to be
who seem to be focused
who seem to be focused on
who seem to be focused on killing
who seem to be focused on killing them.
It's
It's because
who seem to be focused on killing them.
It's because their
It's because their level
who seem to be focused on killing them.
It's because their level of
consciousness
consciousness is
consciousness is attuned
consciousness is attuned uh
consciousness is attuned uh to
consciousness is attuned uh to be
consciousness is attuned uh to be less
than
than 200
consciousness is attuned uh to be less
than 200 and
than 200 and therefore
consciousness is attuned uh to be less
than 200 and therefore the
than 200 and therefore the left
consciousness is attuned uh to be less
than 200 and therefore the left brain
the
the left
the left in
the left in the
the left in the instinctual
the left in the instinctual left
the left in the instinctual left brain
physiology
physiology takes
the left in the instinctual left brain
physiology takes over
physiology takes over in
the left in the instinctual left brain
physiology takes over in which
physiology takes over in which killing
becomes
becomes exciting,
becomes exciting, fun
becomes exciting, fun and
becomes exciting, fun and rewarding.
Huh.
Huh. Yes.
becomes exciting, fun and rewarding.
Huh. Yes. And
Huh. Yes. And these
becomes exciting, fun and rewarding.
Huh. Yes. And these people
Huh. Yes. And these people here
becomes exciting, fun and rewarding.
Huh. Yes. And these people here are
quite
quite reluctant
quite reluctant to
quite reluctant to kill
quite reluctant to kill anything.
quite reluctant to kill anything. And
quite reluctant to kill anything. And if
they
they do
quite reluctant to kill anything. And if
they do it
they do it by
quite reluctant to kill anything. And if
they do it by accident,
they do it by accident, they
quite reluctant to kill anything. And if
they do it by accident, they stepped
they do it by accident, they stepped on
it.
it. [laughter]
Okay,
Okay, the
it. [laughter]
Okay, the next
Okay, the next one.
Uh,
Uh, yes,
Uh, yes, we
Uh, yes, we talked
Uh, yes, we talked about
Uh, yes, we talked about the
Uh, yes, we talked about the 400s
Uh, yes, we talked about the 400s as
being
being uh,
Uh, yes, we talked about the 400s as
being uh, you
being uh, you might
Uh, yes, we talked about the 400s as
being uh, you might say
being uh, you might say man
Uh, yes, we talked about the 400s as
being uh, you might say man reached
being uh, you might say man reached his
greatest
greatest intellectual
greatest intellectual excellence
greatest intellectual excellence in
probably
probably around
greatest intellectual excellence in
probably around 350
probably around 350 BC.
uh
uh ancient
uh ancient Greece.
uh ancient Greece. So
uh ancient Greece. So the
philosophically
philosophically there
uh ancient Greece. So the
philosophically there really
philosophically there really hasn't
uh ancient Greece. So the
philosophically there really hasn't been
any
any improvement
any improvement uh
any improvement uh since
any improvement uh since that
any improvement uh since that time.
any improvement uh since that time. Uh
and
and here
any improvement uh since that time. Uh
and here we
and here we calibrate
any improvement uh since that time. Uh
and here we calibrate the
and here we calibrate the great
any improvement uh since that time. Uh
and here we calibrate the great books
and here we calibrate the great books of
the
the western
the western world.
the western world. Uh
the western world. Uh and
the western world. Uh and we
the western world. Uh and we find
the western world. Uh and we find this
very
very interesting
the western world. Uh and we find this
very interesting overall
very interesting overall collectively
the western world. Uh and we find this
very interesting overall collectively it
calibrates
calibrates around
calibrates around 460.
So
So intellectual
calibrates around 460.
So intellectual excellence,
So intellectual excellence, intellectual
truth,
truth, reason
truth, reason uh
truth, reason uh is
truth, reason uh is in
truth, reason uh is in the
truth, reason uh is in the 400s.
truth, reason uh is in the 400s. Here
you
you see
truth, reason uh is in the 400s. Here
you see the
you see the great
truth, reason uh is in the 400s. Here
you see the great names
you see the great names of
truth, reason uh is in the 400s. Here
you see the great names of history.
you see the great names of history. Uh
uh
uh all
uh all the
uh all the great
uh all the great names
uh all the great names that
uh all the great names that are
uh all the great names that are famous
and
and uh
uh all the great names that are famous
and uh in
and uh in the
uh all the great names that are famous
and uh in the old
and uh in the old days
uh all the great names that are famous
and uh in the old days a
and uh in the old days a liberal
education
education meant
education meant to
education meant to study
education meant to study all
education meant to study all of
education meant to study all of these
writers
writers and
education meant to study all of these
writers and there
writers and there is
education meant to study all of these
writers and there is still
writers and there is still a
education meant to study all of these
writers and there is still a foundation
for
for the
for the study
for the study of
for the study of the
for the study of the great
for the study of the great books.
for the study of the great books. Uh
they
they they
for the study of the great books. Uh
they they advise
they they advise you
for the study of the great books. Uh
they they advise you to
they they advise you to take
for the study of the great books. Uh
they they advise you to take 10
they they advise you to take 10 years.
So
So it
So it we
So it we spend
So it we spend 10
So it we spend 10 years
So it we spend 10 years and
So it we spend 10 years and uh
So it we spend 10 years and uh you
So it we spend 10 years and uh you will
then
then share
So it we spend 10 years and uh you will
then share common
then share common understanding
So it we spend 10 years and uh you will
then share common understanding with
then share common understanding with all
the
the greatest
the greatest minds
the greatest minds that
the greatest minds that have
the greatest minds that have ever
the greatest minds that have ever lived
at least
at least within
the greatest minds that have ever lived
at least within the
at least within the intellectual
the greatest minds that have ever lived
at least within the intellectual and
philosophic
philosophic realms.
philosophic realms. Uh
philosophic realms. Uh the
philosophic realms. Uh the only
philosophic realms. Uh the only ringer
in
in this
philosophic realms. Uh the only ringer
in this whole
in this whole group
philosophic realms. Uh the only ringer
in this whole group and
in this whole group and he
philosophic realms. Uh the only ringer
in this whole group and he got
in this whole group and he got in
philosophic realms. Uh the only ringer
in this whole group and he got in there
by
by mistake
by mistake is
by mistake is Karl
by mistake is Karl Marx
by mistake is Karl Marx at
by mistake is Karl Marx at 130.
Uh
Uh otherwise
by mistake is Karl Marx at 130.
Uh otherwise and
Uh otherwise and Engles
by mistake is Karl Marx at 130.
Uh otherwise and Engles at
Uh otherwise and Engles at 200.
So
So this
So this 130
So this 130 here
So this 130 here brings
So this 130 here brings down
So this 130 here brings down the
So this 130 here brings down the average
of
of the
So this 130 here brings down the average
of the whole
of the whole group.
So this 130 here brings down the average
of the whole group. So
of the whole group. So the
So this 130 here brings down the average
of the whole group. So the the
difficulty
difficulty of
difficulty of something
difficulty of something of
difficulty of something of a
difficulty of something of a very
difficulty of something of a very low
calibration
uh
uh is
uh is that
uh is that this
uh is that this then
uh is that this then starts
uh is that this then starts off
uh is that this then starts off a
uh is that this then starts off a trend
which
which becomes
uh is that this then starts off a trend
which becomes self
which becomes self propagating
uh is that this then starts off a trend
which becomes self propagating in
which becomes self propagating in the
form
form of
form of memes
form of memes mess
uh
uh becomes
form of memes mess
uh becomes self-propagating.
[clears throat]
[clears throat] So
[clears throat] So an
[clears throat] So an infection
[clears throat] So an infection like
this
this can
[clears throat] So an infection like
this can then
this can then spread
[clears throat] So an infection like
this can then spread throughout
this can then spread throughout the
world
world and
world and I
world and I think
world and I think the
world and I think the way
world and I think the way we
world and I think the way we found
world and I think the way we found out
this
this morning
world and I think the way we found out
this morning it's
this morning it's decrease
world and I think the way we found out
this morning it's decrease has
this morning it's decrease has been
world and I think the way we found out
this morning it's decrease has been due
to
to that
to that effect.
to that effect. Uh
to that effect. Uh so
to that effect. Uh so we
to that effect. Uh so we could
to that effect. Uh so we could spend
really
really the
to that effect. Uh so we could spend
really the whole
really the whole lecture
to that effect. Uh so we could spend
really the whole lecture today
really the whole lecture today on
to that effect. Uh so we could spend
really the whole lecture today on any
one
one of
one of these
one of these things,
one of these things, but
one of these things, but these
one of these things, but these were
one of these things, but these were my
friends
friends of
one of these things, but these were my
friends of childhood.
friends of childhood. I
one of these things, but these were my
friends of childhood. I had
friends of childhood. I had a
one of these things, but these were my
friends of childhood. I had a misspent
childhood.
Uh
Uh I
childhood.
Uh I just
Uh I just didn't
childhood.
Uh I just didn't go
Uh I just didn't go for
childhood.
Uh I just didn't go for uh
Uh I just didn't go for uh contact
sports
sports and
sports and wrestling,
sports and wrestling, all
sports and wrestling, all that
sports and wrestling, all that stuff.
sports and wrestling, all that stuff. I
uh
uh was
sports and wrestling, all that stuff. I
uh was a
uh was a bookworm,
sports and wrestling, all that stuff. I
uh was a bookworm, skinny
uh was a bookworm, skinny ectomorph
sports and wrestling, all that stuff. I
uh was a bookworm, skinny ectomorph with
glasses,
glasses, tri
glasses, tri focals,
glasses, tri focals, and
glasses, tri focals, and I
glasses, tri focals, and I and
glasses, tri focals, and I and I
glasses, tri focals, and I and I I
glasses, tri focals, and I and I I live
the
the these
glasses, tri focals, and I and I I live
the these are
the these are all
glasses, tri focals, and I and I I live
the these are all my
the these are all my friends.
These
These are
These are my
These are my friends
These are my friends from
These are my friends from childhood.
These are my friends from childhood. And
uh
uh Socrates
These are my friends from childhood. And
uh Socrates was
uh Socrates was always
These are my friends from childhood. And
uh Socrates was always my
uh Socrates was always my favorite.
Uh
Uh so
Uh so as
Uh so as a
Uh so as a kid,
Uh so as a kid, we
Uh so as a kid, we would
Uh so as a kid, we would get
Uh so as a kid, we would get together,
Uh so as a kid, we would get together, I
had
had a
Uh so as a kid, we would get together, I
had a couple
had a couple other
Uh so as a kid, we would get together, I
had a couple other intellectual
had a couple other intellectual friends,
and
and we
and we would
and we would discuss,
and we would discuss, you
and we would discuss, you know,
and we would discuss, you know, Play-Doh
and
and all
and we would discuss, you know, Play-Doh
and all this
and all this kind
and we would discuss, you know, Play-Doh
and all this kind of
and all this kind of stuff
and we would discuss, you know, Play-Doh
and all this kind of stuff while
and all this kind of stuff while the
other
other kids
other kids were
other kids were playing
other kids were playing stick
other kids were playing stick ball
other kids were playing stick ball or
other kids were playing stick ball or or
they
they were
other kids were playing stick ball or or
they were always
they were always into
other kids were playing stick ball or or
they were always into some
they were always into some disgusting
physical
physical thing
physical thing with
physical thing with their
physical thing with their greasy,
physical thing with their greasy, dirty
fingernails
fingernails gouging
physical thing with their greasy, dirty
fingernails gouging each
fingernails gouging each other
physical thing with their greasy, dirty
fingernails gouging each other in
fingernails gouging each other in the
eyes.
eyes. And
eyes. And I
eyes. And I can
eyes. And I can never
eyes. And I can never get
eyes. And I can never get what
eyes. And I can never get what the
eyes. And I can never get what the point
of
of that
eyes. And I can never get what the point
of that was.
after
after it's
after it's all
after it's all over,
after it's all over, what
after it's all over, what do
after it's all over, what do you
after it's all over, what do you know
that
that you
after it's all over, what do you know
that you didn't
that you didn't know
after it's all over, what do you know
that you didn't know before?
that you didn't know before? [laughter]
I'm
I'm gonna
I'm gonna spend
I'm gonna spend the
I'm gonna spend the afternoon.
I'm gonna spend the afternoon. I
I'm gonna spend the afternoon. I want
I'm gonna spend the afternoon. I want to
know
know what
I'm gonna spend the afternoon. I want to
know what Homer
know what Homer had
I'm gonna spend the afternoon. I want to
know what Homer had to
know what Homer had to teach
I'm gonna spend the afternoon. I want to
know what Homer had to teach us.
know what Homer had to teach us. You
know
know what
know what I
know what I mean?
And
And I'm
know what I mean?
And I'm still
And I'm still that
know what I mean?
And I'm still that way.
And I'm still that way. I
know what I mean?
And I'm still that way. I don't
And I'm still that way. I don't I
know what I mean?
And I'm still that way. I don't I don't
spend
spend much
spend much time
spend much time watching
spend much time watching fiction.
spend much time watching fiction. It's
amusing,
amusing, but
spend much time watching fiction. It's
amusing, but life
amusing, but life is
spend much time watching fiction. It's
amusing, but life is short.
amusing, but life is short. Okay,
spend much time watching fiction. It's
amusing, but life is short. Okay, so
we'll
we'll move
we'll move on.
Uh
Uh we
we'll move on.
Uh we talk
Uh we talk about
understanding
understanding truth.
understanding truth. The
understanding truth. The reason
understanding truth. The reason the
world
world could
understanding truth. The reason the
world could not
world could not arrive
understanding truth. The reason the
world could not arrive at
world could not arrive at a
comprehension
comprehension of
comprehension of truth
comprehension of truth or
comprehension of truth or how
comprehension of truth or how to
comprehension of truth or how to define
it
it was
comprehension of truth or how to define
it was it
it was it did
comprehension of truth or how to define
it was it did not
it was it did not understand
comprehension of truth or how to define
it was it did not understand the
difference
difference between
difference between linear
difference between linear and
difference between linear and nonlinear.
The
The linear
difference between linear and nonlinear.
The linear is
The linear is the
difference between linear and nonlinear.
The linear is the content
The linear is the content definable,
discrete,
discrete, limited
and
it's
it's within
it's within a
it's within a context.
it's within a context. So
it's within a context. So that
it's within a context. So that which
it's within a context. So that which we
see
see within
it's within a context. So that which we
see within the
see within the world
it's within a context. So that which we
see within the world is
see within the world is a
it's within a context. So that which we
see within the world is a fact
see within the world is a fact etc.
it's within a context. So that which we
see within the world is a fact etc. Fact
or
or an
or an event
or an event is
or an event is happening
or an event is happening within
or an event is happening within a
context
context in
or an event is happening within a
context in overall
context in overall field.
or an event is happening within a
context in overall field. And
context in overall field. And the
or an event is happening within a
context in overall field. And the reason
for
for all
for all the
for all the political
for all the political confusion
for all the political confusion and
discord
is
is the
is the failure
is the failure to
is the failure to define
is the failure to define context
is the failure to define context or
acknowledge
acknowledge context
is the failure to define context or
acknowledge context is
acknowledge context is a
is the failure to define context or
acknowledge context is a thing
acknowledge context is a thing uh
restrictive
restrictive on
restrictive on the
restrictive on the part
restrictive on the part of
restrictive on the part of the
government.
government. It
restrictive on the part of the
government. It depends
government. It depends whether
restrictive on the part of the
government. It depends whether you're
government. It depends whether you're at
war
war or
war or whether
war or whether you're
war or whether you're not
war or whether you're not at
war or whether you're not at war.
war or whether you're not at war. That's
like
like a
war or whether you're not at war. That's
like a 180
like a 180 during
war or whether you're not at war. That's
like a 180 during if
like a 180 during if there's
war or whether you're not at war. That's
like a 180 during if there's no
like a 180 during if there's no war
going
going on
going on it
going on it would
going on it would be
going on it would be repressive.
going on it would be repressive. If
there
there is
going on it would be repressive. If
there is a
there is a war
going on it would be repressive. If
there is a war going
there is a war going on
going on it would be repressive. If
there is a war going on that
there is a war going on that changes
going on it would be repressive. If
there is a war going on that changes the
meaning
meaning and
meaning and inferring
meaning and inferring significance.
meaning and inferring significance. So
most
most political
meaning and inferring significance. So
most political discourse
most political discourse you
meaning and inferring significance. So
most political discourse you will
most political discourse you will see
very
very carefully
very carefully avoids
very carefully avoids stating
very carefully avoids stating context.
Context
Context has
very carefully avoids stating context.
Context has to
Context has to do
very carefully avoids stating context.
Context has to do with
Context has to do with the
very carefully avoids stating context.
Context has to do with the timing,
Context has to do with the timing, the
inference,
inference, the
inference, the sequence,
inference, the sequence, the
inference, the sequence, the overall
field
field including
inference, the sequence, the overall
field including the
field including the culture
inference, the sequence, the overall
field including the culture of
field including the culture of your
inference, the sequence, the overall
field including the culture of your time
etc.
etc. So
etc. So context
etc. So context then.
etc. So context then. So
etc. So context then. So truth
etc. So context then. So truth can
etc. So context then. So truth can only
be
be known
etc. So context then. So truth can only
be known if
be known if you
etc. So context then. So truth can only
be known if you uh
be known if you uh state
etc. So context then. So truth can only
be known if you uh state both
be known if you uh state both content
and
and context.
Science
Science only
and context.
Science only deals
Science only deals or
and context.
Science only deals or has
Science only deals or has only
and context.
Science only deals or has only deal
dealt
dealt Newtonian
dealt Newtonian science
dealt Newtonian science with
dealt Newtonian science with content.
dealt Newtonian science with content. Of
course,
course, since
dealt Newtonian science with content. Of
course, since quantum
course, since quantum mechanics,
dealt Newtonian science with content. Of
course, since quantum mechanics, they
now
now are
now are aware
now are aware of
now are aware of the
now are aware of the effect
now are aware of the effect of
now are aware of the effect of context
and
and the
now are aware of the effect of context
and the impact
and the impact of
now are aware of the effect of context
and the impact of consciousness
and the impact of consciousness itself.
So,
So, you
So, you got
So, you got a
So, you got a thingy
So, you got a thingy there.
Uh
Uh people
So, you got a thingy there.
Uh people say,
Uh people say, "How
So, you got a thingy there.
Uh people say, "How can
Uh people say, "How can I
So, you got a thingy there.
Uh people say, "How can I become
spiritual?"
spiritual?" Well,
spiritual?" Well, I
spiritual?" Well, I say
spiritual?" Well, I say first
spiritual?" Well, I say first just
become
become a
spiritual?" Well, I say first just
become a decent
become a decent human
spiritual?" Well, I say first just
become a decent human being.
become a decent human being. Try
spiritual?" Well, I say first just
become a decent human being. Try that.
[laughter]
Be
Be considerate,
[laughter]
Be considerate, decent,
Be considerate, decent, be
[laughter]
Be considerate, decent, be responsible.
You
You say
You say you're
You say you're going
You say you're going to
You say you're going to close
You say you're going to close the
You say you're going to close the door
when
when you
You say you're going to close the door
when you leave,
when you leave, please
You say you're going to close the door
when you leave, please do
when you leave, please do so.
You say you're going to close the door
when you leave, please do so. People
have
have to
have to be
have to be able
have to be able to
have to be able to count
have to be able to count on
have to be able to count on you.
have to be able to count on you. You
have
have to
have to be able to count on you. You
have to be
have to be honest.
have to be able to count on you. You
have to be honest. Here's
have to be honest. Here's really
have to be able to count on you. You
have to be honest. Here's really the
Protestant
Protestant ethic,
Protestant ethic, isn't
Protestant ethic, isn't it?
Protestant ethic, isn't it? No
Protestant ethic, isn't it? No offense
to
to Catholics
Protestant ethic, isn't it? No offense
to Catholics or
to Catholics or other
Protestant ethic, isn't it? No offense
to Catholics or other people,
to Catholics or other people, but
everything's
everything's so
everything's so political
everything's so political nowadays,
everything's so political nowadays, you
can't
can't say
everything's so political nowadays, you
can't say anything.
can't say anything. Anyway,
everything's so political nowadays, you
can't say anything. Anyway, classic
can't say anything. Anyway, classic is
called,
called, you
called, you know,
called, you know, frugality,
called, you know, frugality, hard
called, you know, frugality, hard work,
etc.
etc. Nose
called, you know, frugality, hard work,
etc. Nose to
etc. Nose to the
called, you know, frugality, hard work,
etc. Nose to the grindstone.
uh
uh you
uh you tend
uh you tend to
uh you tend to be
uh you tend to be moral
uh you tend to be moral and
uh you tend to be moral and uh
uh you tend to be moral and uh you
uh you tend to be moral and uh you live
according
according to
uh you tend to be moral and uh you live
according to your
according to your own
uh you tend to be moral and uh you live
according to your own morality.
according to your own morality. It
doesn't
doesn't have
doesn't have to
doesn't have to be
doesn't have to be the
doesn't have to be the same
doesn't have to be the same as
everybody's
everybody's but
doesn't have to be the same as
everybody's but at least
everybody's but at least you
doesn't have to be the same as
everybody's but at least you have
ethical
ethical standards.
ethical standards. You
ethical standards. You tend
ethical standards. You tend to
ethical standards. You tend to be
helpful
helpful and
ethical standards. You tend to be
helpful and easygoing,
helpful and easygoing, thoughtful,
ethical standards. You tend to be
helpful and easygoing, thoughtful, calm.
You
You tend
You tend to
You tend to be
You tend to be genuine
You tend to be genuine and
You tend to be genuine and not
You tend to be genuine and not fake.
You tend to be genuine and not fake. Uh
respect,
respect, you
You tend to be genuine and not fake. Uh
respect, you know,
respect, you know, you're
You tend to be genuine and not fake. Uh
respect, you know, you're respect
respect, you know, you're respect people
and
and you're
and you're friendly
and you're friendly and
and you're friendly and easy
and you're friendly and easy to
and you're friendly and easy to talk
and you're friendly and easy to talk to
and
and safe
and you're friendly and easy to talk to
and safe to
and safe to be
and you're friendly and easy to talk to
and safe to be with.
and safe to be with. And
and you're friendly and easy to talk to
and safe to be with. And if
and safe to be with. And if you
and you're friendly and easy to talk to
and safe to be with. And if you somebody
lends
lends you
lends you something,
lends you something, you
lends you something, you give
lends you something, you give it
lends you something, you give it back.
That
That includes
lends you something, you give it back.
That includes books.
Also
Also includes
Also includes lawnmowers.
[laughter]
Uh
Uh you
Uh you esteem
Uh you esteem wisdom.
Uh you esteem wisdom. Wisdom
Uh you esteem wisdom. Wisdom is
Uh you esteem wisdom. Wisdom is at
Uh you esteem wisdom. Wisdom is at 385.
These
These people
Uh you esteem wisdom. Wisdom is at 385.
These people tend
These people tend to
Uh you esteem wisdom. Wisdom is at 385.
These people tend to be
These people tend to be benign.
Uh you esteem wisdom. Wisdom is at 385.
These people tend to be benign. They're
safe
safe to
safe to be
safe to be with.
safe to be with. You
safe to be with. You know,
safe to be with. You know, it's
safe to be with. You know, it's safe
safe to be with. You know, it's safe to
be
be with
safe to be with. You know, it's safe to
be with them.
be with them. They're
safe to be with. You know, it's safe to
be with them. They're as
be with them. They're as safe
safe to be with. You know, it's safe to
be with them. They're as safe as
be with them. They're as safe as Coco.
the
tend
tend to
the
tend to be
tend to be humane,
the
tend to be humane, uh
tend to be humane, uh tend
the
tend to be humane, uh tend to
tend to be humane, uh tend to be
the
tend to be humane, uh tend to be happy,
sensible.
sensible. They're
sensible. They're called
sensible. They're called the
sensible. They're called the salt
sensible. They're called the salt of
sensible. They're called the salt of the
earth.
earth. And
sensible. They're called the salt of the
earth. And this
earth. And this is
sensible. They're called the salt of the
earth. And this is how
earth. And this is how I
sensible. They're called the salt of the
earth. And this is how I thought
everybody
everybody was
everybody was when
everybody was when I
everybody was when I grew
everybody was when I grew up.
everybody was when I grew up. This
everybody was when I grew up. This was
Middle
Middle West
everybody was when I grew up. This was
Middle West traditional
Middle West traditional America,
everybody was when I grew up. This was
Middle West traditional America, which
is
is so
is so despised
is so despised today.
is so despised today. However,
is so despised today. However, this
is so despised today. However, this is
the
the world
is so despised today. However, this is
the world of
the world of normal
is so despised today. However, this is
the world of normal that
the world of normal that I
is so despised today. However, this is
the world of normal that I grew
the world of normal that I grew up.
is so despised today. However, this is
the world of normal that I grew up. And
I
I presumed
I presumed everybody
I presumed everybody in
I presumed everybody in the
I presumed everybody in the world
I presumed everybody in the world was
that
that way.
I'm
I'm still
I'm still shocked
I'm still shocked to
I'm still shocked to find
I'm still shocked to find out
I'm still shocked to find out it
I'm still shocked to find out it isn't.
We'll
We'll move
I'm still shocked to find out it isn't.
We'll move on
We'll move on to
I'm still shocked to find out it isn't.
We'll move on to the
We'll move on to the next
uh
yeah
yeah this
uh
yeah this is
yeah this is interesting
uh
yeah this is interesting people
yeah this is interesting people uh
uh
yeah this is interesting people uh do
meditative
meditative practice
meditative practice etc
meditative practice etc and
meditative practice etc and they
meditative practice etc and they what
they
they say
meditative practice etc and they what
they say is
they say is they
meditative practice etc and they what
they say is they can't
they say is they can't get
meditative practice etc and they what
they say is they can't get beyond
they say is they can't get beyond the
their
their mind.
their mind. So
their mind. So I
their mind. So I asked
their mind. So I asked him,
their mind. So I asked him, you
their mind. So I asked him, you see
their mind. So I asked him, you see how
the
the mind
their mind. So I asked him, you see how
the mind the
the mind the mind
their mind. So I asked him, you see how
the mind the mind is
the mind the mind is busy
their mind. So I asked him, you see how
the mind the mind is busy and
the mind the mind is busy and it's
getting
getting juice
getting juice out
getting juice out of
getting juice out of these
getting juice out of these activities.
It's
It's a
getting juice out of these activities.
It's a politicizing
It's a politicizing everything.
getting juice out of these activities.
It's a politicizing everything. You
It's a politicizing everything. You see
today's
today's society
today's society politicizes
today's society politicizes everything.
The
The shoes
today's society politicizes everything.
The shoes you
The shoes you wear,
today's society politicizes everything.
The shoes you wear, I
The shoes you wear, I mean
today's society politicizes everything.
The shoes you wear, I mean whether
The shoes you wear, I mean whether you
wear
wear a
wear a jacket,
wear a jacket, everything
wear a jacket, everything gets
everything
everything get
wear a jacket, everything gets
everything get has
everything get has a
wear a jacket, everything gets
everything get has a political
everything get has a political bunker
that
that gets
that gets put
that gets put in
so
so that
that gets put in
so that it
so that it can
that gets put in
so that it can become
so that it can become disputatious
because
because you
because you can
because you can moralize
because you can moralize about
because you can moralize about it.
because you can moralize about it. You
can
can hypothesize,
because you can moralize about it. You
can hypothesize, you
can hypothesize, you can
because you can moralize about it. You
can hypothesize, you can romanticize,
uh
uh you
uh you can
uh you can criticize,
uh you can criticize, you
uh you can criticize, you can
emotionalize,
emotionalize, dramatize.
uh you can criticize, you can
emotionalize, dramatize. So
emotionalize, dramatize. So you
uh you can criticize, you can
emotionalize, dramatize. So you can
emotionalize, dramatize. So you can get
yourself
yourself to
yourself to be
yourself to be victim.
yourself to be victim. That's
yourself to be victim. That's plays
yourself to be victim. That's plays off
very
very good
yourself to be victim. That's plays off
very good in
very good in today's
yourself to be victim. That's plays off
very good in today's world.
Intellectualize,
Intellectualize, mentalize.
Intellectualize, mentalize. So
Intellectualize, mentalize. So you
Intellectualize, mentalize. So you see
the
the mind
Intellectualize, mentalize. So you see
the mind is
the mind is very
Intellectualize, mentalize. So you see
the mind is very busy.
the mind is very busy. However,
uh
99%
99% of
uh
99% of the
99% of the mind
uh
99% of the mind is
99% of the mind is actually
uh
99% of the mind is actually silent
99% of the mind is actually silent and
only
only 1%
only 1% of
only 1% of your
only 1% of your mind
only 1% of your mind is
only 1% of your mind is talking.
only 1% of your mind is talking. We'll
switch
switch to
only 1% of your mind is talking. We'll
switch to the
switch to the next
only 1% of your mind is talking. We'll
switch to the next slide.
Um,
this
this is
Um,
this is hard
this is hard to
Um,
this is hard to see,
this is hard to see, but
Um,
this is hard to see, but once
this is hard to see, but once you
Um,
this is hard to see, but once you hear
about
about it,
about it, you'll
about it, you'll find
about it, you'll find it's
about it, you'll find it's not
about it, you'll find it's not all
about it, you'll find it's not all that
difficult.
difficult. There's
about it, you'll find it's not all that
difficult. There's only
difficult. There's only the
about it, you'll find it's not all that
difficult. There's only the action.
difficult. There's only the action. If
your
your mind
your mind is
your mind is only
your mind is only 1%
your mind is only 1% of
your mind is only 1% of the
your mind is only 1% of the act
your mind is only 1% of the act of
your mind is only 1% of the act of the
action
action of
your mind is only 1% of the act of the
action of the
action of the mind,
your mind is only 1% of the act of the
action of the mind, it's
action of the mind, it's only
your mind is only 1% of the act of the
action of the mind, it's only 1%.
action of the mind, it's only 1%. It's
what
what you're
what you're focused
what you're focused on.
what you're focused on. 99%
what you're focused on. 99% is
what you're focused on. 99% is silent.
That
That 99%
what you're focused on. 99% is silent.
That 99% is
That 99% is below
what you're focused on. 99% is silent.
That 99% is below the
That 99% is below the horizon
what you're focused on. 99% is silent.
That 99% is below the horizon of
That 99% is below the horizon of your
perception.
perception. You're
perception. You're looking
perception. You're looking here,
perception. You're looking here, but
perception. You're looking here, but the
whole
whole rest
perception. You're looking here, but the
whole rest of
whole rest of the
perception. You're looking here, but the
whole rest of the TV
whole rest of the TV set
perception. You're looking here, but the
whole rest of the TV set is
whole rest of the TV set is still
perception. You're looking here, but the
whole rest of the TV set is still and
you're
you're just
you're just looking
you're just looking at
you're just looking at a
you're just looking at a little
you're just looking at a little tiny
figure.
figure. And
you're just looking at a little tiny
figure. And because
figure. And because you
you're just looking at a little tiny
figure. And because you Why
figure. And because you Why are
you're just looking at a little tiny
figure. And because you Why are you
looking
looking at
looking at that?
looking at that? Because
looking at that? Because that's
looking at that? Because that's the
looking at that? Because that's the only
thing
thing happening
looking at that? Because that's the only
thing happening on
thing happening on the
looking at that? Because that's the only
thing happening on the TV
thing happening on the TV screen.
looking at that? Because that's the only
thing happening on the TV screen. See,
uh
uh you're
uh you're not
uh you're not looking
uh you're not looking at
uh you're not looking at the
uh you're not looking at the blank
screen.
screen. You
uh you're not looking at the blank
screen. You said
screen. You said that's
uh you're not looking at the blank
screen. You said that's boring.
screen. You said that's boring. But
uh you're not looking at the blank
screen. You said that's boring. But if
you
you look
you look below
you look below the
you look below the activity
you look below the activity of
you look below the activity of your
mind,
mind, you'll
you look below the activity of your
mind, you'll find
mind, you'll find that
you look below the activity of your
mind, you'll find that it's
mind, you'll find that it's infinite
you look below the activity of your
mind, you'll find that it's infinite and
silent
for
for the
silent
for the same
for the same reason.
silent
for the same reason. You
for the same reason. You can
silent
for the same reason. You can make
for the same reason. You can make the
same
same discovery
same discovery in
same discovery in the
same discovery in the woods.
same discovery in the woods. You
same discovery in the woods. You hear
same discovery in the woods. You hear a
noise
noise in
same discovery in the woods. You hear a
noise in the
noise in the woods.
same discovery in the woods. You hear a
noise in the woods. The
noise in the woods. The only
same discovery in the woods. You hear a
noise in the woods. The only reason
noise in the woods. The only reason you
can
can hear
can hear the
can hear the noise
can hear the noise is
can hear the noise is because
can hear the noise is because the
can hear the noise is because the woods
is
is 99%
can hear the noise is because the woods
is 99% silent.
is 99% silent. It's
can hear the noise is because the woods
is 99% silent. It's because
is 99% silent. It's because of
can hear the noise is because the woods
is 99% silent. It's because of the
silence
silence that
silence that you
silence that you can
silence that you can hear
silence that you can hear the
silence that you can hear the noise.
It's
It's because
silence that you can hear the noise.
It's because of
It's because of the
silence that you can hear the noise.
It's because of the silence
It's because of the silence that
silence that you can hear the noise.
It's because of the silence that you're
aware
aware of
aware of what
aware of what goes
aware of what goes on
aware of what goes on in
aware of what goes on in your
aware of what goes on in your mind.
aware of what goes on in your mind. So
you
you tend
aware of what goes on in your mind. So
you tend to
you tend to uh
aware of what goes on in your mind. So
you tend to uh identify
you tend to uh identify with
aware of what goes on in your mind. So
you tend to uh identify with and
you tend to uh identify with and focus
with
with the
with the silent
with the silent with
with the silent with the
with the silent with the silence
with the silent with the silence that
with the silent with the silence that is
just
just below
with the silent with the silence that is
just below thinkingness.
just below thinkingness. Just
with the silent with the silence that is
just below thinkingness. Just below
thinkingness.
thinkingness. We'll
thinkingness. We'll skip
thinkingness. We'll skip this
thinkingness. We'll skip this one.
thinkingness. We'll skip this one. the
uh
the
the functions
the functions of
the functions of the
the functions of the mind
the functions of the mind uh
the functions of the mind uh you
the functions of the mind uh you see
the functions of the mind uh you see are
infinite.
So
So if
So if you're
So if you're going
So if you're going to
So if you're going to try
So if you're going to try and
So if you're going to try and silence
your
your mind,
So if you're going to try and silence
your mind, you
your mind, you can
So if you're going to try and silence
your mind, you can see
your mind, you can see you
So if you're going to try and silence
your mind, you can see you better
your mind, you can see you better get
busy.
busy. It
busy. It looks
busy. It looks like
busy. It looks like it's
busy. It looks like it's going
busy. It looks like it's going to
busy. It looks like it's going to take
busy. It looks like it's going to take a
few
few thousand
busy. It looks like it's going to take a
few thousand years
few thousand years at
busy. It looks like it's going to take a
few thousand years at least.
These
These are
These are just
These are just all
These are just all the
These are just all the the
These are just all the the activities
that
that it
These are just all the the activities
that it gets
that it gets pulled
These are just all the the activities
that it gets pulled into.
that it gets pulled into. Yeah,
These are just all the the activities
that it gets pulled into. Yeah, we'll
that it gets pulled into. Yeah, we'll go
to
to the
to the next
to the next one.
to the next one. How
to the next one. How to
to the next one. How to transcend
to the next one. How to transcend the
mind.
uh
you
you ask
uh
you ask have
you ask have to
uh
you ask have to ask
you ask have to ask which
uh
you ask have to ask which mind?
you ask have to ask which mind? Well,
there
there are
there are various
there are various energy
there are various energy fields,
there are various energy fields, chakra
systems.
systems. Uh
there are various energy fields, chakra
systems. Uh as
systems. Uh as you're
there are various energy fields, chakra
systems. Uh as you're all
systems. Uh as you're all aware,
there are various energy fields, chakra
systems. Uh as you're all aware, the
various
various shakra
various shakra systems
various shakra systems uh
various shakra systems uh one
various shakra systems uh one one
collection
collection of
various shakra systems uh one one
collection of energy
collection of energy is
various shakra systems uh one one
collection of energy is at
collection of energy is at lower
various shakra systems uh one one
collection of energy is at lower mind.
Lower
Lower mind
Lower mind at
Lower mind at 155.
Lower mind at 155. There's
Lower mind at 155. There's another
collection
collection of
Lower mind at 155. There's another
collection of energy
collection of energy that
Lower mind at 155. There's another
collection of energy that we
collection of energy that we call
Lower mind at 155. There's another
collection of energy that we call higher
mind.
mind. Higher
mind. Higher mind.
mind. Higher mind. Uh
mind. Higher mind. Uh they
mind. Higher mind. Uh they have
mind. Higher mind. Uh they have two
different
different sets
mind. Higher mind. Uh they have two
different sets of
different sets of values.
mind. Higher mind. Uh they have two
different sets of values. what
different sets of values. what one
setting
setting considers
setting considers to
setting considers to be
setting considers to be valid
setting considers to be valid and
setting considers to be valid and true
and
and ethical,
setting considers to be valid and true
and ethical, the
and ethical, the other
setting considers to be valid and true
and ethical, the other the
and ethical, the other the other
considers
considers to
considers to be
considers to be invalid
and
and in
considers to be invalid
and in fact
and in fact in
considers to be invalid
and in fact in fact
and in fact in fact immoral.
The
The lower
The lower mind
The lower mind then
The lower mind then is
The lower mind then is very
The lower mind then is very interested
in
in sensationalism
and
and is
and is very
and is very gullible.
and is very gullible. It's
and is very gullible. It's interested
and is very gullible. It's interested in
being
being smart,
and is very gullible. It's interested in
being smart, exploiting
being smart, exploiting life.
and is very gullible. It's interested in
being smart, exploiting life. So
being smart, exploiting life. So you'll
recognize
recognize television
recognize television right
recognize television right away.
recognize television right away. It
likes
likes to
recognize television right away. It
likes to play
likes to play off
recognize television right away. It
likes to play off the
likes to play off the sensational.
recognize television right away. It
likes to play off the sensational. It'll
take
take some
take some trivial
take some trivial little
take some trivial little incident
take some trivial little incident that
is
is of
take some trivial little incident that
is of no
is of no significance
take some trivial little incident that
is of no significance and
is of no significance and give
take some trivial little incident that
is of no significance and give it
is of no significance and give it major
playtime
playtime and
playtime and something
playtime and something that
playtime and something that really
playtime and something that really is
playtime and something that really is of
profound
profound importance
playtime and something that really is of
profound importance and
profound importance and really
playtime and something that really is of
profound importance and really threatens
all
all of
all of mankind
all of mankind and
all of mankind and they
all of mankind and they give
all of mankind and they give it
all of mankind and they give it only
all of mankind and they give it only a
glance.
So
So you
So you get
So you get a
So you get a distortion
So you get a distortion of
So you get a distortion of values.
275 and
275 and up
So you get a distortion of values.
275 and up then
275 and up then is
So you get a distortion of values.
275 and up then is a
275 and up then is a higher
So you get a distortion of values.
275 and up then is a higher mind
275 and up then is a higher mind and
So you get a distortion of values.
275 and up then is a higher mind and it
is
is into
is into uh
is into uh thoughtful
is into uh thoughtful balance
is into uh thoughtful balance and
uh
uh sensitivity
is into uh thoughtful balance and
uh sensitivity to
uh sensitivity to what
is into uh thoughtful balance and
uh sensitivity to what is
uh sensitivity to what is appropriate
and
and what
and what is
and what is not
and what is not appropriate.
And
And this
and what is not appropriate.
And this mind
And this mind here
and what is not appropriate.
And this mind here will
And this mind here will say
and what is not appropriate.
And this mind here will say well
And this mind here will say well you
know
know this
know this is
know this is so
know this is so however
know this is so however it's
know this is so however it's only
know this is so however it's only for
know this is so however it's only for us
and
and without
know this is so however it's only for us
and without and
and without and it's
know this is so however it's only for us
and without and it's not
and without and it's not balanced.
know this is so however it's only for us
and without and it's not balanced. So
this
this mind
this mind tends
this mind tends to
this mind tends to look
this mind tends to look for
this mind tends to look for solutions
and
and this
this mind tends to look for solutions
and this mind
and this mind tends
this mind tends to look for solutions
and this mind tends to
and this mind tends to play
this mind tends to look for solutions
and this mind tends to play off
and this mind tends to play off uh
difficulties.
So
So there's
difficulties.
So there's a
So there's a big
difficulties.
So there's a big payoff
So there's a big payoff here
difficulties.
So there's a big payoff here you
So there's a big payoff here you see
difficulties.
So there's a big payoff here you see to
this
this level
this level mind.
this level mind. All
this level mind. All right.
this level mind. All right. So
this level mind. All right. So 85%
this level mind. All right. So 85% in
the
the people
this level mind. All right. So 85% in
the people in
the people in the
this level mind. All right. So 85% in
the people in the world
the people in the world their
this level mind. All right. So 85% in
the people in the world their intellect
is
is at
is at this
is at this level
is at this level in
is at this level in America
is at this level in America only
is at this level in America only about
50%.
50%. About
is at this level in America only about
50%. About 50%
50%. About 50% of
is at this level in America only about
50%. About 50% of people
50%. About 50% of people would
is at this level in America only about
50%. About 50% of people would rather
watch
watch something
watch something gory
watch something gory and
watch something gory and horrible
watch something gory and horrible and
sensational
sensational rather
watch something gory and horrible and
sensational rather than
sensational rather than something
watch something gory and horrible and
sensational rather than something that
is
is inclusive
is inclusive of
is inclusive of beauty
is inclusive of beauty let's
is inclusive of beauty let's say.
is inclusive of beauty let's say. Okay.
All right.
All right. So
is inclusive of beauty let's say. Okay.
All right. So we'll
All right. So we'll move
is inclusive of beauty let's say. Okay.
All right. So we'll move on
All right. So we'll move on to
is inclusive of beauty let's say. Okay.
All right. So we'll move on to the
All right. So we'll move on to the next
uh
uh quantum
uh quantum mechanics
uh quantum mechanics and
uh quantum mechanics and kinesiology.
Well,
Well, the
uh quantum mechanics and kinesiology.
Well, the transition
Well, the transition from
uh quantum mechanics and kinesiology.
Well, the transition from Newtonian
physics
physics to
physics to uh
physics to uh quantum
physics to uh quantum mechanics
physics to uh quantum mechanics is
physics to uh quantum mechanics is of
interest
interest to
physics to uh quantum mechanics is of
interest to us
interest to us only
physics to uh quantum mechanics is of
interest to us only in
interest to us only in that.
physics to uh quantum mechanics is of
interest to us only in that. The
discovery
discovery that
discovery that consciousness
discovery that consciousness itself
influences.
You
You see,
You see, the
You see, the Newtonian
You see, the Newtonian paradigm
You see, the Newtonian paradigm of
reality
reality is
You see, the Newtonian paradigm of
reality is causality.
reality is causality. There's
You see, the Newtonian paradigm of
reality is causality. There's a
reality is causality. There's a this
that
that causes
that causes a
that causes a that
that causes a that and
that causes a that and ends
that causes a that and ends up
that causes a that and ends up as
that causes a that and ends up as a
that causes a that and ends up as a so
and
and so.
that causes a that and ends up as a so
and so. And
and so. And therefore,
that causes a that and ends up as a so
and so. And therefore, it's
and so. And therefore, it's only
that causes a that and ends up as a so
and so. And therefore, it's only content
and
and it's
and it's only
and it's only linear.
and it's only linear. However,
and it's only linear. However, through
quantum
quantum mechanics,
and it's only linear. However, through
quantum mechanics, you
quantum mechanics, you discover
and it's only linear. However, through
quantum mechanics, you discover that
that
that consciousness
that consciousness itself
that consciousness itself begins
that consciousness itself begins to
that consciousness itself begins to have
an
an effect
that consciousness itself begins to have
an effect on
an effect on on
that consciousness itself begins to have
an effect on on phenomena.
And
And of
And of course,
And of course, it
And of course, it was
And of course, it was the
And of course, it was the discovery
And of course, it was the discovery that
merely
merely the
And of course, it was the discovery that
merely the Heisenberg
merely the Heisenberg effect
And of course, it was the discovery that
merely the Heisenberg effect was
merely the Heisenberg effect was the
discovery
discovery that
discovery that merely
discovery that merely looking
discovery that merely looking at
discovery that merely looking at an
experiment
experiment already
discovery that merely looking at an
experiment already changes
experiment already changes the
discovery that merely looking at an
experiment already changes the result.
Merely
Merely looking
Merely looking at
Merely looking at it.
Merely looking at it. So
Merely looking at it. So the
Merely looking at it. So the power
Merely looking at it. So the power of
consciousness
consciousness was
Merely looking at it. So the power of
consciousness was now
consciousness was now recognized
and
and therefore
and therefore it
and therefore it was
and therefore it was um
and therefore it was um very
interesting.
interesting. Einstein
and therefore it was um very
interesting. Einstein you
interesting. Einstein you see
and therefore it was um very
interesting. Einstein you see who
interesting. Einstein you see who was
and therefore it was um very
interesting. Einstein you see who was a
master
master of
master of the
master of the linear
master of the linear dimension
master of the linear dimension uh
calibrated
calibrated 499
master of the linear dimension uh
calibrated 499 and
calibrated 499 and he
master of the linear dimension uh
calibrated 499 and he refused
calibrated 499 and he refused to
recognize
recognize the
recognize the role
recognize the role of
recognize the role of consciousness
refused
refused its
recognize the role of consciousness
refused its reality.
refused its reality. He
recognize the role of consciousness
refused its reality. He said
refused its reality. He said I
recognize the role of consciousness
refused its reality. He said I prefer
refused its reality. He said I prefer to
think
think there
think there is
think there is a
think there is a distinct
think there is a distinct objective
linear
linear reality
think there is a distinct objective
linear reality out
linear reality out there.
Um
Um so
Um so we
Um so we can
Um so we can calibrate
Um so we can calibrate we've
Um so we can calibrate we've calibrated
all
all these
Um so we can calibrate we've calibrated
all these things
all these things the
Um so we can calibrate we've calibrated
all these things the shreddinger
all these things the shreddinger process
Heisenberg
Heisenberg process
Heisenberg process the
Heisenberg process the dura
Heisenberg process the dura equations
and
and this
Heisenberg process the dura equations
and this explains
and this explains how
Heisenberg process the dura equations
and this explains how you
and this explains how you collapse
Heisenberg process the dura equations
and this explains how you collapse the
wave
wave function.
wave function. So
the
the reason
wave function. So
the reason is
the reason is that
wave function. So
the reason is that this
the reason is that this gives
wave function. So
the reason is that this gives you
the reason is that this gives you a
scientific
scientific basis
um
um to
scientific basis
um to understand
um to understand how
scientific basis
um to understand how the
um to understand how the phenomenal
world
world occurs.
I
I always
world occurs.
I always tell
I always tell people
world occurs.
I always tell people notice
I always tell people notice that
everything
everything is
everything is happening
everything is happening spontaneously.
The
The limitation
everything is happening spontaneously.
The limitation of
The limitation of the
everything is happening spontaneously.
The limitation of the ego
The limitation of the ego is
everything is happening spontaneously.
The limitation of the ego is it
The limitation of the ego is it thinks
there's
there's a
there's a personal
there's a personal eye
there's a personal eye as
there's a personal eye as a
there's a personal eye as a cause
there's a personal eye as a cause and
based
based on
there's a personal eye as a cause and
based on the
based on the Newtonian
there's a personal eye as a cause and
based on the Newtonian principle.
There's
There's a
There's a a
There's a a this
There's a a this causing
There's a a this causing of
There's a a this causing of that.
Um
in
in reality
in reality there
in reality there is
in reality there is no
in reality there is no no
in reality there is no no this
in reality there is no no this causing
any
any that
in reality there is no no this causing
any that in
any that in fact
in reality there is no no this causing
any that in fact that
any that in fact that phenomena
in reality there is no no this causing
any that in fact that phenomena is
any that in fact that phenomena is not
in reality there is no no this causing
any that in fact that phenomena is not a
possibility
because
evolution
evolution and
evolution and creation
evolution and creation are
evolution and creation are one
evolution and creation are one and
evolution and creation are one and the
same
same thing.
evolution and creation are one and the
same thing. So
same thing. So what
evolution and creation are one and the
same thing. So what you
same thing. So what you see
evolution and creation are one and the
same thing. So what you see is
same thing. So what you see is the
emergence
emergence of
emergence of potentiality
as
as a
emergence of potentiality
as a consequence
as a consequence of
emergence of potentiality
as a consequence of evolution.
People
People the
People the limitation
People the limitation the
People the limitation the reason
People the limitation the reason for
religious
religious conflict
People the limitation the reason for
religious conflict is
religious conflict is a
People the limitation the reason for
religious conflict is a lack
religious conflict is a lack of
comprehension
comprehension of
comprehension of the
comprehension of the nature
comprehension of the nature of
comprehension of the nature of divinity
itself.
itself. It
comprehension of the nature of divinity
itself. It sees
itself. It sees a
comprehension of the nature of divinity
itself. It sees a god
itself. It sees a god who
comprehension of the nature of divinity
itself. It sees a god who starts
itself. It sees a god who starts here
comprehension of the nature of divinity
itself. It sees a god who starts here uh
and
and then
and then one
and then one day
and then one day creates
and then one day creates all
and then one day creates all there
and then one day creates all there is
and
and disappears.
Then
Then after
Then after you
Then after you die,
Then after you die, you
Then after you die, you face
Then after you die, you face him
Then after you die, you face him on
great
great on
Then after you die, you face him on
great on judgment
great on judgment judgment
Then after you die, you face him on
great on judgment judgment day.
great on judgment judgment day. I
Then after you die, you face him on
great on judgment judgment day. I don't
know
know where
know where he
know where he goes
know where he goes in
know where he goes in the
know where he goes in the meantime,
know where he goes in the meantime, but
it
it goes
know where he goes in the meantime, but
it goes the
it goes the way.
It's
It's because
It's because the
It's because the mind
It's because the mind doesn't
It's because the mind doesn't comprehens
comprehend
comprehend infinity.
It's because the mind doesn't comprehens
comprehend infinity. Um,
comprehend infinity. Um, I
It's because the mind doesn't comprehens
comprehend infinity. Um, I understood
this
this at
this at age
this at age 14
this at age 14 or
this at age 14 or so.
this at age 14 or so. Uh,
this at age 14 or so. Uh, I
this at age 14 or so. Uh, I was
this at age 14 or so. Uh, I was on
this at age 14 or so. Uh, I was on a
this at age 14 or so. Uh, I was on a I
had
had longest
this at age 14 or so. Uh, I was on a I
had longest paper
had longest paper route
this at age 14 or so. Uh, I was on a I
had longest paper route out
had longest paper route out in
Wisconsin,
Wisconsin, 18
Wisconsin, 18 miles
Wisconsin, 18 miles every
Wisconsin, 18 miles every day
Wisconsin, 18 miles every day in
Wisconsin, 18 miles every day in the
snow
snow and
Wisconsin, 18 miles every day in the
snow and the
snow and the wind
Wisconsin, 18 miles every day in the
snow and the wind and
snow and the wind and all.
Wisconsin, 18 miles every day in the
snow and the wind and all. And
snow and the wind and all. And one
Wisconsin, 18 miles every day in the
snow and the wind and all. And one day
here,
here, I'm
here, I'm a
here, I'm a kid.
here, I'm a kid. I
here, I'm a kid. I got
here, I'm a kid. I got 100
here, I'm a kid. I got 100 pounds
here, I'm a kid. I got 100 pounds of
papers.
papers. And
here, I'm a kid. I got 100 pounds of
papers. And I
papers. And I said
here, I'm a kid. I got 100 pounds of
papers. And I said I
papers. And I said I was
here, I'm a kid. I got 100 pounds of
papers. And I said I was a
papers. And I said I was a skinny
speckled
speckled kid.
speckled kid. And
speckled kid. And here
speckled kid. And here I'm
speckled kid. And here I'm pushing
speckled kid. And here I'm pushing these
100 pounds
100 pounds of
speckled kid. And here I'm pushing these
100 pounds of paper
100 pounds of paper through
speckled kid. And here I'm pushing these
100 pounds of paper through this
100 pounds of paper through this gale
and
and it's
and it's 10
and it's 10 below
and it's 10 below zero.
and it's 10 below zero. And
and it's 10 below zero. And there
and it's 10 below zero. And there was
and it's 10 below zero. And there was a
big
big snowbank.
and it's 10 below zero. And there was a
big snowbank. So
big snowbank. So I
and it's 10 below zero. And there was a
big snowbank. So I had
big snowbank. So I had to
and it's 10 below zero. And there was a
big snowbank. So I had to get
big snowbank. So I had to get out
and it's 10 below zero. And there was a
big snowbank. So I had to get out of
big snowbank. So I had to get out of the
wind.
wind. It
wind. It was
wind. It was the
wind. It was the wind
wind. It was the wind that
wind. It was the wind that got
wind. It was the wind that got me.
wind. It was the wind that got me. And
so
so I
wind. It was the wind that got me. And
so I dug
so I dug a
wind. It was the wind that got me. And
so I dug a hole
so I dug a hole in
wind. It was the wind that got me. And
so I dug a hole in the
so I dug a hole in the snowbank.
wind. It was the wind that got me. And
so I dug a hole in the snowbank. It
so I dug a hole in the snowbank. It was
a
a crust
a crust on
a crust on the
a crust on the snowbank
a crust on the snowbank in
a crust on the snowbank in Wisconsin.
And
And by
a crust on the snowbank in Wisconsin.
And by February
And by February or
a crust on the snowbank in Wisconsin.
And by February or so
And by February or so this
a crust on the snowbank in Wisconsin.
And by February or so this the
And by February or so this the snow
a crust on the snowbank in Wisconsin.
And by February or so this the snow on
the
the side
the side of
the side of the
the side of the highway
the side of the highway is
the side of the highway is is
the side of the highway is is higher
than
than this.
the side of the highway is is higher
than this. You
than this. You know,
the side of the highway is is higher
than this. You know, it
than this. You know, it gets
the side of the highway is is higher
than this. You know, it gets higher
than this. You know, it gets higher and
higher
higher every
higher every snowfall.
higher every snowfall. So
higher every snowfall. So anyway,
higher every snowfall. So anyway, I
higher every snowfall. So anyway, I made
a
a hole
higher every snowfall. So anyway, I made
a hole in
a hole in there
higher every snowfall. So anyway, I made
a hole in there and
a hole in there and I
higher every snowfall. So anyway, I made
a hole in there and I dug
a hole in there and I dug my
higher every snowfall. So anyway, I made
a hole in there and I dug my dug
a hole in there and I dug my dug a
higher every snowfall. So anyway, I made
a hole in there and I dug my dug a hole
in
in there
in there and
in there and I
in there and I climbed
in there and I climbed in
in there and I climbed in to
in there and I climbed in to get
in there and I climbed in to get out
in there and I climbed in to get out of
the
the wind.
And
And as
And as soon
And as soon as
And as soon as I
And as soon as I got
And as soon as I got out
And as soon as I got out of
And as soon as I got out of the
And as soon as I got out of the wind,
And as soon as I got out of the wind, a
state
state an
And as soon as I got out of the wind, a
state an infinite
state an infinite state
And as soon as I got out of the wind, a
state an infinite state came
state an infinite state came in
And as soon as I got out of the wind, a
state an infinite state came in came
state an infinite state came in came on
and
of
of such
and
of such exquisite
of such exquisite nature
and
of such exquisite nature that
of such exquisite nature that I
and
of such exquisite nature that I cannot
describe
describe it
describe it because
describe it because it
describe it because it starts
describe it because it starts to
describe it because it starts to bring
it
it back
describe it because it starts to bring
it back and
it back and then
describe it because it starts to bring
it back and then I
it back and then I can't
describe it because it starts to bring
it back and then I can't talk.
An
An infinite
An infinite presence
An infinite presence with
An infinite presence with no
An infinite presence with no beginning
with
with no
An infinite presence with no beginning
with no end.
with no end. Its
An infinite presence with no beginning
with no end. Its nature
with no end. Its nature is
An infinite presence with no beginning
with no end. Its nature is foreverness.
And
And the
And the love
And the love is
simultaneously
exquisitly
exquisitly gentle
exquisitly gentle and
exquisitly gentle and simultaneously
exquisitly gentle and simultaneously as
paradoxical
paradoxical as
exquisitly gentle and simultaneously as
paradoxical as it
paradoxical as it may
exquisitly gentle and simultaneously as
paradoxical as it may sound
paradoxical as it may sound infinitely
powerful.
Of
Of infinite
powerful.
Of infinite power
Of infinite power is
powerful.
Of infinite power is this
Of infinite power is this infinite
timeless
timeless love.
timeless love. And
timeless love. And no
timeless love. And no person
timeless love. And no person survived
the
the event.
timeless love. And no person survived
the event. Instead,
the event. Instead, there
timeless love. And no person survived
the event. Instead, there was
the event. Instead, there was only
timeless love. And no person survived
the event. Instead, there was only an
awareness
awareness of
This
This that
awareness of
This that which
This that which I
awareness of
This that which I am
This that which I am or
awareness of
This that which I am or was
This that which I am or was or
awareness of
This that which I am or was or thought
This that which I am or was or thought I
was
was not
was not different
was
was not different than
was not different than than
was
was not different than than the
was not different than than the presence
beyond
beyond all
beyond all time
beyond all time existing
beyond all time existing before
beyond all time existing before all
beyond all time existing before all time
before
before all
beyond all time existing before all time
before all worlds
before all worlds and
beyond all time existing before all time
before all worlds and after
before all worlds and after all
beyond all time existing before all time
before all worlds and after all worlds.
We'll
We'll ask
We'll ask that
that
that which
We'll ask that
that which I
that which I was
We'll ask that
that which I was and
that which I was and that
We'll ask that
that which I was and that which
that which I was and that which I
We'll ask that
that which I was and that which I am
existed
existed before
existed before all
existed before all worlds
existed before all worlds resist
existed before all worlds resist and
will
will exist
existed before all worlds resist and
will exist after
will exist after all
existed before all worlds resist and
will exist after all worlds
will exist after all worlds have
existed before all worlds resist and
will exist after all worlds have ended.
Resist
that
that which
Resist
that which you
that which you are
Resist
that which you are existed
that which you are existed part
Resist
that which you are existed part all
worlds
worlds and
worlds and will
worlds and will exist
worlds and will exist after
worlds and will exist after they
worlds and will exist after they have
all
all long
worlds and will exist after they have
all long since
all long since disappeared.
that
that came
that came as
that came as an
that came as an experiential
that came as an experiential knowingness
which
which totally
that came as an experiential knowingness
which totally transformed
which totally transformed uh
that came as an experiential knowingness
which totally transformed uh my
which totally transformed uh my life
that came as an experiential knowingness
which totally transformed uh my life you
know
uh
uh so
know
uh so I
uh so I don't
know
uh so I don't know
uh so I don't know how
know
uh so I don't know how long
uh so I don't know how long in
know
uh so I don't know how long in clock
time
time that
time that persisted
time that persisted quite
time that persisted quite a
time that persisted quite a while
time that persisted quite a while I
guess
and
and uh
and uh my
and uh my father
and uh my father came
and uh my father came and
and uh my father came and found
and uh my father came and found me
and uh my father came and found me in
the
the snowbank
and
and uh
and uh what
and uh what could
and uh what could I
and uh what could I tell
and uh what could I tell him
and uh what could I tell him nothing
and uh what could I tell him nothing had
no
no words
and uh what could I tell him nothing had
no words to
no words to convey
uh
uh what
uh what had
uh what had transpired
uh what had transpired all
uh what had transpired all right
uh what had transpired all right So
we'll
we'll move
uh what had transpired all right So
we'll move on
we'll move on to
uh what had transpired all right So
we'll move on to the
we'll move on to the next
uh what had transpired all right So
we'll move on to the next um
we'll move on to the next um the
Newtonian
Newtonian paradigm.
So
So yes,
Newtonian paradigm.
So yes, we
So yes, we want
Newtonian paradigm.
So yes, we want to
So yes, we want to go
Newtonian paradigm.
So yes, we want to go to
So yes, we want to go to how
Newtonian paradigm.
So yes, we want to go to how you
So yes, we want to go to how you discern
the
the presence
the presence in
the presence in the
the presence in the present
the presence in the present time.
the presence in the present time. Things
come
come about
the presence in the present time. Things
come about by
come about by they
the presence in the present time. Things
come about by they don't
come about by they don't come
the presence in the present time. Things
come about by they don't come about
come about by they don't come about by
cause
cause and
cause and effect.
cause and effect. You'll
cause and effect. You'll have
cause and effect. You'll have to
cause and effect. You'll have to tell
cause and effect. You'll have to tell me
when
when it's
cause and effect. You'll have to tell me
when it's break
when it's break time.
cause and effect. You'll have to tell me
when it's break time. I
when it's break time. I have
cause and effect. You'll have to tell me
when it's break time. I have no
when it's break time. I have no idea.
>> You
>> You have
>> You have about
>> You have about 10
>> You have about 10 minutes.
>> Okay.
Um
to
to transcend
Um
to transcend the
to transcend the mind
Um
to transcend the mind which
to transcend the mind which is
Um
to transcend the mind which is based
to transcend the mind which is based on
cause
cause and
cause and effect
cause and effect and
cause and effect and the
cause and effect and the Newtonian
paradigm
paradigm in
cause and effect and the Newtonian
paradigm in science
you
you have
you have to
you have to shift
you have to shift your
you have to shift your awareness.
Uh
Uh stop
you have to shift your awareness.
Uh stop projecting
Uh stop projecting the
you have to shift your awareness.
Uh stop projecting the idea
Uh stop projecting the idea of
you have to shift your awareness.
Uh stop projecting the idea of causality
into
into the
into the world.
into the world. There
into the world. There is
into the world. There is no
into the world. There is no causality
into the world. There is no causality in
the
the world.
into the world. There is no causality in
the world. There
the world. There is
into the world. There is no causality in
the world. There is none
the world. There is none out
into the world. There is no causality in
the world. There is none out there.
the world. There is none out there. All
that
that you
that you receive
that you receive and
that you receive and prove
that you receive and prove and
that you receive and prove and think
that you receive and prove and think is
so
so out
that you receive and prove and think is
so out there
so out there is
that you receive and prove and think is
so out there is from
so out there is from your
that you receive and prove and think is
so out there is from your head
so out there is from your head projected
onto
onto the
onto the world.
Within
Within the
onto the world.
Within the world
Within the world there
onto the world.
Within the world there is
Within the world there is no
onto the world.
Within the world there is no causality.
There
There is
There is sequence.
There is sequence. Sequence
There is sequence. Sequence is
There is sequence. Sequence is not
There is sequence. Sequence is not in
the
the world
There is sequence. Sequence is not in
the world either.
the world either. Sequence
There is sequence. Sequence is not in
the world either. Sequence it
the world either. Sequence it means
There is sequence. Sequence is not in
the world either. Sequence it means you
perceived
perceived it
perceived it sequentially.
perceived it sequentially. Therefore
perceived it sequentially. Therefore you
project
project it
perceived it sequentially. Therefore you
project it must
project it must be
perceived it sequentially. Therefore you
project it must be in
project it must be in the
perceived it sequentially. Therefore you
project it must be in the world.
project it must be in the world. It's
your
your perception
your perception that's
your perception that's sequential.
How
How do
your perception that's sequential.
How do things
How do things come
your perception that's sequential.
How do things come about?
How do things come about? The
your perception that's sequential.
How do things come about? The quickest
way
way to
way to enlightenment
way to enlightenment is
way to enlightenment is to
way to enlightenment is to focus
way to enlightenment is to focus then
and
and notice
way to enlightenment is to focus then
and notice that
and notice that everything
way to enlightenment is to focus then
and notice that everything is
and notice that everything is first
way to enlightenment is to focus then
and notice that everything is first of
all
all absolutely
all absolutely perfect.
all absolutely perfect. Everything
all absolutely perfect. Everything is
exquisite,
exquisite, perfect
all absolutely perfect. Everything is
exquisite, perfect and
exquisite, perfect and beautiful
all absolutely perfect. Everything is
exquisite, perfect and beautiful as
exquisite, perfect and beautiful as it
is.
is. And
is. And that
is. And that things
is. And that things come
is. And that things come about
is. And that things come about as
is. And that things come about as a
result
result of
is. And that things come about as a
result of potentiality
result of potentiality actualizing.
Potentiality
Potentiality actualizes
Potentiality actualizes as
Potentiality actualizes as a
Potentiality actualizes as a perceivable
reality.
reality. So
Potentiality actualizes as a perceivable
reality. So what
reality. So what you're
Potentiality actualizes as a perceivable
reality. So what you're witnessing
always
always is
always is emergence
always is emergence of
always is emergence of potentiality.
You're
You're witnessing
always is emergence of potentiality.
You're witnessing the
You're witnessing the emergence
always is emergence of potentiality.
You're witnessing the emergence of
potentiality.
The
The emergence
potentiality.
The emergence of
The emergence of potentiality
potentiality.
The emergence of potentiality is
The emergence of potentiality is for
this
this arm
this arm to
this arm to rise.
this arm to rise. It's
this arm to rise. It's the
this arm to rise. It's the arms
this arm to rise. It's the arms to
rises.
rises. It
this arm to rise. It's the arms to
rises. It does
rises. It does it
this arm to rise. It's the arms to
rises. It does it by
rises. It does it by itself.
this arm to rise. It's the arms to
rises. It does it by itself. You
rises. It does it by itself. You think
there's
there's a
there's a you
there's a you causing
there's a you causing it.
there's a you causing it. I
there's a you causing it. I don't
there's a you causing it. I don't have
anything
anything to
there's a you causing it. I don't have
anything to do
anything to do with
there's a you causing it. I don't have
anything to do with it.
anything to do with it. It
there's a you causing it. I don't have
anything to do with it. It rose
anything to do with it. It rose itself
spontaneously.
All
All is
spontaneously.
All is occurring
All is occurring spontaneously
because
because of
because of the
because of the emergence
because of the emergence of
because of the emergence of potentiality
is
is actuality
because of the emergence of potentiality
is actuality when
is actuality when conditions
because of the emergence of potentiality
is actuality when conditions are
favorable.
favorable. That's
favorable. That's nonlinear
favorable. That's nonlinear dynamics
etc.
When
When conditions
When conditions are
When conditions are favorable
When conditions are favorable so
When conditions are favorable so the
conditions
conditions also
When conditions are favorable so the
conditions also have
conditions also have to
When conditions are favorable so the
conditions also have to be
conditions also have to be favorable.
When conditions are favorable so the
conditions also have to be favorable. So
you
you don't
you don't make
you don't make the
you don't make the flower
you don't make the flower grow.
I
I never
you don't make the flower grow.
I never saw
I never saw anybody
you don't make the flower grow.
I never saw anybody that
I never saw anybody that made
you don't make the flower grow.
I never saw anybody that made a
I never saw anybody that made a flower
grow.
grow. Did
grow. Did you
grow. Did you ever
grow. Did you ever meet
grow. Did you ever meet anybody
grow. Did you ever meet anybody that
made
made a
grow. Did you ever meet anybody that
made a flower
made a flower grow?
Thank
Thank you,
Thank you, God.
Thank you, God. Yeah.
Oh,
Oh, wacko
Thank you, God. Yeah.
Oh, wacko is
Oh, wacko is in
Thank you, God. Yeah.
Oh, wacko is in the
Oh, wacko is in the group
Thank you, God. Yeah.
Oh, wacko is in the group today.
When
When you
When you plant
When you plant something,
When you plant something, you're
When you plant something, you're taking
advantage
advantage of
When you plant something, you're taking
advantage of what
advantage of what I
When you plant something, you're taking
advantage of what I just
advantage of what I just got
When you plant something, you're taking
advantage of what I just got through
saying.
saying. And
saying. And all
saying. And all you're
saying. And all you're doing
saying. And all you're doing is
saying. And all you're doing is when
saying. And all you're doing is when you
add
add conditions
saying. And all you're doing is when you
add conditions are
add conditions are favorable,
saying. And all you're doing is when you
add conditions are favorable, such
add conditions are favorable, such as
sunlight,
sunlight, water,
sunlight, water, and
sunlight, water, and fertilizer.
sunlight, water, and fertilizer. But
sunlight, water, and fertilizer. But the
potentiality
potentiality is
sunlight, water, and fertilizer. But the
potentiality is within
potentiality is within the
sunlight, water, and fertilizer. But the
potentiality is within the seed.
potentiality is within the seed. You
know,
know, it
know, it actualizes
know, it actualizes within
know, it actualizes within the
phenomenal
phenomenal world,
know, it actualizes within the
phenomenal world, not
phenomenal world, not as
know, it actualizes within the
phenomenal world, not as causality.
phenomenal world, not as causality. You
can't
can't force
can't force a
can't force a flower
can't force a flower to
can't force a flower to to to
can't force a flower to to to bloom.
can't force a flower to to to bloom. You
know
know what
can't force a flower to to to bloom. You
know what I'm
know what I'm saying?
Also,
Also, you
Also, you get
Also, you get rid
Also, you get rid of
Also, you get rid of the
Also, you get rid of the idea
Also, you get rid of the idea of
imperfection.
imperfection. Yeah.
Also, you get rid of the idea of
imperfection. Yeah. See,
imperfection. Yeah. See, because
Also, you get rid of the idea of
imperfection. Yeah. See, because here
imperfection. Yeah. See, because here is
has
has the
has the potential
has the potential to
has the potential to become
has the potential to become a
has the potential to become a rose.
has the potential to become a rose. So,
the
the rose
has the potential to become a rose. So,
the rose is
the rose is half
has the potential to become a rose. So,
the rose is half unfolded.
the rose is half unfolded. Now,
has the potential to become a rose. So,
the rose is half unfolded. Now, you're
going
going to
going to tell
going to tell me
going to tell me that's
going to tell me that's a
going to tell me that's a bad
going to tell me that's a bad rose
going to tell me that's a bad rose of
defective
defective rose.
going to tell me that's a bad rose of
defective rose. Something
defective rose. Something wrong
going to tell me that's a bad rose of
defective rose. Something wrong with
defective rose. Something wrong with the
rose?
No.
No. You
rose?
No. You see
No. You see what
rose?
No. You see what happens
No. You see what happens is
rose?
No. You see what happens is the
No. You see what happens is the the
potentiality
potentiality actualizes
potentiality actualizes and
potentiality actualizes and it
potentiality actualizes and it opens
potentiality actualizes and it opens and
becomes
becomes actualized
potentiality actualizes and it opens and
becomes actualized to
becomes actualized to your
potentiality actualizes and it opens and
becomes actualized to your perception.
Nothing
Nothing is
Nothing is causing
Nothing is causing it
Nothing is causing it to
Nothing is causing it to do
Nothing is causing it to do that.
Nothing is causing it to do that. You
can't
can't force
Nothing is causing it to do that. You
can't force a
can't force a rose
Nothing is causing it to do that. You
can't force a rose to
can't force a rose to do
Nothing is causing it to do that. You
can't force a rose to do anything.
can't force a rose to do anything. It
does
does it
does it of
does it of its
does it of its own
does it of its own because
does it of its own because it
does it of its own because it has
does it of its own because it has innate
within
within its
does it of its own because it has innate
within its essence
within its essence is
does it of its own because it has innate
within its essence is the
within its essence is the potentiality
to
to manifest
to manifest that
to manifest that way
to manifest that way within
to manifest that way within the
to manifest that way within the linear
domain.
domain. So
to manifest that way within the linear
domain. So all
domain. So all you're
to manifest that way within the linear
domain. So all you're seeing
domain. So all you're seeing is
phenomena
phenomena within
phenomena within the
phenomena within the linear
phenomena within the linear domain.
phenomena within the linear domain. The
energy
energy of
phenomena within the linear domain. The
energy of life
energy of life is
phenomena within the linear domain. The
energy of life is nonlinear,
non-definable.
Yeah.
Let's
Let's do
Let's do one
Let's do one more
Let's do one more basic
Let's do one more basic principle
Let's do one more basic principle of
life.
life. Um
Let's do one more basic principle of
life. Um I
life. Um I have
Let's do one more basic principle of
life. Um I have permission
life. Um I have permission to
Let's do one more basic principle of
life. Um I have permission to ask
life. Um I have permission to ask what
I'm
I'm asking.
Life
Life is
I'm asking.
Life is indestructible.
Life is indestructible. Resist.
Death
Death is
Death is not
Death is not a
Death is not a possibility.
Death is not a possibility. Resist.
Death
Death is
Death is not a possibility. Resist.
Death is not
Death is not a
Death is not a possibility. Resist.
Death is not a possibility.
Here's
Here's the
Here's the law
Here's the law of
Here's the law of conservation
Here's the law of conservation of
energy.
energy. It
Here's the law of conservation of
energy. It can
energy. It can only
Here's the law of conservation of
energy. It can only move
energy. It can only move from
Here's the law of conservation of
energy. It can only move from one
energy. It can only move from one form
to
to another
of
of substance.
to another
of substance. Materials
of substance. Materials can
to another
of substance. Materials can only
of substance. Materials can only move
from
from one
from one substance
from one substance to
from one substance to another,
from one substance to another, one
from one substance to another, one form
to
to another.
from one substance to another, one form
to another. And
to another. And I
from one substance to another, one form
to another. And I don't
to another. And I don't know
from one substance to another, one form
to another. And I don't know why
to another. And I don't know why the
world
world never
world never noticed
world never noticed it,
world never noticed it, but
world never noticed it, but there's
world never noticed it, but there's the
law
law of
world never noticed it, but there's the
law of conservation
law of conservation of
world never noticed it, but there's the
law of conservation of life.
law of conservation of life. Life
world never noticed it, but there's the
law of conservation of life. Life can
only
only change
only change form.
only change form. So
only change form. So you
only change form. So you can
only change form. So you can hit
only change form. So you can hit the
butterfly
butterfly and
only change form. So you can hit the
butterfly and instantly
butterfly and instantly he's
only change form. So you can hit the
butterfly and instantly he's flying
around
around in
around in his
around in his etheric
around in his etheric body.
around in his etheric body. Doesn't
around in his etheric body. Doesn't even
notice
notice it.
He
He doesn't
He doesn't even
He doesn't even notice
He doesn't even notice it.
He doesn't even notice it. Let's
He doesn't even notice it. Let's see.
The
The moth,
He doesn't even notice it. Let's see.
The moth, if
The moth, if you
He doesn't even notice it. Let's see.
The moth, if you swallow
The moth, if you swallow him,
He doesn't even notice it. Let's see.
The moth, if you swallow him, goes
The moth, if you swallow him, goes right
on
on flying
on flying into
on flying into the
on flying into the thick
on flying into the thick body
on flying into the thick body and
doesn't
doesn't even
on flying into the thick body and
doesn't even notice
doesn't even notice it.
on flying into the thick body and
doesn't even notice it. Resist.
doesn't even notice it. Resist. It
doesn't
doesn't even
doesn't even notice
doesn't even notice it.
doesn't even notice it. So
doesn't even notice it. So heaping
doesn't even notice it. So heaping ashes
on
on your
doesn't even notice it. So heaping ashes
on your head
on your head that
doesn't even notice it. So heaping ashes
on your head that you've
on your head that you've killed
something
something is
something is a
something is a great
something is a great delusion.
You
You can't
something is a great delusion.
You can't kill
You can't kill anything.
something is a great delusion.
You can't kill anything. You
You can't kill anything. You can
something is a great delusion.
You can't kill anything. You can be
You can't kill anything. You can be the
precipitating
precipitating figure.
precipitating figure. It
precipitating figure. It precipit
precipitates.
precipitates. It's
precipitating figure. It precipit
precipitates. It's moving
precipitates. It's moving from
precipitating figure. It precipit
precipitates. It's moving from one
precipitates. It's moving from one form
to
to another.
to another. But
to another. But like
to another. But like the
to another. But like the law
to another. But like the law of
conservation
conservation of
to another. But like the law of
conservation of energy
conservation of energy or
to another. But like the law of
conservation of energy or matter
conservation of energy or matter uh
to another. But like the law of
conservation of energy or matter uh life
can
can change
can change form.
can change form. You
can change form. You can't
can change form. You can't exterminate
life.
life. First
can change form. You can't exterminate
life. First of
life. First of all,
can change form. You can't exterminate
life. First of all, you're
life. First of all, you're not
can change form. You can't exterminate
life. First of all, you're not the
source
source of
source of it.
source of it. Life
source of it. Life emanates
source of it. Life emanates from
source of it. Life emanates from a
different
different source
source of it. Life emanates from a
different source which
different source which is
source of it. Life emanates from a
different source which is [snorts]
different source which is [snorts] not
within
within your
within your domain.
within your domain. So
within your domain. So it's
within your domain. So it's a
within your domain. So it's a problem
within your domain. So it's a problem of
paradigms.
So
So much
So much of
So much of rel
So much of rel mankind's
So much of rel mankind's error
So much of rel mankind's error is
So much of rel mankind's error is he
doesn't
doesn't understand
So much of rel mankind's error is he
doesn't understand the
doesn't understand the limitation
So much of rel mankind's error is he
doesn't understand the limitation of
paradigm.
paradigm. What's
paradigm. What's true
paradigm. What's true in
paradigm. What's true in this
paradigm. What's true in this paradigm
is
is not
paradigm. What's true in this paradigm
is not true
is not true in
paradigm. What's true in this paradigm
is not true in another
is not true in another paradigm.
paradigm. What's true in this paradigm
is not true in another paradigm. And
is not true in another paradigm. And so
what
what I'm
what I'm working
what I'm working on
what I'm working on now,
what I'm working on now, the
what I'm working on now, the current
book
book I'm
what I'm working on now, the current
book I'm working
book I'm working on
what I'm working on now, the current
book I'm working on is
book I'm working on is to
what I'm working on now, the current
book I'm working on is to resolve
book I'm working on is to resolve the
dilemma
dilemma of
dilemma of the
dilemma of the scopes
dilemma of the scopes trial
dilemma of the scopes trial which
dilemma of the scopes trial which has
dilemma of the scopes trial which has to
do
do with
dilemma of the scopes trial which has to
do with the
do with the argument
dilemma of the scopes trial which has to
do with the argument between
do with the argument between is
dilemma of the scopes trial which has to
do with the argument between is reality
limited
limited to
limited to the
limited to the linear
or
or does
limited to the linear
or does reality
or does reality go
limited to the linear
or does reality go on
or does reality go on to
limited to the linear
or does reality go on to include
or does reality go on to include the
nonlinear?
nonlinear? The
nonlinear? The reason
nonlinear? The reason the
nonlinear? The reason the scopes
nonlinear? The reason the scopes trial
couldn't
couldn't be
nonlinear? The reason the scopes trial
couldn't be resolved
couldn't be resolved is
nonlinear? The reason the scopes trial
couldn't be resolved is because
couldn't be resolved is because of
nonlinear? The reason the scopes trial
couldn't be resolved is because of is
they
they were
they were talking
they were talking about
they were talking about two
they were talking about two different
paradigms.
The
The levels
The levels of
The levels of consciousness
The levels of consciousness go
The levels of consciousness go from
let's
let's say
The levels of consciousness go from
let's say one
let's say one [clears throat]
The levels of consciousness go from
let's say one [clears throat] to
thousand.
Science
Science is
thousand.
Science is within
Science is within the
thousand.
Science is within the 400s
Science is within the 400s and
thousand.
Science is within the 400s and spiritual
reality
reality starts
reality starts from
reality starts from 500
reality starts from 500 and
reality starts from 500 and up.
reality starts from 500 and up. They're
[clears throat]
[clears throat] two
reality starts from 500 and up. They're
[clears throat] two different
[clears throat] two different paradigms.
So
So you
So you can't
So you can't resolve
So you can't resolve oil
So you can't resolve oil and
So you can't resolve oil and water
because
because they're
So you can't resolve oil and water
because they're two
because they're two different
So you can't resolve oil and water
because they're two different paradigms.
Science
Science can
Science can neither
Science can neither prove
Science can neither prove nor
Science can neither prove nor is
Science can neither prove nor is prove
spiritual
spiritual reality
Science can neither prove nor is prove
spiritual reality nor
spiritual reality nor vice
Science can neither prove nor is prove
spiritual reality nor vice versa.
spiritual reality nor vice versa. It's
Science can neither prove nor is prove
spiritual reality nor vice versa. It's a
different
different paradigm.
different paradigm. So
different paradigm. So what
different paradigm. So what I've
different paradigm. So what I've tried
to
to do,
different paradigm. So what I've tried
to do, what
to do, what I'm
different paradigm. So what I've tried
to do, what I'm trying
to do, what I'm trying to
different paradigm. So what I've tried
to do, what I'm trying to do
to do, what I'm trying to do in
different paradigm. So what I've tried
to do, what I'm trying to do in this
book
book is
book is create
book is create a
book is create a paradigm
book is create a paradigm that
book is create a paradigm that includes
both
both and
book is create a paradigm that includes
both and shows
both and shows that
book is create a paradigm that includes
both and shows that you're
both and shows that you're just
book is create a paradigm that includes
both and shows that you're just moving
from
from one
from one paradigm
from one paradigm to
from one paradigm to another
from one paradigm to another and
from one paradigm to another and uh
from one paradigm to another and uh that
would
would be
from one paradigm to another and uh that
would be inclusive
would be inclusive of
from one paradigm to another and uh that
would be inclusive of both
would be inclusive of both science
from one paradigm to another and uh that
would be inclusive of both science and
religion.
religion. So
religion. So you
religion. So you see
religion. So you see they're
religion. So you see they're both
religion. So you see they're both true
and
and both
religion. So you see they're both true
and both 100%
and both 100% true
religion. So you see they're both true
and both 100% true within
and both 100% true within their
religion. So you see they're both true
and both 100% true within their own
paradigms.
So
So the
paradigms.
So the ignorance
So the ignorance there
paradigms.
So the ignorance there was
So the ignorance there was the
paradigms.
So the ignorance there was the two
So the ignorance there was the two sides
expecting
expecting each
expecting each other
expecting each other uh
expecting each other uh to
expecting each other uh to agree
expecting each other uh to agree with
what
what is
expecting each other uh to agree with
what is really
what is really a
expecting each other uh to agree with
what is really a different
what is really a different paradigm
expecting each other uh to agree with
what is really a different paradigm of
reality.
reality. Yes,
reality. Yes, you
reality. Yes, you you'll
reality. Yes, you you'll tell
reality. Yes, you you'll tell me.
>> Yes.
>> Uh
>> Uh we
>> Uh we need
>> Uh we need another
>> Uh we need another slide.
Um
oh
oh yes.
Um
this
this has
this has to
this has to do
this has to do with
this has to do with the
this has to do with the it's
this has to do with the it's analogous
to
to the
this has to do with the it's analogous
to the scale
to the scale of
this has to do with the it's analogous
to the scale of consciousness
to the scale of consciousness and
this has to do with the it's analogous
to the scale of consciousness and how
to the scale of consciousness and how to
get
get by
get by duality.
Uh
Uh the
get by duality.
Uh the world
Uh the world presumes
get by duality.
Uh the world presumes there
Uh the world presumes there are
get by duality.
Uh the world presumes there are two
things
things when
things when there's
things when there's actually
things when there's actually only
things when there's actually only one
thing.
thing. Yeah.
things when there's actually only one
thing. Yeah. You
thing. Yeah. You see
things when there's actually only one
thing. Yeah. You see they
thing. Yeah. You see they see
things when there's actually only one
thing. Yeah. You see they see the
thing. Yeah. You see they see the world
sees
sees opposites
sees opposites hot
sees opposites hot and
sees opposites hot and cold
sees opposites hot and cold let's
sees opposites hot and cold let's say
sees opposites hot and cold let's say or
light
light and
sees opposites hot and cold let's say or
light and dark.
light and dark. Well
sees opposites hot and cold let's say or
light and dark. Well dark
light and dark. Well dark is
sees opposites hot and cold let's say or
light and dark. Well dark is the
light and dark. Well dark is the absence
of
of light
of light and
of light and then
of light and then bright
of light and then bright you
of light and then bright you can
of light and then bright you can keep
increasing
increasing it.
of light and then bright you can keep
increasing it. As
increasing it. As you
of light and then bright you can keep
increasing it. As you can
increasing it. As you can see
of light and then bright you can keep
increasing it. As you can see it's
increasing it. As you can see it's not
of light and then bright you can keep
increasing it. As you can see it's not a
matter
matter of
matter of you
matter of you know
matter of you know light
matter of you know light vers
matter of you know light vers versus
darkness.
darkness. That's
matter of you know light vers versus
darkness. That's only
darkness. That's only a
matter of you know light vers versus
darkness. That's only a matter
darkness. That's only a matter of
speech.
Light
Light is
speech.
Light is either
Light is either present
speech.
Light is either present or
Light is either present or not
speech.
Light is either present or not present.
If
If it's
If it's not
If it's not present,
If it's not present, so
If it's not present, so it's
If it's not present, so it's either
there
there or
If it's not present, so it's either
there or not
there or not there,
If it's not present, so it's either
there or not there, which
there or not there, which is
If it's not present, so it's either
there or not there, which is different
than
than seeing
than seeing it
than seeing it as
than seeing it as opposites.
than seeing it as opposites. The
than seeing it as opposites. The same
with
with heat
than seeing it as opposites. The same
with heat and
with heat and cold.
You
You keep
You keep increasing
You keep increasing the
You keep increasing the the
You keep increasing the the temperature
and
and you
You keep increasing the the temperature
and you get
and you get warmer
You keep increasing the the temperature
and you get warmer and
and you get warmer and warmer.
You keep increasing the the temperature
and you get warmer and warmer. Finally,
at
at a
at a certain
at a certain point,
at a certain point, you
at a certain point, you say
at a certain point, you say hot.
at a certain point, you say hot. When
you
you say
at a certain point, you say hot. When
you say hot
you say hot is
at a certain point, you say hot. When
you say hot is now
you say hot is now the
at a certain point, you say hot. When
you say hot is now the opposite
you say hot is now the opposite of
at a certain point, you say hot. When
you say hot is now the opposite of cold,
not
not the
not the opposite,
not the opposite, it's
not the opposite, it's the
not the opposite, it's the absence
not the opposite, it's the absence of
heat.
heat. Cold
not the opposite, it's the absence of
heat. Cold is
heat. Cold is the
not the opposite, it's the absence of
heat. Cold is the absence
heat. Cold is the absence of
not the opposite, it's the absence of
heat. Cold is the absence of heat.
heat. Cold is the absence of heat. It's
not
not the
not the opposite.
Truth
Truth and
not the opposite.
Truth and false.
Truth and false. Therefore,
not the opposite.
Truth and false. Therefore, truth
Truth and false. Therefore, truth and
falsehood,
falsehood, you
falsehood, you know,
falsehood, you know, it's
falsehood, you know, it's the
falsehood, you know, it's the same.
There
There are
falsehood, you know, it's the same.
There are degrees
There are degrees of
falsehood, you know, it's the same.
There are degrees of truth.
There are degrees of truth. That's
falsehood, you know, it's the same.
There are degrees of truth. That's what
the
the calibrated
the calibrated lows
the calibrated lows of
the calibrated lows of consciousness.
You
You cannot
the calibrated lows of consciousness.
You cannot prove
You cannot prove nor
the calibrated lows of consciousness.
You cannot prove nor can
You cannot prove nor can you
the calibrated lows of consciousness.
You cannot prove nor can you you
You cannot prove nor can you you can
neither
neither prove
neither prove nor
neither prove nor disprove
neither prove nor disprove truth.
neither prove nor disprove truth. Yes.
Because
Because it's
neither prove nor disprove truth. Yes.
Because it's of
Because it's of a
neither prove nor disprove truth. Yes.
Because it's of a different
Because it's of a different domain.
neither prove nor disprove truth. Yes.
Because it's of a different domain. It's
not
not in
not in the
not in the same
not in the same domain
not in the same domain of
not in the same domain of the
not in the same domain of the provable
versus
versus the
not in the same domain of the provable
versus the nonprovable.
Therefore,
Therefore, to
Therefore, to get
Therefore, to get beyond
Therefore, to get beyond a
Therefore, to get beyond a lot
Therefore, to get beyond a lot of
dualities,
dualities, all
Therefore, to get beyond a lot of
dualities, all all
dualities, all all you
Therefore, to get beyond a lot of
dualities, all all you have
dualities, all all you have to
Therefore, to get beyond a lot of
dualities, all all you have to see
dualities, all all you have to see is
that
that it
that it is
that it is merely
that it is merely um
that it is merely um an
that it is merely um an arbitrary
that it is merely um an arbitrary scale
of
of left
that it is merely um an arbitrary scale
of left or
of left or right.
that it is merely um an arbitrary scale
of left or right. Are
of left or right. Are you
that it is merely um an arbitrary scale
of left or right. Are you politically
left
left or
left or politically
left or politically right?
left or politically right? It
left or politically right? It depends
left or politically right? It depends on
where
where you
left or politically right? It depends on
where you move
where you move the
left or politically right? It depends on
where you move the pendulum.
where you move the pendulum. You
left or politically right? It depends on
where you move the pendulum. You know,
uh
uh today's
uh today's world
uh today's world when
uh today's world when in
uh today's world when in the
uh today's world when in the world
compared
compared to the
uh today's world when in the world
compared to the world
compared to the world I
uh today's world when in the world
compared to the world I grew
compared to the world I grew up
uh today's world when in the world
compared to the world I grew up would
probably
probably be
probably be all
probably be all in
probably be all in jail
probably be all in jail or
probably be all in jail or something.
[laughter]
They're
They're all
They're all felonies
They're all felonies probably
They're all felonies probably at
They're all felonies probably at the
time
time I
They're all felonies probably at the
time I grew
time I grew up.
So
So is
So is one
So is one right
So is one right or
So is one right or one
So is one right or one wrong?
So is one right or one wrong? It
So is one right or one wrong? It isn't.
It
It just
So is one right or one wrong? It isn't.
It just depends
It just depends on
So is one right or one wrong? It isn't.
It just depends on the
It just depends on the context.
So is one right or one wrong? It isn't.
It just depends on the context. So
It just depends on the context. So as
you
you shift
you shift from
you shift from this
you shift from this context,
you shift from this context, this
you shift from this context, this is
good.
good. And
you shift from this context, this is
good. And you
good. And you shift
you shift from this context, this is
good. And you shift to
good. And you shift to this
you shift from this context, this is
good. And you shift to this context,
this
this is
this is bad.
this is bad. Uh
this is bad. Uh all
this is bad. Uh all you
this is bad. Uh all you shift,
this is bad. Uh all you shift, you
haven't
haven't changed
this is bad. Uh all you shift, you
haven't changed anything
haven't changed anything about
this is bad. Uh all you shift, you
haven't changed anything about good
haven't changed anything about good or
bad.
bad. You've
bad. You've only
bad. You've only shifted
bad. You've only shifted context.
bad. You've only shifted context. All
right.
right. So
bad. You've only shifted context. All
right. So we'll
right. So we'll take
bad. You've only shifted context. All
right. So we'll take one
right. So we'll take one last
bad. You've only shifted context. All
right. So we'll take one last next
slide.
Um
Um and
slide.
Um and I
Um and I think
slide.
Um and I think we
Um and I think we should
slide.
Um and I think we should take
Um and I think we should take a
slide.
Um and I think we should take a break
and
and then
and then we'll
and then we'll do
and then we'll do spiritual
and then we'll do spiritual practices.
Uh
Uh because
and then we'll do spiritual practices.
Uh because to
Uh because to a
and then we'll do spiritual practices.
Uh because to a group
Uh because to a group like
and then we'll do spiritual practices.
Uh because to a group like ourselves
these
these are
these are very
these are very important
these are very important and
these are very important and all
these are very important and all of
these are very important and all of us
have
have pursued
these are very important and all of us
have pursued some
have pursued some spiritual
these are very important and all of us
have pursued some spiritual practice
have pursued some spiritual practice uh
sometimes
sometimes to
sometimes to extreme
sometimes to extreme degrees
sometimes to extreme degrees and
sometimes to extreme degrees and uh
we've
we've given
sometimes to extreme degrees and uh
we've given up
we've given up everything
sometimes to extreme degrees and uh
we've given up everything in
we've given up everything in the
sometimes to extreme degrees and uh
we've given up everything in the world
to
to pursue
to pursue them.
to pursue them. Uh
to pursue them. Uh I
to pursue them. Uh I myself
to pursue them. Uh I myself did
to pursue them. Uh I myself did gave
to pursue them. Uh I myself did gave up
everything
everything in
to pursue them. Uh I myself did gave up
everything in the
everything in the world
to pursue them. Uh I myself did gave up
everything in the world walked
everything in the world walked away
to pursue them. Uh I myself did gave up
everything in the world walked away from
everything
everything and
everything and I
everything and I had
everything and I had it
everything and I had it in
everything and I had it in spades
everything and I had it in spades and
everything and I had it in spades and uh
took
took the
everything and I had it in spades and uh
took the old
took the old truck
everything and I had it in spades and uh
took the old truck threw
took the old truck threw my
everything and I had it in spades and uh
took the old truck threw my tools
took the old truck threw my tools in
everything and I had it in spades and uh
took the old truck threw my tools in the
back
back and
back and drove
back and drove away.
>> [laughter]
>> And
>> And then
>> And then I
>> And then I got
>> And then I got a
>> And then I got a job
uh
uh trucking
>> And then I got a job
uh trucking manure
uh trucking manure in
>> And then I got a job
uh trucking manure in Sedona
because
because nobody
because nobody else
because nobody else would
because nobody else would truck
because nobody else would truck manure.
They
They get
because nobody else would truck manure.
They get their
They get their nice
because nobody else would truck manure.
They get their nice pickup
They get their nice pickup truck
because nobody else would truck manure.
They get their nice pickup truck all
dirty.
dirty. So
dirty. So I
dirty. So I would
dirty. So I would truck
dirty. So I would truck dairy
dirty. So I would truck dairy manure
dirty. So I would truck dairy manure for
the
the people's
dirty. So I would truck dairy manure for
the people's gardens.
the people's gardens. And
dirty. So I would truck dairy manure for
the people's gardens. And I
the people's gardens. And I had
dirty. So I would truck dairy manure for
the people's gardens. And I had a
the people's gardens. And I had a nice
dump
dump truck.
dump truck. You
dump truck. You pull
dump truck. You pull this
dump truck. You pull this thing
dump truck. You pull this thing and
dump truck. You pull this thing and go
like
like this
dump truck. You pull this thing and go
like this and
like this and shoot
dump truck. You pull this thing and go
like this and shoot up
like this and shoot up at
dump truck. You pull this thing and go
like this and shoot up at 45
like this and shoot up at 45 bucks
dump truck. You pull this thing and go
like this and shoot up at 45 bucks a
load.
load. So
load. So that's
load. So that's how
load. So that's how I
load. So that's how I lived.
load. So that's how I lived. [laughter]
[clears throat]
It
It came
It came a
It came a terrible
It came a terrible day.
It came a terrible day. I
It came a terrible day. I backed
It came a terrible day. I backed up
It came a terrible day. I backed up to
this
this lady's
It came a terrible day. I backed up to
this lady's garden
this lady's garden and
It came a terrible day. I backed up to
this lady's garden and I
this lady's garden and I pulled
It came a terrible day. I backed up to
this lady's garden and I pulled the
plunger
plunger on
plunger on the
plunger on the dumper
plunger on the dumper and
plunger on the dumper and it
plunger on the dumper and it just
plunger on the dumper and it just went
ne.
ne. [laughter]
That
That was
That was a
That was a bad
That was a bad day
That was a bad day in
That was a bad day in Black
That was a bad day in Black Rockck
Scott.
Scott. I've
That was a bad day in Black Rockck
Scott. I've done
Scott. I've done everything
That was a bad day in Black Rockck
Scott. I've done everything including
shoveling
shoveling wet
shoveling wet manure.
shoveling wet manure. Okay.
shoveling wet manure. Okay. We'll
shoveling wet manure. Okay. We'll take
shoveling wet manure. Okay. We'll take a
break
break for
shoveling wet manure. Okay. We'll take a
break for how
break for how long?
>> About
>> About 15
>> About 15 minutes.
>> Hey.
>> Hey. Yeah,
>> About 15 minutes.
>> Hey. Yeah, there's
>> Hey. Yeah, there's a
>> About 15 minutes.
>> Hey. Yeah, there's a we
>> Hey. Yeah, there's a we have
>> About 15 minutes.
>> Hey. Yeah, there's a we have a
>> Hey. Yeah, there's a we have a 15inut
break
break and
break and there's
break and there's refresh
break and there's refresh refreshments
in
in the
break and there's refresh refreshments
in the building
>> and
>> and I
>> and I will
>> and I will see
>> and I will see you
>> and I will see you after
>> and I will see you after the
>> and I will see you after the break.
>> and I will see you after the break. God
bless.
bless. [applause]
>> [applause]
[applause]
>> Fastest
>> Fastest way
>> Fastest way to
>> Fastest way to God
>> Fastest way to God is
>> Fastest way to God is through
>> Fastest way to God is through humor.
It's
It's never
>> Fastest way to God is through humor.
It's never listened
It's never listened under
>> Fastest way to God is through humor.
It's never listened under spiritual
techniques
techniques and
techniques and it's
techniques and it's one
techniques and it's one of the
techniques and it's one of the greatest
there
there is.
Why?
Why? because
Why? because it
Why? because it contrasts
Why? because it contrasts belief
Why? because it contrasts belief with
reality
reality and
Why? because it contrasts belief with
reality and you
reality and you see
Why? because it contrasts belief with
reality and you see the
reality and you see the disparity
Why? because it contrasts belief with
reality and you see the disparity and
you
you can
you can get
you can get it
you can get it from
you can get it from humor
you can get it from humor whereas
you can get it from humor whereas you
would
would battle
you can get it from humor whereas you
would battle it
would battle it for
you can get it from humor whereas you
would battle it for decades
would battle it for decades through
reason.
reason. Yeah.
reason. Yeah. and
reason. Yeah. and people
reason. Yeah. and people who
reason. Yeah. and people who have
reason. Yeah. and people who have done
the
the most
reason. Yeah. and people who have done
the most good
the most good for
reason. Yeah. and people who have done
the most good for our
the most good for our society.
reason. Yeah. and people who have done
the most good for our society. Some
the most good for our society. Some of
them
them who
them who killed
them who killed themselves
them who killed themselves anyway
[laughter]
did
did it
did it through
did it through humor,
did it through humor, blew
did it through humor, blew themselves
did it through humor, blew themselves up
and
and all,
did it through humor, blew themselves up
and all, but
and all, but they
did it through humor, blew themselves up
and all, but they uh
through
through humor.
through humor. Uh
I
I remember
through humor. Uh
I remember Jack
I remember Jack Benny,
through humor. Uh
I remember Jack Benny, you
I remember Jack Benny, you know,
through humor. Uh
I remember Jack Benny, you know, Robert
says,
says, "Your
says, "Your money
says, "Your money or
says, "Your money or your
says, "Your money or your life."
says, "Your money or your life." And
says, "Your money or your life." And he
says,
says, "Well,
says, "Your money or your life." And he
says, "Well, let's
says, "Well, let's uh
says, "Your money or your life." And he
says, "Well, let's uh not
says, "Well, let's uh not be
says, "Your money or your life." And he
says, "Well, let's uh not be in
says, "Well, let's uh not be in a wretch
about
about this.
>> [laughter]
>> You
>> You see
>> You see how
>> You see how humor
>> You see how humor brings
>> You see how humor brings up,
>> You see how humor brings up, you
>> You see how humor brings up, you know,
that
that so
>> You see how humor brings up, you know,
that so many
that so many people
>> You see how humor brings up, you know,
that so many people do
that so many people do worship
>> You see how humor brings up, you know,
that so many people do worship money
that so many people do worship money and
physicality
physicality over
physicality over life
physicality over life itself
physicality over life itself over,
physicality over life itself over, you
know,
know, so
physicality over life itself over, you
know, so humor
know, so humor very
physicality over life itself over, you
know, so humor very often
know, so humor very often confronts
physicality over life itself over, you
know, so humor very often confronts you
and
and you
and you can
and you can see
and you can see the
and you can see the answer
and you can see the answer right
and you can see the answer right away.
Intellectually,
Intellectually, you
and you can see the answer right away.
Intellectually, you might
Intellectually, you might resist
and you can see the answer right away.
Intellectually, you might resist it,
Intellectually, you might resist it, but
in
in the
in the form
in the form of
in the form of humor,
in the form of humor, your
in the form of humor, your defenses
in the form of humor, your defenses are
down.
>> And
>> And who
>> And who who's
>> And who who's the
>> And who who's the black
>> And who who's the black guy
>> And who who's the black guy that
>> And who who's the black guy that burned
himself
himself up?
>> And who who's the black guy that burned
himself up? Richard
himself up? Richard Prior,
>> Richard
>> Richard Prior,
>> Richard Prior, as
>> Richard Prior, as they
>> Richard Prior, as they all
>> Richard Prior, as they all say,
>> Richard Prior, as they all say, did
>> Richard Prior, as they all say, did more
to
to decrease
>> Richard Prior, as they all say, did more
to decrease prejudice
to decrease prejudice against
>> Richard Prior, as they all say, did more
to decrease prejudice against the
to decrease prejudice against the blacks
than
than all
than all the
than all the parades,
than all the parades, you
than all the parades, you know,
than all the parades, you know, because
he
he just
than all the parades, you know, because
he just knocked
he just knocked out
than all the parades, you know, because
he just knocked out the
he just knocked out the stereotype.
So,
So, it
So, it was
So, it was too
So, it was too idiotic
So, it was too idiotic to
So, it was too idiotic to even
So, it was too idiotic to even be
prejudicial
prejudicial anymore.
So, it was too idiotic to even be
prejudicial anymore. He
prejudicial anymore. He just
So, it was too idiotic to even be
prejudicial anymore. He just blew
prejudicial anymore. He just blew it
away.
Yeah.
Yeah. So,
away.
Yeah. So, if
Yeah. So, if you
away.
Yeah. So, if you accept
Yeah. So, if you accept your
away.
Yeah. So, if you accept your downside,
nobody
nobody can
nobody can hurt
nobody can hurt your
nobody can hurt your feelings.
[clears throat]
and
and make
and make a
and make a list
and make a list of
and make a list of all
and make a list of all your
and make a list of all your defects
and
and uh
and make a list of all your defects
and uh yeah
and uh yeah and
and make a list of all your defects
and uh yeah and uh
and uh yeah and uh have
and make a list of all your defects
and uh yeah and uh have a
and uh yeah and uh have a good
and make a list of all your defects
and uh yeah and uh have a good time
and uh yeah and uh have a good time with
them.
Stupid,
Stupid, fat,
them.
Stupid, fat, ugly,
Stupid, fat, ugly, right?
them.
Stupid, fat, ugly, right? Yep.
Stupid, fat, ugly, right? Yep. Crude,
rude.
So,
[laughter]
you
you can
[laughter]
you can get
you can get over
[laughter]
you can get over being
you can get over being neurotically
sensitive.
sensitive. You
sensitive. You just
sensitive. You just own
sensitive. You just own everything
sensitive. You just own everything about
yourself.
yourself. You
sensitive. You just own everything about
yourself. You see,
yourself. You see, it's
sensitive. You just own everything about
yourself. You see, it's not
yourself. You see, it's not politically
correct
correct in
correct in today's
correct in today's world
correct in today's world to
correct in today's world to call
correct in today's world to call me
shorty.
shorty. Well,
correct in today's world to call me
shorty. Well, mine
shorty. Well, mine were
correct in today's world to call me
shorty. Well, mine were my
shorty. Well, mine were my name
correct in today's world to call me
shorty. Well, mine were my name was
Shorty
Shorty all
Shorty all through
Shorty all through the
Shorty all through the Navy
Shorty all through the Navy and
everywhere
everywhere and
Shorty all through the Navy and
everywhere and now
everywhere and now that
Shorty all through the Navy and
everywhere and now that would
everywhere and now that would be
hurting.
hurting. It
hurting. It might
hurting. It might hurt
hurting. It might hurt somebody's
feelings.
feelings. Well,
hurting. It might hurt somebody's
feelings. Well, get
feelings. Well, get that
hurting. It might hurt somebody's
feelings. Well, get that you're
feelings. Well, get that you're short.
You
You know
You know what
You know what I
You know what I mean?
You know what I mean? Then
so
Baldi
Baldi or
Baldi or big
Baldi or big nose
Baldi or big nose or
Baldi or big nose or whatever
Baldi or big nose or whatever your
Baldi or big nose or whatever your name
is,
is, that's
Baldi or big nose or whatever your name
is, that's who
is, that's who you
Baldi or big nose or whatever your name
is, that's who you are.
is, that's who you are. So
Baldi or big nose or whatever your name
is, that's who you are. So take
is, that's who you are. So take it
Baldi or big nose or whatever your name
is, that's who you are. So take it or
leave
leave it.
what
what you
leave it.
what you accept
what you accept about
leave it.
what you accept about yourself
what you accept about yourself nobody
can
can hurt
can hurt your
can hurt your feelings
can hurt your feelings there.
can hurt your feelings there. So
can hurt your feelings there. So put
make
make a
can hurt your feelings there. So put
make a list
make a list of
can hurt your feelings there. So put
make a list of all
make a list of all the
can hurt your feelings there. So put
make a list of all the things
make a list of all the things people
can hurt your feelings there. So put
make a list of all the things people can
hurt
hurt your
hurt your feelings
hurt your feelings about
hurt your feelings about and
hurt your feelings about and then
hurt your feelings about and then accept
that
that about
hurt your feelings about and then accept
that about yourself
and
and re
and re recontextualize
and re recontextualize it.
and re recontextualize it. Uh
and re recontextualize it. Uh and
and re recontextualize it. Uh and that
way
way you
and re recontextualize it. Uh and that
way you don't
way you don't have
and re recontextualize it. Uh and that
way you don't have to
way you don't have to be
and re recontextualize it. Uh and that
way you don't have to be defensive.
way you don't have to be defensive. You
don't
don't have
don't have to
don't have to have
don't have to have heart
don't have to have heart hurt
don't have to have heart hurt feelings.
People
People don't
don't have to have heart hurt feelings.
People don't have
People don't have to
don't have to have heart hurt feelings.
People don't have to be
People don't have to be politically
correct
correct about
correct about around
correct about around you.
correct about around you. They
correct about around you. They can
correct about around you. They can just
be
be crude,
use
use vulgarities
use vulgarities and
use vulgarities and etc.
use vulgarities and etc. So
use vulgarities and etc. So all
use vulgarities and etc. So all right,
spiritual
spiritual practices.
use vulgarities and etc. So all right,
spiritual practices. I
spiritual practices. I think
use vulgarities and etc. So all right,
spiritual practices. I think this
spiritual practices. I think this is
very
very interesting
very interesting because
very interesting because this
very interesting because this uh
very interesting because this uh is
very interesting because this uh is of
course
course a
very interesting because this uh is of
course a spiritually
course a spiritually oriented
very interesting because this uh is of
course a spiritually oriented group.
course a spiritually oriented group. The
Lord's
Lord's prayer
Lord's prayer calibrates
Lord's prayer calibrates at
Lord's prayer calibrates at 650.
Om
Om pronounced
Lord's prayer calibrates at 650.
Om pronounced as
Om pronounced as not
Lord's prayer calibrates at 650.
Om pronounced as not uh
is
is at
is at 7:40.
Uh
Uh a
is at 7:40.
Uh a and
Uh a and this
is at 7:40.
Uh a and this is
Uh a and this is an
is at 7:40.
Uh a and this is an error
Uh a and this is an error error
is at 7:40.
Uh a and this is an error error in
Uh a and this is an error error in a
very
very famous
very famous book
very famous book is
very famous book is only
very famous book is only 210.
very famous book is only 210. Uh-huh.
That's
That's a
very famous book is only 210. Uh-huh.
That's a translation
That's a translation of
very famous book is only 210. Uh-huh.
That's a translation of Palia
That's a translation of Palia by
very famous book is only 210. Uh-huh.
That's a translation of Palia by Sacha
Dandanda.
Dandanda. But
Dandanda. But has
Dandanda. But has an
Dandanda. But has an error
Dandanda. But has an error in
Dandanda. But has an error in it.
Dandanda. But has an error in it. You
don't
don't want
Dandanda. But has an error in it. You
don't want to
don't want to do
Dandanda. But has an error in it. You
don't want to do it
don't want to do it this
Dandanda. But has an error in it. You
don't want to do it this way.
don't want to do it this way. You
Dandanda. But has an error in it. You
don't want to do it this way. You want
to
to go
[laughter]
Oh
Oh no,
[music]
Lord.
Lord. I
Lord. I surrender
Lord. I surrender my
Lord. I surrender my life.
Lord. I surrender my life. Amen.
Cha
Cha cha
Lord. I surrender my life. Amen.
Cha cha cha
Cha cha cha 650
Lord. I surrender my life. Amen.
Cha cha cha 650 mi
Cha cha cha 650 mi pad
Lord. I surrender my life. Amen.
Cha cha cha 650 mi pad meom.
Cha cha cha 650 mi pad meom. Aren't
these
these wonderful
these wonderful things
these wonderful things you
these wonderful things you could
these wonderful things you could do
these wonderful things you could do all
day
day doing
these wonderful things you could do all
day doing any
day doing any of
these wonderful things you could do all
day doing any of them?
Gorian
Gorian chants.
Gorian chants. You
Gorian chants. You know what
Gorian chants. You know what I
Gorian chants. You know what I mean?
You're
You're wandering
Gorian chants. You know what I mean?
You're wandering around
You're wandering around in
Gorian chants. You know what I mean?
You're wandering around in the
You're wandering around in the great
Gothic
Gothic cathedrals.
Wandering
Wandering around
Gothic cathedrals.
Wandering around a
Wandering around a great
Gothic cathedrals.
Wandering around a great Gothic
cathedral
cathedral and
cathedral and in
cathedral and in the
cathedral and in the back
cathedral and in the back you
cathedral and in the back you can
cathedral and in the back you can hear
the
the choir.
cathedral and in the back you can hear
the choir. I
the choir. I mean
cathedral and in the back you can hear
the choir. I mean it's
the choir. I mean it's a
cathedral and in the back you can hear
the choir. I mean it's a knockout.
the choir. I mean it's a knockout. So
cathedral and in the back you can hear
the choir. I mean it's a knockout. So I
said
said if
said if I
said if I have
said if I have to
said if I have to come
said if I have to come back
said if I have to come back to
said if I have to come back to this
world
world I'd
said if I have to come back to this
world I'd like
world I'd like to
said if I have to come back to this
world I'd like to be
world I'd like to be the
said if I have to come back to this
world I'd like to be the verger
world I'd like to be the verger in
said if I have to come back to this
world I'd like to be the verger in a
great
great cathedral
great cathedral like
great cathedral like Shark
great cathedral like Shark Cathedral
Cathedral
Cathedral St.
great cathedral like Shark Cathedral
Cathedral St. John
Cathedral St. John the
great cathedral like Shark Cathedral
Cathedral St. John the Divine
Washington
Washington National
Washington National Cathedral.
Washington National Cathedral. They're
so
so incredibly
Washington National Cathedral. They're
so incredibly beautiful
so incredibly beautiful they
Washington National Cathedral. They're
so incredibly beautiful they calibrate
you
you know
you know 700
you know 700 and
you know 700 and up.
you know 700 and up. Uhhuh.
Gregorian
Gregorian chants
you know 700 and up. Uhhuh.
Gregorian chants uh
Gregorian chants uh japa
you know 700 and up. Uhhuh.
Gregorian chants uh japa at
Gregorian chants uh japa at 515
you know 700 and up. Uhhuh.
Gregorian chants uh japa at 515 the
Jesus
Jesus prayer
Jesus prayer at
Jesus prayer at 525.
Sing
Sing the
Jesus prayer at 525.
Sing the rosary.
The
The pilgrimage
The pilgrimage to
The pilgrimage to Mecca.
The pilgrimage to Mecca. Uhhuh.
Uh,
Uh, yogic
The pilgrimage to Mecca. Uhhuh.
Uh, yogic chants
Uh, yogic chants curtain
The pilgrimage to Mecca. Uhhuh.
Uh, yogic chants curtain is
Uh, yogic chants curtain is sort
The pilgrimage to Mecca. Uhhuh.
Uh, yogic chants curtain is sort of
popular
popular lately.
popular lately. 250
popular lately. 250 12
popular lately. 250 12 steps
popular lately. 250 12 steps of
popular lately. 250 12 steps of alcohol
540.
You
You don't
You don't have
You don't have to
You don't have to bother
You don't have to bother going
You don't have to bother going to
You don't have to bother going to church
once
once you're
You don't have to bother going to church
once you're in
once you're in a
People
People are
People are leaving
People are leaving the
People are leaving the church
People are leaving the church and
flocking
flocking to
People are leaving the church and
flocking to God
flocking to God right
People are leaving the church and
flocking to God right and
flocking to God right and left.
People are leaving the church and
flocking to God right and left. So,
[applause]
so
so a
[applause]
so a group
so a group like
[applause]
so a group like this
so a group like this is
[applause]
so a group like this is interested
so a group like this is interested in
spiritual
spiritual truth
spiritual truth because
spiritual truth because the
spiritual truth because the what
spiritual truth because the what you're
interested
interested in
spiritual truth because the what you're
interested in about
interested in about religion
spiritual truth because the what you're
interested in about religion is
interested in about religion is what
spiritual truth because the what you're
interested in about religion is what is
the
the spiritual
the spiritual the
the spiritual the threat
the spiritual the threat of
the spiritual the threat of spiritual
truth
truth within
the spiritual the threat of spiritual
truth within that
truth within that religion.
the spiritual the threat of spiritual
truth within that religion. You
truth within that religion. You don't
want
want to
want to get
want to get caught
want to get caught up
want to get caught up in
want to get caught up in religiosity.
Many
Many people
want to get caught up in religiosity.
Many people substitute
Many people substitute religionism
want to get caught up in religiosity.
Many people substitute religionism for
God.
God. what
God. what they
God. what they worship
God. what they worship is
God. what they worship is the
God. what they worship is the religion
and
and not
God. what they worship is the religion
and not divinity.
Therefore,
Therefore, they
Therefore, they put
Therefore, they put you
Therefore, they put you to
Therefore, they put you to death
Therefore, they put you to death because
you
you don't
Therefore, they put you to death because
you don't believe
you don't believe in
Therefore, they put you to death because
you don't believe in their
you don't believe in their religion.
Therefore, they put you to death because
you don't believe in their religion. So,
that's
that's religiosity,
that's religiosity, which
that's religiosity, which to
that's religiosity, which to me
that's religiosity, which to me is
that's religiosity, which to me is a
violation
because
because you're
because you're substituting
because you're substituting some
because you're substituting some belief
system
system for
because you're substituting some belief
system for for
system for for divinity
because you're substituting some belief
system for for divinity itself.
All
All right.
All right. The
All right. The golden
All right. The golden rule
All right. The golden rule is
All right. The golden rule is a
All right. The golden rule is a 405.
Uh
Uh TM
All right. The golden rule is a 405.
Uh TM 295,
Uh TM 295, prayer
All right. The golden rule is a 405.
Uh TM 295, prayer of
Uh TM 295, prayer of Jabz
All right. The golden rule is a 405.
Uh TM 295, prayer of Jabz 310.
Uh TM 295, prayer of Jabz 310. walking
the
the labyrinth
the labyrinth at
the labyrinth at Shark
the labyrinth at Shark Cathedral
the labyrinth at Shark Cathedral 503.
And
And of
the labyrinth at Shark Cathedral 503.
And of course,
And of course, when
the labyrinth at Shark Cathedral 503.
And of course, when you
And of course, when you go
the labyrinth at Shark Cathedral 503.
And of course, when you go to
And of course, when you go to Shark
Cathedral,
Cathedral, you
Cathedral, you can't
Cathedral, you can't walk
Cathedral, you can't walk the
Cathedral, you can't walk the labyrinth.
[laughter]
First
First of
First of all,
First of all, they
First of all, they put
First of all, they put chairs
First of all, they put chairs up,
First of all, they put chairs up, so
First of all, they put chairs up, so you
can't.
But
But secondly,
But secondly, it's
But secondly, it's full
But secondly, it's full of
But secondly, it's full of mobs
But secondly, it's full of mobs of
But secondly, it's full of mobs of uh
But secondly, it's full of mobs of uh uh
of
of what
But secondly, it's full of mobs of uh uh
of what what
of what what do
But secondly, it's full of mobs of uh uh
of what what do they
of what what do they call
But secondly, it's full of mobs of uh uh
of what what do they call those
of what what do they call those people?
Tourists.
Tourists. Yes.
Tourists. Yes. So,
Tourists. Yes. So, when
Tourists. Yes. So, when you
Tourists. Yes. So, when you go
Tourists. Yes. So, when you go to
Tourists. Yes. So, when you go to the
great
great Cathedral
Tourists. Yes. So, when you go to the
great Cathedral of
great Cathedral of the
Tourists. Yes. So, when you go to the
great Cathedral of the World
great Cathedral of the World now,
Tourists. Yes. So, when you go to the
great Cathedral of the World now, it's
jammed
jammed with
jammed with tourists
jammed with tourists and
jammed with tourists and they're
jammed with tourists and they're on
their
their cell
jammed with tourists and they're on
their cell phone.
their cell phone. So
jammed with tourists and they're on
their cell phone. So here
their cell phone. So here you
jammed with tourists and they're on
their cell phone. So here you you're
going
going to
going to experience
going to experience the
going to experience the splendor
going to experience the splendor of
going to experience the splendor of God
and
and hello
going to experience the splendor of God
and hello market.
and hello market. Well,
going to experience the splendor of God
and hello market. Well, I
and hello market. Well, I just
going to experience the splendor of God
and hello market. Well, I just think
there
there everybody's
there everybody's got
there everybody's got their
there everybody's got their cell
there everybody's got their cell phone
which
which is
there everybody's got their cell phone
which is the
which is the fault
there everybody's got their cell phone
which is the fault of
which is the fault of the
there everybody's got their cell phone
which is the fault of the people
which is the fault of the people running
the
the cathedral.
the cathedral. I
the cathedral. I mean
the cathedral. I mean I
the cathedral. I mean I would
the cathedral. I mean I would say
silence
silence or
the cathedral. I mean I would say
silence or out.
silence or out. [laughter]
the cathedral. I mean I would say
silence or out. [laughter] Silent
silence or out. [laughter] Silent or
out.
out. You
out. You can
out. You can talk
out. You can talk on
out. You can talk on your
out. You can talk on your cell
out. You can talk on your cell phone
out. You can talk on your cell phone out
there.
there. It
out. You can talk on your cell phone out
there. It was
there. It was sort
out. You can talk on your cell phone out
there. It was sort of
there. It was sort of shocking
out. You can talk on your cell phone out
there. It was sort of shocking to
experience
experience some
experience some of
experience some of the
experience some of the great
experience some of the great cathedrals
jam
jam with
experience some of the great cathedrals
jam with people
jam with people [laughter]
experience some of the great cathedrals
jam with people [laughter] on
jam with people [laughter] on their
experience some of the great cathedrals
jam with people [laughter] on their cell
phones.
phones. I
phones. I was
phones. I was sort
phones. I was sort of
phones. I was sort of missing
phones. I was sort of missing what
phones. I was sort of missing what the
whole
whole thing
phones. I was sort of missing what the
whole thing was
whole thing was about.
phones. I was sort of missing what the
whole thing was about. Uh
whole thing was about. Uh so
phones. I was sort of missing what the
whole thing was about. Uh so walking
whole thing was about. Uh so walking the
labyrinth
labyrinth however
labyrinth however we
labyrinth however we have
labyrinth however we have a
labyrinth however we have a local
labyrinth however we have a local church
that
that does
labyrinth however we have a local church
that does that
uh
uh St.
uh St. Dangerous.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, they
uh St. Dangerous.
>> Yeah, they have
>> Yeah, they have a
uh St. Dangerous.
>> Yeah, they have a you
>> Yeah, they have a you can
uh St. Dangerous.
>> Yeah, they have a you can walk.
>> Yeah, they have a you can walk. Uh
genulection
genulection itself
genulection itself is
genulection itself is 540.
Kneeling
Kneeling to
genulection itself is 540.
Kneeling to pray,
Kneeling to pray, prayerful
genulection itself is 540.
Kneeling to pray, prayerful hand
Kneeling to pray, prayerful hand crest.
So
So devotional
So devotional acts
So devotional acts turning
So devotional acts turning prayer
wheels,
wheels, burning
So devotional acts turning prayer
wheels, burning of
wheels, burning of incense,
uh
uh the
uh the whailing
uh the whailing wall,
uh the whailing wall, bathing
uh the whailing wall, bathing in
uh the whailing wall, bathing in the
Ganges.
You
You see
You see these
You see these are
You see these are all
You see these are all devotional
You see these are all devotional acts.
The
The acts
You see these are all devotional acts.
The acts of
The acts of devotion.
You see these are all devotional acts.
The acts of devotion. And
The acts of devotion. And the
You see these are all devotional acts.
The acts of devotion. And the thing
The acts of devotion. And the thing that
I
I find
I find entrancing
I find entrancing about
I find entrancing about going
I find entrancing about going to
I find entrancing about going to Korea
and
and that's
I find entrancing about going to Korea
and that's why
and that's why I
I find entrancing about going to Korea
and that's why I love
and that's why I love going
I find entrancing about going to Korea
and that's why I love going there
and that's why I love going there is
because
because everyone
because everyone greets
because everyone greets each
because everyone greets each other
thusly.
It's
It's strangers.
It's strangers. You're
It's strangers. You're walking
It's strangers. You're walking through
It's strangers. You're walking through a
hotel
hotel lobby
It's strangers. You're walking through a
hotel lobby and
hotel lobby and the
It's strangers. You're walking through a
hotel lobby and the clerk
hotel lobby and the clerk goes
It's strangers. You're walking through a
hotel lobby and the clerk goes sly
hotel lobby and the clerk goes sly and
you
you automatically
you automatically find
you automatically find yourself
you automatically find yourself uh
responding
responding and
you automatically find yourself uh
responding and like
responding and like and
you automatically find yourself uh
responding and like and when
responding and like and when you
you automatically find yourself uh
responding and like and when you get
back
back to
back to the
back to the states
back to the states it
back to the states it seems
back to the states it seems sort
back to the states it seems sort of
back to the states it seems sort of rude
and
and crude.
back to the states it seems sort of rude
and crude. really
and crude. really is
back to the states it seems sort of rude
and crude. really is rude
and crude. really is rude and
back to the states it seems sort of rude
and crude. really is rude and crude
and crude. really is rude and crude by
comparison
comparison to
comparison to the
comparison to the gentleness
comparison to the gentleness and
comparison to the gentleness and the
comparison to the gentleness and the uh
acknowledgment
acknowledgment of
comparison to the gentleness and the uh
acknowledgment of the
acknowledgment of the presence
comparison to the gentleness and the uh
acknowledgment of the presence of
acknowledgment of the presence of God
comparison to the gentleness and the uh
acknowledgment of the presence of God by
so
so that
so that act
so that act itself
so that act itself is
so that act itself is at
so that act itself is at 540
uh
uh bathing
so that act itself is at 540
uh bathing in
uh bathing in the
so that act itself is at 540
uh bathing in the Ganges
uh bathing in the Ganges and
so that act itself is at 540
uh bathing in the Ganges and the
uh bathing in the Ganges and the prayer
of
of St.
of St. Francis
of St. Francis of
of St. Francis of Aisi
that
that I
of St. Francis of Aisi
that I may
that I may be
of St. Francis of Aisi
that I may be a
that I may be a a
of St. Francis of Aisi
that I may be a a pathway
that I may be a a pathway uh
of St. Francis of Aisi
that I may be a a pathway uh of
that I may be a a pathway uh of service
to
to the
to the old
to the old lord
to the old lord a
to the old lord a selfless
to the old lord a selfless pathway
to the old lord a selfless pathway so
selfless
selfless service
uh
uh prayer
uh prayer of
uh prayer of St.
uh prayer of St. Francis
uh prayer of St. Francis of
uh prayer of St. Francis of Aisi.
And
And when
uh prayer of St. Francis of Aisi.
And when I
And when I do
uh prayer of St. Francis of Aisi.
And when I do have
And when I do have to
uh prayer of St. Francis of Aisi.
And when I do have to give
And when I do have to give a
uh prayer of St. Francis of Aisi.
And when I do have to give a sermon
And when I do have to give a sermon some
church,
church, I
church, I I
church, I I I
church, I I I usually
church, I I I usually give
church, I I I usually give it
church, I I I usually give it on
church, I I I usually give it on turning
your
your life
church, I I I usually give it on turning
your life into
your life into a
church, I I I usually give it on turning
your life into a prayer.
your life into a prayer. How
church, I I I usually give it on turning
your life into a prayer. How to
your life into a prayer. How to convert
spiritual
spiritual teachings
spiritual teachings into
spiritual teachings into an
spiritual teachings into an inner
reality
reality and
spiritual teachings into an inner
reality and a
reality and a way
spiritual teachings into an inner
reality and a way of
reality and a way of being
spiritual teachings into an inner
reality and a way of being in
reality and a way of being in the
spiritual teachings into an inner
reality and a way of being in the world
that
that your
that your life
that your life then
that your life then becomes
that your life then becomes the
that your life then becomes the prayer.
[laughter]
You
You become
You become the
You become the prayer.
And
And everything
You become the prayer.
And everything is
And everything is gladdened
You become the prayer.
And everything is gladdened by
And everything is gladdened by your
presence.
presence. And
presence. And as
presence. And as you
presence. And as you walk
presence. And as you walk through
presence. And as you walk through the
woods,
woods, the
presence. And as you walk through the
woods, the trees,
woods, the trees, everything
presence. And as you walk through the
woods, the trees, everything living
woods, the trees, everything living it
is
is aware
is aware of
is aware of the
is aware of the presence
is aware of the presence of
is aware of the presence of divinity.
Whether
Whether you
is aware of the presence of divinity.
Whether you believe
Whether you believe it
is aware of the presence of divinity.
Whether you believe it or
Whether you believe it or not,
is aware of the presence of divinity.
Whether you believe it or not, that's
Whether you believe it or not, that's a
fact.
fact. It's
fact. It's all
fact. It's all aware.
fact. It's all aware. [laughter]
So
So that
fact. It's all aware. [laughter]
So that which
So that which you
fact. It's all aware. [laughter]
So that which you have
So that which you have become
fact. It's all aware. [laughter]
So that which you have become is
So that which you have become is what
transforms
transforms the
transforms the world.
transforms the world. So
transforms the world. So when
transforms the world. So when people
transforms the world. So when people say
what
what can
transforms the world. So when people say
what can I
what can I do
transforms the world. So when people say
what can I do to
what can I do to save
transforms the world. So when people say
what can I do to save the
what can I do to save the world,
transforms the world. So when people say
what can I do to save the world, help
the
the world,
the world, I
the world, I say
the world, I say first
the world, I say first of
the world, I say first of all
the world, I say first of all surrender
to
to God
the world, I say first of all surrender
to God and
to God and then
the world, I say first of all surrender
to God and then become
to God and then become the
the world, I say first of all surrender
to God and then become the prayer
to God and then become the prayer so
that
that you
that you by
that you by your
that you by your by
that you by your by virtue
that you by your by virtue of
that you by your by virtue of your
presence
presence have
that you by your by virtue of your
presence have already
uh
uh changed
uh changed the
uh changed the likelihood
uh changed the likelihood of
uh changed the likelihood of events
uh changed the likelihood of events in
the
the world.
uh changed the likelihood of events in
the world. So
the world. So a
uh changed the likelihood of events in
the world. So a group
the world. So a group like
uh changed the likelihood of events in
the world. So a group like this
the world. So a group like this has
uh changed the likelihood of events in
the world. So a group like this has an
effect
effect on
effect on the
effect on the consciousness
effect on the consciousness of
effect on the consciousness of all
effect on the consciousness of all of
life
and
and uh
and uh it's
and uh it's lifting
and uh it's lifting the
and uh it's lifting the elevating
and uh it's lifting the elevating the
level
level of
and uh it's lifting the elevating the
level of consciousness
level of consciousness of
and uh it's lifting the elevating the
level of consciousness of mankind
level of consciousness of mankind by
virtue
virtue of
virtue of that
virtue of that which
virtue of that which you
virtue of that which you are
by
by virtue
virtue of that which you are
by virtue of
by virtue of that
virtue of that which you are
by virtue of that which
by virtue of that which you
virtue of that which you are
by virtue of that which you are
by virtue of that which you are you
virtue of that which you are
by virtue of that which you are you are
already
already radiating
already radiating out
already radiating out energy
already radiating out energy into
already radiating out energy into the
field
field of
already radiating out energy into the
field of consciousness
field of consciousness itself.
Therefore,
to
to love
Therefore,
to love God,
to love God, to
Therefore,
to love God, to love
to love God, to love your
Therefore,
to love God, to love your human
everything
everything that
everything that exists,
everything that exists, to
everything that exists, to see
everything that exists, to see the
beauty
beauty and
everything that exists, to see the
beauty and perfection
beauty and perfection of
everything that exists, to see the
beauty and perfection of all
beauty and perfection of all that
everything that exists, to see the
beauty and perfection of all that exists
lifts
lifts the
lifts the level
lifts the level of
lifts the level of all
lifts the level of all of
lifts the level of all of mankind.
So,
how
how you
how you help
how you help the
how you help the rest
how you help the rest of
how you help the rest of the
how you help the rest of the people
how you help the rest of the people in
the
the world
how you help the rest of the people in
the world is
the world is through
how you help the rest of the people in
the world is through perfection
the world is through perfection of
how you help the rest of the people in
the world is through perfection of your
own
own spiritual
own spiritual evolution.
By
By that
own spiritual evolution.
By that you
By that you raise
own spiritual evolution.
By that you raise the
By that you raise the level
own spiritual evolution.
By that you raise the level common
By that you raise the level common level
of
of consciousness.
And
And you
of consciousness.
And you see
And you see as
of consciousness.
And you see as you
And you see as you ra
of consciousness.
And you see as you ra as
And you see as you ra as you
of consciousness.
And you see as you ra as you re
And you see as you ra as you re as
of consciousness.
And you see as you ra as you re as you
raise
raise the
raise the level
raise the level of
raise the level of the
raise the level of the sea
raise the level of the sea you
raise the level of the sea you lift
raise the level of the sea you lift all
the
the ships
raise the level of the sea you lift all
the ships upon
the ships upon the
raise the level of the sea you lift all
the ships upon the sea.
the ships upon the sea. Now
raise the level of the sea you lift all
the ships upon the sea. Now if
the ships upon the sea. Now if any
raise the level of the sea you lift all
the ships upon the sea. Now if any one
of
of you
of you or
of you or even
of you or even this
of you or even this group
of you or even this group tries
of you or even this group tries to
of you or even this group tries to lift
even
even one
of you or even this group tries to lift
even one ship
even one ship you're
of you or even this group tries to lift
even one ship you're not
even one ship you're not going
of you or even this group tries to lift
even one ship you're not going to
even one ship you're not going to make
it.
it. All
it. All of
it. All of us
it. All of us together
it. All of us together are
it. All of us together are not
it. All of us together are not going
it. All of us together are not going to
lift
lift one
it. All of us together are not going to
lift one ship.
But
But together
But together we
But together we lift
But together we lift the
But together we lift the sea
But together we lift the sea and
But together we lift the sea and as
But together we lift the sea and as the
sea
sea rises
But together we lift the sea and as the
sea rises all
sea rises all the
But together we lift the sea and as the
sea rises all the thousands
sea rises all the thousands of
But together we lift the sea and as the
sea rises all the thousands of ships
sea rises all the thousands of ships on
the
the sea
the sea and
the sea and the
the sea and the millions
the sea and the millions and
the sea and the millions and millions
the sea and the millions and millions of
tonnage
tonnage is
the sea and the millions and millions of
tonnage is lifted
tonnage is lifted effortlessly.
the sea and the millions and millions of
tonnage is lifted effortlessly. So
that's
that's our
that's our contribution
that's our contribution to
that's our contribution to the
that's our contribution to the world
that's our contribution to the world is
the
the perfection
that's our contribution to the world is
the perfection of
the perfection of our
that's our contribution to the world is
the perfection of our own
the perfection of our own self.
Okay.
Okay. So
Okay. So then
Okay. So then so
Okay. So then so the
Okay. So then so the prayer
Okay. So then so the prayer of
Okay. So then so the prayer of St.
Francis
Francis of
Okay. So then so the prayer of St.
Francis of Aisi
Francis of Aisi then
Okay. So then so the prayer of St.
Francis of Aisi then is
Francis of Aisi then is a
Okay. So then so the prayer of St.
Francis of Aisi then is a way
Francis of Aisi then is a way to
Okay. So then so the prayer of St.
Francis of Aisi then is a way to live
that
that you
that you yourself
that you yourself become
that you yourself become a
that you yourself become a channel
that you yourself become a channel of
God's
God's will
uh
uh to
uh to the
uh to the best
uh to the best of
uh to the best of your
uh to the best of your comprehension
uh to the best of your comprehension of
what
what that
uh to the best of your comprehension of
what that might
what that might be.
uh to the best of your comprehension of
what that might be. And
what that might be. And sometimes
uh to the best of your comprehension of
what that might be. And sometimes you
what that might be. And sometimes you we
use
use kinesiology
use kinesiology to
use kinesiology to decide
use kinesiology to decide which
use kinesiology to decide which way
would
would be
use kinesiology to decide which way
would be of
would be of the
use kinesiology to decide which way
would be of the greatest
would be of the greatest service.
use kinesiology to decide which way
would be of the greatest service. We
would be of the greatest service. We get
invited
invited to
invited to do
invited to do many
invited to do many things
invited to do many things and
invited to do many things and we
invited to do many things and we ask
invited to do many things and we ask in
the
the name
invited to do many things and we ask in
the name of
the name of the
invited to do many things and we ask in
the name of the highest
the name of the highest good.
invited to do many things and we ask in
the name of the highest good. So
the name of the highest good. So the
invited to do many things and we ask in
the name of the highest good. So the way
to
to get
to get the
to get the best
to get the best accuracy
to get the best accuracy with
kinesiology
is
is to
is to ask
is to ask in
is to ask in the
is to ask in the name
is to ask in the name of
is to ask in the name of the
is to ask in the name of the highest
good.
good. In
is to ask in the name of the highest
good. In the
good. In the name
is to ask in the name of the highest
good. In the name of
good. In the name of the
is to ask in the name of the highest
good. In the name of the highest
good. In the name of the highest good.
That
That gets
That gets your
That gets your personal
That gets your personal selfishness
That gets your personal selfishness and
your
your personal
That gets your personal selfishness and
your personal ego
your personal ego out
That gets your personal selfishness and
your personal ego out of
your personal ego out of the
That gets your personal selfishness and
your personal ego out of the way.
your personal ego out of the way. And
That gets your personal selfishness and
your personal ego out of the way. And of
course
course when
course when you
course when you ask
course when you ask for
course when you ask for the
course when you ask for the name
course when you ask for the name of
course when you ask for the name of the
highest
highest good
course when you ask for the name of the
highest good you
highest good you are
course when you ask for the name of the
highest good you are included
highest good you are included in
course when you ask for the name of the
highest good you are included in the
highest
highest good.
highest good. People
highest good. People always
highest good. People always forget
highest good. People always forget that.
I
I think
highest good. People always forget that.
I think you
I think you say
highest good. People always forget that.
I think you say well
I think you say well it
highest good. People always forget that.
I think you say well it would
I think you say well it would be
highest good. People always forget that.
I think you say well it would be uh
I think you say well it would be uh for
the
the highest
the highest good
the highest good for
the highest good for me
the highest good for me to
the highest good for me to accept
the highest good for me to accept this
business
business deal.
the highest good for me to accept this
business deal. Now
business deal. Now that
the highest good for me to accept this
business deal. Now that sound
business deal. Now that sound may
the highest good for me to accept this
business deal. Now that sound may sound
could
could be
could be selfish.
could be selfish. On
could be selfish. On the
could be selfish. On the other
could be selfish. On the other hand
could be selfish. On the other hand if
you're
you're spiritually
could be selfish. On the other hand if
you're spiritually oriented
you're spiritually oriented it
could be selfish. On the other hand if
you're spiritually oriented it could
you're spiritually oriented it could be
are
are you
are you being
are you being of
are you being of the
are you being of the greatest
are you being of the greatest service
are you being of the greatest service by
making
making that
are you being of the greatest service by
making that move
making that move or
are you being of the greatest service by
making that move or not.
making that move or not. So
are you being of the greatest service by
making that move or not. So when
making that move or not. So when you
are you being of the greatest service by
making that move or not. So when you get
a
a yes
a yes or
a yes or a
a yes or a no
a yes or a no that
a yes or a no that includes
a yes or a no that includes you
a yes or a no that includes you as
a yes or a no that includes you as well.
It
It doesn't
a yes or a no that includes you as well.
It doesn't say
It doesn't say it's
a yes or a no that includes you as well.
It doesn't say it's good
It doesn't say it's good for
a yes or a no that includes you as well.
It doesn't say it's good for the
It doesn't say it's good for the world
but
but bad
but bad for
but bad for you
but bad for you or
but bad for you or vice
but bad for you or vice versa
but bad for you or vice versa because
what's
what's good
but bad for you or vice versa because
what's good for
what's good for you
but bad for you or vice versa because
what's good for you is
what's good for you is is
but bad for you or vice versa because
what's good for you is is good
what's good for you is is good for
but bad for you or vice versa because
what's good for you is is good for the
world.
world. Huh?
Once
Once you
world. Huh?
Once you get
Once you get your
world. Huh?
Once you get your ego
Once you get your ego out
world. Huh?
Once you get your ego out of
Once you get your ego out of the
world. Huh?
Once you get your ego out of the way.
Okay.
Okay. So,
Okay. So, the
Okay. So, the next
Okay. So, the next things
uh
uh how
Okay. So, the next things
uh how to
uh how to realize
Okay. So, the next things
uh how to realize um
uh how to realize um yeah
Okay. So, the next things
uh how to realize um yeah this
uh how to realize um yeah this has
Okay. So, the next things
uh how to realize um yeah this has to
uh how to realize um yeah this has to do
with
with enlightenment.
with enlightenment. Uh
with enlightenment. Uh the
with enlightenment. Uh the overall
alignment
alignment of
with enlightenment. Uh the overall
alignment of the
alignment of the lectures
with enlightenment. Uh the overall
alignment of the lectures has
alignment of the lectures has to
with enlightenment. Uh the overall
alignment of the lectures has to do
alignment of the lectures has to do with
achieving
achieving you
achieving you know
achieving you know reaching
achieving you know reaching a
achieving you know reaching a state
called
called enlightenment.
achieving you know reaching a state
called enlightenment. So
called enlightenment. So which
achieving you know reaching a state
called enlightenment. So which means
called enlightenment. So which means uh
uh
uh oh
let's
let's see
uh oh
let's see we'll
let's see we'll get
uh oh
let's see we'll get a
let's see we'll get a towel.
uh oh
let's see we'll get a towel. What
let's see we'll get a towel. What I
think
think we
think we get
think we get some
think we get some paper
think we get some paper towels.
think we get some paper towels. Paper
towels.
Paper
Paper toes.
Paper toes. Naughty.
Paper toes. Naughty. Naughty
Paper toes. Naughty. Naughty flowers.
[laughter]
Bad
Bad flowers.
Evil
Evil flowers.
Look
Look what
Look what you've
Look what you've done.
Look
Look what
Look what you've done.
Look what those
Look what those flowers
Look what you've done.
Look what those flowers did
Look what those flowers did right
Look what you've done.
Look what those flowers did right in
front
front of
front of a
front of a crowd
front of a crowd and
front of a crowd and everything.
[laughter]
There's
There's meditation
There's meditation and
There's meditation and then
There's meditation and then there's
contemplation.
Meditation
I
I tend
Meditation
I tend to
I tend to I
Meditation
I tend to I favor
I tend to I favor contemplation
Meditation
I tend to I favor contemplation because
contemplation
contemplation is
contemplation is a
contemplation is a way
contemplation is a way of
contemplation is a way of being
contemplation is a way of being in
contemplation is a way of being in the
world
world to
contemplation is a way of being in the
world to make
world to make your
contemplation is a way of being in the
world to make your life
world to make your life prepare
contemplation is a way of being in the
world to make your life prepare is
world to make your life prepare is a
form
form of
form of contemplation.
Meditation
Meditation also
form of contemplation.
Meditation also has
Meditation also has its
form of contemplation.
Meditation also has its place
Meditation also has its place and
form of contemplation.
Meditation also has its place and all
Meditation also has its place and all of
us
us have
us have done
us have done it
us have done it and
us have done it and there
us have done it and there are
us have done it and there are various
ways
ways of
us have done it and there are various
ways of doing
ways of doing doing
us have done it and there are various
ways of doing doing it.
uh
uh and
uh and I
uh and I myself
uh and I myself did
uh and I myself did many
uh and I myself did many years
uh and I myself did many years formal
uh and I myself did many years formal uh
Zen
Zen Zen
uh and I myself did many years formal uh
Zen Zen I
Zen Zen I belong
uh and I myself did many years formal uh
Zen Zen I belong to
Zen Zen I belong to the
uh and I myself did many years formal uh
Zen Zen I belong to the first
Zen Zen I belong to the first Zen
institute
institute in
institute in America
institute in America and
institute in America and I
institute in America and I was
institute in America and I was the
consultant
consultant to
institute in America and I was the
consultant to the
consultant to the Zen
institute in America and I was the
consultant to the Zen monastery
consultant to the Zen monastery so
institute in America and I was the
consultant to the Zen monastery so I
consultant to the Zen monastery so I was
quite
quite familiar
quite familiar with
quite familiar with Zen
quite familiar with Zen meditation
however
however the
quite familiar with Zen meditation
however the thing
however the thing about
quite familiar with Zen meditation
however the thing about meditation
however the thing about meditation is
there's
there's periods
there's periods of
there's periods of enthusiasm
there's periods of enthusiasm in
there's periods of enthusiasm in which
you
you meditate
there's periods of enthusiasm in which
you meditate a
you meditate a lot
there's periods of enthusiasm in which
you meditate a lot and
you meditate a lot and then
there's periods of enthusiasm in which
you meditate a lot and then life
you meditate a lot and then life gets
busy
busy and
busy and you
busy and you don't
busy and you don't do
busy and you don't do it
busy and you don't do it at
busy and you don't do it at all
[laughter]
you
you go
you go from
you go from excessive
you go from excessive to
you go from excessive to not
you go from excessive to not at
you go from excessive to not at all
you go from excessive to not at all the
tendency
meditation
meditation tends
meditation tends to
meditation tends to be
meditation tends to be compartmentalized
off
off from
meditation tends to be compartmentalized
off from your
You
You meditate
You meditate from
You meditate from 6:00
You meditate from 6:00 to
You meditate from 6:00 to 7:00
You meditate from 6:00 to 7:00 in
You meditate from 6:00 to 7:00 in the
morning
morning and
You meditate from 6:00 to 7:00 in the
morning and then
morning and then again
You meditate from 6:00 to 7:00 in the
morning and then again from
morning and then again from 4:00
You meditate from 6:00 to 7:00 in the
morning and then again from 4:00 to
morning and then again from 4:00 to 5
You meditate from 6:00 to 7:00 in the
morning and then again from 4:00 to 5 at
night
night which
night which I
night which I did
night which I did for
night which I did for some
night which I did for some 20
night which I did for some 20 years.
Hour
Hour in
night which I did for some 20 years.
Hour in the
Hour in the morning,
night which I did for some 20 years.
Hour in the morning, hour
Hour in the morning, hour in
night which I did for some 20 years.
Hour in the morning, hour in the
afternoon.
But
But it
afternoon.
But it tends
But it tends to
afternoon.
But it tends to become
compartmentalized.
compartmentalized. Uh
compartmentalized. Uh contemplation
compartmentalized. Uh contemplation is
compartmentalized. Uh contemplation is a
way
way in
compartmentalized. Uh contemplation is a
way in which
way in which you
compartmentalized. Uh contemplation is a
way in which you uh
way in which you uh you
compartmentalized. Uh contemplation is a
way in which you uh you align
way in which you uh you align yourself
with
with context
with context instead
with context instead of
with context instead of content
with
with context
with context instead of content
with context and
with context and intention
that
that you're
that your
that your life
that you're
that your life is
that your life is of
that you're
that your life is of service
that your life is of service to
that you're
that your life is of service to the
that your life is of service to the Lord
and
and to
and to your
and to your fellow
and to your fellow human
and to your fellow human being
and to your fellow human being and
and to your fellow human being and out
of
of unconditional
and to your fellow human being and out
of unconditional love
of unconditional love you
and to your fellow human being and out
of unconditional love you ask
of unconditional love you ask God
and to your fellow human being and out
of unconditional love you ask God to
transform
transform how
transform how you
transform how you understand
transform how you understand the
transform how you understand the world.
So
it's
it's a
it's a way
it's a way of
it's a way of being
it's a way of being in
it's a way of being in the
it's a way of being in the world
it's a way of being in the world and
it's
it's contextualizing
uh
uh the
uh the meaning
uh the meaning significance
uh the meaning significance and
intention
intention of
uh the meaning significance and
intention of your
intention of your life.
uh the meaning significance and
intention of your life. That
recontextualization
recontextualization then
recontextualization then transforms
perception
perception transforms
recontextualization then transforms
perception transforms perception
and
how
how you
and
how you see
how you see things
and
how you see things differs
how you see things differs from
and
how you see things differs from the
how you see things differs from the way
the
the world
the world sees
the world sees it.
the world sees it. All
the world sees it. All right.
the world sees it. All right. So
the world sees it. All right. So the
the world sees it. All right. So the the
mind
mind looks
the world sees it. All right. So the the
mind looks out
mind looks out and
the world sees it. All right. So the the
mind looks out and it
mind looks out and it sees
the world sees it. All right. So the the
mind looks out and it sees form.
mind looks out and it sees form. That's
the
the linear.
the linear. It
the linear. It registers
the linear. It registers that
the linear. It registers that and
the linear. It registers that and it
recognizes
recognizes it.
the linear. It registers that and it
recognizes it. And
recognizes it. And how
the linear. It registers that and it
recognizes it. And how does
recognizes it. And how does it
the linear. It registers that and it
recognizes it. And how does it do
recognizes it. And how does it do this?
It
It does
It does it
It does it because
It does it because the
It does it because the mind
It does it because the mind is
It does it because the mind is always
watching.
watching. So
It does it because the mind is always
watching. So I'll
watching. So I'll show
It does it because the mind is always
watching. So I'll show you
watching. So I'll show you the
progressive
progressive fields
progressive fields of
progressive fields of realization.
progressive fields of realization. You
move
move from
progressive fields of realization. You
move from thinking
move from thinking I
progressive fields of realization. You
move from thinking I am
move from thinking I am this
progressive fields of realization. You
move from thinking I am this and
move from thinking I am this and move
back
back and
back and back
back and back to
back and back to realizing
back and back to realizing that
back and back to realizing that you
back and back to realizing that you are
this
this here.
back and back to realizing that you are
this here. All right.
this here. All right. So
back and back to realizing that you are
this here. All right. So at
this here. All right. So at first
back and back to realizing that you are
this here. All right. So at first you
think
think you're
think you're the
think you're the content
think you're the content that
think you're the content that you're
linear
linear and
think you're the content that you're
linear and restricted.
linear and restricted. This
think you're the content that you're
linear and restricted. This registers
and
and you
and you you
and you you it's
and you you it's recognition.
and you you it's recognition. But
and you you it's recognition. But how
and you you it's recognition. But how do
you
you know
and you you it's recognition. But how do
you know what's
you know what's going
and you you it's recognition. But how do
you know what's going out?
you know what's going out? Here's
and you you it's recognition. But how do
you know what's going out? Here's the
first
first jump
first jump you
first jump you can
first jump you can make.
first jump you can make. You
first jump you can make. You can
first jump you can make. You can realize
I
I am
first jump you can make. You can realize
I am not
I am not the
first jump you can make. You can realize
I am not the content
I am not the content of
first jump you can make. You can realize
I am not the content of what
I am not the content of what is
first jump you can make. You can realize
I am not the content of what is being
witnessed.
witnessed. I
witnessed. I am
witnessed. I am the
witnessed. I am the witnesser.
witnessed. I am the witnesser. I'm
witnessed. I am the witnesser. I'm the
watcher,
watcher, the
witnessed. I am the witnesser. I'm the
watcher, the experience,
watcher, the experience, the
experiencer.
experiencer. I
experiencer. I am
experiencer. I am the
experiencer. I am the observer
experiencer. I am the observer witness.
If
If you
experiencer. I am the observer witness.
If you have
If you have a
experiencer. I am the observer witness.
If you have a contemplative
If you have a contemplative lifestyle,
it's
it's very
it's very easy
it's very easy to
it's very easy to recognize.
it's very easy to recognize. It's
it's very easy to recognize. It's not
very
very difficult.
it's very easy to recognize. It's not
very difficult. You
very difficult. You don't
it's very easy to recognize. It's not
very difficult. You don't have
very difficult. You don't have to
meditate,
meditate, do
meditate, do a
meditate, do a lot
meditate, do a lot of
meditate, do a lot of weird
meditate, do a lot of weird breathing
and
and stuff.
meditate, do a lot of weird breathing
and stuff. Prana,
and stuff. Prana, by
meditate, do a lot of weird breathing
and stuff. Prana, by the
and stuff. Prana, by the way,
meditate, do a lot of weird breathing
and stuff. Prana, by the way, calibrates
at
at 190.
at 190. [snorts]
190.
It's
It's a
It's a hard
It's a hard way
It's a hard way to
It's a hard way to get
It's a hard way to get to
It's a hard way to get to heaven.
Takes
Takes a
It's a hard way to get to heaven.
Takes a lot
Takes a lot of
It's a hard way to get to heaven.
Takes a lot of Kleenex.
I
I don't
I don't believe
I don't believe in
I don't believe in artificial
I don't believe in artificial artificial
means
means of
I don't believe in artificial artificial
means of energy
means of energy manipulation.
I don't believe in artificial artificial
means of energy manipulation. There
means of energy manipulation. There are
many
many techniques
many techniques out
many techniques out there
many techniques out there that
many techniques out there that are
many techniques out there that are sold
for
for a
many techniques out there that are sold
for a price.
Secrets
Secrets of
Secrets of the
Secrets of the ancient
Secrets of the ancient mystics.
Mysteries.
Mysteries. Secret
Secrets of the ancient mystics.
Mysteries. Secret mysteries
Mysteries. Secret mysteries of
Secrets of the ancient mystics.
Mysteries. Secret mysteries of the
ancient
ancient occult
ancient occult mysteries.
For
For only
ancient occult mysteries.
For only $5,000,
For only $5,000, I'll
ancient occult mysteries.
For only $5,000, I'll tell
For only $5,000, I'll tell you
ancient occult mysteries.
For only $5,000, I'll tell you what
For only $5,000, I'll tell you what they
are.
[laughter]
All
All right.
All right. By
All right. By intention,
All right. By intention, you
All right. By intention, you can
All right. By intention, you can begin.
It
It doesn't.
All right. By intention, you can begin.
It doesn't. It's
It doesn't. It's very
All right. By intention, you can begin.
It doesn't. It's very simple
It doesn't. It's very simple to
All right. By intention, you can begin.
It doesn't. It's very simple to see
It doesn't. It's very simple to see that
the
the reason
the reason you
the reason you know
the reason you know what's
the reason you know what's going
the reason you know what's going on
the reason you know what's going on is
because
because there's
the reason you know what's going on is
because there's a
because there's a watchingness
the reason you know what's going on is
because there's a watchingness and
because there's a watchingness and an
experiencingness.
experiencingness. And
experiencingness. And this
experiencingness. And this phenomena
experiencingness. And this phenomena is
happening.
happening. spontaneously.
There's
There's no
There's no you
There's no you that's
There's no you that's watching
There's no you that's watching or
experiencing.
experiencing. That's
There's no you that's watching or
experiencing. That's the
experiencing. That's the conclusion.
Watching
Watching and
Watching and experiencing
Watching and experiencing and
Watching and experiencing and awareness.
The
The observing
Watching and experiencing and awareness.
The observing and
The observing and the
Watching and experiencing and awareness.
The observing and the witness
The observing and the witness is
happening
happening autonomously.
So
So when
happening autonomously.
So when you
So when you move
happening autonomously.
So when you move from
So when you move from identifying
happening autonomously.
So when you move from identifying with
out
out there,
out there, you
out there, you realize
out there, you realize that
consciousness
consciousness is
out there, you realize that
consciousness is observing
consciousness is observing and
witnessing
witnessing all
witnessing all the
witnessing all the time.
witnessing all the time. And
witnessing all the time. And this
phenomena
phenomena is
witnessing all the time. And this
phenomena is autonomous.
phenomena is autonomous. There's
witnessing all the time. And this
phenomena is autonomous. There's no
phenomena is autonomous. There's no you
deciding
deciding to
deciding to be
deciding to be aware.
deciding to be aware. Awareness
deciding to be aware. Awareness is
happening
happening of
deciding to be aware. Awareness is
happening of its
happening of its own.
deciding to be aware. Awareness is
happening of its own. It's
happening of its own. It's a
deciding to be aware. Awareness is
happening of its own. It's a phenomena
that's
that's intrinsic
that's intrinsic to
that's intrinsic to your
that's intrinsic to your existence.
that's intrinsic to your existence. The
light
light of
that's intrinsic to your existence. The
light of consciousness
light of consciousness is
that's intrinsic to your existence. The
light of consciousness is intrinsic
light of consciousness is intrinsic to
your
your existence.
your existence. It's
your existence. It's not
your existence. It's not valitional.
So
So you
your existence. It's not valitional.
So you withdraw
So you withdraw from
your existence. It's not valitional.
So you withdraw from out
So you withdraw from out there
your existence. It's not valitional.
So you withdraw from out there and
So you withdraw from out there and you
begin
begin to
begin to see
begin to see everything
begin to see everything is
begin to see everything is occurring
spontaneously
spontaneously of
begin to see everything is occurring
spontaneously of its
spontaneously of its own
begin to see everything is occurring
spontaneously of its own because
spontaneously of its own because of
begin to see everything is occurring
spontaneously of its own because of its
own
own potential
own potential actualizing.
that
that potentuality
own potential actualizing.
that potentuality actualizes
spontaneously.
There's
There's no
spontaneously.
There's no you
There's no you that
spontaneously.
There's no you that thinks
There's no you that thinks about
spontaneously.
There's no you that thinks about it
There's no you that thinks about it and
decides
decides to
decides to do
decides to do it
decides to do it and
decides to do it and then
decides to do it and then takes
decides to do it and then takes credit
or
or blame
decides to do it and then takes credit
or blame for
or blame for having
decides to do it and then takes credit
or blame for having had
or blame for having had it
decides to do it and then takes credit
or blame for having had it having
happened
happened because
happened because of
happened because of the
happened because of the context.
Everybody
Everybody hearing
happened because of the context.
Everybody hearing this
Everybody hearing this plus
happened because of the context.
Everybody hearing this plus the
Everybody hearing this plus the the
wheness
wheness of
wheness of whatever
wheness of whatever is
wheness of whatever is talking
wheness of whatever is talking here,
wheness of whatever is talking here, the
two
two together
wheness of whatever is talking here, the
two together make
two together make the
wheness of whatever is talking here, the
two together make the arm
two together make the arm go
wheness of whatever is talking here, the
two together make the arm go up
two together make the arm go up to
illustrate
illustrate a
illustrate a point.
illustrate a point. You
illustrate a point. You know what
illustrate a point. You know what I
mean?
mean? Didn't
illustrate a point. You know what I
mean? Didn't it
went
went up
went up by
went up by itself,
went up by itself, didn't
went up by itself, didn't it?
Everybody
Everybody thinks
went up by itself, didn't it?
Everybody thinks it
Everybody thinks it went
went up by itself, didn't it?
Everybody thinks it went up
Everybody thinks it went up by
went up by itself, didn't it?
Everybody thinks it went up by itself.
Raise
Raise your
Raise your arm.
Rest
Rest of
Raise your arm.
Rest of you,
Rest of you, the
Raise your arm.
Rest of you, the back
Rest of you, the back door
Raise your arm.
Rest of you, the back door is
Rest of you, the back door is there.
You
You begin
You begin to
You begin to realize
You begin to realize that
You begin to realize that being
You begin to realize that being aware
itself
is
is spontaneous,
is spontaneous, autonomous
is spontaneous, autonomous and
nonvolitional.
Behind
Behind the
Behind the light
Behind the light of
Behind the light of consciousness,
Behind the light of consciousness, you
then
then begin
Behind the light of consciousness, you
then begin to
then begin to realize
Behind the light of consciousness, you
then begin to realize the
then begin to realize the self
Behind the light of consciousness, you
then begin to realize the self and
then begin to realize the self and out
of
of that
of that the
of that the awareness
of that the awareness that
of that the awareness that even
of that the awareness that even the
of that the awareness that even the self
is
is spontaneously
of that the awareness that even the self
is spontaneously being
is spontaneously being what
of that the awareness that even the self
is spontaneously being what it
is spontaneously being what it is.
There's
There's no
There's no you
There's no you involved
There's no you involved in
There's no you involved in all
There's no you involved in all of
There's no you involved in all of it.
There's no you involved in all of it. So
there's
there's no
There's no you involved in all of it. So
there's no personal
there's no personal you
There's no you involved in all of it. So
there's no personal you involved
there's no personal you involved in
anything
anything about
anything about your
anything about your life
anything about your life at
anything about your life at all.
anything about your life at all. It's
all
all delusional.
Ain't
Ain't that
Ain't that nice?
All
All in
Ain't that nice?
All in favor.
[applause]
Okay,
Okay, we'll
[applause]
Okay, we'll move.
Okay,
Okay, we
Okay, we want
Okay, we want everybody
Okay, we want everybody to
Okay, we want everybody to become
enlightened.
enlightened. So
this
this is
this is this
this is this is
this is this is the
this is this is the difficulty
this is this is the difficulty with
this is this is the difficulty with the
relativism
relativism and
this is this is the difficulty with the
relativism and all
relativism and all the
this is this is the difficulty with the
relativism and all the idealistic
relativism and all the idealistic uh
we'll
we'll dance
we'll dance around
we'll dance around the
we'll dance around the map
we'll dance around the map Paul
we'll dance around the map Paul will
we'll dance around the map Paul will all
be
be happy
we'll dance around the map Paul will all
be happy is
be happy is that
we'll dance around the map Paul will all
be happy is that below
be happy is that below consciousness
level
level 200
level 200 this
level 200 this is
level 200 this is how
level 200 this is how the
level 200 this is how the brain
processes
uh
uh input
uh the
uh the below
uh input
uh the below 200
uh the below 200 it
uh input
uh the below 200 it goes
uh the below 200 it goes uh
uh input
uh the below 200 it goes uh uh
uh the below 200 it goes uh uh phalamus
fast
fast to
fast to the
fast to the amygdala
fast to the amygdala which
fast to the amygdala which is
fast to the amygdala which is the
emotional
emotional center
fast to the amygdala which is the
emotional center and
emotional center and it
fast to the amygdala which is the
emotional center and it reacts
emotional center and it reacts and
fast to the amygdala which is the
emotional center and it reacts and This
the
the memory
the memory of
the memory of this
the memory of this phenomena
the memory of this phenomena is
the memory of this phenomena is stored
in
in the
the memory of this phenomena is stored
in the hippocampus.
All
All right.
All right. You
All right. You see
All right. You see the
All right. You see the the
All right. You see the the fast
All right. You see the the fast track
the
the fast
All right. You see the the fast track
the fast track
the fast track is
All right. You see the the fast track
the fast track is through
the fast track is through the
All right. You see the the fast track
the fast track is through the emotional
centers
that
that will
centers
that will have
that will have a
centers
that will have a parade
that will have a parade and
centers
that will have a parade and throw
that will have a parade and throw bombs
at
at the
at the police.
at the police. See,
at the police. See, and
at the police. See, and the
at the police. See, and the track
at the police. See, and the track in
at the police. See, and the track in the
in
in these
at the police. See, and the track in the
in these people
in these people through
at the police. See, and the track in the
in these people through the
in these people through the cortex,
at the police. See, and the track in the
in these people through the cortex, the
prefrontal
prefrontal cortex
prefrontal cortex is
prefrontal cortex is slow.
So,
So, as
prefrontal cortex is slow.
So, as you're
So, as you're standing
prefrontal cortex is slow.
So, as you're standing out
So, as you're standing out there
prefrontal cortex is slow.
So, as you're standing out there and
So, as you're standing out there and the
police
police are
police are hitting
police are hitting you
police are hitting you with
police are hitting you with the
police are hitting you with the fire
hoses,
hoses, etc.,
You
You say
You say you
You say you maybe
You say you maybe it
You say you maybe it wasn't
You say you maybe it wasn't such
You say you maybe it wasn't such a
You say you maybe it wasn't such a smart
idea.
The
The cortex
The cortex is
The cortex is very
The cortex is very slow.
The
The difficulty
The cortex is very slow.
The difficulty with
The difficulty with consciousness
The cortex is very slow.
The difficulty with consciousness level
200 and
200 and the
200 and the reason
200 and the reason they're
200 and the reason they're dangerous
is
is because
200 and the reason they're dangerous
is because it's
is because it's the
200 and the reason they're dangerous
is because it's the animal.
is because it's the animal. Now
200 and the reason they're dangerous
is because it's the animal. Now what
happens
happens when
happens when you
happens when you give
happens when you give an
happens when you give an animal
happens when you give an animal a
prefrontal
prefrontal cortex?
He
He becomes
He becomes a
He becomes a very
He becomes a very dangerous,
He becomes a very dangerous, seriously
dangerous
dangerous animal
He becomes a very dangerous, seriously
dangerous animal because
dangerous animal because now
He becomes a very dangerous, seriously
dangerous animal because now he's
dangerous animal because now he's only
an
an animal,
an animal, but
an animal, but he's
an animal, but he's an
an animal, but he's an animal
an animal, but he's an animal with
reason.
reason. And
an animal, but he's an animal with
reason. And he
reason. And he can
an animal, but he's an animal with
reason. And he can think
reason. And he can think of
an animal, but he's an animal with
reason. And he can think of atomic
reason. And he can think of atomic bombs
to
to kill
to kill you
to kill you with.
to kill you with. He
to kill you with. He can
to kill you with. He can think
to kill you with. He can think of
to kill you with. He can think of better
ammunition.
ammunition. He's
to kill you with. He can think of better
ammunition. He's a
ammunition. He's a brainy
to kill you with. He can think of better
ammunition. He's a brainy animal
ammunition. He's a brainy animal now.
to kill you with. He can think of better
ammunition. He's a brainy animal now. So
let's
let's take
let's take a
let's take a vicious
let's take a vicious animal,
let's take a vicious animal, a
let's take a vicious animal, a komodo
dragon
dragon who
let's take a vicious animal, a komodo
dragon who calibrates
dragon who calibrates at
let's take a vicious animal, a komodo
dragon who calibrates at 90
dragon who calibrates at 90 or
something.
something. And
something. And now
something. And now let's
something. And now let's give
something. And now let's give him
something. And now let's give him a
cerebral
cerebral cortex.
I
I figure
I figure out
I figure out how
I figure out how to
I figure out how to get
I figure out how to get rid
I figure out how to get rid of
I figure out how to get rid of everybody
in
in this
I figure out how to get rid of everybody
in this room
in this room in
I figure out how to get rid of everybody
in this room in a
in this room in a hurry.
I figure out how to get rid of everybody
in this room in a hurry. Wouldn't
in this room in a hurry. Wouldn't you?
You
You got
You got to
You got to view
You got to view success
You got to view success as
You got to view success as a
You got to view success as a Komodo
dragon
dragon to
You got to view success as a Komodo
dragon to transcend
dragon to transcend being
You got to view success as a Komodo
dragon to transcend being a
dragon to transcend being a Komodo
dragon.
dragon. [laughter]
So,
So, we
dragon. [laughter]
So, we have
So, we have leading
dragon. [laughter]
So, we have leading the
So, we have leading the world,
dragon. [laughter]
So, we have leading the world, leaders
of
of countries
of countries that
of countries that calibrate
of countries that calibrate exactly
of countries that calibrate exactly the
same
same as
of countries that calibrate exactly the
same as a
same as a Komodo
of countries that calibrate exactly the
same as a Komodo dragon.
same as a Komodo dragon. Exactly
of countries that calibrate exactly the
same as a Komodo dragon. Exactly the
same.
same. 90.
Uhhuh.
Uhhuh. And
same. 90.
Uhhuh. And now
Uhhuh. And now because
same. 90.
Uhhuh. And now because of
Uhhuh. And now because of their
prefrontal
prefrontal cortex
they
they can
prefrontal cortex
they can utilize
they can utilize scientific
prefrontal cortex
they can utilize scientific discoveries
etc
etc for
etc for the
etc for the intention
etc for the intention which
etc for the intention which is
um
um the
etc for the intention which is
um the wolf
um the wolf pack.
etc for the intention which is
um the wolf pack. You
um the wolf pack. You see
etc for the intention which is
um the wolf pack. You see the
um the wolf pack. You see the world
etc for the intention which is
um the wolf pack. You see the world the
countries
countries of
countries of the
countries of the world
countries of the world throughout
countries of the world throughout time
everything
everything is
countries of the world throughout time
everything is dominance
everything is dominance and
countries of the world throughout time
everything is dominance and territory.
No
No no
No no different
No no different than
No no different than a
No no different than a wolf
No no different than a wolf pack.
No no different than a wolf pack. What's
the
the difference
No no different than a wolf pack. What's
the difference between
the difference between man
No no different than a wolf pack. What's
the difference between man and
the difference between man and a
No no different than a wolf pack. What's
the difference between man and a wolf?
Wolves
Wolves probably
Wolves probably kinder
Wolves probably kinder to
Wolves probably kinder to their
Wolves probably kinder to their kids.
[laughter]
triumphalism.
triumphalism. What
triumphalism. What What
triumphalism. What What do
triumphalism. What What do they
triumphalism. What What do they want
triumphalism. What What do they want to
conquer
conquer the
triumphalism. What What do they want to
conquer the world
conquer the world for?
triumphalism. What What do they want to
conquer the world for? What
conquer the world for? What did
triumphalism. What What do they want to
conquer the world for? What did Adolf
Hitler
Hitler need
Hitler need more?
Why
Why does
Hitler need more?
Why does he
Why does he have
Hitler need more?
Why does he have to
Why does he have to invade
Hitler need more?
Why does he have to invade Europe?
Why does he have to invade Europe? Why
does
does Russia
does Russia have
does Russia have to
does Russia have to overtake?
does Russia have to overtake? Every
does Russia have to overtake? Every one
of
of them
does Russia have to overtake? Every one
of them is
of them is is
does Russia have to overtake? Every one
of them is is into
of them is is into primitive
territorialism,
territorialism, primitive
territorialism, primitive narcissistic
megalamania.
megalamania. Yeah.
territorialism, primitive narcissistic
megalamania. Yeah. All right.
megalamania. Yeah. All right. Once
territorialism, primitive narcissistic
megalamania. Yeah. All right. Once you
reach
reach consciousness
reach consciousness level
reach consciousness level 200,
reach consciousness level 200, now
reach consciousness level 200, now the
brain
brain physiology
reach consciousness level 200, now the
brain physiology changes.
brain physiology changes. the
reach consciousness level 200, now the
brain physiology changes. the sensory
input
input uh
input uh goes
input uh goes fast
input uh goes fast track
and
and then
input uh goes fast track
and then back
and then back to
input uh goes fast track
and then back to the
and then back to the hippocampus.
input uh goes fast track
and then back to the hippocampus. So
and then back to the hippocampus. So it
has
has a
has a positive
has a positive pleasant
has a positive pleasant memory.
has a positive pleasant memory. This
has a positive pleasant memory. This one
has
has a
has a positive pleasant memory. This one
has a negative
has a negative memory.
has a positive pleasant memory. This one
has a negative memory. So
has a negative memory. So with
has a positive pleasant memory. This one
has a negative memory. So with negative
memories
memories you
memories you can
memories you can build
memories you can build up
memories you can build up a
memories you can build up a backlog
memories you can build up a backlog of
hate
hate because
memories you can build up a backlog of
hate because it
hate because it was
memories you can build up a backlog of
hate because it was experienced
hate because it was experienced this
way.
way. Now
way. Now the
way. Now the other
way. Now the other thing
way. Now the other thing that
way. Now the other thing that happens
way. Now the other thing that happens at
consciousness
consciousness level
way. Now the other thing that happens at
consciousness level 200
consciousness level 200 a
way. Now the other thing that happens at
consciousness level 200 a very
consciousness level 200 a very profound
influence
influence which
influence which neurohysiology
influence which neurohysiology doesn't
understand
understand and
influence which neurohysiology doesn't
understand and that's
understand and that's why
influence which neurohysiology doesn't
understand and that's why they
understand and that's why they only
influence which neurohysiology doesn't
understand and that's why they only get
so
so far
so far with
so far with the
so far with the science
so far with the science is
so far with the science is uh
so far with the science is uh the
beginning
beginning of
so far with the science is uh the
beginning of the
beginning of the condundalini
so far with the science is uh the
beginning of the condundalini energy
beginning of the condundalini energy at
consciousness
consciousness level
consciousness level 200
consciousness level 200 there's
consciousness level 200 there's the
inflow
inflow of
consciousness level 200 there's the
inflow of condundalini
inflow of condundalini energy
consciousness level 200 there's the
inflow of condundalini energy and
inflow of condundalini energy and it's
this
this energy
this energy which
this energy which transforms
uh
uh the
this energy which transforms
uh the function
uh the function of
this energy which transforms
uh the function of the
uh the function of the brain
this energy which transforms
uh the function of the brain the
condundolini
condundolini energy
condundolini energy begins
condundolini energy begins to
condundolini energy begins to flow
condundolini energy begins to flow up
through
through through
condundolini energy begins to flow up
through through the
through through the chakra
condundolini energy begins to flow up
through through the chakra system.
So
So below
So below 200
So below 200 you
So below 200 you have
So below 200 you have left
So below 200 you have left brain
dominance.
dominance. Everything
So below 200 you have left brain
dominance. Everything is
dominance. Everything is linear
So below 200 you have left brain
dominance. Everything is linear and
because
because of
because of this
because of this everything
because of this everything is
because of this everything is stressful
releases
releases adrenaline
because of this everything is stressful
releases adrenaline and
releases adrenaline and it's
because of this everything is stressful
releases adrenaline and it's fight
releases adrenaline and it's fight or
flight.
flight. You
flight. You get
flight. You get selier
flight. You get selier cannons
flight. You get selier cannons alarm
resistance
resistance exhaustion.
flight. You get selier cannons alarm
resistance exhaustion. You
resistance exhaustion. You get
flight. You get selier cannons alarm
resistance exhaustion. You get stress
resistance exhaustion. You get stress to
the
the thymus
the thymus gland.
the thymus gland. You
the thymus gland. You know
the thymus gland. You know let's
the thymus gland. You know let's all
the thymus gland. You know let's all do
the
the thy
the thymus gland. You know let's all do
the thy you
the thy you know.
the thymus gland. You know let's all do
the thy you know. Ha
the thy you know. Ha ha
the thymus gland. You know let's all do
the thy you know. Ha ha ha
haaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
haaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa ha
haaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa.
Well,
Well, that
Well, that was
Well, that was sort
Well, that was sort of
Well, that was sort of fun,
Well, that was sort of fun, wasn't
Well, that was sort of fun, wasn't it,
doctor?
doctor? Yes,
Well, that was sort of fun, wasn't it,
doctor? Yes, it
doctor? Yes, it was
Well, that was sort of fun, wasn't it,
doctor? Yes, it was fun.
It
It changes
It changes you
It changes you from
It changes you from a
It changes you from a dangerous,
It changes you from a dangerous, serious
person
person into
It changes you from a dangerous, serious
person into somebody
person into somebody who
It changes you from a dangerous, serious
person into somebody who lives
person into somebody who lives in
It changes you from a dangerous, serious
person into somebody who lives in a
field
field of
field of humor
field of humor all
field of humor all the
field of humor all the time.
All right.
All right. So,
field of humor all the time.
All right. So, below
All right. So, below 200,
field of humor all the time.
All right. So, below 200, you
All right. So, below 200, you have
field of humor all the time.
All right. So, below 200, you have the
alarm
alarm reaction.
alarm reaction. The
alarm reaction. The thymic
alarm reaction. The thymic stress
disrupts
disrupts acupuncture
alarm reaction. The thymic stress
disrupts acupuncture meridians
disrupts acupuncture meridians creates
disease
disease and
disease and negative
disease and negative kinesiologic
response
and
and track
and track to
and track to the
and track to the emotions
and track to the emotions is
and track to the emotions is twice
and track to the emotions is twice as
fast
fast as
and track to the emotions is twice as
fast as it
fast as it is
and track to the emotions is twice as
fast as it is to
fast as it is to reason.
and track to the emotions is twice as
fast as it is to reason. Now
fast as it is to reason. Now above
and track to the emotions is twice as
fast as it is to reason. Now above 200
you
you have
you have right
you have right right
you have right right brain
you have right right brain dominance.
You
You you
you have right right brain dominance.
You you you
You you you relate
you have right right brain dominance.
You you you relate to
You you you relate to the
you have right right brain dominance.
You you you relate to the overall
context
context of
context of the
context of the field
context of the field non
context of the field non nonlinear.
You're
You're interested
context of the field non nonlinear.
You're interested in
You're interested in peace
context of the field non nonlinear.
You're interested in peace which
releases
releases endorphins,
releases endorphins, positive
releases endorphins, positive emotions
that
that supports
releases endorphins, positive emotions
that supports the
that supports the thymus
releases endorphins, positive emotions
that supports the thymus that
that supports the thymus that increases
the
the killer
the killer cells
the killer cells which
the killer cells which despite
the killer cells which despite their
name
name killer
the killer cells which despite their
name killer means
name killer means killer
the killer cells which despite their
name killer means killer of
name killer means killer of germs.
Increases
Increases immunity
Increases immunity and
Increases immunity and healing
Increases immunity and healing balances
the
the acupuncture
Increases immunity and healing balances
the acupuncture system.
the acupuncture system. Gives
Increases immunity and healing balances
the acupuncture system. Gives you
[clears throat]
[clears throat] a
[clears throat] a positive
[clears throat] a positive kinesiologic
response.
This
This is
This is a
This is a difficulty
This is a difficulty that
This is a difficulty that I
This is a difficulty that I don't
This is a difficulty that I don't see
how
how how
This is a difficulty that I don't see
how how international
how how international politics
This is a difficulty that I don't see
how how international politics can
how how international politics can solve
frankly.
frankly. Uh
frankly. Uh the
frankly. Uh the fact
frankly. Uh the fact that
frankly. Uh the fact that you've
frankly. Uh the fact that you've got
frankly. Uh the fact that you've got a
different
different brain
frankly. Uh the fact that you've got a
different brain function
different brain function here.
Therefore,
Therefore, meaning
Therefore, meaning and
Therefore, meaning and significance
Therefore, meaning and significance to
these
these people
Therefore, meaning and significance to
these people is
these people is completely
Therefore, meaning and significance to
these people is completely different
than
than meaning
than meaning and
than meaning and significance
than meaning and significance here.
Uh
Uh these
than meaning and significance here.
Uh these people
Uh these people are
than meaning and significance here.
Uh these people are interested
Uh these people are interested in
than meaning and significance here.
Uh these people are interested in how
can
can we
can we win.
can we win. This
can we win. This people
can we win. This people people
can we win. This people people are
interested
interested in
can we win. This people people are
interested in how
interested in how can
can we win. This people people are
interested in how can we
interested in how can we settle
can we win. This people people are
interested in how can we settle it
peacefully.
These
These people
peacefully.
These people say
These people say the
peacefully.
These people say the way
These people say the way to
peacefully.
These people say the way to settle
These people say the way to settle it
peacefully
peacefully is
peacefully is to
peacefully is to kill
peacefully is to kill you
peacefully is to kill you folks
peacefully is to kill you folks and
peacefully is to kill you folks and then
we'll
we'll have
peacefully is to kill you folks and then
we'll have peace
now.
now. I
now. I don't
now. I don't see
now. I don't see what
now. I don't see what the
now. I don't see what the resolution
now. I don't see what the resolution is.
Okay,
Okay, we'll
now. I don't see what the resolution is.
Okay, we'll move
Okay, we'll move on.
now. I don't see what the resolution is.
Okay, we'll move on. Next
level
level of
level of consciousness
level of consciousness and
level of consciousness and happiness
level of consciousness and happiness and
various
various phenomena.
level of consciousness and happiness and
various phenomena. Uh
various phenomena. Uh this
level of consciousness and happiness and
various phenomena. Uh this again
various phenomena. Uh this again has
level of consciousness and happiness and
various phenomena. Uh this again has to
do
do you
do you know
do you know you'll
do you know you'll see
do you know you'll see the
do you know you'll see the fallacy
do you know you'll see the fallacy of
many
many sociologic
do you know you'll see the fallacy of
many sociologic theories
many sociologic theories you
do you know you'll see the fallacy of
many sociologic theories you know
many sociologic theories you know uh
calibrated
calibrated level
calibrated level of
calibrated level of consciousness
calibrated level of consciousness the
rate
rate of
calibrated level of consciousness the
rate of employment
rate of employment here
calibrated level of consciousness the
rate of employment here is
rate of employment here is 0%.
0%.
0%. Nobody
0%. Nobody 500
lacking
lacking a
0%. Nobody 500
lacking a job.
lacking a job. Rate
0%. Nobody 500
lacking a job. Rate of
lacking a job. Rate of poverty
0%. Nobody 500
lacking a job. Rate of poverty is
lacking a job. Rate of poverty is 0%.
People
People say
People say life
People say life is
People say life is okay
People say life is okay is
People say life is okay is almost
People say life is okay is almost 100%.
The
The rate
People say life is okay is almost 100%.
The rate of
The rate of criminality
People say life is okay is almost 100%.
The rate of criminality is
The rate of criminality is 0%
People say life is okay is almost 100%.
The rate of criminality is 0% apparently
from
from 400
from 400 to
from 400 to 500.
from 400 to 500. Then
from 400 to 500. Then the
from 400 to 500. Then the rate
from 400 to 500. Then the rate of
unemployment
unemployment is
from 400 to 500. Then the rate of
unemployment is 2%.
unemployment is 2%. They're
from 400 to 500. Then the rate of
unemployment is 2%. They're probably
collecting
collecting unemployment.
Rate
Rate of
collecting unemployment.
Rate of poverty
Rate of poverty is
collecting unemployment.
Rate of poverty is practically
Rate of poverty is practically zero.
Happiness,
Happiness, life
Happiness, life is
Happiness, life is okay,
Happiness, life is okay, only
Happiness, life is okay, only 70%.
Happiness, life is okay, only 70%. I
don't
don't know
Happiness, life is okay, only 70%. I
don't know what's
don't know what's the
Happiness, life is okay, only 70%. I
don't know what's the matter
don't know what's the matter with
Happiness, life is okay, only 70%. I
don't know what's the matter with them.
But
But anyway,
But anyway, the
But anyway, the rate
But anyway, the rate of
But anyway, the rate of criminality
But anyway, the rate of criminality is
uh
uh probably
But anyway, the rate of criminality is
uh probably corporate
uh probably corporate embezzlement
But anyway, the rate of criminality is
uh probably corporate embezzlement or
something.
something. 2%.
level
level 3
something. 2%.
level 3 to
level 3 to 400,
something. 2%.
level 3 to 400, unemployment
level 3 to 400, unemployment 7%.
something. 2%.
level 3 to 400, unemployment 7%. Poverty
1%.
Life
Life is
1%.
Life is okay
Life is okay 50%.
Criminality
Criminality 5%.
Criminality 5%. So
Criminality 5%. So you
Criminality 5%. So you begin
Criminality 5%. So you begin to
Criminality 5%. So you begin to see
Criminality 5%. So you begin to see that
these
these phenomena
Criminality 5%. So you begin to see that
these phenomena that
these phenomena that the
Criminality 5%. So you begin to see that
these phenomena that the world
these phenomena that the world strives
for
for are
for are not
for are not the
for are not the result
for are not the result of
for are not the result of a
for are not the result of a Newtonian
cause
cause effect
for are not the result of a Newtonian
cause effect in
cause effect in sociologic
for are not the result of a Newtonian
cause effect in sociologic phenomena,
but
but they
but they are
but they are indigenous
but they are indigenous to
but they are indigenous to the
but they are indigenous to the level
but they are indigenous to the level of
consciousness.
uh
uh the
uh the rate
uh the rate of
uh the rate of unemployment
uh the rate of unemployment here
uh the rate of unemployment here finally
as
as you
uh the rate of unemployment here finally
as you go
as you go down
uh the rate of unemployment here finally
as you go down below
as you go down below level
uh the rate of unemployment here finally
as you go down below level 200
as you go down below level 200 you
uh the rate of unemployment here finally
as you go down below level 200 you see
as you go down below level 200 you see a
huge
huge jump
uh
uh below
huge jump
uh below 200
uh below 200 the
huge jump
uh below 200 the rate
uh below 200 the rate of
huge jump
uh below 200 the rate of unemployment
uh below 200 the rate of unemployment uh
goes
goes from
goes from 50%
goes from 50% to
goes from 50% to 75%.
The
The rate
goes from 50% to 75%.
The rate of
The rate of poverty
goes from 50% to 75%.
The rate of poverty increases
The rate of poverty increases to
goes from 50% to 75%.
The rate of poverty increases to 40%.
Life
Life is
Life is okay
Life is okay is
Life is okay is only
Life is okay is only 2%.
Life is okay is only 2%. Criminality
Life is okay is only 2%. Criminality do
you
you realize
Life is okay is only 2%. Criminality do
you realize that
you realize that below
Life is okay is only 2%. Criminality do
you realize that below this
consciousness
consciousness level
consciousness level uh
consciousness level uh criminality
consciousness level uh criminality is
almost
almost 100%.
conscious
conscious level
conscious level 90
conscious level 90 or
conscious level 90 or below
conscious level 90 or below greater
criminality
criminality is
conscious level 90 or below greater
criminality is almost
criminality is almost 100%.
conscious level 90 or below greater
criminality is almost 100%. They
criminality is almost 100%. They all
live
live via
live via crime.
live via crime. They
live via crime. They don't
live via crime. They don't see
live via crime. They don't see this
crime.
crime. They
live via crime. They don't see this
crime. They just
crime. They just see
live via crime. They don't see this
crime. They just see it
crime. They just see it as
live via crime. They don't see this
crime. They just see it as a
crime. They just see it as a lifestyle.
This
This is
This is why
This is why u
This is why u you
This is why u you know
This is why u you know 90
This is why u you know 90 days
This is why u you know 90 days in
This is why u you know 90 days in jail
doesn't
doesn't cure
This is why u you know 90 days in jail
doesn't cure them
doesn't cure them because
This is why u you know 90 days in jail
doesn't cure them because they
doesn't cure them because they this
This is why u you know 90 days in jail
doesn't cure them because they this was
their
their level
their level when
their level when they
their level when they went
their level when they went in.
their level when they went in. This
their level when they went in. This is
their
their level
their level when they went in. This is
their level when
their level when they
their level when they went in. This is
their level when they come
their level when they come out.
their level when they went in. This is
their level when they come out. So
recidivism
recidivism is
recidivism is intrinsic
recidivism is intrinsic to
recidivism is intrinsic to criminality.
Yeah.
Yeah. See?
recidivism is intrinsic to criminality.
Yeah. See? So
all
all right.
all right. So
all right. So level
all right. So level of
all right. So level of consciousness.
All
All right.
all right. So level of consciousness.
All right. So
All right. So this
all right. So level of consciousness.
All right. So this is
All right. So this is the
all right. So level of consciousness.
All right. So this is the distribution
throughout
throughout the
throughout the world.
throughout the world. Um
throughout the world. Um you
throughout the world. Um you can
throughout the world. Um you can go
throughout the world. Um you can go over
the
the world
throughout the world. Um you can go over
the world map
the world map and
throughout the world. Um you can go over
the world map and of
the world map and of course
throughout the world. Um you can go over
the world map and of course this
the world map and of course this is
throughout the world. Um you can go over
the world map and of course this is a
whole
whole study
whole study in
whole study in itself.
whole study in itself. You
whole study in itself. You can
whole study in itself. You can get
whole study in itself. You can get the
level
level of
whole study in itself. You can get the
level of an
level of an area.
whole study in itself. You can get the
level of an area. You
level of an area. You can
whole study in itself. You can get the
level of an area. You can get
level of an area. You can get you
whole study in itself. You can get the
level of an area. You can get you can
get
get the
get the area
get the area of
get the area of the
get the area of the government,
get the area of the government, the
leader
leader or
get the area of the government, the
leader or the
leader or the populace.
You
You need
You need three
You need three different
You need three different things
You need three different things to
You need three different things to know
about.
about. Some
You need three different things to know
about. Some have
about. Some have wonderful
You need three different things to know
about. Some have wonderful people
about. Some have wonderful people but
rotten
rotten governments
rotten governments and
rotten governments and corrupt
officials.
uh
uh and
uh and other
uh and other people
uh and other people have
uh and other people have wonderful
officials
officials and
uh and other people have wonderful
officials and the
officials and the people
uh and other people have wonderful
officials and the people of
officials and the people of Silia
uh and other people have wonderful
officials and the people of Silia blind
[laughter]
anyway
to
to understand
to understand uh
to understand uh we
to understand uh we can
to understand uh we can apply
to understand uh we can apply this
international
international understanding
to understand uh we can apply this
international understanding and
international understanding and you'll
see
see the
see the value
see the value of
see the value of it
see the value of it when
see the value of it when we
see the value of it when we in
see the value of it when we in another
slide
slide or
see the value of it when we in another
slide or two
slide or two whole
see the value of it when we in another
slide or two whole areas
slide or two whole areas of
see the value of it when we in another
slide or two whole areas of the
slide or two whole areas of the world
calibrate
calibrate at
calibrate at certain
calibrate at certain particular
calibrate at certain particular levels
characteristically
here
here you
here you see
here you see one
here you see one at
here you see one at 410
here you see one at 410 what
here you see one at 410 what is
here you see one at 410 what is that
Australia
>> yeah
>> yeah looks
>> yeah looks like
>> yeah looks like a
>> yeah looks like a good
>> yeah looks like a good place
>> yeah looks like a good place to
>> yeah looks like a good place to go
Australia
Australia New
>> yeah looks like a good place to go
Australia New Zealand
Australia New Zealand you
>> yeah looks like a good place to go
Australia New Zealand you see
Australia New Zealand you see how
>> yeah looks like a good place to go
Australia New Zealand you see how higher
calibrates.
Uhhuh.
In
In order
In order to
In order to get
In order to get into
In order to get into these
In order to get into these countries,
uh,
uh, you
In order to get into these countries,
uh, you have
uh, you have to
In order to get into these countries,
uh, you have to identify
uh, you have to identify who
In order to get into these countries,
uh, you have to identify who you
uh, you have to identify who you are.
[laughter]
We
We crossed
[laughter]
We crossed recently.
We crossed recently. We
[laughter]
We crossed recently. We went
We crossed recently. We went to
[laughter]
We crossed recently. We went to Alaska
and
and when
and when you
and when you cross
and when you cross into
and when you cross into Canada,
and when you cross into Canada, you
and when you cross into Canada, you have
to
to identify
and when you cross into Canada, you have
to identify who
to identify who you
and when you cross into Canada, you have
to identify who you are
to identify who you are with
and when you cross into Canada, you have
to identify who you are with ID
to identify who you are with ID just
and when you cross into Canada, you have
to identify who you are with ID just to
get
get into
get into Canada.
Uh
Uh interesting.
get into Canada.
Uh interesting. All right.
Uh interesting. All right. So,
get into Canada.
Uh interesting. All right. So, we'll
move
move on.
Uh
Uh this
move on.
Uh this is
Uh this is the
move on.
Uh this is the other
Uh this is the other side
move on.
Uh this is the other side of
Uh this is the other side of the
move on.
Uh this is the other side of the world.
So,
So, if
So, if we
So, if we I
So, if we I don't
So, if we I don't have
So, if we I don't have any
So, if we I don't have any names
So, if we I don't have any names on
these
these uh
So, if we I don't have any names on
these uh portions
these uh portions of
So, if we I don't have any names on
these uh portions of the
these uh portions of the map
So, if we I don't have any names on
these uh portions of the map uh
these uh portions of the map uh on
purpose.
purpose. Uh
purpose. Uh we
purpose. Uh we can
purpose. Uh we can just
purpose. Uh we can just see
purpose. Uh we can just see all
purpose. Uh we can just see all I
purpose. Uh we can just see all I do
purpose. Uh we can just see all I do is
have
have to
purpose. Uh we can just see all I do is
have to do
have to do is
purpose. Uh we can just see all I do is
have to do is pick
have to do is pick out
purpose. Uh we can just see all I do is
have to do is pick out a
have to do is pick out a number
purpose. Uh we can just see all I do is
have to do is pick out a number here.
You
You see
You see right
You see right central
You see right central Africa
You see right central Africa 40.
You see right central Africa 40. What
can
can you
You see right central Africa 40. What
can you expect
can you expect is
You see right central Africa 40. What
can you expect is going
can you expect is going on
You see right central Africa 40. What
can you expect is going on there
can you expect is going on there at
You see right central Africa 40. What
can you expect is going on there at 40?
Probably
Probably bar
Probably bar life
Probably bar life is
Probably bar life is barely
Probably bar life is barely subsisting.
It's
It's probably
Probably bar life is barely subsisting.
It's probably criminality,
It's probably criminality, rampant,
savagery,
savagery, people
savagery, people butchering
savagery, people butchering each
savagery, people butchering each other.
And
And that
savagery, people butchering each other.
And that is
And that is exactly
savagery, people butchering each other.
And that is exactly the
And that is exactly the history
savagery, people butchering each other.
And that is exactly the history of
And that is exactly the history of this
region.
region. And
region. And it
region. And it goes
region. And it goes on
region. And it goes on decade
region. And it goes on decade after
decade
decade after
region. And it goes on decade after
decade after decade,
decade after decade, which
region. And it goes on decade after
decade after decade, which the
decade after decade, which the UN
region. And it goes on decade after
decade after decade, which the UN of
course
course ignores
course ignores because
course ignores because it
course ignores because it looks
course ignores because it looks like
course ignores because it looks like a
problem.
problem. Yeah,
UN's
UN's good
UN's good as
UN's good as long
UN's good as long as it
UN's good as long as it doesn't
UN's good as long as it doesn't have
UN's good as long as it doesn't have to
address
address any
UN's good as long as it doesn't have to
address any problems.
address any problems. But
UN's good as long as it doesn't have to
address any problems. But this
address any problems. But this looks
pretty
pretty scary.
pretty scary. So
pretty scary. So good.
pretty scary. So good. What
pretty scary. So good. What uh
pretty scary. So good. What uh it
pretty scary. So good. What uh it gives
us
us a
pretty scary. So good. What uh it gives
us a certain
us a certain realistic
pretty scary. So good. What uh it gives
us a certain realistic expectation
us a certain realistic expectation of
the
the world.
the world. People
the world. People are
the world. People are dedicated
the world. People are dedicated to
the world. People are dedicated to truth
then
then uh
the world. People are dedicated to truth
then uh want
then uh want to
the world. People are dedicated to truth
then uh want to know
then uh want to know what
the world. People are dedicated to truth
then uh want to know what is
then uh want to know what is the
the world. People are dedicated to truth
then uh want to know what is the truth
of
of a
of a thing
of a thing and
of a thing and not
of a thing and not what
of a thing and not what is
of a thing and not what is the
of a thing and not what is the illusion
of
of the
of a thing and not what is the illusion
of the thing.
of the thing. Not
of a thing and not what is the illusion
of the thing. Not what
of the thing. Not what is
of a thing and not what is the illusion
of the thing. Not what is the
of the thing. Not what is the illusion
of
of the
of the thing.
of the thing. What
of the thing. What is
of the thing. What is the
of the thing. What is the truth
of the thing. What is the truth of
of the thing. What is the truth of a
thing?
thing? You
of the thing. What is the truth of a
thing? You know
thing? You know because
of the thing. What is the truth of a
thing? You know because unless
thing? You know because unless you
of the thing. What is the truth of a
thing? You know because unless you know
the
the truth,
the truth, how
the truth, how are
the truth, how are you
the truth, how are you going
the truth, how are you going to
the truth, how are you going to know
what
what to
the truth, how are you going to know
what to do
what to do about
the truth, how are you going to know
what to do about it?
what to do about it? All
the truth, how are you going to know
what to do about it? All right.
what to do about it? All right. So
raising
raising the
raising the level
raising the level of
raising the level of consciousness
raising the level of consciousness here
through
through education
raising the level of consciousness here
through education and
through education and whatever
raising the level of consciousness here
through education and whatever means
through
through prayer
through prayer through
through prayer through prayer
through prayer through prayer and
through prayer through prayer and in
through prayer through prayer and in in
inspiration
uh
uh would
uh would help
uh would help these
uh would help these people
uh would help these people more
uh would help these people more than
money
money because
uh would help these people more than
money because money
money because money helps
uh would help these people more than
money because money helps them
money because money helps them destroy
themselves
themselves fa
themselves fa faster.
themselves fa faster. We'll
themselves fa faster. We'll move
themselves fa faster. We'll move to
themselves fa faster. We'll move to the
next
next slide.
themselves fa faster. We'll move to the
next slide. That's
next slide. That's been
themselves fa faster. We'll move to the
next slide. That's been the
next slide. That's been the experience
in
in what's
in what's the
in what's the voodoo
in what's the voodoo island
in what's the voodoo island at
in what's the voodoo island at Haiti.
Yes.
>> The
>> The more
>> The more money
>> The more money you
>> The more money you give
>> The more money you give them
>> The more money you give them the
>> The more money you give them the worse
they
they get.
>> The more money you give them the worse
they get. And
they get. And it's
>> The more money you give them the worse
they get. And it's because
they get. And it's because they
calibrate
calibrate around
calibrate around 40
calibrate around 40 or
calibrate around 40 or something
calibrate around 40 or something and
calibrate around 40 or something and um
so
so money
calibrate around 40 or something and um
so money is
so money is not
calibrate around 40 or something and um
so money is not the
so money is not the the
calibrate around 40 or something and um
so money is not the the help
so money is not the the help raising
calibrate around 40 or something and um
so money is not the the help raising the
level
level of
level of consciousness.
Does
Does this
level of consciousness.
Does this have
Does this have a
level of consciousness.
Does this have a practical
Does this have a practical application?
Yes.
Yes. In
Yes. In fact,
Yes. In fact, it's
Yes. In fact, it's already
Yes. In fact, it's already been
Yes. In fact, it's already been used
with
with a
Yes. In fact, it's already been used
with a very
with a very solutary
Yes. In fact, it's already been used
with a very solutary result.
Um
Um this
Um this is
Um this is the
Um this is the what
Um this is the what I
Um this is the what I call
Um this is the what I call the
Um this is the what I call the us
Um this is the what I call the us and
them.
them. You
Um this is the what I call the us and
them. You can
them. You can use
Um this is the what I call the us and
them. You can use it
them. You can use it in
Um this is the what I call the us and
them. You can use it in business.
them. You can use it in business. You
can
can use
can use it
can use it in
can use it in many
can use it in many applications
can use it in many applications in
can use it in many applications in life.
uh
uh this
can use it in many applications in life.
uh this is
uh this is us
or
or your
or your company,
or your company, your
or your company, your society,
or your company, your society, whatever
you
you belong
or your company, your society, whatever
you belong to,
you belong to, democratic
or your company, your society, whatever
you belong to, democratic party,
whatever.
whatever. Uh
whatever. Uh this
whatever. Uh this is
whatever. Uh this is the
whatever. Uh this is the US
whatever. Uh this is the US and
whatever. Uh this is the US and you
calibrate
calibrate what's
whatever. Uh this is the US and you
calibrate what's the
calibrate what's the level
whatever. Uh this is the US and you
calibrate what's the level of
calibrate what's the level of the
whatever. Uh this is the US and you
calibrate what's the level of the US
calibrate what's the level of the US and
you
you put
you put a
you put a dot
you put a dot on
you put a dot on the
you put a dot on the line
you put a dot on the line there.
you put a dot on the line there. So
you put a dot on the line there. So it
just
just happens
you put a dot on the line there. So it
just happens America
just happens America at
you put a dot on the line there. So it
just happens America at the
just happens America at the time
you put a dot on the line there. So it
just happens America at the time we
just happens America at the time we did
this
this I
this I think
this I think was
this I think was at
this I think was at 426,
this I think was at 426, wasn't
this I think was at 426, wasn't it?
Yeah.
>> Or
>> Or 421
>> Or 421 something.
>> Or 421 something. Okay.
>> Or 421 something. Okay. Oh
>> Or 421 something. Okay. Oh yeah.
>> Or 421 something. Okay. Oh yeah. So
>> Or 421 something. Okay. Oh yeah. So this
is
is uh
>> Or 421 something. Okay. Oh yeah. So this
is uh we
is uh we did
>> Or 421 something. Okay. Oh yeah. So this
is uh we did it
is uh we did it in
>> Or 421 something. Okay. Oh yeah. So this
is uh we did it in this
is uh we did it in this term.
>> Or 421 something. Okay. Oh yeah. So this
is uh we did it in this term. Uh,
is uh we did it in this term. Uh, this
is
is us.
is us. US
is us. US us.
is us. US us. All right.
is us. US us. All right. Now,
is us. US us. All right. Now, you're
dealing
dealing with
is us. US us. All right. Now, you're
dealing with another
dealing with another country.
is us. US us. All right. Now, you're
dealing with another country. See,
dealing with another country. See, the
diplomacy
diplomacy doesn't
diplomacy doesn't work
diplomacy doesn't work because
diplomacy doesn't work because there's
no
no science
diplomacy doesn't work because there's
no science of
no science of diplomacy.
diplomacy doesn't work because there's
no science of diplomacy. It's
no science of diplomacy. It's just
diplomacy doesn't work because there's
no science of diplomacy. It's just one
liar
liar is
liar is better
liar is better than
liar is better than another.
liar is better than another. [laughter]
Best
Best liar
liar is better than another. [laughter]
Best liar wins.
Best liar wins. Uh,
liar is better than another. [laughter]
Best liar wins. Uh, so
Best liar wins. Uh, so we
liar is better than another. [laughter]
Best liar wins. Uh, so we don't
Best liar wins. Uh, so we don't know
liar is better than another. [laughter]
Best liar wins. Uh, so we don't know how
to
to address
to address these
to address these people.
to address these people. And
to address these people. And of
to address these people. And of course,
they
they say
to address these people. And of course,
they say that's
they say that's the
to address these people. And of course,
they say that's the trouble
they say that's the trouble with
to address these people. And of course,
they say that's the trouble with our
problem
problem with
problem with the
problem with the other
problem with the other side
problem with the other side of
problem with the other side of the
problem with the other side of the world
is
is they're
problem with the other side of the world
is they're not
is they're not handling
problem with the other side of the world
is they're not handling them
is they're not handling them correctly.
Well,
Well, first
Well, first to
Well, first to handle
Well, first to handle somebody
correctly,
correctly, you
Well, first to handle somebody
correctly, you have
correctly, you have to
Well, first to handle somebody
correctly, you have to know
correctly, you have to know who
Well, first to handle somebody
correctly, you have to know who they
are.
are. So
are. So if
are. So if we
are. So if we calibrate
are. So if we calibrate the
are. So if we calibrate the level
are. So if we calibrate the level of
consciousness
consciousness of
are. So if we calibrate the level of
consciousness of of
consciousness of of that
are. So if we calibrate the level of
consciousness of of that which
consciousness of of that which we're
dealing
dealing with
dealing with now
dealing with now you
dealing with now you know
dealing with now you know as
dealing with now you know as a
psychoanalyst
my
my expectation
my expectation is
my expectation is not
my expectation is not that
my expectation is not that the
my expectation is not that the pro
my expectation is not that the pro the
patient
patient is
my expectation is not that the pro the
patient is going
patient is going to
my expectation is not that the pro the
patient is going to come
patient is going to come to
my expectation is not that the pro the
patient is going to come to my
patient is going to come to my level
my expectation is not that the pro the
patient is going to come to my level of
awareness
awareness and
awareness and consciousness
awareness and consciousness but
awareness and consciousness but I'm
going
going to
awareness and consciousness but I'm
going to go
going to go to
awareness and consciousness but I'm
going to go to them
going to go to them so
awareness and consciousness but I'm
going to go to them so I
going to go to them so I understand
where
where they're
where they're coming
where they're coming from.
where they're coming from. How
where they're coming from. How can
where they're coming from. How can you
help
help somebody
where they're coming from. How can you
help somebody if
help somebody if you
where they're coming from. How can you
help somebody if you don't
help somebody if you don't know
where they're coming from. How can you
help somebody if you don't know where
they're
they're at?
they're at? First
they're at? First you
they're at? First you have
they're at? First you have to
they're at? First you have to have
they're at? First you have to have a
diagnosis.
diagnosis. Here's
they're at? First you have to have a
diagnosis. Here's the
diagnosis. Here's the diagnosis.
they're at? First you have to have a
diagnosis. Here's the diagnosis. So
here's
here's the
here's the country
here's the country we're
here's the country we're dealing
here's the country we're dealing with.
So
So here's
here's the country we're dealing with.
So here's uh
So here's uh here
here's the country we're dealing with.
So here's uh here if
So here's uh here if you
here's the country we're dealing with.
So here's uh here if you put
So here's uh here if you put Canada,
here's
here's Canada.
here's Canada. Uh
here's Canada. Uh South
here's Canada. Uh South America
here's Canada. Uh South America in
general.
general. Here's
here's Canada. Uh South America in
general. Here's China.
general. Here's China. Uh
here's Canada. Uh South America in
general. Here's China. Uh here's
general. Here's China. Uh here's the
here's Canada. Uh South America in
general. Here's China. Uh here's the UN
at
at 190
at 190 talking
at 190 talking sense
at 190 talking sense of
at 190 talking sense of the
at 190 talking sense of the UN.
at 190 talking sense of the UN. You
at 190 talking sense of the UN. You can
see
see what
at 190 talking sense of the UN. You can
see what that's
see what that's going
at 190 talking sense of the UN. You can
see what that's going to
see what that's going to do
at 190 talking sense of the UN. You can
see what that's going to do for
see what that's going to do for you.
Central
Central Africa
Central Africa 48.
Central Africa 48. All right.
Central Africa 48. All right. So
Central Africa 48. All right. So we're
going to
going to deal
Central Africa 48. All right. So we're
going to deal with
going to deal with that.
Central Africa 48. All right. So we're
going to deal with that. We're
going to deal with that. We're going
Central Africa 48. All right. So we're
going to deal with that. We're going to
have
have a
have a meeting
have a meeting of
have a meeting of diplomats
have a meeting of diplomats from
have a meeting of diplomats from country
X.
X. And
have a meeting of diplomats from country
X. And our
X. And our diplomats,
have a meeting of diplomats from country
X. And our diplomats, what
X. And our diplomats, what is
have a meeting of diplomats from country
X. And our diplomats, what is it
X. And our diplomats, what is it going
to
to be
to be our
to be our position
to be our position with
to be our position with them?
to be our position with them? It
to be our position with them? It depends
on
on what's
to be our position with them? It depends
on what's the
on what's the level
to be our position with them? It depends
on what's the level of
on what's the level of consciousness
to be our position with them? It depends
on what's the level of consciousness of
country
country X.
To
To begin
country X.
To begin with,
To begin with, we
country X.
To begin with, we have
To begin with, we have to
country X.
To begin with, we have to know
To begin with, we have to know what
country X.
To begin with, we have to know what is
the
the level
the level of
the level of the
the level of the leader
the level of the leader of
the level of the leader of the
government.
government. What
the level of the leader of the
government. What is
government. What is the
the level of the leader of the
government. What is the level
government. What is the level of
the level of the leader of the
government. What is the level of the
government
government itself?
government itself? And
government itself? And and
government itself? And and and
government itself? And and and what
government itself? And and and what is
the
the government?
government itself? And and and what is
the government? What
the government? What is
government itself? And and and what is
the government? What is the
the government? What is the level
government itself? And and and what is
the government? What is the level of
the government? What is the level of the
people?
people? There's
people? There's a
people? There's a country
people? There's a country very
people? There's a country very nearby.
The
The people
people? There's a country very nearby.
The people are
The people are very
people? There's a country very nearby.
The people are very lovable
The people are very lovable and
adorable.
And
And uh
adorable.
And uh government
And uh government is
adorable.
And uh government is so
And uh government is so corrupt
adorable.
And uh government is so corrupt that
And uh government is so corrupt that you
don't
don't dare
don't dare drive
don't dare drive your
don't dare drive your own
don't dare drive your own car
don't dare drive your own car across
don't dare drive your own car across the
border.
border. You
don't dare drive your own car across the
border. You know
border. You know what
don't dare drive your own car across the
border. You know what I'm
border. You know what I'm saying?
[laughter]
And
And yet
[laughter]
And yet the
And yet the people
[laughter]
And yet the people are
And yet the people are adorable.
[laughter]
And yet the people are adorable. And
And yet the people are adorable. And we
hire
hire them
hire them right
hire them right and
hire them right and left,
hire them right and left, don't
hire them right and left, don't we?
They're
They're legal
hire them right and left, don't we?
They're legal or
They're legal or illegal,
hire them right and left, don't we?
They're legal or illegal, who
They're legal or illegal, who cares?
hire them right and left, don't we?
They're legal or illegal, who cares? You
know,
know, you
know, you need
know, you need your
know, you need your lawn
know, you need your lawn fixed.
know, you need your lawn fixed. Best
workers
workers in
know, you need your lawn fixed. Best
workers in the
workers in the world.
know, you need your lawn fixed. Best
workers in the world. I've
workers in the world. I've loved
know, you need your lawn fixed. Best
workers in the world. I've loved every
one
one of
one of them
one of them that
one of them that we've
one of them that we've had
one of them that we've had with
one of them that we've had with us.
one of them that we've had with us. Uh
but
but the
one of them that we've had with us. Uh
but the government,
but the government, as
one of them that we've had with us. Uh
but the government, as I
but the government, as I say,
one of them that we've had with us. Uh
but the government, as I say, it's
but the government, as I say, it's not
safe
safe to
safe to drive
safe to drive your
safe to drive your car
safe to drive your car across
safe to drive your car across because
you
you because
safe to drive your car across because
you because they'll
you because they'll actually
safe to drive your car across because
you because they'll actually put
you because they'll actually put you
safe to drive your car across because
you because they'll actually put you in
jail
jail and
jail and hold
jail and hold you
jail and hold you for
jail and hold you for ransom
jail and hold you for ransom and
jail and hold you for ransom and how
much
much they
jail and hold you for ransom and how
much they can
much they can work
jail and hold you for ransom and how
much they can work your
much they can work your family
jail and hold you for ransom and how
much they can work your family for.
much they can work your family for. And
so
so then
so then you
so then you have
so then you have the
so then you have the opposite.
so then you have the opposite. You
so then you have the opposite. You have
excellent
excellent governments
so then you have the opposite. You have
excellent governments and
excellent governments and very
so then you have the opposite. You have
excellent governments and very poor
people.
people. And
people. And of
people. And of course,
people. And of course, America
people. And of course, America did
calibrate
calibrate at
people. And of course, America did
calibrate at 426.
calibrate at 426. I
people. And of course, America did
calibrate at 426. I don't know
calibrate at 426. I don't know what
people. And of course, America did
calibrate at 426. I don't know what it's
at
at now.
at now. not
at now. not 426
at now. not 426 and
at now. not 426 and uh
at now. not 426 and uh it
at now. not 426 and uh it was
at now. not 426 and uh it was the
highest
highest in
at now. not 426 and uh it was the
highest in the
highest in the world
at now. not 426 and uh it was the
highest in the world except
highest in the world except for
Singapore.
Singapore. Singapore
which
which doesn't
Singapore. Singapore
which doesn't have
which doesn't have freedom
Singapore. Singapore
which doesn't have freedom like
which doesn't have freedom like we
Singapore. Singapore
which doesn't have freedom like we know
it.
it. You
it. You can't
it. You can't throw
it. You can't throw your
it. You can't throw your gum
it. You can't throw your gum wrappers
it. You can't throw your gum wrappers on
the
the street.
[laughter]
Repressive
Repressive government
[laughter]
Repressive government in
Repressive government in Singapore.
[laughter]
They
They arrest
[laughter]
They arrest you
They arrest you for
[laughter]
They arrest you for treason
They arrest you for treason and
[laughter]
They arrest you for treason and various
things
things like
things like that.
things like that. So
things like that. So anyway,
things like that. So anyway, Singapore
calibrates
came
came out
came out of
came out of a
came out of a benign
came out of a benign dictatorship.
Interestingly,
Interestingly, it's
came out of a benign dictatorship.
Interestingly, it's run
Interestingly, it's run by
came out of a benign dictatorship.
Interestingly, it's run by um
my
my recommendation
my recommendation for
my recommendation for the
my recommendation for the best
my recommendation for the best form
my recommendation for the best form of
government,
government, which
my recommendation for the best form of
government, which is
government, which is what?
>> Huh?
>> Oligarchy.
>> Oligarchy. Yes.
>> Oligarchy. Yes. Yes.
>> Oligarchy. Yes. Yes. The
>> Oligarchy. Yes. Yes. The wisdom
>> Oligarchy. Yes. Yes. The wisdom of
>> Oligarchy. Yes. Yes. The wisdom of the
elders.
elders. Yes.
>> Oligarchy. Yes. Yes. The wisdom of the
elders. Yes. The
elders. Yes. The wisdom
>> Oligarchy. Yes. Yes. The wisdom of the
elders. Yes. The wisdom of
elders. Yes. The wisdom of the
>> Oligarchy. Yes. Yes. The wisdom of the
elders. Yes. The wisdom of the elders
served
served the
served the Native
served the Native American,
served the Native American, all
served the Native American, all the
tribes
tribes of
served the Native American, all the
tribes of the
tribes of the world
served the Native American, all the
tribes of the world extremely
tribes of the world extremely well.
Otherwise,
Otherwise, mankind
Otherwise, mankind would
Otherwise, mankind would not
Otherwise, mankind would not have
survived.
And
And although
And although the
And although the United
And although the United States
And although the United States cabinet
is
is supposed
And although the United States cabinet
is supposed to
is supposed to serve
And although the United States cabinet
is supposed to serve that
is supposed to serve that function,
And although the United States cabinet
is supposed to serve that function, I
don't
don't know
don't know to
don't know to what
don't know to what degree
don't know to what degree it's
don't know to what degree it's able
don't know to what degree it's able to.
But
But anyway,
don't know to what degree it's able to.
But anyway, uh
But anyway, uh to
don't know to what degree it's able to.
But anyway, uh to the
But anyway, uh to the chagrin
don't know to what degree it's able to.
But anyway, uh to the chagrin of
America,
America, Singapore
America, Singapore caliber
America, Singapore caliber is
considerably
considerably higher
America, Singapore caliber is
considerably higher and
considerably higher and it's
America, Singapore caliber is
considerably higher and it's a
considerably higher and it's a safer
place
place to
place to be.
place to be. The
place to be. The crime
place to be. The crime rate
place to be. The crime rate in
place to be. The crime rate in Singapore
is
is practically
place to be. The crime rate in Singapore
is practically zero.
is practically zero. All
place to be. The crime rate in Singapore
is practically zero. All right.
is practically zero. All right. So,
place to be. The crime rate in Singapore
is practically zero. All right. So, we
know
know who
know who we
know who we are.
know who we are. So,
know who we are. So, let's
know who we are. So, let's say
know who we are. So, let's say we're
know who we are. So, let's say we're a
company
company and
know who we are. So, let's say we're a
company and we
company and we calibrate
uh
uh at
uh at 2
uh at 2 210
uh at 2 210 and
uh at 2 210 and we're
uh at 2 210 and we're dealing
uh at 2 210 and we're dealing with
uh at 2 210 and we're dealing with a
company
company that
uh at 2 210 and we're dealing with a
company that calibrates
company that calibrates down
uh at 2 210 and we're dealing with a
company that calibrates down here
company that calibrates down here or
calibrates
calibrates up
calibrates up here.
If
If the
calibrates up here.
If the company
If the company you're
calibrates up here.
If the company you're dealing
If the company you're dealing with
calibrates
calibrates at
calibrates at 160,
calibrates at 160, you
calibrates at 160, you better
calibrates at 160, you better be
extremely
extremely cautious.
calibrates at 160, you better be
extremely cautious. That
extremely cautious. That means
calibrates at 160, you better be
extremely cautious. That means they're
going
going to
going to welch
going to welch on
going to welch on contracts.
going to welch on contracts. They're
going
going to
going to welch on contracts. They're
going to give
going to give you
going to welch on contracts. They're
going to give you promises.
going to give you promises. They're
going
going to
going to screw
going to screw you
going to screw you up.
going to screw you up. They're
going to screw you up. They're going
going to screw you up. They're going to
give
give you
going to screw you up. They're going to
give you a
give you a check
going to screw you up. They're going to
give you a check and
give you a check and then
going to screw you up. They're going to
give you a check and then you
give you a check and then you find
going to screw you up. They're going to
give you a check and then you find that
it
it bounces.
it bounces. So
it bounces. So there's
it bounces. So there's no
it bounces. So there's no surprises
it bounces. So there's no surprises then
if
if you
it bounces. So there's no surprises then
if you understand
if you understand who
it bounces. So there's no surprises then
if you understand who you're
if you understand who you're dealing
with.
with. So
with. So this
with. So this isn't
with. So this isn't to
with. So this isn't to make
with. So this isn't to make them
with. So this isn't to make them wrong.
It's
It's just
with. So this isn't to make them wrong.
It's just that
It's just that I
with. So this isn't to make them wrong.
It's just that I know
It's just that I know these
with. So this isn't to make them wrong.
It's just that I know these people's
checks
checks won't
checks won't clear.
checks won't clear. [laughter]
I
I know
checks won't clear. [laughter]
I know that
a
a treatis
a treatis a
a treatis a treaty
a treatis a treaty signed
a treatis a treaty signed with
a treatis a treaty signed with an
Islamic
Islamic nation
a treatis a treaty signed with an
Islamic nation will
Islamic nation will not
a treatis a treaty signed with an
Islamic nation will not hold
Islamic nation will not hold because
Shiara
Shiara says
Shiara says you're
Shiara says you're under
Shiara says you're under no
Shiara says you're under no obligation
to
to adhere
Shiara says you're under no obligation
to adhere to
to adhere to any
Shiara says you're under no obligation
to adhere to any contract
to adhere to any contract that
Shiara says you're under no obligation
to adhere to any contract that you
to adhere to any contract that you sign
whatsoever
whatsoever because
whatsoever because you
whatsoever because you can
whatsoever because you can do
whatsoever because you can do anything
that
that you
whatsoever because you can do anything
that you wish
that you wish so
whatsoever because you can do anything
that you wish so long
that you wish so long as
whatsoever because you can do anything
that you wish so long as it
that you wish so long as it facilitates
triumphalism.
>> [laughter]
>> So,
>> So, at
>> So, at what
>> So, at what point
>> So, at what point is
>> So, at what point is there
>> So, at what point is there signing
>> So, at what point is there signing a
negotiating
negotiating a
>> So, at what point is there signing a
negotiating a contract
negotiating a contract with
>> So, at what point is there signing a
negotiating a contract with people
negotiating a contract with people who
calibrate
calibrate down
calibrate down here?
calibrate down here? And
calibrate down here? And of
calibrate down here? And of course,
calibrate down here? And of course, we
already
already did
calibrate down here? And of course, we
already did what
already did what Hitler
calibrate down here? And of course, we
already did what Hitler thought
already did what Hitler thought after
calibrate down here? And of course, we
already did what Hitler thought after uh
what's
what's his
what's his name
what's his name left
what's his name left signing
what's his name left signing a
what's his name left signing a contract
with
with Adolf
what's his name left signing a contract
with Adolf Hitler.
with Adolf Hitler. Uh
what's his name left signing a contract
with Adolf Hitler. Uh when
with Adolf Hitler. Uh when they
what's his name left signing a contract
with Adolf Hitler. Uh when they signed
the
the peace
the peace treaty,
the peace treaty, as
the peace treaty, as he
the peace treaty, as he walked
the peace treaty, as he walked away,
Hitler
Hitler thought,
the peace treaty, as he walked away,
Hitler thought, "What
Hitler thought, "What an
the peace treaty, as he walked away,
Hitler thought, "What an idiot.
[laughter]
What
What an
[laughter]
What an idiot
What an idiot to
[laughter]
What an idiot to think
What an idiot to think to
[laughter]
What an idiot to think to believe
What an idiot to think to believe that."
Because
Because you
Because you see
Because you see what
Because you see what it
Because you see what it means
Because you see what it means to
Because you see what it means to people
with
with a
Because you see what it means to people
with a narcissism
with a narcissism is
Because you see what it means to people
with a narcissism is that
with a narcissism is that they
Because you see what it means to people
with a narcissism is that they are
omnipotent
omnipotent that
omnipotent that they
omnipotent that they are
omnipotent that they are not
omnipotent that they are not constrained
by
by earthly
omnipotent that they are not constrained
by earthly rules
by earthly rules and
omnipotent that they are not constrained
by earthly rules and therefore
by earthly rules and therefore they
omnipotent that they are not constrained
by earthly rules and therefore they will
do
do it
do it to
do it to make
do it to make you
do it to make you happy
do it to make you happy but
do it to make you happy but they
do it to make you happy but they have
do it to make you happy but they have no
uh
uh decision.
do it to make you happy but they have no
uh decision. So
uh decision. So you
do it to make you happy but they have no
uh decision. So you can
uh decision. So you can know
do it to make you happy but they have no
uh decision. So you can know these
things
things ahead
things ahead of
things ahead of time
things ahead of time by
things ahead of time by doing
things ahead of time by doing us
things ahead of time by doing us and
them
them for
things ahead of time by doing us and
them for your
them for your company,
things ahead of time by doing us and
them for your company, your
them for your company, your family,
whatever
whatever you
whatever you want
whatever you want to
whatever you want to do.
whatever you want to do. Uh
whatever you want to do. Uh this
whatever you want to do. Uh this is
whatever you want to do. Uh this is what
our
our family
whatever you want to do. Uh this is what
our family calibrates
our family calibrates at.
whatever you want to do. Uh this is what
our family calibrates at. This
our family calibrates at. This is
whatever you want to do. Uh this is what
our family calibrates at. This is what
the
the neighborhood
the neighborhood calibrates
the neighborhood calibrates at.
the neighborhood calibrates at. How
the neighborhood calibrates at. How are
you
you going
the neighborhood calibrates at. How are
you going to
you going to work
the neighborhood calibrates at. How are
you going to work out
you going to work out there?
the neighborhood calibrates at. How are
you going to work out there? Okay.
right.
right. So,
right. So, we'll
right. So, we'll move
right. So, we'll move to
right. So, we'll move to the
right. So, we'll move to the next
practicality.
[music]
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
[music]
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
[music]
Hallelu [music]
Hallelu
[music]
Hallelujah.
[singing]
[music]