Excelsior Steel. So I'm wearing the body this morning it's a bit of a problem you just
have to be patient. Sometimes the condition is stronger than others and
you'll have to put up whatever is today. How many people are new today? All right.
It's very easy to see that everything is happening spontaneously. That even your
thinkingness is happening all of its own. And you think that you're deciding
what you're going to think but you're not. So you get detached from your own
thinkingness the same as the world. You see the world around you is moving
without your help. Right? All these people are managing to survive without you
helping them to be here and move and talk. And so what you do is you get detached and you
begin to become the witness.
To become the witness is not a difficult step. It's only a matter of letting go the
narcissistic self-indulgence of the thinking of that there's an I causing
things. Nothing is causing anything. There are no causes in the world. There's only
consequences. And so what you do is you let go of identifying with the linear and
you realize that your reality is non-linear.
That which is witnessing and then behind that which is witnessing that which is
aware that you're witnessing and already you've removed yourself from out there
and individual personal I and the guilt and anxiety of being the cause of all that
happens and you've moved into this the condition of humility. With profound
humility you will see that you're not the cause of anything.
Which is welcome news because that means you're also not guilty of anything.
If something happens you say, I don't know the mind did it. I can't help it, the mind did it, so...
To become the witness, then, you become aware then of
the spontaneity of evolution and you begin to witness all phenomena are the
Evolution of creation.
Creation has a source but no cause.
It has no beginning and it has no end.
You witness the enfoldment of creation.
There is no problem about creation because it's what you're witnessing.
The fact that it's all happening spontaneously is not difficult to see.
It's not difficult to move from the participant subject out there, the linear,
and move into being the field out of which the phenomena,
you're being aware of the phenomena.
That which you are is the field and not the content of the field.
This observation escapes about 99% of mankind.
Let's see if that was right.
99% is correct.
Yes.
At least 99% of humanity is completely unaware of what we're talking about this morning.
We're not counting on widespread acceptance.
Yeah.
That you are the context rather than the content.
You are that from which awareness radiates and out of which consciousness arises.
The source is consciousness itself.
The light of God is consciousness.
the light of God is your own consciousness
and as you let go
misidentifying with that which you are not
it becomes stunningly apparent
at which point you retire
and they call the doctor
he's lost his wits
that's true you do lose your wits
sometimes it's worse than others
so today I am witless
and you'll have to put up with that condition
alright we always have some new people
so we do some review of some very basic things
do you want to start with what's new first
and then move back to what you know
or do you want to start with what you know
to move to what's new
all the new people
you want what's new
start with what's new
then move to what's
we'll do both
beginnings and ends are all in your head
they're in the beginning
laughter
we do start
just for orientation
with the calibrated map of consciousness
as a common point of reference
yeah friend
so that's what we'll do
start with that one
and yes
explain it
I'll explain it maybe a little bit differently
where's the first slide there
where's
there we go
what do you know
I'll re-explain the map of consciousness
I'm sorry I went from one to a thousand
I should have gone from A to Z
because everybody thinks a number
a higher number makes you better than other people
no it doesn't
it just means you're seeing things in a different light
blue green we could do it with colors
and I've decided the best way to do it is with money
laughter
so this calibration
here is not worth much money
laughter
and that's worth a thousand dollars
so we're all trying for the job
laughter
so we're all trying for the jackpot
so the lower levels of consciousness are just not worth much
laughter
they'll only get you a few bomb loads of kids to blow up or something like that
nothing spectacular
laughter
alright so we decided we'd change it to money
and these are not worth much money down here
the exchange rate deepens
it depends on the exchange rate
the media have jacked up the exchange rate
which we'll get into later
laughter
so that this now pays more than this up here
oh god it's hysterical
I don't know how the world survives
and God tells me not to let on
so I won't
laughter
if you ever have preachers God tells them this and God tells them that
I'd listen
I'd hear silence
laughter
the sound of God is silence
that's a thousand
calibrates it a thousand
the sound of God is silence
to have sound you have to have linearity
you have to have that which is sound and that which is not sound
and then you have to give configuration to the sound
therefore mantras and things and going oom and things
will take you to a certain level
and beyond that you get you become aware of the silence behind the sound
and so the purpose of the sound is to take you to the silence
that's why repeating a mantra repeatedly
can sometimes really just lead to an altered state of consciousness
and the high feeling that you get disappears when you stop the mantra
so they all have limited
limited
usages
there are cysts at certain points but you can't put your whole life
as a mantra
you can put your whole life as a prayer
because a prayer is a verbalization of a nonlinear
intentionality
of prayer to make your life a prayer
to become that
and that which you are speaks louder than what you say
essence speaks louder than perception
which we'll get to later
alright so that's the
the levels of consciousness as I said
it's relatively well known
it was an arbitrary scale
because we needed some way to refer to it
it's also logarithmic so that
as you go up the numbers increase very very rapidly
that's why we use logarithms
very very rapidly
alright now what did I say was the next slide after that
any questions on the calibrated level of consciousness
as I say it doesn't say that you're better than others
it's not a matter of better
because our status oriented
you know
society
we say it's better
it's not better
it's different than
different than
and very often to be in a different than
state of consciousness that is not appropriate to where you are
it can be a hindrance you understand
to be blissed out
you know when you're driving is not so great
you have to pull over
so you have to sort of be in what's appropriate
but that begins to adjust itself automatically
but it is true that if you suddenly advance to a high state
you may be quite incapacitated
so it's well to have spiritual friends
hang out with spiritual people
spiritual friends
and you let them know that you're
you know seriously studying etc
and if you go into such states
they will recognize what it is
and that was a function I used to have
for the Zen Monastery back east
I was a consultant to the Episcopal Diocese
the Catholic Diocese
the Ministerial Council
the Zen Monastery
and they would bring in people
and is he catatonic or is he in Samadhi
they didn't know
and because they would go into a silent still state
which is not dissimilar from catatonia
which I used to see in the hospital you know
I think I told you that story
I had a catatonic that hadn't spoken in 20 years
and they would put his hand up like this
and he would stay that way year in and year out
not move
he would have to move his hand down like that
and one time he saw the head of the hospital coming
and the nurses weren't supposed to smoke or drink coffee in the office
and he saw them
he hadn't spoken in 20 years
all of a sudden he turned and he said
Travis
the nurses put their coffee in there
that's the only thing he ever said
Travis is coming
unbelievable
they had to tube feed him
he wouldn't eat you know
catatonia
so in a high bliss state
it might be difficult to tell
is this person catatonic
or in a high state of bliss
and without calibrating them you can't tell
so the value of this discovery of course
my interest was in sharing it with the world
and
you know why I teach is the same reason
Fleming
ran around after he discovered penicillin
you know he discovered penicillin accidentally
just as I discovered
the basis of how we discern truth from falsehood
was a chance observation
which I got in an instant what it signified
and Fleming discovered the same thing with the petri dish
when he noticed that
the moles had
killed off the bacteria
oh my god
he got what it meant you see
one thing to see it is another to get what it means
and Fleming got what it meant
oh my god he got what it meant
and then by experimentation
he discovered penicillin
and of course it's a whole new era
those amongst us who are doctors remember
the days when everybody was dying of typhoid
and malaria and polio and tuberculosis
and all the terrible diseases which no longer even exist
you don't even see these illnesses anymore
so it's transformed the world antibiotics
and so what Fleming was interested in
was the importance of discovery
and he couldn't get anybody to listen to it
because it was coming from a different context
and he ran around for some five years
nobody would listen to him
then in World War II
the combatants of course had injuries
the soldiers and sailors
had injuries so
wound injuries the infections
the infection was what
finally killed you
the infection was the main thing
you got a bullet through the arm
I wouldn't say it was nothing
because I've had similar things
they're not nothing but
what kills you then was the bacterial infection
six weeks later
you had six weeks of high fever
and various things
so what Fleming's motivation was
to share this with the world
and it was only because of the military's need
in World War II
that some of the military
the army finally listened to him
and we now have the whole era
of antibiotics and pharmaceuticals
so that's the motivation
about writing the books
and about giving the lectures
is I know what the catalytic value
of the information is
and my intention is to share that
sufficiently widely that it radiates
of its own henceforth
okay
so that's why we're here today
alright so we'll go on then
we'll go on
oh yes
well we want to know
not the obligations of spiritual teachers
but I want to have
characteristics
we want characteristics of
spiritual teachers
we want
thirty nine
we want thirty nine
can we get thirty nine
okay
we've done this slide before
but because of various things
that come into the office
between lectures
I realize that I may not have explained
certain things adequately
by the style of the question
the truth
all truth is truth everywhere
under all conditions throughout all time
truth is different from a fact
the fact is linear
definable
confirmable
truth is essence
and the majority of people have no way of discerning truth
from falsehood
alright so the alignment of the spiritual teacher
is to share
truth which is a universal truth
it's not exclusive
it's available to everyone
available to everyone
the integrity of the purpose
there's nothing to gain or lose
it's not sectarian
it's independent of opinion
now truth is quite different from opinion
a lot of times people will
you know write and say
how come you said
you said so and so
calibrates a so and so
they presume there's a you though that said that
there isn't any you
much less did that you say anything
it's a measurement
like a barometric pressure
or an altitude
it just calibrates at a certain thing
and
the
we're talking today about you know
differentiating perception from
reality
it's devoid of a position
has no requirements or demands
doesn't charge you know a monthly fee
now you can get on the internet
for a fee you can get enlightened in 30 days
60 days or 90 days
depending on which one you sign up for
it can't be done
I appreciate the spirit in which
it's presented to the world but
it could take many a lifetime you know
you can't really even by coaching
get somebody
and their way to full enlightenment
what I call in the writings the final door
is at $9.99
it's not at $5.99
there's some
teaching out there it's at $5.99
that's a misunderstanding
$5.99 is just before
you hit $600 which is bliss
bliss sat in
sat
chitinanda
the bliss state is at $600
one of infinite peace
and it comes right after the ecstatic phase
the final doorway is
$9.99
and
that is a whole different thing altogether
so
Tegra's teaching is that
you can't really sign people up
and charge them
and guarantee that you're going to raise
their level of consciousness
a couple times a day
and they're going to be enlightened in 30 or 60 or 90 days
it can't be done
what it does is appeal to the spiritual ego
now
the calibrated numbers therefore
the ego
the spiritual ego will instantly get attracted
to want to be better
and calibrate higher
the doorway into heaven
doesn't have a book of calibrations
you see
St. Peter doesn't say
let's see
you calibrated 422
well you got to go to that heaven
you calibrated that
each of us has an essence
that essence automatically gravitates
to that which it is
so
don't worry about
calibrating higher
the purposes of the lecture overall
from a strictly spiritual viewpoint
so I have two levels
one is scientific
as a clinician
I realize the benefit
in many many fields
of being able to tell truth from falsehood
I mean the world hasn't even
glimpsed it yet
what can be done with that
so there's the scientific viewpoint then
the first time in history
you can differentiate truth from falsehood
not only that
but the level of truth
which tells you
what paradigm of consciousness
you're talking about
because most confusion
is a confusion of paradigms
one speaking from this paradigm
the main one in our world today
in America
is the dispute between
consciousness levels below 200
with those above 200
it's really almost like
two different societies
and worldwide
the same conditions are
war between
that which calibrates below 200
with that which calibrates above 200
so it doesn't make you better than
but it does put you in
a different crowd of people
an integrity spiritual group
is very supportive
you don't necessarily need
their physical appearance
the minute you are
you are in your own mind
part of that
then you pick up the energy of that
and then when you decline that
you lose the energy of that
okay
I just wanted to say that the
spiritual teachers
are not supposed to be
controlling people
not having any requirements
or demands
you got to do this
no oaths
no requirements
no dues
no
you don't have to sign up
for anything
next thing
here
what goes after 10
in this world
well that's okay
we might as well restate
the spiritual teacher then
because there seems to be
a great many
I'm somewhat disquieted
when I calibrate
some of the better known
that the fallout
is quite considerable
I consider it the
the responsibility
of those teachers
teachers
to have
forewarned them
of what the temptations are
because they have
you know
fell innocently into it
because
the narcissistic core
of the ego
is in direct competition with God
and the more godly you get
the more
the more clever it gets
in order to survive
uh huh
ah
what
oh
she skipped
okay well
anyway
whatever
non-binding
you don't have to sign up
for anything
you're free to come and go
without a rattlesnake
being put in your mailbox
it's inspiration
you see
you don't see
glamorization
seduction
and theatrics
so when we go over
this list
you know
the list of fallen gurus
which I won't
once presented
and it costs so much
clamor
I can decide not to do it again
uh
it's because of being
pulled into those things
being pulled into
uh
the glamour
and the theatrics
and the
the
the theatre
of
drama
which
is
endemic in certain regions
of the world
uh huh
so
it's detached
from trying to control
things out there
it's benign
because
it's self-fulfilling
it's not intentional
let's say
is there such a thing
as a purpose though
well
as I said
I have two
two motives
one is to share
what I think is beneficial
and
and the other is
by using that
which is beneficial
to delineate
a clear path
through what the world
has classically called
enlightenment
uh
realization of the self
god consciousness
whatever name
you want to call it
and that's
just the progressive
disidentification
with the linear
and
be realizing
that you are
the non-linear
you're the field
in which
the linear mind
operates
if it wasn't
for the field
you wouldn't know
what your linear mind
is talking about
you understand
it's the light
that lights up
consciousness
lights up
the mind itself
so you know
what the mind
is thinking
okay
so then
we'll move on
to the next one
uh
there's an inner
tranquility
and peace
equality
uh
non-temporality
beyond
and it's
beyond proof
so there's
a whole
which we'll get
to later
uh
thrust
in academia
uh
Daniel Dennett
people of that
caliber
uh
who would like
to see
Dennett
just wrote a new book
and he
what he envisions
is all the professors
of the world
to come together
and get rid
of this old
superstition
called religion
yeah
and yesterday's
letter to the editor
of the Arizona Republic
he said
uh
religion
is the cause
of all wars
religion
yeah
of course
the cause
of all wars
is the narcissistic
core of the ego
and it
projects it
onto religion
and lets religion
be the
the flag
under which
it parades
you know
but underneath
is messianic
narcissistic
grandiosity
and
and that's all
you can call it holy
if you want it
holy
well you can call it
but it is
the messianic
core of the
narcissistic
ego
and of course
religion gets blamed
for it
so I wrote a response
to it
and uh
I said you know
the great wars
of history
uh
religion
the Vikings
the Goths
the Visigoths
the great Mongol
conquerors
that conquered
all of Asia
uh
Hitler didn't do it
in the name of God
uh
World War I
wasn't done
in the name of God
Korean War
wasn't done
in the name of God
so what war
is he talking about
is blamed
on religion
the Gulf War
was Kaiwa
wasn't it
and these wars
are all about oil
aren't they
so it doesn't
matter
for oil
people will sell
their soul
kill their
fellow
countrymen
and kill everybody
kill other humans
for the control
of oil
no
the God
of today's world
is oil
oh
you don't
then you
like the oil
well
my favorite
is thermal heat
you see
my favorite
solution
you know
you look at a volcano
it's thousands
of degrees
and what are they doing
with all that free heat
pouring all over
well you take a big
big pipe
of cold water
and you run it in tubes
near enough
to the volcano
I mean
it's about a thousand degrees
you can back out
where it's 800 degrees
and back off
you run big pipes
of white
of water
near a volcano
and then
back out again
as the cold water
gets
near a thousand degrees
the volcanic heat
underneath
it turns to steam
the steam
then shoots out
under high pressure
runs turbines
so that's my idea
thermal heat
is free heat
you know
you don't have to do anything
once the tube is there
and it's running cold
into hot
you sit back
and click
click the watts
as they pour out
the other end
don't you
right
well
I know
I'm on their list now
having said that
my days are numbered
you don't hear much
of gung ho
for thermal heat
do you
it's completely free
it doesn't contaminate
the neighborhood
understand
you just run cold water
near all that
hot
underneath
it comes out
steam
automatically
runs a turbine
what do you have to do
except boil the turbines
once in a while
you know what I mean
that's my naivety
we'll move on
to the rest
of this list
just because
it comes up
periodically
with emails
from peoples
they worry about
certain teachers
that are
charging them
and trying to
sort of exploit
exploit it
you know
I'll calibrate you
for so much
twice a day
that's sort of naiv
I mean
I can understand
the desire
to coach people
but you have to also
realize
what you're doing
non-authoritarian
in other words
the authority
arises
for the
from the truth
of the information
that's stored
within yourself
what is the
authority
not a person
not a declaration
not history
the authority
then
is the truth
itself
so the pursuit
of
the realization
of the presence
of God
via
truth
we call it
devotional
non-duality
you know
devotion
to the truth
itself
because
the truth
itself
is the truth
and you are
in narcissistic
gain
so respect
for truth
means you don't have
to now worship
something mystical
something that spoke
thousands of years ago
on the other side
of the world
came out
of a burning bush
or something mystical
because
these are difficulties
for modern man
the book I'm working
on now
is called
I forget
what the name
of this
spiritual reality
in modern man
yes
the difficulty
the modern man
has
and we're going to
look a little bit
at the modern world
later
the difficulty
the modern man
has
is really
condensed
in the scopes
trial
and in the book
I'm going to
hopefully resolve
the scopes
dilemma
for once
and for all
it's never been resolved
and of course
the reason it's not resolved
is they're talking
about two different paradigms
two different dimensions
you know
science
is in this dimension
and spiritual reality
is in another dimension
and it's only
if you look at it
with the overall context
which includes
both dimensions
and the scale
of consciousness
allows us to do that
which we'll get into
more later
so the teacher
is supposed to be
what should I say
supposed to be
non-authoritarian
you get that
you're not supposed
to be authoritarian
consequently
the capacity
to laugh
at one's self
laugh
so
the teacher
is supposed
to be
non-authoritarian
the Dalai Lama
laughs all the time
I talked to a lady
on the
we did a radio show
last week
you know
and she doesn't really
understand humor
she didn't understand
my humor
and
huh
anyway
it's a radio program
I don't want to say
it was
anyway
she's been around
everywhere
so
you know
I would break into laughter
periodically
and I'd puzzle her
and she'd say
I don't know
the Dalai Lama
she didn't get
the
you know
comparing the essence
with the presentation
comparing
perception
with the essence
she didn't get
the humor of it
but it is
hard to keep
a straight face
so
laughs
yeah
self-supporting
we don't
proselytize
for donations
we don't send you
little return envelopes
laughs
I donate
to some of them
of course
and I always regret
when I do
you make them happy
for a while
no within a week
you get another one
laughs
I just send them a check
you know what I mean
and suddenly you get it
from others
in a similar vein
you know
what do they do
sell your name
you know
I don't know
you give to the animals
the next thing you get
you know
help the birds
I mean
I didn't
it's free standing
complete
and independent
of its own
devoid of induced
or altered states
of consciousness
and you know
pursuing programs
super power
kind of programs
that teach you
altered states
of consciousness
they only calibrate
around 200
or 205
they're not going
to give you
super power
but all
you can see
all these things
appeal to the
spiritual ego
um
the best
laughs
the best thing
to do
is to surrender
your spiritual progress
to God
and follow
what you understand
to be basic
dictums
to just be kind
to be friendly
and cheerful
to uplift
life
wherever you can
okay
we'll go to the next
uh-huh
uh
did we do them all
no no
all right
no this is fine
but we're doing it
topsy-turvy
that's okay
only the mundane mind
has to go from
beginning to end
right
we're beyond that
are we not folks
three cheers
for the disorganized
mind
laughs
anybody
can be logical
yeah
laughs
it's so mundane
and pedestrian
laughs
yeah
therefore
I feel that
uh
the teacher
should make a
declaration
of who they are
to the people
instead of always
the other way around
in which the people
project what they would
like you to be
and see you in that
and then you get all
the appropriate robes
and hairdos
and shave your head
and sit cross legged
and go home all day
there's a new thing
on the yellow book
oh
consult the yellow book
laughs
look at yellow book
very funny
all right
so the
I expect the speech
to tell me
who they are
and why they're here
why should I listen
to them
and what is their
purpose
and then they should
fulfill that purpose
to try and explain
things
to try and
uh
not just make a
essence statement
from a certain level
which is not
comprehensible
to the world
uh
it sounds good
that the world
is perfect
the way it is
but nobody's
going to believe it
that's a fact
but I keep it secret
laughs
to know whether
the world is perfect
as it is
you would have to know
the purpose of the world
wouldn't you
you couldn't say
one way or another
so you can't really
make a moralistic
condemnation
about anything
in the world
unless you're aware
of what the purpose is
if the purpose
of this world
is to have eternal peace
man's been at war
93% of the time
I think peace
is an abnormal condition
he probably falls behind
the evolutionary scale
the only time
you know
the only reason
they have peace
7% of the time
is because man
is busy dying
of the plague
laughs
Katrina
hurricanes
I mean
they got other things
to do
than make war
they're all too sick
laughs
if they were able
it would be
100% of their time
laughs
so the teacher
I think
should just tell you
who they are
what their purpose is
laughs
and where to
look for the knowledge
and where it came from
uh
moral and ethical
conduct with students
a lot of those
fallen gurus
it's all over the internet
so I guess
it's not a secret
laughs
fell on that
you don't want
to be bribed
these are people
who are bribed
explain the teachings
and provide available
make them available
laughs
so there's no secrets
you know
for some
we'll take you in
and teach you
the ancient
mystical secrets
secret mysteries
calibrated about
160 or something
laughs
I know people
giving up their life
for ancient secret mysteries
they calibrated
give me a break
that was just
sold for a price
then
truth is free
and available
so the teacher
teaches out of
sharing
and he precludes
dependency
ah
we see it
autonomous
study groups
AA
is the great
leader in that
probably the most
powerful
spiritual
purely
organization
in the world
today
purely spiritual
is the 12 step group
first of all
it's pure spirituality
which is very rare
laughs
it's
ah
and it pervades
our whole society
and it uplifts
the overall
consciousness
of mankind
so
you want to make
all the teachings
available
explain them
you don't want
the people
becoming dependent
you want to
start autonomous
study groups
and
ah
you have to be
yourself
a teacher
ah
grateful for the knowledge
humble of the knowledge
because it's a given
the only work
the student does
is
the endeavor
that it takes
to remove
the blocks
what happens
after that
is removing
the clouds
from the sky
so you could take
credit maybe
for
removing clouds
but you really cannot
take credit
for the
radiance of the sun
laughs
and those who do
fall
laughs
you can see
they started out here
and then
the calibration fell
because
you think
so the spiritual ego
then
is the undoing
ah
therefore a teacher
has to teach you
about the spiritual ego
and that's why
each level
has it's traps
and I've tried
to share the traps
of that level
that particular level
we'll get into
the 400's
later
where you become
educated
ah
the trap
is ah
intellectual
narcissism
that's a
term that came
to me this week
and I said
my god
that's what it is
I was looking
at a guy
like Dennett
you know
and all these various people
and they're all atheistic
and ah
and they all believe
the way
ah
the intellect
is the ultimate truth
you see
the intellect
is the ultimate truth
ah
so humility means
even intellectual humility
not just spiritual humility
but
intellectual
and
you can be
very high
high IQ
and very erudite
and still be humble
about it
because
it's a gift
the intelligence
you're born
with a high IQ
you're born with that
what can you do about it
you gotta learn to live with it
yeah
it's tough
you know
because
you're not aligned with
a lot of other things
you have to
acknowledge the source
of knowingness
and
forget about
personal credit
or acclaim
and ah
share the means
of access
to the truth
so that's
what we try to do
yes
we try to
fulfill our own
requirements
ah
is that the end of that
oh
provide means of transportation
no
provide means of
inspirational
and devotional
you see
devotion takes
ah
people
picture devotion
as long faced
long faced
and you hear
it's sort of
middle age
gothic
in the background
it's sort of scary
and mystical
you know what I mean
it's sort of
so you inspire
that's a certain paradigm
that's a certain picture
that people have
of
devotional
high devotional states
is
that the robes
and the music
and the gothic
ah
or else
sitting cross legged
and
you know
having a
whatchamacallit
ah
bracelet on
and
all the glamorization
magazines
of spirituality
always have
ah
she's always blonde
and slim
very slick
alright
what's inspirational
and devotional
is
ah
being radically
that which you are
therefore
the image changes constantly
a teacher
who is always
in the same space
is probably
in a self-hypnotic state
of some kind
why
because
truth takes
is constantly
reflection
this time
this day
this miracle
other times you go into
a high state of ecstasy
that almost paralyzes you
ah
other states
in other moments
you go into
a profound state of peace
ah
so each one of those
teaches by
by you sharing
that which you are
so therefore
humor
of a certain level
is
let's say
closer
to ultimate truth
than somber
glumness
you know
somber glumness
and
ah
the deification
of penance
penance
of course
the Dalai Lama
laughs all the time
all right
explain the pitfalls
that are along the way
there
the spiritual ego
and then there's just
the ordinary ego
money
fame
the same thing
that runs Hollywood
ah
image
money
fame
ah
all that kind of stuff
and I don't know
what you do with all that
it's a big nuisance
to your expensive vehicles
I mean where do you
garage them
laughs
you see
so
acquisition
at a certain point
becomes an encumbrance
pretty soon
you just
have all you need
and at that point
you don't need anything
so you don't have
any more
like
wanting this
okay
the true teacher
is really
unguarded
and very genuine
and approachable
and
non
doesn't mystify you
rejects commercialization
so
some became
very very
commercialized
some over time
became very very
commercialized
and
it's because of our society
I don't blame them for it
our society
commercializes you
unless you resist it
you
you get commercialized
society does that to you
ah
and therefore it's
difficult to maintain
the simplicity of life
when the
culture
is really
working on you
you avoid being
pompous
ah
and I believe
in being transparent
ah
and the source
of the knowingness
of course
the source
of the knowingness
is not the personal self
so you can't take credit
for it
because
what happens
is that
what you were
or thought
that you were
ah
disappears
and then
what
what survives
is actually
a state
or a condition
I don't know
if anybody's ever
called it that
it's a condition
it's a way
of beingness
that is just
different than
what it was
when you thought
there was a
personal self
that was the cause
of everything
okay
is there any more
to these slides
okay
all right
so I thought
we'd get to the world
we live in
because
as I say
what I'm writing now
I realize
the difficulty
ah
that modern man has
modern man has
more difficulty
than in the past
because
modern man is
bombarded
by the media
and the media
have no respect
for
ah
truth
whatsoever
you'll notice
most
a lot of the commentators
are saying that
now
tell
recently in television
they don't even know
who to trust
for their source
of information
because
they go on the air
with a verified source
of information
it turns out
to be fallacious
and they look idiotic
and they're all in despair
as to where can you turn
for
the whole truth
they have no means
of discerning truth
from falsehood
no means
and therefore
what
what gets the media's
attention then
ah
is what
what ah
we have to sift through
in the
in
between the
television
and the
internet machine
the
WWW
circuit
thing
the blogger
blogger
blogger lamp
whatever that is
so anyway
ah
now
now when you give
everybody access
then
ah
to
universal means
of communication
ah
what are you opening
the door to
what you're opening
is
this graph
78%
of the world
calibrates
below 200
pretty soon
fallacy
begins
to dominate
over truth
the reason is
the human mind
cannot tell
perception
from essence
the mind
becomes
glamorized
by
the sensational
way
in which
the news
and the
falsity
is presented
ah
the mind
is innocent
so the reason
for forgiveness
for all beings
is that
the mind
in and of
its own
sake
is unable
to differentiate
truth
from falsehood
that's what
Jesus Christ
said
the mind
in and of itself
is unable
to discern
truth from falsehood
therefore the value
of the work
that we stumbled upon
and present here
and share
ah
is for the first time
in human history
as far as I know
there was a means
discovered
ah
to discern
truth from falsehood
so the mind
intrinsically
is incapable
of it
and now
I think people's
capacity
to discern reality
is actually
being injured
ah
because it's being
repetitively
programmed
to think in terms
of certain slogans
and memes
and these
be then
become incorporated
into one's
ah
mental apparatus
and you be
just became
injured
and didn't even know it
and we'll get to some
of those examples
later
78%
of the world's population
so what you read
on the internet
let's do
blogger land
ah
in blogger land
let's see
ah
blogger land
over 20%
is true
over 15%
of blogger land
is true
over 10%
of blogger land
is true
about 10%
of blogger land
is true
ah
and people quote it
widely
you know
and quote it
and put it
on the internet
machine
the email machine
what
what is it
that you quote
it comes in
with messages
anyway
whatever it is
alright so
and you know
all these people
here have
ah
blog sites
you'd be surprised
I never read
this before
but hardly anybody
up here
has a blog site
let's see
if that's correct
that's correct
yeah
ah
you don't know
what a blog site is
and if they did
they wouldn't want
to get involved in it
ah
all these people
have a blog site
picture them
the next time
you check in
ah
there's a big pyramid
behind your TV computer
whatever that thing is
ah
a pal machine
whatever that is
there
yeah
alright
so if they've taken
over the world
well
I don't care
if they take over
the world
who cares
you still get an
ice cream cone
you still get the bus
to where you want to go
so
we don't have to
save the world
oh god
thank you
you don't have to
save the world
oh
well
that really is
a lot of pressure
huh
I was just
worrying
there seemed
like a lot of stuff
here to move
you know
the evolution
of consciousness
consciousness
then
is sort of
a collective
it's the evolution
the unfolding
of potentiality
so divinity
which
arises
emerges
the universe
hmm
and
in our dimension
here
it's evolutionary
evolutionary
so consciousness
the perfect
world
for the evolution
of consciousness
is this world
haha
agree
every second
you have to make
a choice
an option
choose this
choose that
choose the other thing
every second
so
the spirit
the spiritual
is constantly
like moving
a little this way
a little that way
you know
I always look
at the spirit
like a little
iron filing
and the one end
is positive
the other is negative
it's every time
you make a choice
the little iron filing
gets a little more
charged in this direction
now when you make
this choice
it gets more charged
in this direction
and in the infinite
field of consciousness
which is a giant
like a giant
electromagnetic
field
this little
iron filing
automatically moves
so you don't have
to worry about
God doing anything
to you
God just sits there
you do it
to you
God has always
been the big cop out
it's going to be
an angry God
who punishes you
etc
no
by your own
choice
and selection
you put yourself
in heaven
or hell
and the consequences
then are up to you
so the anthropomorphic
God
I agree
with the atheist
the anthropomorphic
God
I agree
with the atheist
by the way
I do believe
in the next
tract
we're in
so
we need
to be
of the
mass
medium
if
in
the
you
plant
but as a consequence of what you are.
It's what you are, your essence that radiates out
and lifts the sea of all of mankind.
People say, what can I do to benefit mankind?
Stay home.
Stay home. Keep out of traffic.
And purify yourself via all the spiritual tools that you have.
Instead of just talking about them and having parades about them,
be that.
Okay, we move on.
Here's the speed of the evolution of consciousness.
You see man is in a very rampant up thing.
Whatever that is. Move on.
And for those that are new, we recapitulate.
The evolution of consciousness throughout all of history.
So, we're driving, but we eventually get to some place
where we're going to go with these lectures.
The nature of the ego itself.
I want you to see that intrinsically,
the ego has to be what it is.
Because when life emerged,
back here some age too long ago to remember,
in order to survive,
animal life,
is not provided with the inner source of energy.
That's the basic conflict of mankind.
From Iraq to everything else.
Man is lacking an inner source of protoplasmic energy.
Consequently, as I always say,
the plants have chlorophyll.
They don't have to kill anybody.
They don't have to conquer anything.
All they have to do is be.
And they survive as a consequence of that which they are.
They're not capable of sin.
They're blessed in a way.
So, the animal, unfortunately,
lacks energy,
has to constantly acquire.
The ego, therefore, is acquisitive.
It has to sample everything out there.
Is it good?
Is it bad?
That which doesn't have an ego,
animals without an ego don't survive.
If you can't tell what's poison and what's food,
you don't survive to evolve.
You understand?
So, we evolve as animals,
evolve then with an acquisition system.
And this is the leading edge of the ego called the processor.
The processor is that leading edge of information,
knowingness, gatheringness.
It then organizes it as memory and intelligence.
That's the intelligent design of the universe.
Intelligent design of life.
It processes.
And it has to know.
And those who are not capable of that die.
So, the ego is then,
is considered to be the source of life.
The source of life is that capacity to,
you know, sample by either perception or essence.
And, of course, once you get to the level where we're at in evolution,
and now it becomes important to know that we're seeing perception and essence.
Because the world doesn't know the difference.
The world thinks perception is essence.
So, the evolution of consciousness,
consciousness, then, means that the formation,
the acquisitive formation,
and the idea that it is the source of life,
it's the guarantor of life.
And, therefore, we assume it is the source of life.
So, the narcissistic core of the ego is a natural,
comes out of the nature of evolution itself.
And, unfortunately, in some people,
it does not become dominated by spiritual energy.
And, it continues on,
in which conquering triumphalism becomes an end in itself.
I mean, what does this country have to conquer this country for?
Is it going to get more buses?
I mean, for what?
You know what I'm saying?
And, you see, history is just one country going in to conquer
and get control of others, you see.
Of course, nowadays, we have oil, so it makes some kind of sense, I guess.
So, that's the evolution of consciousness.
Okay.
And, we see the evolution through the animal kingdom.
The only reason I show the animal kingdom is because it demonstrates
that evolution continues on through all of mankind,
humankind, animal kind.
And, when it reaches a level of 200, it changes its nature.
It changes from violent and aggressive,
and it starts to become more benign.
Here, you see at level 200, these animals are benign.
A deer won't attack you.
I mean, most of these people won't attack you,
unless you push them around a lot.
You get a giraffe mad at you, but he doesn't want to be bothered,
so that's your fault.
So, anyway, then we get up to the dogs and the cats and the African grey,
and the African greys are a very interested parrot.
I don't know all that there is to know about a parrot.
There's something there unknown.
And, the same with the cat's purr.
And, the dog's wagging tail.
There's things we don't know about them.
And, a lot of times, we've asked at a lecture,
and we found out you weren't allowed to ask.
Weren't allowed to ask.
Yeah.
But, the bird at home will ring the phone.
Hello, I'm busy now.
I've got to go now.
Bye.
Click.
Has a phone call on both ends.
Says hello and goodbye in the meantime.
Has a conversation.
All by herself, sitting there.
I said, there's got to be something more to this that we're not seeing.
Why would this be?
It lives to be a hundred years of collecting all this information.
I don't know.
There's got to be some purpose to the animal world that we haven't discovered as yet.
I haven't discovered as yet.
Do you remember during some lectures we asked about the dog's wagging tail
and the kitty's purr,
and we got to know we couldn't go there.
So, I don't know.
There's a mystery.
All right.
Move on to the next information here.
Oh, this is just a quick review because today we're going to talk about reason versus truth.
And, of course, what we find out is that truth is different calibrations.
What's true here is not true here.
It is not true here.
One man, civilization, western civilization, is considered to be truth.
It's pretty much represented by the great books of the western world.
Okay.
Which the greatest thinkers of all time.
The greatest thinkers that have influenced all of western society.
All of western society.
And we've spoken of many of them.
And we've spoken of the downside, too.
We've talked about dialectical materialism as being really the only one that's really out of there.
And I think they made a mistake.
Engels is right at 200.
But the University of Chicago dons with this together.
I think it included Freud as well.
Freud is at 499.
He is a great thinker.
And he belongs there.
But I think they put him in Marx because of his importance in history.
Importance in history.
Yeah.
Okay.
He wanted us to look at it anyway.
We're talking today about the content, which is in here, and context, which is out here.
So you can look at context as the infinite ultimate context, which we mean by calibration level.
Beyond 1,000 is the infinite, and it goes on to infinity.
And it's experiential within the human domain up to level 1,000.
So here is the event and the situation in which it happens.
And here's the society in which you live.
And here's the field of consciousness itself.
So what you identify with then, the meaning of the content, depends on the context.
So we'll move on to the next one.
Content is linear, the ego.
It's definable, Newtonian.
It's cause and effect.
The proximate field, we'd say, would be the spiritual ego.
Current circumstances.
Quantum mechanics is the field.
And then the infinite context is spirit.
It's nonlinear.
It's knowable.
It's experiential.
So the ego and the self, the small s, is concerned and identifies with content, which is linear.
The self with a capital S, the background field out of which all knowingness arises, then is consciousness itself.
Okay.
We'll go on to the next.
So this morning we're doing a quick review.
Now, as I said this morning, this is very easy.
If you're a spiritual student, you should be able to make this jump without much difficulty.
30, 40, 50 years, you'll make it just like that.
You see, you're in a hypnotic condition attracted by form.
You watch people when they walk into the room.
If the TV's on, their attention instantly goes to the form.
See?
The new drapes are not what's happening.
The new rug is not what's happening.
What's happening is some idiot face talking there.
The person's like, oink.
You want the TV to own your head.
That's the question.
You want the TV to dominate your head.
Why?
Because the mind is attracted to form and action.
And it registers that with recognition.
Now, behind that, why is the TV interesting?
Because there's the experiencer.
The experiencer says, I don't want to experience nothing.
I want to experience something.
Better anything than nothing.
And many people will do anything rather than nothing.
It's unbelievable.
It's because they don't like doing nothing.
I'll show you how to like doing nothing.
You get to the watcher, the experiencer.
And you can move into the observer witness.
It's the observer witness that is not difficult to move into.
To realize that you're the witness of what you're experiencing.
How do you know what you're experiencing?
Because there's a witness, a watcher, an observer.
You can realize that that which is unchanging is that you're always observing whether the TV's on or not on.
If the TV's not on, then you're enjoying the sound of the TV.
Then you're enjoying the sound of the breeze.
The sound of the birds.
If the TV's on, you're listening to the sound of the TV.
But there's always the watcher witness remains the same.
It doesn't care what's on the set.
So you can move back from identifying with the content to that which is the observer witness.
The observer witness.
How can you find that?
Because.
If you meditate or look within yourself, you'll see that observing and witnessing is happening all the time without your permission.
It doesn't ask.
It just is your own condition.
The condition of being alive as a human being is to be the witness observer.
That's the only commonality.
People experience what they witness and observe differently.
But what they have in common is that they're all observing and witnessing.
That's the commonality of all humans.
As you're witnessing and observing and experiencing.
We'll figure out later how to get behind this.
So the observer witness then.
You become aware the observer and the witness are happening of their own.
Becoming aware.
As you sit in the audience right now, the being aware is happening of your own.
Because it's a given.
It's part of consciousness itself.
That which you are then is the consciousness itself out of which the observer witness arises.
Are we supposed to take a break this morning from that?
Yes.
In five minutes.
Oh, see that?
What I need to know arises.
Thank you, Lord.
Holy Spirit keeps track of time.
Does all kinds of things for you.
As you get older, you don't remember things as well as you used to when you were younger.
If it wasn't for the Holy Spirit, I wouldn't know where I can put my shoes.
You know what I'm saying?
It's like a constant miracle.
I forget where I just laid something down.
I say, let's see, okay, uh-huh, uh-huh, no.
I can't remember where the hell I laid it down because I'm not tracking things linearly.
So I go to the nonlinear source of all knowingness and I say, Holy Spirit, where did I leave the thing?
And then I walk right over and there it is.
It's just amazing.
I couldn't go an hour without the Holy Spirit.
I'd never survive.
So.
You become more and more reliant and realize that it is the light of consciousness out of which your knowingness and your survival.
And the nature, the divine nature of that reveals itself as you remove the obstacles.
So we'll move on to the next where I want to get all of it done this morning.
This I'm going to just flash on quickly is very profound.
As I said, there's really two civilizations sharing this planet.
Those above 200 and those below 200.
Take my word for it.
There are two different civilizations.
And don't, by apology, fool yourself that they're the same as you are.
They are not.
They are not the same as you are.
So Pollyanna will not get you to the truth.
You know, apologies for that which is not like yourself.
Why are they not like you?
Because their brains work differently.
Politics isn't going to change that, is it?
You're all the holy selling politics.
Oh.
Hand-wringing and all this.
Yeah.
Below 200, you see how their brain processes.
It's the animal instinctual brain.
Dominance.
Tribalism.
Kill.
Dominate.
Revenge.
Get even.
Rip.
Tear.
Kill.
Terrorism.
That's called terrorism.
It's an animal instinct.
It comes out of the left brain.
It dominates consciousness.
It dominates consciousness level below 200.
Consciousness level 200 may be trained socially not to act it out.
But it thinks that way.
It thinks, I'd like to kill the son of a bitch.
Doesn't it?
You know.
It's in yourself.
Anybody here not wanting to kill that SOB?
Yeah.
I'll tell you what.
You can't become spiritually evolved if you haven't wanted to kill somebody.
You know why?
Because you have to care enough about life to get there.
You got to care enough about life to get there.
Don't you?
So congratulate yourself that you care enough about life to be indignant.
Otherwise, you'd be an apathetic whop.
A wet rag.
No.
You got to care enough about it to give a damn.
Then you can evolve to the point where you don't give a damn.
At that point, you turn the world over to God.
And you realize the world is perfect.
You just didn't notice it.
All right.
Over 200.
We're going to finish this before our break.
Over 200, this side of the brain shoots in.
Instead of putting out adrenaline, it puts out endorphins.
It puts out, what is it, oxytocin, the maternal hormone.
Without that hormone, people are not sociable.
The fact that we're sociable and nice is due to the fact the brain produces a hormone that's
characteristic of pregnancy, oxytocin.
All right.
So the other culture, then, is operating in a different brain.
These people have a different brain.
You people have a different brain than the other people.
You think you understand them, but you don't.
You don't understand them.
I kid you so.
To screw you out of a buck is a sign of honor in that society.
To not screw you out of a buck is a sign of shame.
You came home.
How much did you get for the rug?
$50.
You get a beating.
It's only worth $25.
You should have gotten $100.
To not be dishonest.
You understand?
It's a 180.
So you can see the difficulty the world has.
Because these people are operating on a different side of the brain.
This is what it's willing to die for on the top there, conquering other people, getting
even.
It's what they're willing to die for.
It's only 200 and up now.
And that's because the Kundalini energy rises and shifts the brain dominance.
The brain now, instead of putting out emergency emotion hormones, kill or be killed, puts
out benevolence.
The hormones of benevolence.
Therefore, to understand the people, you have to understand that they're operating with
a different brain than you are.
How can you make them wrong?
They're not the same as you.
You can only make them wrong if they were the same as you.
They don't have an option.
They see the world differently, experience it, value it differently, and therefore they're
doing what they should be doing as a good animal.
If you're a good animal, you're supposed to be killing the other wolves to become the
alpha male.
I was a son of a bitch as an alpha male.
Oh yeah.
Went for the jugular.
Bang.
I was fast too.
And when I was a fly weight, a mosquito weight.
I was a living little terror.
A 90 pounds of .
I learned if he hits you once, you're going to be out.
So I'd stay away from getting hit.
And I just got in there so fast they didn't know what happened.
And they had a bloody nose and they went home crying to their mother and I won.
When I did get hit, I would get knocked out every time.
So I quit getting hit.
Yeah, it's time for a break.
We're going to take a what?
15 minute break?
All right.
No laughing during that.
No laughing.
I didn't even have a sip of Diet Pepsi.
I did that whole spiel without the Diet Pepsi.
Ta-da.