So
give
The trouble with focusing on the beauty
of everything
>> is that you get stoned out all the time.
It's very hard to get past these
flowers. I purposely avoid looking at
these flowers
cuz they are so it makes you break out
in tears. You know
how beautiful music makes you break out
in tears.
You can't prove the aesthetic
exquisite joy
that you experience out of beauty.
It's not within the linear domain.
Yeah. Where was I?
I got talking about beauty and you see
it happens. I'm not going to look at
beauty anymore.
It has a positive effect, you know, on
your neuronal connections.
The uh the best uh preparation for your
children is a spiritual religious uh
experiences as a child and u aesthetic
beauty, beautiful music
uh an appreciation for beauty.
Yeah. So
I myself that was part of my religious
upbringing was
a constant exposure to beauty. Both my
parents were musicians
and uh I was a member of the art
institute and I played violin and piano
and I was a soloist, a boy soprano
and I remember being in a Greek
cathedral
and I sang the uh obligato
over Angelus
in this soprano voice. I had a high
soprano.
So there you are in the Greek cathedral,
stained glass windows.
Sunlight is coming in and lighting up
the clouds of incense.
A full choir and a full orchestra at
this cathedral.
And here this voice
came through me. I had the soprano
obligato very high obligato above the
whole choir and orchestra
and a presence sang
it was a presence
that sang
that wipes you out. You shouldn't think
about such things when you're giving a
lecture.
Go back to the next slide.
We're going to uh we're going to put
together a book of slides. We we now
have about 110 of them. Every time we
give a new lecture in Sedona, it creates
a whole new slide. Next one we're going
to do on the miraculous and uh we'll
talk about
the miraculous.
Well, this looks too academic. She says
that's too complicated. We'll go to the
next one.
the the basic people people the basic
just being decent decent human being. Uh
what do you have to do to evolve
spiritually?
Uh I say the best thing to do is to be
kind to all of life and all of its
expressions.
Be kind to all.
Uh and a pervasive goodwill towards
yourself and towards life. So goodwill
means towards your own life towards your
own life goodwill and appreciation for
its beauty and to see your own life as a
gift
that leads to a a style of life which is
contemplative.
Meditation uh has its place and I spent
many years medit meditating on a regular
basis.
Contemplation
is putting into practice spiritual
principles
to such an extent that you eventually
become that. It's not something you do.
It's what you are. What you are is
loving and gentle and supportive and
exquisite.
That's why every we all cried this
morning. Everybody I was greeting. I
just went into a state of joy. They went
into a state of joy. We both are crying.
It's hard to get through a whole crowd.
You know what I'm saying?
Everyone was just being the reality of
their essence. That's all they were
doing. You know, just being what they
actually are. And uh safety is when you
can just be uh what you really are.
So these things may not be
acceptable in the modern post soal
postmodern world.
But these are these were what I grew up
in in uh middle America and Wisconsin
and 1930s around in there 20s.
Uh I thought everybody was like this.
To me there was only two kinds of people
in the world. There were people who were
decent, honest, pleasant, respectable,
etc.
Uh, and then there were gangsters,
Machine Gun Kelly and Babyface Nelson
and and the mafia guys in Chicago,
liquor guys, I forget what their name,
Scarface.
And then there were then then there was
the people that that everybody was
dependable. They tried to get there on
time. They tried to be responsible for
their own emotions and not pour them all
over you. Everybody tried to be neat and
fair and ethical and and uh humane
towards the animals and everybody else.
Everybody was gracious towards uh
everybody else. Everybody tried to be
modest, diplomatic, polite, firm and
nice.
Uh
but what you can see when we calibrated
the level of consciousness of mankind
what what what I consider to be the norm
is frankly the exception.
Uh being sold to the earth is now sort
of I guess exceptional to be easygoing
to let people off the hook. I know you
got them on the hook, so why not let
them off the hook? You know, why not let
people off the hook and forgive them
because
uh people just don't know any better.
All right, so let's move on.
Um this is the to clarify what the
what's going on in mind. Your mind is
99% silent.
99% of your mind is silent. 1% is what
you're listening to.
If you look underneath thought, you'll
see that underneath the thinkingness,
which is the noise going on in your
mind, there is an infinite stillness, an
infinite profound stillness and silence.
That's 99% of your mind is silent. So
instead of bemoning the fact that you
can't seem to get your mind to stop
thinking,
what I advise people to do is stop
trying to don't try to get your mind to
stop. Instead, look beneath the mind and
you'll see that beneath the mind is an
infinite field of silence.
If it were not for the infinite field of
silence, you wouldn't know what you were
thinking.
The television set is blank. If it
wasn't when you turn it on, it goes it
lights up.
If it So, if it wasn't for the field,
you wouldn't know what you're seeing on
the set. So, your mind is like
99% silent.
It's like the noise. It's like walking
through the woods.
The woods is actually silent. And the
fact that you hear a bird, the reason
you hear the bird is be not because of
the song of the bird, but because of the
silence. If it weren't for the silence,
you couldn't hear the bird. Is that
correct? It went for the fact that your
mind is intrinsically silent, you
wouldn't know what you're thinking. So
look and become at one with the silence,
the infinite nonlinear silence. And
that's part of be your life becoming a
prayer.
You see, the mind is always busy. Look
what it's doing here all the time. All
you have to do is turn on everybody's
turn on any night's television.
There's a contest. There's a big contest
amongst the victims. Who can be the
biggest victim? There's two contests.
One is to be the world's biggest victim
and get the greatest sympathy.
And the other is to be right.
people will do anything to be right.
Okay, so this is what the mind is doing
to keep itself busy. And uh we said what
keeps a thing going is the juice you're
getting off of it. So the way to
disconnect the mind is to look and see
what kind of juice you're getting out of
these thoughts, memories, etc. You don't
have to give up the thoughts. You have
to only give up the juice that you're
getting off of it. The same as hate or
any other thing that you don't want to
have. You say, "Am I willing?" You don't
have to be willing to give up hatred.
That's not possible.
Hatred pays off so good in our current
world. You can't live without it.
But we willing to give up the juice that
you're getting out of the hatred. So
once you give up the juice of
resentment, self-pity, guilt, you
realize how narcissistic guilt is
walling around. Oh me, oh bad me, why
I'm so awful. Oh, sackloth and ashes. Oh
penance.
I mean, how narcissistic it is. Don't
you see? You're not doing this for God.
Oh, penance for God, sackcloth, and
ashes. Oh, woe is me.
Now, why would God be happier that
unless he was a sadist of some kind,
pervert or something,
gets a kick out of your suffering.
All right. So, you see, this is what the
mind does. It moralizes. And you see the
great contest in today's world is for
moral.
It's a moral contest. If you read the
evening news, the world is engaged in an
endless of who's got the moral high
ground.
Who's got the moral high ground? The
clash of civilizations is who's got the
moral high ground. The clash of
politics, Democrats, Republicans, all
the rest of them, is who's got the moral
high ground.
It's an endless contest for the moral
high ground because the moral high
ground now gives you permission to do
whatever the moral you think the moral
high ground justifies your doing.
Killing uh infidels or whatever.
Probably a good idea to kill all
infidels. Come think of it. I never
thought of it.
It's smart idea.
Keeps you busy for a long time. killing
all the the the infidels is going to
keep busy for quite a few centuries.
There was a lot of infidels running
around this planet
all over the place. Every rock is hiding
an infidel behind it. Okay, so we're
going
functions of the mind. You see this is
the mind the energy fields. Those of you
are you know familiar with the atheric
energy fields and chakras etc. Uh
there's a concentration at lower mind.
lower mind calibrates about 190, 160,
165.
Uh this is the world of relativism.
Relativism calibrates beyond below 200.
Relativism does not appeal to people who
calibrate higher over 200, especially
275.
It also doesn't appeal to people who
have a reasonably good IQ. So higher
mind looks at abstraction. See, it looks
at abstractions. It looks at
generalities. So it it's it's able to
stratify and go from just the linear uh
pedestrian to the inference, the
abstract inference.
Okay.
So we'll move on.
Uh this is lower mind. This is this kind
of thinking is what characterizes the
media.
uh competition and greed and force and
exploiting things insensitivity etc.
constantly wanting something. Higher
mind sees things not in terms of what
their cash is but their true value. It
sees potential. So higher mind is more
into aesthetics. It's more intuitive.
It's actually more intelligent and it
looks to serve life. It looks to serve
life. Looks to serve life. when I was in
practice. My obligation in my view was
from me to the patient
and often I would think well this this
is not being accepted by general
medicine and did I know it may help this
patient and I remember making the
decision am I answerable to God for my
popularity with my colleagues or am I
answerable to God for having extended
everything I can that will help this
patient. So I've dedicated my life to uh
the healing of the patient
rather than popularity with my
colleagues who might not approve of uh
what techniques I think might help them.
And of course patients recovered by the
thousands with unapproved techniques.
They're still poo pooing these things
that people recover by. I don't know
what's the matter.
people koo poo faith, you know, faith.
And I say, that's a that's sort of hard
to do, isn't it? There are there are
there there are millions of of recovered
alcoholics and people of all kinds of
diseases and they did it purely on faith
and you're ridiculing faith. I mean, you
got to tell me it has no power. These
people who are hopeless and gone and wet
brains and finally they're walking
around. So, all right. So higher mind
then is more intelligent and it looks to
serve life. It tends to be merciful. It
may get angry and then it finally says,
"Oh, but they don't know any better."
But they don't know any better. So I
can't really hate them. I can't really
put them down forever. I have to realize
the limitations of the human condition.
So we'll go to the next one. The
limitations of the human condition.
uh for those of you that there's a
correlation you see we using
consciousness calibration etc
um
using
the things I've taught you can be a
rational human being and still become
spiritually evolved and quite you can
even become enlightened and still be
scientific
why because there really isn't any
problem there are different paradigms
altogether.
The thing I like about quantum mechanics
is that it provides us for the first
time with a crossover
via the Heisenberg principle between the
two paradigms. You see that the 400s are
the paradigm of science and reason and
logic. Last week's Time magazine said
God versus science. God versus science.
That's just what I'm writing a book
about right now. God versus science. So,
Time Moses magazine all seems to go go
along with what I'm writing. I don't
know how they know what I'm doing.
You you can't have God versus science
because they're two different paradigms.
Science is in the in the 400s and
spiritual reality is 500 and up. So, you
can't have a clash because they're
different paradigms. They're different
dimensions. They're different altitudes.
So the Heisenberg principle I I was
interested because
it demonstrates the power of intention
and when we talked about the fact that
things are not hap don't don't happen
virtue by virtue of causality
they happen by virtue of the emergence
of a potentiality into an actuality
when conditions are appropriate and one
of those conditions is intention. So
intention is nonlinear. It's the few in
which a thing happens. I noticed, you
know, I had a lot of psychiatrists work
for me over the years and I noticed some
of them always had very good results and
other people never did. And I find the
ones that never did were very, very
scientific.
They didn't believe in hypoglycemia and
sugar-free diets. They poo pooed all
that. You see, and there may be no
scientific proof. There's probably a lot
of scientific disproof in fact of the
fact that uh functional hypoglycemia
causes depression, anxiety, anxiety
attacks, phobias, and potentiates
addiction.
So although science poo poos it and in
fact science did poo poo it and somebody
I knew very well died of it and uh he
was doing very well off sugar and then
he went to see a well-known doctor in
New York City who pooed it and said
that's not scientific.
Uh so he went back to eating sugar and
he was dead in a matter of months
because uh he would go into hypoglycemic
episodes and then he would get drunk and
uh he was dead at a relatively young age
in his late 40s. Um, so I saw the I used
to I could tell by the phone call by the
time I get off the phone I know what's
wrong with this patient already already
got a whole sense of the whole thing
what's going to be and I say before I
see you next time I want you to stop
eating sugary sweets
and if you don't I'm going to charge you
double. So
you know probably a third of the time
when I saw a patient they said I don't
know doc all those anxiety attacks went
away and I said you got functional
hypoglycemia
don't read any scientific papers on it
just don't eat sugar and sweets you know
oh golly so now many of the therapists
had very high recovery rates and others
did not uh It's not only using
non-traditional methods but intention.
So what what the what this shows the
Heisenberg principle is that a
propensity becomes an actuality
when it's energized by intention. So
spiritual work then is energized in the
whole contextual field of intention. If
your intention is to serve God, to reach
truth, to reach enlightenment,
um to be unconditionally loving towards
all of life, you have made a commitment
that is enormously powerful. And this
intention then begins to contextualize
your life.
Your life becomes different than it
would have been. And by contextualizing
it that way, your life does become a
prayer. your life does become a prayer.
So intention then is extremely powerful
and you can be very very spiritual and
very scientific. And people say you're
not praying praying and going all for
all that faith and God stuff are you?
And I said nope I'm just practicing the
Heisener principle.
I'm just practicing the high heenberg
principle by which the direct process
collap collapses the wave function.
And they say, "Oh, as long as you're not
praying, you're okay."
Thought you were praying there for a
minute. No, I just closed my eyes. I had
something in my eyes
cuz you don't want to appear
unscientific. So, science is the new
god. So Time magazine was very
interesting. It isn't science. It's the
godification of science that's the
error. And the great the f famous
atheists of our day,
the best known all calibrate about 190.
They all calibrate at 190. Uh even
though they're professors, in fact it's
getting to be characteristic of
professors to calibrate at 190.
Um so Henry Snap was on the internet and
I think he has a very beautiful
correlation of science and the impact of
the power of intention. Yes. And a
friend of mine uh wrote a book you know
the power of intention. So now we'll go
on to the next one.
Um in there's two different paradigms.
the Newtonian paradigm of causality.
That's what the world believes that
everything that causes something else
like an endless series of billard bolts.
Now that we're more sophisticated, we
realize from quantum mechanics the
things really have the potentiality to
go a variety of ways and the intention
that you apply to it now begins to
determine.
So intention itself brings about the
collapse of the wave function. The
collapse of the wave function and um so
emergence you see this is the field out
of which emergence is aligning. Uh
possibility becomes an actuality. And
when we get to talk more about the
miraculous, you'll see that the the
power of the spiritual field tends to
potentiate
that in actuality out of a potentiality
if there's karmic permission. Also,
people forget the karmic propensity that
a person may recover from a grave
illness. If the karmic propensity
is there, it may be of greater karmic
benefit to not recover. And people never
think of that. Although the last pope
did bring that to our mind, did he not
that suffering in itself may be serving
some greater purpose which you may or
may not be aware of as a person. It
doesn't mean that one should glory in
suffering. but to accept that perhaps
you have some karmic debt to pay off.
And
uh when we get to that program on the
miraculous,
I've recounted some of them. I remember
from previous lifetime in the middle of
an agony remembering exactly very
precisely in fact exactly who it was
that I did what to
and I was experiencing it back back out
very very specific yeah okay so we'll go
on
um I wanted to show the difference
between truth and falsehood Um
this is this is a way of uh truth does
not have an there is no opposite to
truth. U
it's only a language that says things
are the opposite. Uh
truth is either present or not present.
If it is not present we call it false.
But falsity is not the opposite of
truth. It's the absence of truth. It is
the absence of truth, not the opposite
of truth. Huh? Just as there's light and
darkness,
the light is either on or it's off. Huh?
So darkness is not the abs. Darkness is
not the opposite of life. It is the
absence of life.
Okay. Move on.
Spiritual practices. People are
interested in what is pragmatically
and calibrating the energy levels you
know gives us an interesting we did a
book called truth versus false so which
we calibrated I don't know thousands of
things and of greatest interest to most
of us was the spiritual ones uh
the lord's prayer calibrates 60 650
the sound
is one of the names of God calibrates at
740.
On the other hand, a
pronounced this way is only 210.
That's due to a mistransation in Sicha
Dana Sacha Dandanda's
book on the apherisms and jelly.
Uh so a is only 210 is 7:40
shay 630 chandi shi shi
manip
gregorian chants which I grew up with in
the great cathedrals of Europe.
The great cathedrals of Europe. You can
hear the Gorian chant in the background.
Even when there's no one there,
been going on for a thousand years. If
you can't hear it,
it's still there.
Uh, Japa 5:15, the Jesus prayer, saying
the rosary, the pilgrim pilgrimage to
Mecca,
curtain, which is a yogic chant, and the
12 steps of a a 540. It's pretty hard to
beat the 12 steps. Uh, you don't you can
just remove the word alcohol and put in
whatever it is you're having a problem
with because 540 is a pretty powerful
energy.
The golden rule, which is what we all
grew up with in traditional Midwest
America, is 405.
TM gets sort of highly overrated. It's
295. It's a very good thing. The prayer
of JZ, walking the labyrinth and Chart
Cathedral, it's rather shocking to go
into the Greek cathedrals of Europe.
Rather shocking actually. I've been
there a number of different decades. And
the last time we went and we
recalibrated the cathedrals here, you
would walk into a place of such immense
stunning beauty. You look at a pulpit
and a man spent one entire lifetime, his
whole life just carving this one little
uh pulpit. So you look at a cathedral.
It took a thousand years to build this
cathedral and hundreds of no centuries
and centuries to build the great
cathedral.
They calibrate uh 700 and up the great
cathedrals including the one in
Washington DC
uh the cathedral in Washington DC or the
one in New York Cathedral of St. John
the Divine uh incredible beauty. So you
walk into this stunning Gothic
cathedral, some of the most beautiful
structures that man has ever made that
calibrated in the 700s. And in today's
world they're all on their cell phone.
We couldn't believe our ears. Here you
are in front of this breathtaking beauty
and everybody. Hello Emmer. Did you call
Susan yet about someone?
I don't know why they let them do that.
I took a certain umbrage at the
desecration of the of the beautiful
space. But walking the labyrinth in
Shark Cathedral is 503
genuleen. uh uh so all forms symbolic of
uh that are symbolic these to do this in
itself it's 540
so the charm of a country like Korea
which I have adored is everybody in
Korea
every hotel bellman everybody greets you
thusly
it's very enchanting to live in a world
in which everybody is
So it acts as a devotional act. People
say that's ridiculous turning prayer
wheels. It's the intention behind
turning the prayer wheels. It calibrates
at 540. The burning of incense when it's
done devotionally. So anything done
devotionally is already 540 because of
the intention. No matter what you're
doing, even if it's playing jacks, if
you think playing jacks is a way of
worshiping God, it already calibrates at
540. So you see the world the province
of faith and devotion etc. is not a
place for the skeptic because the
skeptic can only see the literal
pedestrian
u uh image of a thing and they don't get
the essence the essence of
all these the whailing wall bathing in
the Ganges the prayer of St. Francis of
Aisi. Bathing in the Ganges. 540. Yeah.
Bathing in the Ganges. The Ganges River.
Let's calibrate the Ganges River. The
Ganges River. Oh, we have permission to
calibrate that. Here is over 540.
The dirtiest, yuckiest river in the
world. The garbage of 30, 40 cities
dumps into the Ganges. dead bodies go
bumping by
and it calibrates that high. How could
it calibrate higher than most of the
places in America when it's full of
garbage and dead floating bodies? Huh? I
can remember being in China and uh
forget what yellow it was, the Yangy
River, I think it was. And I was in the
bottom of the ship and I can hear this
boom
boom against the bulkhead. Boom. And I
go up and I look over the side. It's
just a dead body bumping against bump.
All kinds of feces, dead body, dead dog,
garbage
floating down.
So how can a river calibrated 540? It's
because of its sanctification over the
many centuries. The Ganges River uh
itself is indeed a holy river. So you
see the linear
secularist would say it's full of
garbage and disgusting
but thousands and thousands for
centuries after centuries have
sanctified the Ganges River and the
Ganges is truly a holy river.
Okay, I thought that's quite
interesting.
I wouldn't suggest drinking any of it.
We go we go to the next
I never drank any of it. Although I did
swallow some water in the Yang Sea or
some place like that. Uh that's another
place I discover. I experienced a
miracle, right? I almost got killed and
uh the miraculous scourge and I uh
instead of being squashed to death, I I
was dropped by this heavy current,
swept off this buoy.
My body almost snapped in half with a
steel cable that shot across the top of
the buoy. Almost cut my head off and I
fell into the water. And in between
these ships, they were smashing against
each other and I hit it right for them.
My body just went like this. I'm on the
prowl of one of the ships and there I
was. 6 in this way, you're dead. Six
inches this way, you're dead. And the
current took me right there into the
prowl of the ship. There it was.
People say that's accidental. Oh no.
Contemplation
and meditation then how does one's
consciousness evolve
is first you are focusing on form it's
registering
you begin to recognize it because there
is a watcher experiencer going on you
can withdraw on your meditation and your
contemplation and it's relatively quick
and easy I like could tell people things
that are relatively quick and easy. By
intention, you can real begin to realize
there's no person going on that that's a
vanity. That's what what's going on is
observing and witnessing.
It doesn't take any great area edition
spiritual edition in any kind of
contemplation or meditation
to withdraw from thinking I am that to
realizing that how do I know anything?
It's be because of witnessing observing
is witnessing and observing something.
There is a you doing
let's see you stop it. It's a you doing
it. You could stop it, couldn't you? No,
you can't stop witnessing and observing.
Everybody in this room right now is
witnessing and observing the phenomena
of this this meeting.
And I want you to observe and be aware
that it's happening of its own.
It's happening spontaneously,
autonomously as a consequence of that
which it is. Witnessing, observing is
not something you do
within a you witnessing or observing.
Witnessing and observing is happening of
its own.
You don't think shall I witness and
observe and experience what's happening
today?
you can't do it. So you begin to realize
that instead of a personal you that
there's a phenomena occurring just like
vision.
See there is no eye that is seeing it.
Vision is seeing it. That's autonomous.
Okay.
You can draw back from identifying with
the content of consciousness
and become aware that become aware
that observing and witnessing is going
on of its own.
It's then not too big a step once you
realize that observing and witnessing is
a autonomous spontaneous phenomena.
There's no personal you doing this.
What is observing and witnessing? The
next step is it's obvious that it's
consciousness itself.
The realization that I am not the
content. I am the observer witness. I am
not the observer witness. What makes you
think that you're the observer witness?
How do you even know you're observing or
witnessing? It is because of the light
of consciousness itself. You get closer
and closer to the self, the capital S
self that the phenomena is happening of
its own.
There's nobody, there's no person
speaking today.
The speakingness is happening of its
own. It's an autonomous spontaneous
emergence of the potentiality of the
ferusha, the self,
the non-personality.
There's no expectation of what it's
going to say. I have no idea what he's
going to say till I hear it. I heard the
same time you hear it. It's happening of
its own. I have nothing to do with it.
Thank goodness.
If it's happening spontaneously
autonomously of its own,
that has different karmic implications,
doesn't it?
The it is the light of consciousness,
consciousness radiating forth as your
existence.
How do you know that you exist? Exist.
Do you know that below consciousness
level 200, the entity is not aware that
it exists? It exists,
but it does not know that it is. It does
not know that it is. It is, but it does
not know that it is.
It's only over 200 that you know that
you are.
Now, to a crowd like this, that would
sound ridiculous.
Most of the people on the planet are but
frankly do not experience
that they exist.
Because of this they have no concern for
others. What characterizes level from
200 up? You project on to the others the
same thing that you're aware of in
yourself that you exist and therefore
their value is the same as yours because
of the same premise that they exist.
below 200 although they see people
they are not aware that they they exist
as such. Therefore other people have no
value
to a dictator who calibrates all all the
world dictators calibrated 90 both in
the past and currently some even more.
It doesn't even cause a twinge
to kill 300,000 people.
Doesn't even cause a twinge.
Let's see if that's so
information. What I just said is so old.
Isn't that shocking? That is so
shocking. That's why America can't get
it. That's why you can't get it. That's
why the citizens can't get it.
It's not comprehensible
that you could kill 300,000 people or
half a million or and chairman M's
starving China 10 million
and not feel a twit about it.
Can you kill 10 million people and not
even feel anything about it?
Yes.
The implications of that are profound.
You see,
is it not
the expectation that restraint that the
enemy will be restrained by common
decency
is a laughable absurdity.
They have no common decency
by which they will be restrained.
Why? Because below 200 although you
exist, you don't really experience your
own existence.
You live the life like an animal, the
animal is, but it does not know that it
is.
If I ask my cat,
"Are you a cat?"
Cat says, "What does that mean to be a
cat?"
I said, "Well, I'll read it to you." I
get down the encyclopedia.
Cat. I flip through it. I read to the
kitty what it means to be a cat.
He says, "That's interesting, but it
hasn't got anything to do with me."
I says, "Why not?"
He says, "I'm not any of those things."
I said, "Well, then then who are you?"
And the kid said, "I'm just me.
I'm just me.
Oh my.
So consciousness then stops identifying
with the content of consciousness with
the linear.
It transcends any illusions of
causality.
begins to experience and witness that
all things are happening autonomously of
their own. The creation is an ongoing
unfoldment.
Instead of thinking in terms of
causality, see that all things are
unfolding.
What's happening is happening as a
consequence of emergence, not a
causality.
Things are happening as a consequence of
emergence, not causality.
You can make a big jump in spiritual
advancement. The minute you begin to see
that things are happening because that
is their potentiality
and if the surrounding manifes
are appropriate, it will.
So as from consciousness levels 540 and
up, the miraculous becomes
almost continuous. Except 570, the
unfolding of everything is miraculous.
You witness the the miracle. What you're
witnessing is the miracle of creation as
it unfolds in one detail after another.
You say there's no parking place there
in front of
uh the opera house, Lincoln Center.
And you leave from home and you get
there right next to Lincoln Center, the
very best, super best parking space
available. You bring your car up, the
car moves out, and you pull in and it's
like, yeah, it's always that way.
It's always that way. It's a continuous
unfoldment of the miraculous.
Uh, and you realize that all of life is
the miracle of creation itself.
Creation is continuous and unfolding.
To the
lower mind, it looks like causality. To
the higher mind, it realizes there's an
infinite number of of potentialities,
you see. And which one will manifest?
Why did it do that?
Why did you do that?
I don't know. I wasn't thinking of doing
that.
Why did it happen?
It just suddenly
goes nuts.
What makes it do that?
All is spontaneously emergent. There is
that emergence, that potentiality to try
to be. That's what you're trying to
explain
to be it.
I am it.
Just like the cat,
we are it. Why search for that which you
are?
This kitty, why should I search for
being a cat when I am a cat?
Oh, think of all the headaches that
saves you. We'll move on.
What do we got?
>> Three minutes.
>> Three minutes to what?
>> To lunch.
>> To lunch. My god. Where'd the morning
go? Somebody has stolen the morning.
Come back here.
Somebody has stolen the drink. Good God.
Oh, the implications are serious.
If seriousness, if you can take being
serious seriously, it's serious.
If it's comical, being serious is
comical like everything else is comical.
The impact the impact for the everyday
reality of mankind is the consciousness
level below 200 has a different brain
physiology than 200 and up. So all the
sophistry and the duturism isn't going
to change this basic fact. Below 200
people are run by the animal
instinctual.
And from 200 and up is the first time
that a the energy of spiritual energy
condundalini energy comes in.
Condundalini energy begins to flow
around calibrated level 200.
And what happens is it shifts the brain
physiology.
Below 200
is being run by animal instinct. Most of
society today and throughout history is
animal instinct. Is it not? You don't
know if you're talking about a country
or a wolf pack.
They want to invade the country next
door. That's what wolfpacks do. The
dominant male has to, you know, got to
have the dominant alpha male. And why is
he invading the country next door? Well,
he wants cuz he's always wanting power
and space. And therefore, he is just an
animal, is he not?
He's nothing more than an animal. He's a
furless animal. It doesn't even have fur
for God's sake.
That was the animal without fur. Imagine
getting yourself born on this planet
without fur. I mean, if that isn't dumb
to begin with.
below 200's the input. You see something
out there, it is has a fast
fast uh relay to the phalamus
and very fast to the emotional center of
the amygdala and very slowly does it go
through the pre prefrontal cortex.
So the person says screw you godamn it.
Dennis Cortex says murder is against the
law.
Well, now what am I going to do?
Well, if you're capable of murder,
you're also capable of lying. So, you
just make up a good story.
The memory of this event is stored in
your hippocampus.
All right? So, that's the animal world.
That's consciousness level below 200.
And
the man's history, the reason he's been
in war almost constantly is because he
is an animal.
The preffrontal to what is the
prefrontal cortex do here? He has a
prefrontal cortex.
He learns to be a clever animal.
Instead of getting you with fangs and
TE's, he gets an atomic bomb. He gets
dynamite,
roadside bombs.
So the prefrontal cortex intelligence is
now put at the service of the animal.
You had a dangerous animal before. You
got a really dangerous animal. Now you
give a dangerous animal calibrates at
190 or 90. Some of these world dictators
playing around with atomic energy.
Calibrates at 90.
He calibrates at 90. This is how he
thinks. This is how he feels. And now
you give him atomic energy. Now you have
an animal that lives by the tooth and
the nail. And you gave him atomic
energy. Prefrontal cortex. Now, so you
learn to be a smarter animal. Above
level 200, you see the brain dominance.
So below 200 left brain dominance linear
releases adrenaline alarm resistance
thymus stress disrupts the acupuncture
meridian leads to diseases you know
track to emotions twice as fast as
through the brain prefrontal cortex
at level 200 the atheric energy comes
starts to rise and you shift from left
brain to right brain now the input is
fast to the cerebral cortex and
importantly to the athetheric brain and
very fast. So right above right brain
dominance is nonlinear. It puts forth
endorphins instead of adrenaline,
positive emotions. It supports the
thymus gland, increases immunity and
healing, balances the acupuncture
system, and you get a positive
kinesiologic response.
two different animals below 200 and
above 200. And to not know the
difference will cost you your life.
Yeah, you don't know the difference in
the jungle. Above 200 then, and the last
thing that we want to say and then we'll
break for lunch is as the condolini
energy rises to cons at consciousness
level 200, you have the formation of the
atheric brain.
The athetheric brain.
What is the atheric brain? The
athetheric brain is an energy field. An
energy field which doesn't happen until
you get to level 200. Below 200,
everybody has a group etheric energy, an
attractor field. All animals below 200
do not have individual karma. They have
a group karma.
Same with humans. 200 and up, you now
have an atheric body. You have
individual personal karma.
The atheric brain then is an energy
field.
How many people here have been out of
body? Out of body. Okay. You know, when
you're out of body, you think just as
well as when you're in body. So if it
Why are you doing that? Because the
atheric brain is energy and not
physical. So how does thinkingness come
about? Because it comes about the energy
field of the atheric brain by induction
activates the neurons.
The neurons in the physical brain are
activated by induction. Just like
magnetism induces electricity in a word
not by cause but by induction. Therefore
the field spiritual intention and
commitment then activates the atheric
body.
condundolini begins to rise. You see and
experience the world differently than
people do below 200. You say, "How can
soand so think that or do that?" It's
because that is how the world is
experienced and how it looks to them.
How can they kill innocent people
because that's the way it looks to them.
What to you would be abhorren abhorrent
uh to them is appealing. Mhm. Uh,
well, golly, that's enough to think
about for quite a few years. Come to
think of it, if I get all that digested
before lunch, it's going to be
something. So, we're going to convene
again at what time?
>> 2:00.
>> 2:00. We're going to convene again at
2:00 California time.
There's so much I want to say to them.
It's so little time.
>> I know
>> we have quite a few people that have
come from out of the country to see us
today. Um, if you could stand up so we
could acknowledge you. Some of you are
from Ethiopia,
Scotland,
England.
Thank you. Thank you so much for coming
such a long distance.
>> John, are you hearing Dr. Hawkins?
>> Are you ready, Doc?
>> Yes, indeed.
>> Okay. Did you want to talk a little bit
or did you
>> Uh, no. I set it up this morning.
>> All right.
I'm obsessed and compulsive. I have to
feel satisfied that I've said all the
things that are important to have said.
>> I have a wall up of books here.
>> Is this handwriting? I can't see
anything.
>> It's a brand new pen.
>> Oh my gracious me.
>> Is that writing? Can you see? Yes. Okay.
Hello.
>> Hi. Hi, Susan.
>> Hi.
>> May I
>> Glorian Excelsio?
>> My question is really short, so I would
like to make a quick announcement. Um,
I've started a grassroots website for
people who are dedicated to
enlightenment and facilitated by your
work. It's called uh
veraritossnetwork.com.
All the services will always be free to
the students who log on. Okay. My
question
my question is
in 12step programs
they have the idea of a sponsorship.
>> Yes.
I have selected you as my teacher or it
was selected for me for you to be my
teacher.
Will do I have your sponsorship and your
blessings?
>> I don't get the question.
>> He wants you to be a sponsor.
>> Do you have a sponsor?
>> I I have no vice.
I I have no Well, at least that I that I
can speak of. Okay. That I can speak of
publicly.
But throughout all my future obstacles,
will you sponsor me?
>> The work itself sponsors you. The truth
of the work sponsors you. You don't need
a personal personal person.
You need the truth of the teachings.
That's the sponsor. The sponsor is the
truth.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
Get a quick picture.
>> Susan,
>> you know what they say about telling the
truth.
After you've told the truth, quickly
leave town.
>> You tell the truth and leave town.
>> Quickly leave town.
>> Oh, wait. Here's
>> some of the blogs we get. I like that.
Yeah. How come?
How could you say?
>> My question is about practice and where
I could use um a little more insightful
guidance.
>> Practice.
>> Practice when you talk about the fourth
state and being in the being the um
>> the silent background.
>> Okay. Leave it just a little bit because
he's having a hard time. Start. Right.
Okay,
>> let me listen.
>> So my question is about practice where I
>> Yeah. Speak slowly.
>> My personal practice.
>> Yes. Oh,
>> when you talk about the fourth state and
being in the silent background and then
about being holding something in mind,
when I hold something in my mind, it
gets a little noisy. And so when that
that silent background that you talk
about being I can do it when I'm
meditating. I can do it when I'm with a
group that I work with. But in my when
I'm out in a places where I'm caught up
in habitual um distractions, how do you
what's a good way to practice that?
trying to be that silent background.
>> It has to do with intentional set.
>> You see, when you make a declaration, a
spiritual declaration
uh
that is an it's called an attentional
set.
And uh there's a psychologist named PhD
a research psychiatrist named M Medina.
me d i n a he just written three recent
articles that appeared in psychiatric
news on attentional set that
your intention sets priorities and then
there's cascades of dominance within the
neurologic system
but you've set the priority you've set
the pri priorities by your declaration
of your intention.
So the intention is what um dominates uh
your choices. It it brings up the
question of free will. Is there such a
thing as a free will? Uh within a
certain intentional set, you have
alternate choices available. Yes.
Then the rest of it is spiritual
practice and discipline. You see how to
not get entrapped by the world with
every squeak and moan,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
>> So the intention will take care of those
times if you
stay with your own.
>> The intentional set means that you have
made a decision to be like that.
So once you make a decision to be that
way when it varies that comes to your
attention then because that's outside
your set.
>> Okay.
Thank you.
>> All right.
Attentional set. Very interesting.
Med- NA.
>> Yeah. He just wrote a series of three
articles on it. I thought it was
interesting. Neurologic correlation.
what we taught teach.
>> Yes.
>> Hello. Um, I've got an announcement.
They said I could make an announcement
before I ask a question. So, if I may
please do that. Um, some folks and I are
starting a David Hawkins study group in
Santa Monica uh in January and we're
planning on meeting once a month on a
Sunday evening. So, if anybody is
interested in being a part of that,
please send me an email. Um, you can
email me at tellyearlink.net.
And the trick is to spell telly
correctly which is t like tom e l y te l
yearlink.net.
Thanks. Uh my question is about how
>> she talks one of those foreign
languages.
www net talk.
It's got an A like that.
www. then there's all kinds of little
things.
If you end up one of make a mistake in
one of little things, you end up in a
totally different universe.
>> So, you're acquainted with that world.
Go ahead, tell me what you're going to
tell me.
>> I'm sorry.
>> What were you going to say?
>> Oh, my question. Um, it's how to
reconcile two seemingly opposite truths.
On the one hand, there's the idea that
you can create your own reality by
thinking
>> That's not my idea. I never said that.
>> I'm sorry.
>> You didn't didn't get that from me.
>> Well, what what I've gotten from you is
more the idea of attractor fields.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, and which seems to me to be similar
to the idea that you can create your own
reality.
>> I don't say anything about creating your
own reality. No.
>> So, okay. So, I guess I'm confused
because um
>> you got that from somebody else.
>> I got what I thought was
>> a slogan. It's a slogan.
>> It's a slogan. Create your own reality.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, what I think I've gotten from you
is that
>> who is the you and what does it mean to
create and what do they mean by reality?
So, it's it doesn't say anything
>> that Yeah, it's very confusing. You can
have a whole symposium all day on it
because it doesn't say anything cuz I
you can spend all day playing with it.
>> What I think I've gotten from you is
that what you hold in your thoughts will
then manifest.
>> What you hold in mind tends to manifest.
Yes. And the higher your level of
consciousness, the more that is true.
Yes.
>> I'm I'm sorry.
>> The more the higher the level of
consciousness, what you hold in mind
tends to manifest. That's what I teach.
Yes.
>> Okay. But so then there's no there's
nothing about then willing something. um
creating something by in other words you
wouldn't agree with the idea that you
create your own reality basically.
>> I don't know you're enamored of that
slogan. Forget the slogan.
>> If you knew what if it was a truth you
wouldn't be asking me what does it mean?
It's because it's it's a slogan.
>> I'm not sure how to reconcile that with
the ideas of
>> forget this. Forget it.
>> Okay.
>> So
you're saying that that's not a
What's the answer to nonsense?
>> Uh, forget it.
>> Hey, baby.
>> Thank you.
>> She was trying. I know what she's trying
to get sense out of something, but it's
it's one of those redundancies.
And because it's a redundancy, you can't
get out of the puzzle box. It's like the
box that says everything. You put a slip
of paper, it says everything in this box
is false. You put it in the box and
close it.
And that double negative does not create
a positive. So, you cannot get the
answer to conundrums, you know. Yes.
It's been two years since I saw you
last. And what happened since then is
the nothingness is available. Looking
inside, nothingness is there. But I
understand that this is just another
block and that allness is available. How
to change from nothingness to allness?
What says that there's nothing
>> looking inside? There is nothing.
>> Oh, no.
>> Okay.
>> There's something. There's something
saying that there's nothing.
>> Right.
>> There you go.
>> The observ There's nothing.
>> What is saying that there's nothing?
You're not saying there's nothing.
You're negating what you just said.
>> Okay.
>> There is something saying there's
nothing, right?
>> That's the doorway out.
>> Okay.
That's true.
>> Nothing is wrong. There's nothing to say
that there's nothing wrong with you. You
understand?
>> Okay, I'm out of it.
>> Good to see you. Good to see you. I
haven't seen Bokar a long time.
>> Okay, I got
>> see these conundrums and they become
memes. meme and they become sort of new
age spirits with jargon
and everybody puzzles them and they have
endless symposiums and all that kind of
stuff
>> and it's going around and around about
you know hypotheses and stuff but it
doesn't get you anywhere. Yeah. You
speak in your writings about when the
mind begins to slow down that there is a
progression from perception to vision to
seeing essence. And my experience has
been that when I look at something
natural I begin to see for example if I
look at a tree I see a certain amount of
space holding it up a kind of suspension
a kind of a more of an emerging of space
and a receding of form. Is that the kind
of experience that happens as the mind
begins to slow transitional. Yeah.
Transitional. Mhm.
You you see the the exquisite beauty and
perfection of it. See?
>> Mhm.
>> In the beginning, the mind says, "Look,
that's a cricket tree. You should chop
it down. It's not standing straight. All
trees are supposed to stand straight."
>> Mhm.
>> After a while, you see that it is
expressing something else. And then it's
a perfect crooked tree.
>> And is there sort of a presentation by
space? In other words, it's almost like
space is presenting the object. Is that
kind of making sense?
>> Yeah. The the essence of its reality
shines forth.
>> So you see the perfection of all things.
So that this tree like this is equally
as perfect as this, even though they
aesthetically
>> fit a different presumptive aesthetic
pattern.
>> Thank you.
>> People are always wanting to chop down
crooked trees. I mean, they take away
all my beautiful crooked old trees.
Leave nothing but the straight ones.
Straight trees are okay, too.
Yeah.
So, do I talk while you write? Okay. So,
I'm very happy to meet with you. That's
the first time I come. I want to say
unlimited. No, unlimited. Thank you for
staying in this form so you can talk to
us. staying in this form so she could
talk to so you could talk to
>> Yeah. Thank you very much for staying in
this form. Okay.
>> Oh, that form there. You're talking
about that.
>> Yeah. Well, that that form
>> unfortunately that's the only one.
>> Everybody plays around the whole room
today. I don't know what what to do with
them all. Anyway, go ahead.
>> So, I was told that there's only one
question and I had many questions. So, I
thought maybe you can decide which one
would be more beneficial to answer.
>> Yeah. uh keep it down to 30 questions.
Okay.
>> Okay. So there's um one of them is
related to oneness is what exactly it
is. Well I I'm not sure more I read more
I feel like I don't I don't understand
things and so oneness is is one I would
like to understand. And the other one it
seems that I maybe I misunderstood but
all of the book I read is it seems that
you need to have someone that is already
enlightened in beside you in order to
achieve enlighten and um obviously as
I'm here with you right now but usually
that's I'm not living here. So what do I
do if that's true? So choose whatever
question you
think is more beneficial to me.
>> You don't need to have a living teacher
in your proximity. All you need is the
energy field of the aura of a teacher
who is enlightened. That then goes with
you. You can then forget about the
teacher if you wish. You know because
the energy field is all you need to pick
up. The information is not
understandable without certain energy
fields. We sort of explained that this
morning that as the condolini energy
rises the atheric brain
consciousness becomes more advanced and
that which was not comprehensible at one
level suddenly becomes a aha you begin
to see it by revelation
very often when you're not even thinking
about it you're just walking along all
of a sudden you got oh I've got what
that means
>> okay thank you
>> so you can mul it mull it over meditate
on And then uh
>> okay
>> let it be on its own and it'll come back
to you.
>> It'll come back.
I love you, Dr. Hawkins.
And I love your team that's behind you.
I feel their support. I feel their love.
>> Yeah. They're like rock.
>> They're the rocks that we
>> Yeah.
This lady just asked my question. And I
um years ago, a couple years ago, I saw
you and I sat across from you in Sedona
and I held your hand and and prior to
that, I had listened to maybe a couple
of hundred hours of you speaking on
audio.
But it didn't mean it seemed like I
didn't mean hardly anything until I sat
across from you and I held your hand and
you looked into my eyes. And now when I
listen to you on cassette or see your
DVDs that I can bring that context
instantly.
And
>> yeah,
>> that means so much.
>> And why
I guess you answered it with that last
lady, but is it the same thing in
visiting a relic or holy places that you
get the context of a place?
>> No.
No, there's a frequency to transmit down
through the ages and it's through the
atheric brain you know through the
higher chakras the chakras above the
crown chakra there is there are more the
Buddha bodies Christ body atmic body etc
and uh the frequency of the energy field
vibrates down through the ages you it
goes from one to to the other we all
transmitted to each other and then of
course when we combine like this we all
share it together. That's why we all
sort of come on the planet together and
go off the planet together. You see
maybe 50 years in between individuals
but you know in time that's like the
same minute you know
100 years is like a second time.
>> Would you take about 10 seconds and just
with me?
Thank you.
>> Hello, doctor.
I just first want to thank you for being
here today and sharing your just
incredibly radiant presence with all of
us here today.
>> Well, Wally and
that uh
>> Kathy
>> Kathy uh the springboards to it.
>> Well, I thank them too wherever they
are.
And I guess we're running a familiar
theme here. My question also has to do
with proximity because I've I've seen
you in person three times now and I get
more benefit coming up here on stage and
being this close to you and looking you
in the eyes and I do sitting in the
audience and I get more out of sitting
in the audience I do sitting at home
reading your books and I was just
wondering if it's bo I know you don't
take disciples but is it possible to
find somebody like Ramana Maharshi used
to do where who takes disciples and to
sit at the feet of an enlightened master
such as yourself for three years or I
guess You're saying it's not necessary.
>> No, what you do is you pick up the
energy frequency of the teacher who who
got it elsewhere comes down through him
to you and you dedicate to studying and
meditating on the work and you see the
teacher periodically if that's possible.
You see, and then that starts a process
going and then the process takes over.
See, you've initiated a process and the
process then takes over
and you you see because you're being
drawn by the future instead of propelled
by the past. So if your destiny is
enlightenment, that means that
destination is pulling pulling you in
that direction.
>> Well, you're certainly pulling me in
It's by your it's because of your
intention to become enlightened that you
that's why otherwise it would have no
appeal to you.
>> Great. Thank you very much.
>> It's your decision that makes it gives
it the power it has.
>> Um should I say anything about the
Buddha relics that are traveling?
>> No
check. I don't have my check. Y
>> thank you for being here. Um
my teacher tells me that I should not
have any goal but I have such a strong
goal for to wake up and um
>> your teacher tells you you should not
have any goals.
>> I should not have goals or desires.
>> Oh yes.
>> So your goal is to not have goals. I
see.
>> I think that is about it. And then my
meditation I'm wondering what that
process I I'm a I practice meditation
daily and I'm wondering what is that
process? What does that do for me?
>> What does what do meditation
>> meditation?
>> Um
what is the purpose of meditation? Why
do you even do it?
>> I do it because well it it quiets me.
I've changed a little bit of the way I
see life, my daily. I certainly have
changed in the way I see other people. A
little less judgment.
>> So, it's somewhat transformative in its
overall effect.
>> I would say yes.
>> Yeah. And so, you're going to have to
redefine what your intention is behind
the meditation.
Why don't you redefine what is the
intention of it?
>> My intention is to wake up. Really,
>> your intention is to reach the core of
truth. source, the essence of your own
existence.
>> Yes. To see things in their essence
>> that you carry it through the next 20,
30 years.
>> Thank you.
Good afternoon and thanks for coming to
Southern California.
My question is how important is it to
identify mistakes in our past karma and
how can we
repair those mistakes and errors that
we've done to carry us forward?
um things that happen to you that create
suffering
uh you can dedicate that to the undoing
of whatever negative karma you have
about that matter.
See
>> okay
>> so this morning I bang my knee and I
uh
as for the forgiveness of all the beings
whose knees I have hurt
forgave myself for being ignorant and
having hurt their knees. So I I I
own everything that happens. Own
everything that happens
and and try to process it out.
Okay.
Very good. Thank you.
I'd like to know how to stabilize
um levels of consciousness. So,
>> how to stabilize what
>> levels of consciousness?
>> So, um
I
>> You have to tell me what level of
consciousness you're talking about.
>> Well, I experience a number of different
levels of consciousness.
>> What
>> she experienced? Yeah. You have to talk
into I said I experienced a number of
different levels of
>> Yes. Okay. Uhhuh.
>> So it's like uh you were saying that you
found that the consciousness of the
United States had decreased you know so
that it's obvious that one's
consciousness can increase and then
decrease or you know fluctuate.
>> So
>> yes that's normal. It fluctuates.
>> Yes. I would actually
>> sad angry mad happy all in half an hour.
>> Yes.
>> Yep.
So, I would like to actually be able to
um stabilize at
>> Oh, why do you want to stabilize it? Did
somebody say stabilizing in in one thing
is good?
>> I'm so sorry.
>> Nobody said that, did they? Nope. That's
a misconception.
>> What you want to do is transcend them.
Move from the lower to the higher.
You're not trying to make something
stay. What you do is process out the
negative because the positive you don't
have to create because the positive is
the inner reality that shines forth. So
all you want to do is remove the
negative by seeing it differently. See
and the the positive you don't have to
try and energize positive
because the positive automatically takes
over. When the waves die down on the
ocean the peace prevails. You can't
create peace. You can't go out and
create peace on the ocean. You know what
I'm saying?
>> Mhm.
>> You try to remove the blocks to it.
>> So that is how you would recommend um
when you find when I find uh that I'm at
a lower level of consciousness. Thank
god below 200.
But you know that's just to identify
what it is that's causing the drop in
consciousness
>> and then release release it.
>> Well, we wrote a book called translating
levels of consciousness. Okay.
>> Each one we we tried to address each
level to make it sort of clinically
specifically.
>> Yes. So if you're stuck with resentment,
then you look what's underneath that
resentment. And as you release that, the
resentment disappears
like unrealistic expectations. Everybody
should be polite, everybody should be so
and so. And then you realize you're
being childish, that the world isn't
that way. And uh so you you try to
relinquish whatever is holding the
negative in place. And the negative will
then disappear automatically. See? So
you don't have to try and create the
positive or hang on to the positive. All
you have to do is remove the blocks uh
remove the clouds and the sh sun sun
shines forth. You can't create the
shining of the sun.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Thank you so much.
>> So that's all you have to do.
>> Simple.
>> Forgive them even if they're dead wrong.
Hello. Uh, hi.
>> Uh, oh yeah. I'm um I'm on the process
as you mentioned, you know, the
spiritual process and it's it's been
going along. It's just been things come
up. I I I clear it. It's been I
experienced, you know, peaceful states.
I've experienced good, you know, clear
what
>> it was nice. So, it's a it's a spiritual
process. He says things come up and he
clears them.
>> Oh yes.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> But now I seem to be stuck. I seem to be
very very confused. I feel that I'm
completely lost. I feel that uh the
spiritual process is very intense now.
That that I only think about spiritual
things. I I read your books constantly.
I play all your tapes. I only focus on
on spiritual things. Nothing else seems
to matter in my life. And that
that leaves me in a state of confusion
of of of what is I feel lost, confused.
I just don't want to, you know, like
this stage. I can't seem to I don't feel
comfortable with it. I feel there's
something that's fear or an anxiety
about it. That it's taking over my life
that it's that it's I'm no longer in
control anymore.
>> So, do you pray to God to reveal to you
what it is you need to clear in
yourself?
Ask God ask
through the Holy Spirit a miracle that
you become conscious and aware of what
specifically is the block that you're up
against.
Do you do that?
>> Well, I've been praying to uh surrender
to the will of God, to surrender to God.
>> Yeah, that's sort of a generality, but
you're you're talking more about a
specific that you're stuck on.
>> I think I'm more concerned with
security. What's going to happen to me?
money.
I think it's probably an issue with that
that I
>> all of it at the same time.
>> Well,
no, you suck more on one thing. Why
don't you clear up this one thing and
then move to the next?
You mentioned specifically money,
>> right?
>> All right. So, why don't you work on
money period and don't worry about the
other things. See, you got that through.
Define what works for you about money.
Whether you see it as a blessing,
whether you feel guilt about it, whether
you feel deprived,
whether you think there's an
insufficiency,
work on money till you can clear that
money. See, and see what money is to
you.
What is money to you
>> quick?
>> For me, security.
>> Oh, so you in for security. Gee, I
thought it was happiness. Oh, he's got
security. Well, security brings you
happiness. Okay.
No, you you're you're all right. You you
think that it has to be more linear and
logical. It isn't linear and logical.
Often it's fuzzy and it's a confused
field that you sort of don't know what
to do with. But but that's ordinary.
That's perfectly all right. You know,
it's not going to come up like chapters
in a book. Well, now I'll work on, you
know, so
>> but things happen that that I, you know,
I go into states that I don't want, you
know, this is just uncomfortable because
I'm not
>> Yeah, that's that's normal. That's
normal. Yeah. So, each thing you process
as it comes up. Forgive yourself for it.
Ask to see it differently.
>> You know, most of it is just due to
being human. 99.9%
is just due to being human. And don't
forget, humans all have the karma of
being human.
People say, "Oh, Christianity doesn't
believe in karma." Yeah. What about
Genesis? What about the Garden of Eden?
You're born with negative karma. That's
why there's suffering and sin and
penance.
Yeah. So, Christianity believes in
plenty of karma.
Why do you penance for your what's all
the penance about?
You're born with original sin. So, get
away with saying they don't believe in
karma. I believe in karma plenty
before you get here. You inherit the
karma of mankind.
Disobedience in the garden of Eden.
The seduction by the serpent. The
serpent seduced
the child within the woman, not the
adult, the child.
So are we all to feel guilty because
some child
to come to temptation?
It was the infant, the child, the
innocence of the child that responded to
the serpent.
All right? So mankind's suffering is
because he filled fell from nonduality
into duality.
Eating of the tree of right and wrong.
There's nothing but duality. So he was
in the bliss of nonduality.
And he fell out of that bliss into the
complexities and ambivalences and
tensions of the linear dimension. Yeah.
>> So I don't want to hear anything more.
There's no karma in Christianity.
>> Thank you.
>> Never let it be said again.
I'm just kidding.
I don't really have a question. I'm
studying a course in miracles and I just
wanted to feel your energy so that it
would help me be a better student. So,
can I shake your head? Thank you.
>> All right. You're doing the course, huh?
>> Yes.
>> What lesson are you on?
>> I'm on like 58,
>> huh?
>> 58.
>> 58. That you're into it. You uped your
ankles.
>> Thank you.
>> Yed your ankles already.
My question is um I have basically
become good at nonattachment
and forgiveness
but uh when I either read fiction or
watch movies which are fiction
I buy into the emotions so intensely
that um I sometimes can't even sleep.
Yeah.
>> What is that?
>> It's because you're not done yet.
>> Okay.
>> Oh, sorry.
>> It just brings up whatever's left, you
know, sympathy for this, resentment over
that.
>> Great.
>> Uh
identifying with various aspects of the
personalities in the movie. Yeah.
>> So, just surrender whatever.
>> Well, just keep doing what you're doing
with it. That's all.
>> Okay. And of course you see television
advances uh
uh
television is a tremendous opportunity.
It allows you to live many lifetimes in
one, doesn't it?
>> Mhm.
>> I mean, think how many lifetimes it
would take you to live through all the
things that you're confronted with in
just one afternoon of television. Mhm.
>> In the old days, you could live within
two miles of where you were born, spend
your whole life as a sheep herder,
never meet any foreign cultures, you
know, and that's why it took many
lifetimes. Now, in the course of an
evening, you can be confronted with
every complexity and dilemma
uh of the human existence in just in one
evening. Mhm.
>> Rage and killing and hatred and rivalry
and vanity and greed. And I mean that's
just in 20 minutes, not even a
commercial.
So in a way it speeds up working through
cuz if you're going to use TV
uh to work through stuff I think it it
it makes very rapid because you get kind
of confronted all over and until finally
you let it go. Okay.
>> You know you hate the bad guys then you
get off that, you know,
>> right?
Tom Mix used to hate the bad guys.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> Yeah,
>> good and evil in in thousands of
different formats is what it's about.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello, Doc. I have a question about
calibrating levels of consciousness as
well. Um, I've been seeing a
chiropractor and she calibrates before
and after and it fluctuates
tremendously, I would say. So, and I
understand that it does do that. Once
one goes through the final door, is
there still fluctuation?
>> Once you go through what?
>> The final door.
>> The final door. If you go through the
final door, there still fluctuations.
>> Is there anything to be fluctuations of?
Yeah.
You don't have to worry about it.
>> Wait,
>> thank you.
>> See, in traditional medicine, they don't
believe in kinesiology. They don't
believe in chiropractic. They don't
believe in any of those things. And uh I
used to use them all.
And after I got through practicing
traditional medicine, I went and saw my
chiropractor and got my neck adjusted.
I had a standing standing appointment
twice a week
with my chiropractor and once a week
with my acupuncturist.
But don't tell your regular doctor about
that. I don't don't Better not to
confide you in.
>> Yeah. Thank you for the influence of
your work, Dr. Hawkins.
>> First, a gift from a friend of mine that
was based on your work. That helped
helped me a great deal.
>> And uh allow me to read the context of
my question first and then and then I'll
uh get your answer.
It's been my observation that in most of
the ancient traditional forms of
spiritual practices uh which I've
investigated and applied in my own life
um physical health practices were
emphasized by the devity to prepare the
body to handle the energy of spirit and
seems that many advanced spiritual
teachers um have experienced various
illnesses, pain, injuries in their
progressive realization.
So my question is how important is it
for a spiritual aspirant to practice
applying principles of health such as
nutrition and physical exercise in
addition to spiritual practice
um to speed one's realization of truth?
And do these practices make the
transfiguration process easier or
faster?
>> I don't think so.
I don't think they they do. you know, uh
they're good for their own sake.
They're good because you're you're
giving recognition, you know, to the
blessing of life itself,
affirming its value.
Does it help you uh advance your level
of consciousness? I don't think so.
>> Okay, then can I then one can I have one
more question on that?
If that and I I'm gonna say if that was
so but of course it is. You just said
it.
Um is this a valuable the teaching of
physical health practices because it's
kind of uh endeared to my own heart. Is
that a valuable form of service for me
to improve the quality of people's
lives?
>> Yes. The quality. Yes. Quality of life.
It's respect for the gift of life to
maintain it in as best a condition as
you can. Yeah.
It's recognition of the gift
affirmation of the gift. You know, for a
certain level that would be meaningful.
>> Thank you.
>> Another meaning level it would be non
meaningful.
>> When when you leave this planet, you
don't leave in the best health usually.
He died in fit condition.
Did 32 push-ups and stop breathing.
>> That's the way to go. Good shape.
>> I want to be in good shape when I go.
That's fun
and it increases one's I think good
physical health the joy of life
to celebrate um the joy of your own
existence exuberantly. Yeah.
>> Well, thank you first of all for your
work. Um and my question is how do you
actually surrender the juice? Is there a
better process? Is there one process
that is better than the other one? How
do you get what?
>> How do you surrender the juice?
>> The devotion to God, the willingness out
of your love for God, you're willing to
let go
the suspect pleasures of juicing
negativity.
For thee, oh Lord, I'm willing to give
up
the glee of hating the SOP, even though
he deserves it.
Then you see the absurdity of it. Then
you laugh at it. Then you ask God for
forgiveness. How could you be so
ignorant? Uh anyway, no, it's out of
love that you do it. It's out of love
for God that this stands in the way. And
if it stands in the way between that and
that which you love and strive for, then
you're willing to relinquish it. And you
have to remind yourself you're
relinquishing the lesser for the
greater.
>> Although it's very fun to hate somebody
and stab them. Take that.
I mean that is fun.
Take that US. So
>> yeah, especially when you're doing it to
yourself. Well, I you know the
willingness to let it go is sort of done
on the basis of faith that as enjoyable
as that is that there is something
greater. So you take the word of the
teacher that something greater will take
its place.
>> So there's a certain amount of faith and
trust in the teacher
that uh that letting go that is that
will bring create the space for the
greater. Mhm.
>> So it's letting go of the lesser for the
greater based on confidence in the
teacher. So that's one thing a teacher
in body can can provide is
is certainty. See because your intuition
tells you whether he's telling you the
truth or not.
>> And if letting it go you were going to
be more miserable. He wouldn't recommend
it. No.
He say no. If you give up rage, revenge,
hatred, and guilt uh you will come to a
more joyful state.
And then you will be doing good to the
world not because of what you do but
because of what you have become
that your life then becomes a blessing
to the world that you exist is already
uplifting
uh the rest of life. So there's the gift
that you give by letting it go.
>> Thank you.
That's St. Francis of Aisi Spirit that I
may be a channel of thy will, oh Lord.
>> Hi.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uh I just wanted to say first of all
that it's it's a blessing just to be in
your presence and I appreciate the time
that you're giving us.
I am absolutely freezing and you're
warm, aren't you?
>> It's hot up here.
>> She's warm.
My question is well first of all the
statement is that um a few years ago
while I was reading one of your books it
was either I or I um something
spontaneously happened where all of the
sudden I had this visual of this entire
life. It was localized to this lifetime.
But um
the visual uh narration if you would was
every event that's happened to me that
was important and some that at the time
seemed trivial but now it was clear that
they were incredibly important. Not only
these events but the sequence of these
events made complete sense. Everything
was absolutely clear from the earliest
memory up until the time where I was
holding your book.
And I was just wondering if you could
provide me any insight into first of all
what it was. Secondly,
um why do I only remember the general
theme of it and its meaning and not the
minutia that I was going through?
>> Well, what would what would you want to
remember the minutia for?
>> Because it gave such beauty to every
event that I that spontaneously arose in
my vision.
>> Well, the the process isn't that good.
That was just that real.
>> And what was the event that happened?
>> You You're talking about a whole
sequence of events. What do you mean
that event?
>> It might have lasted I couldn't tell
you. It was almost like it was outside
of time. It could have been seconds. It
could have been a minute.
>> It was outside of time.
>> At death store, your life unreals before
your eyes. You're familiar with that?
>> Yes.
>> Well, you might have been there near
death store.
Okay, thank you.
>> Yes, you can put your life like on a
>> on a videape and then you can run it
so slow.
>> Okay. Um, I've been doing a spiritual
technique since I was a teenager and I
enjoyed doing it. I've had some nice
experiences. I've grown from it which I
can attribute to some after effects of
the technique or I can attribute it just
to growing older and life experience. Uh
after reading in one of your books about
the deepest level
of reality being infinite love
uh it reminded me of a verse from the
Bible which goes he who abides in love
abides in God and God in him.
So my question is since infinite love is
at our deepest level our deepest essence
is there a way to invoke
that love as a way of enlightenment.
No what you know which I just said
before to the last person what you let
do is you you don't try to invoke
infinite love. What you try, what you do
is you constantly remove the blocks that
stand in the way. See, you cannot force
the sun to shine brighter than it is.
All you can do is remove the clouds. And
as you remove the clouds, this sh sun
sun shines forth. Also, it's not in
control. It's not a linear I do this
now, this will happen. It's more a
generality that you keep chipping it
away, chipping away at all the
negativity.
>> And when least expect it, when least
expect it, suddenly it opens up before
you.
>> Okay?
>> So
it it isn't cause and effect. It isn't
because you're doing this practice, this
happens. It doesn't work in a causal,
it's not in a causal sequence. So you
can't yourself with
>> by commitment etc.
>> Okay.
>> There's a becomingness and that which
one becomes then how it has the power uh
to summon forth certain phenomena.
>> So by aligning
>> what it is be you're listening to what
I'm saying instead of talking.
So you constantly let go
stop putting it in a linear I do this
that causes this. What should I be doing
to cause that? No. Okay. Just keep
removing the negativity itself. And as I
said, as you remove the clouds, the sun
shines forth of its own. Not because you
remove the clouds. The way you're
holding it is if I remove the clouds,
then the sun's going to shine forth.
>> But that's looking at it in a linear
causality framework again,
>> right?
>> Don't try to cause anything or
or bring on any kind of state of
consciousness. Just remove that which
you observed to be negative. Thank you.
>> Oh, okay.
>> So, okay.
>> Did you want to take
>> That's all good.
>> Did you want to take a 10 minute break
or so? Do you want to continue?
>> Well, it depends on the people. Yeah. I
don't know how many people I can see the
back of the room.
>> I mean, if you do, you have
>> I don't need a break room right now.
>> Okay.
>> Talk to people. Thank you.
>> Okay. You know what I'm saying? Don't be
linear.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Be diffuse.
>> Okay. I have to work on that.
>> Um because of the amount of people that
have questions, we have to be out of
here at 5:00. So, we're going to go
ahead and answer questions through the
next break. So, um just to let you know,
we will not be taking an afternoon
break. We're going to continue with
questions
>> and the bookshop will be closing
shortly. So, this will be a last
opportunity.
>> There's another event after us, so we
probably have to be out.
tremendous gratitude.
Um, I thought of you a couple weeks ago
because uh I was outside and I saw a
beetle on the ground on its back flipped
over with it in the air
>> and I went and uh and promptly bent down
and nudged it back over on its front.
But uh he looks up and says to me, "Hey,
I'll turn the die here." here and he
immediately flips back over and puts his
legs back up in the air. I thought that
was confirmed.
>> He interrupted his funeral.
>> Sorry, I just let him uh keep going
there. But um my question is this. Um uh
throughout this lifetime I've uh had
pretty extreme allergies and um mentally
I know that uh allergies are an illusion
and uh spiritually I surrender and um I
don't resist them
and um but physically I'm a train wreck
you know and uh so my question about
suffering
about what you brought up earlier about
how suffering can be a form of devotion
and um although at the time it seemed it
that sounded really beautiful I also a
red flag went up and I thought wow
that's a way my ego is going to say see
suffering is I I can suffer and be
devotive or whatever and so I just
wanted to um see if you could elaborate
on the clear differences about the kind
of suffering that I might go through
with allergies or and how I might
recontextualize that
um into a a form of devotion.
>> Well, you have to let go. U you're an
infinite being. You're only subject to
what you hold in mind. Uh so pollen
doesn't have any power over you. It's
only your belief in in the power pollen.
So the pollen itself has no power. If we
calibrate pollen, colon pollen
calibrates over 90.
It has very little power. I'm sure
you're overnight. So, it's your belief.
You see, right?
People are upset when I say, you know,
certain things, uh, global warming,
human activity has nothing to do with
global warming. Oh, they just go off and
do a fit.
>> Yeah.
>> Doesn't have anything to do with,
>> right?
>> Has to do with the magnetic activity,
the surface of the sun. If you calibrate
that, that comes out true.
>> Right.
All of mankind raises the temperature on
the planet earth about point 0.8°
max.
So all the self sacrifice and stuff is
is nothing. The magnetic activity that
serves the sun. So when they go do polar
polar borings down to 10 10,000 years
ago
temperature depends on the surface
activity of the sun.
That makes people very upset when you
say that.
I got a vested interest in the whole
belief system. See,
>> yeah,
>> I I've been aware that the pollen is
that it's not really can really affect
me negatively. I think very early age
it's transitory. Yeah, it's transitory.
>> It's transitory. No, you grow out of it.
You grow out of it maybe in 20 30
minutes.
I'm an infinite being. I'm only subject
to what I'm holding mind. And uh pollen
is neutral. It has no it's neither good,
neither good nor bad.
And it tends to run in families. You got
other people in your family.
>> Uh not that I'm aware of.
>> You're the only one
>> as far as I know.
>> That's unusual. Yes. Usually the whole
bunch.
Uh but you can transcend it. You can
transcend that.
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. Thank you.
I transcended that and Poison Avy and a
whole bunch of other
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
Hallelu.