question. I was wondering if you would be open to checking to see if it's in the highest good
for me to continue working where I'm working. What is your problem with it? My experience is
that the level of consciousness has started to shift where I'm working at, and I'm just wondering
if it's still in the highest good to remain there. Let's see if we have permission to ask this.
Permission to ask this. We don't have permission to ask that. You don't have to decide it yourself.
Uh-oh. Do you think you want to move on higher, to a higher level? Well, I feel conflicted because
I feel like I make a difference there, but yet I feel like in some ways the consciousness has
dropped, but I still feel like I'm making a difference there. Okay, so I see. You're going
through priorities. You have to decide your priority, what your purpose in life is.
Just one. Do you want to give me three back? You better change your occupation, yes.
Thank you so much for everything. My question is, about four years ago, I started an apprenticeship
with an indigenous Indian tribe in Mexico, and your work came into my life at the exact same
time, and it created a big conflict.
What was the biggest conflict that you had in your life, and how did you deal with it?
Well, the biggest conflict was in my mind, because you've spoken a lot about cults, channeling,
the shamanic world, and I noticed a lot of, the group I'm working with meets a lot of
that criteria. And a year ago, I had a pretty horrible accident where I almost lost my life.
I broke my femur in five places and split my head open. And I was told by my teacher
that the cause of the accident was my lack of commitment to the path, and that my life
was in danger.
My family's life was in danger. My partner's life was in danger. And before that, my prayer
has always been for truth, to be shown the truth in the path.
And anyway, I've been paralyzed over the last year. I've been very fearful. And I've tried
to muscle test, in the name of the highest good, to see what this, this, my teacher,
and this group, calibrates at. The main source of the teachings of this group comes through
a channeled entity.
I don't want to know the entity's name. I have permission to get the number of, the
calibration of the entity. I have permission to get the calibration on the entity. It engenders
fear. The teachings of this entity engenders fear.
Well, there's groups...
If by their fruit you shall know them, you would have to make your own decision, if you're
going to a manifestation.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
The idea of the entity is if by the fruit you shall know them, what are your eyes telling
you? Tell me you're living in fear.
Well, I said to myself, I'd rather die than live my life in fear. So my choice has been
to walk away. And if I die, then I die, I guess. But I have to make a decision, a decision.
I have to make a decision and be in the presence of this entity very soon. And I'm afraid to
go but I feel like I have to go.
Okay.
have to and um afraid to go where to stand before this person to stand before this person or this
entity why are you going what entity the the channeling so yeah well i have to do a renunciation
ritual in order to end my okay see there's there's the programming but so you don't have to do
anything all right anyone that tells you that you're going to die because you're not doing
something it's not the people you want to be around period yes my question concerns
the parusha of the teacher yeah is this an energy that is continually radiating or yes
well that answers that so in the vicinity of the m.i. i should have a little parusha
or could you send a shot of parusha i'll have mine with soda i'm sorry give me a parusha and soda
huh
thank you very much that's actually the self of the teacher the capital s the self of the teacher
because when a person asks the question that's the source of the response the personage of the
teacher doesn't have anything to do with it it becomes a witness i see the personal self is a
witness here's what is being said by the teacher instead of just a witness thank you very much
very often interestedly listens what could be the answer to that question
and then he hears it thank you doctor yeah bless you in my life i discovered that one of the things
that i really enjoyed doing was looking anybody in the eye at all times and saying bless you
i discovered that one of the things that i really enjoyed doing in my life was looking
in other people's eyes no matter where we were grocery store whatever oh yeah and saying bless
you yeah and i felt from my heart that i connected with them in a way that i could
say to them i'm giving you the gift of what's flowing through me as the very presence of that
love to you without grabbing a bat and saying okay here's god you want it and my question is
as i go about my daily life and doing what i do if the day that i'm out there my level feels as
though i'm down because of other minutiae that's going on in my life am i still giving them the
highest that's available when i look them and say you're doing what you can do at the moment
yeah but that will fluctuate yeah there's days you're going to feel higher and more able to impart
that kind of energy but okay so i'm only giving them the highest level of where i'm at at that
time or am i giving them the gift of that that's flowing through me at a higher level i don't look
at as so much as giving as a recognizing of something that is already there
yeah excellent yeah don't picture it like going from me to you just to recognize the
the two of us are recognizing its presence i recognize the divinity within the within you
absolutely bless you one of the things i would love for you guys to consider in one of your books
or in one of your lectures is if you would give us calibrations if one of the things i'd like you
to consider is if you at some point could give us calibrations on jesus christ and the events that
took place after uh the resurrection
i would like to have those in print from you some point don't worry about it
same yesterday today as far as i know a son to deck in heaven to be at the right hand of the father
but let's ask if that's true oh okay great we have permission to ask this resist that is so
okay thank you
words you know the christ on the phone words
in position from without dr hawkins you are me my beloved teacher i do really love you and you're
my window to god thank you very much my first question is why do we get so emotional i have
so many friends right now what do we get so emotional why do we get so emotional with the
sacred things you know faith in the presence of faith yes because it it brings up what's real
um just listening to you and what it brings up what's real it brings up your essence
but crying is really normal sometimes i feel ashamed when i'm in you know in church and then
i just you can't be helped by people who are really devotional okay so it's natural there's
a certain phase where you just cry all the time in monasteries uh nunneries are you are familiar
with it there's a certain level where you just cry cry all the time cry for a couple years now
i went through a phase where if i if a couple i was in an airport a couple would glance at each
other with love that would make me cry the presence of love the expression of love so i
spent a year or two crying all the time because love is just about everywhere when you're open
there are some times that i do not really i cannot make a difference differentiation uh
between somebody else's pain and my own pain i don't know what do you mean that i mean like i feel
compassion for oh yeah yeah but at the same time i look at myself and when i'm looking at somebody
else i feel like it's mine and it feels really bad yeah that's over identifying and something
else you see compassion for the human condition you see that's what you have to have not not the
individual and the individuals distress but for the overall human condition itself which is what
we cry for you see okay
when i saw the totality of the suffering of mankind throughout all the time it was stagnant
beyond this dimension to to describe or comprehend it was of a different dimension when i saw the
totality of it my last question is um about um holy appearances like the virgin uh mother of god
that suddenly you know she's been appearing in in latin america all over the world have you ever
had somebody search are you talking about the miraculous uh-huh what do you want to know is
what he wants to know is is the miraculous real is the miraculous a reality resist thank you
without the reality of the miraculous i wouldn't be sitting up here talking
i've been put away in the ground a long time ago not that i mind but
one way or the other it's all the same i guess
rates high say you have 600 or more do you have to have an equal level of consciousness to steward
that project and what happens if you don't well you're looking sort of at cause and effect
if you want to contribute your energy to something you consider to be worthwhile whether it's
successful or not becomes immaterial i don't know how you're trying to read it if my thrust is to
teach as many people english as i can i'm not going to be able to teach as many people english as i can
then i can't say well i did 22 this year's and 13 last year so this is twice as good as last year
in other words you're trying to put it in a causal numerical the energy and the intention
is the thrust of it out into the world you know so what i'm doing is i'm not asking a
very appropriate question you're phrasing it in terms of cause and effect in a way
if a thing is worth it it's worth it for its own sake okay well i'm involved in a situation and in a
company that we started has a pretty high level of intent and there's three partners and two of us
have left because the other partner is a difficult personality and I'm really struggling with whether
or not to stay involved in it oh and so that was I guess what I was trying to get to oh you know
so you're struggling to be remain involved with the last other partner one is left right there's
only two of you well two of us have left there's one left there was three of us to begin with
yeah and both of us have left because of the other person has a the personalities become more and
more difficult as the project has evolved and we thought well maybe we set the bar too high oh you
know and maybe we can't hold we can't steward that level of intent so what he wants to know is in the
service of the highest good which move to make you want me to phrase it that way please okay let's ask
of your permission we have asked we can't we have permission we can ask in the name of the
highest good it would serve as good for him to remain in in the partnership in the name of the
highest good it would serve the highest good for him to part from the partnership thank you
some attachment he has about the partnership it isn't just the partnership it's some some
attachment he's added to it you know some benefit you know yes thank you can you can you see what
you're doing yes I can it's um 3 18. and uh what time do we oh five o'clock oh so we we're doing
great well we're doing fine well we can take a church break in a minute or two yeah because if
you want to take a break well I'll do this gentleman we're only going to take a very short
one we won't take us along like five minutes thank you for being my teacher Dr Hawkins Susan
thank you uh Dr Hawkins it's been I've been blessed that I've been able to see you in person
this is my second time and whenever you walk in the room I get this rush of joy I you know I just
I'm just in awe yeah and my I mean I know the feeling you know the feeling yeah because you're
around it all the time you're you as a student I felt it also with a high teacher yeah go ahead
so my question for you is what exactly is occurring and what exactly is occurring yeah
what what happens what's is it what am I feeling your your energy is that state of joy yeah that's
all it is is it the joy within him or is it the joy of your it activates his own potential it
activates that this is what activates uh that it's uh it like lights up your own flares okay
and and so when your flares you feel when I'm away from you how do I how do I call that
back how do I recall that feeling um you just keep working on the spiritual work and and it
becomes more and more prominent as a present reality stack of books keep keeping yeah thinking
of the book you know concentrating on the future to recall that it's the your own self with a
capital S shining forth and you experience it more and more okay thank you very much
yes thank you Dr Hawkins I'm just very pleased and excited to be here and all my flares are lit
it's wonderful now I used to always think that I had a naive trust for mankind and what I've
learned through reading your materials is that when you're not so linear you can sort of think
outside the box and bring I don't know what to call it but it's a bigger perspective and I love
that um but I wanted to ask a question because the feeling in this room of course with you and
your team is just it's awesome and I was wondering if we could calibrate how we are I mean how we are
as a group in this room um in relation to your scale oh you want to calibrate the group before
the lecture with permission sure group started out over 400 410 405 410. uh the group group went
up to a high point of over 500 490 495 shot about 80 points okay someone out there is not working
somebody out there is reading funny books instead of listening I gotta I'll be back in two minutes
flat this way I gotta see a man
okay okay hello Dr Hawkins and Mrs Hawkins uh first of all I would like to commend you both
for revealing the truth that everyone needs to know thank you uh in a way um what I do is similar
to what you do on a smaller scale uh I am a
a clinical hypnotherapist a what a clinical hypnotherapist oh yes yes yeah and what I do is I
do the pinpoint method the pinpoint method which is getting to the root of the problem so when the
when somebody knows the truth is when they can change okay so my question is um okay since I
receive a lot of negativity
and I try to shut it off by doing my own self-hypnosis and but still I I take this to sleep
with me and what do you mean you receive a lot of it well everybody that I treat a lot of abuses a
lot of um guilt people that come to me to to heal yeah and um successfully it it I do have a good
practice but how do I shut these people off from my mind
how do you shut the people off I yes how do I not think about this clinical detachment yes
detachment okay experienced clinician you disconnect from the patient as a person as
in a personal emotional relationship see you become the witness and become conscious and aware
and uh you naturally reflect on it you know sometimes but reflecting on it is different than
so tell you know your your job as a clinician is to remain
detached and reflect so that so that your clinical vision is clearer see okay to stay disinvolved
that's called counter transference so in psychoanalysis one of the purposes is to offset
counter transference feeling sorry for people right
may I ask you a question in your practice how did you detach from well you know the actuality was I
cut through you know my own personal psychoanalysis plus I had training analysts who were Supervisors
for the first you know a few dozen cases I have so the training analyst is different than a personal
analyst personal analyst you're with psychoanalysis training analyst looks at your mainly looking at
your counter transference and trying to help you understand your own counter transference
and not even and also not being denial about it you know did did you feel
for that lady when she told you about this and if so yes and if not why not so
you know I brought up as a Freudian so the Freudian analyst is detached and is
really a mirror back to the patient but that's a different perhaps than you what
you picture your function to be you see well I try to detach but it comes up all
the time so you need your own training analyst to consult with okay I only had
out personal analysis for four years or five years whatever it was and then a
couple of other therapists but I also had training there in there so they're
distinctly called training analyst training analyst is only to help you
with your counter transference with your patients okay in other words they're
they're yours but just to help you with the counter transference you know when
the patient says you're an a-hole did you feel mad you know and if not why not
and and if so
and why did you take it personally and then did you reflect that back you know
how they how they are screwing up their life by seeing other people besides you
so but don't forget I had a Freudian analysis which might be somewhat
different in overall context and purpose you know okay and what is your personal
opinion about hypnosis I think hypnosis is wonderful and it's correct place it's
a very tremendous useful tool yeah I mean for past life I've had a lot of
experiences in my life I've had a lot of experiences in my life I've had a lot of
experiences in my self ranges my position a lot of experiences I've really
loved doing hypnosis or anything that you've even you know past life recall
things like that hypnosis is terrific and for self healing of many things you
know so feeling of many things I think hypnosis has a very useful pragmatic
place okay people have a misconception what hypnotherapy really is well you
can't help them with that
in an agreeable state and the patient is in charge at all times. They won't go any
deeper into into a state than they're willing to go. You can't force them to go
against their will. No one can control anyone else's mind, right. Okay, Will. So I think, yes, I
think self-hypnosis is a very useful tool. Every time I go to the dentist, I go
into a state, you know, and they wake me up and say, well, he's out again, there he
goes. I just instantly go into a self-hypnotic state and I'm totally
totally detached. And when it's all over, they'll say, okay, wake up, we're all done.
Okay, thank you. So, I mean, I use it every time I go to the dentist. And you can use
hypnosis for childbirth, for pre-conditioning surgery, it's useful for
many things, as people do not know. Okay, Will, here's my card. Next time I need a session, I'll
give you my card.
Okay, thank you very much. Yeah. Past life regression can be a very, very interesting
experience. Thank you very much. Hello. Sometimes I struggle with trying to find the difference
between going through an experience and juicing it. So I was wondering if you could elaborate
on that a bit. Juicing it is when you're purposely utilizing it for some secondary
gain. There's a secondary gain. So to relinquish it, all you have to do is spot what is the
secondary gain and be willing to surrender the secondary gain. Don't forget, in return
for surrendering, the secondary gain of that which is negative, in return, you get the
positive gain of that which is positive. So you feel better about yourself when you've
forgiven somebody, even though they did actually, you know, did do something wrong.
Then you do by harboring the resentment. So the ego is reluctant to give it up because
it thinks I'm giving up all this wonderful juice of hate and resentment and feeling sorry
for myself in return for nothing. No, you get something back. And after you do it a
few times and find that you feel much better about yourself than you did before you let
it go, it then becomes easier each time. Every time you let that resentment go, you feel
better than you did when you were having the resentment.
For one thing, you don't have the guilt to contend with. And so you receive a benefit
from the letting it go. And after you do that a few times, you feel freer and higher and
better and happier, and you realize that it was worth it.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins. It's a privilege to be here, and I'm very honored. My question, this morning
you said, God's will for us is free choice.
God's will for us is free choice.
Yeah, free choice, yes. Freedom is a basic spiritual reality universe. So that way there
would be no accountability, and there could be no spiritual progression.
Okay. Does God have a plan for us?
Does God have a plan for us?
It can't be answered in the way that you put the question.
Okay.
It's a deterministic contextualization that you've given.
Out of the reality, out of the ultimate reality, emerges a creation with its own intrinsic
nature. So there isn't a you God that dictates that this condition for a you person, you
understand? It's more like out of this arises the whole panorama of all that is possible.
And now as you as a spiritual reality have all these choices.
Right.
That God presents you with a whole carnival of options, you know? Not as a person, God,
giving a person to you that, but out of the sheer reality of that which has been created,
opens up options for all that lives.
Thank you very much.
Wish to express my heartfelt gratitude for all that is in the field at this moment and all that have
contributed to this possibility.
I've been a student of yours since the beginning of the millennium.
I had the opportunity now to be in your presence three times.
And every time I've been before you before or in your presence, that the answers to the
questions I've developed have all formulated and I've not had the opportunity to come up
or the reason to come up and see you.
The question I pose is, coming from a space of non-duality and totally non-positionality,
how does one make a stand for truth?
Actually, it's a whole lecture in itself.
But without positionality, you merely stand being what you are.
See, the eagle stands being an eagle, not in order to scare doves, not in order to,
not for any reason at all.
It just is an eagle because that's fulfilling its eagle nature.
You see?
So when you stand for truth, it's not like you're standing in opposition to falsehood.
You're merely standing for truth.
You see?
Yes.
So.
It is a strength.
It is a strength to stand for the truth as you understand it.
To do so by being it, not to please anyone or to accomplish.
In other words, there's no purpose to it.
It's just because that's the way it is.
So I have a certain obligation as a teacher, is my understanding of it, to fulfill that,
to fulfill that, to have the strength to do so, not for any particular reason except to fulfill
one's purpose.
It's all about one's potential, which is all that God really gives us, is potential.
And my understanding would be an appreciation for the gift of the potential to fulfill it
to the best of your capacity, and thus to serve God.
That might be by being the best athlete, the best cab driver, a good husband, good father,
forgiving citizen.
Who knows what it means, because at each level it means something different.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
How do we, what can we do to encourage our grandchildren to develop an interest in
spirituality, since we see them seldom?
Do you see them very often?
A couple times a year.
Well, you attract them, you try to attract them into things you think would be contributory
to that direction.
We went over some of them this morning.
Appreciation for beauty.
My grandmother used to read me Shakespeare, and my mother would take me to the opera.
And my father would take us to the ballet.
And they would take us to the aquarium.
And they would take us to the, in Chicago, the Museum of Science and Industry, and the
planetarium.
And I joined the Art Institute.
So those things were all endeavors encouraged by the family.
You know, they valued aesthetics, and learning, and wisdom, appreciation of nature and beauty.
So you encourage them in the direction of things that you think,
help build character, join the scouts, you know. I still look at people around me,
they go on trips, they're completely unprepared, and I say, didn't they ever go
to scouts? Where were you when they passed out? Be prepared. So you encourage them
into things that will carry them in the direction you want them to go.
Yeah? Thank you. Appreciation for beauty and all such things. Thank you. Yeah.
Aesthetics. Aesthetics. Sensitivity for aesthetics will result in a
disinclination to anything criminal. People who've had high exposure to
aesthetics practically never become criminal. Almost never. I never heard of
anybody who played the violin for 30 years and then killed his grandmother.
You know? It just goes against your aesthetic grain.
You know?
Hello, Dr. Hawkins. I was raised as a Catholic and I struggle with what I think
you've termed as a fear of the judge. Fear of judgment. Fear, yeah. Yes, yes.
And I'm just wondering, I guess I would like that to go away. Will it ever go
away, that fear? Or will I just, will it just kind of recede as I
continue to work with... You have to have greater faith in the infinite mercy of God, see?
In the fact that God can see the defect of character. And therefore, there's a difference
between culpability and responsibility. They could learn to differentiate responsibility
and culpability. You can be responsible but hardly culpable because you don't have that
much brains to be that culpable. You understand?
Yes, yes.
Culpability would mean that you were of a very advanced capacity for understanding,
and then chose to defy God, which is a different thing. See? You're not capable of that.
So you don't think I have defied God?
You're not even capable of it, you know. You're not about to defy God in any way that
you understand God.
Hmm.
No. The childish fears of God, see?
And spiritual counseling of spiritual counsel.
OK.
they should have gotten you over that by now.
They used to have me see a priest about scrupulosity, you see?
Because I thought every sin showed up like on a glass plate behind you,
you know, and God could see this spot.
And I told you at the time I was gone the way that you're supposed to go to communion,
you're supposed to go to confession Saturday afternoon as late as possible,
so as few hours as possible.
Then you go to the earliest communions in the morning,
so there's very few hours in which your sin might get given by eye.
I tell you, I'm on my way to communion,
and there's a 30-foot Swanson swimming suit I had with this lady in a swimming suit.
Well, I told the old boy nothing but steroids run through his veins, you see?
Here's the 30 feet of feminine pulchritude, and I'm on my way to confession.
I don't know what I did.
Communion.
So I quickly shut off all my thoughts.
I tried not to look at this 30-foot lady.
30-foot long Swanson swimming suit.
The top is down on the top.
29 Model A Ford, you know?
I try not, I avert my eyes in the other direction.
Well, I don't know if a sinful thought,
I was scared that a sinful thought might have gone by without my even realizing it.
And I had fear and trepidation when I went for communion.
I thought when they pass the cup, if I take a drink out of that,
maybe lightning will strike me.
So anyway, I had to go for counseling
to develop a reasonable conscience.
So you maybe have a hypertrophy conscience,
leftover from childhood, see?
And maybe a couple of sessions with the priest
to help you get a more reasonable conscience.
Then what's the fear that comes up at the final doorway then?
That's a different fear.
Oh, that's a different lady that didn't know.
That's totally different.
It had nothing to do with sin and guilt.
The fear was there was nothing left.
It was a very high space.
Nobody, hardly anybody had ever been there.
If you only knew, I saw who'd been there.
And then came the last attraction.
All power, all power is yours.
Own it.
Now that you know you're not accountable,
that you're not, that you're free of all the things that you feared,
that you are far beyond that.
All power is yours.
Claim it, own it.
And I saw who had said yes and who had said no.
And it was ridiculous because at the time I was all that power.
How could I want that which I am already?
I was completely the everythingness of all possibility.
There was only one last thing to lay down before God.
And that came to me as the next realization.
That I laid everything and surrendered all except life itself.
And I thought this too, this too.
Everything had to be laid before God.
I laid ecstasy.
I laid bliss.
I laid serenity.
All.
All things.
The last thing that remained was life itself.
Sense of life itself.
That this too must be laid before the Lord.
So at that point I laid my life.
This to thee, O Lord, to which I surrender.
That which I believe is my life.
And then you see the core of the ego,
it is convinced it is the source of your life.
And it has been since the beginning of life on this planet.
And so then I did surrender my life.
And then a terror came up.
A terror.
A strong terror.
Of death.
And I died.
You actually die.
You fear.
You actually go with the agony of death.
You've never been through the agony of death before.
You all just left the body in order to avoid it.
And then came the agony of death itself.
Anguish.
Extreme.
And beyond that was then.
The revelation of infinite glory beyond all description.
Forevermore.
It only has to be gone through once.
But it's never been gone through before.
You can die hundreds of times and never go through it.
But it came up.
So I did it.
Also it brought up the fear of non-existence for its final run.
Which I was born with at age three.
And which had recurred later at level 850 of
Mesha.
That constantly surrendering the linear brings you to nothingness.
But when the nothingness came back this time I knew it was the Void.
I knew it was not the ultimate reality.
When I'd left other lifetimes as the hinata Buddhist I would arrive at the void.
And that'd be it for that lifetime.
This time because I'd had the experience in the snow bank of the presence of god.
I realized the absence.
It's like an infinite nothingness.
in comparison to an infinite everythingness of God
as absolute bliss.
And therefore, realizing the mistake,
I backed out of it because the presence of God
is signified by a profound and infinite love.
Profound, staggeringly, yeah.
Therefore, there's no mistake.
No mistake.
Thank you.
Yeah? Thank you.
Interesting question.
Hi, I was raised a Catholic, like that lady.
And I went to Marquette University in Milwaukee.
Oh yeah.
And I studied theology.
Oh, right.
And I didn't get all A's, like you did.
You what?
She didn't get everything like you did.
Oh.
So I've tried to make up for that since.
Oh yeah.
And done a lot of studying.
It's just theology, yeah.
Just theology.
Yeah.
I've studied your work and I've read your story
many times. Yeah.
And heard you talk about it.
And I've also read the stories of many of the mystics
and saints, especially the Catholic ones.
And one of the themes that seems to run through
those stories is this depression.
You describe being depressed for a long period.
Oh yeah, very profound.
And many of the saints describe that depression.
And then what?
So I'm just wondering if depression is part of
what we have to look forward to in the past.
Well, the struggle, depression is inevitable.
Yes, you're right.
All the Christian mystics describe states
when that spirit seems to leave you and you leave.
How could you, my beloved, leave me?
Like one has been deserted by one's lover, yeah?
A very profound state.
But you work it through, it's just a condition.
Yeah.
It's just a condition.
It's just a cognition?
Huh?
You said it's a cognition?
No, not a cognition, it's affective, affective.
A affective state.
Well, I'm terrified of facing that.
I feel like it's blocking my progress
because I don't want to go there.
Uh-huh, well, it's some other lifetime.
Put it off till another lifetime?
Okay.
All right.
Your faith and love of God becomes sufficient
that you're willing to go through that for thee, O Lord.
I see.
For thee, O Lord, do I face it?
Do I face this within myself
and I ask for your help and strength, see?
To look at the nothingness at the bottom of the depression,
feeling of worthlessness, whatever it may be,
that you failed God in some way, you see?
So you ask God's help and you just walk right through it.
At the other end is salvation.
So if it led to hell, I would tell you
to avoid it.
It doesn't lead to hell.
Because I've been through as bad as you can go through.
It doesn't lead you to hell.
It leads you away from hell, see?
You're fearing hell, that's all.
Pardon me?
Well, the higher levels of hell are anguish, depression,
you know what I'm saying?
I see.
Yeah, but they're not based on a reality,
so they're safe to walk through, yeah.
Thank you.
And then you come out and you're free of it forever.
Hi, thank you for the compass.
It's been very helpful.
My question is regarding the mind being 99% silent
and 1% hypnotized.
The mind being 99% silent.
Oh yes, yes, yes, yes, okay.
What actually has the power to induce mind
into state of hypnosis, and is it this state of hypnosis
through spiritual work I try to awaken from?
The ego is prone to suggestibility and to entrapment.
It's very easy to seduce the mind.
There's a whole slide we didn't get to,
the seduction of the ego by the novelty, the circus,
the carnival that goes on, you see, emotions and concepts.
So the mind gets glamorized by the drama of all that.
It gets hypnotized by it.
When there's a little accident by the side of the road,
the traffic backs up for miles.
There's nothing but a dented fender, a dented fender,
and they're backed up for miles.
See that?
If I can see through the illusion of that,
then you're free of it to travel.
Thank you.
You have to watch for the seduction of the mind
by the bizarre, the seduction of the mind by tragedy,
the seduction of the mind by oh, oh, isn't that terrible?
Those are all seductions.
You have to refuse the seduction.
The seduction of the mind by tragedy, the widow,
the whole sad story.
Everybody's got a sad story.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
Dr. Hawkins, in Power Versus Force, in Power in Space,
in the sports chapter, you write about Roger Bannister's
four-minute mile record.
And you mentioned that he was running for humankind
rather than for his own glory.
And I've always been very interested in having someone
change the focus from competitive sports
to non-competitive sports where you're
running against yourself instead of running against another team
or another person.
Yeah, yeah, uh-huh.
And I think that endurance events like the marathon
may be the most useful for people to learn
the power of intention.
Yeah, yeah.
I was myself a marathon runner.
I am a marathon runner.
And when you get to mile 21 or 22 or whatever, you hit the wall
and you feel that you just can't do it.
That's right.
But then your intention pulls you through.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
And then it's effortless.
Right, exactly.
It's like you're being run.
Yeah.
So I learned firsthand the power of intention just by doing it.
Oh, great.
Yeah.
And in January 2000, I created a new marathon-type race
from scratch to celebrate the new millennium.
And I coined the term millenathon,
and I called it the millenathons.
And we had the fastest field of women marathon runners
at any race that year.
But I also set a goal for myself to be a serial marathon.
So I ran 16 marathons in 16 months leading up to my race,
partly to promote my race at these other events.
So I say all this to put my question into context.
I'm thinking of a new project now, not to put on another race,
but to get some senior person who's 65 or 70 or older
to run a record marathon time that's faster than the 50 years
old record.
And my question is, will some record like this
have a similar effect to Roger Bannister's four-minute mile?
I still don't get what's the purpose of it.
The purpose is to show that one can do things from intention,
because we have all this talk about aging,
and you're over the hill.
Yeah, OK.
As long as you've got plenty of doctors and nurses there
announcing it, I wouldn't want the liability, the lawsuits
that are going on.
Well, the second part of my question
is that, do I myself have the capacity to do this?
Oh, I'm sure you've got the capacity to do it.
Can you calibrate it?
No, no, I'm just asking you to look at the wisdom of it.
You're soliciting aging people to press past lethal barriers,
and I'm thinking the legal fallout would kill you.
I'd be the first to sue you.
I didn't mean that.
I meant whether I could be the one to actually run the record time.
Oh, that's different.
That's different.
Now, that's up to the, you're looking at it as causality.
That's up to a multi-factors at the time.
Besides, why would you be interested in winning?
I just want to.
Forget about winning.
No, not winning, but running a record time to show that.
Yeah, that's winning.
To show that age doesn't matter.
Oh, age doesn't matter.
If age didn't matter, you wouldn't be even there.
If you didn't think about it, you'd be too old for that.
Move from the linear to the non-linear.
Do the same thing, though, with spiritual endeavor.
Run the spiritual race, yeah, that you can take with you.
The physical race you can't take with you when you leave this world.
Thank you.
Thank you for your question.
Take a picture?
Sure.
I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the,
I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the, I get
the.
I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the, I get the.
Yeah.
The energy of the truth.
Yeah, the energy is wonderful.
Energy is good.
Yeah, the energy's wonderful.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Did you get a sign?
Yes.
Hi, Dr. Atkins.
Thank you for your presence here, the darshan of your eyes, it's appreciated.
So, what I hear from you today is a bit of a comment in the beginning.
For me it's like human form and the animal form, the human form is like an egg, a cocoon
for the soul.
Like at 200 we begin to break the shell and at 600 it's like we get out of the shell and
we go and fly forever after that.
It's all this human process for soul, am I right?
Yes, 600 is set in the classic bliss state, in 600 you enter the enlightened states.
Could we have a glimpse of that and go back after or it's a permanent process when we
get there?
Is it a permanent process?
Can we have a glimpse, an overview of that?
Over 600?
Yes.
What do you mean, can you get back from it?
Yes, I mean that can we have a glimpse, an overview of the 600 state and come back again?
Don't worry about coming back again, in the level of 600 coming back again is not even
a thought.
You're worrying about it from a different level.
What you're asking is a conundrum.
I'm getting to the point where I don't care if I live or die as a physical being when I
care about whether I live or die as a physical being.
No, because 600 is no longer a relevant question.
Oh, it's because I mentioned that a lot of people leave there.
Yes, about 50% will leave.
Okay.
In fact, on each level a high percent will leave.
There's very few that makes it all the way through because most will leave the physicality
by then.
Is it hard on your body to stay on this level?
No.
No?
It's a strain going up.
When you start clearing the energy fields in the 800s or so, yes, it's a burning sensation.
If there's anything negative that you're holding in mind from the collective, it's
because it's an intolerable painful burning sensation like all through your aura.
So you research and find out what kind of an energy it is you're holding and clear it
and purify it and then it disappears again.
Yeah.
Okay.
Did you ever see that kind of light of things?
No.
I can't see it.
It looks like a Christmas wreath.
Yes.
Did you ever see that?
What?
No.
It's around sometimes, around my eyes.
Oh, that's a different thing that you're asking me.
The inner light, it has no configuration.
Yeah.
Okay.
The inner light has no configuration.
No.
It's a state of being.
A state of radiance of being.
Yes.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
I am from Montreal, so I'd like to know if somebody has any questions.
Yes.
Okay.
Thank you.
And I would like to know if someone near Montreal is around here so maybe we can meet
and have...
Is there a Montrealite around here, anybody?
Yes.
Sometimes...
There are some people from Canada.
Yes.
Okay.
So, because...
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
I would like to have a picture too.
Yes.
Yes, that's good.
Do you have a French accent?
Yes, I have a French accent.
You like the French accent?
I like the French accent.
Yes.
it has a certain
plaza to it
a certain panache
you know what I say
you talked about
non-existence
I'm going to cry
and my question is
does
non-existence have
potentiality
no
so how are you rescued
from the pits of hell
by transcendence
not by non-existence
not by
by transcendence not by non-existence
no by potentiality
do you have the potential
to be rescued
is that something
so even in
non-existence
it's not a reality
so you can be
rescued from that
yes
okay
otherwise you would stay there
right
okay
thank you
yes there will be nothing
to bring you back out of it
and nothing to realize the error
Dr. Hawkins
I don't have a question
I just came here
to be
sitting here across from you
God bless
thank you
thank you for being my teacher
Dr. Hawkins
question I wanted to ask you
is that
you say that everything happens spontaneously
including all human thought
happens spontaneously
everything is spontaneous emergence of potentiality into actuality
depending on karmic propensities and local conditions
and intention
depends on context
so intention also plays a part in
the likelihood of it manifestation
now how does that relate to free will
that's the part that I want to ask you about
that's a very interesting question
and I could write you a whole chapter about it right now
it has to do
the non-linear are like prevailing energy levels
in which the more powerful overshadow the lesser
so the lesser operating within the overall larger field of the greater
so by intention you've already set the greater
within that you have the exercise of the greater
the more powerful the lesser operating overshadowed the lesser operating
that's the idea
you understand the complete discussion of free will
would take us a little while
because you're setting propensities and likelihoods
this is interesting in advance theoretical physics
that the more often you make a certain decision
the more likely that decision will recur
it's called the Zeno effect or something like that
that likelihood increases
although it's not a cause and effect relationship
it's that you're affecting the field
so the field is the field of the field
The field is one of likelihoods, so by choice you're setting up fields of progressive dominance
in which the lesser field, although they're intrinsically independent, they are only operating
within a higher field.
So let's say if the highest field of your life is to serve God, then lesser decisions
about health or longevity and many other things will be subservient to that, how you see that
serves your overall life of request, you see?
Should I come all this way and go through all the trouble to come here and speak to
all these people?
I can live without it, right?
I'm sitting at home with my cat and I'm contented and happy.
What do I need?
Why in the world am I here?
So that's the question we ask each other.
Should we do this thing or not?
So we say, well, what is the purpose of our knowing all the things we know except to
share it with others?
So the answer comes out, how do we better serve God?
So when this foundation asked us to come and speak, we both spoke to each other, what do
you think?
She says, yes, well, yes, we should do so.
Then to confirm it, we'll ask the arm, that serves us good, the arm says yes.
So you see, depending on the context of what you think your most important role in life
is, you see, if we had some young children at home who were sick, it might come out differently.
No, don't come.
Don't go.
It serves our good by staying home and helping the young children.
So it would depend on what stage of life, you know?
Are you going to write a book or a chapter about free will and this subject?
Free will.
He wants to write you a chapter in some book about free will.
Yes.
It's a little hard to contextualize.
I, as I said, I gave you a reference, three recent articles on intention, attention.
Attention.
Attention set.
Medina.
M-E-D-I-N-A.
It appeared in the last three issues of Psychiatric News, not the last three, but over the last
year in three sections in the neurological studies of intention, attention setting, intention.
Yeah, it's very interesting to see because the whole argument about free will ends up
as a redundancy and hoisting around in the level of the free 24-20, 4-40 level of the
disease.
You know, it's like a dissertation, which is very boring because everybody knows all
the arguments for and against free will, you see?
Yes.
And so it has to be transcended.
I'll tell you whether or not it exists.
Free will, as commonly understood, is an existent reality, which is, as I understand it, it's
a reality.
All right.
I'll have to explain it.
Yes, because psychology would say all decisions are determined.
You know, you understand, conditioned and determined and cultural and habitual and neurological
and et cetera, et cetera.
If you operate from the option that you have free will, I think that would serve the highest
karmic good.
That would serve the highest karmic good to operate as though it were a reality to resist.
So I see because that's taking responsibility.
I see that.
So it's because of taking responsibility.
It's better to take responsibility.
Yeah.
So you take responsibility and make a mistake than not take responsibility and be correct,
in which there may be no karmic merit whatsoever.
That makes me feel very good.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, Suzanne.
Thank you.
We have only about half an hour.
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
Yeah.
There isn't that many people left.
We're moving along.
Try to get everyone.
Yes.
Thank you for coming today.
My question has to do with an experience I've had.
I'm sorry.
My experience I've had for many years, I can be doing ordinary things during my day.
And these words will escape my mouth that I wasn't thinking about at all.
And the words are, I want to go home.
I want to go home.
And lately, I've just been taking those words as a reminder to come back to context.
And come back to the field to remind myself to do that.
Is there something else I should be doing with that?
With coming home?
Yes.
They keep coming.
The term, I want to go home.
Yes.
Or I want to be home.
Oh, yes.
Keeps coming back to her.
Oh, yeah.
During the day.
What did she want to do with it?
Well, she said she took it as though it was more or less coming back to the spiritual
self.
Oh, yes.
Yeah.
And she's not interpreting it in a corporeal way.
No.
Okay.
So, then you're already heeding that imagination.
Are you not?
You're here, aren't you?
Yeah.
So, what is the question?
Just, is there something, am I repressing something?
Is there something I need to be doing other than that?
No.
You're just looking at a spiritual reality.
Okay.
A lot of people don't look at it until they're on social security.
Yeah.
Yes.
Are you getting a head start?
Okay.
Thank you.
Thank you for being here.
Well, Emma, we ought to start looking at that, don't you suppose?
Having Mind Mastery
Yup!
Yeek!
There's over 700 people here including me who would like to go to enlightenment
and you indicated in the lecture this morning that we're headed there and yet only a few
people make it.
Is that?
Yeah.
Is it a possibility for us to make it in this lifetime or is this still a many lifetime experience?
Yeah, the requirement is extraordinary and so therefore fewer number because the demand is extraordinary,
not that people couldn't, but the willingness to say yes.
Also, you can get off the bus at certain levels, you see,
and most get off the bus on a letter and not going to see it all the way through to the end.
So it's a matter of commitment and...
Tenacity.
...and discipline.
Yeah, yeah, tenacity of the spiritual will.
And also you have to have some awareness of what the levels are so you get some idea of where you are
and whether you want to continue on further.
Also, there's no rush, you don't have to get there, you know, in this lifetime, you know, anyway.
Once you get to 600, it can take forever.
It doesn't make any difference, you know.
Bliss is bliss.
I think there was some prior contract within myself to go further, yeah.
There was some prior contract, understanding agreement, understanding agreement, yeah.
So it seems as though there is the feeling of perfection and peace
and on the other hand this necessity to work hard and solve a lot of problems
and help a lot of people.
And serve and change everything and make it better.
No, forget about making it better.
I'll go along with you on everything except making it better.
You just set up resistance.
Better doesn't want to get better.
Question I have is I see you working hard when you could be home with the cat
and there's just, to me, it sets up some duality there and I kind of...
It's a commitment.
It isn't either or.
It's what one feels called upon.
As one's profession, avocation, commitment.
You know, it's like when I couldn't see one more patient and they would call.
There's nobody else to see me.
What are you going to do?
I say, well, God, and I'll get a yes.
Who else is going to do it? See?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Okay.
You should ask, how is Kitty?
How is Kitty doing?
Kitty is feeling okay.
She's out of pain.
He's able to eat today.
He's got low iron.
He's got low blood iron.
He's not hungry, but he feels okay.
We have a sick kitty at home.
We check out the kitty from here.
The one thing about kinesiology is you can do it anywhere, anytime about anything, see?
And when people struggle to accept it, it always boggles my mind.
Here it is, how to tell truth from falsehood.
Probably the most incredible thing ever discovered.
And it goes right over people's heads.
And I say, for absolutely free, in a matter of seconds, you can find the absolute truth
about anything, anywhere in the universe, anywhere in time.
And they go, uh-huh.
Uh-huh.
You can check out the imponderable.
There's no way you can measure how much pain the kitty's having, et cetera.
You'd have to get a blood sample.
It'll cost you hundreds of dollars, but we can find out in seconds.
See?
So isn't it the handiest darn thing you ever saw?
It is.
Yeah, you can catch it, too.
Shootin' marbles or anything.
Yeah?
Before I started studying your works, I learned to pray in a way where you become
aware of the presence and then you actually try to hold something in mind in order to
change conditions.
Oh.
And since I've been studying your work, that no longer feels appropriate to me at
all.
Correct.
That's correct.
But one of my responsibilities at Church is to help說
pray for other people in that way and it doesn't it doesn't feel right I feel
like I'm trying to manipulate God I understand what you're saying but but
it's been suggested that if I didn't I would be spiritually arrogant because I
need to go to their level you can just do it as a devotional act without
looking at it as a causality see as an act of devotion let's say for the sake
of one's faith for the faith faith the sake of one's congregation one could
enter into a group prayer now whatever the consequence of that is not your
problem but to go ahead and state out loud that I know conditions are a
certain way for a certain person well I don't know what you mean by well when I
am in prayer with a person I'm actually supposed to say out loud that I have the
belief that there can the conditions in their life are a certain way and that it
will happen based on my belief I don't know that I I'd call that outlining
outlining
yes I would call that outlining you know telling God what he should do about
what giving him those specifics I don't think I would feel enthused about that
no I don't I would certainly be happy to join the communal prayer for the
goodness and the highest state of being of some person so just praying for their
highest good and leaving it up that's all you can really do and that's the
highest way I can be of service I think so to send them all your love and
forgiveness don't forget this subject of their own karma so
you know your five cents worth of you know may not come much in the plate you
know but you had your two cents worth for what good it does all right thank
you the person must have some kind of good
camera to be pulling all that prayer in their own direction you know for one
thing yeah when people my question is when
people are hurt unwillingly like for instance two thousand people in 9-11 or
when a big group of people are big groups like at the farmers market a car
goes astray and kills 50 people would you say for instance that they attracted
it or it's karmic destiny or would you say it just is that all is perfect I mean
tell me your explanation for those kinds of actions where people are different
ways of addressing it it's not limited to just one way of looking at I'll give
you a multiple ways you can look at it I'll give you a multiple ways you can
look at it there is the principle of group karma if you look at the history
of mankind you will see millennium after millennium man massacred the innocent
out of sheer savagery selfishness greed sexual rape they didn't take prisoners
they killed them all the Goss the Visigoths the Vikings the Huns the great
Mongol hordes slaughtered people by the millions greater than World War two what
is the karmic propensity
what is the karmic consequence of that and how can they undo that how can you
undo that you've killed the you know 50,000 people how can you undo that you
may not have culpability but you've got responsibility because you're ignorant
you didn't have any culpability in the form of ignorance I mean in the form of
sin see because you were too ignorant to know that was sinful but you do have
responsibility so even though you hit somebody with your car
say it's not your responsibility you're still accountable in the court understand
so there's moral responsibility and culpability and moral responsibility
manslaughter means yes you did kill that person culpability means to what degree
are you guilty
you might have maximum responsibility and zero guilt or might be other way
around because your intention was to kill them just cause you didn't manage
it
mean that you didn't try. So there's group responsibilities. So my understanding, because
we did the distribution of the consciousness levels on the planet, you see great hordes
of people tend to come in at certain consciousness calibrations, and they all tend to distribute
themselves in the same places on the planet, the same continents. Other continents are
of a completely different calibration level, and they seem to come in together. They have
different lessons to learn, you see. There's individual as well as group karma, culpability
and accountability, you see. Also, even though you didn't agree, once you cheer something
on, you join the karmic responsibility. You don't have to be out there killing people
in the killing field, but the fact that you cheer Hitler on and march with a goose step
and his...
army, you are giving him support, and now you are taking on part of the karmic responsibility
for the Nazi fascism. You didn't have to be out there actually killing the person in
a uniform, but the fact that you cheered on the Fuhrer to kill, in the end, it amounted
to 10 million or 100 million, God knows what. You take on some responsibility. So the apologists
for evil, you see, even though they do not personally commit it, you see, they are doing
it.
They are taking on a certain responsibility.
Even if you're just going to the market to shop, the person that gets killed, why did
that person get killed and not...
What did she say?
The person next to them.
Say you're in the market and you were shopping and the car came through and hit the person
next to you, but not you. What would be the purpose of that?
Well, you're looking for a logical purpose. Karma doesn't work that way. It works as propensities,
collective propensities in very ordinary people.
Yeah.
They're often in group form, you see. You have to think of the difference between accountability
and culpability. Once you understand that, it resolves it. As I said before, being born
a human, you already have a karmic past, do you not? What do you need a savior for?
So you think it's...
Karmically, you're born with a need for a savior already, your original sin, right?
So I think it's an issue too complex for me to understand.
I think only divinity, you see. Why is it whole races, generation after generation,
are wiped out over and over again, see? So why do we choose to reincarnate within that
particular race, knowing its karmic propensities? We choose to be that which we become.
Okay, we only have a half hour left and I know there's a lot of questions. We have
to be out of here...
Okay, run faster, faster, faster, faster.
...at 5 o'clock. So if there's anyone in line here...
If there's anyone in line here that have books that we need to sign or they want signed,
I need to do them now in case we run out of time.
So the books can come from this way and the questions can come from this way. Is that
the way we're doing it?
Yep.
Okay.
Sign this one.
Yes, we are.
Hello.
Yes.
I knew I was going to do this. I want to say thank you for your work, your wonderful
books.
Okay.
I heard during reading Devotional Nonduality that coming here was allowing me to speak
to the allness through David Hawkins. Is that true?
What did she say?
Coming here allows you to speak.
Yes.
She says, through you. Is she speaking to the allness?
It occurred to me...
There isn't any other reality except the allness. Yes, you're always speaking to the allness.
Right.
You didn't know the reality.
But your experience going through the door was...
Yes.
Of course.
You're a thrive.
Yes.
Yeah, and...
... your experience going through the doorway to the ultimate death of ego...
Yes.
... and experiencing the transcendence, the allness, you gave up yourself, your small
S-E-L-F.
Yes.
So you are existing here with a straight shot. It's like...
I know we're all divine and we're...
But you are...
To say, you know, we have divine guidance.
Yeah.
The sacrifice of the small self really allows the large self
to become dominant, up-revealing, and any sense of separation.
You can try and cite it.
Do you get transmission of your energy through your DVDs as well?
I was just watching your review of the work for 2006.
Oh, the energy of the speaker?
I don't think you can write on there.
The energy of the speaker transmits through the, what did she call that thing, a DVD?
DVD.
A DVD.
Yes.
Thank you.
DVDs and DVDs and CDs and a whole thing.
Cassettes.
Yes.
And now there's a toy player that you can make a play on.
iPod.
Could I do a portrait of you?
May she do a portrait?
I'm an artist.
Went to the Art Institute in Chicago.
I don't know.
I have to think about it.
Okay.
If you can do it in a second, yes.
Sounds good.
Thank you, Susan.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Sorry, this has been a little...
Susan, do you have a question?
Yes.
My brother-in-law has served two tours in Iraq, and he has orders.
Your brother-in-law, what?
Has served two tours in Iraq, and he has orders.
His orders for February.
Yes.
And he's been talking to me in the evening about the atrocities and the killing that
he commits, and I tell him about exactly what you said today about the fly, in terms of
you can't actually kill something, but when I'm talking to him, I would love to have a
bug in my ear to say what you would say to someone, because I'm not really qualified.
You're trying to relieve his anguish?
Yes.
Or just understand or have compassion?
What would you say to somebody who...
What would you say to somebody who was going through that anguish?
You're trying to relieve his anguish about what he has to do.
Yes.
Right.
But I also don't want him to feel so guilty that he gets himself killed.
Don't give me six questions now.
Okay.
What is it you want to do?
You want to relieve his anguish.
No, I would like to know what I should say, or what you would say.
What would you say to someone that had to serve a tour in Iraq and...
I know.
What is their intention?
You want to relieve his anguish?
His guilt?
What?
What do you want to say to him?
Is he doing good about it?
I want him to find his peace with what he's...
All right.
I would like him to find his peace with what he's done.
She's worried about him not having peace with the actions that he has to commit.
Oh, yes.
Well, it could take a lifetime to recontextualize that.
He's doing his duty as he sees that he must do it.
So that's one priority.
Okay.
So then he has to understand the difference between responsibility and culpability, et
cetera.
It will take him some years of spiritual work to come to terms with it, and that's one of
the reasons for it.
The value of human life, the value of under what conditions.
Is sacrificing your life for a higher principle?
You know, it's his spiritual work to do.
You can only be of help to give him alternate ways he could go with it.
It's a profound and difficult thing.
It takes a lifetime.
Anybody who's been in the service to evaluate ethically, morally, spiritually, ethically,
morally, spiritually, psychologically, the value and consequences of all the decisions
you've made.
It's not just about killing people.
It's many other things.
The camaraderie, the loyalty, the love of your brothers.
The love of the brothers lasts a lifetime.
Maybe to love others as much or greater than yourself could be the greatest lesson.
So it depends on what the lesson is karmically in his lifetime for him.
I learned to love beyond all restriction, no matter what.
All of us together, forever loved and do love, no matter what.
No matter what.
We forgive and love each other forever, no matter what.
So that's what I learned.
Now, he may have something different to learn.
You understand?
All right.
We are sending DVDs to several servicemen over there at this time, too.
They have called and ordered them.
Yes.
And so we are sending them, too.
So he might be learning unconditional love.
I mean, that's what I learned, to let nothing stand.
I don't care what my brother did.
He's going to have us all crying here.
I know.
Cut it out.
A mutual friend of ours, Marcy and Wayne Dyer.
I was with Marcy last summer, and Wayne was there.
And she was telling me about this healer.
He was real.
Healer?
In Brazil.
The John of God.
Oh.
Do you want to calibrate John of God?
No, thank you.
Okay.
He's a fake?
We don't know.
You don't want to go there?
We just don't.
Do you want to ask permission?
I already know the answer.
All right.
Why do you want to know?
You want to go there?
After I talk with you, it will help me decide.
But yeah.
But I was going to get your opinion.
All right.
Thank you.
I ask we have permission.
No, I don't think so.
We don't have permission, no.
Okay.
So it's up to you, karmically, to make the decision.
See, the will to get well will be operative no matter what.
So your belief and your capacity to get well, anybody could be the trigger.
It could be him.
It could be anyone.
Or it could be none.
Okay.
Do I get a picture with you?
You don't need to give away your power to someone else.
I got you.
All right.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Kind of an ailment.
Oh, don't worry about that one.
That'll cure itself.
Yeah, yeah.
We can guarantee you a .
Oh, you were.
Who are you?
Oh.
I keep it to myself, I never hear anything.
Hi Dr. Hawkins.
Yeah.
God bless you.
My question concerns consciousness level 600 and non-duality.
According to your books, once a person reaches this level, there's no identification with
the body.
No separation between the self and the world.
And you say all sense of a personal self disappears.
My question is, isn't there still some awareness, witness, localized in a body?
And even if the soul leaves the body, isn't there still a personal soul?
So each of us has our own unique experience.
Couldn't that be considered...
What are you worrying about? I don't get what you're worrying about.
Make it simple.
Why are you worrying about level 600?
I'm trying to understand what it means to get to that level.
It means that you stop thinking about yourself as a self-existent causal agent.
There is no personal self making decisions or doing anything.
Stop thinking there's a separate causal entity called me.
Okay?
And it continues on doing that because of the constant gains.
As you keep surrendering the gains, there's no gain to believing that anymore and it stops doing that.
And suddenly you go into a high state of joy and bliss.
It's the perfection of love.
You go from 500 lovingness to 540 unconditional lovingness.
Then the love intensifies.
By 570 it becomes saintly.
By 580, 590 it becomes ecstasy.
Extreme ecstasy, you can dance for days non-stop without eating, drinking, sleeping, tirelessly, day after day, endless, ecstatic joy.
Then it comes to you.
This too, O Lord, must be laid down to thee, O Lord, and you lay down the ecstasy, you lay down the ecstasy to God.
It's like the ultimate of all highs, beyond methadrine, beyond anything.
Anything you can expect.
This too, O Lord, must be laid down.
So you lay down your ecstasy and surrender that to God.
And then comes on a piece of such profundity as beyond description.
Beyond which there is nothing more desired or wanted, etc.
And if consciousness and life goes on, it does because of some karmic propensity
because there's no personal you to make a decision about such a thing.
Thank you.
Yes.
This too, O Lord.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
God bless you.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I am moving as fast as I can move, yes.
Minutes.
Yes.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
I wanted to ask a question that has to do with oneness.
And you've spoken, I hear you mention a lot of times, the self of the teacher with the capital S, or the self of the student.
And I'm just wondering, is there not just one self?
Is there more than one?
It's the same self with a capital S.
It's the same self.
You know.
So that which is looking out through me is identical to that which is looking out through all others?
Yes.
And that it is one and the same.
Well, it's the capacity for conscious awareness of existence to begin with,
which everybody has already inherited by virtue of being human, you know.
Then you realize that this is an impersonal quality.
It's a quality of consciousness itself.
And you stop thinking of it as a product.
You stop thinking of it as a product.
You stop thinking of it as a personal I that has, you know, reached that state of awareness.
It's the same I.
Okay.
Thank you.
Come on.
Uh-huh.
Yes.
Thank you.
In case I blink.
Hi.
You answered my questions already.
Good.
But I just wanted to tell you that I wanted to thank you for liberating me.
I've been studying.
I've been studying religion since I was 12.
I entered a seminary at 12 and I was so frustrated and confused and you liberated everything.
You made it.
Good.
I appreciate it.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Dr. Hawkins, could you expand on contemplation and surrender and how I can improve that skills?
Contemplation?
Contemplation is more subtle than meditation.
Contemplation.
Uh-huh.
It's a way of holding something in mind as an attraction to divinity to reveal the answer to it.
It's like a mudra.
I hold what is the highest service to go to California and speak to a large group?
Which is the highest service to the old Lord?
To say and sustain that which depends on my love for survival or to really represent an energy
and...
...knowingness.
So, it's a yin kind of an approach, you see.
Contemplation is more like a yin in which I draw from the infinite wisdom, unknowingness
by virtue of the question, you see.
Contemplative lifestyle is a very yin.
And how does surrender fit into that along with contemplation?
You know what I mean by yin?
Yes.
I don't know what's the question.
By yin.
By being.
The supplication.
Divinity cannot refuse you.
Do you have permission?
Divinity cannot refuse.
Resist.
What more do you want?
Thank you.
You have God at your service.
That's very good.
Thank you very much.
God is at your service.
Therefore, a spiritual teacher sees himself as being at your service.
The teacher is to be at the service of the student.
And vice versa.
Thank you.
And I repeat.
I repeated earlier, come here, by devotion, Krishna says, thou art mine.
Since all questions come and go, and tomorrow or a year from now we will all forget about what we asked or what we talked about,
I would like to spend a few moments in your presence, in your stillness, if it's possible.
You are now doing so. It is done.
Thank you.
It lasts forever.
I just had a very quick question. Is the spiritual energy the same thing as the Holy Spirit?
No, really. Well, yes, it is. I see how you're asking it.
Thank you.
It's an energy field of consciousness which you can now calibrate extremely high.
Earlier today I understood you to say that if a person calibrates below 200, that you really can't talk with that person.
My question is,
Well, you're talking on a different plane, yes. You can talk to them.
My question is, if a nation calibrates below 200 and they do acts of violence, how do we as a nation respond from power rather than force?
I couldn't tell you. I couldn't tell you. See, what you value is meaningless.
Let's say I think democracy is the most wonderful thing in the world. You should have it. I'm going to sit in your seat.
That guy is such a stupid cuckoo man. I don't know how I give him any time and all.
To give the common man a vote is the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
He's so ignorant and stupid. If he wasn't, he wouldn't be worshipping me as his savior.
Stalin, Hitler, all the great ones, Ivan the Terrible, all thought the populists were scum.
In fact, they'll tell you they're scum.
Hitler thought all the Germans deserved to die for losing the war.
And, generation after generation, you know how you can tell it's coming?
First of all, it always goose steps. It always does the goose step.
It always has a big picture that they carry of the leader.
They all pledge allegiance to the leader. They all cheer.
And they all die in the end. Always the same signal.
Over and over, man doesn't get it.
The goose step. The goose step. Don't you see the goose step, yeah?
The militarism. Dying for the leader in the great posters over and over again.
What can you tell people like that?
Don't you read history books? What should you say to them?
What do we as individuals...
Pray for them.
Pray for them. Thank you.
I don't know. It caused me to cry over and over and over and over.
The same picture, the same story, the same parade, the same goose step.
The same goose step. Generation after generation.
I look at it in today's newsreel, and it's the same as the 1930s when I was a kid.
Same goose step.
Hi.
Yeah.
First, I would like to express an infinite gratitude to that which has allowed every truth and wisdom
come and unfolding through you.
Your work and your staff.
Just expressing infinite gratitude.
Now my question.
I have three sets of pairs.
This keeps coming to my mind.
I don't have, like, any idea what to make out of it.
First set, and I would like to see if you have an input or if there is a correlation or relationship.
Right brain, left brain, conscious mind, subconscious mind.
Is there a relation, correlation?
Do you have an input?
I'm trying to...
Okay.
I have three sets of pairs.
I feel...
Three sets of what?
Pairs.
Like, right brain and left brain.
Conscious mind and subconscious mind.
Is there any relation, correlation?
Okay.
I'll give you the second.
All right.
Right brain and intuition.
Are they one and the same?
Right brain and...
And intuition.
Not one and the same.
They're not identities.
People process.
Instinctual information below consciousness level 200 through their left brain, which
triggers adrenaline emergency response, fight or flight.
Yes.
More evolved, over 200, the person now processes things differently with the right brain, in
which they perceive essence, not just appearance.
The left brain is only interested in appearance, and the right brain is interested in what
is the essence and the truth.
You see?
Yes.
And it's more benign.
The right brain puts out oxytoxin, oxytocin, and neurotransmitters, which support peacefulness
and love and caring about other people.
Yeah?
Yes.
Yeah.
Okay.
The last pair that I have, which you probably have answered, transcending duality.
Yes.
And energizing the right brain through certain activities.
Like, if I'm riding with my left hand, this is energizing the right brain?
No.
Because you're just talking about motor activity.
I'm not talking about motor activity.
Okay.
No.
Not motor activity.
All right.
It doesn't have anything to do with handedness.
Yes.
No.
Okay.
Transcending duality and psychoanalysis, removing the blocks between right brain and left brain.
Communication.
Allowing more communication.
Is that why, like, people have denial.
They suffer because they try to push things away, not admitting it.
Is transcending duality the same as allowing more communication between right brain, left
brain?
No.
It's not.
You answered her.
You understand her.
Yeah.
She said that the right brain and the left, she's trying to come into that.
Which side of the brain is non-duality?
Oh.
It would be in a right-handed person.
The right side of the brain, yes.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Does duality exist?
You don't have to worry about this.
Okay.
Unless you're writing a paper on neurology and psychology and the physiology, neurologic
physiology of psychology.
All right.
Yeah, we have to close.
We have to be out of here by five.
All right.
Thank you.
If you've got a quick question, you can be quick.
You know how to be precise and quick?
Quick.
I understand.
All right.
Thank you.
Quick.
Eins, zwei, drei, go.
One, two, three.
Thank you.
Quick, yeah.
What's the difference between preference and positionality?
Oh, positionality is a decision, and a preference is merely a choice.
So preference is okay.
Yeah.
What?
Preference is okay.
Yeah.
Sure.
Preference is a position.
Okay.
Thanks.
Yeah.
It's freedom of choice.
Okay.
We have to be out of here.
I'm sorry.
We couldn't make it.
There you go.
All right.
You're too slow with your questions.
Come up and ask questions.
I'm sorry.
We have to be out of here right at 5 o'clock, and we cannot answer just the questions.
We try to get through everyone, and I'm so sorry.
We're still wired up.
Oh, God.
I give myself to you as your teacher.
I dedicate myself to you in return for which God gives me the presence of you.
You're my presence from God.
Thank you, Lord.
Amen.
I give thanks to all of you.
You are God's gift to me.
You all are God's gift to me.
Thank you.
They are a wonderful crowd, aren't they?
Very nice talk.
I wish I had a little more time to answer them fully.
I can't ... I have such a hard time understanding.
They want to shake hands and take pictures on the way out.
Is that all right with you?
Yeah, sure.