growing, developing field, and we learn as we go.
So the initial naivete, and then therefore people who were not able to do it tried to
do it and said it didn't work, and I couldn't understand why it didn't work because it worked
all the time, and in the video we did called Power Versus Force I think, you know, we used
naive children.
Some people say it's suggestion, you know, but in that videotape we used naive children.
They didn't know who Hippocrates was or anybody was, you know.
So a naive child, it worked very well.
So I must admit that was an ignorance on my part that I presumed everybody could do it.
So that's one of the errors of perception is you presume everybody's like yourself.
Everybody is, you know, eager to know the truth.
You know, for its own sake, and it was a crushing realization that most people do not
want to know truth for its own sake.
They really want a verification of what they already believe.
Okay, so that's enough of that rattling on.
I guess my question is I always wanted to know how deep is hell?
Is it below the level of consciousness scale?
Can you go below there?
It's extremely low.
It's a different dimension.
It's actually a different dimension.
Therefore it's not really calibratable on that scale.
There are other dimensions other than the ones we are familiar with.
There are those astral levels, upper, middle, and lower, you know what I'm saying?
So there are other dimensions, and I don't wish to do a scale for those dimensions, other
dimensions.
So if a human chooses or keeps choosing, what does that mean?
What does that mean?
If a human chooses or keeps choosing to deny truth and fall in calibration, is there a
point where they go to so low that one little spark of light has no chance to return?
It's like they're picked up as an easy pickings from other dimensions.
They call it demonic possession, right?
Is it actual life, part of life, or is it?
It's from a different dimension.
Different dimension, okay.
Different dimension, see?
All right.
I don't understand.
But...
It's like paradigms.
There are other dimensions.
You see?
Okay.
Very good.
Thank you.
You don't want to know about them.
You really don't want to know about them.
Like the crime that was revealed about what this guy was going to do to this little girl
a week or two ago, you don't want to know where that came from.
Just take my word for it.
It's no good there.
The hell that I went into was not...
I was in a hospital.
It was not like that.
What people depict as hell was the upper level.
I mean, that's just the jacks for openers.
The real hell was far, far more horrible than that, but not in a linear way.
It was nonlinear and timeless, and it was not horror.
It was despair at a level of hopelessness that went on forever, and you experienced
forever hopelessness.
Eons and eons.
Eons and eons of timeless hopelessness, and it's beyond description.
All I can tell people is you don't want to go there at all, no way.
You just do not want to go there.
You do not want to go there.
I think we believe you.
Yep.
I know that the intellect does not correlate with the level of consciousness.
I know that intellectually, but in life, I tend to lose track of that fact, so I wanted
to know, to help with discernment, if you could talk a little bit about that.
Yeah.
Do you want to talk a little bit about the origin of the intellect?
The origin of what?
The intellect.
Well, that of course is evolutionary, with the emergence of the prefrontal cortex.
Because of the advance of hominids, once the hominids stood up, then it had two limbs that
it didn't need for locomotion, and that gave it a tremendous advantage.
Of course, the next genetic improvement was the oppositional thumb.
Yeah.
So now you've got an oppositional thumb, you can do tools.
So the emergence of the prefrontal cortex and the gray matter there,
standing on one's feet and freeing up the front two limbs,
so they were now available for exploration instead of locomotion.
You could begin to become acquainted with things, and you could now do things.
So the use of tools was very singular.
And so when Lucy came around, that was three million years ago,
that was the beginning of what we call the modern hominid, you know, called man.
So would the intellect carry over from one lifetime to the next?
I don't know, dear, I don't know.
You mean if you learn algebra in one lifetime, you won't have to learn it next?
No, I don't think so.
It'd be nice, wouldn't it?
Take algebra one lifetime, solid geometry the next.
Dr. Hawkins, I've been working on surrendering the juice of the experiencer as things arise,
and finding it's a continuous process with seemingly no end.
Is there a way, I guess I don't understand truly deep surrender to the point where it doesn't come up anymore?
Yes, no, it takes years.
Don't forget my own evolution of years.
Persistence is what pays off.
Eventually it runs out.
Now you see the peculiar thing about the whole thought of I,
you'll see that the experiencer is trying to constantly fortress the reality of something separate called I.
So when you say I, in a way you're talking about greediness.
Greediness for claim.
It's a whole subject in itself.
I could write a book, well I started to write a book about it, I did one time, called I, I think.
Anyway, the I is, I can't write on that, it's some kind of a disc thing.
The I intrinsically is craving, and it claims authorship and ownership.
And it's constantly looking to reinforce, reforce itself.
The reason it has to constantly reinforce itself is because it's based on an illusion.
If it was based on a reality, it wouldn't have any interest.
No, it's always claiming that I did this, I thought that.
The, if you meditate on the concept I, period, just do nothing but hold I, and be with I.
I-ness, and see what happens.
Right, there's nothingness, then, or allness.
Those are concepts, I told you to just stay with I.
Just stay with I.
You're elaborating already.
Okay.
Just stay with I-ness.
I-ness.
The sense of it, the feelingness, the location, stay with I-ness, and see what happens.
And don't call it anything.
Right.
No, that's clustering it all over.
Just stay with I-ness.
I.
Not your thoughts about I, but the essence of I.
And you will see, it will dissolve, and you'll be left with that out of which I-ness arises.
We'll call you Swami, then.
Swami.
Swami-I.
Hi, Doc.
It seems to me that there's a fine line between surrendering everything to God and apathy.
So, I'm struggling a bit with, you know, why should I do things, when should I do things,
you know, even when I try to...
That's futility.
That's different.
You're labeling it as futile, or useless, or not worth anything.
Surrendering it means control, surrendering control of it, surrendering control of it,
surrendering trying to juice it, allowing everything to just be as it is.
So, I would just continue to do what I think is right to do, and surrender the outcome?
There's a neat phrase for it.
You're responsible for the effort, but not the result.
So result means trying to control, you know, trying to control, say, because you dedicate
your efforts to God, and then whatever is, is whatever is.
That's karma yoga.
Karma yoga means selfless service.
You're not looking at God.
You're looking at yourself.
You're not looking for any payoff.
You're not looking for any gain.
You do it for the sake of doing it.
Thank you very much.
Or you do it because you're the steward of certain talents, you know?
If you're a great pianist, you do it because that's your talent, and you're the steward
of that talent.
So you give your musicality to the world as a result of your stewardship of that gift.
Yeah?
Dr. Hawkins, does feeling the sensations of the body play a role in kind of, you know,
a role in contemplation?
It's something you have to, like, learn how to handle and transcend, just like you do
in meditation.
And eventually, then you discover the spontaneous, that the body and its functions are spontaneous
and autonomous, as you let go, trying to control them or resist them.
And you just accept that that's the way that is.
Like, a horse is what it is.
See?
You don't try and change the horse, but you accept the nature of the horse.
So you accept the nature of this protoplasmic embodiment, see?
And you have to make concessions to the limitations of protoplasm.
Protoplasm can only stand so much, you see?
So you learn to live within the limitations.
It's one of the reasons I say it's difficult to be a human, because you have the spiritual
aspects.
You've got the intellectual concepts.
You've got the emotionality to deal with.
You've got all the yeses and the noes.
You've got all the training, the brainwashing.
On top of all that, you've got this pile of protoplasm to look after.
It keeps you busy, you know what I'm saying?
When you're scratching your toe, you're trying to remember your mother-in-law's birthday,
and you can't remember it, and you feel guilty about that.
You're trying to process that, and just then, you start to sneeze.
On the way here this morning, there was something that went right out of my mind.
And it was, you know, I don't know.
I don't know.
Probably a kitty hair, you know.
I couldn't get it out.
I tried pulling it this way, had to go get an eye cup and wash it out.
You know what I mean?
That's just what I need as I'm leaving the driveway, you know, is to have to wash your
eye out, you know?
It reminded God.
I said, you know, it is difficult.
of being a human.
Oh, Lordy.
If we ever get where we're going,
we've earned it, I'll tell you.
It's a great accomplishment, I think,
to complete a human lifetime,
and it really is demanding on so many levels.
Yep.
Dr. Hawkins, you had said before
that sometimes God uses our minds to think.
How can we tell the difference
between when it is God who is using our mind to think
and when we are doing our own chatter?
Well, it's sort of a languaging problem.
You might say realizations
that are benevolent and holistic
and tend to heal, etc.,
one could ascribe them as coming from a higher source.
It doesn't have to be God personally.
But the radiance of that energy
tends to...
favor thoughts of a certain direction
and not favor thoughts in the opposite direction.
So I never see it as causation.
I see it as likelihood, potentiality.
You know, the intention of becoming spiritual
increases the potentiality
that certain thoughts are going to be more common
than they would be in a person who lacks that intention.
But they're not caused by the intention.
It's more likelihood.
Thank you.
Potentiality rather than likelihood.
It's really, in a way, physics.
Advanced theoretical physics.
Hello.
The question that I had was in reference
to something that I read in
Transcending the Levels of Consciousness.
You talk about surrender and devotion and faith.
And I would just like for you to,
if you would, expand a little bit on the faith
and its faith in what?
Faith is an aspect of personality
without which we can...
without which you couldn't live, you know?
You have faith in all kinds of things all the time.
Every time you put your foot down,
you have faith that your ankle's gonna hold you up.
So faith is really operative.
It has to do with expectation and expected reliability.
I can't do anything except write my name.
So, spiritual faith is something different.
Spiritual faith.
Placing your faith and hope in things unseen is trust.
So that's really trust.
The capacity to trust.
Placing your faith in things unseen, then,
comes as an inspiration to do that.
Now, to do that already increases the likelihood
of the fulfillment of that.
Not from a causal viewpoint.
You understand what I'm saying?
But then you have the likelihood of it is increased
by your commitment and your intention
that the response is going to be
more positive.
More probable in a certain direction than another.
So, you're affecting probability by intention.
So, trusting that the paths in front of me,
of the teachers that were the way-showers,
Yes?
That that's a safe path to follow.
Is that the faith that you're talking about?
Well, we go even farther than faith.
Because we look at the modern mind.
The modern mind would like some kind of mathematical
or logical or intellectual proof as well.
Right.
They would like to have it backed up.
Faith, without good works, you know, is empty.
So, faith for its own sake, then,
is already a certain kind of sacredness, is it not?
I think ocean.
Yeah, it is.
And you're not looking for payoffs.
So, it's sort of like karma yoga
in that you do it for its own sake
and not for some gain, to be gained by thereby.
But thereby you fulfill your own potential to evolve.
The skeptic has no belief in faith at all.
He ridicules faith, except in his own skepticism.
And he has great faith in that.
I get a kick out of that.
Yes?
Do you know there's that saying that God has a,
what is it, tell God you have a plan
and what is the sense of humor?
Tell God you have a plan and then everything just gets messed up.
And today I plan to go into the, on top of that, I think,
to the ocean.
on Shelby Road the other way
and just sit up there and contemplate
and then for some reason Tim picked up a book
and I thought this was a humorous book
this Scorpion book
well it changed my experience sitting up in the Red Rocks
I will tell you that
that was quite overwhelming
but then I wanted to share with you
that somehow the self gets me here
I'm not sure how that happens
because I get in your presence
and I really have a hard time functioning
a hard time what?
who asked you to function?
she just asks questions
but yet I crave this energy field
I hike in the mornings
I don't know how I get out there
or how I get back
but I'm always by myself
there's not an audience
and my spiritual stuff is kind of private
but then I get in your presence
and I come here
and I just crave coming into this energy field
and then I just want to be here
that's all I know
I know what you mean
and I don't really have a question or a story or anything
I just want to be here
that's very common
because you come with a question
but in a certain energy field
the question dissolves
and it's not a question
I don't even have a question
and I know I don't even have a question
I just want to sit here
I just want to be someplace
where I have
where it's familiar
and people understand
because of your own intention
you reflect that fact like a pool
that ripples in a pool to yourself
that's your own self
bouncing off of myself
so now you're only experiencing your own self
well
whatever
this happens when I get around you
I did a seminar with you
it was in Palm Springs
and you're usually wired up
and you didn't ever leave the stage before
and I was sitting on a row seat
and I had my eyes closed
just sort of taking your energy in
and then all of a sudden
with my eyes closed
I had goosebumps on my arms
and the hair on my neck went up
and I started having problems breathing
and then I was getting teary
and I finally opened my eyes
like what is going on
and you were standing next to me
and every time I get in this presence
this happens
and it's just
it's a phenomena
it is a phenomena
I will tell you that
and it's just wonderful
and I don't know
what I would do without you
it's autonomous
it occurs in the spiritual world
it happens of its own
I don't know what I would do without your teachings
because I would be
they're wonderful
they just help me know
what's going on in my life
and I go
oh that's what's important
that's because of who you are
no
if you were somebody else
you'd think I'm a nuisance
I am like
I
I put your video going
and I go
thank you God
thank you for this man
God thank you for this man
everything makes sense
when I listen to your words
so thank you God
yeah
because you're aligned with divinity
in this way
thank you very much
if you were not with baseball
you wouldn't feel that
I'm not much on the ball field
I can't see the ball coming at me
that's why they
they wouldn't let me on the field
Dr. Hawkins
thank you so much for your books
I live to read them every day
and they've certainly transformed my life
right now I'm dealing with something
that you have dealt with
and perhaps I can gain some insight
from you
how to go about
dealing with this
with chronic pain
and potential
a great potential
for physical disability
it seems inevitable
I've tried a lot of things
allopathic
and alternative medicine
and it seems to be
a degenerative process
so you know
being very galvanized
you're mentally degenerating
mentally degenerating
on top of it
good luck to you
right
happy imbecile
happy
very happy
that's what I'd like to be
is happily
happy
is happily in pain
is it possible
how does
I guess what I'm asking
I know you
transcended
pain
and of course
I would not put myself
at the same level
I don't know
that I could
but are there any directions
for dealing with it
so that you can actually
function in life
and do things
other than
you can't label it
pain anymore
you're not experiencing pain
pain is a concept
a thought
see
there are certain sensations
coming up
what you do is you completely surrender and let go any resistance you become one
with the sensation and you thereby disappear them because you can't
experience that which is not resisted so I've tried that I didn't say this is
taking me years but just that's the idea is to constantly surrender also clear
anything in yourself that you think suspect karmically might be an
underpinning of it you understand what I'm saying when you say surrender do you
mean somehow forgive it within yourself admit it thank you I think that answers
it I will proceed and hope it all just dissolves away
next time I see you sometimes the serious thing to do is to ask for
forgiveness for that within within yourself of which you no longer recall
which brought such things to others well Lord forgive me for having brought
suffering pain into the life of others sometimes I think out of guilt out of
the pain you've brought into the life of others which you've forgotten you bring
it upon yourself and once you forgive yourself for that tends to receive
forgiveness and a POWERFULness all the time
it's kind of the fire I'm looking at you different and I thought well you know
he's you're big in real life you're like this
I believe I am a baby compared to midgets yes that's why I like going to
Korea everybody was my height
Really, I felt like a big man. I looked down and everybody was about the same level I was.
Pow!
This is neat. This is like a six-footer must feel.
Go ahead.
First of all, my sister wanted to say she loves you a lot, and thank you very much because you changed her life.
And all she's read is Power vs. Force.
And also friends from Maui, Hawaii send their love.
And I love you very much.
My question is, you often talk about having stewardship of one's gifts and one's assets.
What if all you have is debt and you don't know what your gifts are?
And what?
And you don't know what your gifts are.
Well, to begin with, debts, I guess.
See, because debts become a motivator, do they not?
Yeah, you don't want to have them.
So what do debts mean?
What do debts lead you to do?
Go to work.
Yeah.
Ask Broccoli.
What did Broccoli say?
Go to work.
Get a job.
I was sitting in my study and all of a sudden Broccoli would go, go to work.
Brings me up every time.
Go ahead.
Well, it's actually, it's not the debts that are the problem.
Huh?
The debts themselves are just the debts.
They come, they go.
Yeah, that's good.
It's more not really having an idea of what you want.
An idea of what the gifts are.
You know, stewardship of one's gifts.
Well, I would love to be a steward of my gifts, but I don't know what they are.
You don't have any gifts?
Well, I'm sure I do somewhere, but...
You need a gift therapist, right?
You are my gift therapist.
You got nice teeth?
You still got your face?
You haven't had plastic surgery?
No.
Is that a new nose made out of cartilage from your knee?
It's all, it's all...
I see you don't wear glasses.
Well, I had surgery there.
I had the...
Huh?
I had the surgery.
I had the LASIK surgery there.
And now you see all right?
Yeah, I see pretty good.
Okay.
And you got a full head of hair?
Yeah.
Do you have carcinoma anywhere?
No, I don't even know what that is.
You have health, huh?
Pretty good.
You don't have...
Pain.
I have pain.
Huh?
I have pain, but yeah, I'm not...
You have...
You have physical aliveness.
How old are you?
Forty-five.
All right.
So, you still have youth.
Yeah.
So, but as far as I'm concerned, I don't have any physical aliveness.
You have youth.
You have aliveness.
You have health.
You have good teeth.
You got a job?
Yes, I have a job.
And you have a job?
Uh-huh.
Good golly, what more do you want?
No, I don't want gifts.
You got friends?
Yeah, wonderful, beautiful friends.
I mean, is there something more beyond the lens?
Well, I guess what I mean...
What I'm trying to understand is it's like...
You're probably thinking of a special person.
Yeah.
No, no, no, no.
More of like, a way of being of service in the world as...
You know, like, is it...
That's all I have to do, is just do what I'm doing?
It seems like there's so much more...
Oh, I think so.
If you're friendly and kind and benign to the world, think how exceptional you are already.
Do you remember from that chart in the pyramid?
Uh-huh.
of the people in the world just to be benign and kind and friendly and open and helpful helpful
little ladies crossing the street you know what i'm saying yeah i do always take a little while
begin to label these so you think it gives us something exceptional maybe that's the thing
yeah it's all dark and handsome and rich you see a famous movie star i guess i just feel like like
i like um you have good health you walk around you've got a pacemaker i mean you're way ahead
of the game i guess it's in striving to do in striving to do more that's all it's just wanting
to be a better person well the intention is sufficient and then you ask god to reveal to you
more okay you're trying to use your thinker to get it
forget it
thinker. That which you are is your gift to the world. You understand that?
Okay.
Are you safe to be in a boat with?
I think so.
You don't stand up in a canoe?
No.
You're way ahead of the game.
And you have a charming smile.
I want to say that I've been reading your books a lot. I'm up to the last one.
The growth between ten years ago and now is phenomenal because I was reading people like Thomas Troward and Ralph Waldo Emerson.
Because I'm a religious scientist and practitioner.
And now I'm teaching that class and now I actually understand it.
It was like,
it was like I did it because I had to do it.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
And it's just,
You get meaning behind it.
What a gift.
These teachings have made very clear things that were so confused.
I'm able to actually hold a line of thought until the end of the sentence.
That may sound like amazing, but because of your type of writing.
Now transcendentalism means more to you.
And also, this is, I don't know if it's a question or it's just a confirmation.
I've been involved,
I've been involved in NLP and timeline therapy.
I don't know if you know about that.
It's a teaching derived from Huna.
And I've been doing a workshop,
which I vowed back 13 years ago to do at least one a year.
And it's about emotional freedom.
And the name of my workshop is Emotional Freedom by Giving Yourself a Second Opinion.
So I do this and I do this with my church group.
And I'm just wondering,
I think I know,
but I'm just going to ask you anyway.
There's karmic consequences
for everything, right?
What we do.
And, but then again, there was,
I heard you say today that
it's not exactly tit for tat or life for life.
No, it's not cause and effect.
Exactly.
It's likelihood and potentialities.
Good. Okay, so that's good.
And so I'm thinking if you work with someone
and they release a lot of karma,
and they don't have to go the whole tit for tat route,
is that okay?
Karmically in the world.
I know.
Okay.
Because we only have it to be done with their willingness and their assent.
You're not doing it against their will.
Yeah, oh yeah.
That's absolutely the truth.
That's the truth.
Okay.
So that's it.
I'm doing another two workshops this year.
Thank you.
Anyway.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
God in his ultimate mercy gives us a chance to undo our errors.
Thank you very much.
Okay.
We'll move faster then.
Bye.
Hello.
Hi.
So in all of your books you have them calibrated by chapter,
except for transcending.
Yeah, because each chapter is already about a calibrated level.
Oh, okay.
So then even though the lower calibrated chapters would still calibrate low?
No, no, no.
It's a separate number.
Yeah, but I mean the description, the analysis of it would be of a different calibration.
Yeah, so.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, I just thought that was really curious.
Because I like the fact that each, like in the first one, power versus force, you talked
about how you went through each paragraph and sentence and discovered like the one with
the John Lennon.
Yeah, right.
Line and everything else.
Yeah, yeah.
It's really interesting because I have, kinesiology is very difficult.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
But I've enjoyed your books very much and I love you.
I'm glad you enjoyed them.
Thank you.
Yes.
From the Chicago area.
In fact, I'm part of a group that promotes, you know, it's a spiritual, a new spirituality
group that talks about your books.
And I brought you a present.
This is a book I wrote.
Oh, thank you.
Dedicated to you.
Hey.
Oh, thank you very much.
You're welcome.
And a question I had for you, doctor.
Could I have a hug?
Can I?
What did he say?
Can I have a hug?
You can hug my hand.
Okay.
I understand.
I'll tell you why.
Because all my bones have turned to Styrofoam.
You understand.
Well, thank you.
Thank you very much for everything.
However, I'm doing everything to recalcify the skillet.
I never paid much attention to the body, you know.
So I've done a lot more work.
and now I'm learning you've got to pay attention to it,
otherwise it's going to be a drag.
I understand all the bad things I put in this body.
Thank you.
Do you want to get a picture with him?
Yeah, hi.
Hi.
Thank you.
Beyond words.
So my question is about devotional non-duality.
I think.
And for me, how to live on the razor's edge.
From your teachings, the opening, letting go into the field,
the spontaneity emerging, all the beauty, desire for enlightenment, so what?
The city, so what?
All of it, so what?
And recently, as I've been dealing,
I've been deeply quiet, spontaneously, I reach a place inside
where I think I've met the essence of the ego,
and the density that doesn't surrender.
It has to die.
Yes.
I'll take you up again.
Is that the razor's edge?
You follow the razor's edge, and it'll take it to the core of the ego,
and the ego's belief that it is your creator,
and your source of life, and you surrender that to God,
and then you go through a period that you'll die.
When I'm anywhere close to that?
Oh, honey, I don't know.
It's just a whole evolutionary phase.
And it's not linear, so you can't say,
well, if you're here, now this is coming next.
It's more like fields interacting with fields.
So this field here potentiates all the fields within it.
Now this field is this way, and this field is this way.
Well, the field is empowering every one of these fields.
So if this is empowered this way,
it's even more this way than it would have been.
So it's overlapping coexistence fields of influence.
It's more like a complicated interaction of fields.
Now you did that, didn't you?
Yeah.
So anyway.
The likelihoods, then.
So each field is a potentializing,
and there are multiple interacting fields co-influencing phenomena,
coming from not only the past, but the present,
from fields beyond fields beyond fields,
beyond which is divinity itself,
the infinite omnipresent field,
which empowers all the lesser fields.
So you're doing fine.
You're doing fine.
Don't worry.
Don't worry about a thing.
Just keep doing what you're doing.
Thank you.
You're doing fine.
Fields within fields within fields.
Can you close the doors?
We're losing our air conditioning.
Yes.
I've enjoyed your work for many years.
This is the first time for me to be here,
and I'm very pleased and excited.
I want to thank both of you and your team.
There is quite a bit of experience in living in a communal setting,
and...
This is exquisite for all that you do,
and the details I have great appreciation for.
I have my whole life been highly interested in spiritual evolving.
And one of the things that has caught my passion for a long time
is in the major religions, there is reference to the Golden Age.
Golden Age?
Golden Age, which means...
Historical age, or what?
It means going back before the fall of man,
where...
Where?
Where humanity functioned in full consciousness,
full divine function.
I wonder, especially with what you bring,
if this awakening that I am going through and we're going through
is a gateway of some sort to bring back this Golden Age,
not like it used to be, but in a new way.
I have no reason to presume that.
The previous age was...
It was vulnerable, wasn't it?
Do you want to recreate that which failed the test?
I don't think so.
I would like a future where the fall of man is not a potentiality or even a likelihood.
Yes.
Thank you.
Forget the past.
Past is all illusion.
The ego was the cause of the fall, then.
Yeah.
You don't want to create which was, which failed miserably?
No, I don't.
No.
You want to create that which is immune to.
Yes.
To the
negativity and temptation and ignorance.
It was the naivete of Eve.
number of years now and I wondered if you're planning to have a lecture series
next year. We're in the planning stage of next year. This year we're trying as
every other month. We'll probably still do every other month and then the
workshop in the month in between. That was that everybody liked that a great
deal. Real old-fashioned sad saying you know question answer discourse. I like
walking through the crowd and having a spontaneous conversation with everybody.
That's what I like the best. How about books? How about books? Books I'm planning to do?
Yeah. Yes I told you we're doing an atlas of a hundred charts. We have lectures on
healing and recovery which is gonna be out probably after the devotional nonduality.
And then there's spirituality and modern land.
Healing?
Because the old-fashioned religion doesn't appeal to modern man.
Neither does skepticism.
Skepticism does not fulfill him either.
The Newtonian paradigm.
These men are feeling unsatisfied and unfulfilled.
So what would be a spiritual pathway for a modern man
who isn't a peasant tending sheep on the desert 3,000 or 4,000 years ago?
What appealed to him is idiotic to the modern man.
Bush lit up and started talking to him.
Give me a break, will you?
Swallowed by a whale in, say, three days.
I mean, come on already.
So this forthcoming book is going to be a takeoff from the Scopes trial.
The Scopes trial was never resolved.
They never resolved the argument.
They simply avoided addressing it.
He attacked his character.
The question was never answered.
What can modern man hold on to
and not look like an idiot through old-fashioned religion?
How can you be intelligent, scientific,
and also spiritual,
and religious?
That's modern man's dilemma.
So that's the problem I tend to address.
I want to pick it up from the Scopes trial,
which is in the 20s,
and nobody has answered it yet.
Nobody.
You've got to pick one way or the other.
Old-fashioned religion.
Can I do a picture with you?
Yeah.
And you see the dilemma.
Old-fashioned religion,
which appeals to the scientific mind
is to the ignorant dummies out in the country,
rustic folks,
or else scientific skepticism.
I mean, where is the reality
that embraces modern man?
Okay.
Yeah.
Thank you.
That's what I'm eager to write right now.
Everything else that gets in the way of it,
I'm impatient to get through it.
Yes?
I wonder if you would be willing
to calibrate something for me.
Nope?
Okay.
Generally, we don't.
Then I do have a question.
When you talk about,
I don't remember which book it's in now,
but no need to do anything
in the causality that is.
No need to meditate,
no need to be an activist
for change in the world.
What motivates us?
How do we maintain motivation?
I don't know what you're quoting.
You say no need for something.
Oh.
Okay.
It was one of your...
You're describing passivity.
It was my perception of what I read,
so it very likely was misperceived.
Surrendering a thing to God
is not the same thing as apathy.
What you're accountable for is the intention
and not the result.
The result is up to God.
So you do what you can to help people help themselves,
and now it's up to them
because you don't want the karmic responsibility
or controlling other people as far as outcome.
You can lead them to water,
but you can't make them drink.
It's a horse's karma whether he drinks or not.
Your karma is really to provide the water.
So it's defining what is your responsibility
towards yourself and others.
Yes.
To give yourself and others the best opportunity you can
for the highest level of love that you can understand.
Sometimes the most loving thing is to let them be.
Okay.
Tough love.
Let them be.
It's about surfing.
Actually, it's sort of like that.
Living in causality is like surfing life.
Yes, you got it.
Surfing is very much like surfing.
It's a good idea.
Thank you.
I'm going to move you because you're right in that light.
What light?
Behind you.
We're going to move this light just slightly.
Come on.
It's a filming thing, guys.
That was fun.
Hop, hop, hop, hop, hop.
Hello.
When I first found your work,
it started to smooth out my life.
And fill in a lot of the gaps.
I went along a little further.
And now, just about every aspect is in complete and total upheaval.
You know, being here, I think I've heard this story now from some other people.
Yep.
I'm not exactly sure how to go forward every day, but...
You just follow basic spiritual principles.
That's all.
My hardest role, or what I perceive to be my hardest role right now,
is the mother of a 16-year-old.
Who's in...
I mean, this is my third child.
I thought I knew what I was doing until now.
Yeah.
And now that I'm in such upheaval and everything changing in my life
and in these roles,
I'm looking to see if anybody has any questions.
Anybody else?
has any wisdom, because I'm having difficulty understanding and parenting, where you stop,
where you kind of stop, you know, where you start turning it over to them, and let them
live their life, and not, because I don't have the answers anymore.
To what?
You're very mysterious about all this, I mean, what are you talking about, big turns, your
life is all topsy-turvy about life?
Oh, well, you know, everything has changed my...
Like what?
Religious affiliation, where I live, my relationship with my husband, every person in my family,
all the people that I was...
Right, it's like getting a divorce, right?
It totally changes everything.
It's the whole, everything, yeah.
Quitting a job, moving to a different country.
Right, it feels like that.
Yeah, so what's your question, is what is the role of a parent?
Well, yeah, a parent who's going through all this, who's now having trouble,
where the answers were simple before, they've gotten so much more complex, and I just wondered
if...
You got a therapist?
No.
Well, you need one.
Yeah.
That's one.
Practically.
You're honest with a 16-year-old, you just tell him, I don't have...
The practicality is that I only have a therapist, I mean, the complexity you're describing,
what's the role of a parent?
Yeah.
Yeah, to try and influence a kid in a certain direction without controlling them, but I
really think a therapist would be helpful to you right now.
Yeah.
That's not very true.
That's good.
That's what I needed to hear.
Really psychological, emotional, not spiritual, really, right now.
Adjustment problems.
Okay.
Yeah.
The spiritual seems to have stirred it all up.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
It's like you're going through...
It's just that going through it isn't easy.
Mm-mm.
No.
Well, thank you.
Your intention is to do the best you can in all these various roles.
Yeah.
But you need somebody that you can give feedback about the details, and not generalities.
See, with me here, you're going to have to do a lot of things.
Yeah.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
I'll look.
You can do it piecemeal, piece by piece.
What about this?
What about that?
Okay?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
That's what I would do.
Thank you.
Okay.
Yeah.
There are certain times in your life when having a therapist is like having a best
friend, and it's somebody you can trust and discuss things with, and discuss it at a
different level than personal relationships.
Okay.
Hi. My question was about what exactly is your level of consciousness? Is it like an average of all your attributes or is it one thing?
Overall field, yeah. That's what I thought. It was just at a study group we were having a conversation and there were some disagreements so I thought I'd ask.
Well, different archetypal roles within yourself may have evolved to different levels. The student in you might be quite involved. The devotee might be quite involved.
So the various roles that you have within yourself, some will be more advanced than others, you understand?
So if you calibrated them differently, you know, my social person, what does it calibrate at? What does my student calibrate at?
You might find yourself more advanced.
Your student is quite far advanced. Your social person is retarded. It might be the other way around.
You're a cool extrovert, but when it comes to studentship, you know, you're not well-motivated.
So you could examine different aspects of your personality and calibrate them independently.
I'll try it.
Yeah, it'd be fun to get to know, you know, where are your high points and where are your low points. Are you familiar with Carl Jung and the, you know?
That sounds familiar.
Yeah, okay, never mind.
I guess it is.
You could look at the different aspects of your personality. What's the calibrated level of your friend, you know, being the friend to others?
The student, the son, the lover, the various roles that you have.
How good a neighbor are you? You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
I mean, there are people, there are neighbors so bad that people shoot them.
I sure hope I'm not one of them.
There was a guy, an old man who lived in an apartment, he was 90, in New York City, and the SOB next door would not stop playing his radio loud at night.
So he took a shotgun and killed him dead in a mackerel.
So the guy who played the radio loud was not being a good neighbor.
Now he is. He's a very quiet neighbor.
I sympathize with the old guy.
Thank you.
He probably deserved it, you know.
You often talk about when a person reaches a level of 600 and half of them decide not to stay and half of them stay.
That's so.
So, if this S and so forth is 600,
is 600 and it dies and goes to the other side, the body dies, then does the body have to come back here?
I don't know.
You don't know?
I'm not in the body shop.
No, it's a free elective. It's a free elective.
It's a free elective.
It's very clear that there's no obligation in any direction.
It's all a choice.
There's no gain.
Nothing gained and nothing lost in either direction.
Okay.
That's it.
Thank you.
But it's an open door.
It's okay to walk through it.
That is very clear.
Okay.
Thank you.
I wanted to ask you about deja vu.
I don't have an explanation for it because I haven't looked at it.
I don't know whether it's a neurological doubling back and it's an illusion that you've experienced it before.
I've had it a couple of times.
I've had it a couple of times in my life and it was quite real.
The certainty that you've experienced this before, whereas in fact I know it was not
possible, but the experiential was that you've experienced this exactly before.
I remember the clock being at the same time.
I don't have an explanation because I haven't really researched it.
I'm suspecting it's some kind of a time doubling illusion.
I'm just suspecting that neurologically.
So something just don't necessarily pay attention to?
I don't know the explanation.
Okay.
But I've had it and it's very real.
Yeah, it seems real.
I had it in World War II when I was on the troop ship.
The train broke down in Golden, Colorado.
It took four hours to fix it, the whole troop train.
We all got off.
We got to be back four hours.
I walked to the center of town.
There in the center of town, you look down all four directions in Golden, Colorado.
There's a mountain at the end of each one.
On this corner, there's a great big clock like you see in front of a jeweler's clock.
I experienced that before, and yet I'd never been west of the Mississippi.
But it was very vivid.
So I know what deja vu is like.
I don't know the explanation.
Well, thank you very much.
Yes?
I have a question about the final doorway that you write about in the book, I.
Is that calibrated?
When you...
Sorry.
Is that at level 600 or 850?
Final doorway is at 970.
When I said final, I mean final.
Because for a long time, I was under the impression that it calibrated at 600 because you state
that like Nisargadatta Maharaj went through it, and it seemed unclear that...
Because his calibrated level of consciousness was like 720.
No, that's not the final doorway.
Final doorway, you give up life itself.
They gave up their perception of life.
And they surrendered their perception of life to God.
Yeah.
But not life itself.
Not what the ego believes is life itself, the source of its life.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Hey, Dr. Hawkins.
I'm a college student right now, and I'm surrounded by a lot of alcohol and kind of like a party
environment.
Party environment.
He's a college student.
Oh, yes.
Party environment, yes.
Yeah.
So my question is, how can you be in that environment and be kind and loving without
being taken advantage of at the same time?
Kind and loving doesn't mean passive.
It doesn't mean being a patsy.
It means camaraderie and then drawing lines when they're going to go too far.
If, let's say, someone keeps peer pressuring you, and finally you just tell them, like,
no, is that...
Somebody keeps pressuring you?
Yeah, if you're firm, is that...
Yeah, you tell them.
Still being kind?
I can't go along with that.
Okay.
I can understand it, but I myself can't go along with it behaviorally, you know?
Yeah.
We all have our own...
The way we were brought up, you know, we have our own inbuilt conscience.
There's certain things you just can't do and live with yourself.
Yeah.
You say, look, I could do it, but then I'd have difficulty with myself.
Actually, what I meant more was, like, when you're saying no, it's not the actual alcohol.
I just mean if someone was saying something to you and they're kind of pushing you, kind
of pushing your limit, is it okay?
You know how you're kind of firm a lot of times when you say no?
Yeah.
Is it okay to be firm?
Is that still...
Yeah.
You just say, you know, I can't go there.
Okay.
Thank you.
Limits.
It's hard being...
Limits, yeah.
Limits.
My question was about surrender, and you've already answered it, so I just wanted to come
up and say thank you for the changes in my life.
Thank you.
caused by the books and tapes you've done.
I appreciate it.
That's the most yellow yellow I've seen all day.
Is that yellow or is that yellow?
She's like a walking dandelion.
Electric yellow.
Well, I had figured out how to ask this a minute ago,
but I can't quite now.
Now, I'm the guy that doesn't step on the bugs
and picks the dead animals off the road
because I don't like seeing them squished.
So then I get this opportunity for a job
that entails protecting the environment,
but part of that is having to eliminate beavers at the same time.
So I'm thinking this is one of those perception versus essence problems maybe.
No, you have to eliminate them.
I'd love to be able to move them.
I just don't want to like end up going back from where I came
and have God say, you know, you were doing so good up until that beaver thing.
You draw the line at that which you feel is a violation
of your understanding of the value of life.
And you can tell them, look, I'd be happy to move beavers all day long,
but killing them, I can't do it.
And then I get into one of the thoughts.
One of the thoughts was you're probably just as guilty if you say,
I'll do all the other stuff, but I'll have somebody else often.
Well, you can be a conscientious objector.
During the war, we had a couple guys on the ship
that just didn't want to kill anybody,
but they don't mind doing the radio and doing the scribe.
So you could just say, look, I'm a conscientious objector.
I can't live with a conscience where I feel that I myself have done this.
Okay, yeah.
Tough, tough one.
Yeah, yeah, maybe I should take up woodworking or something instead.
Well, you just, you have to live with yourself.
And you say, you know, it's going to be done.
It's going to be done.
But you don't have to be the one that does it.
That's what I was thinking.
Well, World War II, you know,
one of the greatest things for which I thank the Lord
is I didn't have to kill anybody, you know.
I was on a minesweeper.
I didn't have to kill anybody.
And I would not envy somebody who's in the position where you gotta.
On the other hand, if you gotta,
it's more or less taken out of your hands, is it not?
So it's a difficult one.
And I sympathize with your moral dilemma about it.
Give me something to think about anyway.
Well, I guess I thought about it.
You don't have to be the one that pulls the trigger.
You know what I'm saying?
But still, you know, the guillotine's going to come down anyway.
14.
14,000 were guillotined.
14,000.
But you don't have to be the one that runs the guillotine.
Neither are you going to stop the French Revolution.
So I thought you were going to stop the French Revolution
and save the life of all the beavers.
But it doesn't have to be you that runs the guillotine.
Thanks very much.
We'll get a beaver team.
Small, small-sized beaver-rama.
14,000 people were chopped off for the guillotine.
Yeah.
Yep.
I've been grappling all day over which of two questions to ask you,
and then I realize that they're related.
Three or four times now you've told me directly,
one day I'll be looking at something and divinity will shine forth through it.
The other question, which will become obvious,
is how do you know when you're not playing in the astral domains?
I think I'm confused between...
Paradigms, almost, because particularly at night there are experiences
where what seemed harmless, just watching, have turned into not so harmless.
And so I guess I'm kind of confused.
What do you mean, watching?
On television or in your mind?
No, seeing.
Huh?
Seeing.
Seeing what?
Lights, energy patterns.
Visions of energy patterns and things like that?
But...
Are they benign?
They were.
I would stick with the benign and refuse all others.
So it's okay, it's okay...
You know, you can...
It's called the testing of spirits.
Either it's benign and of the Christ or not.
And you can challenge the spirit.
It's called something, the qualification of the spirits.
To acknowledge Jesus Christ as your saviour, yes or no.
If it says no, you vanish it and get the hints.
Got it.
Thank you.
It's got a formal name in religion.
The qualification or the declaration.
What is it?
The provocation of the spirits?
Who knows it?
Anybody Christians here?
It's called something.
It has a formal name.
All spirits can be challenged.
Or the challenging of spirits.
Do you acknowledge Jesus Christ as your saviour, yes or no?
Yes.
If it says yes, then it is of the Christ.
Then it could be, you know, like an angelic form.
That which is demonic will not acknowledge Jesus Christ as its saviour.
Then you can vanish it.
It's not verbal or anything like that.
But so...
Yeah, but you can hold that as a...
You know what I'm saying.
You can hold it without verbalizing it.
Yeah.
All right.
You challenge the spirits.
That's not playing with the astral circus.
You're already...
The circus is already going on.
You're asking me what to do because it's going to enter us.
That's right.
They're in the screen doors.
I'll tell you what to do if they're already in the screen door.
Can I just deny it all?
I mean, it's just not necessary.
I would just challenge spirits or ignore them or order them henceforth.
Does this mean I'm distracted for lifetimes?
I mean, you've warned against the astral circus and I don't know what happened.
You know, does this mean this is a distraction off of the goal?
Because I don't want it.
You can order them.
You can order them to leave you.
In the name of the Lord Jesus Christ, I order you.
You get to leave.
Yeah.
You can order them.
You call upon the Christ.
Banish them.
That's your right.
If Jesus Christ is your savior, is he?
All right.
Therefore, you have the right.
That's all it takes.
Do you go to church?
Sometimes.
Used to.
You have a priest?
I had to let him go.
You had to let your priest go?
Over the side or what?
He was programming me.
Oh.
A conspiracy theorist.
Oh, my goodness.
Thanks.
It's a mess.
All right.
So, I would just banish the spirits.
And right now, you don't want them even if they're friendly.
I don't know if they're friendly or not friendly.
I'm not equipped to handle it.
My teacher says I should ask you to leave now.
Okay.
All right.
Come back 20, 30 years, maybe.
But in doing that, I'm not throwing the baby out with the bath.
I mean, like I can just deny it all and it won't prevent.
No.
Okay.
Because you don't reach enlightenment via that.
Right.
Is it distracting?
It's a distraction in a way.
Glad we cleared that up.
Yeah.
Thank you.
They'll test you out to see if you're friendly
until they're hanging around and fooling them and playing games with you.
And when you tell them you're not, they'll leave.
I didn't.
It just was so benign.
It was nothing before.
Yeah.
Do what I tell you.
Hmm?
Just do what I tell you.
Good.
You have my word.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
They're seductive by their presence.
Elementals.
Elementals want to play games with their head.
Thank you.
Seduce her into playing with them.
Yes.
Good to see you again.
Hi.
Okay.
It's difficult.
I've been experiencing a lot of changes.
And what was happening is I used to be very career-oriented,
very success-oriented.
Now I'm not.
I don't believe anything.
All my beliefs have fallen away.
I don't feel I know anything.
So I'm left with no beliefs and not knowing anything.
And right now, I'm trying to go back to work.
And I don't know what direction to take.
Do we have a work that we're supposed to be doing, something we're meant to do, a purposeful
work?
Or does it matter?
Well, it's within yourself, your own interests and capabilities.
And you dedicate it to the good of mankind and whatever service you can be, you know.
But you have to make a living.
That's your obligation.
And you're the steward of this body.
And you've got to keep it going.
Well, basically, I'm intelligent, I have skills, I mean, just use those skills.
Yeah, I would use your skills and do what you do best.
If you have mechanical skills, artistic skills, whatever they are.
How does this work?
I mean, will the, will the, you know, ask God for help, ask God for a miracle, and then it will help to bring me the job?
Or I go out and look, and I apply to everything?
Both will happen.
You know, with spiritual help.
With spiritual help, that which you seek, you'll find, you know.
So take action, you say.
Yeah, yeah, they always say take action.
Yes, always say take action.
Like I said, I prayed for a job, and nothing happened.
If it hadn't been for my brother-in-law calling me and offering me a job, I'd still be out there.
Okay.
Can I get a picture?
Yeah, sure.
Yes?
Hi.
Good to see you again.
I noticed today you calibrated broccoli, and broccoli is doing really well.
Yep.
And also, I've heard you say back in November that cats and dogs might have an etheric brain, and you didn't know because you hadn't asked.
I don't know.
So I was wondering if you would ask.
No.
Okay.
For some reason, we've got to know about it.
Just accept their lovingness as a gift and appreciate them.
Okay.
There's something yet that I don't know about it.
I don't know what it is.
Okay.
I was just wondering about their evolution since broccoli is doing so well.
Yeah.
Broccoli is a different kind of energy than a cat or a dog.
It's more intellectual, mental, although she's very affectionate, too.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
Yeah.
I was just wondering about the spiritual evolution of cats and dogs.
I'm not sure.
I don't understand it myself.
Okay.
I sort of have intuitive presumptions about it, but it's something I don't want to know about now.
Thank you.
Maybe 50, 100 years.
Whoa.
Okay.
Thank you.
Should I go to Doggyland?
They're obviously a gift to us.
Many people would have committed suicide if it wasn't for their pet.
Hmm?
Hi, Dr. Huggins.
Uh-huh.
I wanted to ask you to describe Joppa, playing Joppa.
Joppa?
Yeah.
What do you want to know about it?
Well, I want to know if I'm doing it right and if ...
I'm not a Joppa teacher.
Oh, okay.
Why are you doing it?
I do it ... I don't do it consistently, and that's maybe partly why I wanted to ask you
about it.
Maybe I wanted to ... I think I wanted to know if I really should continue to do it.
What attracted you to it?
Hmm.
I think it helps me kind of not be frightened sometimes.
Oh, oh.
It helps me to stay focused, that sort of thing.
Well, it calibrates well, so it's the same as I think it's praying, saying the Lord's
Prayer.
Yeah.
About the same effect.
Okay, so it's like a ..
It pulls up that spiritual energy, and then that spiritual energy, where would
it look frightening or a problem, doesn't look frightening like a problem.
That's right.
Yeah, actually, that's what it does for me.
Yeah, because it pulls up that energy.
And is it in the sound that that happens?
Well, I haven't researched it to that detail.
Yeah.
Okay, that helps, though.
That is why ..
Thank you.
It pulls up that field because of the intention, and that field, then recontextualizes
and reframes it, so it looks different.
Okay.
Up, up, up, up, up, up, buddy. Remember in kindergarten? Up, up, up, up, buddy, buddy.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Before I started reading your books, which I consider my most practical
spiritual help now, I studied the works of L.S.A. Bailey and Helena Polatsky since my
youth, and I enjoyed particularly their exposition on cosmology, cosmogenesis, and so on, which
you don't get into. I was just wondering, I didn't see them on your slide about spiritual
teachers. How would you rate them? I didn't have the White Brotherhood on there, no, or
Alice Bailey, no. I didn't have the White Brotherhood. Or the Theosophical Teachings
as such. Oh, Theosophical, yes, yes. Polatsky in particular has, you know, the Secret Doctrine.
Yeah, I didn't do Polatsky, no. I consider she's way up there. And Alice Bailey, of course,
is part of her.
And the other works were Cosmic Fire, which gets into cosmology. It's just marvelous.
I'm interested in becoming enlightened, not cosmology.
That's a particular field which interests me, but what you have to offer is the most
practical, the most helpful. So if in the future time, if in the future time you decide
to calibrate those.
Well, I didn't do them all. You know, we did Alice Bailey's book Glamour, and I did Alice
Bailey's.
Yes, yes.
Because it explains a lot that without that explanation would be more harder to understand.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
Bless you.
Yes, I respect the White Brotherhood.
Yes.
Thank you for being here. A little closer.
There you go.
Okay. Well, I've been studying your work for several years, and this haunting question
has come back that I suspect is problematic.
Yes.
What I suspect is probably my ego's, the fear of the death of the ego. And it's around,
I only wrote it so that I wouldn't, because it was very hard for me to put these thoughts
together.
Yeah.
It's about my recall of some of the writings that you have talked about over 600, when
we have no more form after we leave this body. That there's, after 600, even up to the 50,000,
what is it, the Archangels at 50,000?
Yeah.
There's no form.
Right.
And so that means there's no experiencer. That means, of course, there's no-
There's no what?
No experiencer.
Yeah.
No ego.
So, the question is, how does one know that we exist without an experiencer?
Yeah. There is the knowingness of existence without experiencing. Because you're already
putting non-ego in terms of the ego, and then asking me how come.
Yeah.
That's the manipulation of the thought form, see? The knowingness of existence is
not a me knowing of that fact. That means the ego would still persist. There would be
me, the ego, making a statement about its state called existence. You see, the dualistic.
There is no this being a that, see? The thing is what it is, and it's completely fulfilled
in what it is without making a statement. It doesn't say I am. It does not say I am.
It just is. So, its existence is at one with its form. So, having form doesn't preclude
except that it doesn't know that. It has no consciousness. So, there's the conscious
awareness of existence without form. In fact, in that conscious awareness is the awareness,
that it's because of I, consciousness, that any awareness of form can take place. Without
me, there would be no form. Without the knower of the form, there is no form. You understand?
So, does that explain what happens when we go into the void then, right?
No.
No? Because we still try to manufacture some kind of form when we go in? No?
Are you talking about the void?
Well, no, but I guess that's the fear the ego has somewhere along the line that if there's
no form.
The ego fears nothingness. Yes.
Right. And so, that's what all of this revolves around.
So, it hangs on to form because it thinks without form it will cease to exist.
Right.
Yes.
And it's a fact. It will.
Okay.
Yes, it feels fear.
So, indeed it is.
Huh?
So, indeed it is. Then the ego is.
So, then you experience out the fear. And then, because all fear is illusion, the truth
takes the place of the illusion.
Okay. Experience it.
Yeah.
Yes.
The ego feels that without form it will cease to exist.
That's it.
Because it identifies the form.
Right.
Yeah.
Okay.
But it's got more to say besides form.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah. It's got more to say.
Thank you.
I tell the ego, you won't run out of juice when you run out of form. You'll think of
some other sneaky way to be around it.
You'll claim to be the author of formlessness, so you'll see. It's got more games.
It's got more games in its pocket to pull out.
Thank you.
Don't give up that.
Hey.
I'm going to start a conversation.
That's a good idea.
Yeah.
Okay.
How are you?
Greetings.
Hi.
Namaste.
Your book has brought tremendous joy to my heart.
I'm glad of that.
It opened my eyes to other teachings that I did not have the validity from them to know
that there was truth in that material.
Oh, okay.
Mm-hmm.
One of the things I'm starting to experience is fear in meditation, that there's something
after me.
Mm-hmm.
I experienced it a week ago when I was in the woods of Virginia, alone at night, and in the silence, the fear came up.
Okay, uh-huh. That's the child coming up in you. That was the child.
Thank you.
Is that the child? That's the child coming up. Yeah, it was the child coming up in you.
What avenue should I pursue to find what is bringing that up? I'll call you soon.
You speak to the child in reassuring terms, and know that all fear is illusion.
Correct.
So you've got to persist fear of what?
Fear of itself.
Fear of fear?
Fear of fear, or fear of death.
Uh-huh. Yeah, well, just keep surrendering that, and it'll negate itself. It'll resolve itself.
Because all fear is based on illusion.
Yes.
Because the risk is going to happen to you as you die.
You said, yeah, well, wouldn't that make you afraid?
No. You don't have to be afraid of dying, you know?
See what I'm saying? You can chase fear right down to its nub, and undo it.
Okay. I will practice that.
Now, one other I may ask. There's a lot of information that you've brought forth to this world.
It gives us credence. How would you like to see, excuse me, back up.
I've been in and out of AA. I'm familiar with Bill Williams.
Yeah.
I went back with a friend that had been...
using drugs, and been back into the meetings.
I see it as being a springboard that could be used to increase the spiritual awareness on this planet.
Great.
Because it does calculate at 540.
That's for sure. That's pretty high.
Have you given it, or considered, or looked in that direction on how you would like to see your material increased on this planet?
And one that I see is in chaos at some points, in ignorance, and have problems coming ahead of it.
Yeah.
Or have problems that...
Or have problems that might come ahead.
Where, the planet?
In the near future, the planet itself.
Yeah. Well, I think grassroots spirituality is based on practical, experiential reality such as the 12-step groups...
Correct.
...have a subtle profound effect that seeps out into society.
I think AA actually influences society. One reason we calibrate what we do is because of the influence of AA subtly on all kinds of ways which people don't know.
You know...
Right.
...people don't know the announcer they're listening to.
You know.
It's been sober 22 years, and they don't know who's in AA.
But that integrity spreads out as an example to the world,
and I think it uplifts mankind.
I don't think the consciousness of America would be the same without AA.
I see that from where I'm coming from,
I see because of your association with Bill W. at one time
that the group itself, if it was made aware,
made is the wrong word, brought aware of the material that you've brought forward,
that it could grow a lot quicker than what it is.
Well, they all blend together, and each one supports the other.
Of course, the miracles of AA and this work,
I mean, they're grassroots.
It's not a formal structure or building or anything,
and those kind of things tend to become more pervasive.
That which has structure and form tends to create a resistance.
That which has no structure and no form
and no...
No program and no agenda that's trying to sell anybody
doesn't create resistance.
I understand.
If a guy wants to be honest on the job
and be an example to others by his honesty and his friendliness,
there's no defense against that.
And you don't even know he's in AA, you know.
Yes, I have run into some resistance through some statements I've made,
or subtle statements, but there is resistance to it.
Yeah.
Well, it's better not to label it.
Don't call it AA or anything.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Yes.
Hi.
For about maybe six months to a year now,
I've been kind of on a rollercoaster of going in and out of like
what I consider like a high spiritual state
and then like a dropping into kind of a low depressive state,
maybe kind of like a dark night of the soul.
Yes.
I'm curious if you have like any advice for...
Yeah, you're just living through it.
You can expect that.
Mm-hmm.
See, because you rise above your karma.
Now, because of the good karma, you're entitled to bring up the next stack.
So what happens is the next stack comes up.
You think you're getting worse.
Yeah.
No, you've got the power and the strength now to handle that stack.
So you go through one stack after another.
They eventually clear up.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
It can seem like a lot at times.
Hey, Doc.
Last time I was here, I was telling you about my...
Ego issues, and you told me to not do, and I did.
I not did very well.
And I quit my job, and life is in a very big changing moment.
But I feel that there's a concern that maybe this surrender is really maybe a recklessness,
a shunning of spiritual responsibility maybe.
I don't know if it's like my spiritual policeman saying,
Hey, be on the ball.
Well, surrender means surrendering, trying to control the world.
And that's the result.
But the effort, of course, is dependent on your spiritual level and your commitment.
Because the way I've been going about it is like surrendering to the current of the river of life.
Yes.
And just flowing in it.
Okay.
Whatever happens, happens.
So I don't know if maybe that's a little too cavalier,
or is that the ego is just begging for that last bit of control?
Like, you can't do it without me.
Well, surrender is different than passivity.
Just make...
You think about that, or look at that.
Because sometimes surrender means surrendering to a responsibility.
You know, surrendering your resistance to the fact that you've got a responsibility.
So look at those shades in there.
I think your problem is in there somewhere.
That works for me.
Yeah.
I love you guys.
Spirituality is more than truth.
And I don't believe in politics.
I ain't going to vote.
And you go like another would say, well, my responsibility as a spiritually integrous person is to vote.
So, you know.
I think it depends on which facet of the diamond you're looking at.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
I have a good friend that's becoming, like, increasingly negative.
And I don't want to, like, play with fire.
I don't know if it's better to avoid him or to try to understand him.
If you understand what's going on with him, it can help.
You can only do that if you understand.
If you don't understand and he's going into a negative direction,
you're probably going to have to part.
Okay.
Sounds good.
All right.
Thank you.
Oh, I brought you a thank you letter, too.
Hi.
I've been thinking about this question.
And in my own spiritual quest, I mean, I've kind of been trying to figure out what's the purpose of any negativity at all.
In the whole spectrum of reality, it seems like, okay, well, and I've thought of this, you know,
why not just existence and consciousness being so pure and perfect in its own essence?
I mean, why?
Why?
Yes.
Why have this contradicting force that we have to go through?
And, like, the one thing that I have came to, like, the conclusion is maybe it's so you can actually recognize
how sweet enlightenment really is once you get there.
But, I mean, it's so painful to have to go through it.
So, I mean, I'm just...
Painful to go through what?
To go through all of the downfalls and everything you have to, all of these, this craziness and madness
before you can actually get that clarity, which I'm starting to get.
Oh, yeah.
And so, I mean, like, what is the ultimate?
I'm trying to figure out what...
What would you say is the ultimate purpose of negativity in any way?
I mean, if God is the consciousness and love within everything...
Yeah.
Why...
What's negativity doing there?
Yeah.
Well, we looked at the chart showing the evolution of consciousness, and we saw that mankind
is on a rising curve, and you're part of mankind.
So, along with mankind, you are, like, transcending the negatives.
The temptation to hate, you're turning it down now.
The temptation for greed, you're turning it down.
The temptation for envy.
So, they have to come up for you to transcend them and turn them down.
It isn't that they're bad.
It's just that you've made a decision to be otherwise.
Yeah.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
So, it's normal.
Normal what you're going through.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you, guys.
You know, 12-step groups, they call...
They have what they call the fourth step.
You take a spiritual inventory.
You take a long, yellow...
Legal-sized tablet.
You start writing down all your character defects.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Yeah.
In the book, Transcending Level of Consciousness, the section about temptations from different
level of consciousness, under this level, ecstasy, you list poor judgment as a temptation.
Can you please elaborate on this?
What do you mean by poor judgment?
It's not a temptation.
It's not a temptation, but it's one quality that the downside of ecstasy is to lead to
excessive behaviors.
Excessive behaviors.
So, each side has its upside and its downside.
Ecstasy could lead you to taking off all your clothes and deciding you can fly.
And people on LSD did that.
They go in a state of ecstasy, take off their clothes, and expect to fly.
So, the downside is brash foolishness.
Therefore, you constantly surrender your ecstasy.
The ecstasy is coming from the awareness of the presence of God as the source of your
existence, and the totality of all that is.
And it's ecstatic when that suddenly dawns on you, because it breaks through, like, overwhelming.
And you're just stunned by it.
So, the possibility would be to go into an ecstatic state and have it mistaken as catatonia
or something.
Let me put you away.
So, what can we do to kind of guard against that kind of irrationality?
Don't worry about it.
If they put you away, you haven't called me, I'll find you.
That's a good advice.
Thank you.
Appreciate it.
This guy is in a state of ecstasy.
What do we do with him, Doc?
We're done.
We have to quit now.
Okay.
We've got just a couple more.
We've got four minutes left.
Yes, we do.
It's four minutes to five.
That's it.
It's five o'clock.
I've got four minutes to five.
Mine is atomic time.
All right, hurry.
You've got to hurry, folks.
Walk fast.
Speak fast.
Okay.
I've been studying the keys of Enoch.
You did not calibrate it very high.
I was drawn to it because of the level of scientific complexity and the possibilities
of connecting with someone who has been or re-spatialized to higher levels of being.
Okay.
Can you comment on this any more about that?
We calibrated the keys of Enoch and all I can tell you is what it calibrated at.
I forget now.
It's in the book, Truth Versus Falsehood.
Okay.
And have you experienced the other, you were talking about the low levels that you're not
calibrating, but have you experienced yourself higher levels with the ascended masters and
the grids of being?
See, those are celestial realms.
I don't go into the realms.
They all have their own hierarchy.
Do you think it's possible for us as humans to go there?
But there's an infinite number of celestial realms and other dimensions.
In this lifetime, I don't have the time to go into them because what can any one of them
offer you?
Enlightenment.
Other than enlightenment, none of them have anything to offer you.
So leave the celestial realms.
From this dimension, you can reach salvation through Jesus Christ.
You can reach the enlightenment through the pathway of the Buddha.
Yeah?
You can reach Krishna consciousness.
So what does another dimension?
That to offer you other than novelty and cutesy ideas and weird names for the divinity of
that dimension, et cetera.
I'll ponder that.
There's nothing beyond salvation, redemption, and enlightenment, is there?
So what is the keys to any kind of a weird other dimension going to offer you other than
novelty?
Let's say I call the head of my dimension Ugg.
Okay?
We all worship Ugg.
So?
First of all, you don't live in that dimension.
You live in this dimension.
So Ugg isn't going to do you any good anyway because you're not an Ugg-ian.
No, I live in Ugg.
You're a human-ian.
We've got Jesus Christ, you've got the Buddha, you've got Krishna, what more do you need?
You know what I mean?
Well, we do have...
You're looking for big animals and you've got an elephant in your living room.
That's all.
What are you pushing me for?
I'm not under a compulsion to walk out the door at this stroke.
We've only got a couple of people left.
Come on.
Move.
Come on, move along.
Yep.
Well, let me thank you very much.
Yes.
Because you've helped contextualize what happened to me.
I was in a 28-day program when I realized that I was in the same boat as everybody else,
and that really I couldn't really...
I didn't know any of the truth from falsehood.
Yes.
And neither did anybody else.
And I went back to my room.
And I went on my knees, and I just asked to just know, like to get better.
That's it.
And I lost track of things.
And how could I put that?
I felt this energy.
That's why I could connect with you.
And the therapist knew that there was something fairly drastic happened to me.
And I knew that I couldn't function in the world like that.
And I still had young kids at home.
And he asked me to pull back, because I was going to go.
And I didn't think I could function.
So I did pull back.
I was there to listen to what I was told.
I made up my mind.
And so I listened.
And I pulled back, went back to my mind, thinking and everything else.
I didn't even have to think then.
And I didn't know what happened, though.
I didn't know.
In reading your books now, I do know what happened.
It's just that I just...
I'm back at that point now.
Back to what point?
That I can just feel the energy up my back.
All over, it's burning.
Have you recovered from the purpose for which you went there?
Yeah, I haven't had a drink, nothing ever since.
So you're doing very well.
Yeah.
Morning in.
Anyway, the question that I have is this here.
I'm at the point where I feel like what I have to do next...
Just feel the energy and just do what I do best.
I'm a businessman.
That's what you do.
And just feel the energy and don't think about it.
Just feel it.
Yep.
Enjoy it.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Good spot on the turn around, yeah.
Yep.
Before I started on my spiritual path, I had a relatively good sense of humor.
And I'm starting to take things so seriously.
Suggestions for recouping my sense of humor.
So logically, I've done.
Yeah.
There's a period where you go through it serious, you know.
Then there's a period where it's humorous again.
And later on, you get serious about your humor.
Then you think getting serious about your humor itself is humorous.
Which in itself is a serious matter, is it not?
Thank you.
Yes, I think humor is of divine origin.
We're all done, yeah?
Yes?
Yes.
There's more, isn't there?
Okay.
Hi, Dr. Huggins.
I'd first like to thank you for your teachings and you've helped me a great deal.
I don't know what I would do without you, to be honest.
I just had a question about my own intentions, my own level of consciousness.
Yeah.
And I'm just worried my own intentions, I'm worried about my own intentions and my own level of consciousness.
Your own what?
Intentions.
Intentions?
Yeah.
What they are.
Your motivations.
Use different languages.
Intention doesn't mean much to you.
Okay.
What do you want to, what's your goal?
Define your intention by your goal.
Okay.
To be more loving, more patient.
Right.
More generous towards others.
To ask for a miracle instead of trying to control things.
Right.
You know.
You just apply that everywhere you've learned.
Right.
Okay.
And then the consequences will come about as a result of what you've become.
The field begins to expand.
And then the field lifts you like a balloon.
Okay.
It isn't like you cause yourself to rise.
Right.
But by the raising of your spiritual intention, you like change your buoyancy.
And you sort of begin to float up in the field where the same field other people have drowned, you float.
Right.
You'll see others drown in the same field in which you float.
That's happened.
Yeah.
And that's a curiosity.
That's true.
Why is it some go down and others go up in exactly the same field?
Right.
That's true.
It's because your intention, your buoyancy is different.
Right.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
Love you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Uh-huh.
I give thanks to Almighty God for the joy of your presence and your love, which is God's gift to me.
You are all God's gift to me.
Thank you, God, for all these wonderful people.
Amen.
God bless you.