song.
Hi.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes. So I know we're only subject to
that which we hold in mind and in my own
life. I don't get sick anymore. My I
don't have allergies anymore. It's it
works very well in my life. Uh my
question is my my uh my son is going
through diagnosis for um high
functioning autism. He's going through
that process now. So, I'm always
thinking about his peculiarities and all
these things that I didn't realize was
was a
a different way of being and but now
it's on my mind all the time. So, my
concern is that is he is he subject to
what I hold in mind. If if I focus by
focusing so much on his uh
peculiarities, are they being
exacerbated?
Oh, I suppose there's a certain
reinforcement via suggestion. And what
are you concentrating on it for anyway?
>> Well, because he's going through this
diagnosis and he's we're going to
doctors and
>> Oh, I see. going through
evaluation this week. Yeah, it's going
on
>> and and so it's on but but so do I does
my mind
and and not by anything I say or even
do, but can my thoughts influence
>> make them better or worse?
>> Sort of. Yeah.
>> No, they're not going to make them
better or worse. No, cuz it's karmic and
physiologic and everything else.
>> Okay. So, if I'm thinking about a lot
now, it's not going to change this
reality. So, okay.
>> You remember during World War II, do you
know like hundreds of millions of people
hated Hitler and he went right on living
and thriving, didn't he?
>> Yeah.
Okay. Okay. Good.
>> Hundreds of millions of people prayed
for his death.
>> Good. He went right on drinking wine,
having a lady friends and gone to the
>> and and same I haven't he hasn't been
told yet and I know the power of
thoughts. I'm just it's like once I tell
him you have this syndrome does does he
suddenly have this syndrome? I mean does
Right.
>> Well yeah then he's got the syndrome by
label and by reality.
>> So
>> well it's like being short you know you
get used to it. You don't have to commit
suicide being short.
>> Okay. All right. No, I just
>> So you say, "Well, I'm autistic." Oh,
okay.
>> So,
>> it's like having dyslexia. I mean, you
know,
>> I've got a dyslexia of a couple letters
and numbers and a number of people have
dyslexia.
>> And you reverse the letters of the
numbers. And it's some kind of wiring in
a kid. You know, I mean, to me, it's a
so what except when I write four, I
write R. When I write, I write four. You
know what I mean?
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> I got to go back and rewrite it.
>> All right. Good. Thank you very much.
There's two other numbers and letters I
mix up, but I can't remember what they
are.
>> There's a funny There's a funny ad on
TV.
>> It It's something for uh memory
problems. Says take member of something,
brother, and forget that you have memory
loss.
>> That's with the ad. Have you ever seen
it?
>> Take memorabite within three months.
forget that you have memory trouble.
I'm sure that was done accidentally, but
it brings me up every time I hear it.
I've forgotten that I was seen now.
Okay,
that last comment reminds me I'm a
nutritionist and when I talk to people
about the supplements they take, they
get to the point where they're supposed
to be saying GKO and they can never
remember it.
They always
>> track. Yeah.
>> I just want to thank you for your
elaborating on the final run. Last
weekend I was listening to your 2002
tape and those words jumped out the tape
on karma. You mentioned the final run.
So thank you for being
>> see one thing after another comes up to
be surrendered. Like he brought up
people's approval. That's a very big
one. It applies to so many areas you
know but that after that something else
comes up and you just keep surrening
stuff as it comes up and you don't have
to keep asking where am I with it
>> you just keep going until you know
there's nothing left and you can see
that each thing is a block you know and
uh
and you don't worry about it don't worry
about it
>> my uh my question had to do with the
spiritual will that you spoke of and I
think it's on the same line in
transcending the levels you spoke about
surrendering so that spiritual will end
up guiding your life is that
>> well will is like intention you see so
will is your intention and intention is
quite powerful as the Heisenberg
principle demonstrates uh intention
already selects all selects all the
possible answers and eliminates the
impossible answers just by the question
they've asked
so if you assume that you're born in
order to evolve into eventually
enlightenment and salvation etc. then
obviously that's what it's going to be.
>> And the intentional set you mentioned
today, is that along the same lines that
you
>> intentional set is uh well I talked
about a contemplative lifestyle by
intention then you're prioritizing
the uh selector system. There's a
>> you have multiple choices available at
one time. So what you've done is you've
set a hierarchy of value by spiritual
intention. you've already shifted the
hierarchy so that these would be more
representative. So that's an intentional
set. Let's say a pilot by intentional
set may not be looking at the dials
directly, but even when he's talking to
his co-pilot, his mind is already
tracking exactly what's going on with
his whole plane without, you know, ne
necessarily linear
uh tracking of it.
his attention is is set so he can has a
joke about something and not lose his
track where he's at. The same with
spiritual intention. Eventually
everything becomes just for the mill.
You see everything all life experience
gets recontextualized as to its
spiritual spiritual importance or
meaning or significance.
>> Thank you doctor. Yeah,
I know. This pen is not writing very
darkly. I don't know.
>> It's a brand new one, but it's Yeah.
>> Thank you for being here.
>> Yes. My question is actually a personal
experience question and I have had a
sense of my spiritual quest as long as I
can remember and somewhere in my mid20s
I had an incredible experience that was
preceded by a lot of spiritual practice
and spending time with different
teachers
and going through a series of out-of-
body experiences quite frequently spun
spontaneously
and then this experience was followed by
the viewing of the oric field.
Everywhere I went, it was just
spontaneous again. And knowing that the
condalini went up, having studied and
experienced all of this stuff, I had a
reverse experience that I probably spent
my whole life wondering what in the
world it was. And so this is basically
curiosity. But I never found anybody who
could even address this question. So I
thought, oh,
>> what question? Well, it was getting the
question is what this was. It was an
energy after about three months of like
a spiritual hermitage of meditation
every day. It is as if a this is for the
this was I can't don't have a word for
it but it was like somebody took a
church key popped it in the top of my
head held a spiritual garden hose to my
head and energy pulsed through my body
and out through my hands.
>> Yes. And it was it was uh it just
happened and it ha it never stopped. And
when I meditate it it picks up again. I
began using it in my bodywork practices
and I never knew what it was because
this sort of came this way. It didn't go
this way.
>> Yeah.
>> And so I thought
>> God smiling down at you.
>> It was amazing. It
>> it's a it's a good energy is what you're
telling me. You're smiling as you talk
about it.
>> Okay.
You're smiling as you talk about it.
>> Yeah.
>> Because it wasn't demonic.
>> No, it was it was like light and energy.
I mean, it was my body expanded.
>> Yes, that's that's that's true.
>> You're identifying then with your energy
body. Uh so why don't you just thank God
and be happy with it?
>> Well, I do.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> I do. Thank you.
>> It's like the cities once they come, you
don't question it. You say, "Wow,
parking spaces always show up right
there." Yeah. Right.
>> Yeah.
>> I grew up Christian and
uh I became atheist,
agnostic.
>> 10 years ago, I couldn't say the word
God.
>> Um found your teaching.
>> Was praying to God, talking to God,
>> doing all that.
>> I'm doing the course now and we're
talking. We keep hearing about the Holy
Spirit.
>> Oh yeah.
>> So I have the Christian. I was I was
Episcopalian
>> father, mother, son, and it was all
anthropomorphic.
>> Mhm.
>> Would you give me a working definition
or a working explanation of the Holy
Spirit? Because it's really got me
caught up again.
The father, the son, and the holy ghost.
Father is the source. The son is the
incarnation. And the Holy Spirit is the
nonphysical
nonlinear
field of consciousness itself which
conveys the capacity for spiritual
awareness.
So when we say the person who's below
200 is not capable of spiritual
awareness,
you can't escort of him because his
brain isn't wired that way. By intention
and devotion he can shift it over to the
other and now he becomes capable. The
the mind is saying the holy spirit is
the presence of god is a nonlinear
uh infinite context of of life. It's
omnisient all knowing and all present
with beginning or end.
When you pray the Holy Spirit for a
miracle, what happens is it gets
recontextualized. And within the
recontextualization, the miraculous
appears spontaneously of its own.
How else would I find where I left my
socks last night? You know what I'm
saying?
>> Thank you.
>> Where do I leave anything? Hello.
Hello.
A couple of weeks ago, I just became
really aware of how annoying mind is and
how I didn't want the distracting
thoughts and how I didn't have to follow
the thoughts. And I had never been so
clear on it before. And while I know
while I believe I'm nowhere near the
final run, I have a lot of work to do
for two days. I surrendered up these
thoughts and I lasted for about two
days. And then it was just the energy
was so great. It was like holding back a
damn and I couldn't do it anymore.
Should I stop? Should I stay away from
that kind of practice at this point?
>> No. Let your friends know that you're
into serial spiritual practice in case
you come catat talk or something and
just let all your thoughts go and
eventually the mind will become
thoughtless.
However, there's a knowingness that that
continues.
This is when you really get to a serious
run. I call this the final run.
Your you your spiritual intention is the
line that you're going to transcend the
ego no matter what. It's the no matter
what that scares the ego. So up comes
fears and thoughts and things and you
constantly surrender them as they arise.
So you end up I was liking it to the bow
of the ship. As the thought arises,
you're already surrendering to it. It's
dissolving before it even breaks on the
prowl as a fully formed thought. With
meditation, you can see that
thinkingness is arising out of an
invisible energy field. It begins to
take progressive form. Long before you
see Rover, you see dogggininess. Before
that, you feel an energy of animalness.
It becomes caniness. This happens in a
split second. Then it emerges as
doggginess. And then it's Rover. And
then the sad story about how poor Rover
got run over and we all cried and it was
my sister's birthday and everything.
So that's what what's happening then is
the ego is juicing all those thoughts.
So you have to surrender the juice
you're getting out of all that. There's
entertainment. So you have to surrender
the entertainment of it. Face the
possibility of blank mind and boringness
and surrender each thing as it arises.
And then you come some incredible states
other doors open that are beautiful.
>> Thank you.
>> After a while you learn how to function
in the world again. But it's takes a
while.
You don't really function the way the
world would like you to function
actually.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Okay, we'll move a little faster.
Yeah. Rotate those. Let's get those legs
going there.
>> Yeah. Right. Um, this is my third time
here and I come for your spiritual
teachings, but I'm also a psychology
student in Flagstaff and I can't resist
the opportunity to ask you psychiatric
questions. So, my question is um,
treating schizophrenia with nice and
vitamin C.
Schizophrenia is a overactive dopamine
receptor. So things like ADHD or impulse
control in children, might that also
respond to treatment with vitamin C and
nasin instead of like rolin?
>> Uh, no. I've never had any luck with
that.
It's a different wiring program.
Different wiring problem.
>> I mean, it's a different wiring problem.
>> Well, that blows that theory.
>> Thank you.
ADHD to me is a neurologic problem. You
treat it neurologically and you should
be able to cure in 10 minutes.
ADHD is curable in 10 or 15 minutes.
Take the ant you take the antidote in 10
15 minutes your mind tracks. Great.
Rin or one of those any of those things.
8:00 you can't add 2 plus two. take a
riddle a quarter after 10 you can do
your calculus
I don't believe in it so I say so stay
stupid and confused like her
self geometry
yeah
thank you thank you thank you
um my question is about about the void
is it is it possible that some of the
individuals here or some of you know the
students u have also been visiting the
void in between.
>> No.
>> Good.
>> I just got back from vacation from
Thailand and every
>> Yeah, I know. Yeah. Anyways, ever since
I've been back, all I've been thinking
about is moving there.
>> Yeah.
>> And I was wondering if you would please
test for me to see if it would be for
the highest good for me to move there.
>> I don't know if I have permission. I
have permission. I can ask the name of
the highest good. It would serve the
highest good for him to move to
Thailand.
It was Let's ask again. It would serve
the highest good for him to move to
Thailand resist.
>> Thank you. Can you bless my mom for me,
please?
>> I don't know your mom. No, I can't do it
blind like that.
>> Can you can't bless my mom? Okay. Thank
you.
>> We don't usually ask personal questions,
but
if they're quick and fast,
>> Dr. Hawkins, um we read your books and
watch uh videos by ourselves, but then
we're drawn lots of times to get maybe
to get together in groups.
>> Yes.
>> Locally or throughout the country,
right? Um what's the best way for us to
um use that time together?
>> Well, you know, the tradition that that
I the most successful spiritual
organization to me is 12step groups.
They usually read from the book, take a
reading from the book and then discuss
it uh or play a tape of some speaker,
you know, and discuss it.
They so you just use something like that
as a takeoff place
>> and then you share your own personal
experience, observation and education
and learning and belief systems about
that
>> and through that sharing this you
develop a certain energy the group
intention energy is quite strong and uh
and and things that you might fall back
because of that group energy you won't
fall back. So the traditional teaching
is hang out with holy company. Why?
Because they have a collective spiritual
energy as a group energy that is
uplifting and all.
>> Well, thank you very much. Just wanted
to hear it.
>> Because I think it helps support the
energy field of the world. Groups like
that.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello.
>> Mhm.
>> I've seen people use pendulums in their
hand to calibrate.
>> Right. I I don't think in transcending
the levels when you talked about
different ways to do calibrations
yourself, you mentioned that and I
wanted to know if
>> I don't mention it uh you know there are
people that do it and if they do it they
do it. I tell people don't try to
calibrate low energies.
Don't get attracted to that which is
evil and demonic and start trying to
calibrate because your pendulum going is
going to get hit by that energy and one
of your energy fields and chakras can
get reversed by the way. So don't play
around with it. The pendulum is not a
game and uh same with any kind of
divination.
It shouldn't be done for sport. Many
people play with divination and we never
hear from them again.
>> So pendulum falls more in the in the
category of um what did you just say?
Not
>> skill. Well, it's a skill. And uh when I
say if you're going to use the pendulum
and don't then don't don't start
investigating everything negative.
>> Right. So the other forms that you
mentioned in transcending the levels
were were much more reliable to use than
a pendulum which was more vulnerable to
>> pendulum for pendulum people. I don't
recommend them to people because they
always they always have to have some
curiosity like there are questions here
>> that it's so hypothetical having nothing
to do with it. Anything could possibly
be your own spiritual destination and
you're just asking it out of idle
curiosity. But often you're playing with
very negative energies when you're doing
that. You're trying to flirt with the
negative and think you won't get burned.
that's not going to happen. And I know a
lot of people who did with pendulums
started checking out other dimensions
and they really blew out and even became
psychotic. So I don't recommend it.
Thanks. Nothing wrong with being
psychotic. I mean
you can lecture at universities and make
a good living.
>> Dr. Hawkins have every professor right.
I'm going to have professors after me.
That's right. And I want them to anyway.
>> Dr. Hawkins, I've heard the word
paradigm used very much a lot a lot more
in my life lately than than ever before.
>> You could say dimension too, the
dimension of realm. Yeah.
>> Okay. Well, my question was, could you
give me a general definition of paradigm
uh as you normally relate to it? And two
uh can intent are are intentions limited
to the paradigm that one may be in.
>> Yeah. And uh paradigm is uh context
is you could say how you frame it. How
you frame it.
>> Okay.
>> Uh and the content then the meaning of
content depends on in you know in what
kind of a frame you're you're framing
it. You know, is this a good world or a
world bad world? You know, apropo of
what? You know, from what context from
the view viewpoint of the man's ego,
it's a very frustrating world full of
war and poverty and sickness, disease
and death and AIDS.
>> So from what level? So the context then
would define you know what you would see
as true or false. So content is always
the answer is always dependent on the
context and the context is dependent on
intention.
>> Okay. So the intention does live within
the the paradigm that
>> intention sets up the paradigm. Yeah.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> You know how it works on the internet
machine. You you push push in the
question. You've already pre-selected
possible answers by pre-selection by the
by the how you posed the question.
Right.
>> Yeah. Now this is true.
>> The WW thing. Yeah.
the W internet.
>> You don't perform weddings, do you?
>> Uh, no. I only married myself once and I
regretted it, so I gave up.
>> Thank you so much. Thank you.
>> Well, you do. You see, you you become
enamored and romantically in love with
the ego, the me me, the ego, the me
generation was the narcissistic
consequence of falling in love with your
personal self. I don't really have any
questions, but I wanted to get a
picture.
>> Oh, yes.
The Mi generation was the narcissism.
Yeah. Me, me, me. What about me?
>> Yep.
Okay,
>> we're rotating through the mill here.
>> There's the mill door in.
There's the middle door. Sit.
>> Sit.
>> Hi, I am a teacher and I'm going to be
back in the classroom on Monday. I teach
a reading program and with in high
school there's a lot of emotional
resistance because they've had so much
failure, a lot of drama. Is there a
technique that I could use to clear
after there's big drama to clear the
energy out of my class
>> so that it's not contagious as the other
kids come in?
Well, it's not a good place to smudge,
but uh
>> I had considered that, but we do have
some dogs that do a little and I don't
know if they would pick that up as
>> something other than
>> I don't know, sweetheart. Just blessing
the place. Just blessing the place is
all I could think it could do. You know,
>> just give a blessing. Yeah. I also
wanted to know I use intuition a lot and
and kind of just real quick knowing what
the next step is. Is there a very very
quiet way to do the thyic thump that
won't be revealed to the class and I
don't want to go h you know
is there a way that I can do that align
myself because last time I was here I
remember you did something and you said
you were not aligned that was a real eye
openener to me
>> because I know you got to clear yourself
once in a while you're going to have to
step out of the classroom I think
>> okay just go in the hallway and
>> yeah well you tell them it's an ancient
Indian traditiona Ha.
>> I I learned it.
>> I could be fired. You know,
>> you tell them you learned it from the
Wii Hachis. And uh
>> Thank you.
>> A warrior. It's a warrior chant.
>> It's a
>> It's a warrior chant. You heard it from
a doctor at a lecture one time. It's a
warrior chant from the
>> Okay,
>> I'll try that. Thank I've just ordained
you as a teacher of the witch hockey
board.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins and Susan. Thank you
for this opportunity. Thank God.
>> Uh I'd just like to ask you a question
about the celestial realms. Um
>> once a spirit travels to this celestial
realm, uh do they have do they always
come back or do they have an option to
stay there? I don't know. The White
Brotherhood stays there for eons and
some may stay there for a great length
of time.
>> Oh, I don't know.
>> Okay. How's broccoli?
>> Huh?
>> How's broccoli doing?
>> Broccoli's uh talking all the time.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you so much.
>> You know, her latest thing she says,
uh,
>> boo.
>> No. What's get a job? Uh, what? Get a
job.
>> Go to work, get a job.
>> Go to work, get a job. She said
she doesn't take any so sister stories.
Broccco promises
get a job, go to work, get away.
She tells everybody, "Get a job, go to
work." That's hysterical.
Oh boy.
>> Are you familiar with the authors Jerry
and Esther Hicks and Abraham? Are you
know are you familiar with Edgar Casey?
>> Yes. How does he calibrate as far as
>> Oh, I think around 5:30 he was
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah,
>> thank you very much.
>> He brought us a lot of very good
information
>> which they used in that clinic down
below too.
>> What was the name of the clinic that
used the Casey remedies?
>> Yeah.
>> What was the name of it? I forget the
name of the clinic but
>> a yeah research and enlightenment.
>> Hi Dr. Hawkins.
First of all I would like to thank you
very much. Your teachings and your books
have had a tremendous influence on my
contextualization of things.
I have a question. Uh
you said we gravitate to and attract to
what we are
>> and what we are is not different from
individual to individual or is it
different and why do we end up at
different level
>> to what we are we gravitate to those who
are about our same level that see life
experience reality define reality the
same way. Yeah.
>> And we stay there.
>> Well, I didn't say you you gravitate to
your infinite potentiality in f in the
future. You you're you're attracted to
that which you are now. When you go go
out in the playground, you play with
those who are like yourself. Yeah. Yeah.
That's all I mean by that. If you're
into chess, you sit with the chess
players. If you're into wrestling, you
play with the wrestlers. So, you
gravitate to that which you are. And
that's the way the various dimensions of
heaven are. When you leave the body, you
gravitate to that which you are.
>> And is evolution possible at that level?
>> I don't know. What would be the point to
reincarnate if you could evolve there?
If everything is in the celestial realm
is like 600. Who are you going to
forgive?
You haven't got any enemies. You can't
even think that way. So, how to go how
do you go beyond 600? You can get
stalled out at 600. I remember the bliss
of it. It's complete. It's total. It's
satisfying. It's all there is. There's
no motivation to continue any further.
Nor is there even the realization that
there is such a thing as further.
>> Yeah.
>> So there is a possibility to stay there
forever. I guess there is a pre-ordained
karmic uh knowingness or something but I
could have stayed in the bliss state and
for some reason I chose to go beyond it
you know and then I found beyond bliss
was was even greater state so
that chirananda is enough for most
people 600 and most of the people who
get there will leave the body 50% anyway
you're in a bliss state you need nothing
more including the physical body, you
leave it.
You know, if the world and karma is
otherwise, then somebody will insist
that you get up and walk around or eat
something or they'll pull you back in
the world. Yeah.
But it's not of your doing. It happens
of its own.
>> And and the entities over 600, are they
entities still?
>> Are they what?
>> Entity.
>> Is there an Are they
>> identity?
>> Oh, identities, right? Oh no, not really
identities by the way people define an
identity. It's a condition. It's a
state.
It's a condition, a state. It's
nonlinear.
It isn't a person experiencing that. The
person is replaced by a condition,
by an overall state. You know, it's like
the individual airplane disappears and
there's only the cloud there.
that which was an airplane dissolves
into the cloud.
>> It's not a person but it's it's a field
which has uh
>> you become the field that you're the
field. It's the field that's the
reality.
Even when you go behind the witness
observer to the field of consciousness
that's a field that's not a personal
self anymore.
Yeah. And that helps the mankind. Is it
>> does that help mankind?
>> Mankind.
>> Don't worry about mankind.
>> It's time to worry about mankind. I'll
call you.
>> Thank you very much.
>> You You'll be God and I want to meet
God, you know.
>> Surrendered the fate of mankind to God.
I would like to express my uh gratitude
and thankfulness uh to you. Uh you are a
great gift to all of us. I had the
blessings and opportunity and fortune to
read all of your books and watch few of
your DVDs and I feel greatly helped and
immensely blessed by your teachings and
by your guidance.
>> Thank you.
>> I just like to thank you very much.
>> Thank you for your gift.
>> Yeah.
Yes. You do me honor.
Everybody honor you.
No substitute for sincerity. Sincerity
speaks for itself.
>> Yes.
>> It's a great honor to be here in your
presence, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes.
>> Um you said um potentiality manifest
into actuality by the power of the
context when when the conditions are
right. Yeah.
>> And
>> and one of the conditions can be
intention. See intention is one of the
conditions. Yeah. Is power of intentions
propelled or directly proportional to
the willingness to surrender?
>> What are the conditions then?
>> What
>> the power of intention? Yes.
>> Is it proportional or propelled by
willingness to surrender?
>> Is it propelled by the willingness to
surrender?
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. The willingness to surrender
because it's always by some replaced by
something greater than that which you
surrendered.
Mhm.
>> Okay. And where I come from, you show
reverence and regard by not by shake
hand, by prostration. Will you allow me
to prostrate?
>> She wants to touch your feet.
>> I understand. Yes, if you wish.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> I understand from India. Yeah.
>> Thank you very much.
It's a tradition, cultural tradition
by which uh she uh acknowledges the
blessing, you know.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. She's a gift to me from God. Yeah.
>> Lot of bookmarks there.
>> Don't move any bookmarks. Find those
places again.
All right.
That's not my question though.
>> That's not my question.
>> Um,
>> if I understand the the notes in in your
later books, right, you don't have much
success with testing people under 200.
>> Success with what?
>> Uh, if you test somebody who's under
200, it's not successful when you do it.
>> No, I can.
>> Oh, you do it.
>> Yeah. But when they try to do
kinesiology, they're not able.
>> Oh, I understand.
>> Because they're not devoted to truth.
>> Yes.
>> You can't get a single one of them
>> to to disengage their narcissistic
intention.
>> Right.
>> God knows what kind of an answer you
could get out of with politicians. In
other words, they're so brainwashed to
prove everything. You know, they'll lie
to their mother in order to win a vote.
So,
>> yeah.
>> Okay. Just wanted to clarify that
because I thought you meant maybe, you
know, because I test two people under
200 all the time and it works fine.
>> Oh, yeah. No, there's no problem at all.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You wouldn't be able to use it on,
>> you know, half the population in the
United States, you know.
>> Well, you could use it on them, but they
couldn't use it.
>> No, that's right.
>> Okay. Thank you. Can I have a picture?
>> Yeah.
>> All right.
>> I'm not going to prostrate, though. I'm
not.
>> No. No.
>> I'm up for that.
>> I hope you don't mind. Sorry.
>> You ready?
>> The Hindu culture, the culture from
India, it is symbolic. It gets the feet
of the teacher. And uh it's happened all
over the world. In Oxford, the game from
India is doing the same thing.
It's uh cultural just like in Korea. you
know uh
in Korea uh spiritual gesture. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Dr. I was looking for some
practice. I had in mind a mantra or
something like that to uh calm my mind
particularly when I want to go to sleep
or something's aggravating me. I was
intrigued in the uh power of um the
truth fully rated ohm at 720. So I kind
of tried that for a little bit, but it's
seems to me I got to make a sound.
>> Oh, you make silently in your mind.
You you you you tone it silently,
not vocally.
>> I tried um I a little bit thinking that
was at a thousand, but it seemed a
little egotistical.
>> No, just do them. That's fine.
>> All right. Thank you. You have a picture
too.
>> Yeah,
>> that was
>> Thank you.
>> That was Mukananda. I think that was his
>> I was with him for six years.
>> Well, then you're asking me a question,
dumb to go back and
>> you're higher level.
>> Yeah. stick. Yeah, that that's a good
>> uh my question has to do with the
relative field that was on your chart
with the general field the the
approximate field I believe is the term
>> approximate. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> That's like local conditions. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Um given that time and space are linear
concepts, position approximate how and
why is it important to the spiritual
process? Well, it's the situation. Is a
thing integrous or not, truthful or not?
Depends on the situation, doesn't it?
>> Yeah. And even a court of law. So that's
also called situational ethics. The
truth or the untruth, the rightness or
wrongness depends on one what
conditions? What conditions? What were
the prevailing conditions in the
person's life and in the country in
general? Yeah.
>> Oh.
>> To take certain moves depends on whether
or not your country's at war. that
totally changes the whole context. So
what I can say in times of peace would
be uh
you know a felony in times of war let's
say.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Or vice versa you know.
>> Good afternoon. Yes. I came here for the
grace of the guru. So, I wanted to make
sure I had a good dose.
>> That would be a dollar.
>> So, I figured I'd better come up here.
>> It's a dollar for a big dose.
>> A big dose. I left my purse back there,
so I have to go get it.
>> What's up?
>> Um, so I just wanted to ask um exactly
how does that work? The grace of the
guru.
>> Yeah, that's called the silent
transmission. It's it's traditional. The
knowingness that I had at the final
moment came as a silent knowingness, not
verbal, not from memory.
Uh it was a radiance from the aura.
Having been in the presence of a very
high teacher at one time, the energy
field picks it up. The frequency
uh the nearest corollary would be the
old pendulum one. You put, you know, if
you put pendulum clocks on a wall, they
will all begin to move together. You
know that hiden or whatever it is.
Anyway, the frequency vibration of the
aura is picked up by your aura by virtue
of your intention. Because of your
intention, you instantly pick up and
pull into your own aura that aura.
Within that aura is a great deal of
information.
Um, you might say encompassed in a
silent non-verbal knowingness,
experiential and subjective. Therefore,
it can't be conveyed verbally. It can't
be conveyed verbally.
Okay.
>> It's it's the energy field out of which
true authority arises.
You you the true authority is one who
has experienced it and been there. So
Jesus the Christ has the power of
salvation having been there and he has
within his aura the power of that energy
just as the Buddha had the power of
enlightenment which has been transmitted
down through the thousands of years.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you very much. I really
appreciate it.
>> It's called the silent transmission.
Yes.
>> Make sure I have it.
>> It it it occurs in the silence. Yeah.
Mhm.
>> Wait, wait, wait, wait.
>> Whoops. Sorry.
>> It's just like when I take the picture.
>> Thank you. Nice meeting.
Um, I have young teenage or young adult
children and I get concerned about
choices that they might make for their
life and um, so I surrender it to God,
you know, to God.
>> The choices.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Is does that help them or is that only
making me feel better?
>> You can't surrender it to God because
you're trying to control them by
surrendering it to God. No. Okay. So, is
there anything that
>> it's truly surrendered by God? They've
got their own karmic
um trip to make
>> and whatever they do,
they do. So, you do the best you can as
a parent
and up to them. It's up to their karma,
their options,
>> okay?
>> Their destiny
>> and what happens happens
>> and whatever happens happens.
>> Okay? And it doesn't make any difference
in the long run which way it goes.
>> Right.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Can I have a picture?
>> Thank you.
>> They're not going to do what they tell
them to do anyway because you know that
>> now each one has to develop their own
independence.
>> Gifts.
>> They develop their own independence. And
uh yeah,
>> I I'm a professional musician and uh I
just had a situation that that happened
that uh I wanted to ask you about. I had
to fire one of my longtime musicians and
I was wondering if there was a more
integrous way than I handled it. Um
I, you know, he had a behavior that was
detrimental, you know, to the band
reputation.
And so I, you know, just wrote him a
letter thanking him, but I had to point
out the incidences of his behavior
>> because I, you know, I guess there's
part of me that wanted him to understand
>> specific. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> So I was, my question is, is there a
more integrous way to have handled it
where I didn't have to point out his
negative behavior?
>> Uh, that would be an option.
Uh, which way to go? to go with an
explanation is uh loving in a way you
know that it's not just arbitrary and it
might help them grow see where
shortcomings that was my hope some
honest feedback
>> although it didn't work out that way
>> and then you might also you know you
know so that they can handle it very
often you just have to tell them you're
gone and I just can't tell you why and
because no matter what you tell them
they're going to use that as an ammo to
fight back at you fire back at you
so it's an intuitive option I can't tell
you which is the best way to go in each
circum each each circumstance is
different
>> right
>> sometimes it's better to part and tell
them frankly I can't give you an
explanation that's just the way it is by
>> right
>> other times you try to give an
explanation oh a lot of people will then
use the explanation to further attack
you and do the very thing that you're
letting him go for
>> well in this particular situation
>> I wouldn't give them a lot of rope
generally I try to give you as little as
rope as possible and tell you
>> frankly it's because it's just not
working out. Period. That's enough.
>> Right. In hindsight, that may have been
the better way because he's in such
denial that he didn't
>> Well, you you you know, it depends on
how you see yourself, you know?
>> Right.
>> Uh you save yourself a lot of static if
you tell him that's just the way it is
and I can't really get into it now.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> If you give reasons, you're opening up a
box of worms a lot of times.
Can I have a Pepsi?
The new president of PepsiCo is a woman.
>> A woman. Head of the second largest
corporation in America. Woman. Yeah.
They've come all the way to the top.
Forget glass ceiling.
Um you mentioned that at first you were
surprised when people addressed you
um
>> because you're not limited to this body
and mind and I think you also said that
it um have calibrated that it's of
benefit for us to be
in your physical presence and I wondered
if you would comment further on that
sort of paradox.
What's the paradox?
>> Uh
the pe the person you see when you're
not the body anymore, you notice
everybody's talking to the body because
you don't you're it's like you're in
more like space and you wonder who are
they talking to because it's like you're
here there and they're talking to a body
over there.
You're not even there. You're not
identified with the body. And people are
talking to this body and it dawn I mean
oh they think that that's you. Oh, I
forgot that world presumes that the body
is where you are and they speak to the
body because they think that's the you
who you are.
>> And
>> you can be out of body and they're in
the bedroom, you know, talking to the
body in the bed and you're not even
there. You're up in the corner of the
room. You know, it's sort of comical.
>> Who are they talking to? Oh, they think
that's you down there. Oh, you're right.
You have to remind yourself.
>> Yeah, I have to tell you. Get down here.
>> That's funny.
>> That is funny. At dinner time, I'm
disappeared, right?
>> Okay.
I think it's not answerable.
Thank you.
There's a readjustment period.
>> Yeah.
>> First of all, thank you.
>> Yes.
>> For everything. Um, as one transcends
the levels of consciousness, is there
any responsibility or importance to
share, you know, spiritual truths or
insights with others?
>> Well, it's your option. Some people
belong to spiritual groups and share,
you know, what the experience was. that
encourages others to choose that
direction or try that out. I think
there's a lot of value in sharing. You
know, the the big traditional ones like
aa sharing is a big part of it.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, I was scared of this and then
I began to see it this way and then I
saw it that way and then when I saw it
this way, it didn't seem so bad. You
know, the guy says, "Uh, hey, you know,
that's it's sort of what I did only I
saw it this way." And the next week they
come back and you know, they shared that
what went on that week when they tried
that. by God. I work that way. And uh
>> so yeah, there's a lot of encouragement
and group sharing.
>> How about with friends and loved ones,
family members?
>> Uh that's an option. I don't know.
Depend on the receptivity.
>> Okay.
>> Some people might think you're a wacko.
So you got to be careful.
>> All right.
Thank you.
>> You can't come out of the blue. You know
what I mean?
I see angels flying around your head.
Yeah. Right.
Best to keep certain things to yourself,
huh?
>> Yeah.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Thank you for
everything. Um my question is in the
12step programs there is the subject of
powerlessness
and uh powerlessness over specific
things but sometimes it is said that we
are powerless over everything.
>> Yes.
>> And uh
>> all power is God.
>> All power is God. Yes. And then uh I
guess I'm confused because I read in
some literature that uh what we hold in
mind tends to manifest or we can
visualize the future and manifest it.
And I'm just wondering if it's best to
see
>> what's the contradiction.
>> I'm just wondering if it's best
>> powerless.
>> Powerless.
>> That means the will.
>> It means seeing yourself as cause that
you have the power to do that. When you
hold something in mind, you're not
making it happen.
uh you're showing the water, you know,
you're creating a place, but the water
is going where it's going out of
gravity. You're not making the water
run. So, if you hold a vision of what
you consider to be optional, the
likelihood is greater that that will be
manifest. But just by intention, the
fact that you selected it is already
imposing intention. By virtue of the
Heisenberg principle, by virtue of the
mathematics of advanced theoretical
physics, you've increased the likelihood
by your choice that you the choice will
be chosen again. The xeno effect, the
more often you make a optional choice,
the more likely likely that is to be
chosen again.
And of course, that's part of intention
set. So the more often you choose to
forgive someone and ask God to see it
differently, that becomes the
predominant response pattern.
>> Okay? Is it is it best to cease thinking
about the future alto together and just
leave it?
>> Forget the future. What future are you
telling me that
>> you don't have any future?
>> You haven't got any future. I can read
in your aura.
You're only going to go from the moment
from now to now to now. You're not going
to have any future karmically. You
didn't inherit any future. You only
inherited now.
You're going to go from now to now to
now to now. Other people have to hang
out and wait for the future. But you've
been saved.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Save for the future.
>> You only have to handle this moment. You
know, this building could collapse in
one second. So, so what? You're always
going to collapse.
I mean, what's the difference?
Call your mother first. You know,
I I can hear the next big. Okay. Mom,
the the building is falling down.
You can't kick it to heaven without a
cell phone.
>> Calling the big guy.
Call letters.op.
Yeah.
>> Um
Jesus said, "Blessed are the humble." I
would just like you to say in your words
what you a definition of humility.
That's the letting go of the
narcissistic
uh the narcissistic investment in the
mind. You know,
humility is the willingness to surrender
all to God and eventually to surrender
the notion there's an independent
individual eye uh that is motivating and
uh etc. that is that is cause and that's
the ultimate vanity. So constantly
surrendering me will eventually take you
to the narcissistic core of the ego. And
then when you surrender that you go into
a real state of bliss because you see
everything is peaceful and perfect and
there's nothing you have to do or
become.
Yeah.
>> And uh I understood the pendulum is okay
but don't do any research on anything
under 200.
>> I I uh I don't advise it. No. So
>> the angels fear to tread there. Why
would you?
>> Because why? It's morbid curiosity. You
want to know how awful awful is? You
want to check out hell? You're not going
to check out hill without getting
burned. I advise people don't go there.
Don't be tempted by the drama of it.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. If you're going to climb the
highest mountain, make note of the fact
that 176 people have died there already
doing it.
>> Thanks. The picture taken.
>> All right.
I would have a sanity check on all the
people that want to climb the highest
mountains in the world. Wonder how many
would pass.
>> Hi, doctor. Hi, Susan. Uh we haven't
been here for a while because we have
been traveling around, my husband and I,
and we're coming from uh Oregon and I
just thought about giving you this
little bitty marberry jam uh just for
breakfast. Uh and uh
>> now we're in a jam.
>> Yeah,
>> I just I don't have a question. I just
wanted to
>> say hello.
>> Say hello. and uh say thank you very
much for everything.
>> So, you're here from Oregon now, huh?
Oregon.
>> Yes. Well, we're going farther up to
Canada, but we're staying for a little
while. We are staying in in Oregon and
we're going to Mexico now to visit my
family.
>> Oh, yeah. That's the other direction.
Yeah.
>> Right.
So, um I just wanted to to to really
express my my gratitude. Yes. uh before
uh reading power versus force I uh I
used to um suffer from anxiety disorder
and panic attacks and even after working
on a 12step program for a while and um
it happened in 2001 the first time that
I got power versus force in my hands and
I read it and I haven't suffered one uh
panic attack at all. Thank you very
much. And um I've also uh seen people I
know people uh some girls that I know
that live in in Texas uh suffering from
um eating disorders after watching the
tape of um losing weight. Um they they
were completely cured to this moment.
It's really
>> you're a blessing and thank you.
>> I'm very happy. I'm very happy.
>> Thank you very much. And I also would
like to um just say thank you for being
the light at the lighthouse and um and
to al also prostrate uh if if that's
okay.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you indeed. Yes.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. God bless. Come over here. Yeah.
God bless you.
All right. Thank you.
Yes, a question.
>> Huh?
>> Yes, a question.
>> Do you want me to say this?
>> Yes.
>> Oh, okay.
>> No, I know. To make the the the test.
>> I don't know what you're saying.
>> Oh, that's the question.
>> What is the question?
>> Yeah. The program I am holding in mind
would serve the highest good.
>> The program he's holding in mind, he
wants us to answer that.
>> Yes.
>> Oh, the program that you're holding in
mind.
>> Yes. Right.
>> Okay. I have permission to ask.
You keep it to yourself.
Uh what he's holding in mind would serve
the highest good. Resist.
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> Yes.
Hi.
>> Um,
my question uh last last night as we
were driving out here, a group from
Texas, we were listening to a tape of uh
someone reading quotes from Nizer Gadata
Maharaj
and one of the quotes was
that
help trying to help others. there's no
value in trying to help others because
in reality there is no others.
And I was curious, uh, some of us kind
of had trouble with that because we're
in recovery and that's kind of the part
of the goal of 12step groups is to help
others.
I was curious if you could
recontextualize that for us.
>> See, each level is only true at its own
level.
>> Uh, it's not true at the level that
you're experiencing reality.
It would become just an intellectual
belief system.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Thanks.
>> Hello.
>> First of all, I'd like to thank y'all
again um for everything and the group.
Also, I've felt the energy and and how
it's helped me to arrive here.
and uh and also felt the energy go back
to my AA group at home and seen it kind
of swarm through the the people there
and and just lift them up and I wanted
to thank you for that. And uh my
question has to do with a family member.
Um, my mother is very ill and uh, it
seems as though she's in a very negative
state and it gets overwhelming to be
around her because of the energy that
she puts off is very negative and uh,
it's like trying to draw me into misery.
>> Mhm.
>> And I just kind of wondered if you could
maybe recontextualize it or how I can
deal with that.
>> So, can you just avoid it?
>> It's kind of hard to avoid my mother.
>> Were you living with your mother? How
old are you?
>> 27. I don't live with her, but I live in
the same city with her. And she's she is
very ill. But it's all
>> Who else is there to look out for her?
>> Nobody.
>> Oh, so you're the only caretaker. Is
that what you're telling me?
>> Well, she's at a point where she can
care for herself,
>> but she goes to the hospital regularly.
She has a lot of postoperative problems
from a
colurectal cancer.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> But it's in remission and she's in a
colostomy bag.
>> Yeah. Oh, yeah. But, uh, the misery that
she's in, it seems like it's just
overwhelming. Negative projections on
everybody's out to get me. Nobody likes
me. Uh,
>> yeah. Well, call a minister and tell her
after you talk to the minister, call me,
I'll come see you.
>> You have to sit down and edict, draw a
line.
>> Just draw I mean, let somebody just mess
with with me just because they're in a
miserable state,
>> right?
>> I just I mean,
>> she can play around hell, but I'm not
going to join. You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
>> No, I think you got to throw back to
herself what her responsibility is to
herself and to others
>> and u the narcissistic self-indulgence
and suffering and playing it for all
it's worth. Uh I would refuse it.
>> Okay. And just one more thing if uh you
could answer it. How do you make your
life a living prayer?
>> You you you practice what you what you
read. You practice what you read.
You practice it at all times. So you
read a sentence, you look at your life
and where can you practice that? You
begin to institute it and practice it. I
would say
say thank you to every clerk who's, you
know, you ask somebody for a phone
number. She gives it to you, say thank
you very much. You just begin by
acknowledging other people. And when you
do that, as I've said, people will
faint. They'll just drop their face
like, "Huh?"
I mean, they've made change for 150
people. You're the first guy who said,
"Gee, thank you for making change." They
go bump just begin by radiating some
kind of gratitude to ours all of life.
Reflect back that you know everybody is
contributing to everybody else's life
and uh be as loving unconditionally
loving as you can towards everyone at
all times
to all that exists.
>> Thank you.
>> Intention begins to transform it and the
opportunities open up.
Time for her.
>> This is the mic. Okay. First of all, uh
thank you so much. Um really, thank you.
I'm nervous, so I'm going to be the only
I'm reading. Okay. Uh
I have I have a doctor's handwriting.
Okay. I'm I'm doing it fast.
>> Okay.
>> Give me the Give me the No, I'm gonna
I'll get You were talking in the
morning. uh about repeating a mantra
over and over leading to bliss, God
consciousness, enlightenment and then
silence connecting with God and I'm a
person who's been uh chanting Namo Ko
many many many years and yeah and I
wanted to you to talk more about doing a
daily practice um you know to reach
enlightenment uh you know it sounds like
you go off into a state of bliss and um
But it we live in the mundane world and
I I feel a need to recharge my
batteries. So I just want you to talk a
little bit about a daily practice.
Prayer, meditation, chanting, whatever
it is that people do.
>> Oh, the daily practice.
You pick out something and you and you
use that as a sort of a primary tool uh
to see the beauty of everything by
intention. um the capacity to forgive
uh to ask the Holy Spirit for miracle to
see uh everything as it is in truth
rather than perception
um to let go and to change things as
they arise to let go and to control them
to let go valuing what people think
about you to stop looking for people's
approval uh any one of those if you just
you see it's persistence ego work I mean
spiritual work is persistence
persistence
Mhm.
>> Okay, that's it.
>> If you walk by the little beetle on his
back and you fail to turn him over, it
bothers you. You see,
>> when it bothers you, you know you're
making progress.
>> When you're the whole way, whether you
survive or not, it's God's problem.
>> I I don't know how you knew. I It's been
a lot of beetles lying on their backs
lately. Anyway, I'm getting the picture.
At one level, it's a mistake to not stop
and help the beetle. At another level,
it's a mistake to stop and help the
beetle. But that's
each each level sees it differently.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
You see that in using some spiritual
jargon, you say, well, there's no
separate beagle, so there's no beetle to
save. You know, but I often think that
becomes a belief system. That's why I
don't like to hear people quote that.
>> Just want to thank
>> We're all We're all one. Yeah. Right.
You're all one.
>> We're all one. What?
>> Your books and your lectures, they've
had a profound effect on my life in the
past past year. And really they were the
the spiritual they were the thing that
basically got me on the spiritual path
>> is reading your your books.
>> Yes.
>> Um
you've stated uh frequently that 540 or
unconditional love has the power if you
reach that level has the power to cure
whatever ills you or whatever disease.
>> Well I didn't say that. No not at 540.
But uh 540 is a level of healingness of
incurable conditions. Aa course of
miracles uh
540 and up uh that which is impossible
becomes possible. Yeah. It's a
transformation to a different dimension
of possibility. Yeah.
>> Okay. So um I've I've suffered from
chronic and clinical depression.
>> Yeah.
>> Um for years actually.
>> Yes. Yeah.
>> Um and I find what what I read from you
um very helpful. Also other things I
wonder as a psychoanalysist
what role I'm starting psychoanalysis
and I was wondering what role that plays
in it or would it is that emotional
what's the word?
>> Well everything is physical, mental and
spiritual. I believe you should approach
it from all three.
>> I think you need psycho analysis. I'm
talking about physical, mental, and
spiritual, right?
>> Okay.
>> All right. Physical, there's entity
presence. A lot of them work in a
miraculous way. They certainly are worth
a worthy try. Uh everything is uh mental
and by mental it's also neuroysiology in
the brain. So trying to affect the
brain, physical, mental, and it's also
spiritual. So I believe you should
attack everything on all three levels.
The psychological, the spiritual, and
the biochemical.
Oh,
>> all three.
>> And then over due time you could
probably drop off, diminish the
biochemical. I see.
>> And also these things are very cyclic.
You may have a cycle of 10 or 20 years
where depressions are frequent or
overwhelming and then they will
disappear.
>> You may have a period where they're
there for 5 years and then they
disappear for 10 years and then it'll
recycle back for a year. So it's also
cyclic
and uh
yeah all three all three levels.
>> Okay. And and uh is there a role for
12step groups in this process? I was
>> I don't know any 12step groups for
depression.
>> That's I don't either. I just was
wondering if they
>> um nearest thing would be course of
miracles uh group because that's
recovery from almost everything.
>> That's what I'm doing. Thank you.
>> Yeah. There's also a group called
Recovery, Inc. I don't know if they're
still around as they used to be years
ago.
>> Okay.
>> They addressed depression directly.
>> Yeah. Depression is the most common
emotional illness. It afflicts onethird
of Americans at some time in their life
>> uh to a serious degree.
If you're not depressed because you're
not reading the paper lately.
too dumb to not get you. If you're smart
enough, you do get sort of depressed a
little about human life, its condition,
its limitations,
>> the traps, the ambiguities, you know.
>> Well, thank you for all your options.
>> All right. Don't be depressed about
yourself. Be depressed about the world.
It's more comfortable.
Worry about the
Hokanduka Indians or somebody that
trouble something.
I just made that up. You know, I forgot.
I'm sorry. Project your worry onto
something, you know, human, but not the
personal human. You know what I'm
saying?
>> Yep.
>> I don't know. I thought that was a good
pen. Yep.
>> I'd like to thank you, too, and you have
been a profound influence on me. I find
myself uh
being pulled into uh legal controversies
and uh things like that. Uh
and my first response was to you know I
can live without the money and other
things that are involved
>> and your uh writings on uh passivity and
so forth.
>> Uhhuh.
taught me that I should speak the truth.
>> Yeah. Stand up. Stand up. Stand up for
truth. Speak the truth.
>> You may not win, but you at least
>> That's right. And
>> the obligation has been to deal the
truth.
>> And there's three or four of these
things going on around me
>> and I'm trying to uh I'm the student of
the course and I try to live by the
principles of the course as well.
>> Right.
>> And uh your advice on Psalm 91 was
helpful to me.
And uh I'm I'm not the 100% that you had
on the screen there on forgiveness, but
I find myself better able to forgive.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh the other thing that I have meditated
and and contemplated
is the renunciation
of the fruits of my actions.
And I feel like that helps.
>> Uhhuh. But uh what else can you tell me
on this?
>> It sounds like you're doing very good on
it so far.
The worst that can happen is you get
totally wiped out in your
>> and I I can you get wiped out and
totally penis. Give me a call.
>> Okay.
>> Well, if I don't ascend in the meantime,
let go of the sandbags. You're going to
float right up there, brother.
It's only woe keeping you in this world.
Let go of the woe and bye-bye.
>> The willingness to let go of it all.
>> Sorry.
>> Has a magical effect.
>> You're like fearless after that.
>> Wait a minute.
>> Thank you for your patience.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
Hold on one second.
>> Everything is multi-function now.
That's probably a microphone that takes
your picture while you're talking to it.
You know,
makes a tape recording and transmits it
via the internet to the whole world.
Read about yourself on the internet.
Everybody's talking about you all over
Mongolia.
>> How did it get out there? I don't know.
It was a
satellite or something.
Isn't it that the way the world is, is
it?
>> Yeah.
>> Complex. Yeah. Mhm. Doc, will you lead
us in a prayer of devotional
non-duality?
>> We end up with that. We end up with
that.
>> Non-duality means uh non-conceptual,
>> nonlinear,
in as much as it's silent,
it'll have to be silence. Is that all
right with you? All right, we'll have a
group silence later.
>> Okay.
>> Hello, Dr. Hello Dr. Hawkins.
And I want to thank the staff, too. This
is great.
Um the question I have and I'm sure this
has been gone over a time or two is
there comes a time there's a couple
times it's came up to possibly calibrate
family and I'm kind of like not sure
about doing that and I mean I tried to
stay away from that part you know and we
do a lot of it a lot of muscle tests my
wife and I and
what is your take on on that sort of
>> be what the motivation is see
>> if you're looking for guidance to
understand
uh so it's the context in which you're
asking your intention
if if what you're angry at a person
about is that they're not higher more
than than what they are then you might
get relief you calibrate them and you
find them look they're only one 90 or
something they're they already at being
the best that they can be
>> so you could let go of your resentment.
So your intent, it would depend on what
is your intention to heal, to forgive.
Uh
what would be the intention?
>> Okay. I guess sometimes it's also
there's been a friend of the family who
was wondering about their spouse and I
go, "No, I'm not even going there.
>> I wouldn't go there."
>> Yeah. I mean, that's what that's what I
say. I go, "No."
>> Angels fear to tread there, brother.
Well, thank thank you very much.
>> You got to watch out for curiosity.
Yeah,
>> curiosity killed the cat.
>> And uh curiosity is a glamour.
>> I never read that, but I just realized
that's the truth. Curiosity
uh is first of all innate to life.
Without curiosity,
h humankind, we wouldn't even live. And
cur and curiosity also takes you right
over the edge. uh and you get fried. So,
uh curiosity is on the one hand a
blessing. On the other hand, it's a
trap.
It's sort of a glamour. Sort of a
glamour.
>> Okay.
>> That you have to know all about
something. I've discovered you don't
have to know anything about something. I
wrap it up. I read the instructions and
I say, "All right." And I put it all
back together and put it back on the
shelf.
>> Thank you very much.
Hey.
>> Yeah.
>> I uh I was hoping you I've been using
these prayer beads on occasion and I was
hoping you might
>> You been eating them?
>> Uh not very often. It depends, you know.
>> Oh, yes. Prayer beads. Yes.
>> Yes. I enjoy them very much.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yeah. Um I uh my question to you was uh
have you ever calibrated the the the
fellow Alfred Adler? He was a
contemporary of Young and Freud.
>> No.
>> Uh would you be interested in doing so?
>> Well, he I can tell you right off he
Adler was uh yeah the will and uh he was
very important in the psychoanalytic
movement. Let's see. I never did Adler.
He's be in the good 400. I have
permission to do Al Adler. He was over
440 450 445. I would guess him around 44
445.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Alfred Adler was a he made a very
good contribution to segue analytic
theory.
>> Excellent.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes. Um, my question is that since I
came out here, I've been having a lot of
memories from
uh they feel like memories from like
ancient Rome and so I just was asking
for confirmation on those.
>> What is it you want?
>> These were like
>> flashbacks.
>> Flashbacks.
>> Yeah. What about it?
>> I I was just curious if like uh the
authenticity of those uh specifically
since I came out here just
>> Did you have a flashback? Uh, I was
remembering times in Rome.
>> Yes. Times in where?
>> Rome.
>> I think it was Rome.
>> Oh, Rome. I thought he meant Jerome.
>> He was having flashbacks of Rome.
They're genuine resistance. They're
genuine. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> A lot of us lived in Rome.
>> I was remembering you. So,
>> a lot of us a lot of us lived in Rome.
Yeah.
>> Um, and the other question was, could I
give you a hug?
>> No, cuz the back is too uh fragile.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Thank you very much.
>> You can hug my hand. Those are those are
okay. Yeah.
The other bones, I don't stress them.
Oh, yeah.
The bones break easy. I had a friend hug
me and broke three ribs on one side.
Then I went to a dancing class. Lady
went under this arm and her head hit me
and broke three ribs on that side.
>> My friends are killing me right here.
>> Hi, my question is work related. I'm a
mental health therapist and I work with
a lot of people who um have are on
probation for committing acts of
violence.
>> Yes.
>> Specifically sexual violence.
>> Yeah. And I'm really interested in your
work on the primitive mind and the ethic
mind and wondering if maybe I should
continue
>> mind and
um have been having questions about
whether I should continue the work or
whether it's really not going to go
anywhere.
>> And what work you mean with the
individual patient?
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Well, it depends what kind of uh
>> I'm I'm using pretty much cognitive
behavioral.
>> Oh yeah. CBT. Yeah. Yeah.
>> And
>> I don't know what the results of it is
in that patient group, you know.
>> Okay.
>> I tend to be skeptical
>> of that group.
>> And I wondered if you could test to see
if it would be for that common good if I
continue this work. Maybe I should
change to something else.
>> Is the work you're doing contributing to
the common good?
>> Right.
>> Okay. Look, let's see. We have
permission. We have permission to ask
that here. Okay. The work she's doing is
serving the highest good.
It is serving the highest good.
>> Thank you.
>> See what you're dealing with last is
less gaspers.
>> Yes.
>> Bottom of the pit.
>> All right. So, a lot of times when
they're at the bottom of the pit,
they're more approachable than when
they're still halfway up there.
>> That's
>> when they're at the bottom of the pit,
they become sweetly reasonable.
Then when they're not at the bottom of
the pit, they're still cocky.
>> They're cocky. You might you're wasting
your time.
>> Okay.
>> So, you just let them go in the
direction they go.
The Buddha said you don't have to bring
anybody down because they'll bring them
themselves down by their own hand. So,
you just wait long enough and they will
hit bottom. And when they hit bottom,
they come become sweetly reasonable.
They're willing to do anything.
>> Thank you.
>> That's what you wait for.
>> Yeah.
Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> I just want to say thank you both for
being here. Really appreciate it and
it's wonderful. And I was wondering
what's the best way to increase my
intuitive powers.
>> Uh you don't want to increase your
intuitive powers. What you want to do is
decrease your reliance on thinkingness
itself and perception
and ask God to reveal to you the
answers. You see, I say, you know, when
you step back, it's invitational. It's a
yin position. You're summoning forth
divinity by your willingness to
surrender. You're asking the Holy Spirit
for a miracle. By a miracle, you mean
what you mean is that the Holy Spirit
recontextualizes it. So you see it see
it differently
>> and because you see it differently your
motivation changes without you having to
actually do anything you know. So being
responsive to that which is sort of
revealed. It's like awareness comes on
without going through the thinking
track.
>> Great. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
That's a very linear way of explaining
nonlinearity, huh?
>> Hello, Dr.
>> Susan.
>> You talked about the difference between
divine love and personal love?
>> Yes.
>> And as a a couple rel in a relationship
um as when they go over 500,
does personal love change?
Does
>> No. Personal love can be still at 500.
Um, impersonal love is at 5:40.
We were watching um, what's that music
we sent away for?
>> Oh,
no. No.
>> Shabb.
>> Um,
>> no. No. Shabbomb. Shabb.
>> Do
little richer.
>> That's it.
>> Yeah. Doo op calibrates at 5:15. Why?
Because it's very romantic. It's not
just love. It's romantic love which is
5:15. Now romantic love is very very
personal. So you got to let go of a lot
to get up to 540 which is impersonal
love. But that duop has a certain ma
wonderful magic romance to it. You know
which the young people of today are
really missing is sort of sad. The music
they listen to is often calibrates at 90
or 110.
So they don't know what it is to be
carried away with rapture on the dance
floor, you know, see 5:15.
So uh unconditional is 540.
>> Yeah.
>> And that's a lovingness towards all of
life and all of its expressions.
It's almost a divine state. From 540 to
570 is really saintthood. and and uh
uh spontaneous miraculous begins to
occur.
Arthur Peio was at 570.
Yeah. Saintliness.
Um a great pope is at 570. Great uh
uh Daly Lama is there around 570.
>> All right. Thank you.
Yeah. Hello.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
I just didn't want the whole day to go
by without me coming up here and
thanking you
because this has been such an emotional
day for me. Um, and also I wanted to
know if I can look out at an audience
because I was frightened last time I was
here. I was really frightened and
sitting in line I wasn't I mean in the
line I wasn't frightened. It was like
all of a sudden the fear just wasn't
there and I go I I nearly just said that
I didn't need to do this and let the day
go by without doing it and I just
couldn't not face the challenge today. I
just something in me needed to come up
here and and um
>> transcend that fear.
>> Yes. And also I needed to come up here
to get a picture of this day
and there was no way to go by without
getting up here to get a picture.
Everybody had a picture and I I felt
like if I let it go by without having a
picture I would have missed the day, you
know. So
>> Okay,
>> that's why I'm here.
>> Okay.
Oh,
thank you. Thank you.
>> So sweet. Thank you, Dr. Hawkins. Thank
you, Susan.
>> I just went out to sea with you. You
know,
that's the way we used to do it, out at
sea when the women weren't around. You
know,
you got a jug of
Hey ho ho.
>> Then you made a wonderful point.
>> Well, that's a different story, right?
>> It's a privilege and an honor, Dr.
Hawkins. It really is.
>> Um, on a personal note, um, I've had
some kind of real upheaval in my
personal life in the last couple of
years. Uh, very, shall we say,
emotionally traumatic and I harbor a
certain amount of bitterness. And I'm
just wondering if you could give me some
suggestions on how to get to a place of
forgiveness and forgiving.
>> You have to dissect the bitterness, you
see, as to his components,
>> right?
>> Um,
you're angry at a person or events,
>> right?
>> All right. So, you've got to be more
angry.
Uh, you have to assign yourself six
o'clock every night, you were going to
have anger period,
>> right? In that period, I want you to be
angry and hate that person and fight
them and skewer them
>> and scream hatred at them.
>> Right?
>> And do it to the full extent,
>> right?
>> No holding back. Just lay on the floor
and writhe with anger and resentment,
>> right?
>> More, more, more and more.
>> Okay?
>> And keep doing that until you run out of
it.
>> But wouldn't that just anchor anchor
anger more into me?
>> No. No. Because what you're feeling now
is a stack.
>> I'm at an impass. And I and I recognize
that, you know, somebody says, "Well,
forgiveness is a gift you give to
yourself." But
>> well, those are all jargon. Those are
all
>> I'm just I I need I'm just I understand
getting angry, but how is that going to
get me to forgiveness? Because
forgiveness is it seems light years
away.
>> Well, first it's anger. Then what what
is the anger about?
Uh
>> unfairness or what? What?
>> Betrayal at the deepest levels.
>> Deep betrayal. Like spousal betrayal.
>> Even deeper than that.
>> Even deeper. Your mother.
>> No. My spouse betrayed me and then she
turned my own mother against me.
>> Your truly.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Oh, that's pretty common.
>> So there's no problem with it.
They do it all the time. Yeah.
>> You get a paranoid who has delusions of
infidelity, goes to your mother,
convinces you, your mother, that you've
been out whoring around with every woman
in town where actually you haven't. And
your mother turns against you.
>> Is that it?
>> That all?
>> No, it wasn't me that was doing the
whoring. It was my ex-wife.
Anyway, the stories you see how they
propagate and in the end they don't
amount to anything because the
relationship is either based on
something of a different level or not.
And if it's not, then there's no loss.
>> Mhm.
>> So nobody's convinced somebody else
>> I'm not worried about other people.
They've got their own drama. They can
keep their drama.
>> Your problem. I still got I still got
bitterness and I can't
>> about what? I can't get out of you about
what?
>> About uh having total faith and trust
and love in a person.
>> Yes.
>> And then it appeared like they just
turned around and stabbed me in the
back.
>> How did they stab you in the back?
Well, I don't want to get in a whole
long therapy session, but I was married
to a woman for 18 years and then she she
ran off with another guy and broke up my
family and destroyed the lives of my
children.
>> Your wife ran off with another guy.
>> Well, but it's not just that. She
destroyed the lives of our children and
our family.
>> The family was destroyed,
>> right? Yeah.
>> And and my relationship with my mother's
destroyed, too.
>> Oh, God. Everything fell to pieces.
>> I'm not trying to complain. I'm just
trying to get to forgiveness. I want to
get to forgiveness.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh,
I don't forgive her. That equal
love. I want to get unconditional love
so that I can move on in my I don't know
my higher levels of consciousness.
>> You're stuck in a resentment. Is that
it?
>> Correct.
>> You're stuck in the resentment.
>> Correct. I want to move beyond that.
>> Do you think she's karmic payback, Mr.
Playboy?
>> No.
>> You don't think so? You've been
fidelities all your lifetime? I don't
think so.
>> Maybe not this time. It could be in the
previous
>> Well, it wasn't in this lifetime. I can
promise you that
>> it wasn't in this lifetime. That's why
it seems unjust.
>> You're paying back for something. Say, I
asked God to reveal to me, you know, the
value of this experience. You're paying
back something.
It's not good karma that you're
experiencing right now, is it?
>> No. But it
>> Now, let me tell you, you were in some
some lifetimes. is you were an SOP. You
hoarded around and really broke all
kinds of hearts.
>> You didn't. You're the first man in life
who didn't.
We were all animals at one time.
>> Right.
So, you think this is my bad karmic?
>> Some kind of a karmic. It's some kind of
karmic undoing. Just my guess. I don't
have the right to ask this, but uh do I
have the right to ask this? Is it okay
to ask this as a teaching example? He's
undoing what he he himself has done.
It's so obvious.
>> When something happens to you that
you've totally unearned in this
lifetime, then it's coming from
elsewhere.
>> So, I'm I'm paying karmic debt for my
previous lifetime.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Right.
>> Don't forget we're evolving up. In past
lifetimes, you weren't exactly a
sweetheart. None of us were.
Anyways, we're not where we are cuz we
came down from there. We're here because
we came up from there. You see?
>> All right. So, in this you say,
>> "Dear God, I don't know what this means,
but I surrender to this experience. I
ask your help to overcome this
bitterness. The bitterness is because I
don't understand it from a larger
context. I ask the Holy Spirit for a
miracle to recontextualize it so I see
it as it is in truth."
Mhm.
Thank you very much.
>> Things of that depth and that pain don't
come about for no reason. There it's the
undoing of something and you've
forgotten. The minute you're the minute
you you're in another body, you totally
blank out on the previous lifetimes,
>> right?
>> You have to suppose the likelihood is of
that. If you learn past life recall
techniques, you could probably go back
there and reexperience it out. But
that's a a nicity. You can just take my
word for it that it's very likely that
this is not happening for no reason.
>> Okay. All right.
>> It's serving some karmic purpose. It's
also a lesson for the other people
involved. You're not the only one
involved in this little drama,
>> right?
>> It's like psycho drama in which
everybody is learning something.
>> Well, I know she's got her own karma to
deal with. That's this thing.
>> So, what can I do to further evolve my
karma to good karma in this lifetime?
Well, just constantly surrender and
forgive yourself for any negative
feelings you have because you're only
human naturally going to have a
resentment, right?
>> It's only human and forgive yourself for
that and stop feeling guilty about it,
>> right?
>> Say, I surrender it to God and ask God
to see it differently.
>> I surrender to God and ask
>> God to see it differently. You know, I
ask a larger context and
>> a larger context.
>> Yeah. And if you get a chance, you can
go into past life recall. People teach
hypnotic techniques. Uh and if you go
back into a past life, you'll it'll
rerun. So your past life is not like a
memory like you saw that movie
yesterday. Past life, you like go in
your astro body, you reenter that time
dimension. And that lifetime begins to
that that runs again as a current
reality. You reexperience the thing. And
now you understand very well why it's
all coming about.
Right.
>> Yep.
>> Okay.
>> It's a very interesting experience if
you find somebody teaches self hypnosis
and does past life recall.
>> Yeah. I've I've actually read books on
it and it's a subject that interests me.
>> Yeah. It might you might be driven to
that just you know for the sake of
undoing this one thing.
>> Right. Okay. All right.
>> Other than your your life going to hell
and your life being a total family
destroyed. I mean it's really not too
bad, you know.
I know. It's great. It's a great life
just to be here with you. That makes it
all worth it.
>> I I think I think most of us in the room
have been in a really bad situation at
one time or another. How many people
here have been in a really baddy?
>> That helps. How many people have never
gone through a real baddie?
No weirdos here. You know,
it's pretty universal to go through a
real crusher at least once every
lifetime because
uh the fact that we're spiritually
evolving tends to bring it up. It brings
it up. Yeah. To live it out. Yeah.
>> I just wanted to check in with the
teacher.
>> Oh, yes. God bless you.
>> God bless you. Thank you.
Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. Everybody here's been through a
cruncher. I guess that's the price of
one lifetime. You can go back, but
you're going to have to go through a bad
cruncher.
That's a you know what in the ringer you
leg in the
>> Good afternoon.
>> Leg in the ringer.
>> I might briefly run a couple things past
you that I've been going through
spiritually. Um,
in meditation, I seem to be finding
uh I spent a lot of time in meditation
and lately I'm hitting a like a black
wall that um it's really a comfortable,
safe place where
>> I always feel like I'm coming out of it
knowing something I didn't know
>> when I was there. Mhm.
>> Um, so it makes me wonder I I understand
the immen immensity of the void itself.
>> I I don't Is there numerous Yeah, it's
not the void. Is there numerous voids
you go through?
>> No.
>> No,
>> no, there's just a blank uh
>> uh No, it's a good space.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah, it's a very it's a very nice
place. It it it just keeps showing up
and and I just kind of hang out there
for a while.
>> We'll keep going further into it.
>> Yes, I will. And
>> we never see you again. and it was the
void.
>> Um there's there's this fabulous tool
that I've been using from the course of
miracles. Yeah. Um Christ guidance and
uh Christ control.
>> Yeah.
>> It was in the course of miracles to hand
things over to Christ guidance and um
when when it's too much to hand it over
to Christ control. I I don't hear much
talk of this um often. Do you have any
any view on that at all?
>> No, it's not a term I'm familiar with
>> really.
Okay.
>> Surrender to God is the general term of
it.
>> Yeah. I would like to say that surrender
has been the most powerful tool that
>> Yeah.
>> that um I've I've used since I started
reading your books which started it all.
So thank you very much doctor.
>> Thank you.
I'm very grateful to be here and um I
just feel so overwhelmed with the love
of this experience and not just yours
but these people are so beautiful. Mhm.
>> Um and what prompted me to come up
because I was feeling very happy to say
stay in my chair, but I decided to come
up because um I'm a mother of three
children and when you were talking about
the brainwashing in the media and in
society and the calibrations of our
universities now,
it is very dismaying. Uh, and I just
wondered if you might have some words of
hope or counsel. No
>> to a parent.
>> It's a jungle out there.
>> Thanks.
>> It's not a great time to have children.
I don't think
for that very reason. Where are you
going to send them to school? How are
you going to counter uh what you know is
coming? I don't know.
It's difficult.
>> Where would you go? Where would you
live? Where would you send them to
school?
What I do is I calibrate the various
universities and schools to see which
ones calibrate the highest.
That's what I do. What else could you
do? Then I would try to educate them in
advance, you know, so that they watch,
they become the the observer witness
instead of the victim of that kind of uh
thinkingness.
>> Yeah. Oh, what about being a parent, you
know, before World War II and all the
Nazi youth are being indoctrinated
with fascist ideology?
It's like boy scout camp. They all go
camaraderie and they all repeat these
mantras, you know, do and die for their
fear. Uh what if you had children then?
>> Depends on how important they are.
It might be important enough that when
you saw the way things are going, you
would leave the culture. Many people
did. They left Germany
and uh did not want to be indoctrinated,
did not. So it's very difficult being a
parent right now.
I would calibrate the various options
and see what is possible.
>> Thank you.
>> You may have I mean you would it would
take private school probably, you know.
>> Yeah. In the old days, people used to
have tutors that taught them in various
subjects, you see. So, you want to be
learned or you want a degree. There's
two different things. You can be have
all kinds of degrees and not be very
learned. I mean, more dumb professors
I've ever met in my life. And you can be
a scholar on yourself and be wellversed
and brilliant and without a degree. So,
you have to decide is a degree
important? If so, in what field? You
know, it depends on what you want to go
into. Some fields you have to have a
degree.
So in that case, you're going there to
get the degree and you're aware that the
learning is going to be limited and
slanted. So for for
to know it in advance, it protects you
from it.
I can just listen to all kinds of
propaganda and not be brainwashed
because I recognize that it's propaganda
when I spot it.
>> So a highly intelligent person who's
aware of that could spot. I hear the
programming coming. You can see them on
television. They talk like uh
they talk like people that are
brainwashed talk in a brainwashed talk.
You can tell the minute that they
they're like in a in a hypnotic state,
mechanical repetition of that which
they've been programmed. You can spot it
in an instant like that.
So it's hard being a parent right now.
>> Thank you so much. Thank you so much.
It's a very tough era to be a parent.
>> Yeah.
>> She inspired me.
>> The last time I came up here,
>> my ego came up and then I froze.
>> Yeah. Yes.
>> So, I just wanted to face the fear.
>> Okay. Good.
>> And say thank you.
>> All right. Sweet.
There's nothing the fear about fear.
Fear itself. You just let yourself be
scared.
>> Just be scared. You're not scared
enough. You let yourself be more and
more and more scared. Finally, we say,
"Oh, the hell with it." You quit.
Scared.
I'm glad you you faced it up today.
>> Thank you.
>> All right.
>> You're right. That's good courage for
you.
>> Stage fright is a scary one.
>> I never seen our audience attack
anybody.
>> No, no, but the unconscious fear, you
know.
>> I just want to say thank you and I was
also inspired to face my fear. So, I'm
doing it.
>> Good. My question is um I work closely
with a woman who seems to be dealing
with a lot of grief.
>> Yes.
>> And what is in her best interest when
that comes up? What is the best way to
react or what is best
>> what's your relationship with her?
>> I'm her caregiver. I
>> Oh, caregiver.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. So, you help her through it is
to decompress it as much as possible.
Let her weep it out and experience it
out.
And uh you try to take her to
acceptance. Yeah.
>> I have a hard time moving from sympathy
to empathy. I feel like she brings up a
lot of emotion in me.
>> Oh, I see. I see. Yeah.
>> Uh get another job. You know,
>> that's what Broccoli say.
What did Broccali say? What would be
Rocky say?
>> Get a job. Go to work. Get a job.
>> Go to work. Get a job.
>> We're all done.
>> No, it's a difficult what her role
should be, you know, and how much she
can help that person
>> and how much she can be of help to that
person. You know, compassionate
companionship in itself is very valuable
that somebody cares enough uh for you to
help you live through the experience.
And somebody asked that we finish it up
with a prayer today uh in line with the
devotional non-duality.
And therefore I thought u um that which
is the voice of God is silence
that we sink into the voice of God. We
sink into the silence which is
indicative of divine presence.
Behind the thought behind the
thinkingness is an infinite silence.
And the infinite silence is the source
of all existence.
And
between the thoughts, under the thoughts
is the profound silence. And all we have
to do is become aware of that silence.
All we have to do is become aware of
that silence by realizing it's there.
Behind all the sound of the universe,
the silence is forever there.
Behind the sounds in the woods, in the
woods are silent.
The sound of the bird
doesn't have anything to do with the
silence. You see the silence
is maintained
even though there's sound above it but
the only reason you can hear the sound
is because it against the background of
silence. So the silence is there right
in the middle of sound. So you focus on
the on the silence which is everpresent
in the middle of cacaphony and
catastrophe as the bullets are flying
around and the planes are crashing and
all hell is breaking loose and there's
nothing but the infinite silence.
So you identify with that silence and
just maintain awareness. You can go
about your daily life and do everything
that you need to do and at all times
still be aware of the presence of the
silence.
So that gives you a centering. So a a
centering kind of prayerfulness is
you're always aware of the silence which
is the infinite context. The reality of
the presence of God is an infinite
silence.
And then that which you hold in mind in
that silence tends to manifest
not as a result of causation
but potentiality manifesting.
And we thank thee oh Lord for thy divine
presence as the infinite silence out of
which arises our existence.
Amen.
Man, that was a pretty fancy prayer,
wasn't it?
Okay. It's my joy to be with you again
and I look forward to our next meeting.
And we finish with the same we started.
Gloria and Excelsius Dio.
We thank thee, oh Lord, for thy divine
presence.
You are my gift. You're my gift from
God.
Thank you, God.
Everyone here is my presence from God, I
tell you.
Yeah. What a blessing.
What a blessing. Look at these gorgeous
flowers. Look at that.
Gorgeous.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
Hallelu.