Excelsis Deo together again. We can all sit down
Homophobes over there Islamophobes over there
Jesusphobes in the back
Buddhophobes and other heretics over there
We believe in unity of course
Everybody's phobed about something
Phobes means fear of fear of like agoraphobia
How many people here have had phobias?
Oh boy
Sometimes in spiritual work you go through a period of phobias. I had it really bad back in New York
I couldn't go over bridges
Couldn't go in elevators. Couldn't be in a closed room. Oh boy. Oh boy
I'm only scared that I won't be afraid of anything
I mean I walk in front of a car or something not knowing to be afraid of it, you know
Well today we're speaking on
God versus science
God versus
science
It's a very large social dialogue a
Couple of months ago. I think November Time magazine had God versus science on the cover
And it was odd because I'm writing a book, you know about that
And I was writing the chapter on God versus science and time came out with a thing God versus science
Synchronicity young Carol Young talked about
Synchronicity how there's a time a time for all things, you know, yeah
So today this today we're going to try to differentiate and solve the problem. We're going to try and solve the problem of the scopes trial
1926 and
That has really never been resolved never been resolved
logic and science versus
Faith and God has never been solved
it's been discussed many books on it and
So I'm happy to announce it today. We will solve it
I mean, it's a snap really once you see it
All these dunderheads keep monkeying around that and the answer is so simple
Golly, all right. So
How many here are new today? Oh my there's always more news than I think
Well, just because we have to decide should we start with the new slides and then move to the older?
Should we just do a quick review of the basics?
What did they say? I?
Can't I can't hear him?
What do they want new slides?
Do you want the new slides you want to jump right off it? They want to jump right in. Oh, they're spoiled aren't
All you folks are spoiled, okay
However it is necessary to start with slide one
Well, it's my obsessive compulsive nature I can't help it
You don't do what you're supposed to do yet to stand in the corner and I don't spend the corner now
We'll skip all of the usual, what we usually do, but I just need slide one, because on
slide one you see the resolution of the Scopes Monkey Trial, and the resolution of God versus
science.
The means of understanding it, is this all fuzzy, is this, or is it me?
It looks like it's not focused exactly right.
Fuzzy, was he?
Fuzzy, was he, map of consciousness, fuzzy, was he, well, I'll give you the secret of
it anyway.
Now, on this map of consciousness, which everybody understands, goes from one to a thousand,
you see, each one of these levels has its own paradigm of reality.
This is prideful reality, this is anger, resentment, getting even.
This is desire, and wantingness, cravingness, Hollywood, a lot of bosoms, and flash, and
stuff, and, well, you can make a living, let's face it, and then there's the whole fearful
domain, so each one of these is a whole domain, you might say, and most people on the planet,
probably 85%, live from here.
Down, 85%, in America, 55%, 55% live below the line, and in the world, about 85%.
So, each one of these has its own paradigm of values and realities, what's acceptable,
its status symbols, each one of these things is its own paradigm.
It's its own world, in a way, so, you know, in the recent headlines, you see, people living
in a certain world, it isn't that world is wrong, it's just that's the way that world
is, and if you're going to play the game of that world, that's the way you play it.
Now, up here, we move into a different domain, we move into a more healthy, positive, and
of course, what's important is the brain physiology changes.
People want to know.
People want to know how we're going to solve the clash of civilizations.
I have no idea, because one civilization lives from here up, and the other civilization
lives from here down.
So, how do they get along in the wild?
Not too good, frequently.
That's the condition of the world, eh?
All right, so here we get up to the world of reason is in the 400s.
The world of logic and reason.
This is the paradigm of reality of the Western world, logic and reason.
Now, the religion that we're having conflict with says, is against reason, does not want
to use logic or reason, because it couldn't interfere with faith.
I can understand the argument, but it does cause a dilemma.
All right, so, you see, reason and logic is in the 400s.
This has to do with intellectual comprehension, the great books of the Western world, and
this is the world of science, and it likes logic and reason and proof, et cetera.
So, this is a whole domain, the level of the 400.
Spiritual realities, you don't really calibrate true spiritual realities until you get in
the high 400s and actually formally in the 500s.
So, the world of science lives in this domain, it's actually a different paradigm of reality,
and the spiritual lives in this, from here up.
They are two different paradigms.
You can't mix levels, you can't mix levels of truth.
So, you cannot apply the processes of this level to this level, nor can you apply the
processes of this level to this level.
This is the world of science.
There is a certain idea that if you follow, if you use reason to follow truth, the truth
will eventually tell you to God, but that will take you to God, but that's sort of hopeful,
unless you're familiar with the writings of Hawkins.
It's only Hawkins who will take you to God through reason and logic, consciousness calibration.
All right.
So, the reason for the seeming conflict.
The reason for the seeming conflict.
The reason for the seeming conflict is because they're two different paradigms.
So you can't prove or disprove God from the level of the 400s.
That's sort of intellectual grandiosity, which we'll see some of later.
So these two, there are two different realms.
And you can't apply the rules of one realm to the other.
You can't solve scientific problems with love and prayer.
Right? Did you try it in grade school? Algebra?
Dude, God, what's the answer to this one?
42. 42.
They don't apply.
So the rules of this level are not the same as this level.
And so the problem of God versus science is really one of mixing paradigms.
Mixing paradigms.
It is not solvable on the level in which it is presented.
It's not solvable.
And then there's all kinds of people who try to do so,
and they sound just as dumb as the people who try to prove it the other way around.
You can't prove God a galactic.
So let's see. We'll move on to the slides we're going to do today then.
Let's see.
We have to jump to...
Well, let's see.
Let's do 91,
and then we'll do 43.
44.
And then we'll move to the slides for today.
We were just talking about the 400s.
I don't think we've shown this slide before.
These are the great scientists over time.
So in science versus religion, or science versus God,
these people represent science.
The great names of history, from Aristotle, Sir Francis Bacon, David Bohm,
David Bohm was about the highest.
He starts to cross over, and his writings tend to cross over.
Niels Bohr, Copernicus, Charles Darwin, who's very big in this discussion, is at 450.
Albert Einstein is at 499.
Euclid, Michael Faraday, Sir Alexander Fleming, the discovered penicillin.
Discovered penicillin.
And Fleming is sort of a compadre.
He's a great man.
He's a great man because the reason I teach is for the same reason Fleming couldn't rest
until he got somebody to recognize the value of penicillin.
Once you discover something of great value to mankind, or you can see the value of mankind,
you can't really rest until you've got the message out there.
So once the world got the message, you know, Fleming had accomplished his goal.
Sigmund Freud at 499.
And here we have Galileo.
Galileo at 485.
It took 400 years to excuse him.
He was excommunicated for 400 years.
It was in the late 1980s that he got finally forgiven for disobeying the church.
It wasn't for what he taught.
It was because he didn't mind ecclesiastic law, which told him to shut up.
He kept blabbering.
Stephen Hawking, of course, still alive at 499.
So we have some real geniuses still alive.
Helmholtz, we have Hippocrates, Thomas Huxley, Kekul, the, what do you call that ring?
Lord Kelvin, Kepler, Malthus, James Maxwell, Sir Isaac Newton, 499.
Sir Isaac Newton was, of course, heavily assigned.
He was a scientist.
So many of the great scientists of history were quite religious in their personal life.
Sir Isaac Newton was very religious.
So a number of these great scientists in their personal lives were very religious.
However, they could not explain it.
They could not explain how come they were religious despite their scientific erudition.
So we have Semmelweis.
We have Steinmetz.
We have Thiel, Adige, Chardin, Pierre, 450, Ludwig Wittgenstein.
So these are the great names.
They represent the 400s.
They represent the 400s as far as their intellectual output and work.
They've changed all of society, and they set the basic structure of science.
This is the basic structure of science looking at it.
Out of that arose all the rest of science.
And yet, a number of them were extremely.
Devout in their personal lives.
Yes?
Okay, let's go to the next slide then.
I don't remember what they were.
Anyway, all right.
So we're going to contrast these two realms.
The great scientists of history in the 400s all the way up to 499.
Freud was at 499.
Einstein, a great many of them.
The great geniuses of science were at 499.
Isaac Newton, 499.
All right.
So that's that paradigm of the 400s.
It stops at 499.
Some of them in their personal life were quite devoted.
But that was not in their public work.
That was in their private life.
Spiritual teachers, on the other hand, this is their public life.
Their work life is the same as their personal life.
So you're familiar with this.
This list, it's in the book, and I tend to repeat it in the books I'm writing subsequently so that people don't have to flip back and look in some other book and look for the page.
So when it's convenient in the book I'm writing now, I just repeat this, and I just say repeated for convenience.
But these are the great names that we know throughout history.
And you'll see they tend to be somewhere in the high 400s, but then they're almost all in the 500s.
And the most erudite, the great sage.
The great sages are really in like 700, are the great sages.
The great avatars, Jesus Christ and Buddha, are in 1,000.
So here we see James Allen.
Not everybody's familiar with him.
He teaches non-duality.
Here we have the great names of spirituality, Aurobindo, Annie Vison, Wallace Black Elk, Bodhidharma, Jacob Bohm, Richard Buck.
Swami Buddha Nanda, Eric Butterworth, a very well-known teacher, Ram Chandra, Confucius, the current Dalai Lama.
Dalai Lama and the popes tend to be, Dalai Lama tend to calibrate about the same.
The level of sainthood is around 570, and the head of the Vatican is usually around 570, and so is the Dalai Lama.
And here we have great sages.
We have great names such as Dogen.
We have Meister Eckhart, who got into his own trouble with the Catholic Church, didn't he?
Because he was a mystic.
So even those who are religious are compatible with the religion only to a certain level.
And once you get up into the 700s, you may not start having trouble with the ecclesiastic authorities.
Because by the 700s, you've become a mystic.
So instead of ecclesiastic doctrine, one may now begin speaking of one's own inner knowingness.
In Catholicism, or in Christianity, it's called Unio Mystica.
Unio Mystica is the equivalent term for the mystic.
As the small self dissolves into the Self with a capital S,
the knowingness begins to spring forth from within.
It constitutes the so-called Purusha, the knowingness teacher within the spiritual teacher.
The spiritual teacher no longer speaks from personhood, but from the awareness.
So the teacher is speaking of an awareness.
The teacher is not talking about himself personally.
The teacher doesn't even have an interest in himself personally.
The person of the teacher is boring.
That's why he never talks about it.
What does he do? He eats breakfast? He takes a nap at night?
What's the talk about, you know what I mean?
So the illumination comes from within.
They then become a mystic.
And the highest teachers then are the mystics,
who go from, let's say, enlightenment is really formally at level 600,
Satchitananda, a state of silent bliss.
And most people that reach that leave then, 50% leave,
once they hit that state, because the invitation is open,
and there's no purpose any further in the physicality.
However, there may be some prior karmic agreement,
and the person may decide to continue on.
So, to have anybody on the planet,
over 600 is rare.
And there are whole centuries, whole centuries,
when there was not one single person on the planet calibrated over 600.
Yeah, not one.
Yeah, for decades.
So these are all, so this is just a different paradigm.
Emmet Fox, you know,
Joel Goldsmith, all the well-known names,
Manly Hall, Aldous Huxley,
Karmapa,
that I had a chance to meet myself,
and people whose names I can't read up here.
Brother Lawrence, of course,
the Jesus prayer,
everybody knows the prayer of Brother Lawrence.
Just constantly keep the love of God within your heart.
It's a conscious recall.
Nisargadatta Maharaj, Ramana Maharshi,
these are 720,
these are recent,
people recently on the planet.
Mutt Kananda, who I also had a chance to meet,
was a very entertaining and fun person to be with.
So, alright, so the only reason to point them out
is I wanted to contrast the great scientists,
it's very obvious who they are, what they stand for,
and how they operate.
And even though they may personally have a spiritual understanding
and be devoted,
their public life is not the same as these people.
These people, their public life
was reflected that which they had become.
So, now, what's the next slide after that one?
44?
Oh, that's just more spiritual teachers, okay.
Well, it's just because I wanted you to see
a whole lot of science over the centuries,
over the centuries,
and that's one paradigm of reality.
And the spiritual people have a different paradigm.
Now, you see, the scientist is supposedly objective,
and he deals with the linear domain,
specifics of the linear domain.
Spirituality went from 500 up,
you're dealing with the non-linear domain.
It's no longer linear,
therefore, it's no longer provable.
It's not in the realm of provability.
So, to apply the rules of science,
which have to do with logical provability,
they have to do with content.
Spiritual reality has to do with context.
You cannot prove context from content.
So, all attempts to prove in either direction are futile, yeah?
Because one is air and one is water, you know?
All right, so, here's the pope in 570,
the last pope in 570,
Father Pio, 585, Plotinus, Huang Po,
who we've discussed a number of times
when we discussed the void.
So, here we have the great names.
You recognize them all.
And here's my pal Socrates,
like an old buddy.
And Socrates really was a big help in my life,
and continues to be until today.
Here's the white brotherhood.
All right, so, we're all familiar now,
and I've put these in circles,
several books to repeat it.
So, you see a contrast between two paradigms,
the linear, which is science,
the linear, documentable, provable.
The non-linear is experiential,
experiential, not provable.
However, now with consciousness research,
it's confirmable.
It's confirmable, but not provable.
In fact, there's something that calibrates at 700,
Ramana Maharshi or something,
and we know what that means,
because we've used it, like an altimeter.
We've been to so many places with the altimeter,
that we know what 700 means.
So, that's confirmatory,
and it's evidentiary,
but it's not logical proof.
So, we'll move to the next one, yes?
What does that say?
I can't read it at all.
Well, let's see what it says.
Let's say this is love.
What does that say?
Passion and attraction?
No, that's the wrong slide.
We don't want that one.
Which one do you want?
Well, let's see.
That's brain function.
We could do brain function.
Let's just do brain function, review that,
and then we'll be done with the review.
23 is brain function.
I just wanted people to notice that.
Okay.
Have you got that one?
Because spiritual work,
just by your intention and your alignment,
your commitment,
brings up kundalini energy,
a spiritual energy,
which then creates the etheric brain
and the etheric body.
This happens at consciousness level 200.
From 200 down,
the brain is dominated by animal instincts.
This is the world of the ego,
and it's natural,
because they're dominated by that,
think in terms of dominance,
pride,
getting,
getting even,
the alpha male,
the wolf pack,
territorial.
So that's today's headlines, isn't it?
The alpha male at the head of a country,
they're all very territorial,
they glare and bare their teeth at everybody else,
and so,
you see,
mankind is still very much
on the level of the animal.
Why?
85% of the population of the world
calibrates below 200.
The language of the animal
makes sense to the populace.
So if I want to be a big man
in a less evolved,
let's say,
country than this one,
I have to talk about enemies
and hostility
and getting even with people
and annexing people next to me
and capturing people
and killing them,
because that's the language
of the jungle.
So that's the world of the jungle.
Kill or be killed,
territorial,
alpha male against alpha male,
challenge,
and the bearing of the teeth
and the growling.
So every night's weekly news
or evening news
is the news of the growling.
This prime minister said that,
this general said that,
this leader or this president
of this country said that.
And they all go
grrr, grrr, grrr, grrr, grrr, grrr,
and then they go,
me bigger you, brr,
me bigger you, brr.
Me, atomic,
ho, ho, homo.
Oh, atomic one.
We blow up the world
and then our savior will be here.
No, the savior just left
when the world blows up,
not when it doesn't get here.
Time for the saviors before,
not after, folks.
They got everything backward
in that culture.
All right, so we see the input
then goes through the emotional,
fast,
it bypasses the prefrontal cortex,
which is man's reason,
and it goes into his emotional reaction.
So below 200,
people, everything is,
has to do with how you feel about it.
You know, when it comes down to reality,
I don't care how anybody feels
about anything.
Tells me they want to feel about it,
tell your mother.
I'm not your grandma,
you know what I mean?
How you feel about it,
what do I care about your feelings?
What do I care about you feel about it?
Feeling is really narcissistic,
isn't it?
You know, you get on your blog site
and you blat away how you feel
and then you talk about free speech.
Well, it's my right to say that,
you know.
So what?
Nobody cares how you feel about it at all.
Nobody cares.
Nobody really cares
how you feel about anything.
Keep your feelings to yourself.
Don't squish them all over everybody.
Here's my feelings.
That's a far left blog site
in the United States.
Push.
Christianity.
Go on.
Faith.
Thank you bloggers
for reminding us
why we chose this spiritual pathway.
They're good for entertainment.
But sometimes
the spiritual pathways
are the ones that we choose.
I mean,
I have a friend
who has a spiritual pathway.
He's a Christian.
Certain things, it says, will not be forgiven.
So when you start playing with evil at that level,
you're playing in dangerous waters,
you can get caught by the current.
All right.
For one thing, it changes your brain chemistry.
You can imagine what your brain chemistry is like
after you play around with that.
All right.
So at consciousness level 200, then,
what happens is the kundalini energy begins to rise.
It begins to flow up through the energy system.
The energy chakras.
And, of course, science would probably poo-poo.
I'm sure science, I never asked science
whether they think of kundalini energy
because I didn't want to hear the response.
But the kundalini energy that inputs
and begins to shift how you process.
Now you process.
You see, these people do not have an etheric brain.
They have a collective root consciousness,
just like animals do,
and certain levels of mankind.
They don't have an individual etheric brain.
So at level 200, then,
the dominance shifts to the other side of the brain,
and you have an etheric brain.
And the information goes very fast
through your etheric brain,
through your spiritual awareness,
and it comes out completely different.
All right.
So two different domains they are, right?
Two different domains.
Processing things differently.
Coming to different conclusions.
So each one actually perceives the world in a different way.
Actually experiences it.
So you can't make people wrong for how they experience it.
How they experience it.
It's how they experience it.
Unless you're a therapist,
you really don't want to know how they experience it.
I prefer they keep it to themselves.
However, if you calibrate a level of consciousness,
you can pretty much predict how they're going to see it.
So when I see the writer is having to do with science and God,
if you know the calibrated level of the writer,
you can pretty much predict exactly what's going to be said.
It's just language is a little different from one to another.
Let's go to the next.
Have you got them set up there?
61.
Huh?
Well, we'll go on to the circle.
The nature of divinity.
Yeah.
61 is the nature of divinity.
Do I have that circled?
Yes.
Okay, circle it.
I mean, no.
Put it up there.
Oh, yes.
Well, because we're going to be talking about science versus God,
science versus divinity,
and we saw what science calibrated in the 400s up to 499.
Freud, Einstein, all the great geniuses
got about as far as 499.
All right.
And then we're going to contrast that with a level of awareness,
which has to do with the 600 and up.
Mm-hmm.
And classically, the great teacher in certain is called an Arhat,
and Arhat is at 800.
You become the witness observer at 600.
So the witness observer is a very reachable level
in which you constantly surrendering.
You're constantly surrendering the desire to experience.
So let go your addiction to experiencing experience.
That's the short and fastest way.
The fastest way to enlightenment is to surrender your desire
and craving to experience experience.
And you allow that you disappear it as it begins to rise.
You can feel the energy of interest beginning to attach to a thought,
and you surrender it right there.
You nip it in the bud.
So you'll reach a point where you're no longer experiencing experience.
And that is just the hip list from which you can do anything,
including leave here.
Seeing into one's self nature is a Buddhist term
because the Buddha did not like to use the term God
because he thought it was so misleading.
Everybody has their own opinions about God.
So if you use the term God,
they're going to be looking for a projection of their own definition.
And that which is the ultimate is not definable,
certainly not within linear conceptual terms.
So the Buddha thought it wiser to give it no name
and just if you let go of your attachments,
let go of your attachments and aversions to the linear domain,
stop identifying with it,
you will come into the presence of the infinite non-linear,
the Buddha nature.
Seeing into one's self nature.
On the way there, you may go through the void.
And people are afraid of the void.
I tell them, don't be afraid of the void
because there's nothing there.
One thing good about the boogeyman,
there ain't no boogeyman in the void.
There ain't no boogeyman there.
Well, I'll become nothing.
So what's your problem with that?
You want to be something, don't you?
The ego wants to be something.
Therefore, the ego is afraid of becoming nothing.
I want to be somebody.
I don't want to be nobody and a nothing.
Why don't you want to be a nothing?
What's wrong with being nothing?
You won't have any problems at all.
No taxes, nothing.
Nobody will be looking for you.
You go through the void of nothingness.
Once you stop experiencing experience,
everything becomes still and infinite and self-evident.
Everything.
Everything is complete and total and self-evident.
And you see things differently.
All is.
That's all you can say.
And how to transcend the void?
We've already covered that.
The void of seeming nothingness is,
that's only a seeming nothingness.
Because beyond the nothingness is infinite love of God.
So you then also refuse the void.
And this time I refuse.
I refuse the void, having been there before.
But now with a different awareness.
That divinity was infinite love and it was missing.
So this time there was the refusal of the void,
negated as this is not the ultimate reality.
The ultimate reality is radiant with an infinite, exquisite,
gentle, infinitely powerful love that is its essence.
And then you know you're there.
And at that point everything turns stunningly beautiful.
And the radiance of all, all shines forth with the radiance
of divinity as its essence.
The essence of all existence is divinity itself.
So oneness, we're talking in 850.
Reality is consciousness, which is the realm of our research.
Reality is awareness.
You see consciousness itself still lacks awareness.
There's consciousness.
And then there is the awareness of what's going on in consciousness.
These are the attributes of God, omniscience, omnipresence, etc.
Those are just qualities of God.
They are not what God is.
They are qualities which is an appearance.
So when we look at these things, this is what we call them.
These are the automatic consequence of the reality of divinity itself,
which is all this.
All right, so now we get to the great avatars, the Buddha at 1,000,
Jesus Christ at 1,000, Krishna at 1,000, and then we get to divinity itself,
God as creator, God as divinity, and now we're dealing with they calibrate at infinity.
So those are the paradigms.
You see the paradigm of science is linear, provable, it's in the 400s.
Spiritual reality is extreme.
Spiritual reality is experiential and radically subjective, radically subjective.
Now, science is paranoid about the radically subjective
and really doesn't know whether the first person is a valid contributor to data.
The first person is subjective, what people say, I, the experience of the I.
So science could not possibly validate spiritual reality
because all spiritual reality is the witnessing of the personal self.
So conferences on consciousness and that exclude the first person narrative
all calibrate about 410 or so.
They're supposed to be on science and spirituality or science and religion.
They can't possibly be at 410, calibration level 410.
So.
Because experiential is 500 and up.
All right, so we'll move on then to the next one.
Okay.
I think these will come out okay once we get them.
Yeah.
These are just the terms used for level 600.
Well, it's what the experience is.
Infinite peacefulness, inner silence.
Everything is still, everything is exquisite, and that's why it's bliss.
And it's silent.
And it's sat chetananda, it's total and it's complete.
And it's non-local, non-local.
All right.
What do we go to?
Self-realization.
Is that how we decided to do it?
I guess we did, okay.
Whatever I said must be sold at the time.
Too bad it ain't still true.
Anyway.
This self-realization then, the pathway that we, the pathway to God through truth.
Let's see.
The only science of religion I know of is the one we teach, actually, isn't it?
So, consciousness research is a clinical science, not academic.
Clinical science at least gives us some dimension of where we are.
Self-realization then results in compassion, timelessness, essence.
Self is God-imminent.
And one, it is a gift of grace.
Grace is hard to obtain.
I'll explain.
Grace means, from a logical viewpoint, not earned, not sought for, not accomplished,
but a given.
So, at level 600, one experiences very vividly that the condition is one of grace, one of grace.
Grace is also a frequency within the aura, and those who have been in a state of grace
now have within their aura the energy, the frequency, and the vibration of that grace.
And that's called the grace of the teacher.
Non-personal.
You begin to see creation as an unfoldment, unfoldment, and emergence.
You see that nothing is causing anything.
We repeat that over and over in all lectures, because it's such a roadblock.
Nothing is causing anything.
What happens is,
everything has a potential.
And under appropriate conditions, that potential becomes an actuality.
So, what you're seeing is the emergence of potentiality when the conditions are appropriate.
Now, one of the conditions that makes things appropriate, and that facilitates their emergence,
is spiritual energy itself.
So, many things sit idle, and the minute, not the minute, but under the influence of spiritual,
the kundalini energy, things begin to manifest that would not manifest otherwise.
So, it tends to precipitate what the world calls the miraculous.
When the world notices this, then the world calls that miraculous.
To the people of advanced consciousness, it's not miraculous at all.
It's just the way things come about naturally.
Isn't that so?
When the weather is warm and the wind is right, the bird takes off.
You see?
But he can't take off unless the wind direction is in such a way.
So, intention, the power of intention then, which brings us to the Heisenberg Principle.
So, the only real crossover to me in science and spiritual reality is the Heisenberg Principle.
The discovery that intention collapses the wave function from the potential to the actual,
so that that which could be now manifest,
as is, it brings into is-ness that which could be under appropriate conditions.
So far, no research has been done on measuring the power of the consciousness level of the observer
and its effect on the experiment.
However, we know from history that the higher the level of the consciousness of the field,
the greater the likelihood of the miraculous to appear.
So, creation then is an eternal, endless evolutionary,
very unfolding, and it seems mystical and unlikely because it's beyond cause and effect.
So, these states then of witnessing can be reached relatively easily by contemplation and meditation.
One can become, without any effort really, the observer witness.
How can you be the observer witness?
Well, you decline making any comments about what you witness.
All comments, nobody cares your opinion about it.
You don't have to give it a name, you don't have to figure it out, you don't have to label it.
You just witness it without doing anything.
That is a great discipline.
The mind wants to do something with it, wants to make it pretty, wants to make it right, wants to make it wrong,
wants to get it, wants to get even with it, wants to conquer it, wants to mate with it.
Eat it, put it in your bank account, vote for it, you know, do something.
Don't just sit there.
Don't just sit there, blogger. Do something.
Have a protest march, okay?
I'm protesting. I have a protest march against bloggers.
I have a blog-a-phobe.
A blog-a-phobe.
All right. The next one.
Yeah. All right.
We're contrasting the paradigms of science,
of the provable, logical, definable,
the so-called linear, which is content,
with the context, which is spiritual.
The context then shifts the brain function.
Things are possible over consciousness level 200
that are not possible below 200.
It's almost impossible to see somebody doing something as innocent
and be forgiving below 200.
Because below 200, you see them as the enemy,
and you hate them, and you want to kill them.
From 200 and up, you begin to feel sorry,
and then you find yourself praying for them,
and also getting out of their way.
Divinity begins to become a reality,
and consciousness itself is the fastest pathway to God,
in my own personal experience.
The pathway of consciousness itself,
because all the trainings and the belief systems and all,
what are they all attempting to do?
They're all attempting to bring you
to a certain level of consciousness,
so why not say that in the beginning and save yourself?
All the mantras and stuff, you know.
Why not do that?
Why not head for that right away?
So when you clear away all the confusion,
you see that all you're really doing
is advancing your levels of consciousness.
You say, well, what is holding it back?
What is holding it back?
The attachments.
So one of the attachments is to the secret pleasure ring,
which is the secret pleasure ring,
which is the secret pleasure we get out of emotions,
and including negative ones,
and the secret pleasure we get out of experiencing.
You look at experiencing.
As you're listening to me now,
you're experiencing the words.
You're experiencing the audience.
You're experiencing the setting.
And that's happening of its own.
Now you ask yourself,
could you let go of wanting to experience the experience of it?
And your mind says, yeah, but maybe it wouldn't experience it then.
that. The fastest way is to let go of wanting to experience experience. You'll see that
you have a craving for experience. In fact, everybody here is an addict. We're all addicts,
experienced addicts. We need to take the 12 steps to recover from addiction to experiencing.
We'll start a new 12-step group. Dear God, I need help. I'm addicted to wanting to experience
experiencing. That's a fact. So step one is to tell the truth, that you're hooked on experiencing
experience. That's where you get your jollies. It isn't being at the circus. It's the experience
of the experience of being at the circus. We could put you in an artificial environment where
you're experiencing the circus without even being there. What do they call those? What do you call
it? The atmospheres? Virtual. Yes. All right. We'll put you in the virtual.
You don't have to go to the circus. You can have all the thrills and the spills and the fun without
even getting out of your chair. A virtual. So you see then, if virtual experiences are as good as
the actual, and they say they are, there's no difference, then what you can see is you're not
addicted to anything out there. You're not at the effect of anything out there. You're solely doing
a solo dance within yourself. A solo dance. The addiction to wanting to experience experiencing.
For what? You can juice out of it, right? More. You'll get more juice out of it by not wanting
to juice it and by not trying to do that. If you do nothing but lay back, then the grace of God
reveals all to you effortlessly. There's no need to seek, to get, to gain. There's nothing to
experience because it's beyond experiencing. Because it becomes identity. You only experience
is a duality. There's an experiencer and then there's that which is experienced. That duality
has to be transcended. There is only that which is, with no division into experiencer and
experiencer. All right. Consciousness is then the source of life. Divinity is the all-person
awareness of that. Divinity is innate to all of existence and all of life. And the one thing we
need to understand is that life energy itself is, is, is not destructive. You cannot destroy life.
This fear comes up only at 850. The fear of the void is the fear of the loss. If I won't
experience anything, then I'll lose life itself. You don't have to be afraid of surrendering
life because only the illusory self as a source of life is transient. And life itself is
an attribute, it's sourced by divinity itself. So you cannot lose life. It can only take, change
form. It can only change form. All right. So then we go to the next. So when you run into
voidness, don't be afraid of it because you cannot die in the way that your mind thinks of dying.
Where are we now?
Oh, we're at 84.
Okay, let's go to 84. Okay.
Hmm.
So we did 43 and 44. We did reason, reason, reason. Okay. Uh you'll have to forgive me
about that. Um, these are the qualities and of divinity we've been talking about and we'll
talk more at the end of the year of creation and evolution. But love is the ultimate expression
of divinity. So whatever state you get to, uh, it can be very beautiful. It could be
very silent.
very empty, the essence of love is always there, and therefore to merely include that.
The state is called, the nephabola cannot be described, therefore the paradigms of science
and divinity are totally different.
There is no common vocabulary.
It's ineffable, it's non-verbal, and it comes from within.
And divinity is the source rather than the cause or the effect.
And as you let go of the idea of cause, which we talk about all the time in all the lectures,
you'll see in the world of the ego, everything moves from incomplete to complete,
now incomplete to complete, incomplete, from imperfect to perfect, from imperfect to perfect.
This is not a perfect fist, now it's a perfect fist, now it's a perfect fist.
It's an imperfect fist.
It's always imperfect, you see what I'm saying?
It moves from imperfect to, it moves from incomplete to complete.
In a higher state of consciousness, you see that reality is constantly moving from complete to complete.
It moves from perfect to perfect.
This is a perfect half-formed rose, this is a perfect three-quarters.
So the world of the ego, the world of science would see this as an imperfect rose.
This is an imperfect rose.
We have to force it.
We have to force it to become a perfect rose.
Spiritual dimension, you see, that it's perfect every instant.
Nor is its beauty any different.
So what is the level, higher levels, you begin to see the intrinsic beauty of all that exists.
Everything is intrinsically beautiful.
Everything is intrinsically perfect.
Everything is intrinsically complete, just as it is.
So in reality, everything goes from perfect to perfect.
From complete to complete.
And potentiality actuates then as emergence under the context of spiritual intention.
So we know that spiritual intention is very powerful.
So what we discuss in all the lectures is not really a doable intellectual feat.
It's the unfolding of that potentiality within you.
And you say, dear Lord, I of myself, et cetera.
And then you step back and you ask,
Divinity, and that's the context then that energizes the miraculous.
Yeah?
So where did we go then?
It says 43 and 44.
We did them.
And we did 91.
Okay.
Then we'll go to 100, which is the subject for today.
We've set up the background.
I wanted to contrast two paradigms of linear, provable dimensionality.
One is non-linear, non-provable, experiential, but not provable, therefore called ineffable.
Spiritual realities are in the world of context, energy fields that are non-linear.
The world of science is this paradigm.
So when you talk about God versus science, you see how dumb the whole sentence is.
It's like having saying water versus air.
I mean, they're two different things.
Two different domains, you know, two different domains.
God versus science.
Well, so we'll take some things out of the current dialogue, and I took a number of things
out of the Time Magazine discussion, et cetera, to track where they're going.
Secularism.
So they say our society is moving towards secularism.
Secularism is 185.
For one thing, it's an ism.
One thing to be a skeptic.
It's another to sell.
It is a big program, political program.
Secularism.
It's okay to be religious, but religionism now becomes onerous.
The same with secular.
If the seculars want to be secular, God bless them, but they don't have to snip the cross
off the top of all the steeples of all the churches, you see.
That's secularism.
What's that famous college where they want to take the crucifixion?
The Catholic Church wants to take the crucifixion out of the chapel.
It's been there seventy years, or seven hundred years, I think.
William and Mary, yeah, the chapel is William and Mary.
For political reasons they're going to take the cross out of the chapel.
Does that sound bizarre?
Take the cross out of the chapel.
What's the chapel for?
I don't know.
Calisthenics.
Is it, do you have gym classes in there?
What do you do?
Anyway.
We don't want to be against them, we don't want to be against them, because each person emerges in this lifetime and traverses making karmic choices, karmic options from moment to moment.
This is a world of salvation, the options. Karmically you can move up or down by your choices.
So secular doesn't appeal to me because it's an ism. They're trying to push something on me. It's like Christianism or any other kind of ism.
They're going to try and hold me down and make me become a secular. But I don't want to be a secular. We know what's best for you.
So in the God versus science debate, we see skeptical scientism.
It's pretty well displayed in the quotes in the articles. It says, you know, scientists are outraged and indignant.
Give me a scientist who's outraged and indignant, please.
So that's ism, scientism. When it's a scientism, then science gets outraged and indignant.
Outraged and indignant. It gets all huffed up about it.
And they end up writing a book like...
Richard Dawkins. He missed it by one letter. Oh, well.
Now here we have a real paradox. He writes a book called The God Delusion.
Calvary State 190. Extremely arrogant. Anyway.
Here is a man who writes a book about delusion.
And this man here has a delusion that God is a delusion.
He thinks God is a delusion. He writes a book called The God Delusion.
But that's his delusion. So he wants to share his delusion with us.
Thank you for sharing your delusion, Mr. Dawkins.
That just struck me as so funny when I saw that I was a God delusion.
He's got a delusion that God's a delusion. It's hysterical.
Why? Because in the domain of his reality, it is a delusion.
There's no proof possible.
And if you live in a world where nothing is real unless it's provable, demonstrable, and verifiable,
and you can't measure it or weigh it,
then from his paradigm of reality, God would then be a delusion.
That is certainly understandable as a conclusion.
Because if that was your only way of...
If your only capability was pedestrian logic,
then you would be pretty much stuck with that.
Anti-religionism and scientism tend to be about the same ilk.
So these are all about 180 or 190.
So whenever you see secular this, secular that,
you know right away they're going to be below 200.
Mechanistic reductionism, natural skepticism,
is sort of being brought up in a slightly negative way.
I think a child brought up surrounded by love and affirmation,
tends to be trusting rather than skeptical.
My downside is naivete.
And you can sell me the Brooklyn Bridge, that's been my...
I've needed guardians to keep me from buying the Brooklyn Bridge.
People want to donate it, and then you find there's taxes due,
that's why they want to donate it.
Okay.
So scientism then becomes a religion in itself.
So you really...
It's not a religion.
It's not science versus religion.
It's two religions banging against each other.
Because scientism is just another religion.
Why?
Because you put your faith in it as the ultimate truth.
Whatever you put your faith in as the ultimate truth,
that is your religion.
You've just religionized it.
If there is no facts except the provable facts of science,
you're now a religionist, a religionist.
Natural skepticism, as I said, to me is somebody who was brought up
to be slightly untrusting, untrusting.
The world I lived in was so worthy of trust.
I mean, you know, everybody went to church.
Everybody was moral.
Nobody cheated anything.
Everything was up front.
Your neighbor returned your grass mower when he was done with it.
He didn't steal it or sell it on the black market.
There was no reason to distrust anybody.
So I never thought of distrusting anybody.
It was a novel idea.
Some people, like the local bullies,
it wasn't that you mistrusted them.
It's just that you knew them too well.
It wasn't that I mistrusted he was going to be a bully.
I knew he was waiting for me around the corner.
That's why I took boxing lessons.
And learned how to give him a bloody nose.
And that was the end of that one.
So there's sweat.
So there's what the article called natural skepticism,
which is sort of a negative way of being in the world.
Mechanistic reductionism is the most pedestrian way of thinking.
And that's the basis of all these skeptics.
This is the so-called bottom-up view of creation.
Because our view is from top down.
And we've confirmed over and over again that all of creation,
it calibrates at infinity.
Is the consequence of divinity.
The bottom-up thinks that we all are descendants of monkeys.
That's why they call it the Scopes Monkey Trial.
That what has come to be has done so as a result of accidental evolution.
Accidental.
Not intelligent design.
Because they don't like that term either.
But things just went bumpity bump in the night millions and billions of times.
And finally certain things worked.
And they worked out accidentally.
I'm writing about it right now.
So I'm sort of up on the topic.
You see, if you don't see intelligence,
you watch the Blue Planet.
It shows on Channel 8 once in a while.
The Blue Planet.
It's all about the life at the bottom of the sea.
It's incredibly beautiful.
Incredibly beautiful photography.
Here you see these incredibly magnificent creatures.
Not only incredibly beautiful, magical, mysterious and wondrous.
But from a scientific viewpoint, they're mind-boggling.
They can detect electrical waves from here to there.
And then light up little things that look like food to somebody else.
And that's actually, gotcha.
So you see the emergence of intelligence.
Intelligence.
And you see the intelligence of the design of all of life.
If you look at all of life, especially in great nature movies,
the quickest way to see it is something like the Blue Planet.
You become aware of the intrinsic emergence of intelligence.
Incredible intelligence.
How you can make electricity at the bottom of the sea
under that kind of pressure, etc.
So, to me, intelligence is also evolutionary.
It's evolutionary.
And it's innate to the gift of life itself.
All right.
So we took care of that Dawkins fella.
And we'll beat him up till he gets rid of his delusion.
Beat on him.
Mr. Dawkins, wake up!
Anyway, we send him our love and goodwill.
And we apologize.
As soon as he apologizes, we'll apologize too.
He says,
Our God is a delusion.
He's an enemy of ours.
I think we'd better kill him.
Don't you think so?
All right.
Without a sense of humor, you can't become enlightened.
So...
You never make it through the tight corners.
You need to...
Why?
Because humor is coming from a greater context.
From a greater context, you see that which is...
Which is stingy and cramped and small.
Is, you know...
You have to do it with humor.
All right.
We're going to take a break.
And then we're going to finish up the new slides this morning.
God versus science.
Okay.
We only got...
We're still on number 100.
And you weren't quite done with that.
Okay.
So we're done.
I want to finish them by lunchtime.
All right.
No.
We stop at 1230.
So that's about 45 minutes from now.
Okay.
Fine.
We'll finish it up then.
Let's see.
Any questions thus far?
Anybody got any questions?
No.
Okay.
All right.
Anybody got any questions?
Anybody?
Okay.
You've had your moment.
Now keep the peace.
Our teacher used to go like this.
Now button up your...
Recess is over.
Button up your lips.
Yes.
Well, we got far as far as the unfortunate Mr. Dawkins.
And scientism and natural skepticism, as I say, I don't believe skepticism should be
natural.
In a normal human being, over 200, it's unlikely.
Under 200, I can see it probably because...
Oh, I see why they're skeptical because they're out to do you in, and therefore, they presume
that you're out to do them in.
I see.
It's a defense of negativity because their way...
See?
If we ask what...
I wonder if we have permission to do this.
We have permission to ask on a mulling and mulling.
Okay.
If we ask on a mulling and mulling, resist.
The percentage of politicians who are continuously, who routinely lie and deceive is over 80%,
85%.
85% of politicians routinely.
We didn't specify where.
In America, over 80%, 85%.
On the other side of the world, over 95%, 100%, 99%, 98%, 95%.
Okay.
That explains the evening news, doesn't it?
Your job is to be cleverly deceptive.
That's what the UN is all about.
That's why the UN calibrates at 190.
Nobody's there to help mankind.
They're out to help their friends.
All right.
So now we understand natural skepticism then would be like the skeptic is distrustful of
other people because they themselves are not trustable.
So if you're trustable, you tend to believe everybody and be sort of naive, I guess.
You believe everything that everybody says is true unless proven otherwise.
So this is the bottom-up position, which is typical of today's scientism.
The vanity of the ego is at 190.
And so much of our society that you see in the news, Hollywood and all that, it always
calibrates at 190.
It has to do with the vanity of narcissism.
The vanity of narcissism.
All right.
So atheism calibrates even lower.
Calibrates at 190.
Calibrates at 165.
Because it's making even more of a mistake.
It's saying that God doesn't exist.
Well, if you're honest, you could say you could be an agnostic.
An agnostic is being more intellectually integrous.
Intellectually, you can neither prove nor disprove the reality of divinity.
And that was the purpose of this morning's lecture.
There are different paradigms.
Consequently, in the world of logic, you cannot prove the existence of God, but neither
can you disprove it.
So with humility, so agnosticism is more humble than atheism.
Skepticism itself calibrates at 160.
Skepticism then represents the cynicism, in a way, of people who have feelings about the
world.
They have faith in their own thinkingness.
Because of their thinking, they say, and of course they ridicule faith, but the skeptic
has profound faith in their own skepticism.
There's a dictionary of skepticism, and the person is egoistic all over the place about
his own capacity to think.
But he thinks on a very pedestrian level.
And he only thinks in the linear domain, the non-linear.
So to the skeptic, the non-linear domain has no reality.
So anybody who believes in God is obviously a fool.
And of course, paradoxically, anybody who believes in faith is an idiot.
And they say that, they make that statement with great faith.
Faith is an idiot.
Yeah.
So.
The other reason skepticism is so low is because it's a variant of nihilism.
Nihilism is that nothing means anything, nothing is of any value.
And it negates the value of all of life.
Sort of aligned with Dawkins' view of the world is the so-called God gene, a famous
book by Dean Hamer.
It also calibrates about 190.
So this is sort of pseudo-science.
It disproves God.
And the hypothesis, this arose because of the testimony of so many people with near-death
experiences, or out-of-body experiences, or a combination of the two, that had to be answered.
So this was an attempt to answer, why is it that the near-death experience all over the,
throughout the ages, for thousands of years, has been almost identical?
Yeah.
And of course, the religionist sees it as merely, you know, confirmation over and over
again in different circumstances of an ultimate reality.
The near-death experience is profound, profound, permanent, profound and permanent.
So they wanted to know, what can they do about that?
So then they came up with a hypothesis that if you're near death, your brain automatically
activates a certain node.
Activates a certain neuronal circuit and creates this near-death experience.
That it's a genetic abnormality or weirdness of the neurologic circuits.
It's not too bright a theory.
First of all, they never found a God gene, so it calibrates at 190.
I think it should calibrate lower, but I'd give it about a 130.
Now you see the narcissism of scientism.
There's nothing more arrogant and dogmatic than scientism.
And debunkers are probably the top of the list.
They're smug vanity as they try to disprove something by setting up some poppycock experiment
that imitates the real.
And now that they've imitated the real, they've disproven the real, which is a non-sequitur.
The fact that you can imitate the real.
That you can imitate a miracle doesn't prove that a real miracle doesn't occur.
And the miracles that I experienced would be beyond duplication anyway.
There's no way you could duplicate the experiences I've had.
And every day there's the unfoldment of miracles.
Now we'll get to science and I've said a few people now pretty soon.
I hate everybody being so calm out there.
The big bang source of the universe calibrates at 135.
Any big bangers out there upset?
I didn't want to upset any big bangers.
But the big banger, like the god gene, the big bang source of the universe.
In other words, the universe arose out of an energy, but it doesn't tell you where the energy arose from.
So big bang is without any source of the big bang, and that's why it only calibrates at 135.
Earth warming of human origin is false.
Earth warming of human origin is fallacious.
It calibrates at, the recent report to the UN about a week ago, the report calibrates at 195.
So when I first calibrated that some years ago, I thought, well I know the earth is warming up.
But the presumption then, and it's become an ism, an environmental ism.
Earth warming of human origin, it's not of human origin.
The cyclic temperature of the planet is due to the magnetic activity of the surface of the sun.
It had nothing to do with humankind.
And core drillings in the Arctic, down to 10,000 years ago or 20,000 years ago,
show the concordance of periods, of cyclic periods of warmth.
So the, if we ask, let's ask, you don't have to get up on your hands.
If the cyclic warming is due to the earth, due to the sun's surface magnetic activity, resist.
Now, when we find there's any disparity between popular belief systems, including sense and consciousness research,
the consciousness research always turns out to be right.
We've never had it the other way around.
And so the first time we did it on earth warming, we got no.
Of course, you know what the cause of earth warming is.
I'll give you the secret.
It's called overpopulation.
No.
I'm sorry.
That's, there's the pollution.
Anyway, earth warming is not due to pollution.
It's due to cyclic magnetic activity of the surface of the sun.
And pollution is a different thing.
So it's the bigger mistake.
It's to mix the two.
Earth, in other words, human pollution is one thing.
Earth warming is another.
They are not causally related.
The cause of pollution on the earth is overpopulation.
Overpopulation.
A zillion people, and they're multiplying constantly, are sending up all kinds of stuff.
So that causes pollution.
But the pollution affects the earth's temperature.
0.8 degrees Fahrenheit.
Earth's temperature is affected.
Okay, so all the fuss is about a very minuscule variation in earth temperature.
The only way to cut down the pollution is to have fewer people.
That's easy, huh?
Stop you-know-what.
All right.
I thought there might be some skeptics here today.
I came prepared for skeptics.
Skeptics?
Any skeptics?
I thought somebody might poo-poo it because, you know, it's become such a big movement, you see.
It's become an ism.
It gets politicized in an ism.
I'll give you the references.
It's going to be on a videotape anyway.
Save people sending me emails.
Tape your email.
The suns serve as magnetic activity, as a source of temperature variation.
The reference is J. Lair, L-E-H-R, and F. Bennett, B-E-N-N-E-T-T, article,
It's the Sun, in Environment and Climate News, 6-4, May.
And there's another reference.
Mailman, uncertainties and projections of human-caused global warming, in the Journal of Science, 278, November.
November, 1997.
So, anyway, those are just scientific references because otherwise I get emails, indignant emails.
I thought I'd just anticipate that.
You see, because once a thing becomes an ism, it gets religionized.
And people are willing to parade and sacrifice and go to battle over it and sue everybody and start a war.
Earth's warming of human origin is not correct.
Parallel universe theory is also incorrect.
There was a recent study that got a lot of publicity in the Journal of Cardiology.
So-called negative prayer healing study.
That calibrated at 190.
Paradoxically, it was financed by the Templeton Foundation.
And the defect is in the setting up.
So many things, what happens is big money becomes available.
Secondhand smoke is another big one.
Secondhand smoke doesn't cause any diseases at all.
I'm not saying that smoking is good for your health, but secondhand smoke.
Because the only way you get a grant, it causes crib death, it causes psoriasis, it causes all these things.
And it finally reached such a point that a federal court reviewed all the documentation.
Secondhand smoke has absolutely no effect health-wise to a measurable degree.
So we build these isms that become a religion.
And no-smoking-ism and earth-pollution-ism and earth-warming-ism become very, like Marecke said, delusions and madness of crowds.
Negation of faith calibrates at 90.
Negate non-linear reality.
Which is context.
Puts you at 90.
So this is the difficulty of the skeptic.
The skeptic negates the reality, the non-linear realities, which is context.
Therefore, they're left with a pedestrian, sort of lower mind kind of, being literal.
In which you have only the linear, but the meaning, the meaning is, they don't understand the meaning because they don't have a context.
Because context is non-linear.
You can't measure it.
Here we have an interesting comparison.
Crick, you know, discoverer along with Watson of the DNA.
The research he did that discovered the secret of the DNA was calibrated about 440.
Didn't he get a Nobel Prize or something?
Or he should have?
Anyway, Crick was an atheist.
But anyway.
The source of consciousness is neuronal, was the last research he was doing.
So the prior research on DNA calibrated 440.
At the time of his death, he'd gotten grants for some university to prove that consciousness is a product of neuronal activity.
In other words, life arises.
Life arises from neuronal activity.
That calibrated at 140.
140.
And he was an atheist.
And of course, this was merely a pseudo-science, actually.
To prove, sort of like looking for the God gene.
So here's the same man at one level.
He's scientifically integrous at 440.
In another, he's trying to prove a proposition.
That consciousness is the product of neuronal activity.
So this is the bottom-up theory.
The bottom-up theory.
Evolutionary psychology misses that.
But it's also tempted to try and explain everything in Darwinian evolutionary terms.
Darwin's theory of evolution calibrated at 450.
Daniel Dennett moves into evolutionary psychology.
He was on the same issue of time.
He was on the same issue of Time magazine.
And Collins was also in the same.
He discovered the genome.
But they're over 200.
So they weren't out to try to disprove anything.
Creationism is a limitation.
It's at 245.
Which means it's an honest limitation.
But it's insufficient explanation.
This stands in contrast.
Genesis calibrated at 600.
Genesis.
And the beginning was the light.
And when we explain the evolution of the human ego,
we always say,
Out of the Godhead arose the Creator.
God as Creator.
The Godhead.
Means it's not defined yet in terms of creativity.
So out of the Godhead is the infinite potential of divinity
to be anything and everything.
Which it is.
Including being the Creator.
So being the Creator then is not just a limitation.
Because God is more than just the Creator.
He's the very source out of which a Creator arises.
The Godhead is, you might say, the source of Godness.
So Genesis calibrated at 600.
Despite many of the things in there that would not be scientifically acceptable.
The gist of it is that out of the Godhead arose divinity
as the source of all existence.
And the source of all of life.
That's...
Discovery of the presence of God.
What is that?
That's a book.
Well that's way up there.
That's because it's aligned with consciousness.
It's because it's aligned with the reality and the confirmable reality
and truth of consciousness itself.
Which is the source out of which spiritual awareness, etc. arises.
So it would naturally be aligned with the absolute truth.
The evolution of consciousness itself.
The consciousness is evolutionary.
As a theory calibrates at 600.
Francis Collins in that same issue of Time Magazine.
I think he was the head of the genome product, wasn't he?
Wrote a book called The Language of God at 400.
So he tried to bridge the gap between science
and religion.
Intelligent design calibrates at 480.
And the creationists, the literal creationists,
don't like intelligent design.
It seems to me intelligent design gives both sides an option.
If they really want peace, they could accept this
because it doesn't include the word God in it.
But the reason the fundamentalists don't like that
is because they were afraid with intelligent design
God could slip in the back door
That's what it says.
God could slip in the back door.
Okay, alright.
The hypothetical.
Now in Scope's trial, William Jennings Brandt
You remember against...
Anyway, William Jennings Brandt calibrated at 505.
Clarence Darrow was at 450.
Now Clarence Darrow was a scientific skeptic.
A very intelligent man.
And of course, William Jennings Brandt was a man of faith.
The whole thing was really set up...
The Scope's trial was set up as a publicity stunt
by the founder of ACLU,
himself calibrated about 190,
together with the town where it occurred.
And so the whole thing was not...
It was contrived.
So from the beginning,
it was somewhat contaminated
because it was contrived.
However, each one represented...
truthfully represented what they stood for.
William Jennings Brandt at 505
certainly stood for what 505 means.
Clarence Darrow at 450
was coming from science.
Was coming from science.
So when Darrow couldn't make the headway he wanted to,
he went to the ad hominem attack.
He fell to the ad hominem attack.
And of course, ridiculed things
that are really allegorical things in the Bible.
Allegorical.
All the allegorical things,
you can remove all of them.
And the meaning and the significance
and the calibration of the Bible
does not change at all.
Whether Jonah spent three days in the stomach of a whale
is irrelevant to the truth of Jesus Christ
as savior and avatar.
.
So anyway, it's very interesting.
But they represent two different paradigms.
So Darrow's paradigm,
that of science in the 400s,
we went over,
and you can see why he is stuck in that.
And you can see why William Jennings Brandt at 505
represents spiritual reality.
So I just never thought
that the issues got resolved
due to the disparity of paradigms.
St. Thomas Aquinas, of course,
at 570,
he wrote a great textbook
in which he tried to integrate
both faith and reason.
And said that
faith without reason
is deficient and vice versa.
He said that the two of them
reinforced each other.
That your faith becomes greater
when you add to it
intellectual comprehension
and vice versa.
So St. Thomas Aquinas
at 570.
And Aquinas is really a fallout from Aristotle.
But when I went to Jesuit University
at the time I was an atheist
and I used to hammer
hammer all of these arguments
for the existence of God.
First cause.
Give me a break.
That which is eternal
has no first cause.
Right?
I was right as an atheist, wasn't I?
Now all I said is that
the arguments for the existence of God
as I see it now
are within the intellect
and from the intellect
you can neither prove
or disprove God.
So then I went from being an atheist
to an agnostic.
You can neither prove
nor disprove
the existence of God
through the intellect.
Evolution is creation
calibrates at infinite
God is the source of creation
is infinite.
So the difficulty you see
with the linear domain is
people tend to think
in terms of cause and effect.
If you think in terms of cause and effect
then you see God as
as
you might say
the spinning the top
and then walked away from it
view.
We try to transcend
the mid 400's
sees everything
from the Newtonian paradigm
of cause and effect.
So the difficulty with the 400's
when it deals with God
is it begins to see God as a cause
rather than as an ever present source.
A cause goes from here
to there in a time scale.
It deals with force.
God as eternal source
means that
evolution is continuous
and ongoing
because that's the nature
of divinity itself.
They become ever more
that which it is
in all of its expressions.
So the difference between
cause and source
makes quite a bit of difference
in understanding Genesis
or the Bible
or in discussing
science versus religion.
God is the ever present
ongoing source.
So that which has no beginning
has no end.
So there is no cause
for the universe.
No cause for existence.
However,
there is an ever present source.
We all get the difference
between a cause and a source.
Everybody get that?
Source is
continuancy.
And a cause comes and goes.
Cause came and went.
God versus science
issue of Time magazine
in November
calibrated at 410
which is quite ambiguous.
It accomplished
what it meant to accomplish.
Carl Sagan,
pretty well known name,
calibrates at 200.
Now 200 is neither here nor there.
200 is sort of neutral.
The planet Earth
calibrates at 200.
The human body
Neither good nor bad.
That's sort of nice in a way, isn't it?
The planet and the Earth so.
From dust you arise
and to dust you return.
From 200 you arise
and then you're 200 for a while
and then you go back to 200 again.
In the linear physical domain.
Theology itself
as an intellectual discipline
calibrates at 460.
That's pretty erudite.
We saw the great books
of the Western world.
This is the range
of the great books
of the Western world.
So theology then
is using the mind
and intellectually
comprehending religion
and spiritual truth.
Evolutionary psychology
we said is at 210
and it has its popular authors
right now.
We said before
Crick's discovery of DNA
was at 460
but the one he was working on
Crick's source of consciousness
is only neuronal
is 140.
So the same person
could be the author of
something very erudite
at the same time.
At the same time
something quite fallacious.
The Heisenberg principle
plays very big
in our explanation
of spiritual reality.
It calibrates at 460.
We'll move to the next.
Heisenberg principle then
is the explanation
that the skeptics
and the materialists
and the reductionists
are missing.
They don't see that
the consciousness intention
of the scientist
is going to already limit
and characterize
the kind of results
he's going to come up with.
A tractor field
non-linear dynamics
which is
explains the levels
of consciousness.
The Big Bang source
of universe theory
we said was false.
Biofield is 460.
The black hole theory
you know
Stephen Hawking
black hole theory
was last revised
I think in 2004
calibrates at 456.
Bootstrap scientific theory
you know these are advances
of quantum mechanics
and chaos theory
all calibrated around 455.
The collective unconscious
the collective unconscious
was discovered by Carl Jung
and the question is
is that a legend?
Is that legendary?
Is that just a psychological concept?
Or is the collective unconscious
a reality?
We see from a scientific viewpoint
at 455
it is a reality.
This is somewhat good to know
in some ways
because there's no explaining
how certain people
develop illnesses
they never even heard of.
I'm just also finishing editing
a book on lectures
I once did on health and healing
and people tend to manifest
what they hold in mind
or what has been suggested to them.
But people will say
I don't remember ever believing
in that
and I never thought
it would apply to me
so how would I manifest it
by holding it in mind?
And where you got it
was the collective unconscious.
You got it from the collective
not from the individual.
A great many of the illnesses
are picked up as a child.
You just hear it on TV
your mother says it
and it becomes a reality
in your mind
and then later on
with unconscious guilt
you manifest it.
A negative belief system
plus unconscious guilt.
Plus karmic propensities
results in the illness.
So you have to try to understand
and undo all of them.
So the collective unconscious
is correct.
And of course
it was from young
we got the term
synergicity.
Synergicity.
Synesthesia.
Huh?
Synchronicity.
So just as I was saying
I was writing a chapter
on God versus science.
Time magazine came out
with an issue
with God versus science.
That was in November
I was writing that chapter.
So that's synchronicity.
Okay.
Let's see.
We did the black hole theory
the collective unconscious.
Consciousness is a consequence
of neuronal activity.
This is a bottoms up theory
and of course
it calibrates negative
just as Crick's research
on that did.
Consciousness calibration
as a technique
as a science
is at 605.
The science of consciousness
calibration is 605.
So that means
you've taken the non-linear
and made it comprehensible
by definition.
And of course
by using a scale
of one to a thousand
you've made it accessible
to the linear.
So you've taken
the non-linear
and by using a tool
consciousness calibration
you've made the non-linear
comprehensible to the linear.
You've somehow crossed over a bridge
at least in a pragmatic
kind of a way.
Consciousness calibration
can tell you the truth
of anything
anywhere in time
anywhere in space.
Why is that?
Because the ultimate reality
as advanced theoretical physics
quantum mechanics shows
because there is no dimension
in an infinite universe
there is no center
to an infinite universe.
Everywhere is therefore
equally the same
as everywhere else.
Because it's outside of time
any time is equally now.
The reason consciousness
calibration techniques
that Suze and I do all the time
works is because
everywhere is right here
and every time is right now.
Is that comprehensible?
That which is dimensionless
there is no center
is there?
Everywhere is
so advanced theoretical physics
if you meditate on it
you'll end up
that everywhere
every place is here
and everywhere is now.
So what happened
10,000 years ago
is accessible to us
right this instant.
And it happened
on the other side of the planet
and it's accessible to us
right here.
The details of ancient Egypt
are as knowable right now
as they were at the time
of the first world war.
They're occurrences.
What the various people thought
what they did, etc.
So it's a little hard for people
stuck in the linear domain
the skeptic especially
to understand how consciousness
calibration could transcend
time and distance and space
transcend the linear
and come out with an answer
which in their paradigm
would not be knowable.
Well, not knowable.
On the other hand
you see how quickly it's knowable.
How soon can you tell the truth
about anything?
In an instant.
The minute the UN report
came out on global warming
on the news
we instantly did it.
We had it right now and then.
Didn't cause anything.
We didn't have to go anywhere.
Didn't have to buy any equipment.
Didn't have to invest any money.
Instant now and free.
Wow.
That's how
like the guy that discovered penicillin
I have the same reason to be here.
He said,
wow, look what you can do with this.
I said,
look at this.
You can know anything about anything.
Right now it didn't cost a second
in an instant.
You got to share it with the world.
All right.
Distant healing.
There was a research on that
and that turned out to be negative.
Divinity as source of the universe
is infinitely true.
The Drake equation
this has to do with
the probability of life
being on other planets
in this galaxy.
The probability of the Drake equation
is about 350.
Here's some other things
that you're not going to lay awake about
but you might worry about.
The Earth's magnetic field is weakening.
Yeah, that's true.
They are.
Now you got something to worry about.
Earth's magnetic fields are weakening.
Oh boy.
In fact,
the Earth is slowly reversing
its magnetic poles.
What do you think of that one?
What are you going to do with your compass?
The Earth is moving gradually
towards the south.
And there's some interesting maps of it.
It wavers.
The magnetic pole is wavering.
So the poles
are slowly reversing.
Earth warming due to pollution
we've asked this in a number of different
language styles.
It still comes out.
Magnetic surface cycling,
yes, 455.
E equals mc squared.
Where have I heard that?
Calibrates at 455.
So you see the power
of scientific proof at 455
equals mc squared.
There's a gentleman
who was in the Arizona
Republic about a month ago.
He keeps writing books denouncing
Einstein's theory as hokum.
He does.
He's on his fourth book or something.
He's been at it for decades.
He writes all the
scientists around.
The emperor who wears
no clothes or something.
That's what he calls Einstein.
Einstein is a fake.
He writes all these books.
He had a big article in the newspaper.
He's up to his fourth book or something like that.
Calibrates at 190.
So I just thought
you'd like to know that
E equals mc squared
passes the muster.
The skeptic who doubts
Einstein.
How does he explain
Hiroshima and Nagasaki?
That's sort of a tough one.
If Einstein's theory wasn't correct
how'd he explain the atomic bomb?
It seemed to me
that would put it into
skepticism.
But skepticism, although it claims
reason, is really immune to reason.
E equals mc squared.
That was the
discovery of the last century.
Einstein named the man of the century.
I think he was.
The god gene we said was negative.
Greenhouse gas earth warming theory.
Again, it comes up no matter how we phrase it.
Heart math on the other hand
which has to do with frequencies
is correct.
The Heisenberg uncertainty
principle itself is at 460.
Homesis is a
scientific theory that a little of
something will immunize you against a lot of it.
It comes out at 180.
That this is a holographic
universe is 395.
It's not really a scientific
fact.
What it's saying is that this has to do with
not what it is
but how you're conceptualizing it.
The inflation
theory of the origin of the universe
the post big bang theory
is that the world
is expanding at the rate of
the speed of light
is 450.
Let's go to the next one.
We're going to be done with this
science by lunch, I'll tell you.
We only have five minutes left.
Five minutes left?
Page one, page two.