In the ancient Greece, Ezeka, you can
In the ancient Greece, Ezeka, you can see that I'm a enthusiast of ancient
see that I'm a enthusiast of ancient
see that I'm a enthusiast of ancient Greece.
There is three things logos, ethos and
There is three things logos, ethos and pyos.
pyos.
pyos. Logos is the integrity of the speaker.
Logos is the integrity of the speaker.
Logos is the integrity of the speaker. Ethos is the integrity of the message.
Ethos is the integrity of the message.
Ethos is the integrity of the message. And posthos is the receptivity of the
And posthos is the receptivity of the
And posthos is the receptivity of the audience. And if you don't pay attention
audience. And if you don't pay attention
audience. And if you don't pay attention to all three, your message doesn't get
to all three, your message doesn't get
to all three, your message doesn't get across.
across.
across. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. H logos, ethos, and pos.
H logos, ethos, and pos.
H logos, ethos, and pos. I know you were just dying to know that.
I know you were just dying to know that.
I know you were just dying to know that. So,
The receptivity of the audience. So,
The receptivity of the audience. So, we're blessed to have such a receptive
we're blessed to have such a receptive
we're blessed to have such a receptive uh audience, you see. Uh
uh audience, you see. Uh
uh audience, you see. Uh because if the audience is dumb, it
because if the audience is dumb, it
because if the audience is dumb, it doesn't do any good to be smart, you
doesn't do any good to be smart, you
doesn't do any good to be smart, you know.
Oh golly. All right. So uh we have uh
Oh golly. All right. So uh we have uh what?
what?
what? >> Oh, thank you. All right. Thank you,
>> Oh, thank you. All right. Thank you,
>> Oh, thank you. All right. Thank you, God. One brain brainy hour. Okay.
God. One brain brainy hour. Okay.
God. One brain brainy hour. Okay. Uh so we talked about of course the loss
Uh so we talked about of course the loss
Uh so we talked about of course the loss of consciousness is what we talk about
of consciousness is what we talk about
of consciousness is what we talk about all the time. adaptational stress to
all the time. adaptational stress to
all the time. adaptational stress to change. There's a constant adaptational
change. There's a constant adaptational
change. There's a constant adaptational stress. It's measurable uh
stress. It's measurable uh
stress. It's measurable uh physiologically and hormonally.
physiologically and hormonally.
physiologically and hormonally. Any change uh brings about a stress and
Any change uh brings about a stress and
Any change uh brings about a stress and the release of stress hormones and some
the release of stress hormones and some
the release of stress hormones and some people really go into exhaustion,
people really go into exhaustion,
people really go into exhaustion, adrenal exhaustion. So change is kind of
adrenal exhaustion. So change is kind of
adrenal exhaustion. So change is kind of stressful to the adrenal glands. the
stressful to the adrenal glands. the
stressful to the adrenal glands. the adrenal glands put out cortisone
adrenal glands put out cortisone
adrenal glands put out cortisone uh the the alarm reaction etc. So when
uh the the alarm reaction etc. So when
uh the the alarm reaction etc. So when you have to change uh your whole
you have to change uh your whole
you have to change uh your whole lifestyle or you change due to age or
lifestyle or you change due to age or
lifestyle or you change due to age or some change in your physiology or
some change in your physiology or
some change in your physiology or physical physicality
physical physicality
physical physicality there's a certain strain. So getting
there's a certain strain. So getting
there's a certain strain. So getting used to the world
used to the world
used to the world with one eye for instance,
with one eye for instance,
with one eye for instance, one dim eye is a stress.
Some from binocular you have to go to
Some from binocular you have to go to moninocular
moninocular
moninocular and uh your memory track fills in what
and uh your memory track fills in what
and uh your memory track fills in what the rest of the image is like. You know
the rest of the image is like. You know
the rest of the image is like. You know what wrong people look like because you
what wrong people look like because you
what wrong people look like because you saw a lot of wrong people.
saw a lot of wrong people.
saw a lot of wrong people. So there's an adaptational stress to
So there's an adaptational stress to
So there's an adaptational stress to change and some people really uh they
change and some people really uh they
change and some people really uh they really collapse in this level. You see
really collapse in this level. You see
really collapse in this level. You see this very frequently. People really uh
this very frequently. People really uh
this very frequently. People really uh collapse uh based on the stress of
collapse uh based on the stress of
collapse uh based on the stress of change. They go into adrenal exhaustion.
change. They go into adrenal exhaustion.
change. They go into adrenal exhaustion. Adrenal exhaustion
Adrenal exhaustion
Adrenal exhaustion adaptational stress to change.
uh we have to get used to the different
uh we have to get used to the different forms of government and of course our
forms of government and of course our
forms of government and of course our our government although its basic
our government although its basic
our government although its basic structure remains the same uh is really
structure remains the same uh is really
structure remains the same uh is really constantly changing its character. It's
constantly changing its character. It's
constantly changing its character. It's constantly changing its character and
constantly changing its character and
constantly changing its character and what was appropriate at one time uh is
what was appropriate at one time uh is
what was appropriate at one time uh is no longer acceptable.
no longer acceptable.
no longer acceptable. Uh my father used to get into
Uh my father used to get into
Uh my father used to get into a big upset every night at dinner about
a big upset every night at dinner about
a big upset every night at dinner about Roosevelt and the New Deal.
And then there were the unions. The
And then there were the unions. The unions were taking over. See, now I
unions were taking over. See, now I
unions were taking over. See, now I can't remember whether he was on the
can't remember whether he was on the
can't remember whether he was on the side of the unions,
side of the unions,
side of the unions, the side of Roosevelt or or not. He was
the side of Roosevelt or or not. He was
the side of Roosevelt or or not. He was very impassionate about it. And it was
very impassionate about it. And it was
very impassionate about it. And it was every night at dinner. My mother would
every night at dinner. My mother would
every night at dinner. My mother would Raymond Raymond are
Raymond Raymond are
Raymond Raymond are God damn it.
Every night this guy, it was hysterical.
Every night this guy, it was hysterical. He would be so upset by something. And
He would be so upset by something. And
He would be so upset by something. And night after night, this went on for
night after night, this went on for
night after night, this went on for years. And I can't remember whether he
years. And I can't remember whether he
years. And I can't remember whether he was pro Roosevelt or anti- Roosevelt.
was pro Roosevelt or anti- Roosevelt.
was pro Roosevelt or anti- Roosevelt. I can't remember which way it was. I
I can't remember which way it was. I
I can't remember which way it was. I think he was insensed that the unions
think he was insensed that the unions
think he was insensed that the unions were taking over. Well, it's because
were taking over. Well, it's because
were taking over. Well, it's because they were rioting. The unions were union
they were rioting. The unions were union
they were rioting. The unions were union riots. So, he was mad because they were,
riots. So, he was mad because they were,
riots. So, he was mad because they were, you know, that law because he was a very
you know, that law because he was a very
you know, that law because he was a very law and order kind of a person. very low
law and order kind of a person. very low
law and order kind of a person. very low and order.
and order.
and order. So, but adaptational
So, but adaptational
So, but adaptational stress to change because the different
stress to change because the different
stress to change because the different forms of government and certainly the
forms of government and certainly the
forms of government and certainly the Roosevelt era was a major change in
Roosevelt era was a major change in
Roosevelt era was a major change in government.
government.
government. Accountability is responsibility and
Accountability is responsibility and
Accountability is responsibility and this is really central
this is really central
this is really central to all spiritual evolution. You're
to all spiritual evolution. You're
to all spiritual evolution. You're either accountable for your answers or
either accountable for your answers or
either accountable for your answers or you're not. If you're not, if you
you're not. If you're not, if you
you're not. If you're not, if you consider yourself not accountable, you
consider yourself not accountable, you
consider yourself not accountable, you cannot do the the muscle test for truth.
cannot do the the muscle test for truth.
cannot do the the muscle test for truth. If you're not accountable,
If you're not accountable,
If you're not accountable, that negates the value of truth, does it
that negates the value of truth, does it
that negates the value of truth, does it not? So those who negate the the truth
not? So those who negate the the truth
not? So those who negate the the truth uh cannot do the test.
uh cannot do the test.
uh cannot do the test. People below 200 don't uh are unable to
People below 200 don't uh are unable to
People below 200 don't uh are unable to do it. And the higher the level of
do it. And the higher the level of
do it. And the higher the level of consciousness, which is research
consciousness, which is research
consciousness, which is research sent to me by Scott and this is Scott
sent to me by Scott and this is Scott
sent to me by Scott and this is Scott Jeffrey and associate that as the level
Jeffrey and associate that as the level
Jeffrey and associate that as the level of consciousness goes up the percentage
of consciousness goes up the percentage
of consciousness goes up the percentage of correctness and calibrating levels
of correctness and calibrating levels
of correctness and calibrating levels increases and the optimal level for for
increases and the optimal level for for
increases and the optimal level for for practicality
practicality
practicality uh would be about where this audience is
uh would be about where this audience is
uh would be about where this audience is mid 400s or so. Mid 400s is where people
mid 400s or so. Mid 400s is where people
mid 400s or so. Mid 400s is where people are intelligent uh integrous accountable
are intelligent uh integrous accountable
are intelligent uh integrous accountable uh take responsibility and are
uh take responsibility and are
uh take responsibility and are consciously evolving.
consciously evolving.
consciously evolving. Uh so accountability then is uh uh
Uh so accountability then is uh uh
Uh so accountability then is uh uh necessary to think you're not
necessary to think you're not
necessary to think you're not accountable.
accountable.
accountable. I don't know at the last moment on on on
I don't know at the last moment on on on
I don't know at the last moment on on on earth what people think about this.
earth what people think about this.
earth what people think about this. In the next second you could be wrong.
Oops.
Oops. So, you leave the body and you go,
So, you leave the body and you go,
So, you leave the body and you go, "Oops."
All the things with horns and tails
All the things with horns and tails hanging off of them.
hanging off of them.
hanging off of them. Oops.
We have to adapt to crime. I was just
We have to adapt to crime. I was just talking to George about it
talking to George about it
talking to George about it and George wasn't aware of the news that
and George wasn't aware of the news that
and George wasn't aware of the news that uh now now they're manufacturing
uh now now they're manufacturing
uh now now they're manufacturing bulletproof
bulletproof
bulletproof uh backpacks for kids kids to go to
uh backpacks for kids kids to go to
uh backpacks for kids kids to go to school.
school.
school. Big sale on them. They're selling them
Big sale on them. They're selling them
Big sale on them. They're selling them as fast as they can put them together.
as fast as they can put them together.
as fast as they can put them together. So you send your kid to school with a
So you send your kid to school with a
So you send your kid to school with a bulletproof backpack.
bulletproof backpack.
bulletproof backpack. Wow. That certainly is a change of
Wow. That certainly is a change of
Wow. That certainly is a change of society, isn't it? Huh? My mother used
society, isn't it? Huh? My mother used
society, isn't it? Huh? My mother used to tell me, "Don't take candy from
to tell me, "Don't take candy from
to tell me, "Don't take candy from strangers.
You're a nice little boy. Here's a candy
You're a nice little boy. Here's a candy for you. Don't take candy from
for you. Don't take candy from
for you. Don't take candy from strangers." So, anytime a stranger would
strangers." So, anytime a stranger would
strangers." So, anytime a stranger would offer me candy, I'd be scared out of my
offer me candy, I'd be scared out of my
offer me candy, I'd be scared out of my wits.
Somebody was up to no good. All right.
Somebody was up to no good. All right. So, now we have Kevlar backpacks for our
So, now we have Kevlar backpacks for our
So, now we have Kevlar backpacks for our children.
children.
children. The next step will be people will
The next step will be people will
The next step will be people will realize they're going to need Kevlar
realize they're going to need Kevlar
realize they're going to need Kevlar backpacks for them.
backpacks for them.
backpacks for them. The next time we hear from the enemies
The next time we hear from the enemies
The next time we hear from the enemies of the United States, we're going to
of the United States, we're going to
of the United States, we're going to realize we all better have kevlar
realize we all better have kevlar
realize we all better have kevlar clothes on.
clothes on.
clothes on. 911 was only a shot across the pole.
911 was only a shot across the pole.
911 was only a shot across the pole. Let's ask. We have permission.
Let's ask. We have permission.
Let's ask. We have permission. We have permission to ask this.
We have permission to ask this.
We have permission to ask this. 911 was only a shot across the bowl.
911 was only a shot across the bowl.
911 was only a shot across the bowl. Resist.
Resist.
Resist. 911 was a shot across the bowl.
911 was a shot across the bowl.
911 was a shot across the bowl. It was not the grand finale.
It was not the grand finale.
It was not the grand finale. So, we all may end up wearing like I
So, we all may end up wearing like I
So, we all may end up wearing like I have on a kevlar vest myself,
have on a kevlar vest myself,
have on a kevlar vest myself, but it comes from a good store. Wow.
but it comes from a good store. Wow.
but it comes from a good store. Wow. Dillards.
Dillards.
Dillards. Dillard kevlar vest.
So that's class class phases. Yeah. All
So that's class class phases. Yeah. All right. Accountability. So therefore the
right. Accountability. So therefore the
right. Accountability. So therefore the extent of crime it's its acceptability.
extent of crime it's its acceptability.
extent of crime it's its acceptability. We see this with the horrible
We see this with the horrible
We see this with the horrible story about the the dog uh what is it?
story about the the dog uh what is it?
story about the the dog uh what is it? Dog fighting. What do you call that? Dog
Dog fighting. What do you call that? Dog
Dog fighting. What do you call that? Dog fighting stuff that the pit well the pis
fighting stuff that the pit well the pis
fighting stuff that the pit well the pis Yeah. that the basketball players gotten
Yeah. that the basketball players gotten
Yeah. that the basketball players gotten into. That's just part of that culture.
into. That's just part of that culture.
into. That's just part of that culture. But you can see the terrible uh
But you can see the terrible uh
But you can see the terrible uh response. And then we have to put up
response. And then we have to put up
response. And then we have to put up with the various forms of pestilence and
with the various forms of pestilence and
with the various forms of pestilence and not not like we did when I was young. Uh
not not like we did when I was young. Uh
not not like we did when I was young. Uh all the all the great uh things that
all the all the great uh things that
all the all the great uh things that scared everybody have disappeared. uh
scared everybody have disappeared. uh
scared everybody have disappeared. uh polio epidemic, uh dtheria, typhoid, uh
polio epidemic, uh dtheria, typhoid, uh
polio epidemic, uh dtheria, typhoid, uh you know,
you know,
you know, where I lived, you would go walk around
where I lived, you would go walk around
where I lived, you would go walk around the neighborhood and you would see the
the neighborhood and you would see the
the neighborhood and you would see the health department would put a warning.
health department would put a warning.
health department would put a warning. Warning, diptheria, warning, measles,
Warning, diptheria, warning, measles,
Warning, diptheria, warning, measles, warning, chicken poo, chicken ducks,
pooping cough. I was going to say not
pooping cough. I was going to say not pooping cough. Whooping cough. Pooping
pooping cough. Whooping cough. Pooping
pooping cough. Whooping cough. Pooping cough. You cough so much you poop. No,
cough. You cough so much you poop. No,
cough. You cough so much you poop. No, whooping cough.
All the diseases that everybody was
All the diseases that everybody was scared to death of, polio myelitis being
scared to death of, polio myelitis being
scared to death of, polio myelitis being one of the worst, uh no longer even
one of the worst, uh no longer even
one of the worst, uh no longer even exist. So that entire shift, that entire
exist. So that entire shift, that entire
exist. So that entire shift, that entire shift then uh of pestilence. Pestilence
shift then uh of pestilence. Pestilence
shift then uh of pestilence. Pestilence uh of course wiped out the third of
uh of course wiped out the third of
uh of course wiped out the third of Europe, you know, etc.
Europe, you know, etc.
Europe, you know, etc. Then you have natural calamities. Well,
Then you have natural calamities. Well,
Then you have natural calamities. Well, the negative depictions of God is part
the negative depictions of God is part
the negative depictions of God is part of a chapter I'm writing right now. How
of a chapter I'm writing right now. How
of a chapter I'm writing right now. How did some religions get such negative
did some religions get such negative
did some religions get such negative depictions of God? Negative. I mean, God
depictions of God? Negative. I mean, God
depictions of God? Negative. I mean, God the punisher, God the killer, uh, you're
the punisher, God the killer, uh, you're
the punisher, God the killer, uh, you're supposed to kill infidels for God. I
supposed to kill infidels for God. I
supposed to kill infidels for God. I mean, what kind of a God is that? I
mean, what kind of a God is that? I
mean, what kind of a God is that? I mean, you don't need a devil.
mean, you don't need a devil.
mean, you don't need a devil. God gets off on your killing innocent
God gets off on your killing innocent
God gets off on your killing innocent children.
children.
children. That puts the devil out of business.
That puts the devil out of business.
That puts the devil out of business. unemployment.
How did all the demonic depictions of
How did all the demonic depictions of God arise?
God arise?
God arise? That God uh is overjoyed that you kill
That God uh is overjoyed that you kill
That God uh is overjoyed that you kill innocent children, blow up a busload of
innocent children, blow up a busload of
innocent children, blow up a busload of them. Uh how could such a evil god
them. Uh how could such a evil god
them. Uh how could such a evil god become
become
become uh sovereign? And you look at the Mayan
uh sovereign? And you look at the Mayan
uh sovereign? And you look at the Mayan civilization that tear the heart out of
civilization that tear the heart out of
civilization that tear the heart out of maidens and hold them up while the be
maidens and hold them up while the be
maidens and hold them up while the be heart is still beating and the blood's
heart is still beating and the blood's
heart is still beating and the blood's squirting down the steps. All the
squirting down the steps. All the
squirting down the steps. All the demonic religions. So we realize there's
demonic religions. So we realize there's
demonic religions. So we realize there's two major classifications of falsehood.
two major classifications of falsehood.
two major classifications of falsehood. The satanic which is basically evil,
The satanic which is basically evil,
The satanic which is basically evil, violence, etc. And the luciferic which
violence, etc. And the luciferic which
violence, etc. And the luciferic which is a substitution of falsehood for
is a substitution of falsehood for
is a substitution of falsehood for truth.
truth.
truth. those which are most evil demonstrate
those which are most evil demonstrate
those which are most evil demonstrate both. They reverse truth to begin with
both. They reverse truth to begin with
both. They reverse truth to begin with and then have a satanic depiction of
and then have a satanic depiction of
and then have a satanic depiction of God. So how how could it be so
God. So how how could it be so
God. So how how could it be so prevalent? You know the Native American
prevalent? You know the Native American
prevalent? You know the Native American Indians I don't believe held such a
Indians I don't believe held such a
Indians I don't believe held such a view. They saw they saw God as the
view. They saw they saw God as the
view. They saw they saw God as the divinity of nature and they saw the
divinity of nature and they saw the
divinity of nature and they saw the divinity of uh and the spirits of the
divinity of uh and the spirits of the
divinity of uh and the spirits of the animal world. So some people escaped it.
animal world. So some people escaped it.
animal world. So some people escaped it. But the prevalence of God the great
But the prevalence of God the great
But the prevalence of God the great punisher. So God in the Old Testament
punisher. So God in the Old Testament
punisher. So God in the Old Testament etc is depicted in anthropomorphic terms
etc is depicted in anthropomorphic terms
etc is depicted in anthropomorphic terms jealous, vengeful and angry. This makes
jealous, vengeful and angry. This makes
jealous, vengeful and angry. This makes a lot of people turn away from religion.
a lot of people turn away from religion.
a lot of people turn away from religion. They don't want to face a god that's
They don't want to face a god that's
They don't want to face a god that's uh we're as bad as a ordinary human
uh we're as bad as a ordinary human
uh we're as bad as a ordinary human being. We all have jealousy, anger and
being. We all have jealousy, anger and
being. We all have jealousy, anger and vengeful. So you know how do you get to
vengeful. So you know how do you get to
vengeful. So you know how do you get to be God with the same character traits?
be God with the same character traits?
be God with the same character traits? So then it it dawned on me. I I thought
So then it it dawned on me. I I thought
So then it it dawned on me. I I thought why is such a negative depiction of God
why is such a negative depiction of God
why is such a negative depiction of God occurring recurring over the millennia
occurring recurring over the millennia
occurring recurring over the millennia in different parts of the world and it's
in different parts of the world and it's
in different parts of the world and it's because of natural disasters natural
because of natural disasters natural
because of natural disasters natural disasters
disasters
disasters earthquake and flood and fire. Uh and
earthquake and flood and fire. Uh and
earthquake and flood and fire. Uh and that's how the gods must be angry.
that's how the gods must be angry.
that's how the gods must be angry. All right. So let's see if we've tracked
All right. So let's see if we've tracked
All right. So let's see if we've tracked it back correctly. I have permission to
it back correctly. I have permission to
it back correctly. I have permission to ask this. I hope I've tracked it back.
ask this. I hope I've tracked it back.
ask this. I hope I've tracked it back. It's been tracked back correctly.
It's been tracked back correctly.
It's been tracked back correctly. That's where it came from. Zippity duda.
That's where it came from. Zippity duda.
That's where it came from. Zippity duda. Nobody ever said that before. I mean,
Nobody ever said that before. I mean,
Nobody ever said that before. I mean, it's so obvious.
it's so obvious.
it's so obvious. Here's a big collapse of big mine
Here's a big collapse of big mine
Here's a big collapse of big mine collapses and earthquakes. There's an
collapses and earthquakes. There's an
collapses and earthquakes. There's an earthquake in Peru.
earthquake in Peru.
earthquake in Peru. Earthquake in Peru killing zillions of
Earthquake in Peru killing zillions of
Earthquake in Peru killing zillions of people. Then you have this tsunamis
people. Then you have this tsunamis
people. Then you have this tsunamis coming ashore. Then you have the great
coming ashore. Then you have the great
coming ashore. Then you have the great plagues.
plagues.
plagues. The gods must be angry. That's all it
The gods must be angry. That's all it
The gods must be angry. That's all it is, isn't it? And if we rip out the
is, isn't it? And if we rip out the
is, isn't it? And if we rip out the heart of human sacrifice, rip out the
heart of human sacrifice, rip out the
heart of human sacrifice, rip out the heart of a the most precious that we
heart of a the most precious that we
heart of a the most precious that we have, this beautiful young virgin. Yeah.
have, this beautiful young virgin. Yeah.
have, this beautiful young virgin. Yeah. Rip out our beating heart, give it to
Rip out our beating heart, give it to
Rip out our beating heart, give it to God, maybe maybe then God will be. So
God, maybe maybe then God will be. So
God, maybe maybe then God will be. So the angry god then is a animistic uh
the angry god then is a animistic uh
the angry god then is a animistic uh conceptualization
conceptualization
conceptualization of natural human disaster.
of natural human disaster.
of natural human disaster. And natural human disaster, you know,
And natural human disaster, you know,
And natural human disaster, you know, the whole principle of karma. Say, how
the whole principle of karma. Say, how
the whole principle of karma. Say, how can that be? How can that be? And
can that be? How can that be? And
can that be? How can that be? And there's no explaining it logically. Why
there's no explaining it logically. Why
there's no explaining it logically. Why you happened to be there at the time of
you happened to be there at the time of
you happened to be there at the time of the tsunami or the earthquake or the
the tsunami or the earthquake or the
the tsunami or the earthquake or the flood, why you were in San Francisco
flood, why you were in San Francisco
flood, why you were in San Francisco during the great earthquake.
So the angry god would be obviously the
So the angry god would be obviously the conclusion. And now you're going to try
conclusion. And now you're going to try
conclusion. And now you're going to try and assuage this god. You're going to
and assuage this god. You're going to
and assuage this god. You're going to assuage this god. You can please him by
assuage this god. You can please him by
assuage this god. You can please him by killing all infidels.
killing all infidels.
killing all infidels. And uh I'm just writing about that
And uh I'm just writing about that
And uh I'm just writing about that problem in a chapter of the book right
problem in a chapter of the book right
problem in a chapter of the book right now. Uh
now. Uh
now. Uh how can you assuage an angry god? Yeah.
how can you assuage an angry god? Yeah.
how can you assuage an angry god? Yeah. Uh
Uh
Uh so therefore you see the negative arises
so therefore you see the negative arises
so therefore you see the negative arises from man's experience
from man's experience
from man's experience and a primitive interpretation. a
and a primitive interpretation. a
and a primitive interpretation. a primitive interpretation
primitive interpretation
primitive interpretation uh based on natural disasters. Uhhuh. So
uh based on natural disasters. Uhhuh. So
uh based on natural disasters. Uhhuh. So we have to please this angry god, the
we have to please this angry god, the
we have to please this angry god, the angry god so that he doesn't strike you
angry god so that he doesn't strike you
angry god so that he doesn't strike you dead.
dead.
dead. This guy's on the street corner. He's
This guy's on the street corner. He's
This guy's on the street corner. He's his wife has run away. He's gone
his wife has run away. He's gone
his wife has run away. He's gone bankrupt. He's got a bad case of the
bankrupt. He's got a bad case of the
bankrupt. He's got a bad case of the hives.
hives.
hives. He's broke bankrupt. And he says, "Why
He's broke bankrupt. And he says, "Why
He's broke bankrupt. And he says, "Why God? Why me?" I don't know, George.
God? Why me?" I don't know, George.
God? Why me?" I don't know, George. There's something about you just pisses
There's something about you just pisses
There's something about you just pisses me off.
So we share the fate of of mankind. And
So we share the fate of of mankind. And that's one thing in a way that instead
that's one thing in a way that instead
that's one thing in a way that instead of being divisive uh can be a
of being divisive uh can be a
of being divisive uh can be a bondingness a bondingness that that that
bondingness a bondingness that that that
bondingness a bondingness that that that like ourselves so the people that we
like ourselves so the people that we
like ourselves so the people that we view as enemies etc are subject to the
view as enemies etc are subject to the
view as enemies etc are subject to the same vicissitudes
same vicissitudes
same vicissitudes the same vicissitudes so that's where
the same vicissitudes so that's where
the same vicissitudes so that's where the angry vengeful God the god of fear
the angry vengeful God the god of fear
the angry vengeful God the god of fear you know fear god fear god I can
you know fear god fear god I can
you know fear god fear god I can remember a preacher saying that fear god
remember a preacher saying that fear god
remember a preacher saying that fear god that made me shake all over because I I
that made me shake all over because I I
that made me shake all over because I I compulsively scrupulous to begin with.
compulsively scrupulous to begin with.
compulsively scrupulous to begin with. All I need is some guy telling me to
All I need is some guy telling me to
All I need is some guy telling me to fear God on top of it. Holy Christ,
fear God on top of it. Holy Christ,
fear God on top of it. Holy Christ, I was afraid to even think, you know,
I was afraid to even think, you know,
I was afraid to even think, you know, you had to watch what you looked at or
you had to watch what you looked at or
you had to watch what you looked at or what you might think that you might have
what you might think that you might have
what you might think that you might have a negative thought. You know, your
a negative thought. You know, your
a negative thought. You know, your mother call you come in for dinner now
mother call you come in for dinner now
mother call you come in for dinner now and you might be angry at your mother
and you might be angry at your mother
and you might be angry at your mother for calling you in for dinner right in
for calling you in for dinner right in
for calling you in for dinner right in the middle of the stick ball game and
the middle of the stick ball game and
the middle of the stick ball game and you're scared you're going to get an
you're scared you're going to get an
you're scared you're going to get an angry thought.
angry thought.
angry thought. It's best not to think at all. just not
It's best not to think at all. just not
It's best not to think at all. just not to even exist. The only way you can
to even exist. The only way you can
to even exist. The only way you can avoid sin
avoid sin
avoid sin is to not be.
is to not be.
is to not be. All right. Adaptational stress to change
All right. Adaptational stress to change
All right. Adaptational stress to change that is is constant. It's a big stress
that is is constant. It's a big stress
that is is constant. It's a big stress on the adrenal glands. Accountability
on the adrenal glands. Accountability
on the adrenal glands. Accountability and responsibility are critical. These
and responsibility are critical. These
and responsibility are critical. These people who leads lives of crime have no
people who leads lives of crime have no
people who leads lives of crime have no accountability. Huh?
accountability. Huh?
accountability. Huh? And on top of all of the complexity of
And on top of all of the complexity of
And on top of all of the complexity of the House of Mirrors we've talked about
the House of Mirrors we've talked about
the House of Mirrors we've talked about so far, you have the media barrage. And
so far, you have the media barrage. And
so far, you have the media barrage. And the media barrage is quite serious. The
the media barrage is quite serious. The
the media barrage is quite serious. The media barrage is incessant.
media barrage is incessant.
media barrage is incessant. It comes along with images and you're
It comes along with images and you're
It comes along with images and you're being programmed all the time. You're
being programmed all the time. You're
being programmed all the time. You're being programmed all the time.
being programmed all the time.
being programmed all the time. the media barrage. Then you can't tell
the media barrage. Then you can't tell
the media barrage. Then you can't tell truth from falsehood. You can't tell
truth from falsehood. You can't tell
truth from falsehood. You can't tell integrity from non- integrity. You can't
integrity from non- integrity. You can't
integrity from non- integrity. You can't tell what's morality. Uh and there is no
tell what's morality. Uh and there is no
tell what's morality. Uh and there is no real accountability. Uh
real accountability. Uh
real accountability. Uh the media barrage is sufficiently
the media barrage is sufficiently
the media barrage is sufficiently severe, especially bloggerism.
severe, especially bloggerism.
severe, especially bloggerism. Bloggerism is a new disease of mankind
Bloggerism is a new disease of mankind
Bloggerism is a new disease of mankind in which it it inflates your
in which it it inflates your
in which it it inflates your narcissistic ego with the me of me being
narcissistic ego with the me of me being
narcissistic ego with the me of me being out there in the YouTube and the me too
out there in the YouTube and the me too
out there in the YouTube and the me too and being out there.
and being out there.
and being out there. Who cares what you think?
Who cares what you think?
Who cares what you think? I don't give a rip what anybody thinks.
I don't give a rip what anybody thinks.
I don't give a rip what anybody thinks. Do you?
Do you?
Do you? Somebody get bloger gets on there. They
Somebody get bloger gets on there. They
Somebody get bloger gets on there. They got nothing else to do. I don't know.
got nothing else to do. I don't know.
got nothing else to do. I don't know. They don't sleep. I guess the blog
They don't sleep. I guess the blog
They don't sleep. I guess the blog blogger bloggerism all night. Anyway,
blogger bloggerism all night. Anyway,
blogger bloggerism all night. Anyway, it adds to the confusion especially
it adds to the confusion especially
it adds to the confusion especially discernment of truth from falsehood.
discernment of truth from falsehood.
discernment of truth from falsehood. The discernment eventually what happens
The discernment eventually what happens
The discernment eventually what happens eventually what happens
eventually what happens
eventually what happens is the capacity to discern reality
is the capacity to discern reality
is the capacity to discern reality becomes injured.
becomes injured.
becomes injured. The reason I'm annoyed
The reason I'm annoyed
The reason I'm annoyed annoyed with academia
annoyed with academia
annoyed with academia is not that they're teaching falsehood,
is not that they're teaching falsehood,
is not that they're teaching falsehood, but that they're damaging the capacity
but that they're damaging the capacity
but that they're damaging the capacity to discern truth from falsehood. That's
to discern truth from falsehood. That's
to discern truth from falsehood. That's what I don't like about it.
what I don't like about it.
what I don't like about it. And they're going to get it, too.
However, the effect of it, you don't
However, the effect of it, you don't forget, I practiced psychiatry 50 years.
forget, I practiced psychiatry 50 years.
forget, I practiced psychiatry 50 years. I listen to the nuances and subtleties
I listen to the nuances and subtleties
I listen to the nuances and subtleties and the what is unsaid behind what is
and the what is unsaid behind what is
and the what is unsaid behind what is said and the capacity to discern reality
said and the capacity to discern reality
said and the capacity to discern reality has been seriously injured
has been seriously injured
has been seriously injured and let's see in what percentage of the
and let's see in what percentage of the
and let's see in what percentage of the present population
present population
present population in today's population as a consequence
in today's population as a consequence
in today's population as a consequence of the media barrage
of the media barrage
of the media barrage the capacity to discern reality has been
the capacity to discern reality has been
the capacity to discern reality has been injured in over 40% of Americans
injured in over 40% of Americans
injured in over 40% of Americans 45%.
45%.
45%. 46%.
46%.
46%. Was 40. It's now at 45.
So for 45% of the people, people who do
So for 45% of the people, people who do nothing but witness this barrage,
nothing but witness this barrage,
nothing but witness this barrage, television, newspaper, magazine, endless
television, newspaper, magazine, endless
television, newspaper, magazine, endless programming, endless falsehood.
programming, endless falsehood.
programming, endless falsehood. Don't forget to bear false witness
Don't forget to bear false witness
Don't forget to bear false witness against your neighbor
against your neighbor
against your neighbor is uh breaking one of the great
is uh breaking one of the great
is uh breaking one of the great commandments
commandments
commandments and in today's world it's routine. It's
and in today's world it's routine. It's
and in today's world it's routine. It's routine in politics to lie through your
routine in politics to lie through your
routine in politics to lie through your teeth disparage little snide innuendos.
teeth disparage little snide innuendos.
teeth disparage little snide innuendos. So 40% of the people in the United
So 40% of the people in the United
So 40% of the people in the United States may have had it at one time now
States may have had it at one time now
States may have had it at one time now can't recognize truth even when you
can't recognize truth even when you
can't recognize truth even when you spell it out for them.
spell it out for them.
spell it out for them. Even when you spell it out for them,
Even when you spell it out for them,
Even when you spell it out for them, when you show them a picture like the
when you show them a picture like the
when you show them a picture like the first first picture today, could there
first first picture today, could there
first first picture today, could there be anybody so defective in the upper
be anybody so defective in the upper
be anybody so defective in the upper story that they don't get that picture?
story that they don't get that picture?
story that they don't get that picture? The reason I like that picture is
The reason I like that picture is
The reason I like that picture is because it stunningly sits in your
because it stunningly sits in your
because it stunningly sits in your memory and you don't have any discussion
memory and you don't have any discussion
memory and you don't have any discussion about it. It's just obvious what it is.
about it. It's just obvious what it is.
about it. It's just obvious what it is. Little Red Riding Hood.
Little Red Riding Hood. So, here we have
Little Red Riding Hood. So, here we have all these Little Red Riding Hoods in our
all these Little Red Riding Hoods in our
all these Little Red Riding Hoods in our world. 40% of them in the United States
world. 40% of them in the United States
world. 40% of them in the United States can't understand truth even when you
can't understand truth even when you
can't understand truth even when you spell it out for them. Spell it out for
spell it out for them. Spell it out for
spell it out for them. Spell it out for them. Spell it out for them.
them. Spell it out for them.
them. Spell it out for them. I've had it happen at a lecture. spent
I've had it happen at a lecture. spent
I've had it happen at a lecture. spent the whole lecture clarifying the nursing
the whole lecture clarifying the nursing
the whole lecture clarifying the nursing perception. In essence, at the end, you
perception. In essence, at the end, you
perception. In essence, at the end, you got a sentence that you realize they
got a sentence that you realize they
got a sentence that you realize they didn't get even the slightest what you
didn't get even the slightest what you
didn't get even the slightest what you were talking about.
were talking about.
were talking about. H So that makes me look is it the ethos,
H So that makes me look is it the ethos,
H So that makes me look is it the ethos, the p pos
the p pos
the p pos is it the speaker, the ethos
is it the speaker, the ethos
is it the speaker, the ethos uh the message or the that which is
uh the message or the that which is
uh the message or the that which is receiving. All right. So the media
receiving. All right. So the media
receiving. All right. So the media barrage then is uh on the one hand it
barrage then is uh on the one hand it
barrage then is uh on the one hand it brings us information never before
brings us information never before
brings us information never before available.
available.
available. On the other hand be aware that the
On the other hand be aware that the
On the other hand be aware that the media is always programming you. It's
media is always programming you. It's
media is always programming you. It's always programming you always.
always programming you always.
always programming you always. Why? Because first of all they selected
Why? Because first of all they selected
Why? Because first of all they selected it to be on the television. That made it
it to be on the television. That made it
it to be on the television. That made it important right away didn't it? Then how
important right away didn't it? Then how
important right away didn't it? Then how much time they give the story. Then the
much time they give the story. Then the
much time they give the story. Then the music behind it. See the drama, the
music behind it. See the drama, the
music behind it. See the drama, the presentation,
everything is sold with
everything is sold with Oh, look.
No matter what you buy,
No matter what you buy, whether it's for your eyes, your feet,
whether it's for your eyes, your feet,
whether it's for your eyes, your feet, new shoes, look at my new shoes do to
new shoes, look at my new shoes do to
new shoes, look at my new shoes do to me.
me.
me. Everything is about sex, right? I have
Everything is about sex, right? I have
Everything is about sex, right? I have guys say to me, "I'm so sick of being
guys say to me, "I'm so sick of being
guys say to me, "I'm so sick of being seduced and barrageed by sexual images
seduced and barrageed by sexual images
seduced and barrageed by sexual images all day. I hate to watch the television.
a barrage of it, you know, and then at
a barrage of it, you know, and then at the same time there's all the abs for
the same time there's all the abs for
the same time there's all the abs for men to improve their performance. I
men to improve their performance. I
men to improve their performance. I mean, everybody is sex obsessed. I mean,
mean, everybody is sex obsessed. I mean,
mean, everybody is sex obsessed. I mean, what goes on, you know? I don't know.
what goes on, you know? I don't know.
what goes on, you know? I don't know. All right. So, just the fact that a
All right. So, just the fact that a
All right. So, just the fact that a thing is selected to be put on then the
thing is selected to be put on then the
thing is selected to be put on then the image you've already been programmed.
image you've already been programmed.
image you've already been programmed. You've already had it. That's an
You've already had it. That's an
You've already had it. That's an important story. Why? because they put
important story. Why? because they put
important story. Why? because they put it up in the first place. And then if
it up in the first place. And then if
it up in the first place. And then if they repeat it over and over again, you
they repeat it over and over again, you
they repeat it over and over again, you think, man, that's a super super
think, man, that's a super super
think, man, that's a super super important thing. Huh? In the meantime,
important thing. Huh? In the meantime,
important thing. Huh? In the meantime, nobody's even have knows what happened
nobody's even have knows what happened
nobody's even have knows what happened to the Dow Jones average.
to the Dow Jones average.
to the Dow Jones average. I say most people have their money in
I say most people have their money in
I say most people have their money in savings, but the news report doesn't
savings, but the news report doesn't
savings, but the news report doesn't even get around to it. What happened to
even get around to it. What happened to
even get around to it. What happened to the Dow today? If you're lucky, they'll
the Dow today? If you're lucky, they'll
the Dow today? If you're lucky, they'll say it drops 60 point and they quickly
say it drops 60 point and they quickly
say it drops 60 point and they quickly flash it off.
flash it off.
flash it off. your life savings is what was it?
And then she's busy telling you about
And then she's busy telling you about what what's important.
Yeah. There there's one that the the
Yeah. There there's one that the the they interview all the time. It's a lady
they interview all the time. It's a lady
they interview all the time. It's a lady psychologist who's supposed to be I
psychologist who's supposed to be I
psychologist who's supposed to be I think a sex therapist. And when she
think a sex therapist. And when she
think a sex therapist. And when she comes on, she's got the most the biggest
comes on, she's got the most the biggest
comes on, she's got the most the biggest cleavage of anybody. Here's a sex
cleavage of anybody. Here's a sex
cleavage of anybody. Here's a sex therapist, Dr. So and so
trying to put them all to shame. Oh god.
trying to put them all to shame. Oh god. I say to guys, if you really like those
I say to guys, if you really like those
I say to guys, if you really like those things, cover your wall with them, the
things, cover your wall with them, the
things, cover your wall with them, the bedroom with them, the kitchen with them
bedroom with them, the kitchen with them
bedroom with them, the kitchen with them until you finally get off of it. Until
until you finally get off of it. Until
until you finally get off of it. Until you finally I've seen enough for a
you finally I've seen enough for a
you finally I've seen enough for a while.
Oh golly. So TV is a endless burles
Oh golly. So TV is a endless burles show, you know. So it's very comical,
show, you know. So it's very comical,
show, you know. So it's very comical, but you realize then uh that you're
but you realize then uh that you're
but you realize then uh that you're being uh programmed all the time.
being uh programmed all the time.
being uh programmed all the time. Everything that you hear now is a
Everything that you hear now is a
Everything that you hear now is a program of one kind or another.
program of one kind or another.
program of one kind or another. Programming you one way or the other.
Programming you one way or the other.
Programming you one way or the other. Uhhuh.
Uhhuh.
Uhhuh. Uh a media barrage. And uh if I wasn't
Uh a media barrage. And uh if I wasn't
Uh a media barrage. And uh if I wasn't doing what I'm doing, I'd like to be a
doing what I'm doing, I'd like to be a
doing what I'm doing, I'd like to be a consultant to advertising companies
consultant to advertising companies
consultant to advertising companies because I can see how to improve ads
because I can see how to improve ads
because I can see how to improve ads right and left. They were blowing all
right and left. They were blowing all
right and left. They were blowing all kinds of money and I get shown how to
kinds of money and I get shown how to
kinds of money and I get shown how to quadruple the impact of their media.
quadruple the impact of their media.
quadruple the impact of their media. So if there is a media barrage then you
So if there is a media barrage then you
So if there is a media barrage then you really have to know how to manipulate
really have to know how to manipulate
really have to know how to manipulate the media and the media is manipulated
the media and the media is manipulated
the media and the media is manipulated by 20somes
by 20somes
by 20somes sort of uh what do you call these uh
sort of uh what do you call these uh
sort of uh what do you call these uh techies?
They call them tickies. Anyway, the
They call them tickies. Anyway, the media barriers by young people. All
media barriers by young people. All
media barriers by young people. All right. Perception versus essence. We
right. Perception versus essence. We
right. Perception versus essence. We said that is now being so injured that
said that is now being so injured that
said that is now being so injured that the capacity to even discern illusion
the capacity to even discern illusion
the capacity to even discern illusion from reality is being lost even when you
from reality is being lost even when you
from reality is being lost even when you spell it out to them. Even when you
spell it out to them. Even when you
spell it out to them. Even when you spell it out to them.
spell it out to them.
spell it out to them. Now we know that all the above
Now we know that all the above
Now we know that all the above is being processed through the human
is being processed through the human
is being processed through the human mind.
mind.
mind. Freud laid out an understanding of the
Freud laid out an understanding of the
Freud laid out an understanding of the unconscious.
unconscious.
unconscious. uh Young did it some from a different
uh Young did it some from a different
uh Young did it some from a different viewpoint but uh Freud was really
viewpoint but uh Freud was really
viewpoint but uh Freud was really correct. There is at the basis of the
correct. There is at the basis of the
correct. There is at the basis of the human psyche uh the id that's the
human psyche uh the id that's the
human psyche uh the id that's the repressed animal instincts the desire to
repressed animal instincts the desire to
repressed animal instincts the desire to kill
kill
kill to maim to injure to rape. Uh it's this
to maim to injure to rape. Uh it's this
to maim to injure to rape. Uh it's this guy
guy
guy uh
uh
uh that calibrated five.
that calibrated five.
that calibrated five. He's a walking id.
The desire and the pleasure of killing,
The desire and the pleasure of killing, which I've spoken about before. I've
which I've spoken about before. I've
which I've spoken about before. I've watched dogs do that. Just kill kill
kill kill kill kill kill kill kill kill kill kill kill kill for the sheer joy of
kill kill kill kill for the sheer joy of
kill kill kill kill for the sheer joy of killing.
killing.
killing. Uh therefore certain politicalization
Uh therefore certain politicalization
Uh therefore certain politicalization brainwashing knows how to access this id
brainwashing knows how to access this id
brainwashing knows how to access this id and release it under permission from
and release it under permission from
and release it under permission from God. Under permission from God you can
God. Under permission from God you can
God. Under permission from God you can become rapidly vicious. Because now you
become rapidly vicious. Because now you
become rapidly vicious. Because now you have permission for this it. Why?
have permission for this it. Why?
have permission for this it. Why? Because what balances the id is the
Because what balances the id is the
Because what balances the id is the superego the conscience.
superego the conscience.
superego the conscience. So if you silence the conscience and
So if you silence the conscience and
So if you silence the conscience and responsibility etc you can release the
responsibility etc you can release the
responsibility etc you can release the id and this is the whole basis of
id and this is the whole basis of
id and this is the whole basis of frantic terrorism the goss the visy goss
frantic terrorism the goss the visy goss
frantic terrorism the goss the visy goss the vikings everybody and then when they
the vikings everybody and then when they
the vikings everybody and then when they conquered people they killed them all
conquered people they killed them all
conquered people they killed them all and piled all the skulls up
and piled all the skulls up
and piled all the skulls up piled up the skulls
piled up the skulls
piled up the skulls they just killed you when you when you
they just killed you when you when you
they just killed you when you when you beat somebody you you killed them so the
beat somebody you you killed them so the
beat somebody you you killed them so the then is the repressed reservoir
then is the repressed reservoir
then is the repressed reservoir of the downside of one's animal nature.
of the downside of one's animal nature.
of the downside of one's animal nature. And people don't want to look at the id.
And people don't want to look at the id.
And people don't want to look at the id. And one of the first things you have to
And one of the first things you have to
And one of the first things you have to do uh in psychoanalysis is align uh the
do uh in psychoanalysis is align uh the
do uh in psychoanalysis is align uh the patient's super ego with your sense of
patient's super ego with your sense of
patient's super ego with your sense of reality
reality
reality so that they can face the fact that you
so that they can face the fact that you
so that they can face the fact that you know how do you feel if somebody gets a
know how do you feel if somebody gets a
know how do you feel if somebody gets a promotion above you and then you know
promotion above you and then you know
promotion above you and then you know the patient's talking about this that
the patient's talking about this that
the patient's talking about this that and the other thing and now what do you
and the other thing and now what do you
and the other thing and now what do you really feel about it
really feel about it
really feel about it and now what do you really feel about it
and now what do you really feel about it
and now what do you really feel about it and then all of a sudden you begin to
and then all of a sudden you begin to
and then all of a sudden you begin to shake and feel nervous and
shake and feel nervous and
shake and feel nervous and ashamed to yourself. How do you really
ashamed to yourself. How do you really
ashamed to yourself. How do you really feel about it?
feel about it?
feel about it? You want to kill him, don't you? Yes,
You want to kill him, don't you? Yes,
You want to kill him, don't you? Yes, that's right. You really unconsciously
that's right. You really unconsciously
that's right. You really unconsciously want to kill him. The guy who passes you
want to kill him. The guy who passes you
want to kill him. The guy who passes you and sticks his thumb finger out. You
and sticks his thumb finger out. You
and sticks his thumb finger out. You want to kill him. Do you know that?
want to kill him. Do you know that?
want to kill him. Do you know that? Everybody here want to kill that so?
Everybody here want to kill that so?
Everybody here want to kill that so? Anybody thinks he should live?
Anybody thinks he should live?
Anybody thinks he should live? Ooh,
it goes by, gives you the finger, he
it goes by, gives you the finger, he should die,
should die,
should die, his car should roll over and the next.
his car should roll over and the next.
his car should roll over and the next. No. In the basis of the id, it thinks of
No. In the basis of the id, it thinks of
No. In the basis of the id, it thinks of killing. It thinks of killing others. So
killing. It thinks of killing others. So
killing. It thinks of killing others. So if you have a real religion that
if you have a real religion that
if you have a real religion that releases the id
releases the id
releases the id and
eliminates the super ego and says God is
eliminates the super ego and says God is on the side of your id. So what we're
on the side of your id. So what we're
on the side of your id. So what we're battling now for the survival of western
battling now for the survival of western
battling now for the survival of western civilization is the god of the it.
civilization is the god of the it.
civilization is the god of the it. The god of the it is the enemy of
The god of the it is the enemy of
The god of the it is the enemy of western civilization
western civilization
western civilization that you will go to heaven or you'll
that you will go to heaven or you'll
that you will go to heaven or you'll have endless
have endless
have endless hotsyatsis
hotsyatsis
hotsyatsis 72 of them or 77
72 of them or 77
72 of them or 77 in as a reward for releasing your id
in as a reward for releasing your id
in as a reward for releasing your id releasing your id and killing. So the
releasing your id and killing. So the
releasing your id and killing. So the superego then balances the pressure of
superego then balances the pressure of
superego then balances the pressure of the id which is in the animal instinct
the id which is in the animal instinct
the id which is in the animal instinct and the ego is in Freudian terminology
and the ego is in Freudian terminology
and the ego is in Freudian terminology not spiritual terminology freudian
not spiritual terminology freudian
not spiritual terminology freudian terminology
terminology
terminology uh the strength that the strength to
uh the strength that the strength to
uh the strength that the strength to balance the two. A healthy ego is able
balance the two. A healthy ego is able
balance the two. A healthy ego is able to handle and accept and uh repress uh
to handle and accept and uh repress uh
to handle and accept and uh repress uh handle instincts and not go into a guilt
handle instincts and not go into a guilt
handle instincts and not go into a guilt trip about it. So the it's the ego that
trip about it. So the it's the ego that
trip about it. So the it's the ego that is aligned with what we call reality.
is aligned with what we call reality.
is aligned with what we call reality. This is the person's reality testing the
This is the person's reality testing the
This is the person's reality testing the capacity to balance the instinctual
capacity to balance the instinctual
capacity to balance the instinctual urges against guilt and the attack of
urges against guilt and the attack of
urges against guilt and the attack of the superego. If the if you allow the
the superego. If the if you allow the
the superego. If the if you allow the superego to become hypertrophied,
superego to become hypertrophied,
superego to become hypertrophied, you end up with scrupulosity. You end up
you end up with scrupulosity. You end up
you end up with scrupulosity. You end up with with guilt and you eventually end
with with guilt and you eventually end
with with guilt and you eventually end up with depression because you judge
up with depression because you judge
up with depression because you judge against yourself. How could I have been
against yourself. How could I have been
against yourself. How could I have been so evil as to been feel angry at my
so evil as to been feel angry at my
so evil as to been feel angry at my mother for wanting me to quit playing
mother for wanting me to quit playing
mother for wanting me to quit playing stick ball and come in and wash my hands
stick ball and come in and wash my hands
stick ball and come in and wash my hands for dinner?
for dinner?
for dinner? All right. So the balance then the
All right. So the balance then the
All right. So the balance then the Freudian ego is the capacity to balance
Freudian ego is the capacity to balance
Freudian ego is the capacity to balance the repressed unconscious and uh people
the repressed unconscious and uh people
the repressed unconscious and uh people like Adolf Hitler said of the great
like Adolf Hitler said of the great
like Adolf Hitler said of the great dictators have learned how to regiment
dictators have learned how to regiment
dictators have learned how to regiment uh the id the id can be silenced by the
uh the id the id can be silenced by the
uh the id the id can be silenced by the herd instinct
herd instinct
herd instinct uh the hanging a group of people hangs
uh the hanging a group of people hangs
uh the hanging a group of people hangs somebody and the fact that it's a group
somebody and the fact that it's a group
somebody and the fact that it's a group they don't feel guilty about it if one
they don't feel guilty about it if one
they don't feel guilty about it if one person did it or a couple did. But so
person did it or a couple did. But so
person did it or a couple did. But so the super ego dissolves in the herd.
the super ego dissolves in the herd.
the super ego dissolves in the herd. That's a basic principle of psychian
That's a basic principle of psychian
That's a basic principle of psychian psychology. If everybody says it's all
psychology. If everybody says it's all
psychology. If everybody says it's all right to kill them, then it's okay to
right to kill them, then it's okay to
right to kill them, then it's okay to kill them. You by yourself would not be
kill them. You by yourself would not be
kill them. You by yourself would not be able to say that. So the herd instinct
able to say that. So the herd instinct
able to say that. So the herd instinct gives the super ego, gives you
gives the super ego, gives you
gives the super ego, gives you permission to owe to be the animal.
permission to owe to be the animal.
permission to owe to be the animal. And uh that's why you get great wards
And uh that's why you get great wards
And uh that's why you get great wards in the name of God in the name of uh
in the name of God in the name of uh
in the name of God in the name of uh collectivist some kind of collectivist
collectivist some kind of collectivist
collectivist some kind of collectivist uh psychology. The Nazi party was called
uh psychology. The Nazi party was called
uh psychology. The Nazi party was called a national socialist party. Japan was a
a national socialist party. Japan was a
a national socialist party. Japan was a divine imperialism.
divine imperialism.
divine imperialism. Uh communism was I don't know
Uh communism was I don't know
Uh communism was I don't know uh workers unite and release your
uh workers unite and release your
uh workers unite and release your chains. The hateful capitalist etc. All
chains. The hateful capitalist etc. All
chains. The hateful capitalist etc. All right. So you can see how man is now
right. So you can see how man is now
right. So you can see how man is now manipulated in group form uh by
manipulated in group form uh by
manipulated in group form uh by manipulating uh the super ego and you
manipulating uh the super ego and you
manipulating uh the super ego and you say it's good to do this now it's good
say it's good to do this now it's good
say it's good to do this now it's good to hate that et
to hate that et
to hate that et so the healthy person with a sense of
so the healthy person with a sense of
so the healthy person with a sense of reality done has a balance between their
reality done has a balance between their
reality done has a balance between their conscience their instinctual they don't
conscience their instinctual they don't
conscience their instinctual they don't have to deny so in psychoanalysis you
have to deny so in psychoanalysis you
have to deny so in psychoanalysis you stop denying primitive instincts
stop denying primitive instincts
stop denying primitive instincts yes I hate them I just assume kill them
yes I hate them I just assume kill them
yes I hate them I just assume kill them uh etc.
So the net effect of this is uh via the
So the net effect of this is uh via the endocrine glands uh as we said the
endocrine glands uh as we said the
endocrine glands uh as we said the stress hormones
stress hormones
stress hormones and it ends up affecting brain
and it ends up affecting brain
and it ends up affecting brain physiology. Now we showed from the brain
physiology. Now we showed from the brain
physiology. Now we showed from the brain physiology chart from before that your
physiology chart from before that your
physiology chart from before that your level of consciousness
level of consciousness
level of consciousness now affects your brain physiology.
now affects your brain physiology.
now affects your brain physiology. It's impossible for half the population
It's impossible for half the population
It's impossible for half the population to comprehend spiritual reality. It's
to comprehend spiritual reality. It's
to comprehend spiritual reality. It's impossible. Why? They can only
impossible. Why? They can only
impossible. Why? They can only understand the linear domain, the
understand the linear domain, the
understand the linear domain, the Newtonian world of causality. They have
Newtonian world of causality. They have
Newtonian world of causality. They have no comprehension of the nonlinear. They
no comprehension of the nonlinear. They
no comprehension of the nonlinear. They don't understand context. They don't
don't understand context. They don't
don't understand context. They don't understand context.
understand context.
understand context. Is it right for the government to spy on
Is it right for the government to spy on
Is it right for the government to spy on your emails to overseas
your emails to overseas
your emails to overseas suspects?
suspects?
suspects? depends on whether you're at war or not
depends on whether you're at war or not
depends on whether you're at war or not at war, doesn't it? Makes all the
at war, doesn't it? Makes all the
at war, doesn't it? Makes all the difference in the world. Makes all the
difference in the world. Makes all the
difference in the world. Makes all the difference in the world. If you're at
difference in the world. If you're at
difference in the world. If you're at war, then certain things and if you're
war, then certain things and if you're
war, then certain things and if you're not at war. So, it's naivity to deny to
not at war. So, it's naivity to deny to
not at war. So, it's naivity to deny to ignore context
ignore context
ignore context to ignore context.
to ignore context.
to ignore context. And the best example of context
And the best example of context
And the best example of context influencing morality is situational
influencing morality is situational
influencing morality is situational ethics. People say, "Well, no, no.
ethics. People say, "Well, no, no.
ethics. People say, "Well, no, no. What's right and wrong is absolute. It
What's right and wrong is absolute. It
What's right and wrong is absolute. It all depends on the context. Uh, every
all depends on the context. Uh, every
all depends on the context. Uh, every courtroom case is a case of context. Uh,
courtroom case is a case of context. Uh,
courtroom case is a case of context. Uh, what was the situation whereby you
what was the situation whereby you
what was the situation whereby you pulled the trigger, etc. Were you being
pulled the trigger, etc. Were you being
pulled the trigger, etc. Were you being threatened? Did you think you were Well,
threatened? Did you think you were Well,
threatened? Did you think you were Well, I thought I was being threatened, but it
I thought I was being threatened, but it
I thought I was being threatened, but it was it wasn't really a gun. It was it
was it wasn't really a gun. It was it
was it wasn't really a gun. It was it was only hamburger.
was only hamburger.
was only hamburger. I was trying to get out of his pocket.
I was trying to get out of his pocket.
I was trying to get out of his pocket. Well,
Well,
Well, that guy's an idiot with a with a cop
that guy's an idiot with a with a cop
that guy's an idiot with a with a cop standing there with a gun and he reaches
standing there with a gun and he reaches
standing there with a gun and he reaches in his pocket for a hamburger. Bye-bye.
in his pocket for a hamburger. Bye-bye.
in his pocket for a hamburger. Bye-bye. What do you expect the cop to do? Stand
What do you expect the cop to do? Stand
What do you expect the cop to do? Stand wait till he gets killed first?
wait till he gets killed first?
wait till he gets killed first? I don't think so. So, anyway, we know in
I don't think so. So, anyway, we know in
I don't think so. So, anyway, we know in every courtroom, we we look at the
every courtroom, we we look at the
every courtroom, we we look at the context the context in which this
context the context in which this
context the context in which this happened. What was the intention? What
happened. What was the intention? What
happened. What was the intention? What was the motivation?
was the motivation?
was the motivation? We know that 50% of u identification of
We know that 50% of u identification of
We know that 50% of u identification of suspects is erroneous.
suspects is erroneous.
suspects is erroneous. What do they call it? Personal ID or
What do they call it? Personal ID or
What do they call it? Personal ID or what do you call it? Personal
what do you call it? Personal
what do you call it? Personal witnessing.
witnessing.
witnessing. >> Huh?
>> Huh?
>> Huh? >> Eyewitnessing. Yes. Statistically 50% of
>> Eyewitnessing. Yes. Statistically 50% of
>> Eyewitnessing. Yes. Statistically 50% of the people they finger from the lineup
the people they finger from the lineup
the people they finger from the lineup is wrong. 50%.
is wrong. 50%.
is wrong. 50%. 50% of the time. That's the guy that did
50% of the time. That's the guy that did
50% of the time. That's the guy that did it. They're wrong. 50%.
We know from that project I was trying
We know from that project I was trying to think of the name of the project last
to think of the name of the project last
to think of the name of the project last night when DNA came out. They went
night when DNA came out. They went
night when DNA came out. They went through the death row of the prisons.
through the death row of the prisons.
through the death row of the prisons. How many people did they let out?
How many people did they let out?
How many people did they let out? I forget. A couple hundred. I forget the
I forget. A couple hundred. I forget the
I forget. A couple hundred. I forget the exact number. And what was the name of
exact number. And what was the name of
exact number. And what was the name of that project?
that project?
that project? It was the It was the crew that was in
It was the It was the crew that was in
It was the It was the crew that was in the famous whatchamacallit murder case.
the famous whatchamacallit murder case.
the famous whatchamacallit murder case. Hera
Hera
Hera Innocence Project something like that.
Innocence Project something like that.
Innocence Project something like that. Yeah. All right. DNA went out and
Yeah. All right. DNA went out and
Yeah. All right. DNA went out and re-examined all the guys in death row
re-examined all the guys in death row
re-examined all the guys in death row and I forget the the total number of
and I forget the the total number of
and I forget the the total number of people who are innocent 195 or it was a
people who are innocent 195 or it was a
people who are innocent 195 or it was a sizable number. Sizable number you know
sizable number. Sizable number you know
sizable number. Sizable number you know society wants revenge and therefore it's
society wants revenge and therefore it's
society wants revenge and therefore it's very willing to believe uh anything
very willing to believe uh anything
very willing to believe uh anything negative to get even seeking revenge.
negative to get even seeking revenge.
negative to get even seeking revenge. Yes, it was a very uh worthwhile
Yes, it was a very uh worthwhile
Yes, it was a very uh worthwhile enterprise and it's sort of scary. It's
enterprise and it's sort of scary. It's
enterprise and it's sort of scary. It's one of the reasons uh that I've always
one of the reasons uh that I've always
one of the reasons uh that I've always been against capital punishment is
been against capital punishment is
been against capital punishment is because if you're mistaken, you can't
because if you're mistaken, you can't
because if you're mistaken, you can't correct it. I mean, who would want that
correct it. I mean, who would want that
correct it. I mean, who would want that on their conscience? I hate to be the
on their conscience? I hate to be the
on their conscience? I hate to be the judge condemning somebody to death and
judge condemning somebody to death and
judge condemning somebody to death and then find out later with DNA evidence he
then find out later with DNA evidence he
then find out later with DNA evidence he wasn't it. I mean, how could you live
wasn't it. I mean, how could you live
wasn't it. I mean, how could you live with your own I would spend the rest of
with your own I would spend the rest of
with your own I would spend the rest of my life, guilt, and penance.
my life, guilt, and penance.
my life, guilt, and penance. Uh
Uh
Uh so, I'm against the death penalty for
so, I'm against the death penalty for
so, I'm against the death penalty for one reason. Not only is it in my view
one reason. Not only is it in my view
one reason. Not only is it in my view uncuthn
correct the mistake.
correct the mistake. So the effect then is on brain
So the effect then is on brain
So the effect then is on brain physiology. So all this media barrage
physiology. So all this media barrage
physiology. So all this media barrage programming is affecting your brain
programming is affecting your brain
programming is affecting your brain physiology
physiology
physiology and it's affecting your indocrine system
and it's affecting your indocrine system
and it's affecting your indocrine system and the your cortisone and stress
and the your cortisone and stress
and the your cortisone and stress hormones.
hormones.
hormones. So while they're pounding away on you,
So while they're pounding away on you,
So while they're pounding away on you, your brain physiology is going through
your brain physiology is going through
your brain physiology is going through stress, your adrenal glands, which sit
stress, your adrenal glands, which sit
stress, your adrenal glands, which sit on top of the adrenal and put out
on top of the adrenal and put out
on top of the adrenal and put out cortisone. Put out cortisone.
cortisone. Put out cortisone.
cortisone. Put out cortisone. The the happy brain, the happy brain is
The the happy brain, the happy brain is
The the happy brain, the happy brain is putting out endorphins. Endorphins make
putting out endorphins. Endorphins make
putting out endorphins. Endorphins make you feel good. And the happy person then
you feel good. And the happy person then
you feel good. And the happy person then his brain is putting out endorphins. The
his brain is putting out endorphins. The
his brain is putting out endorphins. The person living below 200 is constantly
person living below 200 is constantly
person living below 200 is constantly under stress. So he's putting out
under stress. So he's putting out
under stress. So he's putting out adrenaline, act and stress, cortisone,
adrenaline, act and stress, cortisone,
adrenaline, act and stress, cortisone, stress hormones.
stress hormones.
stress hormones. So this all affects our brain
So this all affects our brain
So this all affects our brain physiology.
physiology.
physiology. Yesterday we did a interesting program
Yesterday we did a interesting program
Yesterday we did a interesting program on music. Uh influencing all of this
on music. Uh influencing all of this
on music. Uh influencing all of this overall is also the exposure to music,
overall is also the exposure to music,
overall is also the exposure to music, the arts and aesthetics. We know that
the arts and aesthetics. We know that
the arts and aesthetics. We know that people who are spiritually
people who are spiritually
people who are spiritually uh capable or adaptable or equipped or
uh capable or adaptable or equipped or
uh capable or adaptable or equipped or uh to whom it comes natural very often
uh to whom it comes natural very often
uh to whom it comes natural very often usually had a very uh extensive exposure
usually had a very uh extensive exposure
usually had a very uh extensive exposure to music, the arts and aesthetics. Um
to music, the arts and aesthetics. Um
to music, the arts and aesthetics. Um music and the arts and the aesthetics uh
music and the arts and the aesthetics uh
music and the arts and the aesthetics uh influences brain function and it also
influences brain function and it also
influences brain function and it also influences neuronal connection. As
influences neuronal connection. As
influences neuronal connection. As you're aware, the human brain is
you're aware, the human brain is
you're aware, the human brain is constantly producing thousands of
constantly producing thousands of
constantly producing thousands of neurons all the time.
neurons all the time.
neurons all the time. And unless they connect up and are put
And unless they connect up and are put
And unless they connect up and are put into the circuit they decreate and then
into the circuit they decreate and then
into the circuit they decreate and then a whole new vet comes up. Uh so an
a whole new vet comes up. Uh so an
a whole new vet comes up. Uh so an exposure to music uh religion aesthetics
exposure to music uh religion aesthetics
exposure to music uh religion aesthetics etc and humor humor etc goodwill uh
etc and humor humor etc goodwill uh
etc and humor humor etc goodwill uh influences the way the neuronal
influences the way the neuronal
influences the way the neuronal connections. So I not frequently get
connections. So I not frequently get
connections. So I not frequently get something from a mother. what can I do
something from a mother. what can I do
something from a mother. what can I do to make sure that my child uh develops
to make sure that my child uh develops
to make sure that my child uh develops uh their spiritual capacity? And I
uh their spiritual capacity? And I
uh their spiritual capacity? And I always tell them the best thing you can
always tell them the best thing you can
always tell them the best thing you can do is expose them to aesthetics, to
do is expose them to aesthetics, to
do is expose them to aesthetics, to ballet, to the theater, to opera, to the
ballet, to the theater, to opera, to the
ballet, to the theater, to opera, to the arts, to nature. Uh and develop a love
arts, to nature. Uh and develop a love
arts, to nature. Uh and develop a love and a synchronicity with with beauty.
and a synchronicity with with beauty.
and a synchronicity with with beauty. Uh today's what, Saturday? Yes,
Uh today's what, Saturday? Yes,
Uh today's what, Saturday? Yes, Thursday, I think. Yes. We had a a crew
Thursday, I think. Yes. We had a a crew
Thursday, I think. Yes. We had a a crew that's going to do a program on music
that's going to do a program on music
that's going to do a program on music for some PBS thing and uh all they
for some PBS thing and uh all they
for some PBS thing and uh all they wanted to do was have me discuss the imp
wanted to do was have me discuss the imp
wanted to do was have me discuss the imp impact of music uh on the on the persons
impact of music uh on the on the persons
impact of music uh on the on the persons overall the impact on society.
overall the impact on society.
overall the impact on society. We know that the crime rate amongst
We know that the crime rate amongst
We know that the crime rate amongst people who are raised if you have
people who are raised if you have
people who are raised if you have exposure to religion plus aesthetics the
exposure to religion plus aesthetics the
exposure to religion plus aesthetics the crime rate is practically zero.
crime rate is practically zero.
crime rate is practically zero. The crime rate amongst people with a
The crime rate amongst people with a
The crime rate amongst people with a heavy exposure to aesthetics
heavy exposure to aesthetics
heavy exposure to aesthetics and the love of animals and the love of
and the love of animals and the love of
and the love of animals and the love of nature is practically zero. Practically
nature is practically zero. Practically
nature is practically zero. Practically zero crime rate. Practically zero crime
zero crime rate. Practically zero crime
zero crime rate. Practically zero crime rate. Isn't that amazing?
Yeah. But you got to listen to Bogner B
Yeah. But you got to listen to Bogner B and all that.
So a child brought up listening to the
So a child brought up listening to the overshirt of towniser,
overshirt of towniser,
overshirt of towniser, the overshirt of loan grin.
the overshirt of loan grin.
the overshirt of loan grin. In my family, everybody was musical. You
In my family, everybody was musical. You
In my family, everybody was musical. You see, my grandmother uh played the
see, my grandmother uh played the
see, my grandmother uh played the classical music all the time. She was
classical music all the time. She was
classical music all the time. She was pregnant with my father
pregnant with my father
pregnant with my father and people laughed at her as an ignorant
and people laughed at her as an ignorant
and people laughed at her as an ignorant old Irish lady, you know, and she said,
old Irish lady, you know, and she said,
old Irish lady, you know, and she said, "Yeah, you'll see. You'll see." And it
"Yeah, you'll see. You'll see." And it
"Yeah, you'll see. You'll see." And it turned out he was a great musician.
turned out he was a great musician.
turned out he was a great musician. Yeah. And then she used to read me uh
Yeah. And then she used to read me uh
Yeah. And then she used to read me uh Shakespeare. So uh classical music and
Shakespeare. So uh classical music and
Shakespeare. So uh classical music and Shakespeare. And then Saturday afternoon
Shakespeare. And then Saturday afternoon
Shakespeare. And then Saturday afternoon the Metropolitan Opera would come from
the Metropolitan Opera would come from
the Metropolitan Opera would come from New York City and Milton Cross would
New York City and Milton Cross would
New York City and Milton Cross would explain the opera and pretty soon you
explain the opera and pretty soon you
explain the opera and pretty soon you know you're really caught up in the
know you're really caught up in the
know you're really caught up in the neolong ring and looking forward to low
neolong ring and looking forward to low
neolong ring and looking forward to low and grinning.
and grinning.
and grinning. Uh it becomes intrinsic. uh and of
Uh it becomes intrinsic. uh and of
Uh it becomes intrinsic. uh and of course all this is having an effect not
course all this is having an effect not
course all this is having an effect not only on the brain uh physiology but
only on the brain uh physiology but
only on the brain uh physiology but actually on the brain anatomy the the
actually on the brain anatomy the the
actually on the brain anatomy the the brain neurology the neurons are actually
brain neurology the neurons are actually
brain neurology the neurons are actually so in the presence of beautiful music
so in the presence of beautiful music
so in the presence of beautiful music these neur if in in their absence these
these neur if in in their absence these
these neur if in in their absence these two neurons don't connect in the
two neurons don't connect in the
two neurons don't connect in the presence of it the thrill and pleasure
presence of it the thrill and pleasure
presence of it the thrill and pleasure of it these neurons say oh we're
of it these neurons say oh we're
of it these neurons say oh we're worthwhile we we're what you want and
worthwhile we we're what you want and
worthwhile we we're what you want and they connect up So you progressively
they connect up So you progressively
they connect up So you progressively become uh more spiritually aligned in
become uh more spiritually aligned in
become uh more spiritually aligned in your brain physiology.
your brain physiology.
your brain physiology. So what can you do for your children? Uh
So what can you do for your children? Uh
So what can you do for your children? Uh teach them that appreciation
teach them that appreciation
teach them that appreciation uh for beauty in all of its forms. You
uh for beauty in all of its forms. You
uh for beauty in all of its forms. You get to go to all the art galleries. You
get to go to all the art galleries. You
get to go to all the art galleries. You get to see all the great ballet. And in
get to see all the great ballet. And in
get to see all the great ballet. And in the town I lived in Milwaukee, they uh
the town I lived in Milwaukee, they uh
the town I lived in Milwaukee, they uh the great artists would come through.
the great artists would come through.
the great artists would come through. And of course you went to see them
And of course you went to see them
And of course you went to see them because they were rare in Satler Wells
because they were rare in Satler Wells
because they were rare in Satler Wells Ballet or a New York City Ballet,
Ballet or a New York City Ballet,
Ballet or a New York City Ballet, whatever would come through. You went to
whatever would come through. You went to
whatever would come through. You went to see it. If you live in New York City,
see it. If you live in New York City,
see it. If you live in New York City, you never go to see it.
you never go to see it.
you never go to see it. Why? Because it's there all the time.
Why? Because it's there all the time.
Why? Because it's there all the time. You can go anytime. If you live in New
You can go anytime. If you live in New
You can go anytime. If you live in New York City, because it's there all the
York City, because it's there all the
York City, because it's there all the time and you can go anytime, you never
time and you can go anytime, you never
time and you can go anytime, you never go.
go.
go. If you ask somebody who lived all their
If you ask somebody who lived all their
If you ask somebody who lived all their life in New York City, you ever been
life in New York City, you ever been
life in New York City, you ever been there, ever been to the entire top of
there, ever been to the entire top of
there, ever been to the entire top of the Empire State Building? They'll say,
the Empire State Building? They'll say,
the Empire State Building? They'll say, "No."
"No."
"No." But if they have a visitor from out of
But if they have a visitor from out of
But if they have a visitor from out of town, then they go to see the top of the
town, then they go to see the top of the
town, then they go to see the top of the Empire State Building. It's hysterical.
Empire State Building. It's hysterical.
Empire State Building. It's hysterical. If it's available all the time, you
If it's available all the time, you
If it's available all the time, you know, so the best thing to do is live in
know, so the best thing to do is live in
know, so the best thing to do is live in a city where these things are highly
a city where these things are highly
a city where these things are highly valued because they're not there all the
valued because they're not there all the
valued because they're not there all the time. So when they come through, they're
time. So when they come through, they're
time. So when they come through, they're they're an occasion and worth uh going
they're an occasion and worth uh going
they're an occasion and worth uh going to see. appreciation for music, the arts
to see. appreciation for music, the arts
to see. appreciation for music, the arts and aesthetics uh for ballet and uh the
and aesthetics uh for ballet and uh the
and aesthetics uh for ballet and uh the theater theater arts.
theater theater arts.
theater theater arts. Uh
Uh
Uh the this this phenomena the brain
the this this phenomena the brain
the this this phenomena the brain barrage uh results in a certain amount
barrage uh results in a certain amount
barrage uh results in a certain amount of what's called imprinting imprinting
of what's called imprinting imprinting
of what's called imprinting imprinting uh and this is how you get brainwashed.
uh and this is how you get brainwashed.
uh and this is how you get brainwashed. The program has already happened to you
The program has already happened to you
The program has already happened to you and by the time you decide you're not
and by the time you decide you're not
and by the time you decide you're not you don't want to get involved in that
you don't want to get involved in that
you don't want to get involved in that you've already been programmed. you've
you've already been programmed. you've
you've already been programmed. you've already been programmed.
already been programmed.
already been programmed. The other thing that gives things
The other thing that gives things
The other thing that gives things meaning and significance and importance
meaning and significance and importance
meaning and significance and importance is framing. And of course the media that
is framing. And of course the media that
is framing. And of course the media that what we're talking about is the framing
what we're talking about is the framing
what we're talking about is the framing is that the media has selected it to
is that the media has selected it to
is that the media has selected it to report in the first place. Then the
report in the first place. Then the
report in the first place. Then the sequence in which these things are
sequence in which these things are
sequence in which these things are presented to you will have a different
presented to you will have a different
presented to you will have a different impact on your brain physiology.
impact on your brain physiology.
impact on your brain physiology. In a certain sequence, a certain image
In a certain sequence, a certain image
In a certain sequence, a certain image will disappear and not be recallable. in
will disappear and not be recallable. in
will disappear and not be recallable. in a different sequence is highly has a
a different sequence is highly has a
a different sequence is highly has a great impact. So the programming of the
great impact. So the programming of the
great impact. So the programming of the media then is profoundly significant and
media then is profoundly significant and
media then is profoundly significant and profoundly affecting uh the capacity to
profoundly affecting uh the capacity to
profoundly affecting uh the capacity to uh recognize a reality in today's world.
uh recognize a reality in today's world.
uh recognize a reality in today's world. We of course more sophisticated people
We of course more sophisticated people
We of course more sophisticated people are aware of context versus content. Uh
are aware of context versus content. Uh
are aware of context versus content. Uh context is nonlinear and content is
context is nonlinear and content is
context is nonlinear and content is linear. Whether a thing is a crime or
linear. Whether a thing is a crime or
linear. Whether a thing is a crime or not and how serious it is depends on the
not and how serious it is depends on the
not and how serious it is depends on the circumstances. The context versus the
circumstances. The context versus the
circumstances. The context versus the content.
content.
content. On top of all the other favorable things
On top of all the other favorable things
On top of all the other favorable things is a sense of humor. Yeah. A sense of
is a sense of humor. Yeah. A sense of
is a sense of humor. Yeah. A sense of humor. And I think it's extremely
humor. And I think it's extremely
humor. And I think it's extremely important. I think humor is as important
important. I think humor is as important
important. I think humor is as important as any of the other things. Why? Because
as any of the other things. Why? Because
as any of the other things. Why? Because humor has a healing effect. Humor if you
humor has a healing effect. Humor if you
humor has a healing effect. Humor if you you do the arm on it makes you go
you do the arm on it makes you go
you do the arm on it makes you go strong.
strong.
strong. Uh humor points out the ambiguities and
Uh humor points out the ambiguities and
Uh humor points out the ambiguities and it points out very often the ambiguity
it points out very often the ambiguity
it points out very often the ambiguity between the content and the context you
between the content and the context you
between the content and the context you know and how you sometimes see the two
know and how you sometimes see the two
know and how you sometimes see the two end up really the opposite you know the
end up really the opposite you know the
end up really the opposite you know the opposite the intention is good but uh so
opposite the intention is good but uh so
opposite the intention is good but uh so I think humor has a tremendously healing
I think humor has a tremendously healing
I think humor has a tremendously healing effect I've mentioned that in previous
effect I've mentioned that in previous
effect I've mentioned that in previous lectures
lectures
lectures uh and some people have written books on
uh and some people have written books on
uh and some people have written books on how they recovered from grave illnesses
how they recovered from grave illnesses
how they recovered from grave illnesses by uh just employing nothing but humor.
by uh just employing nothing but humor.
by uh just employing nothing but humor. All they did is laugh all the time and
All they did is laugh all the time and
All they did is laugh all the time and get every funny movie they could.
get every funny movie they could.
get every funny movie they could. So humor uh releases uh endorphins,
So humor uh releases uh endorphins,
So humor uh releases uh endorphins, releases uh positive brain physiology
releases uh positive brain physiology
releases uh positive brain physiology and humor is based so much on ambiguity,
and humor is based so much on ambiguity,
and humor is based so much on ambiguity, the contrast between what is said and
the contrast between what is said and
the contrast between what is said and what we know uh really goes on and it
what we know uh really goes on and it
what we know uh really goes on and it makes us laugh. And that's the way I
makes us laugh. And that's the way I
makes us laugh. And that's the way I think cultural
think cultural
think cultural uh
uh
uh cultural what do you call it between
cultural what do you call it between
cultural what do you call it between classes is there a the natural way is
classes is there a the natural way is
classes is there a the natural way is for it to dissolve through humor. I
for it to dissolve through humor. I
for it to dissolve through humor. I don't know if women do that much but men
don't know if women do that much but men
don't know if women do that much but men do. They're always kidding each other
do. They're always kidding each other
do. They're always kidding each other about about their uh background or the
about about their uh background or the
about about their uh background or the world I grew up anyway. Uh always kid
world I grew up anyway. Uh always kid
world I grew up anyway. Uh always kid each other about their own background
each other about their own background
each other about their own background but it's all very good humor. And uh
but it's all very good humor. And uh
but it's all very good humor. And uh I've mentioned before, you know, the guy
I've mentioned before, you know, the guy
I've mentioned before, you know, the guy had a license plate. I would pass him
had a license plate. I would pass him
had a license plate. I would pass him every morning. License plate said, "Kiss
every morning. License plate said, "Kiss
every morning. License plate said, "Kiss me I'm Irish." No, kiss me, I'm Polish.
me I'm Irish." No, kiss me, I'm Polish.
me I'm Irish." No, kiss me, I'm Polish. I was, "Kiss me, I'm Polish." I mean, it
I was, "Kiss me, I'm Polish." I mean, it
I was, "Kiss me, I'm Polish." I mean, it was so hysterical. So, uh, men have
was so hysterical. So, uh, men have
was so hysterical. So, uh, men have learned in the workplace, in the
learned in the workplace, in the
learned in the workplace, in the workplace, to joke about it and include
workplace, to joke about it and include
workplace, to joke about it and include it in a a noninssulting way and sort of
it in a a noninssulting way and sort of
it in a a noninssulting way and sort of an endearing kind of a way. And we
an endearing kind of a way. And we
an endearing kind of a way. And we couldn't run this brewery without you
couldn't run this brewery without you
couldn't run this brewery without you pullocks. I mean, we couldn't run a
pullocks. I mean, we couldn't run a
pullocks. I mean, we couldn't run a brewery without the pullocks. Milwaukee
brewery without the pullocks. Milwaukee
brewery without the pullocks. Milwaukee and Milwaukee, you couldn't run a
and Milwaukee, you couldn't run a
and Milwaukee, you couldn't run a brewery without the pullocks. No.
So then there it became okay to be who
So then there it became okay to be who you are. So through humor, you has a
you are. So through humor, you has a
you are. So through humor, you has a healing effect because it's okay to be
healing effect because it's okay to be
healing effect because it's okay to be who you are. And I think that justing
who you are. And I think that justing
who you are. And I think that justing between the sexes, if you take out the
between the sexes, if you take out the
between the sexes, if you take out the snide negativity of it, men and women
snide negativity of it, men and women
snide negativity of it, men and women learn to get get along each other
learn to get get along each other
learn to get get along each other extremely well through humor. We were
extremely well through humor. We were
extremely well through humor. We were just talking this morning about men are
just talking this morning about men are
just talking this morning about men are from what are men from?
from what are men from?
from what are men from? >> Men are from Mars.
>> Men are from Mars.
>> Men are from Mars. >> Women are from Venus. Oh, heck. I
>> Women are from Venus. Oh, heck. I
>> Women are from Venus. Oh, heck. I thought it was the other way. Oh,
men are from Mars and women are from
men are from Mars and women are from Venus.
Venus.
Venus. Uh, and men tend to lose
Uh, and men tend to lose
Uh, and men tend to lose uh I don't know about women, but men
uh I don't know about women, but men
uh I don't know about women, but men tend to lose track of that knowingness.
tend to lose track of that knowingness.
tend to lose track of that knowingness. If you haven't read it, it's demanded
If you haven't read it, it's demanded
If you haven't read it, it's demanded that you read it
that you read it
that you read it to become a mature human being. that
to become a mature human being. that
to become a mature human being. that because the the fact that women men and
because the the fact that women men and
because the the fact that women men and women see things differently explains
women see things differently explains
women see things differently explains all the arguments.
all the arguments.
all the arguments. If you understand it, you can look at
If you understand it, you can look at
If you understand it, you can look at any argument and you'll see it's just
any argument and you'll see it's just
any argument and you'll see it's just that they tend to see things differently
that they tend to see things differently
that they tend to see things differently than men. The men will look at it cold
than men. The men will look at it cold
than men. The men will look at it cold hard intellect and she's looking at it
hard intellect and she's looking at it
hard intellect and she's looking at it from emotional.
from emotional.
from emotional. Oh, you know what about the comfort of
Oh, you know what about the comfort of
Oh, you know what about the comfort of the family? I'm saying we already got
the family? I'm saying we already got
the family? I'm saying we already got three cantalopes and now you brought
three cantalopes and now you brought
three cantalopes and now you brought another one home.
Well, I was afraid that wouldn't be
Well, I was afraid that wouldn't be enough.
Okay. Well, I'll eat cantaloupe all week
Okay. Well, I'll eat cantaloupe all week long
long
long to the man reason and logic. You got two
to the man reason and logic. You got two
to the man reason and logic. You got two cantalopes. Why do you need a third
cantalopes. Why do you need a third
cantalopes. Why do you need a third cantaloupe? Well, they're on sale and uh
All right. So, once you get that the
All right. So, once you get that the woman's intention is domestic, she wants
woman's intention is domestic, she wants
woman's intention is domestic, she wants everybody to be provided for and happy.
everybody to be provided for and happy.
everybody to be provided for and happy. And I'll say, "Why? Why are you washing
And I'll say, "Why? Why are you washing
And I'll say, "Why? Why are you washing the the sheets? You just washed them
the the sheets? You just washed them
the the sheets? You just washed them yesterday.
yesterday.
yesterday. Today's a new day, and she wants them to
Today's a new day, and she wants them to
Today's a new day, and she wants them to be fluffy today.
man's intellect says hell there is wash
man's intellect says hell there is wash the day before.
So it's that ambiance of the feminine as
So it's that ambiance of the feminine as the provider as the new the nurturer
the provider as the new the nurturer
the provider as the new the nurturer that and therefore what has to do with
that and therefore what has to do with
that and therefore what has to do with survival as she sees it from that
survival as she sees it from that
survival as she sees it from that picture and the man is only looking you
picture and the man is only looking you
picture and the man is only looking you know at like it's at the office
know at like it's at the office
know at like it's at the office practical
practical
practical and he's saying we got two bananas why
and he's saying we got two bananas why
and he's saying we got two bananas why do you need a third one so
do you need a third one so
do you need a third one so anyway the humor then so everybody has
anyway the humor then so everybody has
anyway the humor then so everybody has to read that book and uh and and don't I
to read that book and uh and and don't I
to read that book and uh and and don't I don't want to hear any complaints unless
don't want to hear any complaints unless
don't want to hear any complaints unless you've wrote it.
you've wrote it.
you've wrote it. I think it's a great book. It just and
I think it's a great book. It just and
I think it's a great book. It just and when I was still in practice, I used to
when I was still in practice, I used to
when I was still in practice, I used to have all the all my patients who were
have all the all my patients who were
have all the all my patients who were having marital problems read it and
having marital problems read it and
having marital problems read it and everyone said it just oh wow made it all
everyone said it just oh wow made it all
everyone said it just oh wow made it all oh I see I see oh oh I see how it looks
oh I see I see oh oh I see how it looks
oh I see I see oh oh I see how it looks to the other person you know. All right.
to the other person you know. All right.
to the other person you know. All right. So,
So,
So, on top of all this, we call all this
on top of all this, we call all this
on top of all this, we call all this indoctrination. Not necessarily
indoctrination. Not necessarily
indoctrination. Not necessarily purposeful indoctrination,
purposeful indoctrination,
purposeful indoctrination, but you're constantly being
but you're constantly being
but you're constantly being indoctrinated and programmed by the
indoctrinated and programmed by the
indoctrinated and programmed by the human experience.
human experience.
human experience. Uh, it comes through as memes,
Uh, it comes through as memes,
Uh, it comes through as memes, repetitive quotes.
repetitive quotes.
repetitive quotes. I mean, everybody hates Bush. You're
I mean, everybody hates Bush. You're
I mean, everybody hates Bush. You're supposed to hate Bush.
Propaganda.
Propaganda. All right. So memes then are re
All right. So memes then are re
All right. So memes then are re repetitious phrases that become quoted
repetitious phrases that become quoted
repetitious phrases that become quoted so often that they're accepted as though
so often that they're accepted as though
so often that they're accepted as though they were truth. They're accepted as
they were truth. They're accepted as
they were truth. They're accepted as though they were truth just by sheer
though they were truth just by sheer
though they were truth just by sheer repetition.
repetition.
repetition. And you see that all the time in the
And you see that all the time in the
And you see that all the time in the media. You see it in the evening news.
media. You see it in the evening news.
media. You see it in the evening news. It's a constant. Uh the meme then is a
It's a constant. Uh the meme then is a
It's a constant. Uh the meme then is a way of becoming programmed and
way of becoming programmed and
way of becoming programmed and indoctrinated
indoctrinated
indoctrinated without realizing you're becoming
without realizing you're becoming
without realizing you're becoming indoctrinated because it's such a common
indoctrinated because it's such a common
indoctrinated because it's such a common phrase. Uhhuh.
phrase. Uhhuh.
phrase. Uhhuh. Stupid what you whatchamacallit stupid
Stupid what you whatchamacallit stupid
Stupid what you whatchamacallit stupid white men or whatever. It becomes a meme
white men or whatever. It becomes a meme
white men or whatever. It becomes a meme after a while.
after a while.
after a while. Behind all of this and all of these
Behind all of this and all of these
Behind all of this and all of these things we talked about is so far is
things we talked about is so far is
things we talked about is so far is intention. All of them are energized by
intention. All of them are energized by
intention. All of them are energized by intention. Whether you're programmed or
intention. Whether you're programmed or
intention. Whether you're programmed or not depends on the intention and the
not depends on the intention and the
not depends on the intention and the intention of the person who writes,
intention of the person who writes,
intention of the person who writes, I call them snides. The blo blogger
I call them snides. The blo blogger
I call them snides. The blo blogger bloggerum. I don't have anything to do
bloggerum. I don't have anything to do
bloggerum. I don't have anything to do with bloggerum. I don't have a computer.
with bloggerum. I don't have a computer.
with bloggerum. I don't have a computer. I don't know how to work one. I don't
I don't know how to work one. I don't
I don't know how to work one. I don't want to know how to work one. And um I I
want to know how to work one. And um I I
want to know how to work one. And um I I avoid bloggerom because so much of the
avoid bloggerom because so much of the
avoid bloggerom because so much of the intention is so snide, so vicious. uh
intention is so snide, so vicious. uh
intention is so snide, so vicious. uh this uh the shift of a word to try and
this uh the shift of a word to try and
this uh the shift of a word to try and make the person look worse. You know,
make the person look worse. You know,
make the person look worse. You know, you know, why don't you just say you
you know, why don't you just say you
you know, why don't you just say you hate them? You don't have to, you know,
hate them? You don't have to, you know,
hate them? You don't have to, you know, why don't you just say that you hate
why don't you just say that you hate
why don't you just say that you hate him? Be honest. And uh so the intention
him? Be honest. And uh so the intention
him? Be honest. And uh so the intention then slants these memes tend to be
then slants these memes tend to be
then slants these memes tend to be repetitious to the point of uh uh
repetitious to the point of uh uh
repetitious to the point of uh uh dangerousness. Dangerousness.
dangerousness. Dangerousness.
dangerousness. Dangerousness. And of course uh our main uh enemy of
And of course uh our main uh enemy of
And of course uh our main uh enemy of this ar western culture in the world
this ar western culture in the world
this ar western culture in the world today have become experts at the at
today have become experts at the at
today have become experts at the at propaganda in fact are following
propaganda in fact are following
propaganda in fact are following precisely exactly the same as as Nazi
precisely exactly the same as as Nazi
precisely exactly the same as as Nazi Germany following exactly the same
Germany following exactly the same
Germany following exactly the same thing. The protocol of the elders of
thing. The protocol of the elders of
thing. The protocol of the elders of Zion picturing the enemy as a vicious
Zion picturing the enemy as a vicious
Zion picturing the enemy as a vicious looking making them look like rats etc.
looking making them look like rats etc.
looking making them look like rats etc. So the programming is going on visually,
So the programming is going on visually,
So the programming is going on visually, visually pictorially.
visually pictorially.
visually pictorially. Behind all this is the power of
Behind all this is the power of
Behind all this is the power of intention. Discernment versus naive. To
intention. Discernment versus naive. To
intention. Discernment versus naive. To merely know the things we've been
merely know the things we've been
merely know the things we've been talking about gives you greater
talking about gives you greater
talking about gives you greater discernment because you realize that the
discernment because you realize that the
discernment because you realize that the mind unaded is naive. The mind, the
mind unaded is naive. The mind, the
mind unaded is naive. The mind, the human mind unaded is unable to tell
human mind unaded is unable to tell
human mind unaded is unable to tell truth from falsehood.
truth from falsehood.
truth from falsehood. People uh write me nasty blogs once in a
People uh write me nasty blogs once in a
People uh write me nasty blogs once in a while about that uh and ridicule it.
while about that uh and ridicule it.
while about that uh and ridicule it. If they got what I was saying, they
If they got what I was saying, they
If they got what I was saying, they wouldn't have written that now that
wouldn't have written that now that
wouldn't have written that now that blog.
The human mind unaded is so dominated by
The human mind unaded is so dominated by the structure of the ego. It cannot
the structure of the ego. It cannot
the structure of the ego. It cannot discern perception from essence. And one
discern perception from essence. And one
discern perception from essence. And one thing that brings it up brings up one's
thing that brings it up brings up one's
thing that brings it up brings up one's level to understand
level to understand
level to understand uh reality is narcissism versus
uh reality is narcissism versus
uh reality is narcissism versus spirituality. Narcissism is so
spirituality. Narcissism is so
spirituality. Narcissism is so interested in just dominating with its
interested in just dominating with its
interested in just dominating with its own viewpoint. And spirituality begins
own viewpoint. And spirituality begins
own viewpoint. And spirituality begins to seek truth for its own sake. Speak
to seek truth for its own sake. Speak
to seek truth for its own sake. Speak truth for its own sake. So the antidote
truth for its own sake. So the antidote
truth for its own sake. So the antidote to all of these things is spirituality.
to all of these things is spirituality.
to all of these things is spirituality. And the answer can be quick and short.
And the answer can be quick and short.
And the answer can be quick and short. God or no God. If you say there's no
God or no God. If you say there's no
God or no God. If you say there's no God, you just had it
God, you just had it
God, you just had it for this time or this time of your life.
for this time or this time of your life.
for this time or this time of your life. And God makes all the difference in the
And God makes all the difference in the
And God makes all the difference in the world. So whether a person, you know,
world. So whether a person, you know,
world. So whether a person, you know, holds that God is the hypothetical
holds that God is the hypothetical
holds that God is the hypothetical likelihood
likelihood
likelihood uh etc is completely different than
uh etc is completely different than
uh etc is completely different than negating. All right? So skepticism is
negating. All right? So skepticism is
negating. All right? So skepticism is one thing. Atheism is another. I myself
one thing. Atheism is another. I myself
one thing. Atheism is another. I myself was a devout agnostic for many years. I
was a devout agnostic for many years. I
was a devout agnostic for many years. I was an atheist and I got more
was an atheist and I got more
was an atheist and I got more sophisticated. I became an agnostic.
sophisticated. I became an agnostic.
sophisticated. I became an agnostic. Became an agnostic. So God or no God uh
Became an agnostic. So God or no God uh
Became an agnostic. So God or no God uh then uh is the overall context in which
then uh is the overall context in which
then uh is the overall context in which all of this happens. The house of
all of this happens. The house of
all of this happens. The house of mirrors looks completely different when
mirrors looks completely different when
mirrors looks completely different when it's illuminated by the light of
it's illuminated by the light of
it's illuminated by the light of divinity.
divinity.
divinity. So this morning we just thought we'd
So this morning we just thought we'd
So this morning we just thought we'd take a quick tour uh through a portion
take a quick tour uh through a portion
take a quick tour uh through a portion of the house of mirrors.
of the house of mirrors.
of the house of mirrors. We'll do it in small doses. We'll do it
We'll do it in small doses. We'll do it
We'll do it in small doses. We'll do it in small doses. And now we're going to
in small doses. And now we're going to
in small doses. And now we're going to have a break and resume at what time?
have a break and resume at what time?
have a break and resume at what time? >> We're going to have a break and we're
>> We're going to have a break and we're
>> We're going to have a break and we're going to resume it at 2 o'clock.
there's all my little fellas,
there's all my little fellas, all my little friends.
all my little friends.
all my little friends. We understand each other. Anyway,
We understand each other. Anyway,
We understand each other. Anyway, let's see. Where were we? Did anybody
let's see. Where were we? Did anybody
let's see. Where were we? Did anybody remember?
We just finished up.
We just finished up. >> Where? Where am I?
>> Where? Where am I?
>> Where? Where am I? >> I guess we must still be in the house of
>> I guess we must still be in the house of
>> I guess we must still be in the house of mirrors.
>> Is this the way to truth? Oh, looks
>> Is this the way to truth? Oh, looks false to me. Oh, I thought that was
false to me. Oh, I thought that was
false to me. Oh, I thought that was true. Sorry.
117.
117. >> Oh, we finished 116. Okay.
>> Oh, we finished 116. Okay.
>> Oh, we finished 116. Okay. >> Okay. Somebody knows where we are.
>> The human dilemma. You know, uh you see
>> The human dilemma. You know, uh you see how exquisitly difficult it really is
how exquisitly difficult it really is
how exquisitly difficult it really is when you look at it objectively.
when you look at it objectively.
when you look at it objectively. Uh we're all walking miracles that we
Uh we're all walking miracles that we
Uh we're all walking miracles that we survived this far, aren't we?
survived this far, aren't we?
survived this far, aren't we? all the deception and illusions and
all the deception and illusions and
all the deception and illusions and brainwashing and not to mention wars and
brainwashing and not to mention wars and
brainwashing and not to mention wars and crashes and
crashes and
crashes and okay
okay
okay now the human dilemma. All right. So
now the human dilemma. All right. So
now the human dilemma. All right. So one's alignment with truth uh one's
one's alignment with truth uh one's
one's alignment with truth uh one's alignment with truth means that at every
alignment with truth means that at every
alignment with truth means that at every intersection you choose that which is
intersection you choose that which is
intersection you choose that which is true and constantly if you constantly
true and constantly if you constantly
true and constantly if you constantly choose that which is true you will end
choose that which is true you will end
choose that which is true you will end up in a completely different dimension
up in a completely different dimension
up in a completely different dimension than people who
than people who
than people who constantly choose what is false
constantly choose what is false
constantly choose what is false and because they end up actually in an
and because they end up actually in an
and because they end up actually in an alternate reality. It is really not the
alternate reality. It is really not the
alternate reality. It is really not the same reality which helps you with
same reality which helps you with
same reality which helps you with judgmentalism because you realize the
judgmentalism because you realize the
judgmentalism because you realize the way you experience the world is not the
way you experience the world is not the
way you experience the world is not the way that person is experiencing it. What
way that person is experiencing it. What
way that person is experiencing it. What seems to you blatant and obvious truth
seems to you blatant and obvious truth
seems to you blatant and obvious truth to them is falsehood.
to them is falsehood.
to them is falsehood. Uh what seems logical and sensible uh
Uh what seems logical and sensible uh
Uh what seems logical and sensible uh doesn't even cross their mind. So it
doesn't even cross their mind. So it
doesn't even cross their mind. So it gives you um you know the lord said to
gives you um you know the lord said to
gives you um you know the lord said to be forgiving towards all and uh to be
be forgiving towards all and uh to be
be forgiving towards all and uh to be forgiving depends on how you see the
forgiving depends on how you see the
forgiving depends on how you see the person. So when you see the person
person. So when you see the person
person. So when you see the person differently then you realize they live
differently then you realize they live
differently then you realize they live in a different sense of reality a
in a different sense of reality a
in a different sense of reality a different world than you do and you
different world than you do and you
different world than you do and you can't judge them by your standards
can't judge them by your standards
can't judge them by your standards because they can't even comprehend your
because they can't even comprehend your
because they can't even comprehend your standards. Huh? They cannot comprehend
standards. Huh? They cannot comprehend
standards. Huh? They cannot comprehend your standards.
your standards.
your standards. So we consider mercy
So we consider mercy
So we consider mercy mercy especially mercif being merciful
mercy especially mercif being merciful
mercy especially mercif being merciful towards the weak and innocent as a
towards the weak and innocent as a
towards the weak and innocent as a virtue. Huh? There's a whole other
virtue. Huh? There's a whole other
virtue. Huh? There's a whole other culture which threatens our own
culture which threatens our own
culture which threatens our own existence actually which sees it exactly
existence actually which sees it exactly
existence actually which sees it exactly the opposite. Contemptable weakness.
the opposite. Contemptable weakness.
the opposite. Contemptable weakness. Contemptable weakness.
Contemptable weakness.
Contemptable weakness. And uh therefore you're deserving of
And uh therefore you're deserving of
And uh therefore you're deserving of death. Yeah.
death. Yeah.
death. Yeah. So your alignment then uh has a very
So your alignment then uh has a very
So your alignment then uh has a very powerful effect on how you experience
powerful effect on how you experience
powerful effect on how you experience the world. What you interpret as truth
the world. What you interpret as truth
the world. What you interpret as truth or valuable all your
or valuable all your
or valuable all your value judgments are coming out of your
value judgments are coming out of your
value judgments are coming out of your alignment.
alignment.
alignment. And out of that alignment we seeking
And out of that alignment we seeking
And out of that alignment we seeking seeking God versus uh materialism.
seeking God versus uh materialism.
seeking God versus uh materialism. The spiritual versus the material.
The spiritual versus the material.
The spiritual versus the material. uh God versus the worship of uh money
uh God versus the worship of uh money
uh God versus the worship of uh money and wealth and uh worldly power,
and wealth and uh worldly power,
and wealth and uh worldly power, worldly power. I don't know what people
worldly power. I don't know what people
worldly power. I don't know what people want worldly power for. It's a seems to
want worldly power for. It's a seems to
want worldly power for. It's a seems to me like a terrible nuisance, but a lot
me like a terrible nuisance, but a lot
me like a terrible nuisance, but a lot of people will do anything to get it. Uh
of people will do anything to get it. Uh
of people will do anything to get it. Uh and uh I mean I think it would be a
and uh I mean I think it would be a
and uh I mean I think it would be a terrible drag.
terrible drag.
terrible drag. So worldly power by many people you know
So worldly power by many people you know
So worldly power by many people you know and uh
and uh
and uh today's liberator is tomorrow's dictator
today's liberator is tomorrow's dictator
today's liberator is tomorrow's dictator as written in italics in my new book
as written in italics in my new book
as written in italics in my new book tomorrow's liberator is tomorrow's dict
tomorrow's liberator is tomorrow's dict
tomorrow's liberator is tomorrow's dict today's liberator is tomorrow's dictator
today's liberator is tomorrow's dictator
today's liberator is tomorrow's dictator you know any cases where that's not true
the whole world today's liberator is
the whole world today's liberator is tomorrow's dictator Yeah.
tomorrow's dictator Yeah.
tomorrow's dictator Yeah. All right.
All right.
All right. Uh, what did I say? Caesar Chavez. No.
Uh, what did I say? Caesar Chavez. No.
Uh, what did I say? Caesar Chavez. No. No.
To me, he's more of a comedian. A
To me, he's more of a comedian. A comedian.
comedian.
comedian. A comedian. I can see our Hollywood
A comedian. I can see our Hollywood
A comedian. I can see our Hollywood luminaries running over to embrace.
luminaries running over to embrace.
luminaries running over to embrace. Embrace him. It's hysterical.
Embrace him. It's hysterical.
Embrace him. It's hysterical. All right. So, on top of all this stack
All right. So, on top of all this stack
All right. So, on top of all this stack of things that you have to deal with in
of things that you have to deal with in
of things that you have to deal with in this house of mirrors, you've got
this house of mirrors, you've got
this house of mirrors, you've got biologic factors and uh hormonal drives
biologic factors and uh hormonal drives
biologic factors and uh hormonal drives driving you crazy. All young men are
driving you crazy. All young men are
driving you crazy. All young men are driven crazy by testosterone,
the instinctual drives.
the instinctual drives. Yeah, testosterone is the seed of
Yeah, testosterone is the seed of
Yeah, testosterone is the seed of madness. And uh it is, you know, it's
madness. And uh it is, you know, it's
madness. And uh it is, you know, it's the curse of being a male is that you're
the curse of being a male is that you're
the curse of being a male is that you're driven by testosterone
driven by testosterone
driven by testosterone which allows you no rest.
Allows you no rest. And uh plus it it
Allows you no rest. And uh plus it it raises the level of uh like an elephant
raises the level of uh like an elephant
raises the level of uh like an elephant and musk. See
and musk. See
and musk. See number males are like elephants and
number males are like elephants and
number males are like elephants and musk. very combative, very uh hostile to
musk. very combative, very uh hostile to
musk. very combative, very uh hostile to each other, very very you know and uh
each other, very very you know and uh
each other, very very you know and uh mounting a female is all the only thing
mounting a female is all the only thing
mounting a female is all the only thing on their mind. You know,
makes your life simple. There's only one
makes your life simple. There's only one thing you're interested in.
It satisfies you at least for an hour,
It satisfies you at least for an hour, maybe couple hours.
maybe couple hours.
maybe couple hours. Yeah. Uhhuh. All right. Sublimation. You
Yeah. Uhhuh. All right. Sublimation. You
Yeah. Uhhuh. All right. Sublimation. You know the Freudian psychology talks about
know the Freudian psychology talks about
know the Freudian psychology talks about the negative uh instincts and negative
the negative uh instincts and negative
the negative uh instincts and negative drives
drives
drives uh to sublimate them instead of acting
uh to sublimate them instead of acting
uh to sublimate them instead of acting them out. So you can take the energy of
them out. So you can take the energy of
them out. So you can take the energy of a lesser drive and put it into
a lesser drive and put it into
a lesser drive and put it into constructive ends uh to overcome evil
constructive ends uh to overcome evil
constructive ends uh to overcome evil for the sake of good.
for the sake of good.
for the sake of good. Uh
sublimation then means you find an
sublimation then means you find an outlet to release some of the pressure
outlet to release some of the pressure
outlet to release some of the pressure of a certain drive. Creativity is one
of a certain drive. Creativity is one
of a certain drive. Creativity is one for instance the instinctual drive. Uh
for instance the instinctual drive. Uh
for instance the instinctual drive. Uh creativity tends to diminish the
creativity tends to diminish the
creativity tends to diminish the preoccupation with it. So sublimation
preoccupation with it. So sublimation
preoccupation with it. So sublimation versus acting out meaning means to
versus acting out meaning means to
versus acting out meaning means to socialize that particular instinctual
socialize that particular instinctual
socialize that particular instinctual drive. Use your anger and your
drive. Use your anger and your
drive. Use your anger and your resentment in a constructive way to like
resentment in a constructive way to like
resentment in a constructive way to like rebuild a better way of doing things.
rebuild a better way of doing things.
rebuild a better way of doing things. Instead of hating this way of solving a
Instead of hating this way of solving a
Instead of hating this way of solving a thing, doing a thing, what you do is you
thing, doing a thing, what you do is you
thing, doing a thing, what you do is you build a better build a better mousetrap.
build a better build a better mousetrap.
build a better build a better mousetrap. Find a better way to do it. Sublimation
Find a better way to do it. Sublimation
Find a better way to do it. Sublimation is a Freudian uh psychotherapy
is a Freudian uh psychotherapy
is a Freudian uh psychotherapy versus acting out. The desire for
versus acting out. The desire for
versus acting out. The desire for control is so endemic and so endemic
control is so endemic and so endemic
control is so endemic and so endemic power over others, dominance, hegman,
power over others, dominance, hegman,
power over others, dominance, hegman, and the whole alpha male syndrome.
and the whole alpha male syndrome.
and the whole alpha male syndrome. There's the famous
There's the famous
There's the famous uh
uh
uh well, we won't even talk about anyway
well, we won't even talk about anyway
well, we won't even talk about anyway uh tries to make let's say you want to
uh tries to make let's say you want to
uh tries to make let's say you want to make America wrong, you can find
make America wrong, you can find
make America wrong, you can find examples of American hegemany. Of
examples of American hegemany. Of
examples of American hegemany. Of course, his doctrine is hegenous because
course, his doctrine is hegenous because
course, his doctrine is hegenous because he's trying to have his doctrine prevail
he's trying to have his doctrine prevail
he's trying to have his doctrine prevail and be dominant over others. You see, so
and be dominant over others. You see, so
and be dominant over others. You see, so the desire for control
the desire for control
the desire for control is in people who put down wanting to
is in people who put down wanting to
is in people who put down wanting to control.
Desire for control, power over others.
Desire for control, power over others. It seems people seem to get a great deal
It seems people seem to get a great deal
It seems people seem to get a great deal out of that.
out of that.
out of that. I've always considered it frankly a
I've always considered it frankly a
I've always considered it frankly a nuisance to control other people because
nuisance to control other people because
nuisance to control other people because then they become your responsibility and
then they become your responsibility and
then they become your responsibility and you got all kinds of karmic liability
you got all kinds of karmic liability
you got all kinds of karmic liability etc. Uh, I just seen everybody drive
etc. Uh, I just seen everybody drive
etc. Uh, I just seen everybody drive their own golf cart, you know,
their own golf cart, you know,
their own golf cart, you know, I don't want to head push them off the
I don't want to head push them off the
I don't want to head push them off the green and get and get one up on them,
green and get and get one up on them,
green and get and get one up on them, you know, desire for control. But you
you know, desire for control. But you
you know, desire for control. But you see how this this is like an obsession
see how this this is like an obsession
see how this this is like an obsession with many people. Uh, and of course in
with many people. Uh, and of course in
with many people. Uh, and of course in marital relationships, who's going to be
marital relationships, who's going to be
marital relationships, who's going to be the one that controls? You know, do we
the one that controls? You know, do we
the one that controls? You know, do we see this movie or that movie? Uh, and
see this movie or that movie? Uh, and
see this movie or that movie? Uh, and people get a sense of power out of that.
people get a sense of power out of that.
people get a sense of power out of that. So it's sort of a narcissistic
So it's sort of a narcissistic
So it's sort of a narcissistic self-indulgence
self-indulgence
self-indulgence to always want to control people in
to always want to control people in
to always want to control people in situations
situations
situations instead of riding with the
instead of riding with the
instead of riding with the but sometimes it's a conflict ethical
but sometimes it's a conflict ethical
but sometimes it's a conflict ethical conflict should one try to take control
conflict should one try to take control
conflict should one try to take control and in your view of it make it better or
and in your view of it make it better or
and in your view of it make it better or just turn it over to God uh you'll find
just turn it over to God uh you'll find
just turn it over to God uh you'll find pragmatically speaking turning it over
pragmatically speaking turning it over
pragmatically speaking turning it over to God it works Well,
what do you call those things? You call
what do you call those things? You call goarounds, you know. And in Sedona,
goarounds, you know. And in Sedona,
goarounds, you know. And in Sedona, there's a big discussion now about
there's a big discussion now about
there's a big discussion now about putting in goarounds instead of
putting in goarounds instead of
putting in goarounds instead of roundabouts. Yeah, roundabouts. Yeah, I
roundabouts. Yeah, roundabouts. Yeah, I
roundabouts. Yeah, roundabouts. Yeah, I think roundabouts are fun. But, uh, if
think roundabouts are fun. But, uh, if
think roundabouts are fun. But, uh, if you get lost, you just keep going around
you get lost, you just keep going around
you get lost, you just keep going around it.
it.
it. I think I was in Paris and the
I think I was in Paris and the
I think I was in Paris and the in Paris and there was a subway strike
in Paris and there was a subway strike
in Paris and there was a subway strike and so there's a goaround a huge one
and so there's a goaround a huge one
and so there's a goaround a huge one that's about six lanes wide and I kept
that's about six lanes wide and I kept
that's about six lanes wide and I kept going I couldn't get off and I was in
going I couldn't get off and I was in
going I couldn't get off and I was in the mi middle and I was trying to get
the mi middle and I was trying to get
the mi middle and I was trying to get over one lane about the third time
over one lane about the third time
over one lane about the third time around this big goaround. I forgot where
around this big goaround. I forgot where
around this big goaround. I forgot where it is there. Anyway, I finally got over
it is there. Anyway, I finally got over
it is there. Anyway, I finally got over one lane. I think it took me 10 10 times
one lane. I think it took me 10 10 times
one lane. I think it took me 10 10 times around the thing by I finally got to an
around the thing by I finally got to an
around the thing by I finally got to an outside one and I could get off.
Let me out of here. The go around go
Let me out of here. The go around go around. That was funny. I love the way
around. That was funny. I love the way
around. That was funny. I love the way people drive in South America. You know,
people drive in South America. You know,
people drive in South America. You know, South America is hysterical. There'll be
South America is hysterical. There'll be
South America is hysterical. There'll be a six lane, you know, down in the the
a six lane, you know, down in the the
a six lane, you know, down in the the tip of Argentina. What's the name?
tip of Argentina. What's the name?
tip of Argentina. What's the name? Bonus. Anyway, it's like Paris and
Bonus. Anyway, it's like Paris and
Bonus. Anyway, it's like Paris and there's this huge boulevard, huge
there's this huge boulevard, huge
there's this huge boulevard, huge fountain. It's gorgeous. Then about six
fountain. It's gorgeous. Then about six
fountain. It's gorgeous. Then about six or eight lanes wide on both sides of the
or eight lanes wide on both sides of the
or eight lanes wide on both sides of the boulevard. See? And people drive like a
boulevard. See? And people drive like a
boulevard. See? And people drive like a mad fiend. There's no arterial stops. So
mad fiend. There's no arterial stops. So
mad fiend. There's no arterial stops. So at every every intersection is who's
at every every intersection is who's
at every every intersection is who's going to who's going to get through
going to who's going to get through
going to who's going to get through first. And when people drive there, they
first. And when people drive there, they
first. And when people drive there, they try drive real tight in these little
try drive real tight in these little
try drive real tight in these little cars
cars
cars and then they one arm goes out the
and then they one arm goes out the
and then they one arm goes out the window like this. It goes like this.
window like this. It goes like this.
window like this. It goes like this. So you see all these cars, all these
So you see all these cars, all these
So you see all these cars, all these arms are out there and they're just
arms are out there and they're just
arms are out there and they're just packed real tight. These little buzzy
packed real tight. These little buzzy
packed real tight. These little buzzy cars.
Hardly any clearance between the cars
Hardly any clearance between the cars and no arterial stops. It's really fun.
and no arterial stops. It's really fun.
and no arterial stops. It's really fun. It is. It's a brinks up all your
It is. It's a brinks up all your
It is. It's a brinks up all your adrenaline.
Now the herd instinct is how is the end
Now the herd instinct is how is the end of the super ego. The superego is one's
of the super ego. The superego is one's
of the super ego. The superego is one's conscience
conscience
conscience and one's conscience is soluble within a
and one's conscience is soluble within a
and one's conscience is soluble within a crowd. The lynch mob, one or two guys on
crowd. The lynch mob, one or two guys on
crowd. The lynch mob, one or two guys on their own can't do it. But if a dozen
their own can't do it. But if a dozen
their own can't do it. But if a dozen guys join you now, it's okay.
guys join you now, it's okay.
guys join you now, it's okay. You know, Hitler's proposition in Europe
You know, Hitler's proposition in Europe
You know, Hitler's proposition in Europe would have been rejected as totally
would have been rejected as totally
would have been rejected as totally outrageous by a few people. But when you
outrageous by a few people. But when you
outrageous by a few people. But when you get a whole crowd sle
now you can bomb Britain you can do all
now you can bomb Britain you can do all kinds of things invade foreign countries
kinds of things invade foreign countries
kinds of things invade foreign countries and it's perfectly okay it's perfectly
and it's perfectly okay it's perfectly
and it's perfectly okay it's perfectly okay if the whole mob does it so
okay if the whole mob does it so
okay if the whole mob does it so the herd instinct then is how large
the herd instinct then is how large
the herd instinct then is how large segments of society
segments of society
segments of society shift 180 degrees and when you look at
shift 180 degrees and when you look at
shift 180 degrees and when you look at the history of the development of some
the history of the development of some
the history of the development of some civilizations you see I I can't believe
civilizations you see I I can't believe
civilizations you see I I can't believe I can't believe they could have done a
I can't believe they could have done a
I can't believe they could have done a 180 on that. They did a 180 because
180 on that. They did a 180 because
180 on that. They did a 180 because under propaganda and a and a charismatic
under propaganda and a and a charismatic
under propaganda and a and a charismatic leader uh the herd instinct takes overh
leader uh the herd instinct takes overh
leader uh the herd instinct takes overh and people will perpetrate
and people will perpetrate
and people will perpetrate extremely horrible acts if everybody's
extremely horrible acts if everybody's
extremely horrible acts if everybody's doing it. Uhhuh.
doing it. Uhhuh.
doing it. Uhhuh. Uh on top of all this, we have a desire
Uh on top of all this, we have a desire
Uh on top of all this, we have a desire for acceptance and approval from others.
for acceptance and approval from others.
for acceptance and approval from others. uh we everybody has to agree with us.
uh we everybody has to agree with us.
uh we everybody has to agree with us. That of course is a narcissistic
That of course is a narcissistic
That of course is a narcissistic orientation.
orientation.
orientation. Uh desire for approval.
Uh desire for approval.
Uh desire for approval. Um
Um
Um you reach a point where you really have
you reach a point where you really have
you reach a point where you really have no interest in whether people approve
no interest in whether people approve
no interest in whether people approve you or not. Uh it's just part of your
you or not. Uh it's just part of your
you or not. Uh it's just part of your information. You know uh whether
information. You know uh whether
information. You know uh whether something is being accepted or approved
something is being accepted or approved
something is being accepted or approved of but it's of no personal.
of but it's of no personal.
of but it's of no personal. Why is that? Because as you evolve
Why is that? Because as you evolve
Why is that? Because as you evolve spiritually,
spiritually,
spiritually, you don't need any progressively less
you don't need any progressively less
you don't need any progressively less and less to the final you don't need
and less to the final you don't need
and less to the final you don't need anything.
anything.
anything. Uh what do you want? Uh at a certain
Uh what do you want? Uh at a certain
Uh what do you want? Uh at a certain level of consciousness, you don't want
level of consciousness, you don't want
level of consciousness, you don't want anything.
anything.
anything. Don't you want to keep on breathing in
Don't you want to keep on breathing in
Don't you want to keep on breathing in and out?
and out?
and out? Well, I don't know that I really care
Well, I don't know that I really care
Well, I don't know that I really care about it that much. It either happens or
about it that much. It either happens or
about it that much. It either happens or it doesn't happen. What's the problem?
it doesn't happen. What's the problem?
it doesn't happen. What's the problem? So letting go of people's desire for
So letting go of people's desire for
So letting go of people's desire for approval means that you're less
approval means that you're less
approval means that you're less controllable because people want to
controllable because people want to
controllable because people want to control you with their approval or their
control you with their approval or their
control you with their approval or their disapproval
disapproval
disapproval and u desire for acceptance and approval
and u desire for acceptance and approval
and u desire for acceptance and approval you know runs a great many people all
you know runs a great many people all
you know runs a great many people all the time. All they're looking for is
the time. All they're looking for is
the time. All they're looking for is approval from somebody out there.
approval from somebody out there.
approval from somebody out there. uh
uh
uh to counteract that there's a capacity
to counteract that there's a capacity
to counteract that there's a capacity for gratitude and thankfulness
for gratitude and thankfulness
for gratitude and thankfulness and I've mentioned that before in
and I've mentioned that before in
and I've mentioned that before in lectures uh if you just thank a clerk,
lectures uh if you just thank a clerk,
lectures uh if you just thank a clerk, thank anybody, a workman who comes to
thank anybody, a workman who comes to
thank anybody, a workman who comes to your house, whatever, uh and tell them
your house, whatever, uh and tell them
your house, whatever, uh and tell them what a great job it was and how much you
what a great job it was and how much you
what a great job it was and how much you appreciate it and and give them a heart,
appreciate it and and give them a heart,
appreciate it and and give them a heart, a a genuine, not a fake thank, a real
a a genuine, not a fake thank, a real
a a genuine, not a fake thank, a real thank you. people drop their teeth, they
thank you. people drop their teeth, they
thank you. people drop their teeth, they go bl
Yeah. Yeah. So, just thanking people.
Yeah. Yeah. So, just thanking people. So, that's just sort of like turning
So, that's just sort of like turning
So, that's just sort of like turning over black beetles so they can walk on
over black beetles so they can walk on
over black beetles so they can walk on their feet. Uh thanking people and
their feet. Uh thanking people and
their feet. Uh thanking people and having a gracious attitudes. So we could
having a gracious attitudes. So we could
having a gracious attitudes. So we could uh contextualize this whole social um
uh contextualize this whole social um
uh contextualize this whole social um millu this whole way of relating to
millu this whole way of relating to
millu this whole way of relating to society
society
society uh
uh
uh as grace graciousness.
as grace graciousness.
as grace graciousness. All right. So the shortcut then to
All right. So the shortcut then to
All right. So the shortcut then to spiritual reality
spiritual reality
spiritual reality is to develop the habit of being
is to develop the habit of being
is to develop the habit of being gracious towards all of life in all of
gracious towards all of life in all of
gracious towards all of life in all of its expressions all the time.
person slams their brake on
person slams their brake on and you rear end them,
and you rear end them,
and you rear end them, what should happen next?
What What would you do next?
What What would you do next? I apologize. I say, "I'm sorry this
I apologize. I say, "I'm sorry this
I apologize. I say, "I'm sorry this happened." I mean,
happened." I mean,
happened." I mean, uh, first person, the average person
uh, first person, the average person
uh, first person, the average person would say, "Well, was your fault
would say, "Well, was your fault
would say, "Well, was your fault standing on the bricks or something,
standing on the bricks or something,
standing on the bricks or something, bitching, I'm suing you, too. God damn
bitching, I'm suing you, too. God damn
bitching, I'm suing you, too. God damn it."
it instantly turn him into an enemy.
it instantly turn him into an enemy. It's true. He slammed his brakes on,
It's true. He slammed his brakes on,
It's true. He slammed his brakes on, gave you no warning. And uh however,
gave you no warning. And uh however,
gave you no warning. And uh however, what you do is you apologize for the
what you do is you apologize for the
what you do is you apologize for the awkwardness of the situation. For the
awkwardness of the situation. For the
awkwardness of the situation. For the awkwardness, so you don't have to demean
awkwardness, so you don't have to demean
awkwardness, so you don't have to demean yourself by, you know, grace doesn't
yourself by, you know, grace doesn't
yourself by, you know, grace doesn't mean to demean yourself and become a a
mean to demean yourself and become a a
mean to demean yourself and become a a lick spittle. It really means, you know,
lick spittle. It really means, you know,
lick spittle. It really means, you know, to apologize for the inevitabilities of
to apologize for the inevitabilities of
to apologize for the inevitabilities of life. You can only drive so many miles
life. You can only drive so many miles
life. You can only drive so many miles when an addended fender is likely to
when an addended fender is likely to
when an addended fender is likely to surface on the horizon.
surface on the horizon.
surface on the horizon. So what you do is you tell the person uh
So what you do is you tell the person uh
So what you do is you tell the person uh who backs into you, you know, in the
who backs into you, you know, in the
who backs into you, you know, in the parking lot denture, you tell them,
parking lot denture, you tell them,
parking lot denture, you tell them, "Look, don't get upset about it. You got
"Look, don't get upset about it. You got
"Look, don't get upset about it. You got insurance. I got insurance. Let's not
insurance. I got insurance. Let's not
insurance. I got insurance. Let's not blow the whole afternoon." Yeah. I'm
blow the whole afternoon." Yeah. I'm
blow the whole afternoon." Yeah. I'm sorry it happened. that instantly cools
sorry it happened. that instantly cools
sorry it happened. that instantly cools down the other person. And
down the other person. And
down the other person. And so being graceful towards life in all of
so being graceful towards life in all of
so being graceful towards life in all of its expressions and uh people have the
its expressions and uh people have the
its expressions and uh people have the right to be wrong.
right to be wrong.
right to be wrong. They should be killed for it, but I mean
They should be killed for it, but I mean
They should be killed for it, but I mean they have the right to be wrong.
they have the right to be wrong.
they have the right to be wrong. So being gracious towards life means
So being gracious towards life means
So being gracious towards life means people have different differing opinions
people have different differing opinions
people have different differing opinions about things and you don't have to get
about things and you don't have to get
about things and you don't have to get up in arms uh over every insult. Uh, you
up in arms uh over every insult. Uh, you
up in arms uh over every insult. Uh, you get used to insults. After a while, you
get used to insults. After a while, you
get used to insults. After a while, you find insults are very amusing.
find insults are very amusing.
find insults are very amusing. And there have been insulting blogs
And there have been insulting blogs
And there have been insulting blogs written about me. And, you know, I think
written about me. And, you know, I think
written about me. And, you know, I think they're hysterically funny. The person
they're hysterically funny. The person
they're hysterically funny. The person who wrote them seems a little
who wrote them seems a little
who wrote them seems a little But apparently,
if they think that's funny, I'd say,
if they think that's funny, I'd say, "You got with an IQ of what? 80. That's
"You got with an IQ of what? 80. That's
"You got with an IQ of what? 80. That's funny." Yeah. An IQ over 100. You
funny." Yeah. An IQ over 100. You
funny." Yeah. An IQ over 100. You wouldn't think it's funny. All right.
wouldn't think it's funny. All right.
wouldn't think it's funny. All right. The capacity for gratitude and
The capacity for gratitude and
The capacity for gratitude and thankfulness. You can say, "Thank God
thankfulness. You can say, "Thank God
thankfulness. You can say, "Thank God it's only a dented fender." "Thank God
it's only a dented fender." "Thank God
it's only a dented fender." "Thank God it's only a dented fender. We're both
it's only a dented fender. We're both
it's only a dented fender. We're both okay. We're both alive. Neither one of
okay. We're both alive. Neither one of
okay. We're both alive. Neither one of us got injured." Yeah. So, you're always
us got injured." Yeah. So, you're always
us got injured." Yeah. So, you're always choosing the high road. You're always
choosing the high road. You're always
choosing the high road. You're always choosing mercy instead of revenge. Of
choosing mercy instead of revenge. Of
choosing mercy instead of revenge. Of course, you could get mad at the guy and
course, you could get mad at the guy and
course, you could get mad at the guy and give him a good poke in the jaw and
give him a good poke in the jaw and
give him a good poke in the jaw and justify that he deserved it. Son of a
justify that he deserved it. Son of a
justify that he deserved it. Son of a Put his damn lights on and I
Put his damn lights on and I
Put his damn lights on and I smacked into him. Idiot. When he gets
smacked into him. Idiot. When he gets
smacked into him. Idiot. When he gets out of the car, you give him a punch in
out of the car, you give him a punch in
out of the car, you give him a punch in the mouth.
That's one way of living. I'm not
That's one way of living. I'm not putting it down. I'm not saying there's
putting it down. I'm not saying there's
putting it down. I'm not saying there's anything wrong with it.
But the value of human life is such that
But the value of human life is such that uh you value the other person's life as
uh you value the other person's life as
uh you value the other person's life as well as your own. So when you value life
well as your own. So when you value life
well as your own. So when you value life itself, then its various expressions are
itself, then its various expressions are
itself, then its various expressions are acceptable. You know that
acceptable. You know that
acceptable. You know that you know that civilizations rise and
you know that civilizations rise and
you know that civilizations rise and fall. Right now, Western civilization is
fall. Right now, Western civilization is
fall. Right now, Western civilization is in a freef fall. The consciousness level
in a freef fall. The consciousness level
in a freef fall. The consciousness level of America is in freef fall. And it's
of America is in freef fall. And it's
of America is in freef fall. And it's okay with you because over history,
okay with you because over history,
okay with you because over history, great civilizations have risen and then
great civilizations have risen and then
great civilizations have risen and then they've declined and they've risen and
they've declined and they've risen and
they've declined and they've risen and they've declined. So, right now, we're
they've declined. So, right now, we're
they've declined. So, right now, we're in a decline
in a decline
in a decline uh and uh in freef fall. So we say well
uh and uh in freef fall. So we say well
uh and uh in freef fall. So we say well uh that's the way it's been since the
uh that's the way it's been since the
uh that's the way it's been since the beginning of time you know great Britain
beginning of time you know great Britain
beginning of time you know great Britain in the early days and
in the early days and
in the early days and the era of the of Rome and and uh Greece
the era of the of Rome and and uh Greece
the era of the of Rome and and uh Greece and all the great uh great civilizations
and all the great uh great civilizations
and all the great uh great civilizations have risen and they've also fallen. So
have risen and they've also fallen. So
have risen and they've also fallen. So with acceptance then with acceptance you
with acceptance then with acceptance you
with acceptance then with acceptance you accept that all such things tend to
accept that all such things tend to
accept that all such things tend to fluctuate.
fluctuate.
fluctuate. Uh do we know why? Yeah. No, not necess
Uh do we know why? Yeah. No, not necess
Uh do we know why? Yeah. No, not necess I don't think you know why. I I don't
I don't think you know why. I I don't
I don't think you know why. I I don't know why. All I know is that the waves
know why. All I know is that the waves
know why. All I know is that the waves tend to come and go. And while we
tend to come and go. And while we
tend to come and go. And while we thought it was going to
thought it was going to
thought it was going to a number of years ago, I thought the
a number of years ago, I thought the
a number of years ago, I thought the consciousness level of mankind is just
consciousness level of mankind is just
consciousness level of mankind is just going to keep going right up through the
going to keep going right up through the
going to keep going right up through the ceiling and then whoops all of a sudden
ceiling and then whoops all of a sudden
ceiling and then whoops all of a sudden it turned down again.
it turned down again.
it turned down again. Went down again. Yeah. Maybe the air
Went down again. Yeah. Maybe the air
Went down again. Yeah. Maybe the air gets too rarified. People can't handle
gets too rarified. People can't handle
gets too rarified. People can't handle it or something. All right. capacity for
it or something. All right. capacity for
it or something. All right. capacity for gratitude and thankfulness and choosing
gratitude and thankfulness and choosing
gratitude and thankfulness and choosing to be merciful instead of revenge.
to be merciful instead of revenge.
to be merciful instead of revenge. Choosing to be merciful.
Choosing to be merciful.
Choosing to be merciful. We do this because we value all of human
We do this because we value all of human
We do this because we value all of human life in all its all of its expressions.
life in all its all of its expressions.
life in all its all of its expressions. And we are very aware that we are mortal
And we are very aware that we are mortal
And we are very aware that we are mortal and limited. The awareness that we're
and limited. The awareness that we're
and limited. The awareness that we're mortal and limited. Mortal. Mortal means
mortal and limited. Mortal. Mortal means
mortal and limited. Mortal. Mortal means that the the days they are numbered for
that the the days they are numbered for
that the the days they are numbered for the survival of the physicality, the
the survival of the physicality, the
the survival of the physicality, the body itself. From the dust we arise and
body itself. From the dust we arise and
body itself. From the dust we arise and from dust we return. From dust we arise
from dust we return. From dust we arise
from dust we return. From dust we arise and from dust we return. So the earlier
and from dust we return. So the earlier
and from dust we return. So the earlier we accept the inevitability of
we accept the inevitability of
we accept the inevitability of mortality,
mortality,
mortality, the less our overall level of anxiety
the less our overall level of anxiety
the less our overall level of anxiety because all fears and anxieties are
because all fears and anxieties are
because all fears and anxieties are basically the fear of death. If you take
basically the fear of death. If you take
basically the fear of death. If you take any track if nobody likes me then what
any track if nobody likes me then what
any track if nobody likes me then what then I'll be abandoned what then I won't
then I'll be abandoned what then I won't
then I'll be abandoned what then I won't have a job then I won't have any
have a job then I won't have any
have a job then I won't have any companionship
companionship
companionship and it if you keep following every and
and it if you keep following every and
and it if you keep following every and then what and then what and then what
then what and then what and then what
then what and then what and then what under every fear you'll end up uh fear
under every fear you'll end up uh fear
under every fear you'll end up uh fear of death and then what and then I'll be
of death and then what and then I'll be
of death and then what and then I'll be friendless and then I won't have a job
friendless and then I won't have a job
friendless and then I won't have a job and then I'll be poor
and then I'll be poor
and then I'll be poor etc. So if you picture the worst
etc. So if you picture the worst
etc. So if you picture the worst possible scenario
possible scenario
possible scenario and accept the worst possible scenario,
and accept the worst possible scenario,
and accept the worst possible scenario, then up will come the next worst
then up will come the next worst
then up will come the next worst possible scenario. And then when you get
possible scenario. And then when you get
possible scenario. And then when you get to the very bottom of it is death
to the very bottom of it is death
to the very bottom of it is death itself. So the way to undo any fear is
itself. So the way to undo any fear is
itself. So the way to undo any fear is to just keep letting go. Yeah. Keep
to just keep letting go. Yeah. Keep
to just keep letting go. Yeah. Keep letting go and then what?
letting go and then what?
letting go and then what? Then and then they'll put me away.
Then and then they'll put me away.
Then and then they'll put me away. Uhhuh. And then what? And then I'll be
Uhhuh. And then what? And then I'll be
Uhhuh. And then what? And then I'll be lonely. And then what? And then I'll go
lonely. And then what? And then I'll go
lonely. And then what? And then I'll go into despair. And then what? And then
into despair. And then what? And then
into despair. And then what? And then I'll stop eating. And then what? Then
I'll stop eating. And then what? Then
I'll stop eating. And then what? Then they'll force feed me. And then what?
they'll force feed me. And then what?
they'll force feed me. And then what? Then I'll kill myself.
At the bottom of every stack of fear
At the bottom of every stack of fear is And then what? So you keep going. So
is And then what? So you keep going. So
is And then what? So you keep going. So anybody here stuck with a stack of fear?
anybody here stuck with a stack of fear?
anybody here stuck with a stack of fear? Anybody still got a big stack? You work
Anybody still got a big stack? You work
Anybody still got a big stack? You work You work through a big stack. All right.
You work through a big stack. All right.
You work through a big stack. All right. You start from the top of the stack and
You start from the top of the stack and
You start from the top of the stack and you say, "And then what?" And then you
you say, "And then what?" And then you
you say, "And then what?" And then you recontextualize the and then what? And
recontextualize the and then what? And
recontextualize the and then what? And so you don't mind. So your hair got all
so you don't mind. So your hair got all
so you don't mind. So your hair got all frizzled and you're ugly. That's true.
frizzled and you're ugly. That's true.
frizzled and you're ugly. That's true. Then what? Then I'll wear a hat and
Then what? Then I'll wear a hat and
Then what? Then I'll wear a hat and nobody will notice it. And then what?
nobody will notice it. And then what?
nobody will notice it. And then what? Then they'll think it's funny I'm
Then they'll think it's funny I'm
Then they'll think it's funny I'm wearing a hat at the party. And then
wearing a hat at the party. And then
wearing a hat at the party. And then what? And then they
what? And then they
what? And then they will socially reject me. And then And
will socially reject me. And then And
will socially reject me. And then And what? And then then what? And then they
what? And then then what? And then they
what? And then then what? And then they won't invite me to any more parties. And
won't invite me to any more parties. And
won't invite me to any more parties. And then what? Then I won't have any
then what? Then I won't have any
then what? Then I won't have any friends. And then what? So you keep
friends. And then what? So you keep
friends. And then what? So you keep going down the and then what and finally
going down the and then what and finally
going down the and then what and finally undo a deep stack and all stacks on fear
undo a deep stack and all stacks on fear
undo a deep stack and all stacks on fear end up at the bottom. If you keep
end up at the bottom. If you keep
end up at the bottom. If you keep working on the stack uh that you'll be
working on the stack uh that you'll be
working on the stack uh that you'll be uh unacceptable, you become a pariah
uh unacceptable, you become a pariah
uh unacceptable, you become a pariah and eventually you'll be left all alone
and eventually you'll be left all alone
and eventually you'll be left all alone to starve
to starve
to starve and nobody will care about you because
and nobody will care about you because
and nobody will care about you because you're not lovable and therefore you're
you're not lovable and therefore you're
you're not lovable and therefore you're going to end up dead. Dead.
going to end up dead. Dead.
going to end up dead. Dead. So
So
So the way to save yourself a lot of
the way to save yourself a lot of
the way to save yourself a lot of anxiety and a lot of working through
anxiety and a lot of working through
anxiety and a lot of working through negative feelings is to accept that work
negative feelings is to accept that work
negative feelings is to accept that work your way down the stack and accept that
your way down the stack and accept that
your way down the stack and accept that now. As you accept that now the rest of
now. As you accept that now the rest of
now. As you accept that now the rest of the fears
the fears
the fears diminish or disappear altogether. Yeah.
diminish or disappear altogether. Yeah.
diminish or disappear altogether. Yeah. Yeah. What'll happen if we have an
Yeah. What'll happen if we have an
Yeah. What'll happen if we have an atomic war? What will happen if we have
atomic war? What will happen if we have
atomic war? What will happen if we have an atomic war? Well, then maybe you'll
an atomic war? Well, then maybe you'll
an atomic war? Well, then maybe you'll die.
and then then this lifetime will come to
and then then this lifetime will come to an end. This physicality will come to an
an end. This physicality will come to an
an end. This physicality will come to an end. Life will not come to an end. Life
end. Life will not come to an end. Life
end. Life will not come to an end. Life will not come to an end. And this
will not come to an end. And this
will not come to an end. And this physicality will come to an end. And all
physicality will come to an end. And all
physicality will come to an end. And all right. So
right. So
right. So that opens the door for a new life which
that opens the door for a new life which
that opens the door for a new life which is probably going to be better than this
is probably going to be better than this
is probably going to be better than this one anyway. So, the sooner you get rid
one anyway. So, the sooner you get rid
one anyway. So, the sooner you get rid of this one, better you get on with a
of this one, better you get on with a
of this one, better you get on with a better one.
better one.
better one. Maybe you'll come back rich and
Maybe you'll come back rich and
Maybe you'll come back rich and good-looking.
The acceptance of mortality and
The acceptance of mortality and limitation. Uh, death's door.
limitation. Uh, death's door.
limitation. Uh, death's door. Well, this uh I've told you about my own
Well, this uh I've told you about my own
Well, this uh I've told you about my own inner experiences
inner experiences
inner experiences of letting go and surrendering
of letting go and surrendering
of letting go and surrendering everything
everything
everything until I came to there was nothing left.
until I came to there was nothing left.
until I came to there was nothing left. Nothing left to surrender to God.
Nothing left to surrender to God.
Nothing left to surrender to God. Nothing.
Nothing.
Nothing. not nothing and everything was silent.
not nothing and everything was silent.
not nothing and everything was silent. And then came the awareness
And then came the awareness
And then came the awareness out of nowhere.
I had not surrendered my life to God.
I had not surrendered my life to God. I'd surrendered everything else but not
I'd surrendered everything else but not
I'd surrendered everything else but not life.
life.
life. And then came the knowingness. This too
And then came the knowingness. This too
And then came the knowingness. This too must be surrendered to the ill lord. I'd
must be surrendered to the ill lord. I'd
must be surrendered to the ill lord. I'd surrendered joy, ecstasy,
surrendered joy, ecstasy,
surrendered joy, ecstasy, peace, serenity, all kinds of things to
peace, serenity, all kinds of things to
peace, serenity, all kinds of things to the the Lord.
the the Lord.
the the Lord. All was gone and all was silent. Was in
All was gone and all was silent. Was in
All was gone and all was silent. Was in a very high space. There was no one
a very high space. There was no one
a very high space. There was no one there. No other entities. No other
there. No other entities. No other
there. No other entities. No other entities.
entities.
entities. In the highest spaces, there are no
In the highest spaces, there are no
In the highest spaces, there are no other entities talking to you or giving
other entities talking to you or giving
other entities talking to you or giving you instructions or giving you
you instructions or giving you
you instructions or giving you dictations.
dictations.
dictations. Yeah. Nothing. But uh the knowingness
Yeah. Nothing. But uh the knowingness
Yeah. Nothing. But uh the knowingness that came out of nowhere came out of the
that came out of nowhere came out of the
that came out of nowhere came out of the frequency and the vibration of some
frequency and the vibration of some
frequency and the vibration of some great guru in past lifetimes. The
great guru in past lifetimes. The
great guru in past lifetimes. The knowingness that that which I am is
knowingness that that which I am is
knowingness that that which I am is beyond life and death
beyond life and death
beyond life and death and the clinging to life was the last
and the clinging to life was the last
and the clinging to life was the last thing.
thing.
thing. Oh wow. And
Oh wow. And
Oh wow. And uh
uh
uh so the tenacity of hanging on to life I
so the tenacity of hanging on to life I
so the tenacity of hanging on to life I surrendered life.
surrendered life.
surrendered life. All fear is illusion. Came the
All fear is illusion. Came the
All fear is illusion. Came the knowingness. All fear is illusion.
knowingness. All fear is illusion.
knowingness. All fear is illusion. Absolutely.
Absolutely.
Absolutely. All right. So the voice of the teacher
All right. So the voice of the teacher
All right. So the voice of the teacher that radiates forth from the aura
that radiates forth from the aura
that radiates forth from the aura has to be has to come from absolutism.
has to be has to come from absolutism.
has to be has to come from absolutism. cannot come from relativism or
cannot come from relativism or
cannot come from relativism or thinkingisism.
thinkingisism.
thinkingisism. It has to come from the ab absolutism of
It has to come from the ab absolutism of
It has to come from the ab absolutism of absolute knowingness of having been
absolute knowingness of having been
absolute knowingness of having been there and done that. So the absolutism
there and done that. So the absolutism
there and done that. So the absolutism of the knowingness that it was that this
of the knowingness that it was that this
of the knowingness that it was that this too I would surrender to thee oh lord I
too I would surrender to thee oh lord I
too I would surrender to thee oh lord I surrendered life itself. life itself.
surrendered life itself. life itself.
surrendered life itself. life itself. No one has ever you never surrender life
No one has ever you never surrender life
No one has ever you never surrender life lifetime after lifetime you don't
lifetime after lifetime you don't
lifetime after lifetime you don't surrender the source of life itself
surrender the source of life itself
surrender the source of life itself because this is the very core the very
because this is the very core the very
because this is the very core the very core of the narcissistic core of the ego
core of the narcissistic core of the ego
core of the narcissistic core of the ego that thinks it is the author of life the
that thinks it is the author of life the
that thinks it is the author of life the center and the core of life. So in
center and the core of life. So in
center and the core of life. So in surrendering what the mind has believed
surrendering what the mind has believed
surrendering what the mind has believed for eons of time, up came a great
for eons of time, up came a great
for eons of time, up came a great terror. Up came a great terror,
terror. Up came a great terror,
terror. Up came a great terror, a severe terror.
a severe terror.
a severe terror. And fortunately, it only lasted for a
And fortunately, it only lasted for a
And fortunately, it only lasted for a few moments, but it was a great terror.
few moments, but it was a great terror.
few moments, but it was a great terror. So I tell you now, number one, it's
So I tell you now, number one, it's
So I tell you now, number one, it's safe. Number two, then up will come a
safe. Number two, then up will come a
safe. Number two, then up will come a great terror.
great terror.
great terror. And surrender to the terror. And then
And surrender to the terror. And then
And surrender to the terror. And then the terror disappeared and
the fear gone forever. Oh, the fear
the fear gone forever. Oh, the fear which had been there forever was now
which had been there forever was now
which had been there forever was now gone forever. Yeah.
gone forever. Yeah.
gone forever. Yeah. So the mortality then is first the
So the mortality then is first the
So the mortality then is first the immortality of the physicality this
immortality of the physicality this
immortality of the physicality this particular incarnation. See
particular incarnation. See
particular incarnation. See and eventually as you keep letting go of
and eventually as you keep letting go of
and eventually as you keep letting go of things the fears all disappear.
things the fears all disappear.
things the fears all disappear. Yeah. And so whatever happens to you is
Yeah. And so whatever happens to you is
Yeah. And so whatever happens to you is irrelevant. You know why is it
irrelevant. You know why is it
irrelevant. You know why is it irrelevant? Because it's God's problem.
If the ceiling falls on us all now, it's
If the ceiling falls on us all now, it's God's problem, isn't it? We're just
God's problem, isn't it? We're just
God's problem, isn't it? We're just going to just sit and wait and see what
going to just sit and wait and see what
going to just sit and wait and see what God's going to do about it. You know,
God's going to do about it. You know,
God's going to do about it. You know, maybe you'll get a truck or a der or
maybe you'll get a truck or a der or
maybe you'll get a truck or a der or ambulances. Maybe you won't. You know,
ambulances. Maybe you won't. You know,
ambulances. Maybe you won't. You know, maybe you'll breathe, maybe you won't.
maybe you'll breathe, maybe you won't.
maybe you'll breathe, maybe you won't. Maybe they'll give you a tank of oxygen.
Maybe they'll give you a tank of oxygen.
Maybe they'll give you a tank of oxygen. Maybe they'll say he looks like he's a
Maybe they'll say he looks like he's a
Maybe they'll say he looks like he's a goner.
goner.
goner. You hear the people say he's a corner.
You hear the people say he's a corner.
You hear the people say he's a corner. Don't bother with him.
He's a corner. Don't bother with him.
He's a corner. Don't bother with him. But
You got a karmic blue cross card. Let's
You got a karmic blue cross card. Let's see your card.
see your card.
see your card. Okay, you got a few more breasts. Yeah,
Okay, you got a few more breasts. Yeah,
Okay, you got a few more breasts. Yeah, he's got a few more breaths left on his
he's got a few more breaths left on his
he's got a few more breaths left on his blue card. Okay, give him a little
blue card. Okay, give him a little
blue card. Okay, give him a little oxygen.
oxygen.
oxygen. Okay, what happens then? You got to come
Okay, what happens then? You got to come
Okay, what happens then? You got to come back to this this particular life again.
back to this this particular life again.
back to this this particular life again. Okay. So the acceptance then of
Okay. So the acceptance then of
Okay. So the acceptance then of mortality as an inevitability and
mortality as an inevitability and
mortality as an inevitability and getting over the fear of it the earlier
getting over the fear of it the earlier
getting over the fear of it the earlier in life we start and it is only a matter
in life we start and it is only a matter
in life we start and it is only a matter of acceptance as I pointed out I you
of acceptance as I pointed out I you
of acceptance as I pointed out I you know about to get blown sky high with
know about to get blown sky high with
know about to get blown sky high with the mind and and frankly was uh you know
the mind and and frankly was uh you know
the mind and and frankly was uh you know I said to him so he died he says yeah
I said to him so he died he says yeah
I said to him so he died he says yeah right so he died what was the big deal
right so he died what was the big deal
right so he died what was the big deal so the fear of death is what makes this
so the fear of death is what makes this
so the fear of death is what makes this seem awful is because you're struggling
seem awful is because you're struggling
seem awful is because you're struggling with
with
with Once you accept it, it's not awful at
Once you accept it, it's not awful at
Once you accept it, it's not awful at all. So you blow up. So what? So you
all. So you blow up. So what? So you
all. So you blow up. So what? So you blow up. Big deal.
You got it. It's okay. If we all blew up
You got it. It's okay. If we all blew up right now, what's the big deal?
right now, what's the big deal?
right now, what's the big deal? We all go together.
One reason people have a fear of dying
One reason people have a fear of dying is because of moral accountability.
is because of moral accountability.
is because of moral accountability. Uhoh.
Uhoh.
Uhoh. Uhoh. The reason they don't want to die
Uhoh. The reason they don't want to die
Uhoh. The reason they don't want to die is because they know they're going to be
is because they know they're going to be
is because they know they're going to be faced with a moral accountability.
faced with a moral accountability.
faced with a moral accountability. One's angel
One's angel
One's angel takes a moral inventory with you
takes a moral inventory with you
takes a moral inventory with you in which you get a chance to look at
in which you get a chance to look at
in which you get a chance to look at yourself. Yeah.
yourself. Yeah.
yourself. Yeah. And uh the whole whole life runs before
And uh the whole whole life runs before
And uh the whole whole life runs before you. Whole life runs before you at the
you. Whole life runs before you at the
you. Whole life runs before you at the last moment. And one one is accompanied
last moment. And one one is accompanied
last moment. And one one is accompanied by an angel at this point.
by an angel at this point.
by an angel at this point. I have permission to ask this. One is
I have permission to ask this. One is
I have permission to ask this. One is accompanied by one's special angel. Is
accompanied by one's special angel. Is
accompanied by one's special angel. Is this
this
this a second?
a second?
a second? >> Yeah. One
one one is accompanied by a a divine
one one is accompanied by a a divine angel
angel
angel one one's guardian angel. So when you
one one's guardian angel. So when you
one one's guardian angel. So when you take the moral inventory the as you exit
take the moral inventory the as you exit
take the moral inventory the as you exit you don't take it alone you take it
you don't take it alone you take it
you don't take it alone you take it along with your own guardian angel who
along with your own guardian angel who
along with your own guardian angel who reviews your life with you then you see
reviews your life with you then you see
reviews your life with you then you see the options and the choices and the
the options and the choices and the
the options and the choices and the karmic energies for the next
karmic energies for the next
karmic energies for the next reincarnation already set set first you
reincarnation already set set first you
reincarnation already set set first you see yourself as you really are you say I
see yourself as you really are you say I
see yourself as you really are you say I I don't want that to be on my my soul
I don't want that to be on my my soul
I don't want that to be on my my soul forever I don't want that I don't want
forever I don't want that I don't want
forever I don't want that I don't want that unkindness I don't want that
that unkindness I don't want that
that unkindness I don't want that negativity ity. I don't want that
negativity ity. I don't want that
negativity ity. I don't want that selfishness to be there. And I and I beg
selfishness to be there. And I and I beg
selfishness to be there. And I and I beg for a chance to to correct that. And
for a chance to to correct that. And
for a chance to to correct that. And then if you're karmically entitled, you
then if you're karmically entitled, you
then if you're karmically entitled, you get a chance to reincarnate. And this
get a chance to reincarnate. And this
get a chance to reincarnate. And this time, you're going to be more
time, you're going to be more
time, you're going to be more sympathetic, more understanding, more
sympathetic, more understanding, more
sympathetic, more understanding, more forgiving, uh more loving, going to
forgiving, uh more loving, going to
forgiving, uh more loving, going to value life above winning. And uh
value life above winning. And uh
value life above winning. And uh so the moral accountability is why most
so the moral accountability is why most
so the moral accountability is why most people are afraid to die because you
people are afraid to die because you
people are afraid to die because you realize that you're about to get
realize that you're about to get
realize that you're about to get confronted with the truth of uh what you
confronted with the truth of uh what you
confronted with the truth of uh what you have been moral accountability.
have been moral accountability.
have been moral accountability. So if we accept moral accountability as
So if we accept moral accountability as
So if we accept moral accountability as we go through life, we don't build up a
we go through life, we don't build up a
we go through life, we don't build up a fear about it. You know, we pray for
fear about it. You know, we pray for
fear about it. You know, we pray for forgiveness for, you know, I was very
forgiveness for, you know, I was very
forgiveness for, you know, I was very short and uh and and not very
short and uh and and not very
short and uh and and not very sympathetic and uh I forgive myself for
sympathetic and uh I forgive myself for
sympathetic and uh I forgive myself for that and I asked God to help me to
that and I asked God to help me to
that and I asked God to help me to become more gracious, more gracious. So
become more gracious, more gracious. So
become more gracious, more gracious. So moral accountability then is one of the
moral accountability then is one of the
moral accountability then is one of the reasons that people fear death. Uh-huh.
reasons that people fear death. Uh-huh.
reasons that people fear death. Uh-huh. Of course, at this point, you see your
Of course, at this point, you see your
Of course, at this point, you see your concepts of your beliefs of divinity
concepts of your beliefs of divinity
concepts of your beliefs of divinity come forth as part of your moral
come forth as part of your moral
come forth as part of your moral accountability and part of your fear of
accountability and part of your fear of
accountability and part of your fear of death. Whether you picture God as
death. Whether you picture God as
death. Whether you picture God as merciful or punitive will make a big
merciful or punitive will make a big
merciful or punitive will make a big difference.
difference.
difference. Whether you picture God as merciful or
Whether you picture God as merciful or
Whether you picture God as merciful or merciful
merciful
merciful or angry and punitive. Now, the
or angry and punitive. Now, the
or angry and punitive. Now, the anthropomorphic God, as we say, rises
anthropomorphic God, as we say, rises
anthropomorphic God, as we say, rises out of man's lack of understanding of
out of man's lack of understanding of
out of man's lack of understanding of the na of nature. And he pictures a
the na of nature. And he pictures a
the na of nature. And he pictures a punitive God who punishes you with
punitive God who punishes you with
punitive God who punishes you with earthquakes and volcanoes and things
earthquakes and volcanoes and things
earthquakes and volcanoes and things like this because he's angry. So, if you
like this because he's angry. So, if you
like this because he's angry. So, if you get beyond the angry God to the God that
get beyond the angry God to the God that
get beyond the angry God to the God that God is the source of infinite mercy,
God is the source of infinite mercy,
God is the source of infinite mercy, then your fear of death dissolves. So as
then your fear of death dissolves. So as
then your fear of death dissolves. So as you grow grow spiritually, you can see
you grow grow spiritually, you can see
you grow grow spiritually, you can see that the fear of death lessens and
that the fear of death lessens and
that the fear of death lessens and lessons because you picture God as
lessons because you picture God as
lessons because you picture God as merciful. You realize on your deathbed,
merciful. You realize on your deathbed,
merciful. You realize on your deathbed, you're going to have a companion. You
you're going to have a companion. You
you're going to have a companion. You realize that uh you're going to be given
realize that uh you're going to be given
realize that uh you're going to be given a chance to undo it if you wish. You're
a chance to undo it if you wish. You're
a chance to undo it if you wish. You're not going to be forced into having
not going to be forced into having
not going to be forced into having another human life. It's only uh by your
another human life. It's only uh by your
another human life. It's only uh by your own option.
own option.
own option. Uh we have permission to ask this.
Uh we have permission to ask this.
Uh we have permission to ask this. You only reincarnate by your own say so
You only reincarnate by your own say so
You only reincarnate by your own say so is this. It's only your own option.
is this. It's only your own option.
is this. It's only your own option. You only come back if you decide to come
You only come back if you decide to come
You only come back if you decide to come back.
back.
back. Nobody's going to shove you out of the
Nobody's going to shove you out of the
Nobody's going to shove you out of the wagon.
Nobody's going to dump you in the dirt
Nobody's going to dump you in the dirt and say, "You want to get off the bus
and say, "You want to get off the bus
and say, "You want to get off the bus here and go around again?" Yep. Yep.
here and go around again?" Yep. Yep.
here and go around again?" Yep. Yep. Yep. Yep. Why? Because I want to correct
Yep. Yep. Why? Because I want to correct
Yep. Yep. Why? Because I want to correct the record. You want to correct the
the record. You want to correct the
the record. You want to correct the record because you see how long the
record because you see how long the
record because you see how long the implication is of that record.
implication is of that record.
implication is of that record. A few a few eons.
You see? Yeah. Uh oh, you get what an
You see? Yeah. Uh oh, you get what an eon means. No, I think I'll correct
eon means. No, I think I'll correct
eon means. No, I think I'll correct that.
Well, eons are staggeringly horrible.
Well, eons are staggeringly horrible. Eons are horrible beyond all
Eons are horrible beyond all
Eons are horrible beyond all description.
description.
description. Just as the most extreme of the highest
Just as the most extreme of the highest
Just as the most extreme of the highest points at I've ever experienced, the
points at I've ever experienced, the
points at I've ever experienced, the lowest were also beyond comprehension.
lowest were also beyond comprehension.
lowest were also beyond comprehension. Hell is not something, as I've said
Hell is not something, as I've said
Hell is not something, as I've said before in these classes, that you want
before in these classes, that you want
before in these classes, that you want to flirt with and play with. Wickedness
to flirt with and play with. Wickedness
to flirt with and play with. Wickedness and evil are not things that you want to
and evil are not things that you want to
and evil are not things that you want to game play games with. Because the
game play games with. Because the
game play games with. Because the downside
downside
downside of moral
of moral
of moral accountability
concept divinity is merciful or
concept divinity is merciful or punitive.
punitive.
punitive. Well, the experience of hell
Well, the experience of hell
Well, the experience of hell was
was
was not in inflicted from without.
not in inflicted from without.
not in inflicted from without. It was that the spirit had uh
had dived to this level.
had dived to this level. Well, this particular spirit was going
Well, this particular spirit was going
Well, this particular spirit was going to see it through,
to see it through,
to see it through, see it through and uh keep going to
see it through and uh keep going to
see it through and uh keep going to explore the depths of hell. And uh the
explore the depths of hell. And uh the
explore the depths of hell. And uh the depths of hell is not something uh
depths of hell is not something uh
depths of hell is not something uh anyone wants to experience
anyone wants to experience
anyone wants to experience even for a few seconds. No. Besides, you
even for a few seconds. No. Besides, you
even for a few seconds. No. Besides, you can't experience it for a few seconds.
can't experience it for a few seconds.
can't experience it for a few seconds. each second is experientially an
each second is experientially an
each second is experientially an eternity. So to choose between heaven
eternity. So to choose between heaven
eternity. So to choose between heaven and hell, all of these things, one thing
and hell, all of these things, one thing
and hell, all of these things, one thing takes you closer to heaven and the next
takes you closer to heaven and the next
takes you closer to heaven and the next decision takes you closer to hell. And
decision takes you closer to hell. And
decision takes you closer to hell. And finally, uh if you become spiritually
finally, uh if you become spiritually
finally, uh if you become spiritually very advanced, you realize that taking
very advanced, you realize that taking
very advanced, you realize that taking the chance is is not worth taking the
the chance is is not worth taking the
the chance is is not worth taking the chance. There's a temporary gain to
chance. There's a temporary gain to
chance. There's a temporary gain to vanity and controlling others and
vanity and controlling others and
vanity and controlling others and getting even and revenge and you know
getting even and revenge and you know
getting even and revenge and you know there's a short chuckle as you punch
there's a short chuckle as you punch
there's a short chuckle as you punch somebody in the mouth
somebody in the mouth
somebody in the mouth who deserved it. Maybe they do deserve
who deserved it. Maybe they do deserve
who deserved it. Maybe they do deserve it. However,
it. However,
it. However, uh the moral accountability then takes
uh the moral accountability then takes
uh the moral accountability then takes you to the a choice between two doors.
you to the a choice between two doors.
you to the a choice between two doors. One door leads to heaven and the other
One door leads to heaven and the other
One door leads to heaven and the other door leads to hell. And the door to hell
door leads to hell. And the door to hell
door leads to hell. And the door to hell is awful indeed. So moral
is awful indeed. So moral
is awful indeed. So moral accountability, concepts of divinity,
accountability, concepts of divinity,
accountability, concepts of divinity, whether God is merciful or punitive,
whether God is merciful or punitive,
whether God is merciful or punitive, it isn't that God God does not throw you
it isn't that God God does not throw you
it isn't that God God does not throw you into hell. You yourself by your own uh
into hell. You yourself by your own uh
into hell. You yourself by your own uh choices have brought you to that state
choices have brought you to that state
choices have brought you to that state of abject despair and hopelessness.
of abject despair and hopelessness.
of abject despair and hopelessness. What are the limits of freedom? Frankly,
What are the limits of freedom? Frankly,
What are the limits of freedom? Frankly, there aren't any, are there? There
there aren't any, are there? There
there aren't any, are there? There aren't any limits to freedom. You can
aren't any limits to freedom. You can
aren't any limits to freedom. You can choose to hate God. You can choose to
choose to hate God. You can choose to
choose to hate God. You can choose to love God.
love God.
love God. You can choose to be generous. You can
You can choose to be generous. You can
You can choose to be generous. You can choose to be stingy. What are the limits
choose to be stingy. What are the limits
choose to be stingy. What are the limits of freedom? Only the capacity of the
of freedom? Only the capacity of the
of freedom? Only the capacity of the human mind to see what the options are.
human mind to see what the options are.
human mind to see what the options are. The willingness to see the options.
The willingness to see the options.
The willingness to see the options. Whether you're grasping or you're
Whether you're grasping or you're
Whether you're grasping or you're generous,
generous,
generous, flexibility, capacity to learn, to grow,
flexibility, capacity to learn, to grow,
flexibility, capacity to learn, to grow, to mature. So most normal people say
to mature. So most normal people say
to mature. So most normal people say well I think what I'll do is I'll I'll
well I think what I'll do is I'll I'll
well I think what I'll do is I'll I'll try to learn from this experience that
try to learn from this experience that
try to learn from this experience that that is not the way to do it. I'll try
that is not the way to do it. I'll try
that is not the way to do it. I'll try and make every part of life subserve
and make every part of life subserve
and make every part of life subserve growing and maturing and developing
growing and maturing and developing
growing and maturing and developing spiritual
spiritual
spiritual there's an innate energy to life. It's
there's an innate energy to life. It's
there's an innate energy to life. It's called the London vitality
called the London vitality
called the London vitality and it really means uh it's a French
and it really means uh it's a French
and it really means uh it's a French term meaning
term meaning
term meaning uh one's life energy one's life energy
uh one's life energy one's life energy
uh one's life energy one's life energy that energy flows through you as a
that energy flows through you as a
that energy flows through you as a certain energy life th flows as an
certain energy life th flows as an
certain energy life th flows as an energy you land vital okay the next one
energy you land vital okay the next one
energy you land vital okay the next one three
three
three uh now man pictures themsself self uh
uh now man pictures themsself self uh
uh now man pictures themsself self uh versus the universe. Versus the
versus the universe. Versus the
versus the universe. Versus the universe. Man pictures himself as thrown
universe. Man pictures himself as thrown
universe. Man pictures himself as thrown into the universe as an accident of the
into the universe as an accident of the
into the universe as an accident of the universe
universe
universe as an evolutionary high point in in
as an evolutionary high point in in
as an evolutionary high point in in evolution that man pictures himself as
evolution that man pictures himself as
evolution that man pictures himself as the evolutionary uh highest evolutionary
the evolutionary uh highest evolutionary
the evolutionary uh highest evolutionary form on the planet. Man does not
form on the planet. Man does not
form on the planet. Man does not consider anything uh uh higher than
consider anything uh uh higher than
consider anything uh uh higher than himself in this planet. From this from
himself in this planet. From this from
himself in this planet. From this from this realm, the next level up is the
this realm, the next level up is the
this realm, the next level up is the angelic. Yes. The next the next level up
angelic. Yes. The next the next level up
angelic. Yes. The next the next level up is that of the angelic. From humanness,
is that of the angelic. From humanness,
is that of the angelic. From humanness, the next level of evolution in the
the next level of evolution in the
the next level of evolution in the nonlinear is the angelic resist. Okay.
nonlinear is the angelic resist. Okay.
nonlinear is the angelic resist. Okay. So you leave the let to leave the length
So you leave the let to leave the length
So you leave the let to leave the length ranks of the bodily uh human humanness.
ranks of the bodily uh human humanness.
ranks of the bodily uh human humanness. And you get to be a junior angel,
an angel in residence, an angel in
an angel in residence, an angel in learning, you know, you get to be like a
learning, you know, you get to be like a
learning, you know, you get to be like a resident angel in in training. So you
resident angel in in training. So you
resident angel in in training. So you get to be a junior angel.
get to be a junior angel.
get to be a junior angel. So there's ranks of angels.
So there's ranks of angels.
So there's ranks of angels. We have permission to ask these
We have permission to ask these
We have permission to ask these questions. We have there are ranks of
questions. We have there are ranks of
questions. We have there are ranks of angels. There are ranks of angelic
angels. There are ranks of angelic
angels. There are ranks of angelic beings. Well, that's a relief, isn't it?
beings. Well, that's a relief, isn't it?
beings. Well, that's a relief, isn't it? Huh?
Huh?
Huh? reach a certain point in which point the
reach a certain point in which point the
reach a certain point in which point the physical body is now a detriment. It
physical body is now a detriment. It
physical body is now a detriment. It served its learning purpose and when
served its learning purpose and when
served its learning purpose and when it's run its course it runs out of this
it's run its course it runs out of this
it's run its course it runs out of this vital energy and then you allow it to
vital energy and then you allow it to
vital energy and then you allow it to fall over and you look at the body
fall over and you look at the body
fall over and you look at the body laying there. Now, if anybody's been we
laying there. Now, if anybody's been we
laying there. Now, if anybody's been we all, we've already asked this before. A
all, we've already asked this before. A
all, we've already asked this before. A lot of people here have been out of
lot of people here have been out of
lot of people here have been out of body, right? A lot of people here have
body, right? A lot of people here have
body, right? A lot of people here have been out of body. And of course, when
been out of body. And of course, when
been out of body. And of course, when you're out of body, you look at the
you're out of body, you look at the
you're out of body, you look at the physical body that here you were willing
physical body that here you were willing
physical body that here you were willing to give your life for this this thing
to give your life for this this thing
to give your life for this this thing here. You look at this body laying there
here. You look at this body laying there
here. You look at this body laying there on the stretcher or the bed or the rug
on the stretcher or the bed or the rug
on the stretcher or the bed or the rug or the road or wherever it is.
or the road or wherever it is.
or the road or wherever it is. And I tell you, it is absolutely not
And I tell you, it is absolutely not
And I tell you, it is absolutely not interesting. It's not attractive. You
interesting. It's not attractive. You
interesting. It's not attractive. You don't identify with it. You don't even
don't identify with it. You don't even
don't identify with it. You don't even think it's mine.
think it's mine.
think it's mine. Looks familiar. The physioammy, the face
Looks familiar. The physioammy, the face
Looks familiar. The physioammy, the face looks familiar. So, intellectually
looks familiar. So, intellectually
looks familiar. So, intellectually you're aware that's that was your body.
you're aware that's that was your body.
you're aware that's that was your body. And uh it has no attraction. There's no
And uh it has no attraction. There's no
And uh it has no attraction. There's no desire to renovate it to re re-energize
desire to renovate it to re re-energize
desire to renovate it to re re-energize it.
it.
it. Would you say those who've been out of
Would you say those who've been out of
Would you say those who've been out of body have had a similar experience?
body have had a similar experience?
body have had a similar experience? There's no like uh panic or terrible
There's no like uh panic or terrible
There's no like uh panic or terrible desire to get back in there and get that
desire to get back in there and get that
desire to get back in there and get that thing going again. Anybody remember
thing going again. Anybody remember
thing going again. Anybody remember that? Anybody got to volunteer and
that? Anybody got to volunteer and
that? Anybody got to volunteer and answer? Anybody? Yeah. What?
answer? Anybody? Yeah. What?
answer? Anybody? Yeah. What? Somebody had their hand up. What was the
Somebody had their hand up. What was the
Somebody had their hand up. What was the uh experience like?
You were just watching it. Isn't that
You were just watching it. Isn't that peculiar? You don't even identify with
peculiar? You don't even identify with
peculiar? You don't even identify with the thing. Here you spend all this money
the thing. Here you spend all this money
the thing. Here you spend all this money getting haircuts,
$400 haircuts,
$400 haircuts, $400 dental bills,
$400 dental bills,
$400 dental bills, all these procedures and all the time
all these procedures and all the time
all these procedures and all the time and attention you lavish on this thing
and attention you lavish on this thing
and attention you lavish on this thing and it lays there like a lump. Totally
and it lays there like a lump. Totally
and it lays there like a lump. Totally uninteresting.
uninteresting.
uninteresting. You look at the thing
You look at the thing
You look at the thing and I I had to go back in it. I forget
and I I had to go back in it. I forget
and I I had to go back in it. I forget where I had to go back in it uh that
where I had to go back in it uh that
where I had to go back in it uh that particular trip, but I had to go back in
particular trip, but I had to go back in
particular trip, but I had to go back in it. You know, I it was part of my
it. You know, I it was part of my
it. You know, I it was part of my agreement or what. Anyway, I remember I
agreement or what. Anyway, I remember I
agreement or what. Anyway, I remember I I went back in the body and I docked
I went back in the body and I docked
I went back in the body and I docked backwards. I got in the body and I
backwards. I got in the body and I
backwards. I got in the body and I looked out the back of my physical head
looked out the back of my physical head
looked out the back of my physical head and there was the floor. So, I had to
and there was the floor. So, I had to
and there was the floor. So, I had to back out my spirit had to back out of
back out my spirit had to back out of
back out my spirit had to back out of the physical body and go back in the
the physical body and go back in the
the physical body and go back in the body this way. Okay. So, looking up at
body this way. Okay. So, looking up at
body this way. Okay. So, looking up at the ceiling.
So, here you're willing to die and give
So, here you're willing to die and give up everything for this wonderful thing
up everything for this wonderful thing
up everything for this wonderful thing called you, which you identify as a
called you, which you identify as a
called you, which you identify as a body. And when you're out of it, I
body. And when you're out of it, I
body. And when you're out of it, I wouldn't give you five bucks for it.
You looked in poor shape. besides and I
You looked in poor shape. besides and I looked at him and God he he looks in
looked at him and God he he looks in
looked at him and God he he looks in pretty bum bummed out shape you know he
pretty bum bummed out shape you know he
pretty bum bummed out shape you know he was pretty sick and lying there in a
was pretty sick and lying there in a
was pretty sick and lying there in a sick bed and uh I I if I had never gone
sick bed and uh I I if I had never gone
sick bed and uh I I if I had never gone back at all be fine with me but the neat
back at all be fine with me but the neat
back at all be fine with me but the neat part about it is that which you consider
part about it is that which you consider
part about it is that which you consider to be you uh continues on unabated. It's
to be you uh continues on unabated. It's
to be you uh continues on unabated. It's just that the U its location and
just that the U its location and
just that the U its location and identification with the body disappears
identification with the body disappears
identification with the body disappears and now that which you call you is sort
and now that which you call you is sort
and now that which you call you is sort of like an etheric uh energy and it can
of like an etheric uh energy and it can
of like an etheric uh energy and it can go anywhere it wants in space. It can go
go anywhere it wants in space. It can go
go anywhere it wants in space. It can go up to the ceiling or sit on the window
up to the ceiling or sit on the window
up to the ceiling or sit on the window sill. It can do whatever it wants
sill. It can do whatever it wants
sill. It can do whatever it wants but the physicality
but the physicality
but the physicality uh is boring at that point. Uh okay. So
uh is boring at that point. Uh okay. So
uh is boring at that point. Uh okay. So man pictures his relationship to the
man pictures his relationship to the
man pictures his relationship to the universe
universe
universe his karmic inheritance his propensities
his karmic inheritance his propensities
his karmic inheritance his propensities is not well understood in the western
is not well understood in the western
is not well understood in the western world. What is meant by a karmic
world. What is meant by a karmic
world. What is meant by a karmic inheritance
inheritance
inheritance uh is that the energy field of that
uh is that the energy field of that
uh is that the energy field of that which you are imprints all your
which you are imprints all your
which you are imprints all your decisions and their consequences.
decisions and their consequences.
decisions and their consequences. And this etheric body then is your soul
And this etheric body then is your soul
And this etheric body then is your soul your spirit. that stays with you and
your spirit. that stays with you and
your spirit. that stays with you and because it's context it tends to
because it's context it tends to
because it's context it tends to influence the likelihood of various
influence the likelihood of various
influence the likelihood of various things happening in your in your life.
things happening in your in your life.
things happening in your in your life. It not it doesn't cause them but it
It not it doesn't cause them but it
It not it doesn't cause them but it increases the likelihood of collapsing
increases the likelihood of collapsing
increases the likelihood of collapsing the wave function from potentiality to
the wave function from potentiality to
the wave function from potentiality to actuality of certain events. So I'll say
actuality of certain events. So I'll say
actuality of certain events. So I'll say to people if you have unfortunate things
to people if you have unfortunate things
to people if you have unfortunate things happening in your life especially if
happening in your life especially if
happening in your life especially if they continue uh then look for the
they continue uh then look for the
they continue uh then look for the karmic inheritance. Forgive yourself for
karmic inheritance. Forgive yourself for
karmic inheritance. Forgive yourself for being the one who did that to others. If
being the one who did that to others. If
being the one who did that to others. If animals bite you all the time then
animals bite you all the time then
animals bite you all the time then forgive yourself for having been vicious
forgive yourself for having been vicious
forgive yourself for having been vicious and cruel to animals.
and cruel to animals.
and cruel to animals. Presume that this is payback
Presume that this is payback
Presume that this is payback karmic inherence. and presume that
karmic inherence. and presume that
karmic inherence. and presume that anything that ne negative happens to you
anything that ne negative happens to you
anything that ne negative happens to you is karmic inheritance.
is karmic inheritance.
is karmic inheritance. It's not a matter of logic. It's not a
It's not a matter of logic. It's not a
It's not a matter of logic. It's not a matter of arguing with it. It's just a a
matter of arguing with it. It's just a a
matter of arguing with it. It's just a a likely presumption. Let's see if it's a
likely presumption. Let's see if it's a
likely presumption. Let's see if it's a very good presumption. We have
very good presumption. We have
very good presumption. We have permission to ask this one. Uh it's a
permission to ask this one. Uh it's a
permission to ask this one. Uh it's a likely presumption. Probably over 90%.
likely presumption. Probably over 90%.
likely presumption. Probably over 90%. Probably over 90%. You know, then
Probably over 90%. You know, then
Probably over 90%. You know, then there's other karmic propensities having
there's other karmic propensities having
there's other karmic propensities having to do with race and color and various
to do with race and color and various
to do with race and color and various other
other
other But personal karmic. So if you're
But personal karmic. So if you're
But personal karmic. So if you're something's keeps happening to you,
something's keeps happening to you,
something's keeps happening to you, somebody hates you and it's very painful
somebody hates you and it's very painful
somebody hates you and it's very painful then you got to find the one in you who
then you got to find the one in you who
then you got to find the one in you who hates others forgive that one because
hates others forgive that one because
hates others forgive that one because you can't remember it personally doesn't
you can't remember it personally doesn't
you can't remember it personally doesn't mean it doesn't exist because you can
mean it doesn't exist because you can
mean it doesn't exist because you can buy into the collective consciousness of
buy into the collective consciousness of
buy into the collective consciousness of mankind. Carl Young described you know
mankind. Carl Young described you know
mankind. Carl Young described you know the collective consciousness the energy
the collective consciousness the energy
the collective consciousness the energy field of the collective consciousness.
field of the collective consciousness.
field of the collective consciousness. So I've had some things happen in my
So I've had some things happen in my
So I've had some things happen in my life. I never had any in fact recently I
life. I never had any in fact recently I
life. I never had any in fact recently I have no memory of having any belief in
have no memory of having any belief in
have no memory of having any belief in that uh possibility whatsoever. I never
that uh possibility whatsoever. I never
that uh possibility whatsoever. I never gave it the slightest energy. Uh how do
gave it the slightest energy. Uh how do
gave it the slightest energy. Uh how do you get osteoporosis? I don't know. I
you get osteoporosis? I don't know. I
you get osteoporosis? I don't know. I never I thought of little old bent over
never I thought of little old bent over
never I thought of little old bent over ladies get that, you know. I never
ladies get that, you know. I never
ladies get that, you know. I never thought of a good-looking middle-aged
thought of a good-looking middle-aged
thought of a good-looking middle-aged gentleman having
gentleman having
gentleman having that their problem.
All right. The what is the purpose of
All right. The what is the purpose of human life? You see all these questions
human life? You see all these questions
human life? You see all these questions arise because how you answer these
arise because how you answer these
arise because how you answer these existential things they seem abstract
existential things they seem abstract
existential things they seem abstract but it is how you answer these these
but it is how you answer these these
but it is how you answer these these which look like a generality that that
which look like a generality that that
which look like a generality that that defines how you choose the particulars
defines how you choose the particulars
defines how you choose the particulars the value of human life. The purpose of
the value of human life. The purpose of
the value of human life. The purpose of human life. We we said in my view the
human life. We we said in my view the
human life. We we said in my view the purpose of human life is when we started
purpose of human life is when we started
purpose of human life is when we started this morning to serve God, to serve
this morning to serve God, to serve
this morning to serve God, to serve humanity and to serve yourself. To serve
humanity and to serve yourself. To serve
humanity and to serve yourself. To serve yourself
yourself
yourself and to serve God by serving yourself to
and to serve God by serving yourself to
and to serve God by serving yourself to serve your fellow man.
serve your fellow man.
serve your fellow man. you fulfill your obligation and your
you fulfill your obligation and your
you fulfill your obligation and your destiny and and potentiality to serve
destiny and and potentiality to serve
destiny and and potentiality to serve Godself and your fellow fellow man.
Godself and your fellow fellow man.
Godself and your fellow fellow man. Having done that, is there anything left
Having done that, is there anything left
Having done that, is there anything left you you can think of to do?
That pretty much clears off the desk,
That pretty much clears off the desk, doesn't it? You've done all you can to
doesn't it? You've done all you can to
doesn't it? You've done all you can to serve God,
serve God,
serve God, to serve your obligation to yourself, to
to serve your obligation to yourself, to
to serve your obligation to yourself, to move from self for the smallest S to
move from self for the smallest S to
move from self for the smallest S to self for the largest
self for the largest
self for the largest and your fellow man and and thereby
and your fellow man and and thereby
and your fellow man and and thereby serve God. Yeah. To be a channel of
serve God. Yeah. To be a channel of
serve God. Yeah. To be a channel of God's will for the good of all of
God's will for the good of all of
God's will for the good of all of mankind as well as your own evolution
mankind as well as your own evolution
mankind as well as your own evolution because after all, you are part of
because after all, you are part of
because after all, you are part of mankind. So don't leave yourself out.
mankind. So don't leave yourself out.
mankind. So don't leave yourself out. It isn't you versus mankind. You are
It isn't you versus mankind. You are
It isn't you versus mankind. You are part of mankind. So in serving mankind,
part of mankind. So in serving mankind,
part of mankind. So in serving mankind, you serve yourself as well.
you serve yourself as well.
you serve yourself as well. The purpose of human life then if that's
The purpose of human life then if that's
The purpose of human life then if that's what it is and the fulfillment of one's
what it is and the fulfillment of one's
what it is and the fulfillment of one's destiny and you fulfill that by service
destiny and you fulfill that by service
destiny and you fulfill that by service to yourself, God and fellow man.
to yourself, God and fellow man.
to yourself, God and fellow man. The society you grew up in in we power
The society you grew up in in we power
The society you grew up in in we power versus force was the first book we wrote
versus force was the first book we wrote
versus force was the first book we wrote in this. The difference between power
in this. The difference between power
in this. The difference between power which is context and force which is
which is context and force which is
which is context and force which is linear and Newtonian. The difference
linear and Newtonian. The difference
linear and Newtonian. The difference between truth versus and falsehood.
between truth versus and falsehood.
between truth versus and falsehood. Love is now becomes a quality instead of
Love is now becomes a quality instead of
Love is now becomes a quality instead of an emotion. You see people think of
an emotion. You see people think of
an emotion. You see people think of love. Oh baby Ken say I love you.
love. Oh baby Ken say I love you.
love. Oh baby Ken say I love you. Love is a way of defining one's own
Love is a way of defining one's own
Love is a way of defining one's own reality. It's a quality. It's because of
reality. It's a quality. It's because of
reality. It's a quality. It's because of lovingness that you step over the black
lovingness that you step over the black
lovingness that you step over the black beetle because you appreciate the gift
beetle because you appreciate the gift
beetle because you appreciate the gift of life. This is his only chance to get
of life. This is his only chance to get
of life. This is his only chance to get this this life and you don't want to uh
this this life and you don't want to uh
this this life and you don't want to uh bring it because love is is valuable.
bring it because love is is valuable.
bring it because love is is valuable. You love quality, the essence and the
You love quality, the essence and the
You love quality, the essence and the good. And all of this as we said earlier
good. And all of this as we said earlier
good. And all of this as we said earlier affects brain physiology. How you see
affects brain physiology. How you see
affects brain physiology. How you see and experience the world
and experience the world
and experience the world is reflected in your brain physiology.
is reflected in your brain physiology.
is reflected in your brain physiology. The childhood experiences then are the
The childhood experiences then are the
The childhood experiences then are the beginning of the be building of these
beginning of the be building of these
beginning of the be building of these stacks and as parents to bring all the
stacks and as parents to bring all the
stacks and as parents to bring all the beauty music and spiritual qualities we
beauty music and spiritual qualities we
beauty music and spiritual qualities we can all of these end up as cultural
can all of these end up as cultural
can all of these end up as cultural norms and mores whether or not people
norms and mores whether or not people
norms and mores whether or not people believe in it or not they say well I
believe in it or not they say well I
believe in it or not they say well I don't believe in ethics and morality and
don't believe in ethics and morality and
don't believe in ethics and morality and god and religion and all that 1950s crap
god and religion and all that 1950s crap
god and religion and all that 1950s crap and uh all they're reciting now is what
and uh all they're reciting now is what
and uh all they're reciting now is what has become a cultural norm
has become a cultural norm
has become a cultural norm and the mories of our current day. Huh?
and the mories of our current day. Huh?
and the mories of our current day. Huh? The mental impact and programming that
The mental impact and programming that
The mental impact and programming that goes on. We've already spoken about all
goes on. We've already spoken about all
goes on. We've already spoken about all of this is advanced by technology and
of this is advanced by technology and
of this is advanced by technology and the effective forms of communication. We
the effective forms of communication. We
the effective forms of communication. We have access now to vast accumulations of
have access now to vast accumulations of
have access now to vast accumulations of knowledge.
knowledge.
knowledge. And out of all of that, from the house
And out of all of that, from the house
And out of all of that, from the house of mirrors, we eventually learn how to
of mirrors, we eventually learn how to
of mirrors, we eventually learn how to sort the wheat from the chef
sort the wheat from the chef
sort the wheat from the chef and get rid of opinion, narcissism,
and get rid of opinion, narcissism,
and get rid of opinion, narcissism, relativism, and instead develop goals
relativism, and instead develop goals
relativism, and instead develop goals and ego ideals that which we wish to
and ego ideals that which we wish to
and ego ideals that which we wish to become
become
become and then you begin to identify with the
and then you begin to identify with the
and then you begin to identify with the models of that. Uh, society needs
models of that. Uh, society needs
models of that. Uh, society needs heroes. Society needs models. That's why
heroes. Society needs models. That's why
heroes. Society needs models. That's why I I believe in that um values to be a
I I believe in that um values to be a
I I believe in that um values to be a comedian had one of the biggest
comedian had one of the biggest
comedian had one of the biggest Bill Cosby. Yes. Yeah. Bill and Bill of
Bill Cosby. Yes. Yeah. Bill and Bill of
Bill Cosby. Yes. Yeah. Bill and Bill of course does that that mentoring. So I
course does that that mentoring. So I
course does that that mentoring. So I believe strongly in mentoring each one
believe strongly in mentoring each one
believe strongly in mentoring each one of us uh becomes a mentor to those who
of us uh becomes a mentor to those who
of us uh becomes a mentor to those who are following behind us. And is that uh
are following behind us. And is that uh
are following behind us. And is that uh Uhhuh. All right. It's almost time to
Uhhuh. All right. It's almost time to
Uhhuh. All right. It's almost time to stop. Does anybody have a final question
stop. Does anybody have a final question
stop. Does anybody have a final question and then we will come to a stop?
and then we will come to a stop?
and then we will come to a stop? Make sure it's brilliant, intelligent,
Make sure it's brilliant, intelligent,
Make sure it's brilliant, intelligent, worthy of being recorded throughout all
worthy of being recorded throughout all
worthy of being recorded throughout all of history. And don't forget, God is
of history. And don't forget, God is
of history. And don't forget, God is going to be looking at this
going to be looking at this
going to be looking at this on his computer as you St. St. Peter,
on his computer as you St. St. Peter,
on his computer as you St. St. Peter, you know, has a computer now. We all
you know, has a computer now. We all
you know, has a computer now. We all have an ID number.
Yes.
Yes. >> Uh because uh you don't experience the
>> Uh because uh you don't experience the
>> Uh because uh you don't experience the world, you experience your experience of
world, you experience your experience of
world, you experience your experience of the world.
the world.
the world. What you're experiencing is your own
What you're experiencing is your own
What you're experiencing is your own experiencing. So that comes out of some
experiencing. So that comes out of some
experiencing. So that comes out of some previous lectures we had. You're never
previous lectures we had. You're never
previous lectures we had. You're never experiencing what you think you are.
experiencing what you think you are.
experiencing what you think you are. You're only experiencing your
You're only experiencing your
You're only experiencing your experiencing.
experiencing.
experiencing. You short you're shortcircuiting
You short you're shortcircuiting
You short you're shortcircuiting the ultimate reality. So
the ultimate reality. So
the ultimate reality. So all the time what you're witnessing your
all the time what you're witnessing your
all the time what you're witnessing your thoughts, your feelings, your images
thoughts, your feelings, your images
thoughts, your feelings, your images etc. is that advanced edge of the ego
etc. is that advanced edge of the ego
etc. is that advanced edge of the ego which uh which I call the experiencer.
which uh which I call the experiencer.
which uh which I call the experiencer. Once the experiencer dissolves
Once the experiencer dissolves
Once the experiencer dissolves there is no me and the universe. There
there is no me and the universe. There
there is no me and the universe. There is no duality of me and the world. They
is no duality of me and the world. They
is no duality of me and the world. They are one and the same
are one and the same
are one and the same there. See, there's no Mia in the world.
there. See, there's no Mia in the world.
there. See, there's no Mia in the world. So, it's like you don't have a TV screen
So, it's like you don't have a TV screen
So, it's like you don't have a TV screen of Fifth Avenue. You're on Fifth Avenue.
of Fifth Avenue. You're on Fifth Avenue.
of Fifth Avenue. You're on Fifth Avenue. Yeah. So, the reality then is beyond the
Yeah. So, the reality then is beyond the
Yeah. So, the reality then is beyond the experiencer. There is a 100 sec second
experiencer. There is a 100 sec second
experiencer. There is a 100 sec second uh delay and I always compare it to the
uh delay and I always compare it to the
uh delay and I always compare it to the playing back from the monitor of a
playing back from the monitor of a
playing back from the monitor of a recording. The old videotape. I don't
recording. The old videotape. I don't
recording. The old videotape. I don't think they even use them anymore, but
think they even use them anymore, but
think they even use them anymore, but it's the only machine I know to work.
it's the only machine I know to work.
it's the only machine I know to work. Anyway, you push record and then you can
Anyway, you push record and then you can
Anyway, you push record and then you can uh you can plug into the uh monitor
uh you can plug into the uh monitor
uh you can plug into the uh monitor and uh so
and uh so
and uh so what you're getting is is the monitor
what you're getting is is the monitor
what you're getting is is the monitor playback instead of the direct
playback instead of the direct
playback instead of the direct experience of the real audio of that
experience of the real audio of that
experience of the real audio of that which is but you don't have to worry
which is but you don't have to worry
which is but you don't have to worry about it.
All right. So then uh what happens now?
All right. So then uh what happens now? >> Huh? question.
>> Huh? question.
>> Huh? question. >> Do we have a a brief break?
>> Do we have a a brief break?
>> Do we have a a brief break? >> Yes, we have a break.
>> Yes, we have a break.
>> Yes, we have a break. >> We have a 15 minute break.