Well, handle both God and science in
five minutes.
Do we have to stop in 5 minutes?
>> You're kidding me.
I better not tell them these things.
Take that off.
Let's see. We'll ask it for the
audience. You You can shut it off now.
Uh we have we have pervision to ask
about Mars, right? Um there are microbes
on Mars resist
there is has been water on Mars resist.
Therefore there is actually life on Mars
resist.
No.
Okay. There are however microbes on Mars
but they're not living microbes exist.
It's some kind of a paradox.
We don't know the right question to
answer to ask. We don't know the right
question to ask folk.
Well, oh, I'm thinking of life as
linear. There is life on Mars in in
nonlinear form. Oh, in nonlinear form.
So therefore, the source of potential
life exists currently on Mars. Resist.
Oh, the potential for life exists
everywhere in the universe. Resist. Wow.
It's funny how those questions just come
up of their own, huh? Without thinking.
You just sort of begin to intuit it. And
then we we had all all morning we could
just keep playing with this and see
where it would take us in the universe
and what kind of life and whether the
circumstances have to be appropriate. So
the potential the energy field of the
radiance of divinity which shone forth
in Genesis is the light of creation. The
light shines forth on the entire
universe.
Out of that light arises existence as as
life. So the potential for life then
exists throughout the universe.
The potential for life is innate to the
universe itself. Resistance.
Aha. Potential for life exists
everywhere because it is an aspect of
that out of which it was created. The
creator, huh? Very interesting.
Very interesting. Got love.
Some people are planning to send space
people out
to the nearest galaxy. They figure it'll
take three to four human generations.
So, they're going to raise people to
live on these space things that hurdle
through space at the speed of light.
And not their children, but their
children's children. By the time you get
to another galaxy, you'll be down to the
grandchildren.
And the idea is that we want to
um inoculate or plant human life in
distant galaxies for fear that we're the
only one. See, talk about the collective
human ego. I thought it was doing the
universe a favor if we just mankind
disappeared.
I can't think of anything more dreadful
than exporting
a population, 85% of which are below
200, to another innocent little planet
just sitting there minding its own
business. And here comes these space
people. Oh god. And and they're going to
bring their blog sites with them.
We're going to conquer that galaxy in
the name of God
and kill anybody who doesn't agree with
us.
>> Now, how do how am I on the 10th?
>> We are right on time.
>> All right. So, we just discovered
something we'd never been aware of
either. that because of the quality of
the source of all of existence that
which exists already has the all that's
necessary for the emergence of life and
therefore the actual emergence would
depend on local conditions and
evolutionary phenomena. So that was a
fun thing to discover. So it's how the
things get discovered that we lecture.
Suddenly it comes to you to ask this and
it comes to you to ask that and it comes
to you to ask that. So,
uh, it's a great investigative technique
and you never know where it's going to
lead and you don't always get the answer
you want. You don't always get the
answer you want. So, the way to get the
correct answers is to be integrous to
begin with and say, I I of myself, oh
Lord, I'm unable to discern the truth.
And what you're really asking is God's
permission that the truth of certain
things be revealed. And occasionally,
you'll get a no. And of course, we've
gotten nos here in class
for reasons I still don't know because I
never got a chance to go back and ask
him why. I'm afraid to ask. I'm not
going to ask him why. I don't want to
know. You say no. It's big enough. It's
okay with me. God
says no. I'll take his word for it.
Don't go there. He says
stay in your own backyard where you're
safe. So
we also use a little caution and uh try
to use a little wisdom in utilization of
a technique which has so much value. I
say not everyone is adept at it. Uh it's
just that some people are adept and
others are not. Others get it with
experience, others uh don't have it and
then suddenly they discovered they have
it. Um it's just a very useful technique
and uh especially if you're doing the
kind of research we're trying to do.
We're trying to bypass all the great
blockages to enlightenment and uh
religious reality. We're trying to
bypass all those things that have
emerged over the ages that have stood in
man's way of realizing the absolute
truth for himself. So he doesn't have to
rely on history. But even those who wish
to rely on history, we've confirmed that
uh spiritual and religious truth out of
history which is confirmable
confirmable.
So we've tried to smooth out the ancient
way and then at the same time create a
new way and in the new way to even
confirm that which is truthful in the
ancient ways. You see right? So what the
Buddha taught was of great information
throughout the ages. essay
is even more comprehensible
uh when you use consciousness
calibration the kind of research we're
doing makes it even more comprehensible
in the teachings of Jesus Christ to
forgive them for for they know not what
they do when we trace the evolution
though of the ego out of the primordial
swamp the protozoa
that it's essential for life to
constantly sample what's out there
because it lacks energy within itself
We saw in our own scientific mind the
explanation of the innocence of all that
exists. So when Christ says forgive
because of their ignorance, we see that
their ignorance comes out of an
intrinsic biologic evolutionary
phenomena of consciousness itself. And
therefore we don't have to come from a
false forgiveness. I think a lot of
times Christians strain themselves
when you really understand how
consciousness arose. You don't have to
false. You don't have to be ungenuine.
You can be genuine. You can say yes.
Like the mind of the child, the little
computer in all of us will buy any
software that you put in it. So our
little ego is nothing but the program
self software put in the hardware. And
we didn't have any say about it, did we?
you didn't get a chance to say okay to
every sentence that you got programmed
with in kindergarten or throughout
school or on the blog sites or so. So
each one stays within themsself
intrinsically
innocent.
So all those innocents will take a break
for lunch and we'll see you afterwards.
We're going to do the last slide here.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> So the u I came to I just want to affirm
that the obligation is of the teacher to
the students.
Spiritual teaching is an obligation on
the part of the teacher to do his best
job because he's responsible to teach to
the students.
I get emails from people who've
committed to some guru somewhere and
they want to move on and now they're
guilten because they're bound. So a
teacher doesn't bind you to them. See, a
teacher frees you from them. So yeah. So
but I just got one this week. she's
afraid to leave
uh this teacher, you know, and now will
she lose
the value of his or her, etc. So, you
don't you don't want a teacher who binds
you.
That's one way to distinguish.
All right, we'll resume the spiritually
incorrect guide to enlightenment.
politically incorrect guide to
enlightenment.
We said some nos this morning, so
we hope to uh recover from that shock.
Oh, I forgot my pointer. Oh, there's my
pointer. Isn't that magical? You just
hold it in mind and appears.
Good golly.
I should have thought of $1,000 instead.
Oh, thank you, Lord.
A big bill.
Ah,
so we were investigating some some
things. All right. So it's one of its
values in science then is with
consciousness research you can check out
a whole research design and know the
know how the outcome before you start
it. uh companies spend very very big
money on research, very big, very big.
And how easy it would be if you somebody
submits a research proposal and you say
this caliber said so and so and you get
a weak arm, you just save that company
$250 million
plus a couple years on the market. So
you can see the great value to science
is to use it uh as a guide. We we know
uh the outcome of a research before it's
done.
All you need is the research design and
you say this calibrates at so and so and
save millions of dollars, time, energy,
equipment, etc. And you can do the same
thing with advertising. This advertising
it will you know what's its effect on?
and then pick out the
who is your target market. So you can
see the application then of
consciousness research in a lot of
different areas and of course in
medicine and various other things. In
medicine it can be extremely important.
You know
medicine is at 440. You have academic
medicine at calibration level 440
academic
clinical medicine calibrates at 445.
Yeah, that extra five points is
significant because you're talking a
logger to the base 10. So the the number
of patients who recover with
a more holistic approach is higher than
with academic medicine. And of course I
had the largest psychiatric practice in
the United States back east for 25
years. So we saw all the patients who
made the rounds of academia
and what we used was more innovative uh
what do you call it kind of medicine?
What do you call the word?
>> Alternative medicine or whatever you
want to call it.
>> It's got a name. Whatever the name is.
>> More holistic. Yes. Holistic.
All right. So with holistic medicine
then of course academics will poo poo
holistic medicine and say you
acupuncture. Oh, this diet diets you
know uh but but the the healing the cure
rate is much higher with the clinical
than academic medicine. If academic
medicine cured them all I wouldn't have
had any patients to see. So
clinical medicine is more uh academ is
more innovative
and we take advantage of the Heisenberg
principle. See the cure rate amongst
patients. I noticed because I used to
hire a lot of therapists, psychologists,
psychiatrists, etc. Some people had
tremendously good results with really
impossible people and other people just
consistently had bad results. And it was
related upon investigation to the
consciousness level of the therapist,
the doctor. See, so Dr.
the true uh the true clinical physician
uh utilizes everything because his
dedication is to the healing of the
patient not to serve some scientific
uh doctrine. So you see the limitation
of science is it becomes a doctrine. It
becomes religionized. You see? So if you
say well you went you want to go see an
acupuncturist. The person goes an
acupuncturist.
Well I've already told the story of my
ulcer intractable ulcer that almost
killed me perforating into the pancreas
etc. which I had for 25 years and I saw
all the clinical I mean the academic
medicine you see. Then I heard that
acupuncture was first coming into
America. Started in Washington DC. And
I've told the story before. I went to
see I flew down there from New York. Saw
this old Chinese. He didn't speak
English. And uh he I remember when he
put a needle right through this wrist. I
thought that acupuncture was painless.
I screamed and he goes, "Ho ho ho, bad
ultra, huh?
Ho ho ho, bad ultra.
his diagnosis. He knew the diagnosis
from the one needle and from the third
treatment on and this is the truth of
God. I've not had any recurrence of a
chronic recurrent douadal ulcer and that
was by a poo poo treatment acupuncture.
So
I'll tell you now that Dr. Cullen and I
were talking about at lunch these
alternative treatments will always work
in a certain percentage of people. So if
we set up a clinical uh academic test,
you know, 100 patients on this and 100
patients on this,
the 100 on the alternative medicine are
probably not statistically is going to
do as well.
But within let's say with if you've got
a 100 people on alternative medicine
let's say acupuncture
let's say 22%
uh are cured and let's say with chronic
ant acids and antis-pspasmotics
uh 47%. It looks like one is better than
the other but I'll tell you where the
fallacy is and we were discussing this
at lunch.
uh out of a out of a group there are uh
there's a subgroup in which the cure
rate for this treatment is 100%.
Out of 100 people with an ulcer, let's
say 27%. If you know who the 27 are,
pull them out and treat them with
acupuncture. You got a cure rate of 100%
of douadal ulcers with acupuncture if
you knew how to pick them out.
Calbach and I figured that out. So you
see with our diagnostic technique we
could screen and say this the person
would respond to this person. So we pull
out the the responders. For some people
that's going to be 100%.
Yep. For some people all you got to do
is take wheat and gluten out of their
diet and their schizophrenia disappears.
Well did that many a time and uh but
which of the crowd are the ones? So
statistics lie. You see when you say
only 10%
cures but amongst that 10% your cure
rate was 100%. You got that point what
I'm saying? Yeah. So one other
diagnostic tool then is is a way you can
discern in your patient subgroup who's
going to respond to what and get a very
high cure rate. Of course alternative
medicine we use everything. the
intention of the doctor. You see, you go
from doctor
academic doctor, you go to become a
clinician clinician and then in the 500s
you become a healer. So there are
doctors who are in the 500s and they
have an even higher rate than the others
because the energy they put out is of a
healing energy in the 500s.
So a doctor who calibrates at 520 is
going to have a higher uh cure rate than
people at 440. You see understand?
So what you want is a doctor who's
spiritually committed, spiritually
oriented and is dedicated to the
recovery of his patients and not to his
own ego. And I can remember making that
decision. the patient sitting there. Was
I going to use a non-traditional way and
cure this patient or am I going to stick
with what my colleagues say and not get
laughed at? And I in in that instant I
said when I took the oath to be a
physician I promised to God to use my
skills for the benefit of the patients
not to become popular with my
colleagues. So in that moment I made the
decision. So
therefore intention plays such a big
part and therefore the Heisenberg
principle although it plays an important
part in the application of science and
especially clinical science.
So
we were looking at strange things like
morphic resonance morphagenetic fields
sheld morphagenetic fields
has somewhat align with what you hold in
mind tends to materialize. Huh. M theory
was formerly known as string theory and
that's arguable in science. It
calibrates as 460.
The fact that there's multiple universes
uh calibrates as true. The Newtonian
causality principle we pointed out sir
Isaac Newton's principles calibrated for
60 and this is really the very center of
science which sees everything in terms
of linear causality
nonlinear dynamics you know at 460
prayer increases healing
uh nuclear fishision reaction the
actuality of nuclear reaction is 200
neutral it's neither good nor bad.
Nuclear reaction is neither good nor
bad. Like the body and the earth, it
calibrates at 200, which is neither good
nor bad. So it isn't the nuclear
efficient, it's what you do with it.
Nuclear efficient theory itself is at
455. Huh?
We did organisms on Mars, parallel
universe theory, quantum coherence,
quantum gravity. Huh? Is this the last
slide?
No.
>> Yes.
>> Are we on 203 or 204?
>> 2024.
>> This is page two of science theory. Is
that the last one?
>> That's the last one.
>> Okay. Thank you. I just want to make
sure we cover all the things that we
mentioned. No. Uh okay. Quantum
mechanics. We've discussed that many
times in the shredding or equations.
Smatrix spiritual experience is the
consequence of neuronal activity. We've
checked that in many different ways. Uh
stem cell research 245. I don't I forget
which is stem cell and which is the
other one. Anyway, subparticle physics
at 455. Telekinesis
is true. You can actually with
consciousness
teleportation of quantum states
electrons and electrons and ions is
calibrates at 400. You can actually
transport things by metal intention. The
United States space program calibrates
at 400 phenomenon process 450. So you
see the application of consciousness
research then to science. We see, of
course, we're most interested in its
application to spiritual reality, the
confirmation of spiritual truth, the
confirmation of the validity of certain
pathways and concepts and teachers and
teachings
over time. But you see, it's universal
application to many uh areas of life.
How many people here actually use uh you
know use the arm with any degree of
frequency? It's just sort of a practical
thing. You know what I'm saying? and you
get to a Y in the road, you say it'd be
better if we take this side or that
side. You know, a lot of time
you get used to using it in a very very
practical way to answer very simple
problems. Now, this morning, as I said,
we say some things that are
not not in alignment with currently
politically popularized theories of
science and etc. But we're more
interested in truth than than
popularity.
So uh now I want to know if there's any
questions you'd like uh we're going to
do specific questions and answers later
of individuals but anything of general
interest about which we have been
talking this morning I want to clarify
it now is anybody like more elaboration
on anything would like to bring up
anything huh
>> yes
>> did you you spoke earlier about um the
the small substance injected would not
it was like an inoculations
were not that theory was not true. Does
that follow along with homeopathy?
>> No, it's not called homeopathy. I think
the the concept is used. Uh the the
basic hormesis is what you were talking
about. Uh hormesis calibrates is not
true. Let's just make sure we're
correct.
Uh hormesis is a is is not true. resist
hormmesis uh
is a theory you know and the theory
calibrates is not true what goes on
clinically of course is
involved in many uh things many things
bring a tend to potentiate the actuality
of a potentiality
>> the intention the intention of the
practitioner so there's many practices
that if you take them up uh academically
scientifically
do not prove is valid but in the hands
of this practitioner with this patient
you get a cure. So as I said you have to
you can't generalize from the particular
hormesis as a theory calibrates as
false.
I'm neither for it nor you know so I
just I pulled it out of the hat hormesis
when we were checking out scientific
theories. Yes. Yes.
Also on the previous slide, distance
healing was listed as false.
>> Let's let's do it again.
>> Prayer.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, distant healing is a very specific
technique. See, a lot of times they do
it by mail and they also charge and they
do it on the internet, you know. So,
doesn't heal you for so much an hour
instead of so I don't know whe they're
distant healing. It could be because of
the intention. He was asking if it's the
same as as prayer like prayer. It's two
different things.
>> Yeah. Two different things.
>> So distant healing gives the power to
the healer. You see understand healing
calibrates is is false resist. Yeah.
Because it's giving the power to the
healer and that's why they sell it and
manipulate you with it. Um praying
praying for people is is something
different. uh praying for for people is
some is something different because
you're not you're not saying it's your
power as a healer, you know, and there's
he no matter what goes on in the world,
somebody makes a racket out of it. You
can soon see it on the internet. Yeah.
Nobody's going to heal you for so much
an hour. There's people they'll
enlighten you for so much an hour, too.
They'll calibrate you every hour and
guaranteed that you'll be go up 90
points a day and for $850 you can get a
light in six weeks. Says right there.
>> Says it right on the internet.
>> Yeah, that's John.
>> I do for nothing. But anyway,
what does it cost? It doesn't cost
anything. See?
>> Yeah. Somebody had their Yeah.
>> You had two different slides on
universes. One was parallel universes
which is false. You had multiple
universes which is true. I don't know
the difference.
>> Well, parallel means like a like a twin
of this one you know twin but there's
multiple universes. Yes. And that's
rather obvious just from the mathematics
of the universe and probability theory.
You would assume that there are many
infinite number of universes. My guess
is that it's close to infinite.
Universes are continually appearing.
Therefore, their potential number is
infinite.
Infinite universes of see the universe
is expanding at the speed of light in
all directions and infinitely expanding.
So therefore, just the statistical
likelihood is that there's other
universes. And then there's that uh
equation which I calibrated. What is it?
410. Uh there's an actual equation.
Chances are 1 in 10,000. I forget what
how it came out in the Milky Way. Yeah.
In the Milky Way, in our in ours, the
chances are that there are 10,000 other
civilizations identical to ours.
According to that formula, and if I
remember that correctly, that formula
calibrated at 410. It's a very famous
formula. I've forgotten the name of it
right now.
>> Drake equation.
>> Yeah. Drake equation. Yeah. The
probability of there being sim life
similar to ours and other planets in the
Milky Way, the likelihood is that
there's 10,000 more according to that
direct equation. And the direct equation
is over 200. So there's some
uh like likelihood of that it's truth. I
mean it's not going to change your life
any you know
we can't sleep later tomorrow morning
because of it.
Uh I just wanted a general question
having to do with the work afterwards
when we do questions and answers. People
are rather personal about things but I
thought these having to do with the
lecture itself. Yes.
>> Stem cell research calibrated at 245 is
in the body at 200. Is that why there is
that relationship?
>> I haven't thought that out or even
examined that. A lot of people make a
big issue out of it and I've never had
you know I never looked at it at all. uh
that when we asked you know in the
abstract that's what came out you know
stem cell research
well there's a number of concepts
involved you know
the spirit doesn't come into the embroio
until the third month with third month
so apparently three months it's only a
physicality a biologic animal thing it's
not really like a humanness until the
spirit comes in in the third month so
there could be certainly some definition
of why why the cal the calibrations
would vary whether you know stem cells
are taken before after the third month
something like that it's not an area
that I have much area addition in
>> mhm
>> doctor the uh the row versus weight
decision had to it created this
arbitrary thing of trimesters and that
seems to follow along with this idea of
the spirit coming in three months was
there any truth guiding the uh arbit
arbitrary division of a pregnancy to
trimesters.
>> No, it's sort of traditional in medicine
to refer to them as tr semester
trimesters
and uh certain things are appropriate
for each trimester. Uh we just happen to
hit upon it you know uh because of
people's guilt about abortion etc. So if
you abort a fetus less than 3 months it
it's an it's only a physical thing. It's
not a it is not human yet. Of course, it
has human potential, but uh
nevertheless, it's not a human spirit
involved in it yet. You know, it's still
just an embryo. And that's what we found
for research. As I say, I don't have any
position about it. Don't know the other.
You know, I myself don't feel justified
to take human life once it exists as
human life. I would not take it upon
myself. And uh the oath of apocates I
took is not not to destroy it. So I I I
would not be allowed by my own medical
ethics to do so you know despite the
sociologic problem the lady has.
Sociologic problem is a sociologic
problem should be solved sociologically
uh you know within its own realm. I
think
>> context versus uh context versus u
content is very confusing to me. Is
there a way of maybe
uh getting a little better handle on
that.
>> Well, content is uh yes, we have a in
fact we have a slide on it. Uh content
versus context.
The content is uh what's within the
field. It's defined. It's linear.
>> Demarcated. I see. But this doesn't
happen in a vacuum. It happens in an
overall field. Now,
a field and the field influences the
consequence. Let's say are certain
procedures
violations of uh
um the rights of citizens uh privacy
etc. are they a violation or not a
violation? So you read the law
it depends on the context. So it's
obvious that in a time of war this is
appropriate. In a time of peace it is
not appropriate. So the context makes
all the difference in the world. We did
things during the war because we were at
war that you can't do at peace or if
you're at peace. You see uh it's not
appropriate. So the
>> so the context then is the overall
field. Now context includes intention.
So it it it brings us to situational
ethics. Uh even the courts of law, how
guilty is a person? We're talking about
culpability. Now, how culpable is the
person? Well, the court of law says the
context is this is a mentally
person who thought Jesus was telling him
to do this. That totally changes the
consequences of the action. On the
contrary, let's say the other condition
would be a jealous lover who was
intoxicated and shot somebody. The
context is completely different. So in
one case the jury would be lenient and
the other case they would be more
stringent because the context is
different. Yeah. So context then is also
an energy field. The infinite context of
consciousness itself is the emanation
of the power in the form of energy of
that which is divinity. Huh? Out of
which arises all creation.
One cubic centimeter of empty space has
within it more potential energy than the
total gravity and mass of the total
universe.
That's correct. Resist one cubic inch of
empty space has within it
because don't forget every second it's
also the center of the universe.
has within it the equivalent of more
equals mc^2
than the total mass of the entire
universe.
So you're dealing in staggering
dimensions. Staggering dimensions. So
here's the
there's really three things. Here's the
event that's linear. You take a
photograph of it. Somebody running over
a dog in the street. Yeah. Here's the
approximate field. And the there was the
nearest conditions is it was a rainy
day. A rainy day. And she had a few
highball. She had a few martinis.
It was a rainy day. She had a few
martinis and she ran over the dog.
However, the reason she had the martinis
is her mother and father had just died
and she was grieving, was trying to
quiet herself, etc. So the even greater
context was although she was wrong here
you could see. So each factor that you
add then adds to to the context
context the infinite context of course
is the mind of God. The infinite context
is the infinite
infinite field of consciousness itself.
And the reason we talk about the justice
of divinity is absolute. And the reason
we talk about cons consciousness as the
absolute
is because its power is infinite.
And karmic propensities are every time
we make a choice or a decision in the
infinite field of consciousness which is
infinite power. We gave you an anal
analogy of power.
The field of consciousness which is the
radiance of divinity. Its power is
infinite. its power. So the infinite
this this field here
its power is infinite. There's a wow
thereby
I use the analogy of an iron filing.
This little iron filing is positive at
one end and negative at the other end.
So it's your little karma iron filing.
This is your little spirits. Every time
you say yes to that which is integrous,
it charges you this this end of your
little magnet. Every time you say yes to
that which is not integrous, you pull
yourself down in the field. So as you
make thousands and thousands of
decisions, if you ever look at how many
decisions you make 24 hours, it's
amazing. Thousands. Literally, you got
to choose between here or there. Every
time you move your body, you got to make
a choice.
So this is a world of the greatest
karmic opportunity to undo the negative
and to gain the positive. Because every
time you choose integrity and truth etc
you charge yourself this way and every
time you choose the opposite you move
yourself this way. Now this is not
happening this is not happening in a
vacuum. This is happening in a field of
infinite power the consciousness of
divinity itself.
So where you are in the overall field is
just a consequence of that which you
have become. That's why there's no need
to worry about where you go after you
leave the physicality. You go to that
which you are.
So all these little iron filings then
you can see the justice of God is
constant. There's no judgment day
isolated day. It's all the time because
you're constantly moving closer and
closer to to divinity in its positive
aspect etc. And then when you refuse
that divinity, you say, "I don't believe
in God." And you become blasphemous.
Man, you go down to the bottom of the
thing and you leave the body and find
yourself in hell by your own choice. By
your own choice.
To be in the complete absence of God is
hell. It's agony beyond all
descriptions. I've inferred it here
inverted to you here a number of times
and describe my own personal experience
with hell.
Yet it's far beyond the most horrible
imag imagination you can conjure up in
which torture and all that kind of stuff
is child's play.
It's an agony of the denial of hope
forever. And in the state of agony of
hell, you experience forever. You get
what forever is. And the dread of
foreverness of damnation is the horror.
It's not just the damnation. It's the
foreverness. Forever eternally.
Eternally with no hope at all. Eternal
hell.
So that's why I tell people don't fool
around with which is negative. Don't
even play with those with those toys
because they're radioactive.
It's not any place you ever want to go
ever. Not any place you ever want to go.
Therefore, you'll never regret having
chosen the Integress level. You know,
you could say, well, if I had only
bought that stock, I'd be worth this
much. So, if I had only done this, those
are all the hypothetical, you know,
because we're guided by our karmic
propensities. So, you value some things
more than personal gain. And the fact
that you value integrity and truth and
honesty and love greater than gain or
already moves you in the field as you
can see. And therefore, you don't have
to be afraid of leaving the body because
when you leave, you're going to be with
that which you are.
If you're like the purr and love kitties
and love puppies and you're a heart
person, when you leave the body, where
are you going to find yourself? You're
going to find yourself automatically
with the heart with the heart energy
field, the heart, the heart heavens.
There's multiple heavens. Multiple
heavens.
Some of these things will just reaffirm
because some people may not have been
there. I'll get to them that one next.
Yes. Resist. There's multiple heavens.
Resist. Each one is the equivalent of
exactly that which you are. Resist. So
nothing to be afraid when you die. See,
we already said none of us are afraid to
die if we could all go to go over at the
same time. We did that last time, didn't
we? We all go over at the same time. Is
it okay to die? Yay.
We got to go over all by our little lone
selves.
No.
>> So, you're going to be with that which
you are because how else could it be?
So, you're the Aaron filing. That's your
spirit. And when it moves out of the
physicality, then it's in the non the
nonlinear. And uh it's it just is with
what it is. So, there's multiple
heavens. Multiple heavens. And all these
religions that claim an exclusiveness to
heaven are both wrong and they're right.
They they don't have an exclusiveness to
all of heaven. They only get their
neighborhood.
They get their they're the pipeline. So
if you're whatever that guy is that's
running for Congress, what do they call
him? Someplace or other. They they have
their own heaven. You got to have 13
wives or something to get there. Well,
that's true for that heaven. And if
you're not one of them, a Mormon, I
guess. If you're not a Morren, you don't
get to go to Mormon heaven. Well, that
sounds okay, isn't it?
So each sect, each religion, each
denomination has its own heaven. You
don't get into that heaven. So it does
control the pipeline. So I don't know
that Catholics get into a Baptist heaven
or not.
I expect that whatever you are in this
lifetime in its idealized form has its
own dimension in the nonlinear domain
and you become attracted to it because
like goes to like because you merely
radiate out that which you are. Yeah.
you wouldn't be attracted to something
that is not what you are. Yes.
>> Dr. Hawkins, what I'm hearing is uh
almost a little disconcerting from the
standpoint of
if you're moving over with the same
state of consciousness.
Are you taking all of the You know, it's
like there's some things I'd like to
leave behind.
>> Well, you can leave the body behind.
>> If I can leave the mind behind. If I can
leave the mind,
behind, right?
>> Well, what did the Buddhist say about
that?
>> What are the great the great teachers?
>> Quang po.
>> It's only your addiction to the linear
that brings you back to the physical in
the first place. So, let go of your
identification and addiction to the
linear both attractions and aversions.
>> But where does that fit then with what
you're saying?
>> Fits perfectly. Just what I said
years. Huh?
>> Take it home and contemplate it for
another time.
>> Oh, no. No. Ask your question. What is
your question?
>> Well, in other words, you're what I'm
hearing you say is that you're you're
taking over In other words, where you
are right now, you're taking over um
that state of consciousness. And you
said no. Yeah.
>> Because all your in other words, that
would mean you would take all your
addictions or attractions or whatever to
the linear. So, I don't get what what
you're saying is to to where I'm hearing
if if the surrender of the linear
>> yes
>> is my primary purpose and the state
>> yes because it takes you to the high
don't forget the heavens calibrated
different levels so
uh
attachment to the linear doesn't mean
you can't go to heaven it just means
that it it's contextualized within a
decision to be loving and benevolent and
forgiving and certain virtues that
doesn't mean you're enlightened. It
means that you would be uh in a very
heavenly uh good place. Enlightenment is
something uh different than that.
>> So the lack of awareness of what that
could be is not unusual. In other words,
um I don't have a clue what that might
>> You're talking about heaven.
>> Yeah. In other words,
>> all I know is what the good book tells
me. What she's afraid of is she's going
to take her addictions along with
>> Oh, you're going to take your
addictions. It's your attachments.
>> Yeah.
>> It's the linear. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well, yes. That's why you're
supposed to surrender them.
If I'm surrendering, if I'm
surrendering, if I'm surrendering all to
God and staying in that sense of
awareness,
>> yes,
>> then I there would not be an awareness
of what would be
to come as such. In other words, in a
transition,
>> that's the most complicated hypothetical
I've ever heard. What are you saying in
English?
>> What goes around comes around.
She's not the point of the choices.
>> What about the choices? Yes. The choices
are
>> If you make a bad decision, you go down.
But if you make a good decision, you go
up higher.
>> Yeah. Of course. You know, that's Yes.
On the other hand,
>> you make a bad decision, you're down
here. But if you make a good decision,
you're up there. That counters that.
>> Yeah. You can undo negative karma.
>> You're undoing that karma. So, in other
words, if you live a good life here,
then you're undoing the negative karma
that you might have
>> created down here.
>> So, the sense of bringing anything with
me is an illusion as well. Well, you
want to live a good life, but you're not
going to take all the good stuff.
>> You're going to bring with you that
which you are,
>> right?
>> It's not something external to what you
are. Yeah.
>> So, in other words, you want to get rid
of all this negative karma down here.
>> Okay.
>> Let me have this arm a second.
>> I have permission to ask this.
The principle of karma is a factual
reality. Use this. Okay. Just in case we
got any karma doubters.
This lady over here's been ask
>> what
>> when do you stop uh reincarnated and end
up in the letter?
>> End up in the letter file.
>> We reincarnated.
So when do we stop being incarnated and
ending up?
>> I don't know. I think you know it's a
whole field of research in itself.
Whether you karmically are entitled to
make a decision whether you're more or
less compelled to follow certain
pathways due to your own actions. You've
lost the freedom of choice.
I think the hills are people who've lost
the freedom of choice and they're not
allowed to
uh change their mind and they have to
undo it. Undo it. So we see on this
planet a lot of people are on their way
up from hell if you ask me and uh
learning a new way. Some make great
progress, others do make do make very
little progress.
>> Another quick one.
Huh?
>> I watched the movie that you suggested
years ago.
In res.
>> What is that honey?
>> It's a movie about this lady who had a
car accident and died and she saw her.
>> Oh, resurrection.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes, that was a wonderful movie. Yes.
>> Yes, it was. She died. Confused me
though.
>> Yeah,
>> because if people have reincarnated, how
can you see these these souls if they in
another body? She was waving at her
loved ones and they were waving at her.
I don't know because it's so many years
since I saw that.
>> She went over on the other side, right?
Yes.
>> Yeah, we're on the other side. She sees
her deceased in in her out of body
experience.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> She sees her deceased loved one
>> that had gone before
her dad, her little whatever. She sees
her relative.
>> Oh, I see. Okay.
>> They were in another body.
>> She was in she was in like one of the
so-called Bardos. Bartles.
>> She went to one of the so-called
Bartles. B A R D O. Yes. Resist. Yeah.
She was one of the Bartles. Yes.
>> The inner plains they're called in
commonly referred to as the inner
plains. Mhm.
>> I don't know because I've forgotten the
details of that story.
I remember that it it was basically
true. I remember
Yeah.
>> If they weren't in some sort of form,
she wouldn't have recognized them anyway
and they wouldn't be waving back.
>> Oh, so she had to recognize the form.
Oh, I see what she I I see what she's
talking about. Yes. Okay. Yeah. She's
talking about um Yeah. Well, they call
Bardos. The inner plains. She's talking
about the inner plains. Resist. Yeah.
>> About the so-called inner plains where
you go in between lifetimes
to hang out with your pals.
Well, there are certain realms where you
have the privilege of uh undoing the
negative and gaining the positive.
There's other realms where you do not
have that. You have to earn that, having
the having disputed it, having spit at
it, having thrown it away. Uh you may
have to go through quite a bit before
you get that uh the permission for
choice back again. Yeah. People who uh
spit at God and divinity and things may
find that they've lost the uh choice.
They've lost the freedom of choice.
That's the penalty you pay. I always
tell people is it's not a good idea.
>> Okay, we're about five minutes over. So,
you can answer one more question and
then
>> Okay, one more question. I Yes. May we
have it quickly?
>> Yeah.
>> Go ahead. Calibrate the audience.
>> The audience.
>> Okay. This audience is over 440 450
440. This audience is over 440.
The consciousness of mankind is at 205.
>> The consciousness of mankind currently
>> is over 204
205. Consciousness of mankind is at 204.
And this audience comes in at a
consciousness of 440,
right? 445. Yeah. As compared to
mankind, you realize it's that's an
extremely advanced group, you know.
Uh the consciousness level of mankind.
The consciousness level of America.
We've been doing that every month, too.
Keeping a sharp eye on it.
See if they see if they need any kind of
help from us folks.
>> I can't do that.
>> H consciousness level of America. We
have permission to do that. It's over
421. Resist.
Oh god. It went down again. It It went
down again. Oh, nuts. It's at 420.
Resist.
Yeah.
M
>> we're doing something wrong.
>> We're down to 420. Yeah. Well, when you
look at the
combination of uh Islamic terrorism for
relativism, as the pope said, uh is
enough to bring down Western
civilization. Let's see if that's a
fact. That's a fact. Resist. Yeah, the
Pope's right. I agree with him right
along. Take the combination of the two.
mode opens the door for the Trojan horse
and then the Trojan horse jumps out. So
we're recapitulating ancient Rome
which the same conflict was inevitably
headed in the same direction for the
same reason for the same reason. Yep.
It's the downside of democracy.
Now said as Socrates said, you give
freedom of speech to the people and
freedom of the vote, they will bury
themselves eventually. They will sooner
or later destroy themselves because the
unprivileged will vote themselves all
the privileges and they don't have the
responsibility to respect the freedom of
free speech. Free free speech is
constructive if it's used
constructively.
It's destructive if it's used
destructively. See, you can't say free
speech is great because free speech will
kill you.
You can say anything on today's blog
sites, correct? To destroy yourself,
destroy your family, destroy reputation,
destroy companies, destroy integrity.
So, it's a two-edged sword. Course of
miracles teaches, you know, only a one-
sword. Forgiveness is a one-d sword.
Freedom of speech, etc., is a two-edged
sword. You can cut yourself as well as
you can cut your opponent. So we have to
be aware of what is the downside of our
society, its upside and its downside. So
that we have a balanced view that the
things we've died for are fantastic. And
if misused, they'll kill you.
If you misused, they'll kill you. So
that's our cheery thought for today.
Do we do what do we do now? Do we have a
break again? break.
>> Uh, that's our upbeat note. No, what it
means is but what it means is freedom is
ours. Freedom is ours. So, you see the
karmic opportunity of free speech.
You're now given that with which you can
curse God and blaspheme and destroy your
soul and try to destroy the souls of
others. Or you're given the freedom of
speech to stand for integrity and
virtue. If the law says you can only do
this and not this, there's no karmic
merit, is there? The only karmic merit
is you're free to either steal the
chocolate or not steal the chocolate. If
there's no chance to steal the
chocolate, you haven't scored anything
for virtue, have you? So every time we
calibrate it, we get that this human
life is the most perfect opportunity for
the advancement of your consciousness,
for the gaining of positive karma and
the undoing of negative karma.
Therefore, this world is perfect as it
is. Resist Zoe.
Yeah, I'm I'm I I'm honored to be with
such people. I'm honored. We should be
honored to be with each other. We are
honored to be with people who have
gained sufficient karmic merit that they
have been allowed to be in a world like
such as this where we have the power to
transcend the negative other dimensions.
They have no such choice that we have
earned, you know. So we can respect each
other that we have earned the choice to
gain by merit and to pay the price by
lack of merit and sure enough we do pain
pay with pain and that's one reason we
grow. So we're uh this group is
enlightened to you know is destined to
become enlightened. This is a class of
the future enlightened which I've known
all along. This is the class of the
future enlightened beings of the coming
worlds. I understand
and it can evolve and come back. Evolve
and come back. So these are the teachers
of the future standing here right now.
And that's why I am honored to be your
teacher.
>> I I'll make sure. We'll see what I can
do.
Okay.
>> Look at the beautiful flower.
>> Do you have a pen?
>> Really?
>> Oh, yes. I'm sorry.
>> How are you?
>> No question. I just wanted to sit here
for one moment.
>> Okay.
>> Oh, a book by a genius. Good God.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you so much.
to laugh at yourself makes you immune to
being laughed at by others.
You laugh at yourself, nobody, you know,
makes you immune to being laughed at by
others.
>> So, I should start laughing.
>> How can they how can they hit you where
you haven't already laughed at yourself?
So, that's why being sensitive is so
neurotic. You see,
give me a break from being sensitive.
You know what I'm saying? How was
somebody could laugh at themselves?
>> Yeah, you are shorts, fat, stupid, and
ugly. Yep.
>> Now, what else?
And you're cheap, too. Y
Dr. Hawkins, you've talked about um the
experience of the total suffering of
mankind at one time.
>> Yes.
>> And you've described it as a revelation.
>> Yes. Was that a divine revelation or was
that um more of a luciferic? Um
>> neither one. It was a realization
uh an opening of an awareness. It's like
I saw the totality.
Uh it came on spontaneously.
But I you know been studying the
endeavoring to reach the core of truth.
you see uh for its own sake and uh and
wasn't consciously thinking about any
such thing but then it came as a
revelation and if you see uh something
like 85% of mankind lives below 200 and
the amount of hell that people are
experiencing is enormous. Now, if you
project that back in time, the totality
of the suffering of mankind throughout
all the time,
it blew me right out of being a
religionist to being an atheist.
>> So, I'm trying to understand how to
avoid making uh that kind of mistake.
>> It's not a mistake
>> of jumping to the conclusion that there
is no God.
>> Oh, that's part of one's process. The
it's one You might say a karmic test
what you do with the revelation.
Use that to curse God
uh or dedicate to overcome it. So you
could choose the high road or the low
road to help relieve that suffering or
to add to it.
>> Thank you.
>> It could be a physician is more uh
aligned with seeing that because you're
confronted all the time with human agony
and suffering
and it's like your enemy in a way. In a
way, it's your enemy
to be subdued and beaten. Yeah.
>> Dr. Hawkins, as I listen to your
lectures and I study your works, a
couple of things became seem to become
clear. One is that it's important to not
mix up levels that
>> Yes. But another is that it is important
to apply spiritual truth in our lives.
>> Yes.
>> And yet often times people may go astray
or make mistakes because um spiritual
truth has been taken out of context and
misapplied.
>> That's correct.
>> Can you speak to us a little bit about
how to recognize more accurately when
that's being done so we don't fall into
that
>> other than calibrating it? You see
because at a certain level of awareness
you intuit it. You see it uh at level
600 the opening of the third eye of the
Buddha body the third body
you you have the capacity to discern
appearance from essence before that you
don't.
It would be up to your spiritual area
edition that you picked up from the
teacher and the teachings and from your
own spiritual study
but after a while you begin to intuitit
it. You see, when I get a letter, I I
always know what the calibration is. As
I open the letter, I get the energy of
this ready,
>> right?
>> And I'll say, I don't think I'll read
this letter.
I heard enough of that.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Spiritual education. Spiritual education
is what uh would serve you in thatstead,
you know.
Hi.
>> Yes.
>> Um, I'm from Malaysia and you left it
out of your book. Can you calibrate?
>> I don't know where Malaysia is.
>> It's above Singapore, below um,
Thailand.
>> I never knew where Malaysia was. I never
been there.
>> Can you calibrate it?
>> Malaysia.
It's between what?
>> It's just above Singapore, below
Thailand. above Singapore
>> below Thailand.
>> It's on the other side of the globe.
Right.
>> Exactly. On the other side of the globe.
It took me 49 hours to get here.
>> Mission to do Malaysia. It's over 350
375. 370. That's very high.
>> Wow. Okay. And I just wanted to know if
you could just send a good wish to my
children.
>> A good wish. I'm sending it right now.
God bless you.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Singapore ranks quite high. the best
part of the world.
>> Sign it.
>> Oh, it sure is.
>> Well, Malaysia is a is a Muslim country.
What kind?
>> Muslim and Singapore is not.
>> Yeah.
>> So, Singapore is higher.
>> Yes, it is. Singapore is higher. I never
I was uh in China in South China Sea for
Mosa
and uh Shanghai and that we swept minds
in East China Sea after the war as soon
as the war was over. So I got to explore
that part of the world. I loved it. It
was very exciting. I loved the the
>> You can come to Malaysia.
>> I didn't come to
>> I'll send you a ticket.
>> I'll have to find out where it is again.
Just get on the airplane.
>> I only see the near side of the globe
when I have breakfast, you know. I can
see this side of the globe.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you for being here, by the way,
from Malaysia. Let's have a hand for
Malaysia.
>> That was a long flight.
>> It took her 36 hours on the plane.
>> Needed some more books.
Yes.
>> Uh you had talked about uh uh John Paul
II
and uh John Paul
>> the pope.
>> Yes.
>> Oh.
>> And about um
>> the current pope or the one right before
him?
>> The one before.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. John Paul. And also you talked
about Dalai Lama.
>> Yes.
>> And you said that if they moved on they
would not be able to manage their
organizations.
>> That's true.
>> So um how would they move on then?
>> If they go higher on the scale they
can't. It seems to
>> in other words if 570 would be the ideal
level for the head of a world church
by the time you get into the really high
500s
>> you're not able to function that well
and at 600 they would have to get
somebody else to run the church because
it's the last thing you can do to take
care of all that linear
>> right so for any of us if you move to
move on does that mean we have to give
up our businesses or families and
>> stuff like that
>> there there are times where that will
would be a choice. Yes.
>> Is there any time a choice where you can
stay present in in this life with your
responsibilities and still uh evolve
spiritually?
>> Yes. There's nothing standing in your
way of evolving because it's not just
what is but how you are with what is.
>> It isn't what is, it's how you are with
that.
>> You could say if you're a millionaire
does that mean you can't get to heaven?
No. It's how you hold that million.
If you're willing to lie for it, cheat
for it, if you worship it, if you see it
as the source of happiness, if you see
it as a source of something outside
yourself,
>> you can be povertystricken,
>> right?
>> And be much more materialistic than a
millionaire to whom the million is
nothing. It's just a responsibility that
he has to use for the good of mankind.
Yeah. Many millionaires become
philanthropists, you know, because they
want to turn it to a better use,
>> right?
>> They've already fulfilled all the
personal needs and another million
doesn't mean a thing to them,
>> right? Does that mean that the Dalai
Lama is attached to his his uh managing
his uh you know,
>> no, I didn't say it was attached,
but he's suitable for that.
If you're going to be a swimming team,
you got to be a certain length, a
certain stroke. You know what I mean?
you're just suitable for that.
>> So the most suitable for a world church
would be around 570. By 590, you're not
going to be that interested in the
world. And below that, you won't have
enough spiritual power uh to head a
world worldsized church, you know. So
570 was probably ideal. You see, by the
time you get to 600, you bliss out.
I don't even know why this body is still
here. Because at 600, you're invited to
leave. Everything is perfect. this
complete and total fulfillment except
you've made some karmic
um agreement before this lifetime
>> which is what I get out of it. You know
this is what went on with this entity
here. Yes. Because of a prior agreement
I knew that there was something to do
with that because you don't have to come
back in the world but some come back in
the world but not many most leave. 50%
leave the minute they hit 600.
So for this group that you said it was
mostly teachers in this life, next life
will have they made a commitment to to
stay for mankind
and many of them will make that choice.
Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> It's good, isn't it?
>> It is good.
>> It's not an obligation. Okay. It's like
when when Sir Alex Alex Fleming
discovered what penicellin could do. He
saw what it could do. Now, he didn't
have to do what he did, but he felt his
being a member of the family of man.
Here was something of great benefit. He
couldn't rest until he knew somebody
picked up the ball. said the same with
consciousness research to be able to
tell the truth from falsehood is
understood by only 15% of the people who
who hear it. Do you know the great
majority of the people even after I've
said it to them 20 times don't get it?
>> You have an instant capacity to tell the
truth from where falsehood about
anything anywhere in time about any
subject whatsoever with very few things.
>> How many people get that?
>> I didn't get it.
>> I tell you last time you said something
about
>> it's totally impossible. Yeah.
>> Something simple like don't eat sugar
and chocolates and you won't get
depression. and I remember it for one
month and then I forgot
>> and then I listened to your CD and I
remember it again.
>> Yes,
>> it takes a number of repetitions.
>> That that's why we repeat that. We keep
going and back over it because I want
people to get it by familiarity, not by
linear memorization.
See, so if I read, you get a new car, do
you ever get the manual that goes with
the new car? You'd have to take a month
off from work 24 hours a day reading all
this stuff. Instead, you have the
salesman show you where's the onoff? Oh,
it's here. Then how do you make the
windows go up and down?
So you learn familiar. You learn by
familiarity. So the reason I read I'm
somewhat repetitious
>> is it becomes sort of an automatic
knowingness in yourself without having
to go through the linear description of
reading the operator's manuals. E.
>> Yeah. Now, now I've read your books many
times except for the last one, but the
practice of it is is not easy. What is
it? One thing that you would say to each
of us that if you keep practicing that
one thing,
>> it gets easier and easier. The
resistance, don't take it personally.
It's not you personally resisting. You
personally have decided already to
transcend it. Yes.
>> It's the ego fighting for survival.
Mhm.
>> You're asking the ego to give up its
what it's learned is the is necessary
for survival. So you're pitting your new
right brain with the condundolini
energy,
>> right?
>> Against your old animal left brain whose
instinctual says bury your teeth and
growl and kill your enemies. See?
>> Yeah. Even if I have that thought, I
don't want to have that thought. Makes
me unhappy.
>> Yeah.
>> So what you talked about earlier,
>> so you assimil you assimilate. You say
that's just my animal nature and thank
you God because without my animal nature
I wouldn't be here complaining about my
animal nature.
>> Thank you.
>> So we have to love the little animal in
in us because it weren't for the little
animal in us we wouldn't be here to
complain about the little animal in us.
>> Thank you Susan.
>> Susan, can you make sure that they lean
into the mic?
If you could, everybody asking a
question, lean further into the
microphone so the satellite room can
hear.
>> Thanks.
>> Great question.
>> Hey D. Hey, what do um teachers of
Advita teach west on purification but
more on sort of disidentification with
the ego that the false sense of personal
doership?
>> Let's see. Start over slower.
>> Yeah, I'm nervous. I'm sorry.
>> Um a lot of teachers of non-duality,
>> they don't really
>> a lot of teachers of non-duality.
>> Yes.
>> Oh, yes. Yes.
>> They don't emphasize purification to the
same extent that they emphasize the
false sense of personal doership that
there's no figure behind thoughts, do
behind actions. So is purification of
the personality really necessary to
reach enlightenment?
>> Yeah, there's no contradiction between
them.
>> Yeah. Not to not to say they're separate
paths, but for instance, u Romesh
Balsikar teaches that it's just a sense
of personal doership.
>> Yes.
>> And he says instead of trying to go out
and purify your personality, he's saying
to analyze your actions until you come
to the firm conviction that you are not
the doer.
>> What do you think of that technique?
>> That's a faster way. That's the way of
non-duality.
>> Okay. Yeah, that's what I'm asking.
>> That's what I teach. Non-duality.
>> Yeah.
>> The the direct way through consciousness
itself.
>> Okay.
>> Yes. You don't have to bathe every
morning in the Ganges to accomplish it.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> The upside of that is you don't have to
bathe in the Ganges.
The downside of it is you don't get the
blessing of bathing in the water of the
Ganges. Remember the water of the
Ganges? Calibrates over 500, right?
Despite dead bodies, garbage
>> Malaysia forgot her picture
>> because it's been sanctified by the
devotion
over the centuries of the faithful.
>> Here we go.
>> Okay, great. Thank you.
>> She cut in line there, didn't she?
>> Did you cut in on you, lady?
>> Yes.
>> I'm up here because I'm I'm terrified to
be up here and that's
>> Oh, good. Good for you. Scared. You
should be scared.
>> Being in front of large crowds of people
that I don't know just sends me into
major panic attack. And having a camera
pointed at me is my
>> Having a camera pointed at me is my
second biggest.
>> They can't pay any attention to them.
>> Okay. It doesn't
>> It doesn't make any matter what they
think.
>> Okay. Well,
>> if they think you're good, they're
stupid.
>> If they think you're bad, they're
uninformed. So, why pay attention?
>> Okay.
Can I get my picture taken with you so I
can get over that one also?
>> Oh, golly. Liz,
>> just sign it. It's open.
>> Oh.
Yeah, speaking phobia. I had a speaking
phobia when I was young and uh one time
I was presenting a case to when I was an
intern to the whole medical staff of the
hospital and uh once a month we had a
medical staff meeting. So I'm presenting
this case and as I get through about
twothirds of the first page of the of
the case, I knew my voice wasn't going
to last the rest of the page. So, I
concluded it
and the and the medical audience went,
they thought I was done. I learned
nobody's listening to you.
That's a true story. They applauded.
Isn't that funny?
>> Did you hear what she was talking about?
>> He He didn't know what you're talking
about. So,
Thank you.
>> We project our fears out into the world,
you know.
>> Here you go.
>> You always have to ask yourself, well, I
look at myself as I'm answerable to God
at all times. I'm answerable God to God
for what my choices and what I become.
>> Huh?
>> Okay, we're moving along. Yeah.
>> Hi, Doc.
>> Hi. Hi. Um my question is about the
experience or edge of the ego. Um does
that mean one transcends the experience
of existence itself?
>> Eventually
eventually you you become the witness to
the phenomena but there is no entity
doing the experiencing. So you realize
it's a sentence without a subject.
The phenomena is happening of its own.
That comes just as an awareness. You're
not trying to accomplish that
realization. You're walking along and
pedaling your bicycle and listening to
the birds and suddenly you realize it's
all happening spontaneously of its own.
>> Mhm.
>> And uh
well besides being the experiencer, you
see the the reason you're identifying
with it is because the the ego juices
the experiencer. It wants it's more than
just experience. It wants to experience
experience.
It's a subtlety. With meditation, you'll
get it.
>> Thank you.
>> You can watch the movie or you can be
wanting to be the one who watches the
movie.
>> Thank you. May I have a picture?
>> Yes.
He wants a picture.
Give him a picture ticket.
Dollar and a quarter.
Extra 50 cents. I smile.
Hi.
>> Yes.
>> Um, I have a question about um I seem to
have a lot of intellectual curiosity.
Um, like my um like I'll be listening to
you and my mind will kind of wander off
on something sort of I think ultimately
irrelevant of what you might say that's
actually going to help me with my
spiritual growth. And how do I my
question is how to um not go there.
>> Well, each I would look at each piece of
information of equal value
and because you don't know when you're
going to need it.
I think something I never paid any
attention to in this entire lifetime
that what I call the final doorway came
out of nowhere.
Came out of nowhere.
Not from any place, not from any entity,
not from any mind, not from any memory.
It was just a knowingness already
present within the space.
So you don't know what's valuable or
not.
>> So don't weigh it.
>> Mo mostly what you don't think is too
valuable right now is someday you'll be
walking down a path and wow, you get it.
You say, "Oh, uhhuh."
So you build up a store of knowledge and
that's one part of spiritual endeavor
that you build up a store of knowledge
of teachers, teachings, pathways,
religions, different ways of looking at
it. The 10,000 pathways to God.
>> 10,000
that take a while to check them all out,
right?
>> Thank you. And I have one other quick
question to ask you. Um you I've heard
you talk to people about um with being
in the process of like moving out of
depression, healing, transcending it,
and um you talked about staying off
sugar and
>> Oh, that of Yeah, you you can try that.
>> I I've I've been going about it and um
I've looked at different like books and
cookbooks even. I like food and I wanted
to find yummy stuff and um a lot of them
say like lowfat, no caffeine. Um, and
some of them I've got contradictory
though. Some of them say like low fat
and then the next one will say eat
milkshakes and have beel for breakfast.
>> But you're talking about a sugar-free
diet. What that got to do with
sugar-free diet?
>> That's what I'm wondering. I've looked
at hypoglycemia diets and so fat doesn't
>> No,
>> no, just stay away from
>> you live on protein and fat and you
avoid sugar especially on an empty
stomach.
>> Okay.
>> And if you do eat something sweet,
h the best sugar is fructose. Fructose
is fruit sugar. It does not create an
insulin response.
>> Okay.
>> And in the health food store, they have
fructose candy bars and fructose uh
sweets.
>> So stay away from like
>> in fact it's more sweet than glucose or
dextrose.
>> Okay.
>> But it does not release insulin.
>> Fructose.
>> So you can sweeten anything with
fructose.
>> Okay.
>> Clorically I think it's about the same
but you don't trigger insulin response.
>> Excellent. Excellent. Thank you very
much.
I had the first barrel of fructose in
the United States. It was shipped to me
from Scandinavia.
>> What do you want me to do with this?
>> Just sign
>> in return for which I wrote the forward
of a book for somebody who had written
about the value of fructose in various
ways.
>> Just
>> and if I wrote the forward, they would
ship me a barrel. I had the first barrel
in the United States. So we had it all
packaged up in little pound packages for
our patients with hypoglycemia that they
could put fructose on their cereal in
the morning.
>> Okay.
>> Lead a normal life.
>> Um
I want to talk about an experience that
I had. First of all, I want to thank God
for Come on. You got to get up next.
>> First of all, I want to thank God for me
being here and I thank God for you.
I was reading the eye of the eye and the
power of now and I went to this class
and it was the class was about staying
prayed up. So the teacher says
just say you love your God with all your
heart with all of your soul and with all
of your might. So I go home and I sit in
my wing back chair and I get comfortable
and I brea She said breathe in too. So I
breathe in.
I love God with all of my heart, with
all of my soul, with all of my might.
>> This energy took control of me.
>> Energy.
>> I would say it.
>> It was said in my sleep when I turn up
at night.
>> Oh.
>> And I play this little game with myself.
I try to see how long I could go without
thinking. But thought came to my mind, I
would blink it out and I would say, "I
love my God with all of my soul, with
all of my heart, with all of my mighty."
Dr. Hawkins, I was reading your book and
I felt your presence.
The energy from you was in my home.
Things got better.
I was going
I thought you were going to say somebody
stole the chocolate out of your pantry.
>> And this this this present was with me
and it grew
and I knew I was going a place I had
never been before. The silent got so
strong it hurt my ears and the birds,
all of the background music came forth.
>> Yeah, I got where you were.
>> I was sitting on my patio and it had
been raining.
I looked down. There was a worm.
I could see the worm suffering. I could
see everything around me. We was all
connected to God. We was from the same
source.
This energy got into my hands. It was so
marvelous.
>> I was I got up in the morning. I was
going to work
and there it was. Everything was still
>> Everything was still
>> Everything was still and silent. I stood
in my my bedroom and everything was
silent.
>> And I knew I was in the presence of God.
>> You knew you were a child of God.
>> I knew I was in the presence. it. I felt
the presence.
>> Oh, I got you. Yep.
>> This feeling came over me to leave.
I And then I go, I can't leave. I got
grandkids.
>> So, I didn't go. But then this fear came
over me. The fear was total terror.
>> It was
>> The fear was terror. The ter the fear.
>> She turned down the chance to go.
>> Oh, the chance to go. Yeah. Yeah.
Because the fear came up
>> after that.
>> Yeah. I was there and then the the fear
came.
>> Yeah.
>> And this energy it felt like energy was
this energy was in my home. It was it
was extremely scary.
But now at at the at the point I'm now
it's as though
God is in me
but it's more dormant sort of
>> but more what
>> dormant
>> it's there you know but it's not
>> she had a real high experience and now
she's kind of come back down.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. That's a revelation. Yeah.
>> Yeah. So that's what you
>> the presence of the self with the
capital S as the ego diminishes takes
over and you get periodic like an inner
radiance
>> yes
>> inner radiance comes up sometimes like a
light
and then sometimes it stays sometimes it
diminishes sometimes it goes away and
doesn't return for a while because
there's other things you got to
accomplish in the meantime
>> right come back
>> if that light that dazzling state stays
then you don't accomplish anything
further in the world you Generally,
>> I can see why.
>> Let me take you out.
>> But it's it is it's hard to
>> I can see why
>> I can see thing that I didn't see
before.
>> Yeah. The revelation
>> that it is hard to deal with certain
things that I see
>> because people don't know what they're
doing.
>> You do well.
>> I keep praying.
>> Yeah.
>> You do.
>> Thank you. You're good. Okay. Thank you.
Yeah, the field comes up of its own.
Let's see. It was angelic. I guess I
think one of my angels
visitation of an angel. Huh.
>> Yes.
>> So, you're visit by the angelic. You
know, she was consciously aware of the
presence of the angelic.
If I'm honest about it, I have to admit
that uh sometimes when things don't go
my way, uh a feeling of resentment will
come up sort of towards life or fate or
towards God. I, you know, I don't know
how to
>> Good thing
>> articulate it, but yeah, it so I'm
wondering I mean,
>> how do I transcend that?
>> Oh, yeah. No, that that's normal. And of
course uh you just to keep applying
spiritual principles to see it
differently to experience it
differently.
Uh instead of resisting it you welcome
it and uh forgive yourself for being
that which you are. Yeah.
See a lot of people out of guilt will
repress and suppress such things instead
of facing them. And then you look to see
what aspect of yourself is that coming
up, you know, and you pray to outgrow
that aspect of yourself.
Thanks.
You ask what aspect of yourself that is,
what role that is. Trouble I always had
was with the spiritual knight. He was
always getting mad and indignant at
evil.
>> Hi, I want to thank both of you very
much. And I came up here for two
reasons. One, I like being close to the
two of you. And the other is I have a
question. If your life's karma gave you
an autistic child who's low functioning
and let's say plausibly below the level
of 200, do you have any advice?
one has a child who calibrates below 200
>> who's autistic.
>> Well, you you you try to be the best
possible parent you can. Yeah, that's
all to overcome those proclivities. You
know, uh if you can engender a love of
beauty, of music, of uh of church going
of uh alignment with integrity.
Yeah. Alignment with integrous people.
Join the Boy Scouts, the Girl Scouts.
People laugh at that. The Boy Scouts and
the Girl Scouts calibrate higher than
about 90% of people in America.
>> But if his
>> 460 480 So all the things you can to add
the structure of integrity and
the pleasure in fulfilling one's
potentiality, you know,
>> if his manifestations are noisy and hand
flapping and non-verbal and kind of
disruptive to other people.
>> How old?
>> 16.
16.
>> Oh, is it a treatable condition?
>> I don't know. I you know, I haven't seen
progress past a certain point.
>> He's still in school.
>> He goes to a special school for autistic
children.
>> Oh, yeah. Okay. So, he's a special child
with special needs. Okay. So, now you're
making Yeah. Okay. Putting him in a
diagnostic category.
>> Well, you do what you can on every every
level the same as what you would with
anybody else. Yeah.
And uh there are certain obviously
karmic propensities that came forth in
this way and certain things that could
only be learned per perhaps by the
entity except in this particular form.
>> So you bless it forever whatever its
karmic purpose may be.
>> Thank you.
>> Do you mind if I have a picture?
>> Must be difficult for the mother.
Thank you very much.
>> It'll push you towards saintthood
quicker
>> having a rambunctious child, you know.
>> Yeah.
>> Dr. Dawkins, if one intends
enlightenment,
is it is it best to envision this
lifetime or just forget timing and leave
it all up to God?
>> Yes, I would forget about the time.
Uh you know what the work is, you know
what the pathway is. So you just do
that. Besides, there's no way you can
rate your progress
because
just when you think you're doing the
worst, you can suddenly break through
into a realm that is beyond anything
here to for
uh so there's no way of guessing, you
know, where you really are with it.
The best thing is to just persevere.
Persevere with faith that
you're being attracted by your destiny.
You see, most people consider themselves
propelled by their past. They never
realize that your destiny, which you've
chosen by your own commitment and
alignment, is what's pulling you towards
the future. You're not being driven to
enlightenment. You are being pulled
towards it because of your attraction
because you're having said yes to it.
So, you set the machinery in motion when
you decided that you would like to
become enlightened. It wasn't such a
light decision. And it was a heavy one
because now it realigns your whole life,
you know, and your whole life is now
being pulled in that direction. So you
don't have to look look at it as though
I I of myself
alone have to drive myself to the
future. The future is pulling you. So
you let go resisting it.
>> That's the easy way.
>> Let go resisting
being pulled towards the future.
You don't have to drive yourself to see
the beauty of all that exists. The
beauty of all that exists has a magnetic
attraction. I mean, look at that rose.
It's enough to knock you out. If you
really look into that rose, you're not
going to get off this stage here. And
neither am I.
I mean, it's incredible.
The just the color is stunning.
It's perfection is stunning.
The color is stunning and it's
stillness. It's stillness is perfection.
The absolute perfection. So if you see
it there, then next thing you know is
you see it here. Then you see it here.
Then you see it here. Then you realize
that it's not different than what you
are. That you are also perfect at this
moment.
You are the perfect expression of that
which you are at this instant.
Good enough.
>> I love you.
>> Yeah.
>> Except we don't have to water you every
day like the rose.
>> This is the most incredible rose. I
mean, it's just unbelievable.
Hallelu.
Hallelujah.