What's that?
>> I I don't understand how money can trump
peace. That doesn't make sense.
>> Money trumps peace. Yes. Because in our
in our world, let's take the UN. The UN
calibrates about 190. In the UN
routinely, money always trumps peace.
They've never had peace once.
Money always trumps peace. All the UN is
all the 198 countries dealing with each
other. I'll give you these oil
contracts. You give me this uh lower the
import tariff fund cotton and you
compensate with a little gasoline money.
It's deal making. Deal making. Yeah.
It's only self-interest.
The League of Nations didn't work either
and for the same reason because people
are way too self-centered.
You'd have to be, you know, quite high
to give up a gain for the good of the
world. For the good of the world, you
know,
and if you ask them about it said,
"Look, I'm a politician. I'm not a
saint." You know, business is business.
Hallebertton made 90 billion so far in
this war and moved to Dubai where the
taxes are lower.
Doesn't want to even help pay for the
war that they're making the 90 billion
off.
And the one of the biggest philan
one of the multi-billionaires that
finances the far left interestingly
bought 400 million worth of
uh Hallebertton stock.
I think you see what I'm saying.
He's a big protagonist of all far-left
causes. about when Hallebertton moved to
die bay and they wouldn't have to pay
the taxes he saw the you know they was
400 million or 400 billion or something
so rich billions and trillions if
all right US philanthropists you see are
the United Nations
is not a philanthropic organization
none of them give any money to anything
they calibrated 180 to 190 so here
you're vilifying American America, which
is the most humanitarian country in
world history,
even the richest of the rich, calibrated
455.
Uhhuh.
And then you condemn America and say,
"Well, we should turn I never forget
that politician in the last election. We
should turn to the United Nations."
I turned to the United Nations.
So the UN is the sheep's clothing. The
sheep's clothing. Don't you see how
simple it is? Sheep's clothing.
Now the world loves blame. I just quoted
you a couple of uh these philosophers.
The most one who just died this in March
that America deserve 911 you see because
uh it's ginous and uh successful
successful
blame. Blame calibrates at 180. Look how
people hang on to blame. Why? Because
blame the real struggle in our world is
for moral superiority. There's only two
things that count in this world. Don't
kid yourself.
The moral high ground and money.
And in the meantime, linking up
a 17-year-old sailor's dream come true.
Link up, baby.
We never would have gotten a war fought,
I'll tell you.
In contrast to blame and hate and all
these things that the world clings to
and milks them for all they can get out
of it, the Amish response to the murder
of the children calibrates at 540.
I thought it was the best demonstration
of Christianity and the teachings of
Jesus Christ that I've ever seen. I've
never seen that level of
presentation of the teachings of Jesus
Christ. forgive them for they know not
what they do. Imagine remember the Amish
did and then they provided money for the
families of the perpetrators because
they knew if they were indicted and put
in prison the families would be without.
They collected food and clothing and all
for the families of the killers.
So the Amish uh you know shamed us all.
They really did a magnificent job of
being that which they they
to talk about things is one thing to
become them is another. So the Amish
really showed us what it means to become
you know that which you teach. They
became that at 540. The 540 is
unconditional love and that is a whole
level 0.4 4% of the world's population
ever gets to 540. I guess they must all
be Amish.
Most of them must be Amish. The rest are
in AA. I guess
I've already told you that AA story. The
guy comes to the meeting, he's all
looking all wimpy and horrible and
crying and everything. They said,
"What's the matter with you?" They said,
"Well, my wife ran up with somebody and
my car got wrecked and the house burned
down." And they said, "Yeah, but that
was yesterday."
That was yesterday.
All right. So here we see from the view
of point of reality and truth that
phenomena with the world in within the
world uh appear as a consequence of the
reality of that which they are not by
that which they are labeled. It's by
virtue of their essence. Then so you see
the whole argument about nominalization
falls down.
Emergence is a principle beyond
causality
and it means because it's the work of
the it's be it's the work of the whole
both the content and the context
and then you throw in evolution and
things begin to
evolve. We say
what you're seeing is potentiality
becoming actuality
because of local conditions and one of
the local conditions is intention. The
intention for a thing to come about
increases the likelihood.
Uh it doesn't control it but it adds a
powerful thing to the field. Huh? So
emergence you see phenomena are not
occurring as a result of causality.
Causality is based on mechanistic
materialism.
Yeah. And the laws of Newtonian logic.
Huh.
Phenomena become
the their own potential.
So what you're seeing is not really
evolution, but you're seeing the
emergence of this transforming into
that. you're really seeing
transformation.
The consciousness calibration itself is
605.
It's five points higher than than the
600 level. Five points higher because it
does add some additional information to
what is learned.
Opinion and is 140. But you see opinion
is all narcissism.
So my two my face me me me me me me me
me me me me me me me me me me me me me
me me me me me me me me webs webs webs
webs webs webs webs webs webs webs webs
websitites are then the glorification of
narcissism.
So consciousness calibration. One reason
it's 605 is it eliminates your personal
opinion about the matter. If you do it
correctly it eliminates it. It doesn't
matter what you think about something.
If you look at it your pupil will
instantly calibrate it.
It's beyond personal opinion.
All right.
Calling a spade a spade is not popular
in today's world.
There were some things I was going to
present this morning. We asked the arm
and said no.
You can't always call a spade a spade
about everything anytime anywhere.
So discretion then
discretion
discretion means that you just can't
blab everything without taking any
responsibility
for the context in which you're saying
that there's an old Christian I never
liked the term don't throw your pearls
before a swine it sounds insulting you
know swine but we know what it means
but anyway what what it means is you
can't just blab everything and anything
without responsibility for the same
reason you can't call, you know, shout
fire in a theater. You can't just shout
fire in a theater. But what we're seeing
now is fire being shouted in the uh
theater of the media. Mhm.
Calling a spade a spade then
is different than the apologist. The
apologist is at 190. The apologist tries
to pretend, "Oh, they're just harmless
good folks."
When I say, "Good folks, why is your
vest bulging?"
Oh, little bombs. Oh.
Oh, little bombs to blow up the bust out
of the children. Right. Okay. Calling a
spade a spade then is part of spiritual
integrity to standing up for the truth.
You don't have to make a public display
about that. But you yourself should be
willing to do that instead of being an
apologist for truth for dis for untruth.
Become an apologist. Then what happens
when you're an apologist for evil is you
become
aligned with that energy. You pick up
the karma of being the supporter of non-
integrity.
If you cheer on
and make excuses for that which is
vicious and cruel
etc. then you pay the price. The karmic
consequence
of the apologist is that you share in
the consequences of that which you are
apologizing for. Let's ask if that's
true.
That's true.
So when you're an apologist for that
which is not integrous,
make excuses for them. You now share in
that karmic responsibility
and the karmic consequences. So we said
that is one explanation for many of the
phenomena we see in the world. major
tragedies, whole whole groups, whole
cultures are beset.
And if you go back and and do research,
you find karmically they are the same
people that were the
invaders that slaughtered all the
innocents. The Vikings, the Huns, the
Visigos. You look at the history of
mankind,
the Huns, the Visigos. One after
another, the barbarians swept through
and killed everyone.
Mongolian emperors, they killed whole
masses of people, whole countries, whole
cultures. They killed whole cultures.
So you see, there's a collective karmic
debt. Collective karmic debt.
Yeah.
So we see the evolutionary stages of
mankind in society.
Much is made out of slavery, right?
People are still trying to milk it. What
George Washington did.
Slavery was a condition of mankind. All
of mankind until recently. In fact, it
still goes on now. The last country only
made it illegal in 1988.
and it was a financial
benefit.
Now, let's chase back slavery and see if
we can find out what's the truth about
it instead of all the political bias.
In the days of the barbarians,
the Goss, the Visigos,
all the giant hordes, the Vikings
especially,
they swarmed over Europe and various
cultures again and did same thing they
were in. And they killed everyone.
They chopped them up.
When they got through with the invasion,
the skulls of chopped off skulls were
heaped 100 feet in the air. Thousands of
skulls of the people chopped off. The
purpose of
he was supposed to chop your head off.
Some bright Viking somewhere
got you could instead of killing him, we
could sell him.
Oh, so instead of killing the conquered
the later the kings of Africa who were
the basis of the slave trade that we're
familiar with discovered instead of
killing all the members of the opposite
tribe, you could kill you could sell
them for good money. Whoa.
Slavery was the nature of man. Ancient
Greece, most people were slaves. Nine
out of 10. Ancient Rome, nine out of 10
are slaves.
Slavery was a way of being in the world.
And go forget it was a cast society.
Cast society. The emperor at the top,
the slaves are at the bottom. I mean,
who else is going to do the labor except
slaves? And where do you get slaves? You
buy them.
So, they became like cattle. Okay.
Now, don't you see the benefit of
slavery is if you got your choice
between having your head severed or
picking cotton, which would you take?
I got family and kids. I'm going I'm
going to put up with whatever goes with
being alive.
We see that in prisoners of war. They
will put up with whatever it takes. They
don't commit suicide.
So slavery then was a step above for a
step forward for mankind.
You let people live then. Don't forget
they was is as valuable as his
livestock. So you took care of them. So
the lifetime, the length of life of a
slave in early America
was 15 years longer than if he'd stayed
in his native Africa.
He lived 15 years longer. He had
protection. He had vision. He had
dentists. He had doctors. He had
shelter. He wasn't uh killed by
neighboring tribes. So his life was
survived. So he became valuable. At
least as valuable as cattle, horses,
sheep, dogs, right?
So slavery was a step up for mankind.
And of course, the reason the South hung
on to the slaves is because they had all
their money invested in slaves. It
wasn't just a goody goody moral deal. If
you had all your money invested in
slaves and somebody wants to make them
illegal, you're about to go bankrupt. So
the whole economy of the south was based
on the economy of not the moral ethical
uh situation of the slaves but economic
economic.
So you see when you recontextualize a
thing in and put it in historical
background it looks different. It looks
different.
The the ancestors of every person this
in this room were slaves.
What I just said is true. Resist.
Every person in this room, your
ancestors were slaves. It's just how
many centuries do you want to go back?
I'm of English, Scots, Irish descent.
So I'm sure it was the Vikings that
slaughtered my forebears. You see,
and you can track it out with genetic
genetic tracing.
So in other words, to do a make wrong,
if you take a thing out out of the
context of history, you can make a make
wrong out of it. And of course, today's
world constantly tries to juice
everything. tries to juice race, sex,
gender, the whole business, age, tries
to juice it. Why would they want to
juice it? Why? Because the ego gets its
juice out of conflict, contention.
We'd say, you know, that's the problem
in spiritual evolution is you have to
give up the juice out of a that you're
getting out of a position. Now this one
to to the narcissistic core of the ego
is almost irresistible and that is to be
superior and to be right. So the whole
core
of narcissism relativism
is the narcissistic core of the ego.
You would rather lie
and be right and be truthful and not
have a cause that you can beat a drum
about and get a parade going, you know.
All right. Calling a spade a spade then
is honesty.
And the wolf and sheep's clothing
calibrated. I was surprised how low it
was. It was really lower than many other
things that you would think would be
worse. There's something more severe
spiritually
about deception.
Just as the rape of and seduction of
children is a worse crime than the
seduction of adults, the seduction of
the innocent. So the wolf in sheep's
clothing, Little Red Riding Hood, how
does the story go? Little Red Riding
Hood. You remember
how does the story go? Little Red Riding
Hood.
She's gone. She's gone. She's gone.
I thought you remember the wolf and
sheep's clothing. Anyway,
okay. Social equality in the United
States is guaranteed by the United
States Constitution at 550. You see,
sexism and racism and all those things
are at 180. So to try to do a flip over
make wrong, well, you say social
equality is guaranteed by the United
States Constitution 550.
Therefore, if it is not provided, we
should question how come it's not
provided and do something about it. So,
it doesn't mean becoming passive.
Transparency is 425.
Uh deception is 160.
160. Yeah.
And I uh part of the integrity of
spiritual teachers that I teach is
transparency. the teacher what the
teacher's motives, goals, uh everything
should be transparent,
transparent to all. Uh this interesting
paper about a local group in this week's
uh what is it called? Red Rock News.
Yeah. About a a group that operates in
the exact opposite of what we've
recommended. Yeah. Exact opposite.
Transparency means everything is open.
and you've got nothing to hide and
you're not resorting to deception. Okay.
Uh truth itself calibrates as a concept
at 475.
It's Latin version 485 somewhat high
because it has it comes out of greater
history. Slander and false witness is as
low as 75.
Therefore, it must be very difficult to
be a politician.
All right.
In in the other than the US, politicians
lie over 99% of the time. 100% of the
time
outside the US politicians lie about
100% of the time. 99%.
In the US, I wonder if it's over 90. In
US it's
a truthful over 90%. No women.
Okay.
>> Okay. We have permission to ask this
one.
Politicians as a matter of course are
forced to
tailor the truth close to 100% of the
time. All right. So it's because of
their job. They have to tailor the
truth. tailor the truth. All right. But
they're not the quickest pathway to
heaven, right? I guess
we won't substitute a politician for the
pope anyway.
All right. Social equality,
transparency, then truth and veritas
against slander.
Uh what is this here sitting here?
The label came off of something.
What?
>> Oh, it's time to Oh. Oh. Oh.
Anyway, the Bill of Rights,
Constitution, and US juristprudence all
are extremely high. And um All right,
we'll we'll quit here. We'll resume
afterwards. Any questions before we go?
Anybody got anything quick and easy?
Quick and easy.
>> No. Quick and easy. All right. We'll can
reconvene at what time?
>> At 2 o'clock.
>> 2:00.
>> We shall resume.
Okay. What uh slide were we on last
week?
>> 103.
>> So, how many uh let's see those new
slides. How many did I give you? I gave
you four, right?
>> Yeah. There's four slides on that.
>> Yeah, we're on we're on 103 and there's
104, 105, and 106.
>> And we're on 103.
104.
>> So, how many more have we got to go?
>> Two more to go after 104.
>> Okay. Oh, boy. I better hustle up.
>> Um, I don't know where our sheets were
that were here.
>> What?
>> We had sheets.
>> Oh, no. Yeah, but those are removed.
>> Well, we got a secret this morning. Uh,
we learned a secret that, uh, money
trumps peace.
That means we can have peace and you do
it via money.
We thought you could only get it by war
and killing people. You make sufficient
financial adjustments around the table
that people would rather have peace and
be rich than war, which is expensive.
So, we buy them off. Isn't that easy?
Give a few shares of Walmart and
Well, I think there's a certain truth to
that that money
money is really in the most practical
way money adjustments, you know,
>> the made the secret to the way of peace
is money.
You heard it here.
Heard it here.
>> You buy your way to peace.
People do it, don't they? Don't they?
Ransom or all kinds of ways.
Why? Because peace becomes an ism.
pieces becomes a ideolog ide ide
ideological
politicized thing which immediately sets
up resistance. Immediately sets up
resistance. Yeah. Anyway, I thought that
was an interesting uh interesting uh
thing to notice.
Uh where are we? I don't even remember
where we were.
>> Oh, we did the Amish truth
>> constitution Bill of Rights.
But
>> Einstein calibrates at 499 and there's
still people writing books criticizing
Einstein. They calibrate at no.
And if Einstein was wrong, how do they
explain Niroshima and not Nagasaki?
That would be an uncomfortable truth,
right?
New Testament minus Revelations
is 880. Secularism is 165.
So if you give people a choice, you see
the choice they're making to refute uh
you know Christianity or or spiritual
truth for secularism. You can see now
why the calibration level of western
world is sinking because as it
it isn't that uh religion is really
destroyed or under attack. It's too busy
scuttling its own ship.
You look at the history of the Episcopal
Church in recent decades, you know,
they've scuttled their own ship. Yeah.
The Archbishop of Canterbury who
calibrates at 400 writes a book in which
he puts in BCE instead of and and AC or
with these secularized things. He
doesn't want to offend
the Muslims. I don't want the Muslims
reading the New Testament. Do you?
They've got their own book, you know.
So, you know, it's scuttling its own
chip via relativism. Via relativism.
Yep.
Okay. Humane Society calibrates at 410
and PETA calibrates at 100.
There's a book called uh
let's see what's the name of the book. I
forget the name of the book. Anyway, it
gives you it gives you the back the
background on the on the people who
founded like you ACLU uh PETA etc. Uh
intellectual morons I think is the name
of the book is
when you read about the people who
founded these organizations you say I
don't believe it. It means all of
mankind should be sacrificed
for the animals. In other words, it
comes between your life or an animal's
life. the animals life should take
precedence. So you you see relativism is
like a complete reversal.
Uh American Civil Rights Union ACLU
versus the American Civil Liberties
Union. Well, the guy who set up the uh
the Scopes trial is the same guy that
founded American Civil the ACLU. ACLU
calibrates at 130.
It's opposite is the American Civil
Rights Union which calibrates at 460.
This was founded by a bunch of uh
ministers, I think Protestant ministers
at 460.
It emphasizes that the constitution
guarantees the right to freedom of
religion. Freedom of religion. Which is
why the pilgrim fathers came here.
Pilgrim fathers.
We did. Uh, didn't we do this?
>> Yes.
>> All right. That was number two. Okay.
>> So, now we want number three, right?
>> Uh, yeah. We we did one to two. After
dad comes three, after two comes three,
right?
Didn't until I went to college. Now it's
a 2 plus two is four is is a white man
oppressive.
All right. So we see uh one of the
greatest books written interestingly is
extraordinary popular delusions and the
madness of crowds by Mackey I think
written in the late 1800s revised in
1980.
Extraordinary popular delusions in the
madness of crowds. You see uh
here we have an example. The earth's
temperature
uh is of human origin
as proposed in inconvenient truth
calibrates at 180.
What humans do is create pollution but
pollution is not the cause of the earth
warming. And we got a negative on that.
And uh I remember I was surprised too. I
thought, huh?
And so I investigated further. So when
you don't get an answer that conforms
with what you would imagine, you start
doing research and I found that the
Earth's temperature is due to the
magnetic activity on the surface of the
sun.
And I think I've given references to
that before, Science Magazine,
Environmental Report and News. Uh by you
know core drillings in the Arctic going
back 15,000 years. the uh cyclic
temperature of the earth is correlated
with the sun. But when you look at the
amount of energy the sun puts out and
the size of the sun compared to the
earth, you realize that that man's
contribution through pollution
uh is 0.8
degrees Fahrenheit. If we all stopped
all polluting,
the earth would cool down zero.
81 degree Fahrenheit.
So what's the cause of then of uh
pollution is overpopulation is it not?
Yes. So you want to get rid of pollute,
you want to get rid of earth warming,
pollution is not the answer. But if you
do want to get rid of pollution, uh you
just can't have so many people, too many
people. I hate to tell the quick
connectors that, but that's the way it
is.
I guess quick connectors don't make
people. I imagine that's Oldfashioned.
What do they call them? Contact
connectors. No. What do What's the
website?
>> Quick quick connector. What do they call
it?
>> Well, maybe I will get reborn. What the
hell?
The word I grew up abstinence until
you're married was the abstinence until
you're married. Anyway, I guess that's
really old fogy. All right, let's pick
1955 again. Academia in 1955
calibrated at 440.
440 is the level of the colleges
recommended in that book I gave you the
citation if you're interested in. We'll
put it on the website the reference to
it. ISI international
students or something.
Anyway, 440 is traditional academia in
which they teach the great books of the
western world etc. Academia in the
United States currently is at 180.
So you're you're sending your children
to become indoctrinated. Marcus says the
purpose of education is indoctrination.
Indoctrination, not education, but
indoctrination. So you're spending all
that money, tuition money
with professors. There's a book called
the professors. The professors 101
famous professors in the United States.
Then n then I'm calibrated over 200.
101 professors it's called. I forget the
the author of it. I got it somewhere if
I could see out through these.
>> Huh?
>> Yes. Correct. Yeah. Uh-huh. All right.
So,
at least we know what what what things
are going on. Logical integrity
calibrates in the 400s. You see,
sophistry, which is what rhetoric and
relativism is all about, calibrates 180,
190. Now, the argument between sophistry
and and intellectual integrity
was solved back 350 400 BC.
Haven't the universities heard that yet?
It was Psalm 450 BC and recorded
throughout history in Plato's dialogues
and
oh golly, how can that be? Logical
integrity is the 400s rhetoric which was
taught in one ancient Rome. how how to
present a thing in such a way as to
influence the audience
has nothing to do with logic, integrity
or truth
at all.
Traditional morality
uh that's called traditional America is
490.
Now currently Mark Huz and all those
recommend that it be replaced by
hedonism.
hedonism. The purpose of life then is
self-indulgence
and especially of the erotic variety.
Hollywood uh movies, remember they had
the haze office. Well, that's the next
one. Hollywood back in 55 was a 265
and in 2007 it's a 180. Huh. The um
Hayes office.
uh people here don't remember the Hayes
office but in Hollywood they used to
have like a a review board and if it was
too erotic unsuitable for children etc
uh they ruled against it they had
certain rules or they at least
classified it mature adults their
children etc. So they tried to protect
they didn't restrict free speech. You
could still say it but it was not
recommended for children.
So Holly with the Hayes office
calibrated at 430
at 430
and porno films still existed but they
were in theaters rated AAA or quadruple
4A. The ad would say 3A, you know, and
that meant adults only. I mean, don't
bring the kids. So, freedom still
existed. It was separated from the main
current of society.
Uh, Hayes office, the Sundance Film
Festival this year calibrates at 165.
How to have sex with horses and various
interesting things.
I don't know. Horse never turned me on.
I just don't know.
In other words, you know, to to explore
deviance for its own sake is what it's
about, you know. And the guy who runs
this, well, he was going to leave uh he
was going to leave the United States,
what's his name, got reelected, but he's
still hanging out. I don't know.
He was going to leave. Uh okay. The
classic philosophy then is we all know
440 to about 485.
The Frankfurt school calibrates 130 to
180. That's what relativism came out of
came out of. Now the Frankfurt school
interestingly was really a Marxist
society.
They thought the name Marx Marx would be
too inflammatory. So they called it
social social theory or something.
under the Nazi during the Nazis they
they moved for for safety sake even
though they were Marxists they did not
move to Russia they did not move to
Russia interestingly yeah they are
Marxist they didn't go to Russia for
safety they went to Columbia University
in the United States the Frankfurt
school then was lodged during World War
II at Columbia University
who who's president not God in 190
and whose faculty has dropped
precipitously. Anyway, it came to
Colombia University and and then when
the coast was clear, uh it moved back to
Frankfurt. Moved back to Frankfurt.
So,
Hayes office, Boy Scouts and Girl
Scouts, calibrated 450. Now, these two
organizations are anma
Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts do everything
that relativism considers horrible.
Uh, patriotism,
integrity, truth, helpfulness to others,
concern for others. So, in contrast,
what the ACLU supports is NAM law, which
calibrates at 140, which legally
safeguards the attempts of older men to
rape uh, young boys. Yeah.
Raping young boys is okay.
Girl Scouts and Boy Scouts not okay.
You see an inversion of what's called
the traditional
uh luciferic inversion. Satanic as well
as luciferic
boy scouts and girl scouts which are
character building on honesty. You know
a scout is honest a scout is helpful a
scout isn't. And this is the right to
seduce and rape young boys. Yeah,
classic philosophy as compared to the
Frankfurt school. So we have substituted
Aristotle at 498 with Maruz and his
teaching is called critical theory.
Critical theory at 140 to 150. And I
read you some of the dictims of critical
theory this morning. Sophocles uh at 465
the relativistic philosophy 130 to 190.
Hangpo
calibrated at 960. Oh yeah here he is
960. Uh Dawkins who feels that you know
religion should be banned
calibrates at 190. So what rel
relativism is doing is asking us to move
from the level of the 400s 500s live
300s down to less than 200.
Therefore that would explain why when we
calibrate
uh consciousness level of the western
world uh we see that it's going down. We
see that it's going down. I had thought
even in some of the beginning lectures
we gave here that consciousness the
level of man was going to go up and keep
going up like that. No, it turned over
and came down.
So it could be the karmic purpose of
this life, you know, is such that we
have the options and it may be that
there's going to be waves of fluctuation
in which mankind overall rises and then
falls. You know, I don't know because I
haven't been alive for that many
millions years.
Classic philosophy. Aristotle and
Sappathy. All right. Quang Poe versus
Richard Dawkins.
Dawkins. People of the lie. Uh M. Scott
Peek at 450.
M. Scott Pek was a psychiatrist. Can
compared conspiracy theories and
paranoia, you know, nutty professors,
etc. Now, M. Scott Peek was a
psychiatrist and uh it's a very
interesting book. It was a bestseller
some years ago. How many people here
have read People of the Lie? Oh, good.
So, there's, you know, familiarity.
Um, I just rediscovered that book. I'd
totally forgotten about it. But, uh, he
concluded that the basis of evil was
narcissism.
the refusal to grant that there's
anything greater than yourself or your
own ego, even if it's uh your
neighborhood school, uh that evil is
really nothing but unabashed, totally
naked narcissism.
I thought that was interesting. So, here
he is a psychiatrist and after listening
to some people for some years, he
decided basically they weren't sick,
they were just evil.
Well, that was not exactly a popular
opinion in the psychiatric field. Evil
good evil and goodness didn't enter into
it, you know. So, I thought it was quite
brave of him to write that and he's
written a couple other books I think
confirming the same idea. But the fact
that he identified narcissism is the
core of it all I thought was quite
interesting. Quite interesting.
Now you see modernism is 400. Modernism
means um Oh, some of my favorite cars
were back in the 30s. They they came out
as streamlined. Remember the first
streamline cars? I mean, they were
terrific looking. They're collector's
items. I mean, they were sleek, gorgeous
looking cars. And of course, they
replaced the old model A Ford. So,
suddenly when a sleek car came out, it
knocked me out when I saw the first
streamline car. So that was a modernism
was really modern design in architecture
and in auto mode design and
refrigerators everything. Uh so
modernism is 400. Postmodernism however
is only 180. So from modernism it then
fell fell down. U yeah
intellectual morons. Oh yes, I mentioned
that book this morning. Yeah, because a
lot of the people were quoting. It's
it's a very interesting book. I mean
not, you know, it could be boring if
you're not interested in the subject,
but the question is how could such a
tremendous reversal
uh 180 occur? How could it possibly
occur?
And uh this gives you the the personal
lives of these various people. And I
found it was very educational just like
M. Scott Pick's book is educational
intellectual morons. US society in 2007
is currently at 421.
Yeah, it was a day or two ago.
The world overall right now comes out at
205. Uhhuh. Now, they had both been
higher. You'll remember from our
lectures a couple years ago,
uh they it's come down just about four
points uh just in the last couple of
years, I suppose, from the impact of the
two things that we're talking about
today.
Cable News calibrates 410 to 440. That's
higher than I thought. Uh oh, the
Huffington Post, MySpace, YouTube is at
140.
Although we castigate the the
announcers, they do have a certain
amount of credibility. That's the cable
news. Okay. So, we'll go to the next
one.
I just wanted to put that in because
the the blogger land, whatever they call
that, www internet computer world uh
zone thing is is uh has quite a
detrimental effect apparently.
and and I just picked up I never heard
of her before but I was on TV the other
night in the news and I said well what
does that calibrate at? I mean what are
people looking at for their political
viewpoints and uh that it's that low is
sort of shocking.
Uh the essence here we have man has the
capacity for reasonal
cortex his intellect. So his intellect
really starts about 200 and then
continues on up.
See animals have intelligence. They have
intelligence.
Now, so reality, truth and essence uh
really requires the prefrontal cortex
which is not really too operative till
you get to 200. Relativism which is
based on appearance and illusion depends
on the physiology of the other side of
the brain which is called the limbic
system operating out of the amygdala
which is emotionalized
narcissism
emotionalized narcissism.
So, how are we going to talk people who
think with a different part of their
brain into seeing things the way we see
them?
Maybe we're not.
Maybe that's up to evolution. Maybe
that's up to karmic merit.
Maybe that's up to something other than
political persuasion.
However, after what we've learned this
morning, I would try to buy these people
out.
They'll do anything for money.
Why not give up war for money?
Give them money for everybody they don't
kill.
Discretion then is 375.
Vilification and desecration are 120. So
the disagree. To disagree, you don't
have to go to vilification
and desecration. See, you don't have to
drop way down to 120 or 130. You don't
have to curse America or curse Americans
or or you can just totally disagree, you
know, and just say, "I don't believe I
would do it that way."
The Statue of Liberty uh like patriotism
and the flag and other things calibrates
at 500 because its energy is more than
just its physicality.
The MM's plane setup calibrates at 180.
Yeah. So this incident is trying to hide
under the cloak
of freedom and liberty.
We will imitate exactly how plane
hijackers operate right down to the last
iota and then if we get a response. So
this was a fake setup. This was staged
uh then we will threaten to sue. So this
was a setup which under the cover of
relativism
they get away with. But calling a spade
a spade, it, you know, it was very
obvious what was going on to begin with.
In fact, they went to extremes to ask
for seat belt extenders. So they
imitated exactly
what the hijackers had done. And when we
responded, so
what we're up against is people that are
more crafty, more crafty, more crafty
than we are. We're still naive babes in
the woods.
People think that had to do with
religion. It's got nothing to do with
religion. It has to do with setup.
Setup.
All right. Abstract thought, you see, is
at 450.
Concrete thinking is at 190. 190. So
this level of thinking can't pick up
the context that you're being set up,
baby. You just fell right into it. They
set it up and you fell right in.
because you don't get the abstract
meaning. See the abstract thought is
450. Concrete thinking is 190. So
all right
meaning itself is where relativism it
really falls down. It says nothing means
anything except what I say it means.
It's totally narcissistic. So it says
I don't have to serve what anything uh
means because it'll mean what I want it
to mean. It'll be what I want it to
mean. It's the ultimate of narcissism.
And we know from Louisis Carol's in the
looking glass.
I forget who it is, the rabbit or the
madhatter. It says a word means what I
mean it to mean nothing more and nothing
less.
That's today's modernism. a word will
mean what I want it to mean. Nothing
more and nothing less because nothing
has any intrinsic essence or meaning.
Therefore, I can label it any way I
want. Any way I want. Uh so the victory
of subjectivism over being objective,
you know, higher mind is a 275 and lower
mind calibrates at 155. These are
different energy uh constellations,
actual different energy constellations.
Uh to be friendly calibrates at 255.
So you can see uh my kitty Bootsie.
Bootsie is overly friendly. Actually
threw himself all over you. Calibrates
at 255
and hostile is at 125.
So why should we be hostile? Why should
we give up friendliness for hostility?
Okay. To stand up for the truth
calibrates at 500. Wow. Why is it so
high? Because truth itself is only in
the 400s. But to stand up for the truth
is different than quoting the truth. 500
then takes
a higher degree of te integrity.
To stand up for the truth willing to
stand up and be counted. It does that
does not however mean to be foolish and
indiscreet. you know to stand up for the
truth
you see is not combative. It's just that
you stand for what you believe in. So
you could stand up for the truth and say
in my viewpoint America is taking the
wrong direction and this is why nothing
wrong with that. Yes. Not into not not
in not not
so tolerance then in the maruzus of
political meaning is 190. It's current
political usage when they talk about
tolerance uh calibrates at 190. It means
tolerance to
to to
stand for which uh you politically
believe in and to try to destroy that
which you do not. So tolerance does not
mean so when people hear tolerance they
haven't read Maruz's
definition of toler to tolerance. Marus
says tolerance means tolerance for the
left and intolerance to everything in
the right which should be destroyed and
attacked and it has no rights. So it's
the complete opposite of free speech. So
you're selling intolerance based on
freedom.
What is the purpose of the world anyway?
Is it up to us to run out there and try
and save it? Let's go burning all
Marus's books.
Should we panic because we see the level
of consciousness of mankind went up and
then now it's coming down again. Uh is
the world our responsibility?
Well, we say what is the question of
this? What is what about the world as a
karmic expression?
A world of you know infinite karmic
potentiality that calibrates at 575. 540
is above in unconditional love. 570 is
is saint saintthood. To see this as a
world of karmic expression then the
unfoldment of potentiality of the human
evolution
is 575. To see the world is unfair
is 200 because you would have to define
what you mean by unfair.
If it's a perfect karmic unfolding then
the world is completely fair. Human life
is completely fair. Let's see if we have
permission to ask that. We have
permission to ask that. Human life is
completely and totally karmically fair.
Resist. Wow.
So, let's give up all the blubbering.
Oh, poor us. Poor humans.
I feel sorry for us. Poor humans. I
think being human is is difficult.
It really is difficult. Really is
difficult. And by by handling and facing
and owning that difficulty, uh you earn
karmic merit. Mhm. You don't get into
heaven that easy.
Got to put a few years in the in the
lines. You know, world as karmic
expression is 575. So the world is not
unfair. Not unfair.
It's doesn't say it's fair nor that it's
unfair because 200 is really neutral.
It's neither fair nor unfair. Therefore
it depends on how you experience it as
yourself. If you see the world is
maximum karmic opportunity.
That's 600. 600. This world is the
world. So this is what the Buddha
taught. The world said lucky it is to be
born a human. lucky it is to be born
human, even luckier yet to have heard of
the Buddha and her enlightenment etc. So
the Buddha said this is a world of
karmic opportunity and that calibrates
at 600.
Its enemies, the enemies of truth say
this is an the world is exploitive. 180.
The world is exploitive. The world is
unfair. The world is unjust. It's a
world of oppression. See,
so that's the victim mentality
that the world is exploitive now means
that the minority
is always being exploited by the
majority. So Marxism always sees that
minorities are all victims. So Maru is
taught
then instead of having it industrial and
has something to do with capital and all
uh what you do is say that
what you do is you say that the minority
is always being exploited by the
majority.
Therefore,
the majority can never be right from the
viewpoint of Marcos.
You instantly become wrong if you become
the majority because now you're the
exploiter. You're the exploiter. Every
minority then becomes
uh a victim.
Old psychiatrists are victims.
Old white psychiatrists are super
victims.
So anything can be colored with what
whatever kind of paint you wish to spare
it spray it. It's a world I prefer to
see it as a world of maximum karmic
opportunity in which you're grateful for
the karmic opportunity to undo negative
karma and create positive karma.
rel the impact of traditional religion
on US society is 450.
The impact the total impact of
traditional religion ethics, morality,
answerability, accountability etc.
uh is 450. Secularism on the other hand
is 190. In secularism you're not
accountable because whatever is wrong is
somebody's fault.
All right, we did money trumps peace.
And now we have a secret that nobody in
the world knows except us.
Give up the peace parades and get some
money and buy us some peace around here.
Now, we're I want to test out what, you
know, the Pope's declaration.
Uh Mhm.
In nonlinear dynamics there's a term
called iteration. Iteration
it means if even in the 26 decimal point
you're off one digit repeated it enough
time it's it will eventually reverse the
world.
Even the an error in the 26th digit
which was in some computer I've
mentioned it in previous lectures some
computer program or something I forget
some chip or something. Yeah. Well they
figured you know 26 decimals out
nobody's ever going to get that far on a
daily use basis. But as it turned out
they did because
so iteration means that the slightest
error slightest error almost
imperceptible error if repeated often
enough will eventually have a profound
effect.
If you're a little bit a little bit a
little bit suddenly you're way off way
off. Okay. So
the destruction of society by iteration
calibrates at a confidence level of 510.
Oh,
so this is merely confirming what the
pope said. In other words, chipping away
at truth, pitching postmodernism,
teaching religious concepts that are
really more satanic and luciferic than
than logical.
eventually by repetition by repetition
by iteration constant repetition.
So that's my concern about the modern
media. The repetition this little
politician gives this little twist. This
little diverseman gives this little
twist. this f uh photograph, you know,
up upstage is the central figure whose
message it is you want to get across
subtly subtly subtly round the clock
round the clock seven days a week year
in and year out by iteration then it
chips away at your capacity for reason
and it results in
damage
to the human capacity to discern
illusion from reality.
So my only complaint or worry about it
as a physician is that this by iteration
the human capacity to discern truth from
falsehood to discern the essence of
truth is injured
that's true resist
so it's the damage to the human psyche
about which I have any concern
not the falsehood itself because
falsehood comes and goes
but the innate capacity of the human
mind. So the programming that goes on in
academia for instance to me I don't
resent the falsehood of it but the fact
that their capacity
to
recognize truth when they hear it has
been injured has been injured
and that's why I want my tuition back.
It isn't that they can't jump
jump uh various hoops anymore, but that
their legs are no longer strong enough
to take them over the barriers. You
understand? They're
their mental anatomy and capacity has
been I see it as urgent. Now, what is
the repair of all that?
What is the repair of all that?
It means that each and every one of us
tries to be as integrous as they can
within their own domain, within their
own life.
Because the energy that you put out, as
you could see from the last slide,
where's the last slide? U affects others
just by that which you are. Yeah. See,
just that which you are to merely be
friendly is 255.
Therefore, one person being friendly is
more powerful than five people being
nasty.
So, the way to offset it is not to make
an enemy out of it and attack it because
that's being seduced to fall into the
trap. But each one of us by being as
loving as we can is
as loving as um helpful as truthful as
honest integrity by our own integrity.
Then as we've said before uh each one of
us you know uh adds to the level of the
sea and as the level of the sea rises it
lifts all the ship ships on the sea. So
the way to help with this situation is
not by attacking falsehood, not by
attacking falsehood, but instead
becoming the fullest uh fulfillment and
development and expression of your own
spiritual potentiality.
Now a group like this, curiously enough,
can be the tail that wags the dog.
We have permission as this.
This group alone already affects the
consciousness of mankind. Resist.
This group alone affects favorably the
consciousness of all of mankind.
Why? Because it is rare. It's unique.
You hardly get this many people together
of a higher level of consciousness
anywhere in this world.
much less with the awareness of how to
discern truth from falsehood and
conscious awareness of consciousness and
the part it plays from
evolution etc. So this this group by
virtue of that which just that which
they are helps uplift all of mankind.
This group alone this group alone
uplifts the conscious level of all of
mankind resist.
Uhhuh.
I just want you to respect the
the innate
the the power of innate divinity within
you. It isn't you as a person. It's that
that which acknowledges and reflects the
power of divinity
already uplifts
all of mankind.
So you didn't exactly waste Saturday
afternoon.
So the contribution you see is not what
you do. That's why I'm not enthused
about peace parades and all because they
just set up oppositional and the cops
and the hoses and the dogs and all.
There is no opposition to you becoming
the fullest expression of your own
potential. There is no opposition to
that.
You have no enemies. Nobody can do
anything about it.
You see, you see how beautiful that is.
So every time you look at the little bug
and you say, "Oh, little bug. Look at
him. His arms ling his back and say,
"Oh, that little bug." You turn him
over. You just change the world. Huh?
You just changed the world. The person
who says bugs, well, I hate them. And
walks on.
Oh, poor little bugs. Anyway,
that capacity to be compassionate to
identify and see the divinity of all the
innate divinity of all of life. Then you
begin to recognize it in all that
exists. And you're walking through the
woods and you look out and you see the
radiance.
Oh, I better not look in there. You you
see the radiance
of nature. You see divinity shining
forth as the glory of the perfection of
all creation
because the creator is not different
than that which is the created. The
creator is within creation, ever
present, ever evolving. And you see the
divinity of all creation.
First you see
uh through lovingness you appreciate its
beauty. It's incredible beauty and you
walk through the woods and suddenly one
day you see a tree as you've never seen
a tree before.
Stunning perfection
stands there radiating out the
perfection of divinity.
And uh
the radiance of divinity begins to shine
forth as all as all all existence.
And therefore your own existence is a
reflection of divinity within yourself.
You also reflect divinity to to a
nonhuman looking at you. They would fall
back in wonderment at the energy that
radiates forth from you. The animal
feels the human coming down the path. He
already picks up the radiation and the
energy of it. You know, whether it's
friendly or not friendly, etc.
So to become all the highest greatest
fulfillment of all that we can become is
to be of maximum service to God, to your
fellow man, to life, to the planet, to
the animal kingdom, to nature.
The best environmental act you can
perform is to be the perfection of that
which you are, to fulfill that
potentiality.
In doing that, I think that's the way to
worship God, who was probably sick and
tired of bills, incense, kneelings, and
drapery. Holy drapery.
God's got I say, "Save me the holy
drapey. I had a couple centuries of
that." You know,
water some flowers. Do something.
Ah, yes. So uh the message that I just
conveyed let's see the message I just
conveyed I have permission
calibrate server 700 8 cal 750
740 745 740 is good enough for Saturday
afternoon
the truth of what I just said is not
just a personal observation that's the
reason I wanted to calibrate it it's
just a recognition of a very profound
truth truth and the more you become the
mystic and less the religionist, the
more these things become very obvious
that the radiance of that which you are
to the world is your the greatest gift
you can give the world to be all that I
can be to this world through thee, oh
Lord,
through thy glory. Amen.
Now, I don't know if we stopped early.
Did we?
>> We can stop early.
>> We can stop early. Uh, well, we're going
to break and then we're going to have
what after after that?
>> Question and answers.
>> We're going to have question answer
>> for questions and answers. If they'll
line up the questions on this side of
the room and book signing on this and if
you have questions and books, that's
fine, too.
>> All right. Now before we break, has
anybody got a got a question of general
interest to the population? Not about
you and your mother-in-law, but I mean
any kind of a general question having to
do with the theory, the essence of what
we spoke about today, pertinent to it.
Yes.
>> You mentioned that
the United Nations isn't serving its
purpose. Is there anything we can do to
promote more harmonious
No,
>> because each one is there to serve their
own constituency.
If a country sends me and pays my way to
get a better deal for hog farmers, I
can't go back that I've given away hog
farming to the Chinese or something. I
have to come back that I got a deal and
how much did it cost? So, it's a it's a
marketplace, a Wheeler dealer. It's a
bizaar. The UN is a bizaarre, a trading
bizaar. Political favors, financial
favors,
status favors, good mentions, etc. Um,
it can only be what it is. I'm not
saying it's bad. It's just that I think
people put false hope in those things
because it sounds utopian. Utopian. You
know, we tried the League of Nations and
that ended up as World War I. Now we
have the World War II that it just
doesn't work. It's idealistic. It's
idealistic but not practical.
>> Yeah.
>> Can you distinguish between being an
apologist
and being forgiven?
>> What' you say about apologist?
>> Being apologist and being forgiven. She
wants to know the difference between
apologist.
>> Well, an apologist makes excuses for
evil and thereby joins it karmically.
Uh
you can forgive evil because they know
not what they do. No problem. But to
forgive it is different than being an
apologist. When you you when you're an
apologist, you take on the part of the
karma. If you say, you know, Nazi
invasion of Europe is okay.
Uh then you take on some of the karma.
Take on some of the karma.
>> Yes.
Bill of Rights.
>> The bill of rights is the constitutional
guarantee of equality and especially
also between the sexes. Shara is a
wholly diff completely different thing.
Uh Shier has to do with certain belief
systems primarily political. You realize
the Quran is 90 about 90% political has
very little to do with religion. It has
to do with the rights of various
subgroups, political groups, physicians,
men, women,
etc. Divides, the Quran divides the
world into two houses. The house of
Islam
and the house of war.
And if you believe the way they do, then
you're in the house of Islam. And if you
don't believe the way they do, then
you're in the house of war. The United
States is in the house of war.
>> Yes.
I wonder if you can help me with one of
the comparisons you made and that is
that I'm a Eagle Scout from the late 50s
and early 60s and um as you described
it, it was the best essence of Boy
Scouts from that era. I'm also a father
of six children, one of whom is a gay
son who is an Eagle Scout. If they had
known that he was gay, and I'm not
talking about being sexual, I'm talking
about attractions as young teenagers
are. If they would have known he was
gay, he would have been kicked out. Yes.
>> And so I'm having a trouble with with
the whitest of the white and it's better
than the black.
>> It has to do with being a scout master,
not a scout. A scout master, you see, is
an author authority position. The
history of people with that kind of
disorder is not too good with with young
children. I myself went through it
myself. So I didn't read this out of a
book.
So somebody can be very integrous, teach
Sunday school and
crawl you into pedestrian which you can
do nothing because the person is bigger,
older, stronger and has authority and
you're nobody.
>> So it's taking them out of that
uh position which is seductive to the
scout master himself. he now knows that
he has available all these kids and
they're saying it's doubtful whether
that person would be able to handle it.
I wouldn't want the legal liability.
I wouldn't want to be running a
kindergarten and knowingly hire somebody
who is known to violate the rights of
children.
>> I wasn't talking about I agree with that
black. I was talking about their
position on the gay issue that's been so
brought up to the Supreme Court and
everything. That's the news side of the
Boy Scouts, not the 1950s and60s. And
that's what I'm having an issue with
trying to look at the Boy Scouts versus
the worst of the worst that ACLU might
uphold. I don't know. I don't get the
question. They're just two different
realms of integrity. Boy Scouts and all
that is about 440 460
and ACLU is about 130. It's just, you
know, pedestria,
you know, they don't even I don't know
if they really know what they've been
def what they defend.
Do they know what it is to be a child
held down by a big powerful strong
person and have your anus reaped and
then you can't hold your feces and you
got to go see the doctor and you're too
ashamed to tell your mother.
They have no idea what they're talking
about. That's what they call them
ideologists.
An ideologue will tell you, you know,
but that's not the reality.
Any boy has been in the reality. I used
to get
h I can't tell you how many times passes
were made at me.
It's not a political issue.
Last time a pass was made at me was
>> Should we tell them?
>> Huh?
>> Yeah.
>> We This will be the last story that
we're going to bring.
>> Went to San Francisco to see my favorite
uh uh opera, La Boy. Yeah.
>> And the San Francisco Opera House, if
you stand out during the intermission,
you're looking over San Francisco City
Hall, a very, very beautiful building.
And I was standing out there
uh during the break and a man came over
and solicited me and I was 75 at the
time.
But he did it in a way that uh his I've
always felt very okay about that because
I could tell the man was really lonely.
He was really a lonely person. And I
felt compassion for his loneliness.
And I always felt like saying, you know,
if I could I' I'd be with with you in
whatever way would please you just out
of your your loneliness. It was his
loneliness that I and of course they
intuit whether you're safe or not safe.
or you been intuited that I was safe and
I just said, "Uh, I I can't really do it
today." And my wife is over there. He's
like, "Oh."
So, I mean, that kind of that kind of
thing is perfectly okay. There's nothing
wrong with a person's solicit.
>> Yeah. But he comes back to me and he
goes, "I'm 75 years old and they're
still hitting on me.
Well, I felt sort of good about it in a
way, too.
And everybody gets hit on when they're
75, you know, too old and ugly.
All right. Now, we're going to take a
break for how long? 10 minutes.
>> It'll be about 15 20 minutes and then
we'll set up for the
>> All right. Thank you so much. We'll see
you after the break. Yeah.
You're a great group.
Are the mic set up for her?
>> Yeah,
>> I'm ready. When you're ready,
>> go.
>> My question is actually somewhat
technical and goes back to the workshop
that you gave in LA in November.
>> My question is about something that he
mentioned in the LA workshop in
November. You talked about attention and
intention and I'm writing on that as it
relates to business and leadership and
you gave some citations
for Medina but I couldn't find them and
neither could my librarian.
>> I think you wrote me about that. I told
you
>> I did. Oh, I never got it.
>> It's I did write you. Uh it was
spiritual I mean it was um psychiatric
news.
Medina, I have the I have the uh
reference. It's uh relatively recent.
>> I may have said psychiatric news instead
of there's two psychiatric newspapers.
I may have given you the wrong one.
Medina should be there on the internet.
He wrote several papers on the subject.
If you send me another email, I'll get
it for you.
>> Okay.
>> I I did answer the email. I remember
specifically answering the email and
giving you the reference because I
looked it back up again.
>> Okay. I don't know. I didn't receive it.
>> Madina. Yeah. He wrote about a series of
three or four papers and they have to do
with the power of intention.
>> Intention sets because it sets your
priorities
which I thought is interesting. It
>> it sets the screen from which you view
the universe. Would that be correct?
>> Yeah. It sets your prevailing overall
intention, you know. Mhm.
Thank you. Going to do a picture.
It gave neuroscsychiatric confirmation
of what we've been teaching about
intention. You think
neurossychiatrically it's been
confirmed.
So you might say in the highest court
you're you're respon you're you're
accountable for what you did and you're
morally responsible for your intention.
It can be a disparity.
More than a question I have an
experience I'd like to relate to you.
Um, it's a memory of waking up laying on
my back and I was looking up to the
ceiling and the walls had this paisley
green wallpaper and it was a window on
the south side of the house and it was a
paper blind drawn down. as light was
streaming through this little crack and
I was laying there just admiring this
dust particles and I was in the most
profound bliss. I could I was happier
than I can't express how the joy that I
was I was experiencing was a broken
light fixture on the ceiling and I could
hear my mother and a woman that I knew
in the other room along with another
woman that I didn't know and I could
hear the tinkling of cups. I knew they
were drinking coffee or tea.
And the door opened
and an 8-year-old girl stepped in the
room with long brown hair and a couple
of teeth missing and smiled and turned
back and told my mother, "He's awake."
And then she walked over to the side of
the bed and started playing with me and
I was talking with her. I was
communicating with her and she couldn't
hear me. And I couldn't roll over. I
couldn't do anything. And I recognized
in that moment I thought, "That's right.
I'm stepping into my existence. You
>> hear you thought what?
>> I was stepping into my existence. This
was a period of my birth just right
after my birth. I couldn't roll over. I
couldn't talk. But I knew
>> Oh,
>> the people in the other room. I knew
that this was my sister.
>> Oh, I see.
>> And it fled right after that. It was
just it was just gone.
It was an opportunity for me and I
pondered that many times in my life of
of knowing of a of a pre-existence,
knowing of a a time before this life.
>> Yes.
>> There was another time when I was 19. I
was in a motorcycle accident and I was
killed and I was gone for a period of
time. had an opportunity to sit with
three what I thought were individuals
and I thought that I was through with
this opportunity on earth. This this
this
>> spirits, right?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> And I was ecstatic to be there. I could
feel this again this most profound love
this this overwhelming joy. By the time
my my definition of it was there were
tens of thousands of previous loved ones
that had been on this earth were
surrounding me and and I was just
overwhelmed with the joy and the love of
being there. And they they said, "Well,
slow down just a minute. What do you
want to do?" And I said, "Well, what do
you mean? I mean, I'm through with the
thing on earth. I'm here. I'm just this
is what I want to do." And they said,
"Please hold on a moment." And they left
and they retreated. There were three in
originally and two returned and said,
"Listen, we've we've just looked over
your existence and we strongly recommend
that you go back. you've accomplished a
great deal, but there's so much more to
to be accomplished.
And I tried to make deals with them to
stay.
And they kind of they got a kick out of
it. They thought that was pretty funny.
They said that, you know, it doesn't
work like that. Just come back. And I
recognized they were going to keep
insisting that I come back until I make
my own decision to be here. And so I
did.
>> And I wasn't very happy about it for the
longest time. I felt why did I have to
come back?
>> Well, you get a chance to leave again.
Don't worry.
I get that.
>> I just wanted to share those with you.
Thank you, doctor.
>> Yes, I like it.
>> Great. Yeah, they were nice.
>> Visitors from other dimensions.
>> Angelic visitors.
>> Thank you. Okay.
>> Sometimes they have to turn back.
Sometimes they can you can let them
rest.
>> Yeah.
>> My question is about um karma.
And here in the United States, I think
most people when you say the word karma,
they mean the sum total of all the
karmic merit or demerit we've acrewed
during the course of our life. What we
do. But when I was reading about karm
karmic theory, I saw the mention of two
other types of karma. One being the um
the planet earth has its own karma. And
sometimes we have acts of nature that
affect us and that seems that seems
pretty um pretty reasonable. But the
third type of karma that's been
mentioned in my reading is group karma
where the activities initiated by others
can forcefully impinge on your life.
>> Yes.
>> So that things can happen to you that
really have nothing to do with your
individual karma.
>> Sure.
>> They're more about the karma of the
people
>> doing it. And it's really um just that
you were there at the wrong time and
place
>> and it happened to you.
>> Yep.
>> So you agree?
>> Thank you.
>> Yes. Is group karma?
>> See just by agreement with the culture
you now have you know for better or
worse.
But you know it can be also for better.
You know, people forget that it can be
for better,
>> right? Group consciousness can
>> group
>> really affect Yeah.
>> our lives.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> You know, you see massive phenomena,
tsunamis and earthquakes and
plagues that affect, you know, large
populations of people.
>> Hello. Um
my question is about um the ego and
self- sabotage
uh like suffering and I don't mean like
uh you know a little guilt here, pride
there. I mean like misery where you
almost like choose that where you rather
be miserable.
>> Yeah.
>> And uh how to transcend that?
>> What's the question?
How to
um how to get out of like self- sabotage
of like a
>> oh self- sabotage is a label.
>> Okay.
>> Everybody has ups and downs, you know,
along the pathway and every time you
have a down, you can't label it
self-sabotage.
You know, that's sort of
pop psychology, you know, call it.
You're not really self- sabotage.
Lots of painful feelings in this
lifetime. You can't call them all
self-sabotage. You wouldn't live long
enough to die, you know.
>> Lowered feelings. Lowered feelings, you
know.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> They come up to be recognized. And then
if you can see the essence of them, you
forgive that within yourself which is
associated with that you know. Mhm.
>> Okay.
Thank you doctor
books by these.
Um, I really don't have a question. I
just wanted to be in your presence for a
moment and say yes indeed.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Yeah.
>> Love you, Doc.
>> Okay.
>> Hi, guys. Okay. Huh?
>> No, the the pathway of devotion, you
see, that's why the the hands folded
this way are so appealing to me. That's
why I liked being in Korea or amongst
Indian people where the devotion
you know to give recognition to the
divinity within the other is so
charming. It's so charming.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't have a question either. I just
uh I have so much panic and fear about
getting up in front of people. I just
thought I'd come up here and just
experience it out every day.
>> We're all going to laugh at your
ridicule and probably attack you with
knife.
>> Now we uh we all are on your side for
the courage to do that and face it.
>> You years ago I had stage fright. I
couldn't give a lecture to two student
nurses.
>> I remember you saying that.
>> Two student nurses.
>> I could I couldn't hold eye contact with
someone for over 30 seconds for most of
my life. But uh
>> and then one day I discovered that humor
broke the back of it.
>> So I want you to keep laughing and think
make everything see the comedy and
everything that exists.
>> Okay.
>> I say I was frozen with terror and then
I by accident said something funny. The
whole crowd laughed instantly. All the
anxiety went away and I've never had it
since.
>> I'll be funnier.
>> Just be funny or see how ridiculous and
absurd and funny life is. Funny. Funny.
Haha. Okay. Can I shake your hand?
>> Okay. Mhm.
>> Thank you.
>> How's it going?
>> Yo,
>> he's a gung-ho kind of guy. He's a guy's
kind of guy.
Um,
if you guys don't mind, I was going to
see if you guys wouldn't mind asking how
many people are on the planet that are
above 600.
>> Oh, we didn't ask that.
>> No, I used to keep keep track of it on
the bullet board. There was uh
over 600. We have permission to ask this
uh question.
Uh there's more than five people over
600 on the planet right now.
More than four.
>> More than five. Four on the planet.
There's less than there was. Maybe
that's why the Oh, I see.
>> That's right.
>> Oh, yeah. That's one of the main reasons
it came down. Oh, wow.
>> That would be good.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> I remember.
>> So, how many did I say? There was
>> four.
>> Oh, four. I don't listen to myself.
Yeah.
>> See, four over 600 is enough to
counterbalance a huge amount of the
population.
>> Yeah.
That's very interesting.
>> So, there's a 600 spot out there
available.
>> Money wins over peace. So, we're selling
it for $10,000.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. Thank you, Susan.
Love you guys.
>> He's a great guy. We met him under other
circumstances.
No question again, Doc. I just want to
come and
>> Oh, yes. Hi. Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Can I get a picture?
>> Yes.
Yes.
My pleasure.
>> Oh, I take such good pictures.
Hello.
>> Hello.
>> I have a question about um creativity.
I'm a musician and a singer and my
intention is that my music would uh
serve be of the greatest service and
good.
>> And I'm wondering
how do I do that? the greatest beauty
that you can summon up and uh your
greatest love or sympathy. I mean,
whatever it is you're trying to bring
forth in your music, beauty itself is
uplifting and loving music is even more
uplifting.
>> Yeah.
>> Is it possible to create a song that
calibrates higher than I do?
>> No.
>> The answer is correct. Resist. Okay.
>> Okay. And um
does a does the let's say a song
calibrates at 400.
Could I give a a performance that's
higher than 400 or a performance that's
lower or will the performance of that
song always?
>> You can't you can't say that.
>> Can't say that. No, you're making it
through prosaic
>> because right in the middle, let's say,
of a song at 400 and you at 400,
you'll suddenly feel a surge of
incredible inspiration and love and
suddenly you shoot all the way up.
>> I see.
>> I mean, this audience blows me out all
the time, you know, because once you
feel that energy come up from the crowd
and, you know, it it summons forth, it's
reciprocal in yourself. So, you're
getting a reflection back of that which
you're sending out. So, the more love
you send out to your audience, the more
they'll they'll uh reflect back to you.
>> I see. The way to have a loving audience
is to just be crazy in love with the
audience.
>> I see. Um
>> I think the Stones used to do that. I
mean, he just gets high on on the crowd,
doesn't he?
>> I'm sorry, who?
>> The Stones.
>> The Stones. Yes. Yes. Um,
as an expression of gratitude, may I
offer a very short a very short piece of
a song that I composed? Very short.
>> A tidbit of a song.
>> Give us a tidbit.
>> Tidbit of a song.
>> Tidbit.
>> Okay.
For all that you are and all you are
not.
I am so thankful
for all that we've got.
You are the reason my purpose for
breathing.
Thank you for sharing
this beautiful feeling
and I love
you.
>> Lovely.
Let's hear it for that guy.
>> Next generation
Jagger.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. That was beautiful.
>> That was very nice.
>> Very good.
>> Yes. I closed my eyes. It's beautiful.
>> I also just came up to sit with you.
>> Yes. And a question kind of came through
a little bit and this is about what is
it that is seeking enlightenment.
>> Good question.
>> Very good question. Nobody.
>> Nobody. It's just like the no mind thing
then. The no mind question. So there's
no mind. Nobody's seeking it.
>> The seekingness is happening of its own.
And there's nobody that is seeking.
Seek. Seeking.
>> Oh wow. seekingness like it it returns
to its source.
Your consciousness wishes, you know, it
returns to its source
and then you're the witness,
participant, observer of that. You may
say it drags you along
by your by your agreement. By your
agreement, nobody's forced against their
will into an enlightened state.
So you're uh you let go resisting the
nature the the
nature of consciousness it is self which
is to return to its source.
>> Okay. So there's no ego involved.
There's not really can you say it's
consciousness seeking its source.
>> Well the it's consciousness is the field
in which all this phenomena is
happening.
>> Okay.
>> And you're the witness observer. Mhm.
>> There it is.
>> You're the witness observer. Mhm.
>> Yes. When you when I'm sitting here with
you and you're telling it to me, somehow
something is transmitted through no
mind. I don't know what it is, but it's
like a transmission that happens.
>> And it's seems to happen whenever you
look into my eyes.
>> So I think everybody's going to come and
look into your eyes.
>> Yeah. Makes sense. Makes sense. Yes.
>> And that and that's what happens. I only
reflect back to you the reality of that
which you are. That's all I do. All
you're doing is witnessing yourself.
So I shine back to you the radiance of
the self which is you.
>> Right?
>> So that's the that's the the godhead
source, the source that is being
reflected.
>> The essence of that which you are is
reflected back through my recognition of
it in you.
>> Right. Mhm.
>> It's like when I put words to it, I It's
gone.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I can't put words to it.
>> Yes. That's exactly it. Okay.
>> Just look at the tree and fall over
weeping with joy. Don't call it a Don't
call it a tree.
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Don't call it weeping with joy.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Just fall on the ground.
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> Have the Let the worms have you if they
want.
>> We got it.
>> Well, worms got a too, you know.
Thank you.
>> I I agree with her. When I come up to
ask you a question, I get lost in your
eyes and I have to get the video to know
what you said to me.
>> That's true.
>> We want to express our gratitude for
your teachings,
>> right?
>> We want to express our gratitude for
your teachings.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And English doesn't do it.
I hope I hope perhaps this expresses
what it feels like
when I'm in this presence. Yes.
>> Oh, beautiful. Yes. Thank you very much.
>> It's a
I don't know how to explain it. Not
really sense that
>> it's
it's just an expression. It's
>> like a radiance. Radiance.
>> It's a radiance. It's a radiance.
>> And in the radiance, you see the beauty
of the tree outlined against the light
in the back.
>> Right.
>> Mhm.
>> Thank you so much.
>> It's almost like a rainbow.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Beautiful. Thank you.
Well, I want to thank both of you for
the uh the opportunity to be here.
I'm not sure if I can even articulate
this question. And if you allow me to
use the David Hawkins experience from
birth on to try to articulate it as a
reference. Um I believe I've heard
understood you to say that at about 3
you realized you came in at maybe 8:50.
>> No, I didn't realize that at 83.
Now looking back on it maybe you realize
that was it
>> age3 I I came out of nothingness into
existence
>> and I was not pleased
>> in the wagon
>> discovered that I existed
>> as soon as I realized I existed
immediately up came the fear of
non-existence.
>> So I believe one time you expressed that
is you came in from the void.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. The reason I'm asking that
question is because you had as you
matured in this physical body, there
were other experiences in the snowbank.
There were experiences of the state of
of being in hell. There was experiencing
the condition at I believe what you
expressed on time, the experience of
conditioning
enlightenment which would be a 600 or
700 and then later experiencing the void
again. Is there something about our
physiological maturation that would
prevent us from realizing those states?
You came in at 850 and later on you
reexperienced 850 with other things in
between.
>> Does that make sense?
>> I don't really understand the question.
Yeah. So spiritual evolution is not a
linear
uh you know linear like this. What
happens is you surpass a certain energy
field and flash you got the whole thing
that opens up the pathway to the next
realization which could be 10 years
later.
And it's not a linear sequence, you
know.
>> Oh, just it just seemed it was funny to
me and it probably is the question of
linearity. Why someone could come in at
850 and then have go through the
experience of moving through the 600 700
that kind of thing.
>> You're trying to give it some
chronological se sequence. It doesn't
work that way, right?
>> It could have happened in the other
direction.
>> Ah,
thank you very much.
Hallelujah.