song.
Gloria and excelsius.
Glory to God made to thee, oh Lord most
high. Amen.
It makes me cry to say that. So I better
stop.
All right. This morning we're speaking
about uh
we're speak I don't know what we're
speaking about this morning. Oh,
creation versus evolution. Yes,
we'll be talking about creation versus
evolution. How many people here are new
for the first time?
Oh, there's always some. Yes, indeed.
Yes.
All right. So, what we usually do is we
go over some slides and they've covered
the basics. We're up to 122 slides now.
We better stop talking, right? Okay,
we're up to 122. Well, we're going to
put them all together as sort of an
atlas, you know, after a while.
Flip through them.
So, today we're talking about creation
versus evolution.
Uh, which is a very timely subject. You
know, uh, last month, Time magazine was
devoted to it, uh, week or two ago. in
Alabama
they had a a major meeting on on it. So
it's an ongoing thing since 1926
uh the Scopes trial defined it but it's
an ongoing debate in our society of
course politically quite viferous debate
whether God should be allowed in the
public arena or not.
You picture God sitting up there.
We're trying to decide whether a llama
on this planet or not. You know, you can
go anywhere but not the US. You can't go
there.
God says, "Well, by myself." I would
hardly believe what I've just heard.
So, we we usually do s a run through the
basic slides for the people that are
new.
and to refresh our memory of the basic
orientation. Huh. And uh and then uh
we'll get to the lecture that's more
specifically to the subject of the day.
So now we're all set to go with the
slides. And uh aren't we?
Well, we could start with one.
Oh, yes.
Anyway,
the reason for this is that it's a
common point of reference, common po
point of reference which has become
pretty much well known worldwide and uh
uh endless people are writing endless
books and they keep wanting to know if
they can reprint this. Uh all right. So
the map of consciousness then is is
important for today's lecture
because we'll see that uh the difficulty
with
evolution versus creation is uh one of
paradigm.
One of paradigm and uh so the
religionist the person who follows truth
uh you know calibrates 200 200 and up.
Do I have a witchimler? Witchimler. I
guess this isn't a blank bag.
Anyway, 200 and up is truth. So, the
amazing discovery was that uh the human
body reacted differently
uh to truth versus falsehood.
And we'll get to the reason for that.
Oh, yeah. Thank you so much. I knew I
forgot something.
So on a scale of one to a thousand uh
you it's an arbitrary scale. You can
make up your own scale if you want and
uh you could make it one to 100 or
uh a th00and to a million. In any case
you'll find that there's a certain level
below which your arm goes weak. Now
this call it you could call it the truth
reflex. The muscle response is that in
the presence of that which is integous
or truthful, the body goes strong. In
the presence of that which is false or
felicious or wicked or evil or whatever
you want to call it, the arm goes weak.
So if I say to hold something in mind
uh that calibrates below 200, her arm
goes weak.
There's no suggestion involved because I
don't have to tell her what I'm holding
in mind.
I don't have to tell her what I'm
holding in mind. So the transmission of
the information
is nonlinear. It's not trackable. It's
not within the world of Newtonian
physics and uh it's only comprehensible
from quantum mechanics and actually the
Heisenberg principle etc. So this
roughly is a is a means of you can
calibrate anything in the world. Now the
thing that's very interesting about
calibrating levels of consciousness etc
is that because you're in a nonlinear
domain
you're not limited to time or place or
causality.
That means we can ask anything about
anything anywhere in time or space not
limited to the Newtonian dimension.
What went on with uh Amelia Heheart,
the uh the famous kidnapping, the Hman
Hman kidnapper, etc. Any of the unsolved
puzzles of puzzles of history, uh you
can find out for yourself
and it's better not to tell other people
because that deprivives them of the fun
of finding it out for themselves.
What happened to Amelia Erhard? Yeah.
All them great mysteries of uh history
uh can be solved within an instant.
Uhhuh. Is uh bin Laden alive and well?
Yes. What is he calibrating now? Where
is he located? You just go over the map.
We always know where area where he is.
I just got a new map this week. Very
wonderful map. You can pin them right
down to what mountain and what cave,
etc. You just you know you say uh you
take a picture of the area you know that
area of Pakistan and then Afghanistan
and then you say which quarter
you get this quarter then you enlarge
that divide it in four you say which
quarter this quarter okay you expand
that divide that in quarters and you
keep doing that by quartering it down
you ex get exactly he's the 224 Helsinki
street second floor rears
Should we tell him how he travels? It's
okay to tell him how he travels.
It's okay to tell him how he travels.
He's 6' five or six
and people in that area are not usually
that tall.
So, he never w travels standing up. He
always sits down and is carried in a
whatchamacallit sitting down. and he
disguises himself as a woman. So it's a
woman sitting down being carried from
here to there. And then the other thing
he uses the people there's only two
people that know where he is.
This is the chain link phenomena.
If I'm a link in a chain, the only
person who knows me is this link and
this link. The third link doesn't know
know me. Only this link knows me and
only this link knows me. Therefore, I
can get from here to there to there
without this person knowing where I am.
You understand? The chain is only to two
two links.
So, one person knows where he is. You
see, that's all that's necessary. And
one person knows where that person is.
But the sixth person in line doesn't
know where the first person in line is.
He only knows the one next to him.
And so
we'll ask again
that's the that's the chain link
technique resist that's why he can't be
found. So now we have this why why he
can't be found and we know where he is
and he stays out of mischief pretty much
stays out of mischief. Yeah. All right.
So the map of consciousness is very
useful and it's only limited by your own
imagination.
It's uh such a change of uh uh sense of
reality
uh to know that from anywhere any place
you can ask anything about anything and
get a a truthful answer and I think we
defined that only about 15% of the
audience really gets that usually today
today let's see today today over 20% got
it 30% 40% 60% 55% 60% %. All right.
Wow. Used to be 15%. Now 55% that people
get
that uh once you're outside the
limitations of the Newtonian paradigm,
you're unlimited in time and space. You
know, you can investigate the secret
life of Cleopatra if you want. See,
there nothing to stop you. However, the
only thing you have to do is ask whether
you have permission to ask that
question.
And so you say, I have permission to ask
this. And if you're going to know, it's
best to leave it alone and not check out
why. Just go walk away. Okay. Next next
next thing. So we're all familiar with
that. We're also familiar with the fact
that the majority of the world's
population this is the world's
population 100%. The the majority of the
world's population is below
consciousness level 200. So the critical
point is 200. 200 and over is truth,
integrity, reliability, divinity. Under
200 is falsehood. It's uh falsehood and
most of the world lives there. That's
why I always look at this world as p
primarily purgatorial.
This is where you get a chance to choose
and undo bad karma and uh acrru some
good karma. All right. So the majority
of the population, so here's the
population of the the world.
And uh this is the percent above 200.
You see now the limited number. And why
doesn't the world fall over? So we'll go
to the next slide. World doesn't fall
over because
uh this percent here is enormously more
powerful than this percent here. So very
few people over here can counterbalance
a great many people over there. If it
wasn't for that, the world would
self-destruct already. Yeah. Next slide.
Huh. The evolution of consciousness over
time. We haven't corrected this one yet.
Over the percent of time, elapse time.
This is the way consciousness has been
rising. You see, at the time of Buddha,
at the time of uh Buddha, consciousness
was here. At the time of the birth of
Jesus Christ, it was here. And then it
slowly slowly slowly went up uh to 207
and then it came back down to 204. So
we'll have to make a note to put a
little curly Q at the top of this. We
all thought it was going to keep going
up
and we all thought it was we're going to
keep going up. Uh so anyway, it took a
downturn. So it looks as though the
level of consciousness fluctuates. It
doesn't make a smooth straight line. It
seems to fluctuate and evolve. And uh
the likelihood of what's bringing it
down right now as far as we know is
primarily
few things we don't want to mention.
All right, we'll move to the next. So it
just to show the earth epics to show how
the level of consciousness of life life
not even human life or particular life
but life itself over the over time you
know began first as an amoeba a bacteria
and then it evolved through more and
more complex
uh life forms more and more complex life
forms
what's important is that for life to
survive so Life resulted from the
interaction of the light of divinity,
the godhead radiating forth.
Encountering matter creates life and uh
this life then evolves and in the animal
world, the prozzoa, the bacteria
versus the um vegetable world. Anyway,
the animal protoplasm of which humans
are made uh lacks inner sources of
energy has to obtain energy from the
environment. Therefore,
while the plant has chlorophyll and just
sits in the sunshine and gets all the
energy it needs, um animal life has to
acquire a source of energy from outside
of itself. Therefore, it has to have a
method of cognition, a method of
comprehending what is supportive of
life, what what should we eat, what
should we not eat. So, the amoeba, the
bacteria from the very lowest level
begins to evolve,
sensing mechanisms of how to sample
what's out there. And the human mind is
one of the most uh developed and
advanced. We think about a thing about
whether it's going to be useful or
harmful etc. We don't have to nibble it.
All right, let's move to the next.
This evolution of consciousness through
the mamleian kingdom. So as we said
starting out here, you have to have this
is the birth of the human ego. This is
the birth of the human ego. You have to
develop an opinion and an information
processing system to tell you what's out
there. And it becomes more and more
evolved, more and more evolved.
And finally, you get up to the reptiles,
the alligators, the dinosaurs.
The dinosaurs calibrated 60.
Well, that's interesting.
We have people in the everyday everyday
news reel that calibrates 60.
You know, schoolyard shooters.
The schoolyard shooter, the worst one,
Sun Cho or something, calibrated the
lowest of anybody we've ever calibrated.
Calibrate five.
Five. Some kind of a primitive
primitive consciousness.
Uh almost like a dinosaur's brain got
into his dinosaur's consciousness got
into them. Do we have dinosaurs up here?
Where's dinosaurs?
>> Well, he's not up to a dinosaur yet.
He's less than the camod dragon. Worse
than a shark. It's uh amazing how that
guy got on this planet. He got on the
wrong planet. He got on the wrong got on
the wrong bus. I don't know. He got on
the wrong bus.
He got on the wrong bus.
Sun cho. Suncho.
Calibrated at five. That's the worst
we've found. Worst one we found so far.
Then we come up through all the uh
wonderful uh animals that we all have
learned to love, you see. And uh then we
get up to the hippopotamus
um and the grazers. So you see a shift
consciousness level 200. Below 200 life
is rapacious. And then from 200 up you
have the option of the herbivore, the
giraffe, the deer, uh the elk, etc. Then
you get up to intelligent animals and
elephant is extremely intelligent and
the farm horses and the kitties at 240,
family cats and dogs and uh family dogs
and the monkeys and the gorillas and the
chimps. And then we have these
exceptional
exceptional ones here. The one who can
identify when somebody's going to die.
The uh calibrated 250. Then we have the
song bird song and the kitty's purr and
the dog's wagging tail. The kitty's purr
and the dog's wagging tail are somehow
magical. Magical.
And every time we want to ask questions
about it, we get not to bother with it.
So we don't
I don't know why but they have something
like a heart in them you see something
like a heart in them that's why we love
them for companions okay so we move next
uh the intellect is uh critical
this is this is very critical today's
academia
we have some members uh here uh and our
staff as well that are very conversant
to what's going on in today's academia.
Uh so this is the traditional academic.
uh the liberal education of the era of
the world in which I grew up was to
become not masterful but at least
familiar with the great books what the
great books of the western world
represent
the renaissance of the intellect uh and
the great minds of history
um and as we've pointed out here's
Darwin who's going to come up today
we're going to be talking about Darwin
at 250. So, you know, Decart at 490
uh angles at only 200 and then the
disappointing pointing one in the whole
list is Markx 130. And uh the difficulty
with the marks is it's based on
dialectical materialism
which is a faulty uh mode of quasy
mentation and uh it underlies
relativism.
So out of the marxian
out of this ideology
arises all of uh relativism.
And so these are the great minds
throughout all of history. and everyone
should have some kind of a passing
familiarity with them. Um,
this was the backbone of liberal
education. It was the backbone of my
education as a child. As I say, other
people like to play stickball and other
disgusting games,
sticking their grammy fingers in each
other's eyes.
And we had the great books of the
Western world. I could read the
Aristophanes. I could I could stay home
and read intelligent things. So I was a
bookworm, a bookworm as a child, you
know. And so these were my playmates. I
I love to uh see how the minds of all
these people work, you see. And uh
there's Plato, one of my great my heroes
are Plato and Socrates is probably my
favorite in history. Socrates.
Yeah.
So we'll move on to the next thing.
Uhuh. Quantum mechanics.
This has to do with um
the theory of quantum uh theory of why
consciousness calibration works. It's
because uh when we use the arm, we don't
get a yes or a no. We get a yes or a not
yes. In other words, if what I'm holding
in mind has a reality, then her arm goes
strong. If it has no reality, it goes
weak. Uh
so going weak is not a no, it's a not
yes.
So all questions are answered either yes
or not yes. There is no such thing as a
no.
Uh nature in the universe cannot say no.
Universe cannot say no.
That's a fact. Resist.
It's impossible for the universe
to say no. Isn't that interesting?
It can only say yes or fail to say yes.
But it can't say no. Isn't that
interesting? So, you don't have to know
the answer to two questions, yes or no.
You only need yes or not yes.
So the kinesis this response we used to
call kinesi logic but we've given that
we just call a muscle truth reflex
uh is either a yes or a not yes. If a
thing has reality then
it responds. If it is what we call false
it has no reality and because it has no
reality uh there is no response.
And these are calcul you know all this
is we've gone over this before the
shreddinger equation this is Eisenberg
process and this is a direct process etc
and the Henry stap now has a new book
out uh n 2007
uh called mindful universe in which he
goes into all of this quite extensively
quite extensively and far more than uh
we need to know except that there is an
advance of consciousness in quantum
mechanics represents a real advance.
Okay, we'll go next. This
uh difference in the levels of
consciousness is is this clear or is
that blurry?
Is that clear or blurry?
Huh?
What
is clear? Okay. Okay.
I'm just asking, not complaining.
Is the world going to end or not? I
mean, I'm just asking. I'm not
complaining.
Above and below 200 has very major
implications.
Major implications.
And one of its most major implications
is the effect on brain physiology.
The brain. This is the way the brain
processes information.
uh input uh above and below to to the
level 200 is quite different. One side
is one below 200 you get primarily an
animal response and above 200 then you
you get a different kind of response
because from consciousness level 200 and
up the condundolini energy begins to
flow up the chakra system.
There is no really
comparable English word in a way. You
could just call it spiritual energy.
Spiritual energy begins to
evolve as an atheric body, a etheric
brain. And uh there's quite a difference
below 200 and above 200. Uh below 200
you get a linear left brain dominance.
You get fight or flight and you get
alarm reactions.
You get stress to the acupuncture system
and a negative muscle test response.
Above 10 200, the body tends to release
endorphins.
Endorphins
and positive emotions and immunity goes
up and so does healing. Therefore, all
the healing systems that are based on
adopting positive emotional attitudes
are not so woo woo as they sound.
Somebody some people say, "Oh, that's so
woo woo."
I love that people say Sedona. Oh,
that's where all the woo woos live.
All the woo woo. So anyway, a positive
attitude and embracing positive concepts
and images etc. uh praying and
meditating and all the things that would
uh surround yourself with beauty. You
try and let go of negative emotions. Uh
therefore those all those things assist
healing and uh they tend to shift the
brain dominance
brain dominance in a favorable
direction.
All right. So, we'll move to the next uh
thing. Yeah.
Uhhuh.
What?
Oh yes. Oh yes. Okay. Uh the idea that
happiness is something that comes from
out there
fades away. Uh so this is a very
important
important uh
chart because happiness is uh an inner
inner response to out there. So changing
outness doesn't really uh have much of
an effect.
What changes things then is as your
level of consciousness goes up, as the
level of consciousness goes up, the
percent of happiness increases rapidly.
Percent of happiness. So the happiness
is not a result of what you do or have.
Happiness is a result of that which you
have become. That which you have become.
So inner work transforms that which you
are and fulfills your potential and
therefore happiness arises from within
and uh so that helps again get over the
illusion that it can be acquired by
something without. It isn't the getting
the thing but the letting go of the
wantingness that brings the happiness.
Yeah. that happiness is an internal
internal creation and not the
consequence of out there. Right? That's
a very sophisticated understanding and
not all probably a small percent of the
world would agree with that. I think if
you're rich and famous and happy
uh if you're rich and famous then you
will be happy.
If you're rich and ha and and famous,
the next step is they put you in rehab.
Rich and happy put rich and famous puts
you in rehab. I think that's so funny,
isn't it?
But it is true, right? If you watch the
TV every night, it's somebody rich and
famous and they're in some kind of
terrible trouble. Uh some kind of
terrible trouble. If they aren't guilty
of it, they've been accused of it
anyway. So, in today's media world, it's
just as makes no difference to be
accused or be convicted. It's all the
same.
All right. Then we go to the next.
The true nature of divinity. Uhhuh.
That's we're we're going to be talking
about this today and that's why we're
going to do this chart which we usually
don't do. Uh these are familiar terms in
the world of spirituality.
Uh seeing into one's self-natured
uh teacher 800
um oneness 850. These are all 850.
Reality is consciousness itself.
Reality is awareness.
Omniscience
omnipresence and innipotence. So 850 and
up is a very very advanced uh realm. You
see the Buddha is at 1,00 Jesus Christ
was at 10,00. And then we when we ask
about divinity itself,
we get that the answer is infinity.
So the Buddha is not God. Buddha
calibrates at 1000, not at infinity.
See, so it's good to not mix up
uh very advanced teachers and avatars
with divinity itself. Yeah. The creator
is infinity. Divinity is infinity.
And God is in calibrates at infinity.
Well, in a world that can't tell God
from not God, can't tell the devil from
the angel, uh, this is a very useful
tool. Huh? All right. So, many people
think that God belongs down at the
bottom. Down at the bottom. See, freedom
of speech belongs at the top. Infinity.
To say f you and have it legal, that
should be infinity.
And God is a hoax. you should be down at
zero.
So the world problem with the world is
that it stands itself on on end as we're
going to be talking about today. Yes.
Next uh slide. Huh.
Um
these are all the uh definitions of God.
Uh God the father, the creator, the
almighty, maker of heaven and earth,
ruler of the universe, maker of all
things visible and invisible,
omnipotent, omnisient and omnipresent,
the absolute supreme, the Holy Spirit.
All of the names for God calibrate at
infinity,
the God of Moses and Abraham.
Uh the Christ, Christ consciousness,
uh the self with a capital S, Utman.
Then we move to celestial hierarchies.
We see that angels go from
they're currently going for 50 50,000
and up.
You want to buy an angel, you better
start saving.
Yeah, archangels are 50,000 and up, I
guess. And if you get hit by an
archangel, it totally transforms your
life. I remember I got hit by the
thought, the the notice of an archangel.
Let's see.
That's a fact.
An archangel noticed the thought, the
the the cry. Yep.
Just the response from an archangel like
10,000 volts totally turns you around.
And uh
my hair used to be curly. Yes.
I asked if there is a God, I ask him for
help in the in the depths of absolute
despair
in the pits of hell. And that appeal was
heard by an archangel. And I was hit by
a profound with 180.
So the Buddha nature etc.
the ma native American great spirit 850
the Buddha nature
all these aspects of divinity
you can corroborate the reality and the
existence of divinity and that they all
calibrate in in a range that verifies
the truth. Yes. So, we go to the next
one.
All of these things are verifying the
truth. This is God versus science. Huh.
Um, let's see. How many more have we got
to go before we come to today's uh Huh?
>> Oh, thank you. So, I have an idea how
much time I have. Yeah. I have no idea
what time it is.
Huh?
Yes. Do I have half an hour before a
break?
>> Okay. Good. All right. All right. So, I
don't want to skip over what's
important.
All right. So, God versus science is
very much in today's world. Um, constant
conferences on it. uh uh
a fellow named Dawkins wrote about the
God delusion
and that what we need to do is get rid
of God and the delusion about God and
that of course has started a whole lot
of dialogue. Um that concept calibrates
about 190 I think. Uh all right. So we
see the world right now is our political
world is very much uh this is what our
political world is about. Uh the
struggle for secularism.
Uh to remove any reference to God and
blot it out completely from everything
uh is the dream of the secularist.
And in Europe, we see the drop in
consciousness of the level of the
western world. Uh many of those
countries have become secular. There's
nothing wrong with secular. It just you
could say you don't need to mention God
in public. And that's perfectly true. So
I uh
secularism in itself is not
intrinsically evil. It's just that it's
sort of lacking in goodness.
It's not heartwarming. It isn't. It's
not like a pup dog's wagging tail. You
realize a dog's wagging tail calibrates
higher than secularism.
A kitty's purr calibrates higher than
secularism.
So people are willing to die for
It's sort of pathetic.
Kill that dog.
We don't want any wagging tails around
here.
We don't want any wagging dog tails in
public and we don't want any kitties
purring in public.
They are to be illegal.
skeptical scientism is about 190. So we
say this is what you know one of the
things triggering it is the god delusion
and Dawkins appears on multiple uh
interview programs pitching uh atheism
actually see
anti-religionism
is uh calibrates less than just plain
atheism.
It means uh that you're actually against
religion.
Against religion the belief that science
is of the highest caliber uh caliber
it's 190. So it's not really in the in
evil it's more in fallacy. Scientism
then
you see here science has become an ism.
Science ism. Once the thing becomes an
ism, it automatically drops to 190. It
becomes a belief system.
Environmentalism, man is causing the
earth warming, etc. Then if you got an
ism, then if it falls from a verifiable
truth, then it becomes uh a political uh
bandwagon.
Natural skepticism is something I
invented.
195.
Natural skepticism is uh you could
actually call it caution. Caution. These
are nickel biters and uh
natural skepticism.
Well, the human mind, the human ego is
tired of being made a fool of and
therefore it tends to try to protect
itself by having at least a veneer of
skepticism. Yeah, well, I'll believe it
when I see it and uh well, we'll see how
he votes about that and watch that
stock. Maybe it'll go up and maybe it
won't. So, it's a protective mechanism.
So, it's what I call uh natural
skepticism.
is uh you see it doesn't show a a
positive faith in life. It's still
protective. It's below 200. And so
that's the that's the professional uh
nickeler.
Uh and uh mechanistic reductionism
is a bottomup theory of how evolution
that um the world started out as a bunch
of molecules and these molecules somehow
magically combined themselves together
in mystical magical ways and out of that
evolved uh life.
Uh
so that's what's called the bottom up
theory that life evolved from just a
chemical accident chemical accidents. It
only calibrates at 185. So it's not too
impressive.
What it avoids is the the fact that uh
life cannot uh be created. Life cannot
come from evolve from non-life.
Life can only come from life. That's the
law of conservation of life. Let's see.
That's true. Okay. The only source of
life is life itself. The radiance of
divinity.
The only source of life is the radiance
of divinity.
So the mechanistic reductionism is a
dead world. And no one has ever created
life out of non-life. It's not a
possibility.
Not a possibility to create life out of
non-life. Uhhuh.
Uhhuh. So mechanistic reductionism then
is insufficient. First of all, as we'll
get to it, it's in the wrong paradigm.
Uh and it reflects the vanity of the
ego. The vanity of the ego is that it
thinks that without divine help, it can
understand the mysteries of the universe
and of creation and evolution, which it
cannot do.
uh skepticism and a atheism is a
different form. Atheism is uh farther
down than skepticism. Skepticism has a
certain reality to it that says I of
myself do not know. That's actually
quite honest. U
so atheism on the other hand says I do
know. The reason it's lower is because
it's a vanity.
The honest person would say
via my intellect alone I am unable to
either prove or disprove the existence
of God. Uh the more
narcissistic ego uh says not only that
but I can actually prove that God does
not exist. I can prove that God does not
exist. Uh I went through that phase in
my own youth and I gave up atheism as
being stupid.
and I became an agnostic instead.
So agnostic is closer to the truth uh
than the skeptic or the atheist.
Nihilism denies the validity of all
truth 120. Nihilism is the reason why
skepticism calibrates so low and
nihilistic philosophers all calibrate
very low. Some of them are were quite
world famous and have made quite big
inroads in academia.
Nihilism
at 120. It leads to
u social collapse. Uh-huh. The God gene
is written by Dean Hammer. It's
calibrates at 190.
That was a research thinking that it it
tried to explain
the near-death experience.
Why is it the near-death experience has
been described the same throughout all
of history in all cultures? And the way
they that that the atheists tried to
solve that was by saying that there is a
a neurologic basis God gene that as you
die this gene gets triggered and then
you get this vision
uh which has been reported throughout
history of being transported through
tunnels and meeting uh past relatives
long since dead and meeting angels etc.
So anyway, the God gene is uh not true.
It's below 200.
Um the idea that the source of the
universe is strictly physical uh
strictly a big bang calibrates at 135.
Oh,
bam.
I was hoping for the big bang. You know,
like a monster Fourth of July in the
universe.
No, it says that's only 135.
All right. So, this is the the
negatives. Uh secularism. Uh we say that
the only healthy one is so so-called
natural skepticism
just that you don't to protect you from
making a fool out of yourself. Uh
earthwarming of human origin of course
is very big in today's uh news and it
calibrates as faults and we've explained
previously why that is so.
uh that earth warming is due to the
electromagnetic activity of the surface
of the sun that calibrates at 450 or
something. Due to human cause, it
calibrates as false. Earthwarming of
human origin,
I think if we've said before, uh
accounts for
08 0.8
degrees Fahrenheit. Okay. The earth
human contribution the earth warming is
less than one degree Fahrenheit is 0.8
0.7
about 0.8
of one degree is due to earth human
uh contribution. You see? Uhhuh. So
what's what's interesting is that these
theories then become
uh politicized and popularized as an
ism.
U
fallacies throughout history. Uh and
this is how they all uh arise.
The tulip bulb frenzy uh in the past.
What's the name of that book by Marqua?
Popular delusions in the madness of
crowds.
Mass popular delusions in the madness of
crowds. Is that right? By Mackie. Yes.
Anyway, anyway, all the all the uh
errors that mankind has universally
subscribed to that the earth is flat and
that the sun goes around the earth etc.
Uh so earthworming of human origin is
facious
par that there's a parallel universe to
this is also sort of a favorite amongst
sort of u wo woo science people.
There's also woowoos in science. So here
we have woowoos in science and here we
have wo woos in science. These are all
woowoos in science. God gene and
parallel universe theory earthworming of
human origin. All right. There's there
was a negative prayer he hearing study
of journal of cardiology which I
mentioned before. Uh see the downside of
scientism is there's a lot of bad
science out of there. There's a huge
amount of junk science. You have to be
involved in the world of science to
realize how this comes about. Every
university needs a faculty and the
faculty gets to be faculty by pulling
grants and you pull grants if your
research is politically in favor with
the grant givers.
Yeah. So if I want to do a research
showing that earth warming is of human
origin, I can get a grant. If I want to
get a grant showing it is not of human
origin, I won't get a grant. It's very
simple. That's why all these uh projects
usually ahead for bigname universities
because the bigname university has more
media impact. So if I can get a a grant
and Harvard University shows that
something other is so that sounds very
good. So political bias then has
completely
uh warped uh the world of scientific
research. negative prayer healing study
was published in the journal journal of
cardiology
about two years ago. It calibrates at
190 and that that cost $1 million. This
study cost $1 million and its results
were strictly facious because it the
research design was rigged. It was
rigged.
We all know from prayer healing from
experientially
uh let's say alcoholics anonymous treats
uh incurable chronic a destructive
disease incurable by all of medical
science. There is no nothing in medicine
that can help
uh an alcoholic is going down in the
tubes. And uh they all ended up mad or
dead. Mad or dead. Mad or dead. And then
along came
uh uh prayer the prayer healing prayer
healing of the 12step groups. Along came
the 12step groups and and now a chronic
progressive deteriorating
disease that leads to convulsions and
madness and sanity and cerebral atrophy
is cured. So a negative prayer healing
or negation of faith you could see would
be foolish. Negation of faith uh as a
healing of modality calibrates at 90
calibrates at 90.
Yeah. So
therefore trips to lords and things like
this have a profound effect. Uh the
miraculous
uh happens as an actuality
uh at Lords. Resist.
The bodies of great saints uh are
indestructible. Resist.
Bodies of great saints are resistant to
destruction.
Oh, they slowly deteriorate. Okay. All
right. But they don't have that much
negativity. So they deteriorate slowly
over great many centuries.
All right. So anyway,
faith then has a profound uh uh healing
uh capacity and negation of faith then
uh due to uh doubt and etc.
context and we're going to be
contrasting context. If you negate
nonlinear reality of context that
calibrates at 90. Now the usual
nonlinear context is divinity. However,
there are others etc. But truth can only
be known via content within a specific
context. The the difficulty with
skepticism and all is it only deals with
content and totally ignores context and
therefore it's a paradigm limitation.
Um Crick and we mentioned before uh
Crick himself was a atheist
uh and he when he found when he
discovered DNA
that this discovery which led to the
Nobel Prize I think uh calibrated at
440.
Now Crick himself was personally an
atheist and therefore he did his last
research before he died uh was to show
that the source of consciousness is
strictly physical that uh it is only a
phenomena
a a product of neuronal activity that
calibrated at 140. Now we know ourself
that uh the way it works is pretty much
like Maxwell's magnetic induction of
electricity. The way the neurons work is
the atheric body uh is an energy body uh
and this atheric body has an energy
which is like the magnet on a wire and
stimulates the flow of electricity down
the wire. So by induction, so the
atheric body by induction stimulates the
neurons, stimulates the brain. Let's see
if that's correct.
Uh it works by induction and the energy
and the power is in the atheric brain.
Is this? All right. So the atheric brain
then is attuned to truth and the
knowingness of that truth is because the
energy of the aetheric body
uh activates the energies within the
neurons.
As you remember from physics when if you
put a magnetic field around a wire it
creates electricity. Vice versa if you
run electricity around it creates
magnetism. So magnetism, electricity uh
shift back and forth uh to each other.
Uh so the human brain then as we see
from when we were talking about the
difference between the two hemispheres,
spiritual awareness then activates the
flow of the condundalini energy and
activates the atheric brain. The atheric
brain then uh activates the knowingness
of the physical brain through its actual
through its physicalness through its
physicalness.
All right. So that answers a lot of the
questions of research questions and
mysteries uh over time. How come certain
things can be? It's because the
knowingness, the theoretical aspect is
the athetheric brain which is not
physical, non-physical.
So the atheric consciousness
is what continues
uh after death resist
the atheric. We have permission to ask
this
atheric then consciousness continues on
after death. I know. Anybody who's been
out of body knows that once you're out
of body, that which is you.
When you're out of body, there still is
a sense of me. There still is a sense of
self. Even though the physicality is
lying there, you just no longer identify
with the physicality.
It's just laying there looking sort of
stupid and uninteresting.
And the real you is sitting in the
middle of the crowd here. See? So, if I
was out of body now, I'd be sitting up
there looking looking around and and
looking at this guy standing up here and
thinking how strange he looks, you know,
with no particular appeal to him. See,
it's amazing when you go out of body,
but physical the physical you has
absolutely no appeal. It's just a dumb
looking lump laying there.
And if karmically you're destined to go
back in it, you do so, but you're not
joyful about it. You wouldn't say, "Oh,
great. Great. I get to go back in my
body and be me again." No, doesn't work
that way.
How many people here have been out of
body? Wow. Yeah. Am I speaking truth?
>> Yeah. Yeah. You're sort of reluctant to
go back in the body and uh it's sort of
a drag. So people when they fear death,
I'd say what to make yourself advance
spiritually to help yourself. One of the
biggest blocks is the fear of death
itself. So if you meditate on death
itself, you first you realize that it's
not even a possibility. It's just that
the you will eventually uh let go of
this physicality.
Not only that, but it'll be happy to do
so.
Not a tragedy.
The self is happy to dump the baggage.
I have permission to ask this. Resist.
You get that? The real self is happy to
dump the baggage. It's true. True.
You're not cheating on me.
It's happy to dump the baggage because
it's a limitation out of body. I can uh
in one instant be the back of this room
and then the other in I can be there or
I can go outside and the weather and
I'll be back in and nobody even knows I
left.
Also, without a body, you know, 90% of
what you want is gone already or gone
already. You don't need a new pair of
shoes.
You don't need money. You don't need a
car. Yeah. You want to go from here to
there. You just think there and then you
are there. You're there. The minute you
think there, it's really swell.
I don't know why why we're hanging out
here. I don't know why more I talk about
I don't know why we're hanging out here,
but we are anyway to learn what we can
learn in this dimension, this domain
uh because of the karmic opportunities.
You see this is linear and definable and
uh correctable and identifiable. So we
learn in the in this physicality
um all right Darwin's theory of
evolution calibrates at respectable
450.
So we don't knock evolution. We say it's
applicable to the physical realm.
Daniel Dette did uh studies on
evolutionary psychology
and there is some reality to that. It
calibrates about 250. So it's useful
knowledge.
Uh creationism
already becomes a limitation.
Now let's see creationism is what do we
say 245 according to creationism that's
sort of a literal interpretation of the
Bible. It says that uh the world is
6,000 years old and things like that.
So, creationism
trying to make the Bible literal,
scientifically literal,
uh is not valid. And uh you end up
trying to prove that the earth is 6,000
years old. And we know just, you know,
from the skull of Lucy that it's uh a
lot older than 6,000 years. So that's
creationism. Then it's taught in some
schools a literal interpretation of the
Bible.
Genesis itself in the Bible. Um that
book of Genesis calibrated 600. 600. So
you're better off going with Genesis
than creationism,
etc. At 600 is certainly a very advanced
level of consciousness.
Discovery of the presence of God
uh is 950. I don't know what that is.
Discovery of the presence of God. Uh oh,
that was a writing. That was a book. Oh,
yeah. That's a book about spiritual
truth. Uh pretty close to the absolute
truth. Yeah.
And um so
see we verify uh all of our belief
systems and our observations and our
opinions
and try to discern what is the closest
we can get to uh the absolute re
reality.
Evolution of consciousness is a concept
at 600. So the the muscle test response
calibrates at 600. At 600 is the opening
of the third eye of the Buddha body.
It's the capacity to differentiate
essence from appearance.
So the biggest benefit of the muscle
reflex is
the uh
the response is based on essence and not
on appearance.
It's based and the world's problem is it
cannot differentiate perception from
essence. Cannot differentiate essence
from appearance.
Uh all right
evolution of consciousness. Francis Col
Collins uh wrote the language of God and
he calibrates at 400
and he's the one who set in opposition
to the um atheist
intelligent design. intelligent design
which is pressing for recognition as a
substitute for creationism or uh
divinity etc. It seems to me intelligent
design offers sort of a a halfway
between secularism and religionism.
uh intelligent design
William. Now when we get to the uh
scopes trial, we'll be talking about
William Jennings Brian who calibrate who
was a religionist. He calibrated over
500. He calibrated 505 to 510.
And in the Scopes trial, his opposition
was from Clarence Daryl. Clarence Daryl
was a great lawyer, a great lawyer and a
great speaker. and he calibrated at 450.
So at 450, Daryl represented what he
stands for, logic and reason. And at 505
or 510, William Jennings Brian stood for
faith.
Now St. Thomas Aquinas uh um calibrated
at 570 which is
um saintthood.
Now what we are going to be talking
about today is to break down any
misunderstanding and arrive at the
obvious uh what is obvious is that
evolution is creation. That's true at
the level of infinity.
Evolution is not evolution versus
creation. Evolution is creation.
And that God as the source of creation
is gen is infinite infinite.
Time magazine uh God versus science was
November of 2006 a whole issue devoted
to this and that was quite an integrous
article 410
at 410
and it was um
it was a dialogue with Francis Collins
on one side and uh this other fellow
this idiot on the other
The God delusion guy
that God is a delusion is his delusion.
So
that God is a delusion is itself
delusional. So there you have the the
box within a box that says everything
within this box is false.
God is the source of creation.
So you see that was Time magazine and I
say two weeks ago the Scopes trial was
rerun
I think in Alabama
Sagon uh his view of science was quite
uh influential for a while and you see
he's at 200 that's just on the just on
the edge
200 then is just on the edge is neither
really true nor really false theology as
a discipline Flynn is 460.
So, theology is trying to figure out God
using the intellect, using the
intellect. And theology, I got a
straight A in theology, etc. And I, as I
studied theology, I saw both its upside
and its downside. Its downside we'll get
to later. Um, evolutionary psychology we
said is 210. Uh, and that's also at the
top. Francis Crick, discovery of DNA. We
mentioned that that that was it. I
thought it was 440. It's 460.
Um, discovery of DNA in which he won the
Nobel Prize, I believe. Uh, that
research was 460. Then before he died,
he tried to show that, uh, he was an
atheist, that there isn't any god. So he
was trying to show that neuronal
activity is strictly
uh physical and that was only uh very
low. So all right so that was Francis
Crick and the Heisenberg principle which
we're quite interested in here is it
calibrates at 460. Now the Heisenberg
principle is very useful and of course
the Heisenberg principle is the basis of
advanced theoretical physics and it's a
an explanation of why the muscle test
for truth works. Heisenberg principle is
the collapse of the potential into the
actual. Now in order to collapse the
potential into the actual
the stimulus has to exist. It has to be
real.
So the Heisenberg principle means if you
pose uh reality then the universe will
respond and the potential then will re
collapses the actual. If I pose to her a
question that has no reality then there
is no energy to collapse the potential
in the potential into the actual. It's
like nothingness. Therefore
that which is negative is equivalent to
nothingness and nothingness has no
capacity to collapse the w the wave
function only that which is real. So
when I if I say something is over 600 if
that's real it has the power to collapse
the potential to the actual and the arm
goes strong.
So there's either truth or the absence
of truth. There is no such thing as
falsehood. There is only the absence of
truth. And for vocabulary linguistic
convenience we say is it's falsehood
actually it's the absence of truth so
that which is has no existence cannot
collapse the wave function cannot
collapse potential and the actuality and
that's why the um the only explanation
of uh the muscle response we use is
coming is coming from advanced
theoretical physics and the mindful
universe is really a very uh interesting
book it gets more complic licated than
you need to know.
But you can always say, "Well, I read
it." Yeah. Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah. What? Uh oh. Okay, we'll move
to the next slide.
What?
Here's our old friend. Uh
this is the the enigma
uh that plagues human humankind.
This is the the problem with humankind
today. You cannot tell the wolf from
sheep's clothing. The deception of the
illusion. So this is what we call
illusion and this is reality. This is
the illusion and this is the reality.
You see? And now politically you see
this is the the battleground. Uh these
are nice people here. All we have to do
is be nice to them.
All you have to do is be nice to them
because this is what they are. We're
just peacemongers.
We can we're just peacem. So then people
say, "Well, we can be nice to them." And
so that differentiate essence from
appearance is what we do with
consciousness calibration. It's the only
way I know to differentiate truth from
falsehood and perception from essence.
All right. Now, I think that pretty much
covers the review. What's the next uh
slide? Right.
What's the next slide? Yes.
>> Well, I mean, can you show me what is
the next slide? Okay.
All right.
Okay, very good. So, that's where we're
going to start after a break. Okay, so
we'll take a break and then we'll handle
the we'll solve the rest of the
mysteries of the universe.
>> Well, this morning we reviewed the
familiar
because uh learning is both left brain
and right brain. Left brain is linear,
memorizing things, arduous.
You can move to a city and you can buy a
map and then try and memorize the
streets. You see, or you can just live
there a while and you automatically know
where to go. So, the reason I review
things is because
by circling over the familiar
constantly, you know it just through
familiarity. Everything we said this
morning, you don't have to memorize
the calibrations or anything like that.
you just sort of intuitively so it
activates your intuitive knowingness so
that your knowingness is automatic and
uh so that's why we do familiarity you
don't have to think anymore
save you the problem of thinking and uh
the one thing is obvious is that the
reality of that which you are is what
activates the body and not vice versa
Therefore, one of the be quickest ways
to make spiritual progress to let go
your fear of death. Death is not a
possibility.
Death is not a possibility.
That's true. Resist.
That's true. At the level of infinity,
death, the law of conservation of life.
Mankind talks about conservation of
energy and matter. And this is the most
important one. The law of conservation
of life.
Life can change form, but you cannot
extinguish life. So you can't get killed
or killed kill anybody. So if you've
murdered anybody this lifetime, forget
feeling guilty about it.
It's good to confess it though because
you'll feel better.
Okay. So now we'll put in the new
material. This morning we became
familiar, reactivated that which we
already know and circled over the
familiar so that it becomes automatic.
All right.
Today we're talking about creation
versus evolution because it is a
constant constant in our society. It's
constant politically. It's constant in
our educational system. It's constant uh
philosophically.
Uh so we start with the that which we
know already. The Newtonian science
which calibrates in the 400s is based on
cause.
Now
creation is causeless. It has no cause
and it
it's it has a source. So I remember in
theology at Jesuit University
uh the argument for the um existence of
God of first cause I was skeptical and I
knew that it didn't ring true. There is
no such thing as a first cause.
That which for is forever is forever
present. Has no beginning and has no
end. So there can't be any first cause
for that which is eternal. So the idea
of a cause, a first cause then is a
Newtonian idea of causality of a this
causing of that.
As we've explained many times,
everything is happening spontaneously
as a consequence of its potentiality
being actualized. Yeah. By vition.
So God is first cause is quite different
from God is ongoing source.
So because God is forever is forever
timeless there is no first cause. So God
is not the first cause of the universe.
So the uh the popular image of God is
rolling the dice. You know uh there
wasn't a universe and God suddenly bong
and the dice ruled and uh so that's
causal. So God is far beyond cause.
God is the everpresent source.
Therefore, things as they emerge, things
as we witness phenomena
are not caused. There is no cause of
anything in the universe. Let's see if
that's a fact.
There's no cause of anything in the
universe resist. There's no cause of
anything in the universe.
Your science teacher won't like to hear
that but
instead everything emerges from
potentiality into actuality
and depending on the overall context
depending on the context.
So phenomena uh are constantly occurring
of their own and we now have the
scientific principle of the high
Heisenberg principle which defines
intention.
So the potentiality actualizes
in a field of intention. So intention is
an overall field is an overall field.
So potentiality then can actualize by
intention by saying yes. Potentiality
can a actualize nonvolutionally
because of the field itself. And this is
important in understanding creation.
It's not because of what God does but
because of what is because of what God
is. Not so seeing God as a causal agent
who creates you know in a linear
Newtonian paradigm is a very naive idea.
Uh so to say a thing is God's will is is
only a matter of speech not exactly.
So creation then is the emergence of
evolution as the unfolding
evolution is creation. So creation and
evolution are one in the same thing.
Creation and evolution are one and the
same thing.
Evolution then is the unfolding of
creation. Why? Because of the infinite
potentiality
is activated by
the omnipotence of divinity. The
omniscience and the omnipresence.
But it is the omnipotence. So therefore
if you have a potentiality
will it actualize it depends on the
power of the valition.
The Heisenberg principle reaches its
maximum expression
uh as divinity.
Man likes to speak about the will of God
because he's anthropomorphic.
um all comes about not because of some
capriccious uh decision by divinity but
merely as a consequence of what divinity
is in an infinite field then to hold an
idea in mind tends to make it manifest.
You see so
therefore you can't blame things on God
anymore.
Everybody likes to blame everything on
God. Well, it's God's will. Yeah. God's
will. You mean it's your will amplified
by the presence of divinity. Divinity.
Yeah.
All right. So, what you hold in mind
then because of the power of the field,
the nonlinear field of intention tends
to manifest.
That's why it all right.
We spoken. So, creation is the emergence
of evolution. And we and we always say,
you know, in all of our lectures, you
know, the reason things are happening
has nothing to do with a personal you.
What you're seeing is the actualization
of a potentiality. See, the arm goes out
by itself.
There is no personal eye that says, I
think in order to illustrate that
sentence, I will move my right arm to
the right six and a half inches and hold
it there for one and a half minutes and
then I will take it down again. That's
such everything happens automatically of
its own, does it not?
Everything is spontaneously
expressing the essence of that which it
is.
So if expressivity is a latent capacity
of human consciousness, then
expressivity if you're giving a lecture
takes place through physical expression,
tone of voice, it's a vocabulary,
posture. The whole thing is
synchronized. The whole thing is
synchronized and it's all outside of
awareness. There's no personal you that
makes a decision. I think I'll shift my
weight from one side of the other. You
wouldn't get very far in life yet.
Make everything linear. So what's
happening is actually nonlinear
and we see its expression in the linear
domain. So the linear domain is where
the nonlinear intention potentiated by
intention then actualizes. So what you
see is the linear is the actualization
of potentiality
because of the infinite field. So the
human will then has the same uh effect
when we say yes we potentiate that
actuality.
So spirituality then when we say yes to
uh being the servant of God etc being
selfless and
etc to being kind and generous and all
the virtues uh when we say yes to that
we greatly increase the likelihood that
that will manifest in our life and the
often oftener we say yes to that the
more likely it is to be so it isn't what
we do it's what we have become that
changes the worldh
You would say, "What can I do
uh to save the world?" Well, you could
stay home and stay out of trouble. That
would be a big help.
Stay off the
stop crowding the subway. Stay home and
watch TV or something.
Uh I didn't I don't want to go to the
next slide yet.
I want to go back to one.
Um,
all right. So, we said creation is the
consequence of what God is versus God
does. So, you become more sensitive by
realizing that to see the amount of
anthropomorphism
projected onto God. God's will this,
God's anger at this, God's revenge, uh,
pleasing God, etc. Yeah.
God's will then we also define as divine
ordinance all manifests as a consequence
of divine ordinance not via God's
capriccious will by divine by the
presence of God by ordinance we mean
that the quality the quality of that
which God is omnisient omnipresent
omnipotent
that which is omnipresent
and omnisient and omnipotent
gets activated when you hold it in mind.
It's because of the infinite power of
divinity
that when you decide to have a a sip of
coffee, you're able to do that. The only
reason you're able to do anything is
because of the presence of divinity
without which your valitions would have
no effect on the universe. You would
think I'll have coffee but the body
wouldn't move.
Nothing would happen.
It's only because of the infinite power
of divinity that anybody can do or be or
think anything.
Isn't that marvelous?
You wouldn't be able to sit here. You
wouldn't be able to understand. You
wouldn't be able to go to the bathroom.
You get older, you guys will know what I
mean.
Oh god.
All right. So all comes about
only because of the consequence of the
presence of divinity as to the the
infinite power.
There would be no such thing as a
personal will. The only reason your
decisions manifest in any kind of change
or action is because they are surrounded
by the infinite omniscience of God,
omnipresence and omnipotence of God. All
right? So creation is a consequence of
what God is versus what God does. So
that gets rid of the roll of the dice
view of God. You see
God's will as divine ordinance means
that that's because of his quality of
that which he is
and valition is an anthropomorphic
concept. So we we are anthropomorphic
about our own self which sounds
paradoxical. We say it's because I
wanted to do that and held it in mind
that I made it happen. That's actually a
a fantasy.
Teology is another uh error.
Yeah, it's a presumption you often heal
here in the biologic uh explanations for
creationism and order that that things
became a certain way in order in order
to bring about a certain end result.
Uh
if that was possible then what you would
have would be uh
a universe create created by intelligent
design.
Now, people who argue with what I just
said like to sell you intelligent
design, but when you boil intelligent
design down to what it is, they become
uncomfortable about it because they
think everything becomes the way it is
in order to something. In order to
something, it doesn't become that way in
order to be be anyway in order to
anything.
Uhhuh.
It becomes that way because that's what
survives. That's what survives is is.
And you say, well then it does that in
order to survive. That's again an
anthropomorphic projection. A buck
doesn't care whether it survives or not.
Had no interest in it.
Bug just is
survival is in your head.
He doesn't care. Now the ones who
survived are because they fit into
nature the way it was.
Satiliologic reasoning in order to
presumes
a valitional uh goal.
Mechanistic reductionism
is the bottomup theory of evolution.
It has to do with the mechanical.
Mechanically nature went this way. it
was favorable and therefore it tended to
uh repeat itself.
Mechanistic reductionism calibrates
let's see mechanistic reductionism
calibrates over 100
105 110 depends on who pronounces it.
But mechanistic reductionism
uh is a simplistic mechanical linear
explanation
and it's not even in the arena of
explaining nature or reality or much
less creation or the universe. Okay.
Well, so we'll go to the next slide
then. Huh?
Uh and so these arguments all end up
between uh matter versus spirit. Now the
the the materialist denies that there is
such a thing as spirit and he's very
spirited about that denial.
You read scientists are up in arms up in
arms that what are they up in arms about
if they're scientists?
uh scientists are up in arms and
outraged and therefore uh the guy who
wrote the God delusion
uh you know appears on various interview
programs and the other thing interesting
about him is he's got this he's outraged
by it all. So in order to get in the
news today all you have to do is be
outraged by something.
I'm outraged by outrage.
I'll be on a rally and say, "I'm
outraged by outrage." And rally say,
"I'm outraged by your outrage about
outrage."
He gets outraged over
lack of morality, etc. Matter versus
spirit,
nonlinear essence versus form. Now, what
we're talking about is the essence of
things has nothing to do with form. Form
is a superimposition.
The essence of a thing is its energy and
its energy itself is beyond form. It's
the it's the form that gives that energy
that particular delineation.
So all form is linear information.
That's an interesting definition for
form. U linear information is what form
is about. So anything that's linear you
can analyze and you get information from
it in all form is linear information.
So the universe then is an expression of
an infinite field an infinite universe
forever expanding at the speed of light.
So the universe is forever expanding at
the speed of light.
uh resist
the universe is forever expanding at the
speed of right light.
So when people talking about they're
going to reach the edge of the universe,
I say I'll meet you there.
I'll meet you there in the infinite
future. Yes,
the universe is expanding
faster than the speed of light. That
sense that universe is expanding faster
than the speed of light. Resist.
Faster than the speed of light. Oh, I
see. Its potentiality is expanding
faster than its reality. Okay. Oh, I
see.
Uhhuh. Infinite potentiality. All right.
Oh, well I know you wanted to know that.
So I thought
the universe is expanding at the speed
of light faster than the speed of light
uh in all directions simultaneously.
Now the interesting thing about the
energy of the world universe
that is why E= MC² was one of the
greatest finds in history. It still only
calibrates in the 400s because it
talking about the linear domain but out
of that came all of uh our present life
dilemma nuclear energy etc. the world's
u problems solutions. This is the answer
to man's problems solutions. It's also
the source of man's problems because we
now live in an atomic energy, the world
of atomic potentiality.
And the world lives now in constant
threat
because just like dynamite can either be
helpful to engineering projects or kill
people, E= MC² can lead to great
discoveries. It can also lead to its
atomic energy.
So we have an infinitely expanding
universe.
The energy in one cubic centimeter
of space is greater than the equivalence
of the total mass of the universe
to give us an idea of infinite power.
One cubic centimeter of space,
empty space, contains within it
more energy than its equivalence in the
total mass of the entire universe.
That's beyond imagination.
We have permission to ask this. Resist.
That is a fact. Resist.
It's a fact. In one cubic centimeter,
the amount of potential energy in one
cubic centimeter of space is greater
than its equivalence as the total mass
of the existing universe.
Oh boy, that's scary, isn't it?
What if you plugged into that by
accident?
Plug into
you go brilliant flash and that' be
you'd be a memory huh
energy in one cubic inch of space is
greater than the total mass of the
entire universe. So we need the word the
total we need to put total in there. The
total mass of the entire existing
universe
is less than the energy potential of one
cubic centimeter of space empty space.
Wow.
So what people get committed to them the
reason that we even have this conflict
is because of paradigm allegiance and we
have spoken about paradigm at other
times.
uh
the calibrated levels of consciousness
delineate really paradigms. So the
literal uh
mechanistic reductionist
uh is unaware of cal the realities that
calibrate 500 or over.
So what we see the whole thing about
science versus religion is really a
conflict of paradigms. So science says
only up through consciousness level 400s
is reality and we say that the real
reality is 500 on up. All right. So you
cannot find spiritual reality within the
400s within the 400s. There are many
journals of uh consciousness and
religion and various house sounding
titles but when you calibrate them
they're in the 300s to the 400s. There's
no way
no way a journal on consciousness or
spiritual reality and science could
exist that's only limited to the 400s
because it eliminates all of spiritual
reality or any possible means of uh
ascertaining spiritual reality. Uhhuh.
So that's the limitation of science is
is a limitation of paradigm. So we speak
of paradigm allegiance. Paradigm
allegiance.
paradigm allegiance. So the skeptic is
you know confined to sort of a
pedestrian level of the linear uh
Newtonian
paradigm of reality and the five in the
400s is as far as it can go. So
skepticism has no basis upon which it
can negate anything that calibrates 500
or over because it it doesn't go there.
It has no reality and therefore you
cannot use the linear to disprove you
cannot use the linear to disprove the
nonlinear. They are different paradigms.
Uh so we know for instance you can
measure
uh various things but you can't measure
pleasure. How much pleasure do you get?
You can't measure love. All the things
that are meaningful, meaningful,
love, devotion,
aesthetic beauty are all non
unscientific non-measurables.
So, so the scientist lives off the
non-measurable satisfaction he gets off
of claiming that science is all there
is.
The reason he says that's all there is
is because he has faith in that. At the
same time he denies that faith has any
reality.
If faith had no reality, he wouldn't be
able to speak of science or anything
else either. So it's a limitation of
awareness and uh we pray for them.
We pray for them. They can come back
another lifetime.
come back another lifetime.
E= MC² then it's very exciting.
Paradigm allegiance then is a limitation
and it's one which people are not aware
of. I never read of paradigm allegiance.
I never read about anything about
paradigm
uh because you're limited to to a
paradigm. uh you cannot see anything
beyond your paradigm because it has no
reality to you. Now we talk about
paradigm if you uh if you're trying to
describe reality
let's say if you go up in a balloon you
look at the the earth and you say the
earth is uh crazy and rocky and um and
it also is wet and and then
you try to describe the world from these
limited views. Each view of the world is
accurate, but the difficulty is thinking
that's all there is. There are not
different worlds. They're only different
perspectives of the world. So, a
different perspective. So, paradigm has
to do with perspective.
Yeah.
Paradigm allegiance then is a blindness
of which the people themselves are
unaware. I'm sure the people who write
all these interesting journals on
uh religion especially
uh are not aware of the fact that they
are limited to the 400 level of
consciousness.
uh Zyon Zyon and various very they're
very areodite intellectually but they
wander around in the high level high
300s to the 400s
um and they polish up the definitions
and significance of words and concepts
but they are still circling around in
the same box same box.
So
Darwinian evolution then at 450 is a box
and once you're in that box of
causality. So this is the box. So
there's a paradigm allegiance
to the concept of causality as the
explanation for phenomena within nature.
The divinity uh divinity as the source
of the universe is
uh calibrates at infinite.
So mechanistic reductionism calibrates
quite low. Divinity as this source of
the universe calibrates at infinity.
So
all those people have to do is read our
work and that'll solve it. Divinity
is the source of the universe not the
mechanistic reductionism.
Intelligent design is another argument
in today's uh schooling and the academic
world. The intelligent design would seem
to offer some kind of a uh inbetweeness.
Uh but uh the secularist hates the idea
of there being intelligence. it wants to
think that mechanistically
uh things uh worked out satiliologically
and that's why they survived.
So there's also a battle over
intelligent design. So what can be
taught in schools now is very very
political. Uh you can't mention God at
all and intelligent design is very
suspect and so you end up with sort of a
mechanistic reductionism
which becomes a new religion. it becomes
religionized.
So you see the religionization of
secularism.
Secularism now becomes the new religion.
Yeah, it's the new religion. So there's
much resistance to intelligent design
because it's thought by intelligent
design that you could slip God could
come in the back door of that. God could
come in the back door of intelligent
design. If you watch uh something like
Blue Planet on television
uh Blue Planet uh which does nothing. It
doesn't make any comment about the
world. It just takes you through uh the
world and the undersea world and you
just look at it. You just look at it.
It's magnificent aesthetic perfection
and it's it's just exquisite.
And if you
if you can't see the intelligence behind
that design, then you shouldn't be in
the argument at all.
The um the beauty and the significance
of that which survives
because that which survives is often
very very beautiful. The box jellyfish
floats through the air.
Box jellyfish,
you're dead.
There you got perception versus essence
boy.
Well, if we were just nice to the box
jellyfish,
then they we'd be okay.
That's the political expression of that
design. Now, if we're just nice to the
box jellyfish, they'll be nice to us.
Whoop! Woo!
As soon as they blow you up, then
they're nice to you.
Intelligent design. All right. So,
intelligent design then is obvious to
people who are quite conscious.
Intelligent design ends up as
aesthetics. The stunning beauty of all
that exists. Intelligence
is quite intuit. You can intuit it the
intelligence behind the design and you
don't have to ascribe it to some kind of
an external god. You see, so causality
uh blocks the awareness that because of
the essence of that which it is, it
fulfills its potential as a consequence
of that which it is, not that which is
caused to be. Nobody forces the box
belly jellyfish to look cute as he
floats through the water. The box
jellyfish just
So its beauty is intrinsic to its
existence. Yes.
Intrinsic to his existence. Intrinsic to
all that exists is an is a potential
beauty.
All right. So Newtonian causality then
is a very limited paradigm. The paradigm
of the 400s.
intelligent design is a far more
advanced at 480. Uh you can see the
brilliance, the brilliance. You go down
in the dep the great depths and you see
fish and all kinds of ma magical
creatures that discovered electricity a
long time ago.
Here's a
intelligence then creates electricity a
couple of thousand feet down in the
darkness of the ocean are these things
that have a glowing headlight on them
like this and their little lights flash
back and forth and back and forth like
that. They have electricity and they
have ways of turning it on. They've got
circuitry.
Uh if that isn't intelligence, what do
you call it?
Uh so they say, "Well, naturally fish
that have these little signal lights are
going to survive better." But how did
the first first fish to create these
little fog lights, how did that come
about? It's got to be the first little
fish that dangles a a bait like a light
in front of him. So intelligence is
obvious.
uh if your own consciousness is at 480
480 so the high 400s when you look at
beauty you you realize the intelligence
behind it
and uh Duncan's God delusion then
calibrates at 190 so his problem was he
was born with a D instead of an
I'm sure Dawkins has a sense of humor.
Anyway, I pray he does have a sense of
humor. We're just joking around and
after all this life is transitory
anyway. So,
as an explanation, the beginning was the
late is Genesis 600.
I like I like the way Genesis describes
that
from the Godhead
radiated light and out of that light
originated life in the universe. So I
love the way Genesis uh describes the
birth of life as a spontaneous evolution
of the godhead
emerging as godness. Okay, next one.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu