afternoon, Dr. Hawkins. Yes. Tomorrow's Father's Day. Uh-oh. And your spiritual children are out
there. Oh. I want to give you a card. Oh, thank you. And I wanted to thank you for the
and my question is dealing with avoidance of evil. Early you were talking about dealing with what?
The avoidance of dealing with evil, correct? In the past, in the past 7th, 8th, and 9th century,
10th century, Islam had been very successful in achieving high science, math, architecture,
and astronomy, as I perceive it. And for the last thousand years, it's kind of nothing's really
happened. Yes, it had its high period, yeah. And my question for you is dealing with the perception
of what do you feel is the real reason that Islam has slipped? Is it their influence and power or
not achieving their high ideals in these areas?
I really don't know. It's, you see, don't forget it's factional. It's factional. Islam is factional.
Much like the Catholics and the Protestants in Europe, you know, medieval Europe. Where are all
these little covers come from? And it's factional. Also, Islam is political. People like to think of
it as a religion. It's a political religion. It's very political. It states there is the house of
Islam and there is the house of Islam. And there is the house of Islam. And there is the house of
war. The house of Islam is us and the house of war is everyone else. So, it's very egocentric to a degree, yeah.
Is there dissatisfaction in Islam because of their lack of influence in the world as it once was today?
I don't know. You're asking me a lot of political questions. My, you know, the principle of hegemony, hegemony.
Who's the name of my writing? Hawkins? Oh, yeah. I can't handle all these covers. I don't know. I don't know.
I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know.
I can't handle all these covers like this. There is the, I view it as primitive. Hegemony, hegemony is part of animal life.
They want to be the dominant alpha wolf. You don't see religions acting any different than a wolf pack.
This is my hill. I'm the dominant one. And this other wolf pack wants to come in. And so we will kill them and drive them away.
How is that different?
No different. So it's the dominance of the animal ego to dominate, to be king of the hill, to be the alpha male.
That's why it's unimpressive from a spiritual viewpoint and why the Sufis calibrate so much higher.
Because the Sufis transcend all that, you know, lower side of human nature really, see? Yeah.
Thank you.
Yeah.
If a person wants to be an Islamic, I tell them become a Sufi and avoid all that politicalization.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins. I don't really have a question. I just wanted to express my gratitude to you and Susan and ask for a blessing.
Yes. Yes.
I'm asking for your blessing.
What? Oh, I thought you were asking me a question.
No.
Oh, God bless you, my love.
Thank you.
Be passionate for God. That's what...
Dr. Hawkins?
Yes.
Question. When we contemplate and meditate, at least for the earlier students, right now when I contemplate,
the I which is witnessing the silence is still the I, the ego. It doesn't seem to be I, the awareness.
How do you go from I being the ego to I, the awareness when you are contemplating?
Oh, yeah. From self with a small S to self with a big S.
Right.
All right. Yeah. It isn't so much what you do as what you let go of. As you let go of the self with a small S as being a reality, an intrinsic reality, what you do is you surrender the small self to the large self.
And all spiritual endeavor is really aligned with that.
Yes.
The realization of the presence of God within is the consequence of removing anything that would be in its way.
At that point, the small self is dissolved into the greater self.
So we let go identification with the ego, which presumes that it is the self.
They just sign it right there.
Yeah.
So all the spiritual techniques are devised to do that.
Prayer, supplications, karma yoga, selfless service.
And, you know, be helpful to life without looking for any payback.
You see a little beetle on his back flying with his feet in the air.
You know, you put him on his feet.
You see a hungry kitten.
You put some food out for it.
You see a dog that's lonely.
Sometimes dogs will bark.
There's one that barks near me.
And I'll go out and I'll say, you really don't have to bark.
You're not all by yourself.
And he stops barking.
He's lonely.
He wants some kind of contact with some other being.
And I discovered that just going out, even if I tell him you're being a bad dog, please stop barking, he'll stop barking.
Because all he wants is that sort of human companionship.
If I say to him, if you don't stop, I'm going to call the police, he'll stop barking.
And if I say to him, if you stop barking, I'm going to call the police, he stops barking.
So he wants that.
Yeah.
That dog wants to hear a human voice.
I guess the folks tie him out and go to town, you know, and leave him.
And pretty soon, woof, woof.
Woof, I'm lonely.
So I read it that he's lonely.
And no matter what I say to him, he stops woofing.
You can do that psychically.
I used to do that psychically.
Picture yourself leaving your body and going as a lovingness to the dog.
And saying, sweetheart, I love you.
And hugging the dog.
And seeing that he's lonely.
And the dog will stop barking.
You can actually leave the body and go to the dog.
And the dog's spirit will get a warm, okay feeling.
Yeah.
Can you bless me?
Thank you.
Yeah.
You can send your spirit to the dog.
Say, oh, I love you.
You're adorable.
You're such a sweet dog.
And the dog will stop barking.
I want to thank you first for your dedication to us as a teacher.
And wanted to ask you if you would please chant one om with me.
Shouldn't you do the om?
No, no, no.
You want to do an om today?
Yeah.
Everybody wants to do an om.
Om.
My voice is gone.
Did it go?
Yeah.
Got you.
Yes.
Hi, dog.
Yeah.
Today you spoke about the declaration to God.
Yes.
Could you please talk more about that?
It takes one sentence.
To be the second.
Make up a sentence that covers what your intention is and how you align your life.
And then make that as a formal declaration to God.
We do that at the start of every lecture.
Glory be to thee, O Lord, most high.
You're acknowledging Almighty God as the most high.
All power and glory be to thee, O Lord.
Most high.
Amen.
So by acknowledging divinity, you're already making a declaration that you acknowledge
their divinity.
Krishna says, those who commit to me become mine.
The Psalms say, those who call upon me are mine.
So take advantage of that truth and you belong to God once you acknowledge that he is your
God.
Krishna says, those who call upon me are mine and are divine.
So take advantage of that truth and you belong to God once you acknowledge that he is your
God.
So you're acknowledging divinity as your God and you're telling us to are mine and are
dear to me.
Which psalm is it, 29, 19 or is it 19?
I forget.
It says the same thing.
Those who rest their head upon me are mine.
Thank you.
That's transformative to make that declaration.
I tell you my memory is something.
29th Psalm or 19th.
Yes.
My question is how can one transcend what still appears to be a duality of God imminent
and transcendent?
That's not a question.
God knows what God knows.
He knows that God knows what He knows.
He knows that God knows.
He knows what He knows.
When you're worshiping God, you know that all the things that Он knows are the same
How can one transcend what still appears to be a duality of God eminent and transcendent?
Yeah, that's not a duality.
That's just a nominalization, just semantic, just semantic.
It's a concept.
God transcendent is the traditional God of religion.
The transcendent God is elsewhere in time and space.
He's back there before he threw the billiard ball that became the earth.
And he's up there in heaven.
So he's depicted as the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel.
God reaching down to man.
See, he's up there.
Now, if you go by Genesis, God appeared, created the world, and then apparently disappeared in the interim.
So God was, and even if he is, he's up there.
So that makes you feel separated from God, does it not?
You're down here and he's up there.
Created the universe and disappeared.
Left you rolling out there all on your lonesome.
That which is infinite is always.
Has no beginning, has no end, has no location.
The realization I had in the snowbank, and we'll confirm the truth of it.
I'm going to confirm it.
That which I am existed before all worlds.
That which I am will still be after all worlds have disappeared.
It's just out of divinity.
Divinity arises out of the Godhead, arises divinity as creator.
And first there is the Godhead, out of which arises God as creator.
And God's creation manifests as the universe.
But each one is a different level.
Thank you.
Godness arises out of the Godhead.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Hello.
I am struggling with trying to stay aware of God.
In the busyness of my day.
I may start out in the morning making a commitment.
And then by the end of the day, I see that I wasn't even aware of God all day.
Well, you weren't thinking about God.
Awareness is one thing.
Thinking about is something else.
Awareness is present or you wouldn't be complaining that you'd stop thinking about God.
So don't confuse thinking about God with awareness of God.
Because of awareness of God, you're distressed that you, you know, stop thinking about God.
Okay.
Because there are some people who think about God all the time, but it doesn't do much good.
And then there's other people who only think of God rarely, but it seems to do them a lot of good.
So you make your declaration for the day in the morning.
Okay.
Your declaration for your life and your declaration for the day.
And you ask God for forgiveness that you can't function within the world and mentally keep repeating his name all the time.
You can do that if you're in an ashram.
Okay.
Thank you so much.
Yes.
I just want to thank you for being a teacher and all you've done and all you are doing for us.
So just thank you.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Oh, he brought a bowling ball with him.
Down the alley.
Dr. Hawkins, I wish to extend my love and gratitude to yourself and Susan.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Dr. Hawkins, would you be willing to muscle test if I am dual or multiple personality?
We'll ask permission.
We have permission.
Ask.
You suspect it could be a factor based on the occurrence yesterday, possibly recontextualizing.
Well, he's talking about different levels of consciousness.
He doesn't really have two personalities.
You know, he is not a compartmentalized personality, because you wouldn't be complaining about it.
No, they usually do not suspect it.
Wow.
Tragedy.
Thank you very much.
People who worry about it, they don't have it.
What they really mean is different moods, different states of consciousness, but not different personalities.
Everybody has their upside and their downside, you know.
Yeah.
Isn't that so?
We kid around.
Hello.
Yeah.
If time is an illusion,
how come there is a progression from birth to childhood to adulthood to old age?
Well, you're, you're conjecturing something called time in which this occurs.
It would occur without the conjecture of time and see this go into this.
You don't need time to explain that to you.
Where'd you come up with time?
It's a superimposition and you're saying this is happening in time.
It's sort of like a track at the bottom of a TV program.
Yeah.
What do they call that track that I've done at the bottom?
Uh, time gets imprinted on, it gets imprinted.
It's not innate to experience.
And if you let go resisting the experience of time, it disappears.
The experience of time, which is subliminal all the time.
If you become conscious of it and let go resisting it, what will happen is you'll disappear time, which is sometimes handy.
Got to drive.
I'm Phoenix to Sedona and it takes place experientially in, uh, less than a minute.
You just leave Phoenix and you're in Sedona and there's no memory of, uh, you know, uh, time progression.
In fact, that's one of the fastest ways to transcend the ego is to let go.
To let go of time.
Time imprinting and let go resisting this, the experience of time.
And if you let go resisting it, it will eventually all of a sudden disappear and then you're in timelessness.
Yeah.
Then you constantly have to ask people, you know, what time, how much time we got left here and would the body then stop aging?
No, no.
The body goes on by itself, but he doesn't eat by time.
It eats when he thinks it needs to eat.
You can let go needing to eat too, you know, and then somebody has to remind you, you better eat.
There's always somebody nuisancing.
You're telling you it's time to eat all the time.
I said, I ate Tuesday.
All right, the hell I want to eat now.
It's only Thursday.
Then they complain you're too skinny.
You know, you can't keep them happy.
I don't know.
Thank you.
You, your work and research has really changed our lives.
Yes.
Time is a fast track to transcending the mind.
What is this?
Yes.
Time is a super imposition, which is projected on to phenomenal.
It is not intrinsic to.
Awareness.
There are people who live in different time dimensions.
There are different cultures in which time is experienced differently.
I told you when I was in Ecuador, there was two planes out a week from, uh, there were two, two planes a week out of Ecuador, Wednesday and Saturday or something like that.
And I got there for the Wednesday plane.
They said the Wednesday plane was leaving till Saturday.
And in Ecuador, 10,000.
10,000 feet.
It just didn't make a darn bit of difference that happened in Chicago.
I would have been all of a sudden, but in Ecuador, they sort of live beyond time.
So anyway, I told you before in the middle of the airport in Ecuador, yeah, is a clock, which stopped many years ago.
Nobody bothered to fix it.
The Wednesday plane is not leaving till Saturday.
I said, okay, Saturday went back.
I was there at quarter 12.
Plane was going to leave at 12 and all of a sudden there was one plane.
One, one airplane on the whole, in the whole airport.
And, uh, all of a sudden this engine shut down, uh, because it was siesta time.
They shut the engines down on this plane from 12 till three o'clock at three o'clock.
Brrng, the siesta time was over.
The engines started up.
I got aboard.
We took off.
Didn't have a slight, didn't feel the slightest stress.
It was just okay.
Somehow in the never, never landed at 10,000 feet in Ecuador.
Yeah.
I heard that on your video.
It's a fact.
It's wonderful to hear.
It's a fact, yeah.
Live.
No distress.
Wonderful to be here.
Yeah.
I came here to thank you with my respects.
Yeah, that's a fact.
You just sort of transcend time.
So no matter what happens, just pretend you're in Ecuador.
Time doesn't make a difference.
I loved Ecuador for that reason.
It was like never, never land.
I hope I can remember my question.
Uh-huh.
I've been, um, I've been in a happy place for quite a few years and suddenly I come
up upon retiring from my job.
She's been in a happy place for years?
Yeah.
You know it.
She's retired.
Oh, retired.
I thought you meant a psychically happy place.
I do.
Oh, okay.
So, so this retirement seems to be bringing on, and I'm thinking it might be my animal
fear of the future.
Uh-huh.
And I identified with that, and I got in a very bad place from my perspective, and I
just.
You mean like health worries, financial worries, or what?
Financial worries.
Right.
Oh, you just get to be poor, that's all.
Hey.
And, and what's wrong with that?
Yeah?
What's wrong with that?
Nothing.
Well, then you live like a poor person lives.
Mm-hmm.
No spending money.
I didn't spend any money for years.
Or you go find another job.
That's what you can do, too.
Yeah.
And all those things are part of your life.
All those things were kind of, um, not in my awareness.
I was just aware of all of the negatives.
All of the what?
Negatives.
Oh, you were writing these negative scenarios.
Yes.
Oh, well.
What you do is you surrender all these negative scenarios.
Yes.
You, uh, are homeless, you live on a park bench, you cover yourself up with newspapers,
let it be okay.
And when you're hungry, you go to the bank.
They always have tea and cookies there.
Then you, uh, borrow the Wall Street Journal from the bank.
And you go out in the park and read the Wall Street Journal and eat your cookies and coffee
from the bank.
Yeah.
And then you hang out with the bag ladies and, uh, jolly them up and see how they make
a living.
So pretty soon you get a basket yourself.
Yes.
Awesome.
Well, see how free a bag lady is.
She doesn't have to be to work.
She doesn't have to pay any taxes.
I mean, it's pretty simple.
Yeah.
She doesn't have to pay any taxes.
I mean, it's a pretty great life in a way.
You live in the park.
Mosquitoes are bad, though.
Mosquitoes are bad.
I'm glad to have, um, come out of that.
I just did not understand why I should go there.
It just didn't make any sense for me to...
Oh, your mind...
I know all this stuff.
Your mind will come up with common sense, uh, ways to provide for your needs, you know.
Absolutely.
How old are you?
Sixty-three.
Well, two years to heaven.
Sixty...
Well, that old Social Security rules, then.
Well, you can sign up for Social Security early.
Did you sign up for it early?
I may.
Oh, you signed up for it early.
Mm-hmm.
Because you don't live long, maybe, to...
You might as well use it up while you're living, you know.
Very true.
You won't be poor next year.
I know.
You know, now, you can be poor when you're 95 and you've run out or somethin'.
Yeah, don't worry about it.
The whole episode was rather silly as I look on it now, but when I was in
it, it felt horrible.
When you're in it, it was fearful because fear propagates fear, you know.
Survival fear.
And, of course, the ultimate is to let go one's survival fear and to let one's survival be
up to God.
Yes.
Because the inevitable is inevitable.
And what's the difference, when it's an hour later?
You know what I'm saying?
it doesn't really make that much difference
unless it's only how you look at it
oh isn't that awful
but in the reality is it doesn't make any difference
thank you
thank you very much
it's constantly surrendering
the fears as they come up
surrendering the fears as they come up
I'll be poor and I'll be homeless and then what
and then I'll die
if you're on your way to dying
what do you need a picture for
I want to give it to my husband
oh
demand ID at heaven's door
so security card
picture ID
thank you
picture ID isn't that funny
well they probably do demand picture ID
hello
how do they know they got the right person
thank you
I don't have a question
but I just wanted to say thank you thank you so much
yes
for your work and your dedication to God
thank you
yes and thank you for thanking me
yes
it's inspiring and I'm very grateful
alright honey
God bless you
yes
here we have Kleenex
give you a slight charge
Kleenex surcharge
yes go ahead speak
I just
had an experience literally
the day that I was coming out here to see you
where I discovered that somebody I was in a relationship with
completely betrayed me
and lied to me
like contrived lies
like my intuition had been screaming at me
and I confronted this person
like
and what's distressing me is like
how
like the why of the
like the attraction of that
like how I brought that into my life
and I'm like
oh yeah karma
it's called karma
yeah it's called karma
yeah
each life is a marine with karma
yeah stop weeping and listen to me
stop the crying now and just listen to me
and so this person betrayed you yes
alright
therefore you have to forgive the one in you
who has betrayed others
what comes at you is always what is already within you
therefore
you pray to God for forgiveness
for the one in you
who unwittingly
or not being conscious like you are now
betrayed others
that's the only way to heal it
you have to own that within yourself
and ask for forgiveness
and forgive the one in you
who betrayed others in other lifetimes
because it didn't
she didn't know better
he didn't know whatever it was
that's how you heal it
and disconnect yourself from the karma coherence of the collective
alright
forgive the one in you who betrayed others
if it weren't for that one
you wouldn't have brought this negative karma
this is why
this is a realm
in which the undoing of negative and the gaining of positive
so you forgive the one
and ask God for forgiveness
for the one in you who betrays others
how many could live
you know many a lifetime
without betraying somebody else sooner or later huh
difficult
yep
okay
you probably did it in the name of survival
or gain
survival or gain
yeah
oh you can look at survival as a gain can't you
well surviving is a gain
hello
yes
it's a prophet
that's not for a signature
that's for the question
whatever
the question
yeah
yes
in the textbook of A Course in Miracles
oh the textbook yeah
on page 41 it says
before Abraham was M.I.
where does it calibrate on the map
this level and why Abraham
oh you're talking about the Old Testament
about which I know very little
oh
okay
well the religiosity that went on
at that time
on the other side of the world
involved other religions
other cultures
other belief systems
and I find it difficult to apply that
to the
you know
to today
there is a lot
so the quote
the quote was
before what
Abraham was M.I.
was I.M.
now before Abraham
I was
yeah
who was before Abraham
God
yes
so what's the problem
well
before man
was God
divinity preceded the appearance of man
before Abraham
was
Abraham
yes
so what's the problem
well
before man
was God
was
I.M.
yes
there is a
a large movement
these days
of
thinking
and
it's
channeled
teachers
that call themselves
Abraham
so I was
more asking
if there may be connection
that actually
what this
no it's a different Abraham
they're talking about
oh okay
thank you
they're talking about Abraham Hicks
different thing
there wasn't any Hicks
at the time of Jesus
thank you
she's confusing the name
you know the name
yes
that's only nominalization
I can't control what people ask me you know
well I'm not going to ask you anything
my weather
stormy weather field
likes to be in your weather field
thank you
you bet
to discern the level of truth of a statement
you know you calibrate the level of truth you see
you don't need a personal opinion
you just calibrate
what's the level of that
and what's the level of this
and they may come out of different contexts
hello Dr. Hawkins
one thing is true in this context
and the other thing is true in this context
but this is not true in this context
you understand
yeah
hello Dr. Hawkins
you answer all my questions through your work
and I'm very grateful
and I thank you very much
however there is somebody very dear to me
who wants to ask you
a question
who wants what
who wants to ask a question
somebody wants to ask you a question
which is my dear wife
oh oh
where is she
she's at home
oh oh
and she keeps asking me
how come a man
is meditating 3-4 hours a day
and he's always with his tapes
with his headphones on his ears
a real man wouldn't do that
and the only answer I can tell her
is that it's an attraction
I don't know
it just happens
and then she says
well day by day you're getting crazier and crazier
and then you're getting as that old crazy guy on TV
that you're watching at
and I said God willing
so you turn me on to this
can you please turn her off
you have a divergence of alignment
and many relationships end because of it
one gets God struck
and the other doesn't
and very often the one who doesn't is jealous
and hates the one who's God struck
because they're not God struck
and so they do end in divorce yes
you have to choose between God and her
but it's her decision isn't it
she's the one making the decision
yeah
she's the one that's turning away from God
and you turn towards God
yes that can cause quite a divergence
so now I can go home in peace
you can go home and be
in peace
in peace I said
oh peace yeah yeah
you answered the question thank you
you pray for her
okay
well I committed that I will serve her as I would serve God
so let's see what that brings
yeah okay
thank you
thank you doctor
yeah
just pray secretly
don't let her know you're praying
while you're eating your toast in the morning
and look at you you flip the page
and see you're surreptitiously praying
how you doing doc
could you talk further about
the identification with
the light of consciousness
about what
identification with the light of consciousness
could you talk a little bit about that
it's by letting go what you are not
that it's revealed to you
that that which is the source of consciousness
and that which you are
are simultaneous
it isn't affirming what you are
because that's probably just a thought
instead you just constantly surrender
what you are not
and where does awareness
does awareness come out of consciousness
the light is consciousness
and awareness is like a quality of consciousness
yes
so the light of consciousness
which is universe
is universal
out of the light of consciousness
when it strikes matter arises life
see
because it is the source of life
yeah
becomes protoplasmic life
when it encounters organic material
organic
not inorganic
but organic
yeah
so you let go of what you are not
it's not necessary to affirm what you are
because what you are becomes
it's like surrendering
it just kind of reveals itself
it reveals itself
and if one were to live in that silent space
all the time
what would happen to the ego and the experiencer
they disappear
thank you
yeah
hello Dr. Hawkins
yes
my question is
for someone who is looking to move eventually into the 400s
and eventually transcend the 400s
would you recommend higher education or college
or is that necessary
yeah
I think education helps
it just sharpens certain faculties
however it's not necessary
it's not necessary
anything that lifts your level of consciousness
education, dedication, selfless service
any one of them will do it
the Jesus prayer
to merely say the Jesus prayer from within all the time
you don't need to go to college to do that
see
so
it depends on what
how you picture your future life
if it's devoted to teaching
then the education would be beneficial
if instead you tend to become
more a spiritual initiate
then it's not necessary
you know some orders are
educative orders
and then there are orders that are not educative
they are more of service
so you serve God by gardening
and you also serve God by translating
doing the book of Kells
did you ever look up the book of Kells
K-E-L-L-S
you know
so you see the monks
spent lifetimes
doing this incredible work
so
anything might inspire you to
want to move in that direction
you know
somehow I feel compelled to tell you to look up the book of Kells
I don't know why
thank you
maybe you're one of those monks reincarnated
going to the bathroom all the time
instead of working on this
I have some books of cat poems
and painted cats
but I was told they were done on the computer
so no cats were harmed
what did she say
kitty books
oh kitty books
don't show me kitty books right in the middle of the
oh
stop
it's like incredibly beautiful music
it just stops you in my tracks
if I hear a beautiful strand of music coming out of somewhere
I'm just done
uh huh
I was wondering if I could either hold your hand
or sit in your presence
when you said
Gloria in excelsis Deo
thank you very much
Lord most high
that is a commitment you just made
thank you
a wonderful one
yeah kitties knock me out
puppies knock me out
beautiful music knocks me out
hello
oh
um I sent an email to you guys a while back
and I asked a question
I don't know if you understood the uh
what the question was
but this is what it was
I've recently been watching the videos from the earliest seminars
in 2002
January and February
and I noticed that uh
some of the numbers on the calibrating like ohm
and uh
was up at the high 900
uh
back then
and in the book
truth versus falsehood
it's at 740
and uh
Russia
at 431
back then
and
things change don't they
yeah
the consciousness level of mankind is shifting
last month
right as we talk
yeah
that then
kind of when I was here last time
I almost asked the question
but as you were
the
as uh
I was sitting there listening to all the questions
a guy got up and asked on the calibration of a book
that I had asked upon
uh
two years prior
when you calibrated that book for me it was at 560
and when you calibrated it for him last
in April
it was at 295
sometimes when a question is asked twice depending on the
we get different answers
yeah it's the real
because it's based on what the real question is
the intention of the question
so it
that does happen
but it's
um
it's uh
because you readdress it
it's the
what is that
I've already
you've already changed it
yeah
so
so what which would be the more accurate then
well you want to know currently
currently what's its effective energy
so how do we rely on what a book calibrates at then at any time
who said I rely on it
I'll just tell you what it calibrated at that time
under those conditions
a different person under different conditions
may get a different thing because
they're living on a different scale
than I am
does that make sense
I'm still not
it's still
I still don't
I still write
I don't know why
you know
it was 560 versus 295
and
you know it was a spiritual
well it could have been a second printing
it could have been
no the other things are
that the world changes about it
and changes what it is
it actually changes what it is
and that intention also changes
what it is
so the contextualization of intention
let's say if I tell you a statement
in the context
in no context whatsoever
then it's limited to its own verbalization
its own depiction
if I present the same thing in a different context
I may get a different reading
because in that context that's what it means
in the context of essence
a thing may be one thing
in the context of a different field
it may be calibrated something differently
now
spiritual intention
religious intention
and religions
for instance
tend to show that figure
you can do some of the great religious teachings
can find a difference in calibration
within the teaching itself
some verses are very high
some verses are very low
now
how I contextualize this is
whether I'm doing it as a student
or as really just
trying to get a linear
depiction
or whether I'm doing it in the context of
is this the highest truth
you see
so it would be some
dependent
everything
all context is dependent on
all content is dependent on context
so you could get
you could have an influence of intention
and the context in which it's asked
within this context
it calibrates at this
it calibrates at that
you know there is a worldly
teaching that calibrates at 700
and yet
a great many of the verses calibrated
have far below 200
so you say
how could that calibrate at 700
when practically a third of the verses calibrate
30% of them calibrate 200
the other thing is that things are not logical
the real answer is
that things are not logical
and that the answer comes out of
studying it as a study
studying it further
if there's a disparity
what we do is we go at it like a brand new research
program
and begin to ask lots of questions
and a lot of times only after you ask
quite a few questions
does the reason clear up
so I wouldn't go just by appearance
I'd say
I want to know why there's this disparity
and then I would start asking questions about it
until I clarified the answer
like I thought
you know
earth-warming was due to human
endeavor myself
see
then when I got to know I thought
wow
what do I mean to know
alright so I would say
you know if it puzzles you
it would be a project
and maybe there's some meaning that you need to know in it
and that's why it comes to your attention
I have an idea
I would make a study of it
yeah
there must be some reason
you were doing the om
instead of asking what does om calibrate at
or saying om calibrates at
you were going om
calibrates at
so that you know I thought
maybe that's it
you know
yeah
anyway
I would take any seeming disparity
and just ask a lot of questions
until you're satisfied with the answers that you're getting
because there is an
you know there is an explanation
and
we hit puzzlers ourselves too
you know we hit puzzlers
and
we hit puzzlers
and it's only after we take out time
we have to take out time from a busy life
to research it out
but it's good to research it out
I think there's probably some
thing you need to know revealed in it
and that's why you're focusing on it
okay
you know there's some benefit
you may be bringing up something we all need to know
who knows
so thank you for looking at it
and bringing it up
thanks
I know we get stuck with it ourselves
we get puzzled with it
also at different times
the same thing or person will calibrate differently
hello Dr. Hawkins thank you
yeah
I've been in the 12 step program for the last four years
and I've also been studying the Course in Miracles
for three and a half years
and I was introduced to you about six months ago
and I've made a lot of changes in my life
I've made a lot of progress personally in my life
and right now as we speak
I'm making some major personal changes
thank you
in my family
and what I wanted to find out is
if you can help me answer the question
I believe
this is for the greater good of my family
and I wanted to know if you can help me answer that question
what question
I believe
is my decision
I'm getting divorced
yeah
and I believe it's the answer to
you know my problem with my family right now
yeah
and I want to know if it's for the greater good of my family
and I want to know if you can help me answer that question
I don't think I'm allowed to ask that
no
I'm not allowed to answer that
okay I understand
would I have permission to calibrate me personally
no
okay
uh
it's partly you know it's partly because you're in a 12-step program
okay
yes
that the context is different
see
that um
the karmic gain to doing it on your own
as a result of prayer
you ask God
in the 12th step
what is the 12th step
12th step is continue um
continue to carry a message to um
oh that's 12
okay what's 11
11 is sought through prayer and meditation to continue your conscience
to continue your contact with God as you understood him
praying only for his knowledge and his will to carry that out
okay only for knowledge of his will for me
so then that comes as a knowingness and a certainty
okay
yeah
obviously you feel that's fulfilling
what's your obligation your spiritual obligation is right now
okay I respect that I appreciate it I wouldn't
I just wanted to ask I didn't want to leave here without asking but thank you very much
yes
right gain is greater to make his own decision
those are tough ones
yes
hi Dr. Hawkins
my name is Neha
and uh
I came to know of you quite recently this is my first time here seeing you in person
I don't know what you said
this is your first time here
you speak slowly right into the mic I don't know they're too far away from the mic
so this is my first time I'm seeing you in person
oh okay
and I got introduced to you uh a while back
yes
um
and one thing led to another and I was uh
listening to all your beyondtheordinary.net talks
um almost all night long
uh
beyond the what
beyond the ordinary
the ordinary
oh oh yeah yeah yeah
I'll get to my question now
um
so
um I set my and I declared my spiritual intention to realize myself
uh I I face a mental conflict at times when I'm not um
when I hear that everyone else is meditating or reading or doing a lot of things and
um
and I'm not doing that
and I go back to thinking whether I should be doing that
but
um
I I don't know is is is
is uh setting
you you you fulfill a thing you do things based on the strength of your motivation
if you can't be bothered to meditate then your motivation is not there
your motivation is not that intense yet
you'd rather watch tv huh
yeah
that's what I thought
she's honest
of course she's honest
but I get excited and happy about feeling that you know that I want to know myself
I want to know God you know just
well you got a whole lifetime you know you
you got a while yet
next 40 50 years you'll get it you know
why rush it
so um till then my uh responsibilities should be just to focus on um
well you're talking about self-discipline to say you know it helps to set aside a certain time period
you know I used to meditate an hour in the morning and an hour in the evening you know
for many years see
always no matter how busy life was
see
and if I had to be at the hospital early at seven o'clock I got up at five so I could meditate for an hour before I left for the hospital
so you arrange your life around
your meditative schedule yeah
so would self-discipline do good to me for my spiritual intention
what
would self-discipline
yes that would be be indicative
so you have to make an agreement with yourself what time you're going to set aside for strictly spiritual work
contemplation meditation prayer
singing psalms whatever you want to do
going to church whatever
okay
yeah
yeah it's not complicated
oh yeah
so my husband is going to ask another question now after me
I wanted your blessings on us as a couple to remain aligned with the spiritual intention
choose your blessings
blessing of what
of the couple
yeah
with my husband
where's the husband
we have to get his permission
is that okay
of course sir
God bless the two of you
in God's love
Amen
love is always blessed
yeah
you know
God is love
yeah
oh my goodness
thank you
she is so cute
I also have a question for you
yes
this is a little simpler one
basically my wife is vegetarian
and I am not
and
she's a vegetarian
a vegetarian
yes
oh yeah
and I am not
and one of the things which I noticed was that
she's a vegetarian
yes
and I am not
and one of the things which I noticed
was that
the
the herbivorous animals
they are
more benign
or they are higher in scale
yes yes
and I think we kind of have this discussion
and I was wondering
if let's say humanity decided to be vegetarian
would it raise the level of consciousness
or
it doesn't matter
if everyone was vegetarian
would it raise the level of consciousness
no
vegetarianism calibrates at 210
which is not you know
going to knock over the globe
okay
yeah
all right
thank you very much
yeah
you just asserted being spiritual and a vegetarian
oh
a lot of people say if you're not a vegetarian they'll kill you
environmentalism
yeah
I would like to express a profound gratefulness that I feel everywhere in this room for you
yes
it's for the group
yeah
it's a group
I just feel it everywhere
so I don't want to mention myself in that
I have a pretty burning question for my whole life
and it comes from other lifetimes
and this one as well
is there a time
because I know on your map of consciousness
that suicide rates at a negative 50
is there a time in a person's life
at the end of their life
when they're suffering
and there's no
you know
dying
they're basically dying
is it
karmic
are there karmic repercussions for taking your own life
or assisting somebody in taking their life at that point
well you're asking about
you know
what does suicide calibrate at
depends on who's committing suicide
and for what reason
and in what context
it's not necessary to commit suicide
if you want to die
just allow yourself to die
what's the problem
but not everybody knows
if someone wants to die
they can go in there
they can go in the garage
and close the door
and turn the engine on
you don't need a doctor
to give any injection
you know what I'm saying
so that's not a karmic
there's no negative
that's trying to heap the responsibility
on the doctor and society
if you decide to leave the world
that's pretty easy to do isn't it
and that's
that doesn't have bad karmic repercussions
I didn't ask about that
I don't think we can ask
because it depends on who
and in what context
and what they think death is
right
so there are levels of death
so the motivation could be fear
of pain
fear
yeah
it could be cowardice
if you want to die
that's very very simple
I'll tell you how to do it for nothing
stop eating
stop drinking fluid
and lay on the floor
you don't have to hire a doctor
to come in and give you an injection
doctor death or somebody
you know
so I'm hearing
to die
all you have to do is do nothing
and you will automatically die
yes
you lay on the ground
and you
and the sun comes up
and the sun comes down
you become dehydrated
you lapse into coma
and you leave
what's the problem
you don't have to hire a video crew you know
and make a big drama out of it
it's very simple to die
you let go wanting to live
and you let go wanting to live
the desire to live slips away
and the breathing slows down and down
and you can be very very close to death
and still come back
because at the last moment you realize
it's still up to you
and then you get the karmic implications
and the meaning of this
and you then may change your mind
it is you know
on one hand
the reason we calibrate low
is because it's like negating divine mercy
you see
as you're turning your life to God
you're turning it over to the divine mercy
in the death process
is then bearable
can even be ecstatic
out of God's grace is given the strength
to bear death
so constantly surrendered to God's grace in the matter
is what summons it forth
I don't want to calibrate suicide because
people will go into a negative space of all of it
sometimes it can be an act of bravery and courage
other times it can be courage
it can be cowardice
so you don't know which is which
so you can't generalize it
it depends on who's doing it
or what motive
yeah
hello
there's a way of committing suicide which is passive
in which you don't
you just don't resist death
yeah
and then death takes over
I have experienced chronic fatigue
for over six years
what
chronic fatigue
yeah yeah
and I'd just like to know what caused this
and how to get over it
I've
you're talking about a medical diagnosis
I've been to about 15 doctors
it's been going on for a long time
and I've tried different healing modalities
oh chronic fatigue syndrome
yes sir yeah
CFS
well yeah
okay
there are many theories about it
chronic fatigue syndrome
and there's also many
a whole set of modalities of treatment
and I treated many in my lifetime
each one seemed to me to be different
there was no like
a cause of it
so I used to use a whole
bunch of things
nutritional
consciousness
acupuncture
a whole variety of things
and
I forget what the last
most powerful things I found were for
I've sort of forgotten now
it's been some years since I've been in practice
antidepressants
Prozac
various things
you've probably been through all them yes
yes sir yeah
yes
all right
so then it could also be
some kind of a karmic propensity
could be a karmic propensity
chronic fatigue syndrome
I've sort of forgotten all the different modalities
I used to use
but there was about a dozen
and about 90% of the time
one of them would work
you know one or the other would work
okay
so nothing specific to my case
that you can pick up on that
I don't think
it's a causal link
you have to run through a gamut
okay
yeah I've done that so
yeah
all right
okay
thanks very much
sure
I'll put that on so it wouldn't fly out
I'm sorry
he was fatigued
but he ain't no more
I'll tell you
now it's a tough
it's a tough diagnosis
because nobody really knows the
specific answer to it
or a specific cause
you know
yeah
I think it's still to be discovered yet
you know
hmm
hello
thank you for today
and for everything you've done for all of us
yes
I have a wonderful job
as the event coordinator for my church
and in this book
Discovery of the Presence of God
and I think one other
you present a very long and comprehensive list
of what we should look for
in integrous teachers
yes
my senior minister
how long and what list
a list of what constitutes an integrous teacher
oh yes yes
my senior minister
my boss
has recently invited someone to be a guest speaker
at our church
who's starting to look very much to me
not like an integrous teacher at all
ah
as the event coordinator
what kind of karmic responsibility do I have
here
it's not up to you
it's up to the rector
I would tell the rector
when I look at
you know
what
what signifies
you know
the best
this person
isn't always the best
seems to be
linking
and let the rector decide
because if they're lapsing
but in an area
that's going to be harmless
in your community
it might be permissible
you know
yeah
great
thank you
somebody who doesn't rape
small children in the
between the pews
would help
yeah
it doesn't
it doesn't look like it's someone like that
well there's some gurus on TV
that do that
yeah
pedophiliac
yeah okay
and this is an invitation
from my church
for you and Susan
oh thank you
you've been in Sacramento before
but we'd love to have you again
thank you love
thank you
see
not everybody needs to be perfect
but you need to know
where they're capable
and where they're not capable
see
so if he's a good brain surgeon
I don't let
you know
look to him
to do a good appendectomy
you know what I'm saying
don't look at any more kitty pictures now
I'm happy to meet you
Dr. Hawkins
okay
I didn't know
that I was supposed to sign your hand
or shake it
I wanted to shake your hand
so
I'm here
because I wanted
you to help me
with some confusion
so
three or four days a week
I have the perfect morning
I go to mass
I work on my spirituality
then I go to yoga
I work on my mental
then I go to private pilates
and I work on my physical
so I'm really
really happy
after that
about two hours later
the monkey mind
because I have been so
busy
with my physical
I'm really
really happy
after that
about two hours later
the monkey mind
because I have been
so busy
with my physical
because I have been
so mindful
all morning long
the monkey mind starts
and it's
I just don't like it
I'm all over the place
and I wanted to know
what practice
you would recommend
to me
I'm judging
this
you'll have to do a meditative
contemplative practice
in which you're
at one pointedness of mind
you know
you'll have to
perfect one pointedness of mind
you know
you can take the image
of a great teacher
a great guru
a great avatar
and hold
that in your mind
at all times
who is your
highest teacher
Christ is my
all right
so hold the picture
of the vision
of Lord Jesus Christ
in your mind
at the same time
you pray to him
yes
but I keep having
no matter
what you're doing
you're not listening
to what I'm saying
you're busy talking
yes I am
but I mean
I just
I said to keep the picture
it's okay
the vision
of Jesus Christ
in your mind
period
okay
and then
I didn't say
my thoughts will go away
you're not doing it now
okay
you're trying to
seek gain out of it
gonna try and milk
picturing Jesus Christ
to shut up
your monkey mind
I didn't ask you
to do that
I asked you
to just picture
Lord Jesus Christ
yes
not in order
to get some kind of
gain out of it
that you can shut up
your monkey mind
because that just
obliterates the value
of the whole process
you're looking
at the gain already
you look at Jesus Christ
because
you see
the perfection
of his heart
and you just
stay with that
period
that's all
thank you
no comments
no notations
no scribbling
in the margins
okay
thank you
very much
okay
it's hard
to make a thing
simple
it's very
it's exhausting
thank you
so you don't
do spiritual
practice
in order
to
anything
in order to
do it
because
that's
who you are
yeah
I brought you
a spare sword
oh boy
the next time
I run into
one of those guys
I'll put it
right through him
skewer
snicker snack
through and through
oh
look at he
disappeared
into nothingness
that's neat
I can carry that
in my blank bag
happy birthday
when it collapses
like that
that's what makes
it easy
it doesn't screw up
and it goes a little
farther
oh it does
it runs you through
special security
cool
yeah that's very nice
yeah
tell them you made it
you just did
oh did you make it
I did
oh you made it
oh my god
isn't that wonderful
yeah it's all
look at the wood
oh that's
manzanita
oh my god
isn't that pretty
that's wonderful
yeah thank you so much
it fits in your hand
feel it
oh my god
it's beautiful
manzanita
manzanita flavor
there you go
that's very nice
thank you very much
you're so welcome sir
thank you
earlier you were talking
about discernment
at 600
yeah
and yet it seems
below that level
there's something
that you could call
intuitive knowingness
oh yes
is there a relationship
well no I'm talking
about the perfection
where discernment
becomes automatic
as a consequence
of level of consciousness
there's discernment
long before that
yes
discerning right
from wrong
and there's a lot
of discernment
that goes on
before that
but be able to see
past perception
and see the essence
see the wolf
within the sheep's clothing
doesn't really come on
spontaneously
and autonomously
classically
that's called
the opening
of the third eye
of the buddhic body
which you see
past perception
you see
you don't even
see a sheep
there anymore
you just see
the wolf
bless Vicki
bless you
thank you
and he's out
to get you
this is wonderful
you're always afraid
you're gonna lose your
yes
I'm always afraid
I'm gonna lose it
or not find it
or forget it
or something
so we'll put it
where it's safe
hi doc
yes
no question
thank you
alright
good for you sir
good for you
hello
this is along
the same topic
of vegetarianism
that you addressed
just a few questions ago
do we incur
our karmic debt
from eating
dead animals
if we have a respect
of all living things
specifically
Specifically, does meat-eating calibrate lower than vegetarianism?
Vegetarianism calibrates 210.
Now, it doesn't have any spiritual positive or negative.
It would have only to the degree that you're fulfilling
what you feel is a spiritual obligation.
And most people go through a period of vegetarianism, et cetera.
Thank you.
It's because of one's intention to not harm living things.
And you don't incur any karmic debt from that?
No.
The Rig Veda, you have to read the Rig Veda,
and you will understand what I'm saying.
Rig Veda.
Calories at 900.
Okay.
Each thing earns its own transcendence
by serving that which is below it.
By allowing myself to be eaten by humankind,
the cattle earns its right to evolve
eventually to humanness.
By my sacrifice to thee, O Lord of my life,
to that which is higher,
do I earn the karmic right to become higher?
Calvary's 900.
The Rig Veda recontextualizes the whole question.
I once saw it.
I saw a bird that was caught by a hawk,
and I saw that the bird, I saw its spirit.
It supplicated itself to the hawk.
I saw it.
I give myself to thee, O Lord, is what it was actually saying.
I actually saw it.
And then the hawk again will surrender that which I am to thee, O Lord.
And each one goes higher and higher.
I actually witnessed it long before I read it in the Rig Veda.
Thank you.
Can I also get a blessing for my husband and I?
We're recently married.
A blessing for what?
Her husband and I were recently married.
Oh.
Oh, yeah.
You can have his promotion, too.
The Native American manner of holding, the sacredness of the spirit of the animal, is
another way of acknowledging the divinity of the essence of life in all that lives,
and giving thanks to Almighty God for the life of the animal.
So the American Indian, you know, blesses the sacrifice of the animal, and thereby, you know,
and thereby, affirms the divinity of all of life, you know, the sacredness of the great spirit.
Native American acknowledges the great spirit as a source of life.
So, God bless the two of you.
Yeah.
God bless you in love, in love, and alignment in love.
Thank you.
And in love.
Yes.
I was going through a stack two weeks ago, and didn't get to sign the card, so I got
you another one.
Oh, thank you very much.
Here's a dollar for the question.
Kitty.
Yes.
The stack has got to do with two things, but one of them is for the many years.
various people connected to
a now deceased guru.
Connected to what?
To a now deceased guru.
To what?
A deceased guru.
Or deceased.
Deceased.
There.
This is a very large organization
and there are many people in there
who on many levels
are very wonderful people.
Yes.
And I know that at one point
this guru calibrated fairly high
in the high 500s and then fell.
Yeah.
I don't get that it was about sexuality,
power, or those other things.
Yeah.
Would it be for opening up students
without properly preparing them?
It could be any defect.
What do you mean the guru fell?
The teacher fell?
The teacher.
Well, that I don't have.
I know that you had calibrated him
at around 570
and then he went down to the 100s.
That's rather common, yeah.
And I don't get that it was for the usual ones
or money, power, sex.
Yes.
And I don't get that from...
You don't know what the reason is?
Yeah.
You'd have to be more involved
and then it'll become apparent.
I don't want to be more involved.
The person will become more secular,
more interested in money, fame, power, glamour.
It could be any one of them.
Would opening...
Energetically opening a huge amount,
a mass of people
without properly preparing them,
would that also be one of...
Would that be a spiritual trap?
That'd be a control issue.
It's kind of a research question.
It's a research question,
but what you're presenting as a possibility
is you're going to force people
to desire spiritual awareness
without their agreement, you know?
Okay.
So I'm also thinking of myself
as a teacher and my responsibilities
to my students in terms of
is there a line?
I guess there is no real line
for any of this, is there?
Oh, yes, there is.
Okay.
Yeah, there's definitely a line.
So where do I find that line?
About what?
You're mixing up a whole bunch of issues here.
I don't...
You're vague on your question,
so it's very difficult.
You can't control the consciousness level
of your students,
and you've got to let go
wanting to control that, right?
Yes.
You're not going to force them
to become enlightened.
No.
Oh, okay.
So it's like the Shaktipat,
which would be a forceful issue.
So what you do is
you give them the information they need.
Right.
And as much encouragement as you can,
but then the evolution is up to themselves,
you see?
Right, yes.
Thank you.
Or you teach them a certain technique
that will help them
to achieve their spiritual goals, you know?
Thank you very much.
Yeah, so techniques are useful,
but they're only a technique.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Thank you.
You know,
like surrendering the,
resisting the experiencing of time,
you know,
it's only a technique, you know?
Mm-hmm.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
Yes.
Well, Hustle.
Hello.
Oh, hi.
This morning was exceptional
in its clarity
and expansion
of our learning your work.
Yes.
We have a group
that meets twice a month in Phoenix,
and what we've been doing
is showing a DVD
of a Sedona,
Sedona presentation.
Yes.
It's on a weeknight evening,
so we only have like an hour and a half to two hours.
Some are requesting that we pick a book
and go through a paragraph at a time,
and others prefer that we watch a DVD
and get a more like an overview.
You can do it both ways.
Sometimes if you meet twice a week,
one night you do a video,
and the next night you do a discussion,
or discuss a book.
Yeah.
Good.
You know, both ways are used,
you know, like in AA,
they will take a lesson for the day,
12 steps,
they'll do a step or a tradition,
or because nowadays we have DVDs,
you know, they do a video.
Yeah.
Excellent.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
Thank you.
I have a question.
Sure.
Recently I've been doing a lot of releasing,
and now it just feels like
I can't really feel any,
you know,
emotions coming up,
but only the,
I guess,
the physical sensations in my stomach.
And I was wondering,
is that normal,
or am I actually supposed to be feeling something
when I'm surrendering?
Yeah, that's normal.
Okay.
Is there any,
I mean,
additional advice that you can...
About what?
...collaborate?
Advice on what he should be doing,
where to take it from...
What he should be doing about what?
I guess, yeah,
where to take it from there.
He wants to know where to go from here.
From where?
I don't get where,
from where?
Repeat it one more time.
If he's finding physical,
you know...
I'm only feeling,
like, physical sensations,
usually around,
I guess,
the solar plexus.
Yeah.
Oh, let go in to change it.
Let go resisting it.
And go in to change it.
Let it be there.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
The way you disappear a thing
is by letting go resisting it.
I'm afraid that I'm actually,
like,
actively suppressing,
negative emotions or something.
Afraid of what?
Suppressing a negative emotion
or something.
No.
Well,
if you're suppressing
a negative emotion,
the way to clear it
is to let go resisting it.
Okay.
The way to get rid of pain
is to let go resisting the pain.
And you've got to be right on it
as it arises.
And then it will disappear.
Thank you.
You were telling earlier,
about an hour ago,
about when you make,
I'm going to say
it's the ultimate
last step
or something
when you go through
the door.
And I was,
I have someone,
I know someone
that did that
and I was wondering,
is that the ultimate
when you go through
that door and...
The door I'm talking about
is final.
But you're still here.
The body is.
Oh.
Yeah.
Ego,
that which
was presumed
to be me
disappeared
a long time ago.
So,
after you go...
The physicality
has its own
protoplasm
and,
the protoplasm
has its own
karmic propensity.
I have nothing
to do with it.
So,
my question is,
after you go
through that door,
what level
of calibration
are you at?
I don't know
that there is
any calibration
because there's
nobody to calibrate.
That state
of consciousness
is what you're
asking about.
Yes.
Yeah.
The void
is at 850.
Okay.
Yeah.
The void
is at 850.
And then you come
into the,
I guess,
what you would call
the 900s,
no?
Yeah.
Anyway,
that's covered
in Transcending
the Levels
of Consciousness
and that book
there will tell you
in the final
chapters,
yes.
Okay.
I have a gift
for you.
It's,
in 1992,
Mother Teresa
addressed
the Scripps
clinical staff
after she recovered
from her
heart problem
and she just
talks for
40 minutes
and it's
amazing.
How very nice
indeed.
Thank you.
We treasure
those things.
Yeah.
She's back
in the news
currently,
huh?
Yes.
I wonder
if you can
help me
with my
chemical imbalance.
With your
what?
Chemical
imbalance.
That's a chemical
problem.
Well,
you told me
not to use
the word
depression
in the past
so I'm trying
to use
the word
depression.
Oh,
okay.
Thank you.
All right.
Okay.
That's good.
Yeah.
I said
that's a
clinical
problem
of brain
chemistry.
Yeah.
Okay.
So now
what?
So I've
been having
this feeling
toward myself
and I can't.
What?
Herself.
What about
herself?
She's got
things
involved.
Yeah?
And anyway,
I can't stop
the thoughts.
Are you seeing
a doctor like
advice?
Yeah,
yeah.
All right.
Tell him
about that.
What spiritual
problem
you got?
Well,
Good girl.
I mean,
I got
some
about thinking
negative thoughts
that come
on their
own that
I'm not,
you know,
I'm not
looking for
them.
They're just
other than
prayer and
meditation
and commitment
that takes
care of
the spiritual
and biochemistry
takes care
of the physical
and between
the two of
them,
you're doing
all you can
do and
therefore
yes,
that is true.
Lots of things
are uncomfortable.
Just being alive
is uncomfortable.
I know
you're doing
better.
You're better
than you were.
You're much
better.
I would say
some,
some spiritual
service
somewhere
that you
earn the karmic
merit that
those kinds
of thoughts
be removed
from you.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'm working
on that already.
Thank you very
much.
That means a
lot to me.
It's because
you're doing
what you're,
you know,
I asked you
to do.
Mm-hmm.
Doing what
I asked you
to do.
No,
you're much
better.
And I
think,
I think some
service,
some place
in your life,
I don't see
service yet.
Some area
of service.
Humane
society.
Yeah,
something.
Take your
flowers to
Well,
I'm already
selling,
I'm selling
newspapers for
real change,
which is,
you know,
for homeless
and people.
Oh,
that's very
good,
yeah.
And,
and people
who,
you know,
are just
making it.
And I'm one
of the ones
that is just
making it,
so I'm doing
it for the,
yeah,
doing,
she's doing
up there as
well.
From hopeless
to hopeful.
Yes.
Hi,
Dr.
Hawkins.
I have a
question about
my personal
life.
I have a
boyfriend that
I suspect
is not
at the
calibratable
level of
200.
And I
think
I am.
And if
I choose
to be
at the
calibratable
level,
is it
likely that
he will
raise his
calibratable
level up
or that I
might,
my level
might come
down?
Either one.
You may
go down
with him.
Okay.
So it's
somewhat
dangerous
to stay
in that
relationship
then,
with that
risk?
What?
Because he's
reading that
Is he out
of jail?
No,
he's,
it's just
that sometimes
he's,
I caught him
in lies.
Lies.
In lies.
And even though
they weren't
big lies,
they were,
the integrity
level seems
I don't know,
you got to
discuss it
with him.
The intention,
there was
some reason
he thought
he was
going to
do that
because he
has started
reading the
Course in
Miracles.
So he may be
just on his
way.
Okay.
He probably
thinks he
needs to
do that
for some
reason in
the relationship
and you'd
have to
clarify to
him that
he doesn't
need to
do that,
you know.
He probably
thinks he
needs to
do that.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yep.
Yeah,
I know you're
in the course
of,
yeah.
Hello,
Dr.
Hawkins.
Yes.
My name
is Liz.
And I need
help evicting
a housemate.
Need help
with what?
Evicting
a housemate.
Yes.
He moved
in June
1st.
He was
aggressive the
next day.
He had
a bad
instinct
and I
had a
bad
instinct
on him.
It was
a bad
instinct.
And when
I got
to
the
house,
my
instinct
told me
that I
didn't
like him
but I
went ahead
anyway.
Yeah.
So it's
my
action so i have filed a three-day eviction which he did not do i went to the court superior court
and they said it's a tenant landlord thing and i was doing it for aggressive behavior for protection
he's an aggressive male and we're the house is so negative it's he's tested at 170 well
so what is your legal uh mike yeah well i i tried to do it on aggressive uh behavior oh and i tried
to get him out on the three-day eviction under a nuisance thing so he if i'm friendly to him he
doesn't take it seriously yeah so i'm now not looking at him i'm not talking to him and it's
a horrible place to live energetically and so i'm asking you what can i do to hopefully
energetically
you
help him change to leave you're gonna have to do it through there she's gonna have to do it
through legal means well i'm still in that process yeah yeah no you can get her out get
him up by legal the lawyer says my case is not that strong what lawyer you got uh one that does
evictions huh an eviction lawyer oh well in that case nobody could ever evict anybody he says the
case is not very strong because of the behavior he's had he hasn't actually hit me because he
hasn't
hit her oh he's just oh it has to be violence yeah there has to be a reason other than just anger
get a better lawyer i'd say that you need a better lawyer really i know somebody just evicted
somebody and well the one housemate that's been there five years is now moving out because this
other one won't so it's it's just becoming a mess so you're saying get another one i don't
see what you can do via consciousness per se well it's influencing me and i earn a living you know
doing spiritual work so it's i mean i'm thankful to my friends who brought me here so that i could
shift myself out of it so i guess what i'm asking you is there a way that i could not fall into his
lower behavior on a consistent basis so that i'm not influenced while he's still there is he home
all the time yeah is he uh disabled no he's a navy veteran and he gets a pension and he doesn't leave
the house
does he drink no what does he do all day look at tv uh he works out yes he's got muscles yeah uh
fixes food stays in his room is on the internet yeah kind of i don't want to say i don't even want
to be judgmental but it's like he's wasting his time so i don't know it's still a legal problem
i don't know with your consciousness what you can do maybe you have some karmic problem with it too
i don't know you're linked to or something you're linked to him somehow
what links linked somehow to him you see i'm linked to some somehow to him or what he stands for
or a link to what he stands for some aspect of yourself you're disowning which is expressed by
him therefore it's intolerable okay they wonder what idles away their time and self indulgence
or whatever what is it he does he watches tv and eats what else he doesn't watch tv he just does
other stuff he does muscles yeah
machine stuff yeah okay so just get a bit of lawyer i don't know you need a more sophisticated
lawyer i think that's what he makes his living on evictions so he makes his living as a lawyer
he specializes in evictions that doesn't mean anything okay i've known nuns who took teeth
out all day long and they went with the damn okay i went from bad lawyers to good lawyers okay
both have same expertise i went for a long time
nowhere saw another guy within the first two minutes he told me how to handle it and that did
it so the difference between the top and the bottom in the professions is enormous correct
people don't suspect that they think all lawyers are in the same category they go from genius to
idiot there are doctors who take out the you know you don't want them to operate on you okay so
now you do you need a different legal opinion okay all right thank you very much
i'm watching now we're gonna have to go yes hi yes how are you i have a question about
experience that i had when i was very dedicated in my spiritual path many years ago i was giving
a talk i don't know what he's saying okay i'm sorry i'm good okay okay i will repeat
uh when i was in a spiritual teaching in the past
and i was giving a talk in front of people okay and at that time it's about witness and
observer at one moment i saw myself speaking and my mind and my body just speaking by itself
like yes behind my back yes is it what you mean by witnessing and observing yes that's witnessing
it's happening all by itself
so your condition right now is always like that observing like what david
hawkins is doing no i never witnessed or observe it anymore no no i don't care what he's saying
why should i witness of the observant i've heard him a dog before haven't i
but that is that is what you yes express no that's the way it is though it's just spontaneous by
itself and then you let go after a while of the phenomenon of witnessing
observing itself and all just everything merely is without a witness or observer you see the the duality
there's a there's a what's happening and there's a witness and the observer that's dualistic
eventually that disappears to be replaced things are just uh happening of their own
there's no witnessing or observing and it's all within consciousness
because it's like out of body we see the body and the mind speaking by no no okay
good spiritual practice to speak of us as the third person oh not necessarily no no there is
a phase where there's a tendency to do that but that's more like depersonalization yeah
yeah you witness the phenomena there's no pronouns involved you know the world is using pronouns but
they don't mean anything there's no me you it him he everything is happening spontaneously
okay so that's what i saw at that time yeah it's all happening spontaneously okay that's it
wait i have one more one more lady she came from canada okay thank you very much yeah yes
i'm sorry i'm slow i hear don't hear well don't see well
other than not seeing hearing something kind of any problem
uh
yeah is there anyone else that need pictures taken after this question yes go ahead
speak speak um i'm asking this question on behalf of a six-year-old child my nephew
six-year-old child yeah my nephew his mother my dear sister and i have grown up together really
really close and my sister used to be a typical
girl, very materialistic. She had a huge selection of expensive makeup, jewelry, and expensive
fashionable clothes. About two years ago, she got really interested and started practicing
Buddhism. She got it right. She went into Buddhism. Oh, yes. And then finally, in December
last year, she became a Buddhist monk in a very small temple in a mountain in northeastern
China. Basically, she left everything behind. She was a manager of a family business for
10 years or so. So she left everything, excluding her six-year-old child. And I was overjoyed
at my sister's decision, this commitment.
However, the little child cannot comprehend. And she, he is, plus he's being over-influenced
by the grandparents.
The child is living with the grandparents now?
Yeah, because the father has divorced my sister, and the father goes on business
quite a bit. And a lot of times, the child is...
Yeah.
...is looked after by the grandparents.
Who are still...
Grandparents.
The father's.
Father's parents.
Oh, okay.
And they are, the grandparents still resent, hold a lot of resentment toward my sister's
decision.
Yes.
So...
She should have waited until the child was older. Is that right? That's what they
think.
No, my question...
What is the problem?
The problem with my child is that if what Auntie Gigi, which is me, had told me true,
my mother still loves me, and she still cares me, how come she left me and doesn't even
call me?
Good question, yes. I just got through giving you the answer. The more spiritually
advanced way would be to wait until the child is older and would have understood it, rather
than to desert the child at age six. So there is some truth to the past.
What is the parents' anger about it? That they deserted, that she deserted the child
and left the child to them. Is that so? Is that so?
Yes.
I don't know.
Oh, you know it's true. Of course. Why do they have resentment? Why are the parents
resentful? What is their anger about?
But I know that my sister loves her son dearly.
Yes.
That's not what I'm talking about. You're talking about the grandparents' resentment,
about the mother deserting the child at age six. You're trying to understand it, and
I say it's only reasonable. Their position would be she should have waited until the
children were over. To do it now, she's being spiritually selfish. That's the judgment that
you're facing, yes? And it's their ...
He's presenting it as their side so you can understand why they feel this way.
Yes, yes.
You understand that?
It has nothing to do with her decision.
No.
It has to do with the way the parents ...
The way the grandparents are seeing it, you see?
Okay, he wants you to see their side, not just the sister's side, but just the other
side.
Yeah, there you go. So that way you can have compassion for both sides. You can understand
how the parents have a resentment and how the child feels that way.
But how we as adults explain to the six-year-old the mother still loves him and still cares
about him, but just not saying him.
So those are just ...
Those are just empty words. I don't think you can do so.
There was a saint, I forgot the name of the saint, who literally walked over her son's
body to enter a combat when the spiritual inspiration hit her. And she's a saint in
a Catholic church now.
Huh?
She literally walked over her own son's body to enter the order. So this is something that
when the spiritual calling comes, when a child enters an order, it takes a toll. So there's
something about all of us.
Right.
And so have you ever ...
comes that it takes a lot to be able to give up family is like a command and yes
it's almost like a command so we can understand your sister's side as to why
she did this but you have to also understand the grandparents side and
have compassion for their side because they feel like she abandoned this child
yeah then you see it from the child side to both sides so that you can present it
to the child in a reasonable manner without taking more one side than the
other grandparents and say that you understand their position you know and
as an aunt that you'd be more than willing to help with the child if they
needed any kind of relief that's that would be my way of approaching it as a
compassionate person each one could see the other ones viewpoints okay yeah
thank you
yeah and so but you do have to you know that's why he was kind of tough on you
because he wanted you to see that other side of the parents and it is very
difficult and there is a lot of there will be some resentful feelings in this
in this particular case but the best way to do it is also the child's karma to
you yeah the child's karma too okay thank you for such a complex problem
there's how we would like the world to go and then there's the way it goes all
right so there that's enough well let's give thanks to each other for each
other's presence it's all turned to the one next they say thank you for being
here thank you for being here and I thank everybody for being here
yeah
yeah I think this is the I think this is the good Karma group this add on a good
Karma group you know that we earn the right to each other's presence to the
right to be aligned with each other and I I think that that's a great gift from
God that so we're are we're we're God's gift to ourselves okay yeah we give you
you we do give each other our speciality thank you for being on this with us a long time thank you, very much THANK YOU!
other to ourselves to each other we do and I think by doing that we try to
fulfill God's purpose for us to be all that we can be to each other and the you
know the impact of that on the world I think is salutary but I don't think we
should do it for that reason we should do it as the fulfillment of our own
potential through our own alignment with devotion to God and therefore I give
thanks to all of you because you are God's gift to me yeah thank you God for
everyone here mm-hmm God spoils me he really spoils me thank you again so much
amen I'm spoiled rotten spoiled run terrible I'm spoiled run such a great
crowd