Yes.
First, I would like to say just thank
you for everything.
>> Yes, thank you.
>> And also, I'd like to
we've heard you all chant the word
several times uh during lecture. I've
never heard the entire group do it. And
I think as
>> do what? Chantm together
>> and as an expression of maybe a vote,
>> right? All for saying M. Raise your
hand.
All chickenhearted, raise your hand.
>> Maybe just experience the mis the
mystic.
>> Let's just uh do an M for Christmas.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh.
Wow.
>> Steal a picture as well.
>> See, he didn't cause the M, but without
him, the M wouldn't have happened.
I'm sorry about the phone and I
>> I'm sorry about the phone.
>> It was co and I'll I'll catch you later
for the $5.
>> Well, we had fun. If it wasn't for you,
we wouldn't had as much fun.
We didn't have anybody to poke fun at or
abuse or beat on.
>> I just wanted to say quickly,
thank you for saving my life and thank
you for putting your wings over me.
Thank you.
I know what it means.
>> I don't have a question. I just wanted
to be in your presence for a moment and
shake your hand.
>> It's my joy.
>> Thank you. I love your book so much.
>> Your joy is my joy.
He's in a near ecstasy state.
>> Hello, Dr.
Seems like
I have the conviction.
I have the willingness and the
intention.
And it seems like I've been hawanized.
>> You've been what?
>> Hawanized. He's hawk.
>> Hawinization. Yes. Oh, hanization.
>> There is no end to your DVDs, CDs,
books,
>> and there's more on the way.
>> Yes. And the question is,
there is an end to this. I mean, I know
to the this soul it doesn't seems I'm
perfectly all right with it and I'm
attracted to it. If I look back a few
years, I would say that it's an
addiction. A lot of people call me a
weirdo just like you mentioned, even my
grandkids,
and
I don't know what to answer. I just
accept them and let them be. So,
>> nobody will understand you.
Nobody really understands once you get
caught with the fire of spiritual drive.
Uh other people don't understand it and
you can try and explain it but they
don't really understand it
that you can walk away from everything.
>> Thank you very much. Instead of a
picture, would you allow myself to look
into divinity's eyes and recognize
myself? For
>> you can see yourself. Yes.
>> And I'd like to hold your hand.
>> There's nothing there except your own
self shining forth.
You see the infinite love.
Love without reservation.
the adoration of all that exists because
the divinity of its essence shines
forth.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> What are all these things I'm signing? I
don't understand.
>> Hello, teacher.
>> Hello.
Uh I actually came here to Sedona to
simply ask for a blessing.
>> Yes.
>> And then I learned that there was a
microphone.
>> Oh yes.
>> So I thought I should have a question.
And that is
um I found a particular attraction to
teachings about light and illumination.
I wondered if you could explain any more
about those
>> illumination. Mhm.
Well, we spent the whole day talking
about it.
>> Maybe maybe how how it was experienced
um here.
>> Any one of the yogas, any one of the
pathways or combinations thereof will
lead you to that state. Now, of course,
yoga is a Hindu kind of a name, but the
yogas exist in all religions.
uh adoration, selfless service,
meditation, contemplation.
They have different names in the
different religions, but they all amount
to the same. The basic yogas
in Christianity and Judaism, they're not
called yogas, but yogas are the generic
name, you know.
through service hat yoga I mean uh karma
yoga
raja yoga
meditation etc
through the various yogas and
disciplines
one transcends attractions and aversions
and stops projecting specialness on them
when it comes to the awareness that
specialness is something you project
onto a thing.
You say, "Well, aren't but what about
millions of dollars?" Well, you project
a specialness onto millions of dollars
that now with millions of dollars, you
are going to be happy and enlightened.
God knows what all except you wake up
with a headache the same as usual and
you break your ankle over going in the
closet. So, the millions don't do you
much good, do they?
>> No, they don't.
>> They're comforting as a, you know,
comforting thought.
You remember the story mother mama's
bank account?
No, not your generation. Mama's bank
account was a very famous story. The
whole family that grew up I think on the
lower east side, you know, and uh in
that era growing up in the lower east
side, the money was very very tight, you
know, and etc. And the kids would get
worried. We won't have enough money to
pay the electric bill this month. She
says, "Don't worry. Mama's bank account,
I'll cover it." Oh, then that would come
one emergency after another. Mother's
mama's bank account would handle it. All
the kids grew up. They got through all
the crises of life that mama's bank
account would handle it. Don't worry
about it. We'll get evicted. No, mama's
bank account will handle it. And after
mama died, they discovered she didn't
have any bank account.
It was a famous story, I think, in the
reader's digest. But anyway, mama's bank
account just the belief system that
there was some help someplace somehow
was all that people needed, you know.
>> Yeah. It wasn't the money. It was just
the belief that, you know, intercession
was possible, you know.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I think that was readers digest
some of
back in the 40s or
Yes. Um,
I want to thank you too because you have
role modeled for us uh the love between
a man and a woman and I have uh listened
to almost all your CDs and I rarely hear
you talk about relationships between men
and women except for a little bit. And
coming down from Seattle, I've gotten a
chance to witness you guys loving each
other. And I think the last time I was
here, there wasn't a dry eye. And a lot
of it had to do with the love we got to
see between you two. And today when you
did this, you know, about the
protections in the wings and you looked
at Susan and I can felt her pain in
knowing that she wants to love and
protect you and make sure you're okay.
So I just wanted to ask you to maybe
speak to the challenges
it is to to love somebody on the path
when they are a mystic. You know the um
because both of you are doing this for
us.
>> You're going to make us both cry and
they want us to talk.
>> That's why we have a whole box of
Kleenex. Okay.
There's like a m mutual adoration of the
divinity within each you see and like a
commitment see to go through with the
other person to go through with the
other person
and there's a fulfillment then of a
potentiality of fulfillment
of that potentiality. Yes.
The fact that there might be a wrinkle
in the sheet bothering her while she
sleeps bothers me and I have to remove
the wrinkle. Why is that? I don't know.
It's just
like uh mutual ducks. See,
sometimes she ducks me and sometimes I
duck her, you know.
Also, I think that
no matter what
um
kind of relationship there is between a
man and a woman, there has to be a
higher
power between
>> that's what we mean when we say the
relationship is both of us are are
vertical and not just horizontal.
The ordinary relationship is solar
plexus to solar plexus and they're
constantly tug tugging for power for
whose way is it going to who gets to go
to whose movie
who's going to get what who's going to
lose win lose sort of a win-lose
struggle power struggle when you're both
aligned with the same intention then
you're both parallel there is no
crossing each other I want whatever
makes her the happiest she wants
whatever makes me the happiest therefore
there's no
struggle
>> but after you that there's always that
alignment.
>> So I think that just
>> oh the basic belief out of which that
arises. Yes.
I think the relationships these days do
need that
extra.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, it's because it's revealing. It's
because of it reveals the essence of the
feminine to me.
essence of the feminine, the essence of
the maternal,
the essence of the of the caringness of
the feminine
to me, you know, I see the constant
caringness in all of its expressions.
Yeah.
But I think if both of you don't believe
in a higher being
a
relationship.
>> Yes. Otherwise you end up with the
struggle of the two egos. Who's going to
win? Who's going to lose? Who's right?
Who's got a resentment now? And
>> exactly,
>> you know.
>> All right. So you find your own
fulfillment by finding the fulfillment
of the relationship. You fulfill your
own potential.
>> I remember you saying that you were in
the snow and you breathed because you
for the love of your father.
>> Yes. And I think of you do and I think
you know one of you may not be here or
will leave you know and so I just wonder
how you integrate that yourselves
knowing that
>> we all have to go
>> you know but what we do here on earth
uh
as people
uh that gives other people life.
>> Yes it does. So
>> and and in the end you really have faith
in the infinite mercy of God.
>> See I hate the thought that I would be
leaving sooner and leaving you with the
grief of
>> or it could be the other way around is
in my life that's happened more often.
the woman died. And uh
so God in his infinite mercy provides
for the infinite mercy of God takes care
of that crisis. Takes care of that.
>> I think there's a little bit of um
of
knowing that
our work would long
past our lifetime.
>> So, I think there's a little bit of of
self-fillment or it doesn't really just
knowing that what that we both have
devoted
>> to each other and the teachings that
that'll go along that will be here long
after we're gone.
>> Yes, it's true. And maybe that's why we
have so many DVDs and CDs
is because we're making sure everybody
gets to hear it.
>> Yeah.
>> But when we present it, we present it in
different ways. And sometimes, you know,
we'll express it this way and certain
amount of people get it and then you
express it another way and a certain
amount of people get it. So, and I've
been to all the lectures
and I always I never fail to pick up
something that I didn't know or
something that it was explained or
something that the light went on and I
go, "Oh, yeah."
>> So,
yeah. I just want to honor you, Susan,
because uh you know, you talk about
calibration, but the love that you give
this man and so grateful that you
support him and that he's with us the
way you're doing it.
>> That proves that threats work.
And I want to honor you both too because
it's really something to see partners
like this. And thank you Anna just again
to say thank you for everything. you
have no idea through the years um what
your words have meant and you know it's
just phenomenal and the other thing I I
guess I need a mother's bank account
type of um story in a way but um you
know I'm um I teach and I teach fifth
graders and should we be telling them
about the or even thinking of the future
of water not being there or for me like
I'm I think for my
>> water not being there,
>> clean water, fresh water in the future.
I mean, for me, I I figure I'm probably
coming around many lifetimes still.
>> Well, you drink dirty water.
>> And so that's what I was wondering. If I
come around,
for those of us who are coming around
for the next couple hundred years or
whatever, will we be okay?
>> I'm serious.
>> Oh, I guarantee you 100 years from now,
you'll be fine.
two or three. I mean, really? Okay.
>> Yeah. You allow God to be the shepherd
of existence, the shepherd of the the
savior of the world.
>> Yeah.
>> You put in your own two cents worth, but
I think it serves more of the ego than
any reality.
>> Yeah.
>> Lake Michigan was here before I got
here. Lake Michigan will be here after
I've left.
>> Yeah, I know. I'm I'm wondering several
lifetimes
will it be there?
>> I don't know. I have a hard time getting
through till tomorrow.
>> I know. Okay. It's just I figure I'm
coming around to get
>> well the wellbeing.
>> And that is an anxiety.
>> Can't control.
>> Well, what you're really asking is the
well-beingness of mankind. Is the
well-beingness of mankind guaranteed
>> and for myself because I figure I'm
going to be back there.
It's really it's an anxiety for my
coming back over and over
into the world with what it could be
like. Change your life now. You don't
have to come back.
>> Not I don't know
>> the job of saving the world. I would
surrender to God myself.
>> Okay.
All right.
And people will be okay who are there?
>> What if they weren't?
Yeah. Well,
>> mankind might become extinct.
>> Okay. And then you'd just be a different
life form.
>> Well, you wouldn't be a human on this
planet. No.
>> Right. And that would be okay.
>> You might be something else in another.
>> That would be okay.
>> Yeah. But so we happy than a miserable
human being, would you?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Thank you.
Oh, yes.
>> I don't exactly know what this is for,
but it's frankincense and myrr.
>> Oh, good. Merry Christmas. And there's
incense. Frank.
>> Frankincense and myrr. I love
>> you.
>> You're welcome.
Thank you very much.
>> I love the smell of it.
>> You're welcome.
>> Have you got a place to put it?
>> Yeah, we'll burn it. We get
>> my question. Um I think in one of your
books you said that
all spiritual suffering is due to
resistance. And I was wondering if you
could
elaborate.
>> What?
>> Elaborate. Help me
>> elaborate.
>> Elaborate.
The last lady is unwilling to turn the
planet over to God and face the
possibility that Lake Michigan could be
contaminated. Human life not may not be
possible.
So resisting that she's experiencing
anxiety about the future of mankind and
all
and the answer is to surrender it to
God.
So resisting surrendering control. So
she wants to control the destiny of
mankind and this planet.
I would let God be God
rather than trying to control the
destiny of mankind and this planet and
the evolution of life in this universe.
You understand?
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thanks, Susan.
>> Oh, give me back my pen.
>> She's so mean. I mean, that's your
That's your mean sign.
>> All right, I'll I'll promise. I'll
promise.
>> I'll right. I'll promise. Oh, I forgot
about the microphone.
>> Oh, I forgot about the microphone.
>> Bad me.
I I too come bearing gifts, but I don't
expect you to look at them right now.
Oh,
>> they're from your some of your students
in Denver.
>> Oh, Denver. Yes.
>> And we send you great love.
>> Thank you so much.
>> And much gratitude.
And you were in Denver four years ago.
>> And I asked you the same question I'm
about to ask you.
>> I'm a little bit slow, I guess.
>> Am I supposed to sign this?
>> I think you did.
>> Oh, are you? So, this thing we call
work.
>> I'm I'm It seems to be the big dilemma
for me. I haven't worked in several
years and I need to go back to work and
it's just so unappealing. So, I was
hoping
I was hoping you could help me
recontextualize.
>> What do you like to do?
>> A thing
>> sit here with you. A thing is work when
you call it work.
>> True.
>> See, that's a teaching in Zen.
Nothing is anything except what you call
it. And what you call it is not what it
is. So,
what what you call work,
>> going out to a job and get earning a
paycheck and
>> Okay. What would you rather do?
>> Stay home and read and study. not work,
>> right?
>> Well, why don't you do that?
>> Well, I have been, but it's not going
over very well with my husband.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh. So, you would rather work
than go through his displeasure.
>> Correct.
>> What you really want is some kind of
work you enjoy.
>> Correct. I
>> mean, there's nothing in this world that
you enjoy.
>> That's a good I mean, of course, there
is. There is.
>> There's many. Do you like taking care of
sick pets? Little doggies with a broken
leg.
>> I love pets. Yes.
>> All right. Why don't you get a job as a
helper in uh
>> in the Humane Society?
Uh there's a program on every night on
channel some other
>> animal rescue
>> 184 I think. Yeah.
>> Animal Rescue Detroit. Animal Rescue
Phoenix.
>> You could be a volunteer in the Humane
Society. Start caring for suffering
beings.
>> You know that you get joy out of.
>> You see the animal coming in like this
covered with pain.
>> Don't you get a feeling of joy when you
relieve his pain and he looks at you.
Gee, thanks.
>> Yeah, but volunteering is not bringing a
paycheck.
>> Well, you've got to start somewhere. So,
>> all right. Well, after you're a
volunteer for a while, you then become
an experienced.
You become experienced in that
department, Humane Society department of
helping with animals. And from there,
it's easy to move into getting a job
with their veterinarian, getting a job
at the Humane Society. You move from
volunteer to employee by the excellence
of your work and your dedication.
I mean, I love animals. I could spend go
around the clock and not even hardly
sleep because a suffering animal bothers
me to such an extreme that I really need
to
>> relieve the animal of its suffering.
Every night part of my prayers is I pray
I pray for the relief of suffering of
the animal kingdom.
>> So out of your love for some aspect of
life, you can be you can enter in there
something that you care for and love.
young children without mothers or
animals that are suffering or
dogs that need training. I mean, there's
a million things you can do in this
world other than some humrum being a
cashier and a dinosaur. You know what
I'm saying,
>> right?
>> You're limiting the work area to such a
limited
mundane pedestrian boring level.
>> True.
Thank you.
I once had a job as an usher in a
theater. Well, I got to see all the
movies, didn't I?
I saw every movie as it appeared. Got to
see every single movie.
>> You know what I mean?
>> And then after the everybody left when
the evening was over, everybody left.
And as assistant manager, I had to clean
up and check out the cash with the
number of tickets and all. And I'd go up
and down the rows and uh people always
lose change out of their pockets during
the movies. I'd make $2.15. It'd be two
dimes here, a quarter there. When I was
a cab driver, I did the same thing. When
I check in the cab, I take the seat out
of the back seat. Sure enough, there was
always a couple of bucks and change.
Money would
So, I mean, you know, a job is fun if
you think it's fun.
>> Right. Right.
>> Being a bartender is fun. All the
stories you listen to, it's hysterical.
You know what I'm saying?
>> I'll keep some of those things in mind.
>> Yeah. Be a happy bartender.
>> Thank you. Thanks.
>> And the bartender at some I'd say that
is the saddest story I've ever heard.
And the same with the cab driver. You
hear all these stories. Everybody gets
in and laments this and that. And
>> so when they say your bartender is not
your psychiatrist, don't believe them.
Really? Really?
>> So you're you're looking at it in a very
negative way. Just fun jobs, being a cab
driver, being a bartender,
>> you know.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Being a greeter in a wh house, God knows
what.
>> I'm going to take you home.
I'm trying to fire up her imagination,
you know. She's just looking at it so
dullly. And
>> Dr. Hawkins, Susan, thank you.
>> She's looking at it so dullly and
uncreatively. I'm trying to show her
that it's a creative challenge, not a
job challenge.
>> Dr. Hawkins, I have two uh quick
questions. Uh would you be willing to
muscle test the instructions I was given
that were just muscle tested with uh the
uh in terms of instructions to use
frankincense? Can you just tell me if
what was what the result I got is true?
>> I can give you
what is your question. You want to know
Frank ladies uh who are wicas that live
in our neighborhood and they're sending
negative energies to our house. The
muscle test said I just wanted you to
validate if what we did the work I did
this week is true.
>> Oh, smudging.
>> Yeah, with frankincense.
>> I would tell you smudging always is
useful.
>> Understand? Is there any specific
instructions?
>> I think just smudging. We've tested
smudging before.
>> Could you use it with cedar? Have you
seen the Indian?
>> Sure. Sure. Sure. I'm just I'm just I
just want to know like I was I I don't
want to go into the detail of what the
muscle test said. I just want to know is
what we did true
>> because then I have the answer.
>> What what you're doing is uh is correct.
You're you're uh what he smudging is
helpful to his problem. Is this
>> specific instructions I was given. Okay.
Okay. And then the the last one is uh
>> um
money uh I'm I'm receiving money. I've
been retired 10 years from a source
under 200. Um, if I say I don't want it
anymore, which I'm prepared to do, uh,
my wife will take it. Um, is my karmatic
obligation over after I
>> I can't answer that. That's a personal
question. And the karma Oh, the karmas
of these two are so entwined.
>> Understand?
>> There's no way of answering it. Besides,
you could shift the whole balance by a
shift of attitude.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you very much.
>> And give her everything. Take it.
>> No, no, no, no, no. I'm not I'm gonna
I'm just going to let her know the
responsibility she may have if she takes
it. And that's and then I don't know
what else I can do other than leave uh
the house or something like that. So
thank you
>> very much Dr. Hopkins.
>> It sounds like a box of worms. I don't
know if I want to get involved.
>> Thank you.
>> Marital disputes are so complicated. The
intertwining karmas of the people
involved and then third parties and the
children of the parties and the mothers
and parents of the parties.
>> Sure. Sure. Sure. Sure.
>> The ramifications are quite complex. No,
that's why I don't want to get it to yes
or no.
>> No, no, no. It's understandable and I
just wanted to put the intention out
there. Thank you.
>> I got you.
>> Is this mine?
>> Yep.
>> Thank you. It's been a wonderful honor.
I I'd like to ask you if you would uh do
a blessing for my children. And um I
also have one question.
You want what?
>> A blessing for her children. She has a
question.
>> Well, which is it?
>> The question is when the uh
consciousness of the United States is
calibrated
where do you fit in the in the uh do are
you out of the equation?
>> I don't know. I don't
>> I've never asked it that way,
>> but as that is a curiosity. Yes,
>> that is curiosity. I don't know.
Uh the most recent calibration we got
for US was what 420
>> 420 or 425 somewhere like that.
>> All right, let's just do it for fun.
Right. We have permission to do this.
Currently the US is at 420 421.
It's at 420.
That's with with the speaker. Okay.
Without the speaker. I never asked that
one. It's over.
>> Ask permission.
>> Oh.
We have permission.
>> We can cancel it, right? That we can
cancel if we don't have to do this one.
>> We uh it's it's advisable to calibrate
to find out the answer. Is this
>> okay? Not advised.
>> Fine.
>> Yeah. But America is currently 420.
It'll vary a little bit.
>> Yeah,
>> it was 424. So, it's come down four
points, you know, something like that.
>> So, someone out there doing something
wrong.
>> We know who don't know who.
>> Yeah,
>> the bad guys.
>> The bad guys.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you for the blessing for my
children.
>> Ah, you're welcome. God bless.
>> We got plenty of time. We'll finish.
>> I want to finish them all and get them
all satisfied.
Oh, we just came to spend this moment
with you.
>> Yes.
>> So, Peter,
>> and I did bring you something, too.
>> It's for you.
And that's for you. I made scarves for
you. Very good for today.
>> Yes, that's very wo those for you.
>> They're woven. Oh, wow.
>> Oh, thank you so much.
>> I didn't bring one today.
>> No, no, no.
>> I got to wrap it all up now.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. Yes.
Thank you.
>> Is this loom weaving?
>> Don't pick on that. Okay.
>> Hello.
>> My question was on a previous lecture
you had talked about angels and how
sometimes they show up in human forms
and actually can help us out.
>> Yes. And I had always understood angels
before as more of an etheric sense. And
I was wondering if you could wait.
>> And I was wondering if you could
elaborate on that.
>> What's elaborate?
>> Well, just I mean, do angels live whole
lives as a human form or do they just
come in and out or
>> Well, angelic beings uh some have the
option to take uh physical form
for some particular purpose. Yes. Some
choose to serve in a in a in the
physicality resist.
>> They choose.
>> Okay.
And can I get a picture?
>> You can do things in a body that you
can't do out of body and vice versa.
>> That's a very interesting question.
>> Yes, it is a good question.
in physical form and
>> well I remember the angels that stopped
for me were on the road a number of
times when we asked were they an angels
and they said yes
>> Dr. Hawkins, I'm still very puzzled by
this question of ego and choice and
right action in the world. And I know in
um previous talks you've made a
distinction between the the Freudian ego
and the spiritual ego whereas the
Freudian ego a healthy one has a balance
between not being overpowered by the id
and primordial instincts and not so
overridden either by guilt or
repression. Yeah. keep a balance between
the id, the super ego and
>> okay
>> the world. Yeah.
>> So that's one kind of ego.
>> That's the fian ego.
>> And then the spiritual ego,
>> the psychological ego.
>> Okay.
>> Strong healthy ego can handle stress and
you know not collapse.
>> But then on the other hand you say that
it's really no eye or self making a
choice. Um and so I'm wondering
>> you're mixing realms. One's a
psychological real, the other spiritual.
>> Okay. So, I guess my question is um
would would a healthy ego be able to
distinguish between truth and falsehood?
Are you talking about
>> an eye that's so confused because it's
either repressed so much or it's coming
from a place of instinct that they can't
>> Well, the healthy differentiate the two
>> has a good re the capac reality testing
is one of the capacities of a healthy
ego. Reality testing. Okay.
reality testing is one of the capacities
of a healthy ego. Yes.
>> And then um beyond that though uh you
you're talking about us not really
making a choice. It kind of goes back to
the previous questioner and it's still
clear dimension that different the level
of consciousness
>> right but
>> psychology doesn't operate on the level
of consciousness it operates on levels
of psychological intention etc. But
yourself choose do you say that you
choose to come you know out of your
comfortable surroundings your home come
out and be exposed as Susan was saying
to uh other forces that are painful is
that
>> there aren't any painful other forces.
>> Okay. Well, she was referring to below
200 or those kinds of things affecting
you. Really, it the question is are you
choosing or not choosing? And I I I
think the the concept of you know us not
making a choice can often times
>> how is a choice made spiritually
speaking, okay, is made through
>> cascades of dominance.
Cascades of dominance.
Um
>> not sure what you mean by that.
>> Well, there can be I'm trying to think
of the author. Uh there's an author who
writes uh very interesting things on
choice and cost
attunement. Um
what's his name? Uh
uh well it has to do with the options of
choice. So you you you make a general
choice. This covers uh thousands of
topics and then within that topic there
is another general heading of topics and
then within that there's other general
headings. So let's say you you choose uh
you know forgiveness. Let's say you
choose lovingness and gentleness. Okay.
All right. Then then because you've
chosen that that's going to be a
dominant energy field. Then subsumed out
of that are specific examples that arise
in life and the conflicts that would
arise in the application of that. So
they're cascading levels of dominance.
Now each of these decisions you could
calibrate at different levels of power
the human will
and its power and depends on how evolved
the individual is. Uh so you have the
power of the will then you would have
the power of the uh choices the power of
the alter alternatives
desiring and the wantingness etc. So you
may have a very powerful decision
uh to let go all of want all let go of
wantingness
and as soon as you let go of wantingness
you're going to want something that's
guaranteed.
Who is the you or the I that's doing
this in your
>> Well, I'm using the generic you, but it
takes enlightenment to discover that
there isn't any you as you commonly
think of it. The totality that has
evolved over time that you refer to as
the self,
you know, is is a unity functionally
speaking and karmically speaking. Yes.
But it's a unity of a great complexity
because every choice you make shifts it
a little bit. All right? So I compare it
you know the consciousness a field of
the field of consciousness itself to a
powerful infinitely powerful magnetic
field and the human will is like an iron
filing within the within it. So choosing
this this way is yes and this way is no.
So every choice you make uh changes the
position of the iron filing in the
infinite magnetic field. To say yes to
this moves you a little higher in the
field. Well, now that you're higher in
the field, you're exposed to these
questions here which we would not have
been if you'd stayed here.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Once you become a physician,
for instance, you're you're presented
with decisions and choices that don't
occur unless you're a physician. Life
and death. and you know moral decisions
and options etc. So each choice you make
now puts you into a different
category of being and the choices and
decisions there are different
>> right and how is one to sort of see
which is sort of right action versus
>> oh through through spiritual maturity
and evolution of consciousness. So there
is something within ourselves a
conscience or a intuition that sees the
difference or certainly not not just the
calibration test of
>> No calibration is just a useful
measurement.
>> Okay. So
>> no within yourself is the will. It's the
will that determines karmic outcome.
You you can will in a direction and have
it go in an opposite direction against
your will. Mhm.
>> Just because you decide this way doesn't
mean it'll be that way.
>> However, you did make that choice. So
that moves your whole field over to
here, you know,
>> for another choice.
>> Yes. So this choice here would not have
occurred
>> had you not made this choice here. So as
you see these are each one of these
choices affects an attractor field of op
options. Each of the attractor fields
are of relatively different power power.
So the interaction of these u attractor
fields which are energy fields in
nonlinear dynamics
you can have a dominant overall field
within which there are lesser fields
within which there are lesser fields.
See
>> I I I do see I'm just kind of curious
how does one though differentiate how
does one find in a state of mind or
attention or awareness or what is it
that one needs or can generate to um I
want to say make the right choice but to
make that
>> you're trying to make specific that
which is not specific that because of a
generality towards being kindness let's
say towards animals
>> okay
>> you would have decisions to make
>> right
>> this animal is sick and incurable. Shall
we put it to sleep or not put it to
sleep?
>> Okay.
>> Which is better? Yeah. Right. Like that.
Okay. I see that one.
>> So each of those it comes up then.
>> Yeah.
>> Should we at this point alleviate the
suffering or try to keep it going? So
each choice you see arises out of the
qualities that you have become yourself
as a human being.
I was following a car one day and down
the highway uh and uh the car actually
went up on two wheels in its attempt to
run over an animal. There was an animal
running in front of it, I forget, a
squirrel or cat or whatever it was.
>> And and this guy was so intent on
killing this animal, he actually went up
on two wheels trying to get over to the
side of the road to kill this animal.
>> Yeah.
>> See?
Well, thank you. Helps. Would you have
permission to take a picture?
>> Yes. So,
>> so
>> the karma of that person, you know, just
that intention, whether he killed it or
not, I don't remember, but the intention
I think I don't think he did kill it. I
think but he I think I remember how it
went now. It was so damn negative I
forgot it. He ran over the the animal
and broke its neck. And the animal was
lying by the side of the road in a in
terrors of agony with a broken neck,
curable.
>> And I had then to make the decision
whether to bring its life to an end or
relieve its suffering or not.
>> And you were making that that
>> I had to make the decision because I saw
the squirrel or the rabbit, I forget
which it was, with a broken neck laying
there. Obviously irreparable damage.
But but often times we can get the
impression that it wouldn't have
mattered what choice you make from what
you say. I mean this is where I'm
confused like it doesn't matter what
choice you make because it's not really
you choosing anything. This is kind of
>> but on the other hand it makes all the
difference in the world.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> Simultaneously
>> at the same time. Okay. I'll leave it at
that. Thank you.
>> Ambiguity spiritual work you learn to
tolerate ambiguity.
It both means everything and
simultaneously means nothing.
The world did not change.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Hi. Nice to meet you.
Um, today you called the physical world.
>> What? Today you call the physical world
an illusion and a fairground
and I understand it to be somewhere
where we have experiences
maybe to learn.
>> I'm not understanding her.
>> She said today you call the physical
world
>> an illusion.
>> Yeah. No, I don't call it an illusion
though.
>> Okay. I misunderstand
>> how you perceive it. How you perceive it
>> is illusory but its existence is not
illusory. how you perceive it as kind or
cruel or
>> okay
>> a disaster or a blessing
>> or somewhere to experience
>> how you perceive it is is is subjective
you know
>> my question is what's the point of our
physical reality and our physical bodies
if we all come from if we're all one
we're all the name.
>> Those are different levels of
abstraction. You're mixing levels.
>> Okay.
>> The oneness is that of context,
not of physicality.
The one emerging as the many.
The oneness of life emerges then through
multiple expressions.
The whole animal kingdom, the vegetable
kingdom,
although they're multiple in their
physicality, they are one in the source
of life itself. The source of life is
one in all living things. Yes. And yet
the form form
is one of multiplicity, diversity.
>> So what's the point of the physical?
Doesn't have to have a point. What do
you need a point for?
>> To make meaning.
>> What?
>> To have meaning.
>> Meaning.
>> Don't give it any meaning. Had no
meaning.
>> Okay.
>> Just is. The world is. That's good
enough.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> The book I'm just finishing gives you an
option of about 35 different meanings
that you can project onto the world.
>> Thanks.
The world is a mad house. The world is a
recuperation
ward.
The world is a joke. The world is a
tragedy.
The world is a perplexity.
The purpose of the world is salvation.
The world is purgatorial.
The world is a comedy. The world is a
sadness.
What you make of the world is your own
projection.
>> It's all of those things and none of
them.
>> Thank you.
Hello. Um, I gave up uh giving to
charity because I heard you say the
world is perfect as it is. And
yet when I pass by the homeless people
that I encounter frequently, um, I just
pass them by, I feel like there's a
stone here in my chest. So, I don't know
what that is. Maybe I'm just not at the
level where I see the world
um, perfectly.
Well, that's perception.
>> You don't have to materialist
or other
donate food.
>> But she's asking about meaning though.
Meaning
>> I understand she gave up giving. I don't
at all.
>> Oh, you can give up giving.
You can't.
>> Oh,
>> don't they have poor houses?
Won't they have workhouses for the poor?
>> Get money from a hardworking man.
Mr. Scrooge. Yes.
>> So, just give in other ways then.
carrying this, you know,
>> volunteer at the hospital,
>> you know,
go in and at the children's hospital,
volunteer to read stories. There's lots
of things to do,
>> okay?
>> You know, it might require time, but it
doesn't necessarily require anything
else.
write a check.
>> Okay, sounds good.
>> Can I get a picture?
>> Laugh at comedian's jokes.
>> Well, those are all loving things you
can do.
Thank you.
>> Yes.
It's been a year since I've sat here
that I've been able to be in this place
and I just wanted to come and present
myself to you and give great thanks for
what you have offered. I've been
fortunate also to be able to watch your
videos and listen to your CDs throughout
the year. So, um, being far away doesn't
mean I'm far away in spirit. And
um
I guess uh what I've I don't really have
a question, but what I've come to is um
it is only a matter of letting thy will
be done.
And um
to do that in each moment
uh I'm not always very good at. I have
my
>> Well, don't make it a serial
>> a serial series of of decisions.
>> You make a blanket decision
without reservations.
And when you do that, you make decision
about
how much variation you will allow
yourself
and then you can live live with that
decision. You only need to make one
decision.
Let's say you make a decision to be as
loving towards all of life and all of
its expressions as you can. That's a
blanket decision. Now you don't have to
make a lot of little decisions.
>> Just one.
>> Thank you.
Thank you.
>> Make one blanket one that covers them
all.
>> Covers them all. Okay. Thank you,
doctor.
Um, Dr. Hawkins, I was um hoping you
could say a few words about your
relationship with Bill Wilson.
I knew Bill for years
and u worked with him.
We went on speaking together a couple
times.
We worked on u evolving treatments for
the recovery of alcoholics.
The clinic I had in Manass, Long Island,
uh treated great many of maybe the
majority of alcoholics
on Long Island. And uh we specialized in
difficult cases that weren't able to
recover or get better.
And uh we had a certain routine that we
did.
Uh many of them had functional
hypoglycemia. They stop drinking and
then they go in for hot fud Sundays and
on Sunday they're very very depressed.
Say the hell with it and go get drunk.
So sugar-free diets and high doses of
vitamin B3
they recovered by the hundreds. Frankly,
the they had been hopeless. Functional
hypoglycemia being probably the worst
one because you you your blood sugar
shoots way too high. You know, you used
to get drunk every Saturday night. Now
Saturday night you have a hot fud
Sunday. So your blood sugar drops up
high like this then it skyrockets down.
So it's really a problem of
hyperinsulinism.
This input of glucose then precipitates
uh a release of insulin. The insulin
brings the blood sugar down rapidly. It
doesn't come down slowly and stop at 110
or something. It skyrockets
gets down and will get down to 70 or 60
and then you start shaking.
Okay. Have a hot fight Sunday for
breakfast and see how you feel. About
1:00 in the afternoon, you'll notice
your hands are shaking. Your emotions
are brittle. You're willing to kill
yourself, commit suicide, throw the
radio out the window,
become irrational. Some people become
violent. We have many patients who were
arrested over and over for unsolicited
violence.
And all they all they had to do is stop
eating sugar and sweets.
So when people call for an appointment,
I say, "What's your problem?" I get
angry. I'll get depressed. I say, "Well,
I want you to stop eating sugar and
sweets until I see you." And about half
the time by and when I saw him for the
first appointment, they would say, "You
know what? It's gone already."
The most misdiagnosis
also poo pooed by conventional doctors.
I remember a guy weighed 400 pounds.
He had sugar, a voracious appetite for
sugar like you never saw. He would sit
down at a table and he would be like,
his eyes were like riveted. Anything
with sugar in it. And uh I told him, I
forget what his prom was, being drunk, I
think. Anyway, so I told him, you got to
stop sugar and sweets. Well, he
recovered. Yes, he recovered. That's
right. He recovered and he was perfectly
fine. And uh then he went to see a lady
who was president of the uh some medical
society and alcoholism and she said,
"Oh, hi guys. See me a poo poo poo." She
said, "Poo poo poo." Of course, that's
what he was waiting for at 400 lb. He
went right back into the sugar and
sweets and he was dead within months.
Got drunk again. Dead.
So her disbelief cost him his life.
When your blood sugar drops, you become
irrational. So many of these people you
see commit senseless crimes. They're
always looking for a motive. There isn't
any motive.
They don't have any motive.
That which the Freud call, you know,
Freud called the id, in the bottom of
the id is all the negativity that's
possible. All you got to do is bring
down a person's blood sugar far enough
and the average person will become
psychotic, violent,
shoot their schoolmates. Crazy as all
get out.
So yes, we worked on things like that.
And uh so I got to love Bill you know
and uh he was also into exploration of
various things you know and when he died
I was one of the doctors that came in to
see what we could do to increase
oxygenation in his brain and certain
things that were good for it weren't
legal in the US so we bootleg them. So I
would
I would bootleg it in order to get it to
Bill trying to increase the oxygen
consumption in the brain cells you know
and Bill would say you know Bill died
slowly he would say he laughs off into
dream you know semi comeoma comeos
states and then he would come out of it
and he would say my father's house had
many mansions
He got to visit a number.
Funny thing, we reconfirmed that with
consciousness calibration
that there are multiple regions in in
heavens, even not just one heaven. It's
the same for everybody. On the contrary,
there are like neighborhoods of heaven.
So if you're a strict Mormon, you go to
Mormon heaven. If you're a strict
Presbyterian, you can go to Presbyterian
heaven. Strict Catholic, you can go to
Catholic heaven. So there's different
dimensions for the spirits that belong
to these various belief systems. So Bill
was right. And in other words, we
confirmed that there are yes various
regions.
So some religions claim that only
through them can you get to heaven.
That's true. Only through by practicing
what they teach can you get to their
heaven.
But if you don't want to go to their
heaven, you can believe anything you
want. There's a lot of, you know, more
sophisticated heavens.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. Bill was unforgettable.
>> Huh?
>> Oh. Oh, I'm always doing something,
aren't I?
>> It's not me. It's the body does that. I
have nothing to do with it. Yes.
>> I want to thank you both. Yeah.
>> And all my questions were answered on
the way up here. They all came to me.
Thank you very much. I just wanted to be
here. Thank you personally again.
>> Yes. Thank you, Doc. My mentor.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. And thank you for like getting us
to a Hawkins group. We love it. They're
wonderful people. Oh,
>> thank you.
Oh my goodness.
>> I started these already.
>> Oh, these are
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes.
>> Uh, I wanted to thank you so very much
for your teachings.
um not only your teachings but your
calibrations allow us all to explore
other other teachings as well. Ramano
Maharshi and others for many years I've
been um a spiritual student but kind of
directionless going from one spiritual
bestseller to the next.
>> Yeah. Well, that's a normal phase
investigative phase. So uh so with your
books uh truth versus falsehood and
other books where you've calibrated
these things you've really helped us out
a lot and uh I can see huge changes in
in my life
>> and I want beneficial yes
>> um and we came up uh to just ask for a
blessing and to thank you.
>> Yes.
Okay.
>> Thank you so very much.
>> Thank you.
>> God bless you.
>> Thanks.
>> I love you. Thank you, Susan.
>> Thank you.
Yes.
>> Hi, Doc. Hi, Susan.
>> I'm all nervous, but I felt compelled
today. Just
>> You're not nervous enough. Please be
more nervous.
>> I've just been feeling compelled to come
up here to thank both of you again for
the example that you set for us in
service to others.
And I just felt like I needed to look in
your eyes.
>> I'm glad you enjoyed it.
>> This is a great lecture.
>> I'm glad it turned into it was of
service to you, you know.
>> Thanks, doctor.
>> Wow. Where are these coming from? I
can't believe this.
>> My god, they're coming out of the
woodwork
>> there.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. I was just told I
couldn't give you a hug and that wasn't
what I wanted to do.
>> Oh,
>> I wanted to give you my heart.
>> Oh. Oh, well that's right.
>> It's easy to carry. It's joyous and
happy.
>> And I would like to um thank you
for
being you.
>> Uhoh. Uhoh.
>> And
>> there wasn't anything else I could do
about it, was there? I know.
And
>> it's stuck with who being who you are.
Yeah.
>> Yes. So over this past couple of years.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like I was offered every test
possible from physical to letting go of
everything.
And
what I would do, particularly one point
where the pain was so excruciating
and I'm looking down at my body
and it was like I didn't want to be
caught into
into the pain and the cry of the body,
but I wanted to be able to comfort it
and thank it. If it was my time to
leave, thank it and
surrender.
>> And you're still here.
>> And I'm still here. That's so that's
this matter of surrendering.
Surrendering the life. It's not my life.
The life.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Surrendering the future. Surrendering
the will. Mhm.
>> Surrendering the capacities.
>> Mhm.
>> And
then you find out what's really there.
>> And I thank you.
>> That is true.
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> The Irish person is afraid that what
they'll find is nothingness. So they
come they stand back from the fear of
nothingness. Yes. And when I was just a
very small girl and two little girls
friends, we found this brown paper bag
when we were walking in the field. And
we opened it and there were three little
kittens that were just deteriorating but
still life.
>> Oh. And I sent my two friends on
and I took a rock
and I did what?
>> You put them to sleep.
>> Mhm.
>> They were too far gone.
So you you know you did it out of mercy.
But don't forget their their life energy
quickly finds another rebirth,
>> which Yes. It was it was
>> quickly finds a rebirth. But the guilt
has stuck with you all this lifetime.
>> Now forgive yourself because all you did
is release it from that prison that it
can find a better home.
>> Yep. Instead of a suffering kitty, you
know, it became a happy, healthy kitty.
>> That's right. Three.
>> One little spirit.
>> Yes.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you.
>> The angers we fe feel over animals, you
know,
because we see them as life, you know,
>> we love them. Yes.
>> Hi. Hi, Susan. I was here about two and
a half between two and a half and three
years ago. That was my first time. This
is second. And uh you helped me to
transition from paddling my own canoe to
flowing with the Dao.
>> And uh I thank you for that. That was
terrific.
>> Um, today is a new transition into
another phase because as we speak, my
daughter is moving out
and my husband's helping her. And you
know, my whole a lot of my karmic focus
has been on my daughter.
>> How old is she now?
>> 25.
>> Oh, well,
>> I'm finished.
So my question is, how does one without
the gun in the head surrender the
husband and the daughter to allow the
enlightened state?
>> Oh, I don't mind that. I She's been away
at university.
>> Yeah.
>> My husband is based in Luxembourg. So,
um, I'm back and forth. I have six
months alone. I I prefer nature and
solitude and I'm very content with that.
But I I just feel a sense of interest. I
have to admit some desire to see her
life unfold or my husband retire
eventually and so on. There there's some
desire attachment there, you know, not
huge but it's there.
>> Desire to change it or just witness it
>> just to uh be there for them and see the
joy of it. But um
>> you say people often stay for because of
love. But on the other hand uh I mean it
may be lifetimes away but we all have to
do our part in surrendering all we can
to be available to allow uh the
enlightened state. So you know I mean
the only other attachment I can think of
is chocolate and uh and well the
Mexicans call it fruit food of the gods.
So, I figure we don't have to touch that
one.
H, no, that was just a joke.
No, it's really just um you know I can
sort of release the beauty of the planet
and home and friends and so on, but when
it comes to husband and daughter being
the closest connections,
I don't even need to see them for 10
years. But it's just the finality of
releasing them and not being there for
them in their life is something I I
would be interested in.
>> I don't know what you mean by being
there for them. You mean physically?
>> I would like to be in a conscious a
humanly conscious state to see her
marriage and and her have a child. But
if it's between her and God, you know, I
let her go. But on a human level, it
would be interesting to know how more
easily to say
I won't necessarily be here for you.
>> I don't understand the question.
>> Well,
>> she's parting from her physically. She
acts like she's dying or something.
>> No, no. It's just I understand that if
you go into another state, you may not
be available
for the people in your life.
>> Oh, then they're on their own.
>> Yes.
>> They only got God to look after them.
>> Exactly.
>> Oh, they'll have to struggle.
>> You believe in angels? Yes.
>> Well, then you'll become an angel and
you still see.
>> Well, I I just wondered if there was
another
way of transcending
um you know
>> a fondness for
>> How can you let them go without letting
them go? Huh?
>> Well, you feel like you should be there
for them, you know.
>> Well, you could just let them go without
letting them go. How's that?
>> Yeah.
Okay. Well, I'm not sure that I
understand.
>> Surrendering people to God means to
surrender wanting to control them.
>> Oh, well, that's or long gone. Then
>> to control your experience of them.
That's what you're saying. You want to
control your experience of them.
>> I would like to be consciously aware of
their life and be there for them. I
haven't let that one go.
>> You know,
>> do they want you to be there for them?
>> Yes, they do.
>> Well, then just be there for them.
What's the problem?
>> Well, if you're in an if you are to
allow an enlightened state in some
lifetime and we're to work on that now,
I may not be there for them in in a
conscious state.
>> That means you'd have to surrender them
to God.
>> Yes. So, it's you're wanting to control
it, right? Is that
>> Well, I I I can't.
>> Yeah, you're wanting to control it. What
do you say no for?
>> You just got through saying you want to
control your relationship with them and
how you experience your relationship
with it. It's all about control.
>> It's all about
>> fondness. Wanting to
>> Oh, you can call it fondness. You can
call it service. You can call anything
you want. It's all control.
>> So, I should just let go of them.
>> If you're going to let go of it, then
let go of it. But you want to let go of
it. But hang on.
How can I let go and hang out?
>> I don't want to do both. I want to let
go, but I I understand that I'm holding
on.
>> Do that.
>> Okay. Well, I've already told them about
it, but
>> I found it's interesting that the day
she moves out and is my transition day
and I find myself here.
>> Oh,
>> you know, so
>> it's advice for the next step, you know.
>> All right. So,
>> see what you want to do is let go and
and keep her hooked with your little
finger with your tootsie.
>> No.
>> Yes.
>> Do one or the other.
>> Be honest with yourself.
>> You want to let them go so you can feel
good that you let them go, but you
really want to keep your little tootsie
hanging on there.
>> I I would
>> You want to listen in on her phone
conversations. Don't you want to know
what's going on?
>> Oh, no. No, no. She's They're both very
independent. I see my husband six months
of the year. She's away at university
usually. Uh I'm quite content on my
life.
>> You got an ideal life.
>> I know I do.
>> I know.
I
>> You got to pull it out of her. You know
that my life is really okay the way it
is. Okay.
>> But I have to say to God,
>> but don't give me any buts.
>> To let go means that I may not be there
for the rest of her life.
>> That's true. Oh, now you're getting what
let go means. Yes.
>> Yeah. Not be there for wedding child
anything.
>> Thank you.
>> You got it.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> You got to beat her fingers loose.
>> She's fun. Yeah, she's fun.
>> She's a fun lady.
>> Yeah. Hi.
>> Hi, Dr. Huggin. Hi, Susan.
>> Hi. Um, got a lot of fear going on right
now.
Um,
I'm going to be honest. I first when I
first came here, I first came up to to
talk to you and I had a question, but
um, what was going through my mind at
the time was that I was I was the second
Christ and all this stuff. And I had
this experience after reading your book.
And um
the second time I I after I took
suggestions that you had
uh I wanted to come up and thank you and
I didn't really get a chance to do that.
So that's what I'm here to do this time
and um I thank you.
>> You're welcome.
I thank you for your thanking me.
Thank you.
Is that yours? Yes. Yep.
Yeah, that is his. Yes.
>> Those are incredible, aren't they?
>> Hi.
>> Hi there.
This is not for you.
Um,
I'm not sure why I'm up here,
but um, maybe
to talk to you about being wishy-washy.
>> I like him already.
>> I'm not. You're going to take a firm
stand against being wishyw.
>> I would do that. Take a firm stand
against being wishywashy.
>> But a stance against something
>> Yeah.
>> isn't a strong stance. So the stronger
stance would be to be for
>> being not wishy.
No, you can cancel a thing by choosing
to be it, too. You know, choose to be
wishy-washy. You're not wishy-washy
enough.
>> Okay, I'll do that.
>> All right.
>> Apologize all the time for everything.
>> Sorry. Okay.
>> I do. All right.
>> You're sorry. You took up my time now,
aren't you? I am. Yeah. Good.
Yep. Yeah.
>> Don't be wishy-washy about being
wishy-washy. Be strongly wishy-washy.
>> I'm not being wishy-washy enough.
>> Right.
>> All right.
Merry Christmas. Blessings. Thank you.
>> He's fun. He's fun. He's fun.
>> That was cute. You could have fun with
him forever.
>> I know.
>> Yeah.
>> Dr. Hawkins and Susan, I want to thank
you both for modeling this mutual
admiration society. I hope my partner
hears that. Anyway,
what what happened this morning when you
came down the aisle, you said you liked
my hat, so it be really became important
to me. And you called it a fisherman's
hat and all. So, I'd like your blessings
on my hat.
>> Oh, God bless your hat. It is a
wonderful hat.
>> Thanks a lot.
>> This one just like it.
>> You do? Oh yes.
>> Yes. The Greek fish.
>> It is like Zor. I think Zora used to
wear this.
>> He wears one just like
>> Yeah. Mine's from Greece. Yep.
>> Mine too.
>> Yep.
>> That's the best kind.
>> Yes.
If anybody needs one, it's mired a hat
on and you're all in Louisiana.
>> Thanks a lot.
>> Yeah, they're wonderful hat.
>> Oh, forgot about the
>> Oh, yes.
>> Go get your hat.
>> No, no, no. I don't know where it is
right now.
>> Hello, Dr. Hopkins.
>> Oh, it's an honor and a pleasure. Um,
actually had a question about an
organization. It's um it's called WWASP,
the Worldwide Association of Specialty
Programs. They run schools throughout uh
different countries. And I was wondering
if you could calibrate the organization
for me.
>> Uh I don't know. Let's see. We have
permission to calibrate this
organization. Resist. WWP.
>> Yes.
>> Is over 200 resistant.
Over 200.
>> Thank you very much.
>> That's all that's important. Is it over
or under?
>> All right. That's That's the only
question I had.
>> Well intentioned. That means it's well
intentioned there.
>> Yes.
>> The view of service. Wellented.
>> All right.
>> We have this little
>> Thank you.
>> Yep.
>> Hello.
Um let's see how do I ask this question.
Um
I have two
uh aspirations alongside my life. One is
deeply spiritual which I'm not sure if
I'm very diligent in pursuing but I try
to and the other one is with my career
which in one sense is also deeply
spiritual for me. And I'm not
perfectly understanding it right now.
But what I want to know is any advice to
um make an alignment. Now my practice is
in uh you know architecture and design.
So it's uh very um secular and uh u
material literally material and it's
this dedication to
uh trying to manifest beauty
is almost um seems similar to me as my
spiritual dedication
but uh I would uh love some advice you
know how does one align one's
spirituality
with one's um career.
>> Well, because your overall intention
about your life colors everything you
do, including vocation. You're making
vocation sort of a separate department.
You know, you want to be of service to
the world, uh create efficiency, also
beauty, uh creativity.
So, you combine them all under the same
umbrella. You know, they're not
divergent gains.
Yeah,
>> I always love architecture and uh I love
uh design
and I've done a bit of it myself, you
know.
I think it fits in with trying to create
ambiance, beauty,
>> refinement.
I think architecture is very
fascinating.
Yeah, I do too.
>> Um, so in terms of of um actually uh the
work is uh full of complexity and uh
strife sometimes. Um and um sometimes I
wonder I should just be meditating more
in my life rather than forcing projects
through. Um but I guess one in its own
good time, you know. Everything in its
own good time.
>> Okay, that answers my question.
>> You don't want to retire in your 20s,
you know.
>> You're uh
>> a time for time for everything. A time
for everything, you know.
>> Yeah.
>> So, right now you're into career
building is not in conflict with
spirituality unless you compartmentalize
it mentally that way.
I try not to or at least readings and
your practice reminds me um actually
brings a spark of it into my everyday
life. So I deeply thank you for that.
>> Oh yes
>> both all of you. Yes. Thank you.
Thanks.
trying to respect the time.
There's more people than I thought.
>> Um, since we're almost out of time, I
just wanted to say thank you, Dr.
Hawkins, and ask if I could have a
picture.
>> There we are.
>> Thank you. Hi, Susan. How are you? Thank
you.
Hi, Dr. Hawk.
>> Yes.
>> I love you.
>> This is It was a real um I've been
praying for weeks to come up here.
>> Yes. and be able to get through it
without coming to pieces because when I
think of you in the presence of what you
are, who you are,
>> I um cry a lot these days.
>> And
I was uh my question was going to be
about baptism.
Um you know, kind of what the
uh what the
what it's all about, what it's for.
>> Baptism.
>> Yes. because of
>> Catholic like
>> yeah because my mother was a devout
Catholic and um
>> but I've never had a a draw to that or
anything but I have a draw a strong
strong desire for enlightenment and
truth and so I just what what I want to
do is I want to take the vow to thee oh
Lord I dedicate my life and will you
bless me for that
>> you want to dedicate your life to to the
Lord.
>> There there's no higher calling than to
be dedicate your life to being ser to
the service of the Lord, you know.
>> Thank you.
So I, you know, I had that thing around
baptism. You have to be baptized in
order to have that, you know,
acceptance or or whatever it is. But
>> well, you go get baptized, too. I mean,
>> I give you a couple of bucks. You go get
baptized. You just find some holy water
and there you go.
>> Well, your blessing is
>> Okay.
>> All I need.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you. Thank you. I love you.
>> Whoops.
>> Many people are baptized and you're
still
>> I I know that. That was part of my
>> So, you live here locally?
>> You live here locally?
>> No, I don't. I mean, I live in Idaho.
>> Oh, Idaho. That's not local. Yes. Okay.
I was going to try and arrange for a
friend of mine to baptize you, but no,
we got it.
>> But
I feel like
>> Well, I didn't think that it did. I just
know that my mother had my sister
baptized and dad didn't want the rest of
us baptized.
>> Oh, I get you. I get you.
>> And then I have this I had this feeling
was well, you know,
>> it has to do with apostolic succession.
So,
>> if it makes you happy, why don't you go
get baptized? You know, it' be fun.
>> Yeah.
>> Why make it a big issue? You know,
>> is Well, it was just like who do I go to
to have
>> Well, you go to the nearest for any like
church.
>> You go to the nearest uh church that
appeals to you and tell the minister you
never been baptized.
>> Okay.
>> Slip my fin and he'll baptize you.
>> I love your humor. I love your humor. I
love humor. Thank you. Thank you.
>> You really feel that that that was
something that you
>> you should take care of it. Yeah.
>> Otherwise, on your deathbed, you're
going to say, "Oh my god, I didn't get
baptized."
>> No, I didn't really feel myself that I
needed to have that done. I just I just
kind of felt that you have that kind of
convoluted sense of, you know,
>> the havetos and the shoulds and all that
sort of stuff through religious
background. Yeah. Type of stuff.
>> Yeah. But I just felt like I have a
dedication to truth and to God and that
would be enough.
>> Yeah. Well, getting baptized would just
be a a vindication of it, you know, an
affirmation of it. Another way to affirm
it, you see.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Great.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you. Thank you. All right. Merry
Christmas.
>> Merry Christmas.
Um, I
also just come to say thank you for
teaching and to ask you for your
blessing.
>> God bless you.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Are we waiting for someone?
Are we ready?
>> Yes.
>> I'll make it very quick. I wanted to
thank you so much for your dedication in
your work. It's given me inspiration to
do some work of my own. And I believe
that what I've learned through you has
helped my clients. I'm a mental health
counselor and because
>> you know that
>> I've learned I've learned some things
through you that have helped me and I
feel like that helps my clients as well
and I wanted to thank you.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I very much appreciate what you both do.
>> It radiates out. It's contagious.
>> Thank you. God bless. Thank you. Thank
you, Susan. Thank you very much.
Yes.
>> Namaste.
>> Thank you both. That's all I wanted to
say is thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> And a picture with my brother for his
birthday.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
Bless you.
>> Okay, we'll try and take um if it gets
too close to 5:30, we're going to have
to cut off.
>> I thought there was a dog barking.
>> Yes.
>> Hello, father.
>> Yeah. I was wondering if you could um
give me the teaching of how you would
have me surrender when positionalities
come up, when desires come up, when
belief systems come up to awareness, how
you would actually have me surrender.
>> Do you ask yourself, would you be
willing to turn over trying to control
this to God?
>> Yeah, that's how you do it.
>> God to make the decision about the
outcome.
>> Just ask God. That's simple. It's very
simple. It's only a matter of
willingness.
So, it's really a matter of the will.
The will is extremely powerful.
So, when you're you make a decision via
your will to surrender a thing to God,
that's a very that's very powerful, much
more powerful than an intellectual
decision.
Thank you. You bet.
Do you want to do that now?
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I just want to take those never
have asked Dr. a question at first to
come forward.
>> I thought we had we just have one more
question.
>> Um I'd like to know if you would muscle
test something from me.
>> What if muscle test?
>> Uh if you
>> maybe or maybe not.
>> Okay.
>> Um uh I inherited some property and I'd
like to know if I should sell it.
>> I can't really use it for that. Okay.
You know,
>> it's it's a personal
>> Yeah. What you do is you would ask and
then would it serve the highest good to
retain it or not retain it.
>> Okay.
>> My guess would be it doesn't make any
difference because your intention is
going to dominate the decision anyway.
>> Okay.
>> I don't think we can ask it. It's too
personal. It's not advisable to ask it.
It's not advisable.
>> Okay. It's just a decision because
you'll have the karmic consequences. If
I tell you what I think you ought to do,
then you know it's a different deal.
>> So, so
>> you have to look at your motivation is
>> okay.
>> Motivation is
>> If you don't want to be bothered with
the responsibility or that you want to
play the real estate market it all that
yeah I want to bring the highest motive
to it. That's why. Okay. So, I'll I'll
work on that. I'll make it a matter of
prayer. Um, the other thing I wanted to
ask you is if St. Bernard calibrated at
650 at the end of his life. You
calibrated St. Bernard at 650. And I'd
like to know if he
>> Why do you ask that?
>> Because of what I've studied about him.
He he um
>> he became very involved in church
politics and he
he seemed to have attacked scholars and
and it seemed that some of the things
that he did were um unscrupulous and
>> oh unscrupulous
>> so I I wanted his name
>> St. Bernard
>> and so I wanted to know if he perhaps
dropped at the end of his life.
>> Uh we have permission to ask questions
about St. Bernard.
>> We don't have
There might have been motives that we
don't know about
>> took place at time or political moves.
You know, there's a lot of things
involved in that as to why he took those
stances.
>> It would take research is probably why.
>> Yeah, it's a research question.
>> I'm writing about him. So, I have I'm
trying to try.
>> Does your life depend on how he ended up
as life and why?
>> Well, the way I'm writing about him will
>> Oh, you're writing about him. That's a
different story. And I very much want to
write fairly about him and and everybody
that writes about him is polarized. Some
people think they can't say a bad word
about him and other people hate him. So
I'm trying
>> Oh, well, don't take any position.
>> Well, I don't know how to write about
him.
>> Well, maybe you shouldn't be writing
about something if you don't know enough
to write about it.
>> Well, I didn't think he calibrated at
650. I never dreamed that he calibrated
that high.
>> Why do they call him a saint?
>> Well, I don't know. Is everybody who's
called a saint? I didn't know. I really
didn't.
>> Saint is 570 and up.
>> Does the church ever make mistakes about
saints? I mean, are they ever
>> You have questions about his spiritual
integrity? Correct.
>> Yes, I do.
>> All right. The problem is your questions
about his spiritual integrity.
That's the problem.
>> You mean the problem is mine?
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
Do
>> you want to judge him or what do you
want to know for?
Well, because I'm writing about a story
that it that is connected with him.
Yeah.
>> It's it's
>> it's very hard to say
>> and he is kind of generally considered
the antagonist in the story. But I I
want to be you're picking at something a
little pickly because you don't know
what his intention was. Some people seem
to have been disservice
but on a higher level they are being of
service to the church which they
consider to be the pathway to God.
>> So you and I would moralistically in
today's world condemn certain behaviors
but they thought they were saving your
soul. You understand the burning of the
witches, the Inquisition,
they were saving your soul from hell.
at confessing
that you're the work of the devil, etc.
So,
we would say, "Oh, how horrible." But
they were trying to save your soul. So,
you see what I'm saying? Your
perception, you're projecting onto it. I
wouldn't project any perception. Let the
reader make a decision. What was the
circumstance and what are the options,
>> okay,
>> about why a certain decision was made?
You see what I'm saying?
I can find many thing wrong things wrong
with the Catholic Church all the time.
See
>> because I don't belong to the college of
cardinals. That makes it easy.
>> Yep.
>> Okay. So I can write him from his
intention. That helps.
>> Why don't you do that? Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> How the various ways it could be
perceived and let the the the reader
decide. the
>> intuition of the reader will cut in also
their karmic propensities in those
directions.
>> That's very helpful.
>> Thank you always. Thank you.
>> Well, it it's a question that really
requires some study. That's why I don't
want to give you a snap.
>> Well, I'm studying it though until I'm
going crazy. So,
>> write about somebody else.
>> Write about
Watch the
>> Okay,
>> that was tricky.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello. Hi.
>> Uh I'm not sure if I remembered what you
said in one lecture that your cat helped
your osteoporosis.
>> My cat?
>> Well, my cat has helped a lot of things
get better.
>> Oh, not my cat. There is a cat, famous
cat named I think
>> Oscar.
>> Well, no. Oscar is the one that predicts
people's death, isn't it?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. No, there there's a cat that that
heals people. If you've got
osteoporosis, he will lay on your back
and your back will get better. Yes,
that's a documented the heal the cat who
is a healer. Yes, there's a cat who's a
healer.
>> Oh, okay.
>> I don't know.
>> I thought it was your cat that
>> No, no.
>> had helped you. had a cat who laid
across his thyroid when he had thyroid
problem.
>> When I hyper thyroidism, yes. Yeah. The
cat would sleep right across my neck
every night.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Hi, Susan. Uh, as
always, I want to thank you with all my
heart and soul for all that you give us.
Um, I hope that our love and devotion to
you feeds and nourishes your spirit.
>> Thank you.
>> You're welcome. Good. Um my question is
about recently I've started to have some
nightmares and this is unusual for me
and um I feel that it's almost like a an
attack or energy attack by some dark
energies is what it feels like and I'd
like to know if you have a suggestion of
a prayer that I can say before I go to
bed at night just to give myself a
deeper feeling of protection.
Yes, I've been smudging.
>> All right. So, it may not be dark
energies. Uh it it's uh it's a it's due
to the evolution of your consciousness.
Through the evolution of your
consciousness, you're unccoring some
negatives and when they first come up,
they it's like a nightmare.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I assume yes.
>> All right. So, let go resisting them and
let whatever it is come up.
>> Okay. Yep.
>> So in a prayer I can say to the oh Lord
I
>> oh I would turn it over to God you know
ask the the Lord to to guide your
awareness about the meaning and the
significance of these dreams.
>> Okay.
>> I asked the Lord reveal to me what is
the purpose? What should I learn? What
what is the meaning of it? What should I
be obtain from it?
What is the message of the dream? you
know.
>> Okay. Thank you. And I ask for your
blessings as always.
>> God bless you.
>> Thank you. God bless you as well. I love
you. Love you too. Thank you.
>> A lot of times it's what people believe
to be evil is not actually evil itself.
Yep.
>> Yes.
Thank you.
Yes,
>> thank you so much for the topic on the
natural world and and how all of nature
loves its life just as we and it was
just very tender to me and I I thank
you. Um last week a dog that I had
almost 16 years died in my hands and it
was just so lovely. So it was just a
moment of connection that I had with you
on that. Uh the question I had had to do
with if you could assist me in in
collapsing time. Um, I was really aware
of of um how timelessness appeared in
many of your of your charts today. And
when you stood up with us in the
beginning and said that you were with us
forever,
you know, that that took me right into
that same thought. You know, at some
level I know that I'm not quite letting
go of time. And I wondered if you had
any um assistance.
>> Oh, you're working on it. You're
transcending the illusion of it.
Um
so we we did time is also looked at as
sequence of events.
So how you contextualize time
uh determines how you experience it. If
you let go resisting the experience of
time, you disappear it.
And it how long does it take to get from
Phoenix
uh to here? If you uh let go resisting
time,
it takes no time.
You leave Phoenix and next thing you
know, you're here.
You experience the time is by resisting
it.
One of the fast track is to let go
resisting the passage of time. You you
don't think you're experiencing time,
but you are. You're always you're always
across the bottom of the screen.
the your timer is going 612, 613, 614,
16. You don't realize it, but you're
projecting a time track onto all events.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much. Okay. Love
you.
>> Oh,
>> yes.
>> Hello.
>> Yes. Um, I'm hoping you can share with
me your understanding of the value and
significance of taking the Eucharist.
>> Um,
>> or I know you've calibrated it at 700,
right?
>> Yes, correct.
>> It's uh distinctly a value
>> uh and it's recommended.
It's uh
one of the which it's one of the
sacraments of the church.
>> Mhm.
>> Therefore of uh value and as you say
we've calibrated it at 700.
>> Okay.
>> Thanks.
>> Yes.
Hi, Duck.
>> Uh, as of late, I've had a very hard
time uh controlling my anger.
>> Anger just comes up repeatedly. So, I
was wondering if you could speak to
that.
>> Well, I have no idea what the source of
your anger is. You know, you'd have to I
know have to know a lot more about it.
>> Yeah.
>> You could first stop eating sugar and
sweets to see if that affects your
angryness.
>> Then you could look for resentments that
you may have, you know, still from
childhood.
Uh so it's a matter of selfsearching to
see if you can find what what they're
associated with. You see
>> it's too general a question because
everybody has resentments all over the
place.
>> You know,
>> okay,
>> take some research.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you. Mhm.
>> I think everybody who has trouble with
anger try cutting out sugar and sweets
and just see about 50% of the time it
will disappear.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello.
>> Yes.
>> How would you suggest that one transcend
their anthropomorphical
image of God? Oh.
Uh, yeah. The ceiling of the cysteine
chapel. Huh?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. That's the image you're talking
about.
>> Yes.
>> Oh, yeah. Uh,
well, you could you don't have to res
change it, but you could ask God uh to
uh move on to a more sophisticated
view. You know, there's nothing wrong
with the father image of God. God the
father, God the son, God the holy ghost.
So there's nothing wrong with it. It's
just that it is a limitation
because it looks like a personality, you
know, a personhood.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh God the father. So father really
means founder.
The founder. God the founder.
>> Right. Yeah.
Well, it's like, you know, as little
kids, I call it the Santa Claus god. Oh,
yeah.
>> Because I think most of us were raised
with this image of God like Santa, you
know.
>> Oh, everybody has that.
>> Yeah. Watches everything you do. And
you're either good or bad. And if you do
the right thing, you get the presents.
And if you don't
>> Well, if I were you, I would do the
right thing.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you.
You could switch him to a jolly Santa
instead of a patriarch,
>> right?
>> Yeah. He He's too patriarchal. That's
what you're saying. You know,
>> judgmental and authoritative looking
Jehovah,
>> lightning flashing out of his axe or
something,
>> right?
>> I always remember what was it? It was
where they said, you know, God makes
mistakes. Look at the avocado. What was
that? You know, the pit's too big.
>> That's funny. I never heard that one.
>> Um,
>> that's a funny one.
>> Oh god. Yeah. The movie Oh God.
>> Oh, that's funny.
>> And he goes, you know, George played
God. He goes, he goes, "God makes
mistakes." He says, "Look at the
avocado. The pit's too big." Yeah,
>> that's funny.
>> Thank you.
>> You got to be kindly towards God. It
helps.
Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yes,
>> that's all.
>> Oh, you're in good shape. Thank God
you're in good shape. God bless you.
>> That's it.
>> Oh, it is.
>> No. Do you want to introduce all of our
staff? Yes. And how about our staff
coming up? Anybody? All our staff, you
want to come up and say Merry Christmas
to the group.
>> Okay.
>> Um, we want we want to have our staff
come up on stage so that you have some
idea of who who works for us.
>> Yes, we already asked. Wally, Kathy, you
need to come up here, too.
>> Okay. All the people that are on the
staff, associated with
>> Kathy are responsible for uh speaking at
Long Beach.
>> The number of people who it takes to put
put things on, you know,
>> contributors uh to the work and uh and
they're all a great joy to us. They're
all a great joy to us. They're all a
great joy to us and we consider
ourselves very fortunate to be
surrounded by such
>> We have some more coming. We they're
from the More coming. Who? Uh.
>> Oh, yes indeed. Oh, yes indeed. All
right.
>> Lou, Shel.
>> Oh,
>> well, uh,
>> this this is and then I have Donna and
Brock and a lot of other people that are
not here.
>> So, there it takes quite a few of us to
put on a lecture. So um I hope all of
you will you know appreciate the time
and effort and all these a lot of them
volunteer their time that to uh make
sure that we're able to put on lectures.
So I like you to all give you give them
a big hand for this work that they're
doing
>> and a merry Christmas and a merry
Christmas.
Now, now we're going to ask the staff to
sing.
>> Okay. One, two, three.
>> Jingle bells,
>> bells, jingle bells, jingle all the way.
>> Oh, what fun it is to ride on a onehorse
open sleigh.
Jingle bells, jingle bells, jingle all
the way.
Oh, what fun it is to ride in a onehorse
open sleigh. Pow! Yay!
All right. Thank you everyone. Thank
you. Yeah. And merry Christmas to
everyone. Amen. Amen.
All right. Thank you so much.
>> Oh, that's a pretty star you got there.
Where is the photographer? The
photographer. Yeah.
>> Oh, you're beautiful people. Yeah.
Oh,
>> now we get to see them tomorrow
afternoon. The people from Korea. Yeah.
Hallelujah.