We start all the lectures with a glory and excelsis deo.
If that makes you nervous, this is the wrong lecture to be on.
Having been forewarned.
All right, today we're talking about reality.
Reality, as everyone knows, is a crutch.
Our modern society pays no attention to it at all.
Because you can't make political hay out of reality.
Only out of distortions of reality.
So, anyway, everyone presumes that they understand what reality is.
And we asked everyone in the room, do you comprehend reality?
Anybody here say no?
If they don't comprehend reality?
We have a room full of idiots.
Well, this lecture and the next.
The next one has to do with truth.
This one has to do with reality.
Reality is more concrete, literal.
It has to do with content.
Truth has to do with context.
What one derives from it.
So, we've got some interesting slides, which I hope you like, because I slaved over them.
We've given about 100 lectures worldwide.
100.
Over 50 here in Sedona.
So, we'll be approaching our 100th lecture birthday soon.
We'll give out free ice cream cones, or something.
So, let's start with the first lecture, which will, I mean, the first slide, which will remind me what we're talking about today.
Oh, oh, that.
Let's see.
Oh, we need to know how many people here are new.
How many people are new?
Oh, there is, there is some.
All right.
Because there's new people, we always do a brief review of the basics, just so that you have an orientation.
And then we go on to the new material.
So, we have a few review slides.
And as soon as I can, oh, there she goes.
The map of consciousness.
And we remembered our pointer today.
Very good.
The map of consciousness is probably, you know, pretty well known worldwide.
That reality, everything that exists radiates forth an energy.
And that energy can be picked up.
By the field of consciousness itself, which is non-linear, beyond form, everywhere present, throughout all of time, yes.
And it's our point of reference.
It constitutes the absolute.
Now, a lot of people have a negative idea about absolutism.
And they are absolutely convinced that absolutism is false.
Yes.
It knows where it is locally, but it doesn't really have any point of self-correction.
So if the instruments on the ship are off, the ship will be lost.
And over time, they have, of course, at the bottom of the Great Lakes are the wrecks of
6,000 ships.
Just at the bottom of the Great Lakes, that's rather amazing.
So not having a compass to tell you truth from falsehood is why mankind barely survives.
So the map of consciousness, then, is picking up on essence.
One of the main themes of these lectures is to differentiate appearance, what a thing
looks like, or what you think about it, or what's your opinion in, from essence, which
is independent of what you think about it, or how it's pictured, or how it's projected
into the world.
Reality, then, is self-confirmatory.
So on a scale of 1 to 1,000, you can calibrate the relative energy of the essence of anything,
anywhere in time.
Think about consciousness, which is more comprehensible from quantum mechanics, is non-locality.
The essence of consciousness, it has no beginning, it has no end, it has no midpoint.
It has no beginning.
It has no here, and it has no there.
It has no now, and it has no then.
I don't know what the heck all that means, but it sure sounds impressive, huh?
In essence, it means we can calibrate the level of consciousness of Cleopatra, as well
as Mrs. Clinton, or what's that crazy lady on TV?
She rants and raves.
No.
Rosie.
Rosie, yeah.
All her favorite people.
I love Rosie, yeah.
You can make millions being mad as a hatter, you know?
It's wonderful.
You don't have to be sane, logical, anything.
That's freedom.
It's wonderful.
That's America.
Thank God.
So we can calibrate, then, by consciousness picks up the essence of things, and the reason
it does so, because the evolution of life in this planet, as we've said before, the
most primitive protozoa has no energy within itself.
It's not like chlorophyll green plants just sit there and enjoy the sun.
That which is protoplasmic has to obtain energy from out there.
Consequently, it has to be able to diagnose what's edible and what's lethal, what will
kill you and what will support life.
So that's an intuitive knowingness, you know, that it derives as an essence of life.
Yeah.
That's the secret of life itself, especially in its expression as protoplasm.
On this scale of consciousness, the way it turned out, the scale is arbitrary.
We could have picked one to a million or any other number, but as long as it's the same
point of reference.
So it's pretty much like a thermometer or an altimeter.
And I have no personal feelings about calibrated numbers.
Other times I hear critics, you know.
he said this, or he said that, I didn't say anything, folks.
He doesn't say anything about it.
He doesn't even care about it.
Why do I care what the pyramids in Egypt calibrate at?
You know what I mean?
I don't own them or anything.
So I don't have any vested interest
in what things calibrate at.
Having done tens of thousands of them,
we've gotten to be able to pretty much guess in advance
at least what range a thing is.
But occasionally, we're surprised, too.
The presumption is that it would come out in a certain value,
and it comes out quite differently.
If so, then we look elsewhere to see
what is the explanation of that.
And of course, the one that upset some people
was we said that earth warming is not due to human at all.
Oh, the angry blogs and everything.
You see people.
F you, brother.
What do you think about it?
I get such nice emails sometimes.
So when we got, no, earth warming is not due to pollution.
We had to look, why is that?
And we looked deeper, and we found, yes,
it's due to magnetic solar activity,
the magnetic radiation of the surface of the sun.
And our core drilling is down through 10,000 years
if you don't calibrate it.
And now, that hit the news this week.
So as of this week, I'm an OK person in the world again.
Thank you, Lord.
I don't want to offend certain people, you know what I'm saying?
So one of the reasons people have difficulty discerning truth
and reality is there's so much investment
in what they believe in.
So if you want to stay free and become enlightened, don't pour
a lot of emotion into any view.
You know, you don't have to die for environmentalism
or, you know what I mean, some particular viewpoint.
It supersedes reality.
People throw all this intense emotion
into what they believe.
It's bad enough to even believe it,
but it's even worse to throw a lot of emotion into it.
If Al Gore's book don't win, you're
going to die or kill yourself.
You should bomb the Pentagon or something.
I don't know.
Anyway, be passionate for God, be passionate for God
rather than political labeling and put on everything.
Because everything that's political in today's world,
you can't mention anything but it's got a label.
And then all the passion that goes with that label,
you know what I'm saying?
One reason not to get so passionately committed,
is because if it's proven wrong, you look like an idiot.
That's one.
Anyway, the good news is that NBC News and all those now
agree with the old doc here.
He was right all along, wasn't he?
My god, I thought that would show him, huh?
The octogenarians are going to start off with a bang.
All right, so we can calibrate the level
of anything in the world.
Now, only about a third, which I didn't know
when I first started all this, only about a third
of the people in the United States are capable of doing it.
To get the correct answer, you yourself
have to be calibrated over 200, which
means you're more interested in truth than in falsehood.
Only a third of the people in the United States
are more interested in truth than in falsehood.
Hm.
More interested in being right than knowing what the truth is.
So that's called narcissism.
All right.
So what distorts the capacity to perceive essence rather
than appearance is a detached commitment to truth,
to reach God through truth.
And the pathway through God, you can
sort through everything ever written by man anywhere
in time and calibrate what's true and follow what's true.
It'll take you to God.
All truth will eventually take you to divinity.
God is the source and the essence of consciousness
out of which arises truth.
So if you do nothing, every time you come to a split in the road,
you follow which one calibrates to the higher.
And you keep doing that, you'll end up God.
So truth is a pathway to God.
Devotion, all these things.
Devotion.
But devotion can lead you astray, too,
because people are devoted to Nazism,
not devoted to all kinds of horrible things.
Devotion to what?
Devotion to truth.
So we call this the devotional nonduality.
Nonduality meaning you're beyond truth and falsehood.
You find out what is the truth, and then you
devote yourself to it.
So in your life, then, all you have to do is look up these things.
And you can see those things that will bring you to God
are the highest, an inner joy, lovingness.
Reason precedes that.
You'll see that reason is beyond emotionality.
Reason doesn't have anything to do with emotionality.
The answer to a problem doesn't depend on how you feel about it,
does it?
No.
So reason is in the 400s.
There's still emotionality in the 300s.
And however, it's positive.
It's positive, positive emotionality.
And then below level 200, you have all the negatives.
190 is pride.
Most of the negative.
And the blogs we get calibrate at 190.
And those are like the guy who writes the books that disproves Einstein.
He's still writing them.
How he explains the atomic bomb, I don't know.
So pridefulness, then, is at about 190.
And then you get just hatefulness.
So then we get some blogs that are just, I hate you.
That's OK.
At least he's honest.
Then people hate things and think they love them.
All right, so we'll move on.
We're just going to do a quick review.
These are the enlightened and divine states.
And as you see, the higher you get,
enlightenment really starts at 600.
That's formally on that chart, 600.
That's beyond the experience.
Reality is nonlinear as context rather than content.
And then you go all the way up.
You see, you go on up to 1,000 in this world.
And then you go up to infinity.
I don't know where the numbers are.
We had numbers here.
Archangels at 60,000 and up, 6,000 and up.
Anyway, what the calibrated level of consciousness does
is confirm spiritual reality.
Confirm spiritual reality.
Confirm it.
Doesn't prove it.
Confirms it.
So we'll move on, then.
Here's the distribution of the consciousness in the population.
You see approximately 80% of the world calibrates below 200,
which explains the nature of the news.
OK, next.
So man is on an evolutionary pathway.
So distribution of the levels of mankind, about 22% of mankind
is above 200.
And the great man.
The mass of mankind is below 200.
Therefore, truth does not prevail in society.
Falsehood prevails.
So why doesn't the world just destruct, then?
We'll go to the next slide.
It doesn't destruct because those above 200, you see,
is a logarithmic chart.
So the power of those above 200 is so enormous,
that it balances the approximate 80% below 200.
A group like this, which we've calibrated a number of times,
is enormously powerful in balancing out these energies.
So a group like this is right here.
And because their power is exponentially, logarithmically
very high, it counterbalances negativity.
Now, the negativity is very high.
It's very high.
They are greater in numbers, but their energy is far weaker.
So spiritual groups that are highly committed
help maintain the energy level of mankind overall.
OK.
And here is the evolution of consciousness
over a timeline which you're going to have to throw out.
Because it recently took a dip down.
Recently took a dip down.
Consciousness of mankind is is brilliant.
kind of just dropped five or seven points in Western civilization, in the U.S., and
in the world in general.
So let's make a note.
We have to repair that one.
We have to go like this.
I don't argue with God about it.
If he wants it to go like this, it'll go like that.
It'll go like that, maybe.
I mean, this is just the evolution of the energy of life over great eons of time, great
eons of time, and you can't see it from back there, so we'll go on to the next one, and
that evolution through the animal kingdom, you see?
Can you imagine if this was a couple of million years ago, we'd be out there saying, save
the dinosaurs, save Tyrannosaurus.
Alex, save Tyrannosaurus, Alex, save Tyrannosaurus, Alex, save Tyrannosaurus, Rex.
It's so adorable, so cute.
So here we see the evolution of mankind then through life.
Life can only originate from life itself.
No skeptic has ever been able to create life out of non-life, which is the downfall of
the materialistic.
The secularist is that life is a totally different energy.
It cannot arise from non-life, either organic or non-organic.
So life originates from a different source than the material world.
So here we see all the animals and all our favorites that we've talked about over the
years, Komodo dragon and the octopus.
Octopus is extremely intelligent.
It really should be more than 20.
Couldn't we pluck them up a little bit?
There was one on the octopus on TV the other night.
They're so smart.
They're just really brainy, you know, smarter than people, many often.
And then we go up through why dolphins calibrate different than whales.
I don't know.
Whales and dolphins.
Sometimes I'll get an argument in the email.
How come?
I don't know.
Don't ask me how come.
So here we come up through the evolution.
The evolution of the animals, animal kingdom, and you see the major shift at level 200.
From the carnivore who lives by the death of others, eats others, to the herbivore, which
becomes benign, so it's similar to our chart, 200 and up is benign, and less than 200 tends
to be carnivorous, it'll kill you.
And here we come up through all of our favorites.
Dogs.
There's something very special about dogs and family dogs and cats, because you see
the cat's purr is at 500, and the dog's wagging tail is at 500.
There's something very, very special about them, spiritually speaking.
Their capacity to love, loyalty, et cetera.
Yeah.
Okay.
We'll go on next.
So when we skip the negative and then we get up to low.
level of truth, then we get up to the level of emotions, positive emotions, and then when
we get to the consciousness level of the 400s, you leave the world of emotion.
Reason and the intellect don't care how you feel about it at all.
Some people try to mix the two, how they feel about facts and reality, and it's really irrelevant
how you feel about it.
So these are the great books of the Western world, which are the foundation, the emergence
of the Renaissance, the great intellect.
It's really a rebirth of what went on in ancient Greece.
The high point of human civilization was really in ancient Greece, then it fell apart, and
then it was resurrected.
Let's see if that's so.
The high point of human evolution, we have a person that asked this, was the intellectual
world.
The intellectual world was the foundation.
The intellectual world was the ancient Greece.
That's a fact.
I was intuitive, but I never did the Aramon.
So then it was reborn in the Renaissance, and now these are all called dead white men,
I guess.
They don't allow them in the academia anymore.
Yeah, but this is the intellectual elegance all the way up to consciousness level 499.
499 is the level of great geniuses, Sir Isaac Newton, Freud, Sir Isaac Newton, Freud,
who else?
499, Einstein, 499.
So 499 is as high as you can push the intellect.
So I have always had respect for this presentation of the development of the human intellect
over time.
Because it's the intellect.
That differentiates man from the animal, yeah?
I mean, animals can hate and animals can love.
So what makes you different is that you have a prefrontal cortex.
So we'll move on.
The purpose of the prefrontal cortex is to think.
Let's work.
Now we talk about content.
So here's to the content.
And content, what does it look like?
It depends on the proximate context, the situation.
A crime.
At the time, he was intoxicated and the lady's dog was biting his leg and all.
So proximate context influences our understanding of what went on.
He shot her, but he was drunk and she was attacking him with a knife, yeah?
So that's the proximate context.
Then the infinite context is consciousness itself.
So truth and understanding and reality.
So that's the proximate context.
And understanding and reality is to interpret content within context.
So one of the easiest ways to lie in our society, and it's done all the time, is to just ignore
the context.
Ignore the context, because that way you can make people wrong.
Because if you put it in the context, then you can't make them wrong.
So you know, say we were at war at the time, oh, okay.
All right, so we'll move on to the next.
This I just put on for, not that I understand it.
But it sure looks impressive, don't it?
Quantum mechanics.
Because quantum mechanics is in the linear domain or in the intellectual domain, coming
closer and closer to an understanding of consciousness.
And Henry Stapp, whose book you can get off, you can get for free, Henry Stapp, you can
print out his book for free, his most recent book, you know, brings an approximation.
And of course, what he's emphasizing.
And which I emphasize, is the effect of intention.
The effect of intention.
So we say that this world does not operate according to the Newtonian laws of causality,
of this causing of that.
Instead, there is a potential, a potential.
And under the proper conditions, meaning the proper context, the potentiality emerges as
an actuality, not as a result of causation.
So the little seed is not caused.
Nobody forces it to grow into a blossom.
Under proper conditions, one of those being your intention for it to grow, the conditions
you add are warmth, and sunlight, and water.
And now, like a pupa coming out of a cocoon, it emerges as a flower or a butterfly.
But nobody forces it to do that.
Nobody causes it.
You can take a cocoon and squeeze it and apply all the force you want.
you won't create a butterfly, you'll just create a mess.
So intention is very powerful.
So if you listen to the lecture with the intention
of advancing your own level of consciousness
and doing it communally with all of us together,
that is the likelihood that we'll develop, yes?
So a group like this is very powerful
because of its intention.
All right, so as I say, you can get this for yourself,
happily, Henry Stapp, you can print it out for nothing.
Okay, let's go next.
Yes, the other difference that bothers people politically,
everything bothers people politically,
is that the two levels, above and below 200,
have a different brain physiology.
This is profoundly important.
Below 200 people process things.
Left brain dominance, completely differently.
They do it through the left side of the brain,
and these are the primarily animal responses.
The animal responses.
So things, this is how perception becomes distorted.
So if you perceive the world through the left brain,
below 200, you're seeing it more as an animal sees it.
If somebody agrees with you, they're a friend.
If they don't agree with you, you're an enemy
and have to attack them.
People that don't like what we say here,
read in the book, have a cup of whiskey and sodas,
they sit down at the computer,
F you, you dumb ass.
Isn't that what they say sometimes?
She reads them.
I'm not allowed to read them.
The office staff won't let me.
I say, what's that there?
You don't need to see this.
All right, so how does forgiveness come about?
Forgiveness is seeing error as limitation
because this is a physiologic limitation
due to brain function itself.
That's what Jesus Christ said,
to forgive because people who are not integrous
cannot help but be that way.
Cannot help but be that way.
So the forgiveness then,
people say forgiving is very hard to do.
It's not hard once you understand this,
that the person is limited
by their own brain physiology.
And from this side, out this end comes F you.
We call a spade a spade in these lectures.
And what did Jesus Christ say about them?
He said to avoid them.
He said, don't attack evil.
Avoid, do not become engaged with it.
Do not try to prove it that it's wrong.
Don't go to war with it.
Don't get into an argument.
Throw their emails away.
So we don't answer anything that calibrates under 200.
They bring in a message and say it was a calibrative set.
If it's under 200, we just throw it in the waste basket.
What happens at consciousness level 200,
which one arise at through karmic advantage
and devotion, et cetera,
through prayer and through forgiveness
and through the mercy of God,
is now the brain shifts sides
and there's the production of kundalini energy.
What shifts the brain chemistry from here to here
is the emergence of kundalini energy.
And with kundalini energy emerges the etheric body,
the etheric brain, the etheric brain.
So the processing that goes on here
is instantaneous through the etheric brain
before it even gets to the prefrontal cortex.
And therefore, this person sees things differently.
And one of the reasons they see things differently
is because that's their intention.
I see things differently now is a stock phrase in 12-step groups
of course of miracles.
Anybody spiritually devoted will eventually
begin to see things more benign and feel sorry for people
rather than hate them, feel sorry for them.
I don't hate the Komodo dragon, but I don't step
into his cage in my bare feet.
So it doesn't mean to be stupid.
Sometimes I think it's misinterpreted
as being stupid and tell you, oh, Komodo dragons,
they won't hurt you.
Then they're OK.
They're OK.
That's the last thing they said.
So being blind to danger doesn't mean to be oblivious.
You can love the animal and not bother with them,
but I wouldn't get in the cage with them.
Yes.
All right, so below 200, then, you have a different,
there's a columnist named Pitts, and he coined the term, which
I've quoted in the current book,
that these people on the left here
live in an alternate reality.
This is an alternate reality, and it's a different reality
from this level here.
One reason it's different, it literally is.
Pitts was right, even though he's a columnist.
They actually have a different reality.
They process things differently.
They see them differently.
They experience them differently.
Over here, you experience things more.
He's more benign, above 200.
So if something is destructive, out of respect,
out of respect for his reality, I don't provoke it.
So that's respect.
I respect the Komodo dragon.
So I don't make them wrong.
I don't hate them, but I respect them.
So unfortunately, sometimes idealism
reaches the point of being the fool.
Thinking that you can ignore the reality of what it is.
Don't you see that's disrespectful?
If you don't think certain people in this world
are out to kill you, you're not being respectful
of their belief system.
And I believe the international problems we have
is a failure to not only to understand
that different viewpoint, but to give it due respect,
to give it due respect.
If somebody is carrying a loaded 45,
you don't stick your fingers in his arm.
He's always, that's disrespectful.
OK.
So I believe in respecting one's energies.
Your biggest safeguard is your respect for them.
Because out of respect, then you feel
obligated to understand them.
And when you understand them, you're not so likely
to stumble into offending.
OK, next one.
God versus science.
I don't know how this got in here.
We did God versus science.
We won't need to do that again.
We'll go to the next one.
Oh, here we are at today.
I knew we'd get to today somewhere.
What is real?
Everybody thinks their mind knows what is truth.
And we're going to do that next lecture.
And what is real?
So I thought we'll start with just simple definitions.
What is real?
First of all, there's a definition.
We say, well, it's actual.
It exists.
And mainly what we say is real is physical.
I really have 10 toes.
Yes, really have.
I had 10 toes in here.
And so it's within the linear domain.
Because it's linear, it can be confirmed by the senses.
So even the animal is capable of material linear reality.
So the fox can see.
Or the hare.
And it's confirmable by the senses.
So you only need your left brain animal world to see whether a thing is in reality factual.
That is manifest.
Then we jump to the next level from just sensory confirmation, the fox sees the rabbit there,
to mentalization.
And we run into the world of science.
In science, for a thing to be real, it has to be, or true, it has to be measurable.
Some, you know, it has to have dimensions, and it must exist somewhere in time and space.
So, therefore, science is not really capable of dealing with the abstract.
You see that? All the answers to life will not come out of science.
The world that we deal with is adequately described by science,
with its advance now to quantum mechanics and the Heisenberg principle,
it enlarges its realm.
You know, the current view of the universe is that the universe is held in place
by virtue of consciousness itself.
It's consciousness itself that holds this world in its present state.
Without consciousness, the universe would not exist.
So all, as you read in Stapp's newest book,
the whole universe exists
within consciousness itself,
within consciousness and because of consciousness.
So when you look at a thing, you see,
you have delay going from potentiality to actuality.
By observation, you block the collapse of the wave function.
So the universe is suspended between potentiality and actuality
because we've collapsed the wave function at its present level, see?
That's all incorrect scientifically, so we'll forget it.
What is real is confirmable by the senses.
Science then measures things via information about it,
such as measurement, time and place.
And when you look at, when you say,
I think a thing is real,
you've really drawn a mental conclusion of your sensory experience.
And it's really the lower mind in the animal that says it's real.
The animal doesn't have to think about it.
You're in, within you is an animal.
You know, within every human there's the animal.
So it's your animal that says the thing is real.
Ouch, oh, oh, that's a stone.
It says it's real.
What it means is something else.
Therefore, it's a subjective based on faith in sensory input.
What you say is real is based on your faith
on your sensory input.
It's therefore a subjective statement based on faith.
Therefore, knocking faith means you would have no way
of knowing anything about anything.
You have faith in your own sensory experience.
And throughout evolution then,
we've developed the capacity to be able to sense
the linear domain in a group.
It's a great level.
However, it's also prone to errors we'll get to later.
I am is provisional to consciousness levels above 200.
This is a mystification that people themselves are limited
in their level of consciousness.
Below 200 they exist and they are sensory,
but they are unaware of their existence as such.
It doesn't say I exist, it just is.
Yeah.
So, you see,
if you don't realize the value of life as a gift,
as existence itself,
then you don't value it in others.
So, you see cultures that destroy life of others
because they themselves,
although they exist as an animal,
they're not really aware of their existence as such.
So, the sensory world is based on interpretation of data.
The argument about what's real
and what's not,
we'll run it through again when we get to what's true.
And we did run through it once before
when we talked about relativism.
You see, the intellectual problem is,
Pythagoras, as reported in Plato,
says,
the world I experience is real to me
and the world that you experience is real to you.
Therefore,
there is no absolute reality.
All reality is only subjective,
which is really the basis of solipsism,
that the way I experience the world is my world.
So, it ends up with,
actually, the intellectual argument,
philosophic argument,
ends up with an absurdity
because the fact that you say you exist and I exist
doesn't mean that neither one of us does.
There are two, actually.
Socrates, of course, then brought this further
and pointed out how illusion is perceived as a reality.
And Socrates is a great friend to spiritual students
because he gives you an avenue
by which forgiveness comes about through understanding.
How can you forgive people
because, as Socrates said,
illusion, then, is your perception of reality
and it's projected out into the world.
What you want, you see.
What you desire, you see as the good.
So, the trouble is you cannot see truth from falsehood.
And this was further elaborated, of course, by Descartes,
who pointed out, you know,
there's the world within
and then there's the world without
and the comprehension of reality
depends, then, on transcending that duality.
Now, the only way to transcend these dualities
pointed out throughout time
from Jesus Christ on through Socrates, Descartes, etc.,
or Protagoras,
the only way to transcend
the possibility of making an error
about reality or truth
is, frankly, consciousness calibration.
There's absolutely...
man has never, until now, evolved a way
to transcend that duality.
Never.
All of mankind's history,
he's never been able to discern
essence from appearance.
And now, we have a very simple scale.
It's like he never could tell altitude
until somebody discovered an altimeter
and now it's simple.
So, we don't have any opinion or view on things.
We just calibrate what is the level of truth,
what is the essence of that which is being described.
And we can be completely determined
and detached from that.
Therefore, what we think is real
is a sensory and a mental presumption.
And here we have a review of what I just said.
The universe is purely a mentalization.
There is no out there, only in here.
It's only in here.
There is no you and then the universe.
So, how do you prove what's real?
It's through consensual validation.
If I say a thing weighs so much,
you weigh it and you get the same,
then we both agree.
That doesn't create a reality,
but that creates an agreement
on what both of us presumed to be a reality.
Still does not tell you what's real,
but it tells you what is confirmable
within the usual definition of reality.
What's the next slide?
Okay, so what we did now
is review up to the present time
we just got through saying
reality is subjective
based on faith in one's senses.
It's experiential of one's senses.
Therefore, an animal is capable
of discerning what's real.
He doesn't discern what's truth,
but he gets what's real.
And it's dependent on the reliability
of the information that your senses are giving you.
So, therefore, it's actually a testimonial.
All statements about reality
are a testimonial.
If you want to get somebody else
to get rid of their argument,
just say, call it,
it's just a testimonial.
Just a testimonial.
We all say that it fulfills
the criteria of facts,
which is reliable data.
To know what is real
is a subjective presumption.
Everybody's mind says,
well, I know what's real.
I know what's real.
And we've become more
or a little humble, more humble,
when we realize that that's the presumption
that this mind is making now.
And we always leave room
for correction later.
So a sophisticated spiritual student
drops a lot of their narcissism
and instead takes on a certain humility
that whatever I think and believe now
could change later
because additional information comes in.
So as spiritually committed people,
we tend to be somewhat more humble
about our statements about the world
and know that it's subject
to editing later on.
How many planets are there?
Well, there were nine,
and now there's eight, right?
So we're somewhat humble then.
So intellectual humility
then serves
a spiritual purpose
that we're not so dead sure
that we're absolutely right
about everything all the time.
It's a likelihood, a presumption.
So all information then
in a spiritual context
is held as presumptive,
and it's only provable
by actually becoming,
by actually becoming.
Fulfills properties of content, yes.
You're going to tell me
when it's time for a break?
I don't know.
Oh, okay.
I'll finish up this slide.
To know what is real
is a subject of resumption.
And therefore, with humility,
so we talk about humility
in spiritual work.
Spirituality means an openness
to receive.
And as I've often said,
it's yin in nature.
It's yin in nature.
And certainty is like yang.
Oh, I know that,
and I know that,
and no worth warming
is up to evil Americans at all.
I mean, that's very yang.
Doesn't leave any room
to back off gracefully.
Tentative means,
it seems to me,
even now,
that the temperature variation
of the planet
is likely due
to the magnetic activity
of the surface of the sun.
But even now,
I don't say it's certain,
even though it's been
scientifically proven.
I say it's likely,
because that could change
tomorrow, too.
So we don't want to catch
in all our chips,
so...
In the Vegas of spiritual work,
you don't put all your chips
on one thing.
All right.
To know what is real
is, therefore,
a subjective presumption.
And it's best not to invest
narcissistic emotionality into it.
Look how difficult it is
to get off a position
when you've poured
all kinds of emotional energy into it
and become sort of
a fanatic about it.
I don't know why people
just can't have a view
about a thing
without becoming maniacal about it.
You know what I mean?
You want to change
a little thing,
they have a whole parade,
you know,
and what are they going to have,
a summit aid or something?
People are out there
with parades
and all kinds of...
What's all the emotion about?
Why contaminate,
you know,
the intellectual world
with emotion?
Anyway,
to know what is real
is a subjective presumption.
And with humility,
we say it's a likelihood.
And all we're talking about anyway
is content.
And what it really means,
we haven't even gotten to it yet,
because what it means
is signified as
a consequence of context.
So it's a product
of the sensory world,
that's the animal world.
Then you add human mental processing
and editing.
Therefore,
all information is itself
only tentative and provisional.
Everything I say today
is tentative and provisional.
It is the best understanding
that I have at the moment,
you see?
To think you know
is a narcissistic premise.
Actually,
you know about,
you can know about a thing.
The only way to know a thing
is to be it.
The only one who knows
what it is to be a cat
is a cat.
And the only one
who knows what it is
to be a cat
is a cat.
And the only one
who knows
what it is
to be a cat
is a cat.
And the only one
who knows
what it is to be a cat
is a cat.
You can know about a cat,
but you cannot know.
To actually know
is to be.
All right.
And this brings us
to a very sophisticated
philosophic
and metaphysical understanding.
That reality
is identity
rather than description.
This is where
we run into
a political problem
in the United States.
Reality is
what a thing is
rather than
how it is described.
In our world
of the media,
we no longer see
what a thing is.
We see how
it's politicized,
glamorized,
presented,
whether it's
in technicolor,
whether it has music,
whether it's
scantily dressed.
Vote for.
Oh, God.
If the world
was all women,
we'd be on there
saying,
vote for.
So,
reality
is definition
by identity
rather than
a description.
We can know
about the cat,
but only the cat
knows
what it is
to be a cat.
And we've used
this example before.
You can read
a cat,
everything you read
about cats
in the encyclopedia
and say,
the cat,
what do you think
of all that?
And the cat says,
well,
that's not,
I mean,
that's interesting,
but it's not
got anything
to do with me
.
Now,
what does the cat
experience?
The cat experiences
only that
I am me.
The only reality
you know
is that you are
I am me.
Everything else
is a description.
So,
reality then
is identity
rather than
description.
This is important
to the mystic
because
one becomes
what
a religionist
would describe.
It's no longer
describable.
In fact,
you can't
even,
describe it.
Any attempt
to mystical
transmitting
information
about the
mystical
self-awareness
is frankly
impossible.
For one thing,
there's nobody
there to
describe it,
which is
not even
comprehensible
to the average
person either.
Everybody thinks
there's a you.
there's a you
there.
Because they think
there's a you,
they project that
and assume
that there's a you
there.
There's no you
here at all.
If that's true
of me,
that's true
of all of you
also.
The highest levels
of consciousness,
there is no you-tube.
They really mean
me-tube.
There is no
actual me,
you see,
because what you
concern as you
as me
ends up
as a definition.
And when you
let go of definitions,
that's the reality
of your existence.
The reality
of your existence
about which nothing
can be said.
You can't even
prove that you
exist without
going through
a mentalization.
And if you
prove it will
kill you
anyway,
so.
Mahatma
Maharshi
said it.
The world
you see
doesn't even
exist.
It's surely
a projection.
And of course
that's true
at consciousness
level 700.
The world
you see
doesn't even
exist.
Reality is
a dream.
It doesn't
make sense
to level
700.
And therefore
try to
twist your mind
into seeing
it how Ramana
Maharshi
sees it
doesn't work.
Actually
what you
do is you
let go
giving reality
to the linear.
And by
detachment
from linearity
then
you become
detached
and that
world no
longer exists
as a reality.
What's
the next
slide,
eh?
Huh.
We say
for a thing
to be real
it has to
exist in
a linear
dimension.
That's
sort of
prosaic
science.
However
many things
are real
that do
not exist
within the
physical
dimension.
Mental
reality
you have
a picture
a reason
in your
head
you have
images
imagination
so these
are real
but you
can't
prove
them.
So trying
to reduce
reality
to the
pseudo
scientific
primitive
then
it
doesn't
work
because
not
it's
a
reality
in which
you cannot
be confirmed
scientifically.
So you see
the limitation
of science
because a
lot of
people
will try
to refute
spiritual
reality
and they
come from
sort of
a pedestrian
level of
science,
the level
of the
skeptic
sort of
which is
very
important
to the
experience
so
we could
say that
reality
is what
you
experience
is real.
So we
come back
to
Protagoras
make full
circle
back
to his
discussion
with
Plato.
What's
real
to you
is real
and what's
real
to me
is the
emotional
and what
you actually
end up
with is
if you've
removed all
the sources
of error
what you end
up with
is a scale
of consciousness
and I've
done it.
I've taken
everything ever
written about
the subject
and transcended
it,
canceled
it out,
gone
beyond
it and
the only
thing you
end up
with is
a scale
of consciousness
and it's
because of
that consciousness
that holds
it
between
the potential
and the
actual
is partly
the result
of the
Zeno effect.
So
when you
transcend
the emotional
all this
mentalization
all the things
we've
talked
about so
far
all you
end up
with is
a scale
of consciousness
and it's
very important
to understand
the difference
between reality
and illusion
between perception
and essence
and some
of the questions
that have
come at
the end of
previous lectures
I realize
I have
failed.
You've
failed
to have
gotten across
the difference
between
perception
and essence.
Perception
Essence
and how
it's
differentiated
from appearance.
So
oh my god
my brain's
all fagged
out.
Well we went
through the
intellectual
we went
through the
beginning
of the
representation
because every
time I like
to recontextualize
it so it
becomes innate
after you
hear it
enough
you don't
have to
reason
because if
you go up
in a plane
and try and
memorize
the map
of what you've
seen
and go back
down and try
to memorize
it you'll
have to go
over that
field over
and over
again but
if you go up
in a plane
and you've
gone over
that terrain
many times
you know
exactly
where to
turn.
You know
you turn
around and
you know
where to
go.
It's just
obvious due
to familiarity
right?
And save
everybody
thinking I
don't want
people to
get stuck
in thinking
or understanding.
You get
there by
familiarity
because with
you bypass
just the
intellect
and all
of your
faculties
which are
enormous
to consciousness
it's obvious
isn't it?
I mean you don't
have to even
think about
it you know.
I don't want
people thinking
about anything
we said.
Alright so
we'll take
a break.
Somebody wrote
me that
Pepsi Cola
would kill
me.
If you think
that don't
drink it
because it
will.
Where are
we?
Back to
where we
started
a few
minutes
ago.
I don't
think
anybody
was
going
to
drink
Pepsi
Cola.
I think
everybody
is going
to drink
Pepsi
Cola.
We're
going
to drink
Pepsi
and keep
our
spirits
fresh.
We're
going
to
drink
Some of them are famous names, professors and all.
And when you calibrate why is it they can't do it,
you get because they're actually atheists.
So if you negate truth,
then you don't have the privilege of access to it.
If you negate truth,
then you lose the capacity to discern truth.
All right.
As you can see, we're negating all these various pathways
to knowingness through the intellect,
through what you think is real, et cetera.
And next time we'll get to what people think is truth.
And you end up with a condition known as divine stupidity.
Now, divine stupidity is much to be desired.
I remember ending up in divine stupidity myself.
And, you know, in the spiritual traditional literature,
it's described as a state.
Divine stupidity.
I, myself, know nothing.
Because whatever you think is a definition,
all definitions are not factual.
It's what you are.
What you are is sufficient statement
about which you say nothing.
You no longer say I am this or I am that or this is that.
You experience like the cat does.
That which you are, you are.
And there's nothing.
There's nothing you can say about it.
So you end up with divine stupidity.
I'm sure if you asked Ramana Maharshi what he thought
about something, he'd tell you he had no idea.
Because you give up those little thought bundles.
And because you see them, that they're just thoughts,
that they're evanescent, and that they have no intrinsic reality
other than the belief.
In fact, the only reason you believe this sensory information is
because you have faith in God.
You have faith in belief that they're telling you what's true,
that they're telling you what's true.
So you end up then with divine stupidity.
And therefore, the more lectures you attend, the dumber you will get.
Somebody says, what do you think about so-and-so?
And you tell them, I don't know.
I just don't think about it at all, to tell you the truth.
I don't think, I just don't have, I don't know.
I just don't think about it.
I don't know what to think about it.
.
All you can say is what you've heard.
All right.
Now, you see, that's a different dimension.
I have heard such and such.
And even the Buddha related that.
I have heard thus and so.
Even spiritual knowledge, all you can say, I have heard.
So I have heard, you see, is a much more humble position.
I have heard that such and such is so.
And now, through my own inner work, I will arrive
at whether or not I have heard such and such.
Whether that is true or not, you know.
And, of course, in the world, there are those who can hear
and those who cannot hear.
Therefore, lectures such as the one here are heard by some
and not heard by others.
And so, the other dictum that went with it is that those
who can hear, hear.
And don't worry about those who cannot hear,
that's god's problem.
So, that, you don't have to...
.
don't have to they'll save you the whole trip of saving the world saving the
whales saving the dinosaurs saving mankind say salvation is up to God yes
so we can improve the pleasantry of living here but so divine stupidity you
end up with no opinion on anything because you see all opinions are just
mentalizations and you can change your opinion depending on the folks you're
hanging out with what happens to be beneficial what happens to be the meme
of the day the meme of the day and they come and go so we even give reality then
to that which is evanescent such as a dream or a memory what is real we
give emotions reality yeah what reality does an emotion have an animal has
emotion so people who are big enthusiasts about emotion I would say
you know what of what value is that to have a lovingness towards all of life
and all of its expression covers everything and everything is merely
upsetting because it's an interference you'll notice most anger is really an
upset
you'll notice most anger is really an upset
that you always put the mayonnaise here and somebody moved to there
I mean that's the that's the big upset who moves my mayonnaise your home it's
who moved the pickled herring where's my pickle Larry the quiet the angry
beast
she says here's the fickle hearing okay so you see these passing things are of
no great moment and there's no point in killing yourself or them
I think I'll kill myself if I can't find the big old herring.
So the emotional, then, is depending on how seriously we see these things.
If we see them as trivial and evanescent, then we know that they're going to work out.
The reason they work out is because of unconditional love.
So even though the other person did it wrong and shouldn't have put the mayonnaise in the wrong place,
we're willing to forgive them because when I can't find my pickled herring,
she knows where it is.
So the context, so that's why we talk about relationship is alignment.
The two people alignment rather than involved.
Instead of a push-pull ego battle, you see, of who's going to be in control,
when people are both aligned, neither one wants the other one to be upset.
And so the two are aligned with peace, and therefore the decision that is made
is one that tries to resolve issues rather than prolong them or inflame them further.
So content, then, is our understanding of content depends on the context,
whether a certain thing is right or wrong.
So today's world, what you see is a struggle for moral superiority.
Moral superiority.
That's all this world is about.
Who's right and who has the moral high ground.
And if you don't think I have the moral high ground, I'll kill you.
The moral high ground.
So you see, it's constant.
The evening news is comical,
which everything is twisted a little bit to give it a moral high ground twist, you know, moral high ground.
All right.
So then, it's subject to the context.
Now, spiritual, we, these are what are real to us.
Is faith, hope, devotion, prayer, commitment, devotion, those are real.
Those, of course, are all intangible, not provable.
So to disparage them is because people are coming from the wrong realm.
These can either be proven or disproven.
And as I say, the skeptic ridicules faith.
And has tremendous faith in his skepticism.
He lives and dies by his skepticism.
I mean, has he got faith, maybe?
I was going to kick this big rigmarole he writes about faith, you know.
Nobody's a bigger sucker for faith than the skeptic, you know, the cynic.
All right.
So these states to divine idiocy, divine stupidity, go through humility.
The realization of one's limitation.
The awareness.
The awareness of it.
And by observation and mindfulness, you see the mind taking off in these various directions.
So mindfulness is then a spiritual practice to be aware of where you are at all times.
To be aware of what your mind is doing.
And, of course, eventually, as you let go of everything and through contemplation,
you begin to realize what the mind is, you see.
And the mind is like addicted to experiencing.
Oh, it's hooked.
It wants to experience.
It tries to extract experiencing.
And that's the way it's going to survive.
So enlightenment is when your awareness, when your observation gets beyond experiencing.
The leading edge of this.
The experiencer takes place in one ten-thousandth of a second.
Within one ten-thousandth of a second, the mind has already interpreted the incoming stimulus.
It jumps in there and categorizes it, makes it right, makes it wrong, makes it attractive, has an aversion.
To get beyond the experiencer, just to the witness observer,
just to witness and observe without necessarily extracting experiencing.
Experiencing.
So the experiencer is the leading edge of the ego.
So meditative and contemplative, then, is to be with consciousness-awareness without
necessarily experiencing the content of consciousness-awareness.
That sounds tricky, but one time it suddenly comes to you that one is the witness of it,
one is the observer.
But you don't know.
But you don't necessarily have to experience it.
You don't have to juice it.
So the ego, to survive, is addicted to experiencing.
And it survives because of the juice it gets out of that.
So we eventually transcend that through faith, hope, devotion, and prayer.
Oh, God, please take me, help me go beyond that.
Through humility.
Through self-realization and awareness.
Through mindfulness.
We get to the observer-witness.
That is not difficult to do.
That can be done.
And because we notice that below the thinking mind, there is a silence.
And if you focus on the silence, you'll notice that your mind isn't saying anything about
what's going on out there.
The ego jumps in, tries to fill it up with something.
But if you lose your attraction to the titillation and novelty of the mind's thinkingness, trying
to extract experiencing, you'd be satisfied with having no experience, thoughts, feelings,
or anything about it.
Some of you say, well, what do you feel about that?
I don't have any feeling about it at all.
Feeling about what?
The world's coming to an end.
Oh, oh, yes?
Oh, what do you know about that?
It's not to allow.
SKYPETS
The world's coming to an end.
Alcohol is coming to an end, doesn't it?
God's coming to an end anyway.
It's not a year before 12 anyway.
December 21, 2012.
Pay your bills before then.
The world's always coming to the end.
There's always a guy on the sidewalk with a sandwich board.
Repent.
The world is coming to an end.
And the fact that he comes from the Mayan calendar doesn't give it any more truth than
it does.
firm people. I mean, the world is coming to an end in the year 2012. Oh boy. I got a whole
refrigerator full of pickled herring and I want to eat it. Cramming them down. And then you get
to December 22nd, 2012, and you're not dead. You think, Christ, I ate up all the pickled herring.
Spent all my money. Oh, so if the world doesn't come to an end, that's what you got to worry
about. If the world comes to an end, you'll have no problems. If the world's not coming to an end,
worry about that. Actually, it doesn't make any difference. So all right. So humility then
and mindfulness, you become aware of what your mind is doing. It's always anticipating the future,
trying to get one up on the future, and clinging to it.
And to the past. So therefore, the present moment is ignored because your mind is either clinging to
what just happened, trying to juice it, or it's anticipating what might happen, whether we're all
going to expire in 2021, for instance. So these eventually lead you through mindfulness then,
through divine stupidity, and through choice, then reflection and meditation,
that I'm describing become common. The mind generally focuses on the small self, the ego, on gain,
desire, accepting and rejecting. I like and I don't like. I like and I don't like. I like it and I don't like it.
Somebody say, what do you think of that movie? Frankly, I don't think about it at all.
Frankly, I don't think about it. All right. So these character traits carry you this.
Perseverance.
Perseverance and commitment and acceptance. And the power of declaration, which we haven't spoken about yet.
There is intention. And then there is something beyond even intention that activates intention.
And that is to make a declaration and then live by the declaration.
How many people have made a declaration about the purpose of their life?
Oh, wow. Quite a few. All right. Pretty sophisticated group.
It is.
To declare that one is the servant of God and that one's purpose is to realize the divinity of one's own inner self
and the divinity of Almighty God and to become one with God.
That is a declaration made by, hmm, I hate to ask the number,
declaration made by less than a half of one percent of humanity, less than a quarter of a percent.
A fraction. It's really a fraction of one percent.
Ever reached the evolution of consciousness where they make a declaration that the meaning and purpose of my life
is to serve God, to become one with God, to become enlightened.
And as we said, I think in power versus force, the number of people interested in reaching enlightenment
is less than one in ten million. You know, what do you want to do here in this world?
So these are the spiritual options.
So life in this world is purgatorial in my view of it.
Purgatorial. You don't have to worry about purgatory later. You're here.
What are you doing purgatory? You suffer out bad karma.
And you have the option to choose options for good karma.
Isn't that all purgatory is? So why be afraid of purgatory?
Because you're in it.
You know, if breaking your ankle doesn't hurt, then you'd be in a different place.
In this realm, purgatory, if you break your ankle, it hurts.
Yeah. So, in a celestial realm, you don't have any ankle to break.
The fact that negativity means this, in this world, people bemoan it.
And you have to repeat, this is not a celestial realm. This is not a celestial realm.
As a realm, my inner experience of it, however, can be heavenly.
So, by perseverance, by acceptance, by declaration.
So, declaration is very powerful.
If you declare who you are and the purpose of your life,
you've made a very major impact on what your consciousness is going to be attracted to.
It's going to be attracted to those things that bring about enlightenment.
And it's going to be not attracted.
It doesn't mean, does not mean to have an aversion.
An aversion is something different.
It means you're not attracted to it.
No, I'm differentiating.
To not be attracted is different than aversion.
Because aversion, like attraction, is a trap.
To have neither attraction nor diversion.
But just have no interest in a thing.
So, there's lots of movies that come up and are popular and lots of things on television and all.
That I just don't have an interest in.
I just say, I'm not really interested in that.
When I was 22, I would have been.
Thank God for old age, I tell you.
It solves a lot of problems, folks.
You can't remember who you were mad at.
I knew I was mad at somebody.
I can't remember what I was mad at about.
I was mad at about something.
The level of consciousness, then,
is how you're going to experience the world.
And what you see you do with your personal experience
is what you see happening in society
is to dramatize the story into a narrative.
Usually a poor me or a bad you narrative.
There's a way of describing things now coming out of relativity.
There's no descriptions of relativity.
There's only narratives.
There are only narratives.
And that's the story that your mind makes up about it.
And, of course, the dramatization of it.
To make a bigger impact on others.
All of this comes out of meaning.
What does a thing mean?
And we'll get more into that next time.
Meaning cannot be understood without context.
That's why the cynic, you know, can't get anywhere with reality.
It's because...
What he doesn't see is that it's the meaning,
the significance, the implication,
the non-linear, non-languaged understanding and comprehension.
So all spiritual understanding is revealed in its abstract meaning,
out of which you have an interpretation.
Use various adjectives, inferences, connotations, attitudes, etc.
But those are all elaborations.
It isn't just what happens, the significance, the content, the context.
But what is the meaning of that?
So you could take all of life and you say,
What is interesting about it?
Nothing's really interesting about it except what it means.
If it's lacking meaning, then it's just a passing animal experience.
The animal sees a rubber ball go by.
He sees a cat go by.
But he doesn't get any meaning out of that.
Meaning, what is the meaning?
So our significance then arises from our meaning.
What is the meaning of our existence?
What's the meaning of our existence?
What is the value of existence itself?
Why is it so great to even be a human being?
It would be better to be a kitty and just purr all day.
See a dog and wag its tail and be happy.
What's the meaning?
The mind's proclivity for error.
We got one more slide after this?
Yes.
Go faster.
The mind's proclivity for error.
We mentioned that 50% of blog sites are fallacious.
Don't write me an angry hot letter tonight.
Over 50% of the information in blogger land is fallacious.
Over 50% of all that bloggerism is fallacious to begin with.
Not to mention its intent, which is often vicious, frankly.
This is about what you would expect.
Now, in law courts, you'll find out there's a 50% error in lineup identifications.
You know, these are the possible suspects.
Is this the man you saw on the street?
50% error.
I saw the crime committed by a guy.
Is he this one, this one, this one, this one?
He's this one.
50% likelihood that they will be wrong.
How many guys in the...
Whatchamacallit project have been released from prison?
What's that called?
The Mercy Project or something?
I forget how many.
90 of them, at least, on death row.
And then when the DNA came out, they found that they were on death row, that they were actually innocent.
And most of them were convicted due to a false identification.
So, if you can't even believe your eyes, well, can you believe?
Even your eyes lie to you.
Even your eyes lie to you 50-50.
And bloggerdom is 50-50.
What's going to happen to mankind?
Buried by bloggerism.
Death by bloggerism.
No, go to number four.
I mean the next, last one.
Yeah.
Death by bloggerism.
So, the decline of consciousness of mankind.
We went from 207 back down to 204.
Then the decline of consciousness level of the Western world, which is currently in free fall.
And the decline of consciousness level in America itself.
So, America went from 426 to 421.
Mankind went back down.
He went from 190 to 205.
Then he went to 207.
Now he's back down to 204.
And the Western world is also declining.
Huh?
The reason we can't see what's real is because of bias.
Because of the negativity of the intention.
Because of how you're aligned.
That determines your preferences.
And that determines your attractions and your aversions.
So, I always think if people don't like the things I say, please don't read the book.
Who asked you to read the book?
It says Dio on the first page and he's offended because you're defending God.
Can't you read the first page, you idiot?
So, the intention to disparage truth, divinity, etc. blinds people.
And they end up writing the dumb blogs at 1 a.m.
Naivete. What is real?
Naivete is another downside.
That's overcome by familiarity, interpretation, sophistication.
So many objections.
Many objections to truth are really facetious.
And every once in a while we'll get one.
It's just plain facetious.
Facetious.
You see?
And understanding is also reflective of intelligence.
Intelligence is an overall state.
Not just one's IQ.
Intelligence operationally depends on your education.
How you've been indoctrinated.
How you've been programmed.
So, if you've had the good fortune to have been brought up in a family that respects morality, ethics, etc.
Then you're going to be more aware of when it's out.
Social influence, cultural norms, and expectations depend on many factors.
You see people think, oh, how wonderful my mind is.
Well, what you're thinking has to do with how you were brought up.
Has to do with your neuronal connections.
Has to do with the social class, your sex, your gender.
Political indoctrination, the way you're brought up.
Has to do with the way things are labeled.
Depends on whether they're popular.
And not all depends on the media hype and the glamour.
What is truth in today's world is what people believe because it has been pounded into your head via the media.
Repetitious memes reappear, reappear, reappear.
And therefore, what people believe is true is how they've been indoctrinated.
Cultural norms and expectations.
Labeling, popularity, and how much media hype it gets.
So, in today's world, for media hype, people will sell anything.
Will they not?
Nude pictures of themselves or the most god awful information about their life.
Because it gets you on the daily news.
And I feel sorry for that.
I feel sorry for the people who become victims.
Because you can see they're victims not only of their own egotism, but of all their controllers.
All the people who are getting multi-millions, feeding dispersion to the dogs.
So they really get fed to the dogs for a price.
And those are the social influences.
Intention.
You see how things change.
If you're active.
If you do.
If you inspect things.
If you enjoy them.
Remember them.
Find fault with them.
Criticize them.
Or want to destroy them.
So these all are values coming out of intention.
So if you're trying to extract the truth about something, your intention about it is already interpreting it.
So some of the funny blogs we get, or one of those things you get on the internet machine,
has to do with the person's intention.
To become facetious in order to ridicule something.
And you can see the departure from truth and integrity.
On top of this, there are in our world, diminishers and expanders.
I'm just showing you all the processes, the chances of knowing what is the truth.
We've got four pages of things that can destroy that capacity.
People can generally be divided into minimizers and diministers.
Minimizers and expanders.
Minimizers say, oh.
And expanders say, wow.
Wow, look at that Denmark vendor.
And a diminisher will say, oh, that's nothing.
$50 worth of paint will fix it.
You see?
So you can diminish or expand.
And that's not within one's conscious control.
The mind just automatically tends to do it.
You need to have a mind that depends on your childhood experiences.
Whether spilling milk was a big deal, or it was a minor deal, don't worry about it, I'll mop it up.
Or whether it was a big deal.
So diminishing and expanding then comes from childhood training
of what your parents consider to be emotionally important.
And they do this by dramatizing it, exaggerating it, or minimizing it.
Also how you interpret things depends on your overall mental capacity.
the old Freudian balance of the ego. The Freudian view of the ego is somewhat
different. It has a more positive view of the ego. It sees that as the mental
capacity to balance the id, that's one's emotional animal instincts, and the
superego, which is one's conscience. So in classical Freudian analysis, your ego's
capacity to get away from excessive guilt, excessive guilt, at the same time
not give in to your id, which is just an instinctual animal. You can't run around
raping people. On the other hand, you can't kill yourself because you made a
slight mistake. So the Freudian ego is defined as reality testing, the capacity
for reality testing. Balancing the id, which is a crazy animal and is out to
kill you and everybody else, or the superego, which is punitive. And I think
as I've said, I'm not going to go into too much detail about that, but I think
I've told you, when I was young, I had to go for counseling, for, you know,
scrupulosity. The slightest infraction of truth in my viewpoint was like
unforgivable blot on your soul, and God could see this black spot. So you lived
in dread of having even a passing sinful thought. All right, so generally then, the
capacity for reality testing, the superego, which is an instinctual animal,
capacity for understanding reality is a balance of mental, emotional health, where
you have balance, you have maturity, and unconscious psychological factors, such
as poor self-esteem and things like this. Yep. Whether the absolute reality is
allness or nothingness is a differentiation which we've made in more
advanced lectures. And then we come to the last one, which I don't understand at
all, and therefore I'll explain it to you. And that is, what is the absolute reality?
And that is, what is the absolute reality? And that is, what is the absolute reality?
The so-called quantum Zeno effect. Yeah, x-what is the absolute reality?
Well, the more often an
An absolute reality Ori Magajan
equation is chosen, the more likely the
that
so-called quantum Zeno
The so-called quantum Zeno
x- vertex
the
enser으룪
option
no effect. The more often an option is chosen, the more likely the option will
be chosen again.
So, this has to do with intention and commitment then.
The more often you choose to forgive, the more likely you will be to forgive.
So you get this extract
Even though statistically the options are mathematically the same, length of time
the same, the likelihood is that consciousness, because of its own nature, because you choose
a certain option, you are more likely to choose that option again.
So the more often you choose a benign option, a benign way, you say, well, I could be seeing
this such and such.
So if you get into a negative thought or a negative fix, you ask yourself, well, how
could I be seeing this?
And of course, that's part of the Course in Miracles, and one reason it works.
You ask the Holy Spirit to recontextualize it so you see it differently, so you see it
through the eyes of forgiveness, and you see that whatever you're upset about is because
you've stopped time at some particular point, and when you expand it beyond that particular
point and you see it's sort of an evolutionary revelation, you see the innocence of what
you were just upset about.
So what you're really asking God to do is to recontextualize.
The way you're experiencing and comprehending a situation, and that takes you out of right
and wrong and condemnation of yourself and others, and that takes you out of guilt and
anger and hatred.
So the recontextualization then is done as an option because that's your commitment to
be that way.
Now another person doesn't, you know, another person who is not spiritually oriented just
sees something and hates it.
It feels justified, and that's okay with them.
But as you grow spiritually, the negatives are no longer so pleasantly tolerated.
Now you find they're not welcome anymore.
It's like you're used to beautiful music, and some awful music comes on, and you're
used to beauty now.
The worst music in the world is on the Weather Channel.
If you want to do something to help God and humanity, write the Weather Channel.
They have the worst God-awful.
Disharmonic, harmonious music I've ever heard.
I'll say this to them, turn it down, I can't stand the music.
They have the unhearing ear for bad, bad music.
Anyway, we'll forgive them because after all, the only reason we're looking at it is to
find out if it's going to rain on the day of the lecture anyway.
And our intention must be okay because so far we've had good weather.
And we've given altogether about 50 all-day lectures locally since 2002.
We've given another 40 of them or so elsewhere in the world.
So we'll be approaching, we'll have given maybe before long 100 all-day lectures, including
descriptions, slides, lectures, explanations, and sharing oneself to the best of one's ability.
So that is one's, that comes out of one's declaration of one's intention.
Which is the same intention I had as a physician because I practiced medicine for 50 years.
And that was to be helpful in every way that you could to the people entrusted to your care
because you know you're answerable to God for what you did with this person.
You know that you're answerable to God.
And so to be answerable to God for one's life then almost guarantees spiritual purification.
Really?
realize that you're dedicated to God and that you're answerable to God, then you become
very aligned with truth and integrity.
The people that are dangerous in this world are ones who do not believe they're answerable
to God.
They're dangerous, yeah.
And you can trust people who realize, accept, I'm answerable to God.
So that is a constant state during these lectures, and I realize I'm answerable to God for any
error I make.
I'm scared to death of making an error.
So you take responsibility for the truth of what you teach others, and people who won't
take responsibility for the truth of their own teaching are very dangerous.
But to be responsible.
So I accept responsibility for the truth of all I have conveyed, and I accept responsibility
if I have made any errors, because I've done them unwittingly.
So I feel the teacher should recommit his devotion to the truth and to his students
and restate what his commitment is, what the commitment of his life is.
So as each one of us does that by declaration, then.
We become responsible.
We become that, which counterbalances the negativity of the world.
Because how many people are willing to do that?
Only a group like this is willing to really stake your answerability to God for the integrity
by which you do your life.
It doesn't mean you can't make a mistake, but it was an honest mistake.
And even if it was not an honest mistake, you then admit that it was not an honest mistake.
I contrive that.
In order to feel sorry for myself.
I make everybody else look bad, you see.
So even then, the truth gets you out of a falsehood, out of an error, by telling the
truth about it.
You say, well, my ego just wanted to be right about it, I guess.
And I mean, the Weather Channel does that bad music.
I don't know, I remember the director of music there, I don't know, would never have passed
the seashore music ability test with, I don't know, I never would have made it.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's see our last slide.
I'm going to shut them up otherwise.
Ah!
God, this comes from my wonderful editor.
She found this somewhere out there in blogger land or internet land, WW internet world.
And I think it's so wonderful.
So I may not have gotten it across verbally, one of the questions in the last lecture,
she said, I said, oh my God, I have missed completely.
Making the difference between appearance and essence.
What percentage of politicians, let's ask something about politicians.
The majority of the politicians lie routinely.
It's part of their job.
Therefore, please don't quote a politician as the source of authority.
The politician is supposed to make things work by whatever means, you understand?
His commitment is not a spiritual one.
So there's no point in making a politician wrong.
He has to make the thing work by whatever means he can to make it work, see?
And if he tells everybody, if they do it this way, this is going to happen, everybody's
going to do it.
And as far as he sees, he's fulfilling the good and the good is the fulfillment of a
certain specified objective.
So a spiritual person has a different whole set of what is integrous, what is truth, what
is honesty and what is reality.
But isn't that adorable?
Yeah.
Well, I just get such a kick out of that, see?
And the reason I emphasize this so much is because I was surprised when we calibrated
Wolf and Sheep's clothing.
I was surprised.
It only came out at 120.
I said, wow, that's worse than I thought.
Because a lot of political bullshit is, calibrates at 190.
I thought, well, it's going to be 190 coming out of prideful egotism, et cetera.
No, it came out at 120.
Which 120 then means.
That it is the hiding place of evil itself, that what you're looking at is evil.
That's why 120.
So that's why it's so important to become sophisticated and realize essence is one thing,
perception is another.
This calibrates at 120.
I just think that's very, very significant.
So it's a serious error, see?
It's not just a minor one to be, to misperceive.
To take advantage of it.
It's a serious error.
It's not just a minor one.
I think that the Komodo dragon is safe because you're a humanitarian, you love all of nature,
blah, blah, blah.
Doesn't mean you can step in the cage with it.
So the downside of Western civilization is it's lost that capacity.
We have to be nice to all the Komodo dragons and invite them here.
Because they're just nice animals.
Just nice animals.
So that error is quite severe at 120.
Therefore, I thought this.
This teaches in one glance, you know, what it would take a number of lectures to get
across to many people.
I myself have been deceived by the sheep's clothing.
Anybody else here ever been deceived by the sheep's clothing?
All right.
So I think, I thought one picture is worth a thousand words.
And that's why we brought it to people's awareness.
Yeah.
And so, now let's see.
Where are we on time?
I get you to watch.