song.
I'm greatly honored by your presence.
Now, today uh is a review and we put it
on for the many people who've tried to
get into lectures and couldn't. They
were always booked up in advance. So,
this one was restricted to just new
people and um and some sneaker iners.
>> Well, we're going to go do a fast review
of the whole work and uh emphasize some
things that are important in today's
world.
Some things that are important about the
work itself. I have to have respect. I
have respect for the work itself. You
see these things occur spontaneously
including the discovery of what this
work is all about and and what it's
based on uh it came as a gift. So I have
respect for the gift and feeling a
responsibility to the gift to explain it
to the best of my capacity
uh because of its rather obvious and
intrinsic value.
Its obvious and intrinsic value is so
stunning that very few people get it.
I So I wear myself out trying to explain
and make obvious the obvious,
which we'll do again today.
Yeah, you can put up the first slide and
if I'm not standing in the way, it'll
shine on the I am standing in the way.
Well, that's all right. You don't need
to see it anyway.
It's just for my comfort.
Anyway, uh intrinsically what the world
is what what the work is about is um the
capacity to tell truth from falsehood,
appearance from essence which has never
occurred in the history of mankind
and the lack of which is responsible
I would say for the totality of human
suffering
because even if a rock falls on you and
crushes you to death.
That's not really a problem if you
surrender to it.
It's your clinging clinging to
physicality that creates the suffering.
I don't want to go yet. Well, well,
you're leaving. Bye.
The absolute surrender to the phen
seemingly phenomenal reality as it
unfolds.
And so
I can't think of anything uh that I'd
want to know other than how do you know
everything.
Today we're going to tell you how to
know anything about everything.
Let's see how many people got it in the
audience.
Uh, we have permission. This is more
than 20% got it. Wow. More than 30% got
it. Wow. More than 50% got it. Wow.
49% got it. 50% got it. Oh jeez.
Yeah. that the work is not
comprehensible to the intellect except
through uh I would say advances in
quantum mechanics which we'll review the
Eisenberg principle and the principles
of quantum mechanics. So we can outline
a scientific understanding of it but
that's really beside the point. The
point is that consciousness an intrinsic
quality of consciousness is that it
instantly knows the difference between
truth and falsehood.
Now what when we calibrate things what
we're consulting is an infinite field
with no beginning no end no dimension
outside of time. Therefore when we ask a
question we're asking it outside of time
and location
in the infinite everythingness of the
radiance of divinity is it shown forth
as consciousness.
whose consciousness that illuminated and
brought forth life.
In that which is infinite there is no
middle. In that which is infinite there
is no beginning. In the infinite there
is no end. Therefore there is no no
sequence. There is no then or now. There
is no future or past.
There is no here or there.
Consequently,
everything that is is right here this
instant in the foreverness of the
reality of the present. Huh?
Consequently, whether I ask about
Cleopatra or I ask about Mrs. Clinton,
it's all the same. It's all the same.
There is no difference in time between
the two of them. All time is now.
Everywhere is here.
Consequently, right here and now, I have
access to all that ever has been.
Wow. Wrap around that one.
completely understandable from quantum
mechanics which we'll get to later in
the references which is now out in a
book a very expensive book but
nevertheless in a book
the quantum mechanics. So what we're
going to do when we when we calibrate
something
when we calibrate something then it's
really based on the quantum Heisenberg
principle of going from the potential of
the shredding equations to the actuality
by collapsing the wave function and what
collapses the wave function is that a
thing has reality. If I pose a question
to her arm and ask her to resist that
that has no reality
then because I have supplied nothing
happens. If I make a statement that has
a concordant reality, it then has the
power to collapse the wave function from
potentiality to actuality from the wave
from the wave which is really a
mathematical
uh mathematical
nature uh to the actuality.
So
the bridge between traditional science
and logic and reason and in our work is
really via the Heisenberg principle
where you bring potentiality into
actuality by posing to consciousness the
infinite field whether a thing is or is
not. So in the kinesis in the in the
response that we use it's not a yes or a
no. It's a yes or a not yes.
So the strength of her arm then is like
with truth it's like electricity going
down to the going down the wire and her
arm goes strong.
With falsehood there's no electricity
going down the wire. Therefore arm does
not go strong. So there is no such thing
as knowness in the universe. You can't
send none electricity down a wire.
It's either on or it's not on. So that
simplifies the intellectual
understanding.
All right.
Any questions about that? Simple enough,
right?
I can't see you out there anyway. So
if I don't call on you because I can't
see anyway. So all right. So then
uh the phenomena was witnessed uh many
years ago that that which is true or
strong that which is good for you if
held near your solar plexus will make
your arm go strong if you press down on
it. That which is poisonous or anti-life
or false your arm will go weak. So
you know that's simple.
Then we ended up uh with a scale a scale
calibrating at 1 to a th00and it's
calibrating it to 1 to a,000
uh denotes relative truth. So
the scale of consciousness uh it goes
from the lowest denominator the amoeba
let's say uh on up to Sir Isaac Newton
and Einstein and great genius and then
up to the great spiritual teachers
throughout history. So
we started it at one.
I started at one. That's just the
emergence of life in its lowest level
and said that the top of the scale would
be the greatest beings who've ever
lived. And they turned out to be the
great avatars, Jesus Christ and Buddha
and Zoroastra.
And they calibrated at a thousand. So
everything can be
stratified somewhere along a scale from
1 to a,000.
uh of relative truth and level of
consciousness.
So the scale that we use is just sort of
like a barometer like a barometer and um
it just gives us a number. It gives us a
number. However, these numbers correlate
with human experience throughout time
and uh we find that this is very very
consistent and uh is ratified every time
we uh use the system. Uh that there are
stratified levels of consciousness
uh and they are very very crucially
important
because they determine success or
failure, happiness or unhappiness.
And therefore
we we call these various levels here. Uh
the highest level is enlightenment and
600 and up are the levels of peace. Now
when you hit 600, you know it because
you bliss out. If you don't care if you
ever get off off the rock and the body
falls over, you know you're at 600.
A state of infinite bliss and infinite
peace. And it's a glimpse of the
eternal. At 600, you are aware of the
infinite, the infinity of God's love.
And
it's very tempting to leave the world.
And half the people who hit 600 uh leave
the world. So there are very few people
on the planet at any one time at the top
of the scale. And one of the reasons is
50% of the people when they hit 600
leave. And that's true at each higher
level. As you go up, half these people
leave, half these people leave, and
therefore there's seldom more than a
couple of people on the planet. However,
because these are logarithmic numbers,
uh the the power is enormous. So to
counterbalance, as we'll see later, all
of mankind, you only need really
relatively few people near the top to
counterbalance the rest of negativity.
All right. These various levels have
psychiatric, psychological, emotional
nominalizations.
We see below the level of 200 then um is
the major it defines really two
different uh populations.
The population above and below 200 are
very very different. Very different.
They don't think alike. They don't feel
the same. They don't have the same
values. They don't have the same
capacity.
And what is the uh the reality impaired
is what Lou calls them. The reality
impaired. Yeah. Uh so anyway, we we
notice that it the level of 200 is the
capacity to tell the truth. And then
above that we call neutrality. And
neutrality is very comfortable. It's
okay if things go this way. It's okay if
they go that way. Willingness is even
higher. They let let's pitch in and
acceptance is an even higher one. And
then you get to reason. These are all
willingness and these are emotion
uh and motivation. But then you have to
add reason. And then beyond that the
400s of the logic is love and then comes
joy and then peace and the higher levels
are are like ecstasy. ecstasy and joy
and then profound and infinite exquisite
peace.
Below 200 is where all the troubles of
the world and all human suffering comes
from. All human suffering comes from
consciousness levels 200 and below.
Throughout all of history and in today's
world and everyday's uh Fox News or
whatever they are.
Anyway, so here we have a lot of cont.
Here's where most of the political
contention comes in about 170 to 190 uh
or 150 160. Most political contention is
coming right here. See? Uh
so there's pride. Then under there is
anger, desire and cravingness, fear,
grief, apathy, guilt and shame. So these
are levels uh and they're accompanied by
emotions.
The way to shut off the mind is to let
go of its cravingness, desiringness.
The mind is the ego is like greedy for
sensation,
for symbols, images and have something
to do. Uhhuh. So
we say these are levels of inflation.
People are puffed up with pride and
these are levels of aggression etc. And
then finally you get down into
depression and apathy etc.
The lowest human we've calibrated so far
is that his named Cho CHO
shot up 32 people or something and went
on all day a TV thing he calibrated at
five right that's about as low as we've
seen. Huh?
All right. So these levels then are
these are the levels that are negative
and of course there's a major shift in
brain function and brain physiology.
All right let's uh move to the the view.
Yes. Okay. I was just going to say
something. You chopped me off.
Okay. We forgot God. Yeah is
I heard you.
All I heard was H.
Oh yeah. Oh yeah.
The big guy. Oh yeah.
All right. So you see in the lower
levels, people are indifferent to it.
They're atheistic. Uh they even hate
God, deny God, or view God as very
punitive and primitive, which is easy to
fall into.
very easy to see God as punitive because
early man didn't understand that sort of
nature. And so here's how the negative
views of God which are still quite
prevalent by the way negative views of
God is jealous, angry, uh punitive and
he's going to get evil with even with
you and throw you into hell etc.
So ancient man saw the disasters of
nature, earthquakes and floods and
tsunamis and
and assumed the gods must be angry.
Wouldn't you? If you were a primitive,
you hear the volcano, the smoke starts
shooting out, lava comes down
or a great tsunami sweeps over, flood
and pestilence.
So the primitive mind felt the gods must
be angry and therefore call for
sacrifice.
Sacrifice to the gods is characteristic
of all ancient and primitive religions.
Some it became predominant in Mayan
religion etc. They're always taking some
young maiden and tearing her heart out
and holding it up to the crowd who cheer
it on. Oh here anyway makes me faint to
think of it.
So the idea was to pacify this horrible
god, this angry god,
the god of angry, anger and vengeance,
the p god of primitivism. Uh so we are
still trying to plate them, are we not?
We're going to sacrifice innocent people
to make God uh happy. Uh we will blow
them up out of off the planet and that
will make God happy and then we will go
to heaven. Uhhuh.
So the angry God we're still trying to
plate.
So God here is seen as here uh vengeful.
Uh vengeance is mine said the Lord.
Okay. And punitive, uncaring,
condemning, vindictive.
Gets even with you. Oh boy. Whoa. That's
scary. I I wouldn't commit any sins at
all if I was going thought God was going
to get even with me.
That's why I spent my youth scared to
death of sin.
Scared to death of sin. All right. Here
God is seems to be the source of your
capacity to be inspirational. Here God
is merciful, wise, loving, oneness, all
beingness and not different than that
the self of that which you are. God you
know is imminent as well as
transcendent.
uh God is imminent as well as
So which one of these is true? It seems
to you it depends on your own level of
consciousness.
All right. So that's enough of that.
We'll go to the next lecture, next
charge chart.
Uh the enlightened divine states
uh this calibrates at infinite. The
supreme godhead is infinite and the
archangels calibrate 600,000 and up. Uh
Christ, Buddhahood, Krishna, Brahman all
calibrated at 1,000. So avatar.
So this is divinity expressed within the
human domain by incarnation. So Jesus
Christ is is God incarnate. Incarnate.
All right.
Uh
Then we come down and we see the various
uh levels uh of enlightenment and you
see yourself as not different than
existence the quality of existence
itself.
Uh
I as the divinity and allness. So
spiritual progress moves from the self
with a small s which is the ego to the
self with a large s. And it's the self
with the large s that we become more
interested in than the small self. The
small self is limited in time and the
infinite self is unlimited in time.
That which is infinite is capable of
being experienced at both the top and
the bottom of the chart.
I first experienced it
uh at the top in the snowbank. I fell in
the snowbank and went into a state of
infinite infinite presence beyond all
time.
Infinite love beyond all description.
Later in life, I went to the bottom.
I forget what brought that on. Anyway,
whatever brought around
uh I decided I would go for it and I
went to the depths of the psyche and
again emerged into an infinite state
infinite beyond all time and that was
hell. The infinity the everythingness
allness of and the hopelessness of hell
is also experienced as as an eternity.
eternity of hopelessness and hell. Yeah.
Anyway, you don't want to go there at
all, you know.
All right. So, all right. Let's move on
to the next one. We're all aware of
them. This is this is the energy level.
Uh the higher the level of uh
consciousness, the greater the power.
And it was uh this is done by one of our
students and he who calibrated who's
into mathematics who calibrated the
relative power in microwatts
relative correlation in microwatts.
So
uh only one person on the planet is all
you need. You know like 900 or 850 or a
th00and all you need is one here. Okay
to counterbalance all the rest of it.
All right so let's look at the next and
see how that works.
Uh, this is all of mankind.
78% of the world's population
is below 200. Let's see if that's still
true.
That tends to vary. I think it's worth
now. Uh, we have permission to ask this.
More than 78% is below 200 now. No, it's
still at 78%. Huh. Great.
Great. Grad. All right.
Uh so anyway, the great, you know, as
far as population, numbers of
population, the great majority are of
mankind are here. And as you see, as you
move on up, uh they become fewer and
fewer.
This is the level that we work with the
most. People in the 400s uh uh are on
their way to enlightenment and they have
capacity for the intellect to
understand, etc.
And uh so there all right we can move on
to the next one
and and this is another another way of
explaining it that's all uh to
understand uh human history then and the
current current history current uh life
uh world worldly events are
comprehensible if you realize that
there's
the minority are capable of being
integrous and ethical and wanting to
know the truth for its own sake. rather
than being inflating their ego and
holding on to a position or an opinion
or winning fame, becoming famous and
rich and famous and powerful.
So there's only 22% of the population
then. So this whole population then uh
depends depends on these people here.
Yeah. Okay. We'll move to the next. And
this is how how they depend
uh
these few here their power is sufficient
that it counterbalances
uh the mass of mankind. All right. So
that's a function one just serves uh as
a consequent as a consequence of that
which you have become. People say, "What
can we do to make the world better?" And
I tell them, you know, worry about
yourself.
You become the greatest that you can be.
It's what you are that influences all of
mankind, not what you do. All kinds of
people are doing all kinds of things.
And it's so what?
It's what you are then uh is what lifts
the level of the sea. And when you lift
the level of the sea, you lift all the
ships upon the sea. So each one of us
here who struggles to advance our
consciousness, become more enlightened,
become more unconditionally loving, etc.
Uh is serving mankind.
So you can really serve mankind
staying in a closet and not causing
trouble out there.
Doing more good meditating in a closet
than you are in the nearest peace parade
which are always too dangerous. I never
go to them.
Okay, next one.
Oh yes. And this is the bin. This is the
level of consciousness over elapsed
time. You see um percent of elapsed
time. And you see here we we presumed uh
we presumed that this was going to
continue up. And then the last couple of
years it suddenly took a downtrend.
Mankind went from total
uh it went down to 204. Let's see. So
let's just review history. I have
permission to ask this. Uh, mankind was
up to 207,
208, 207. All right. Mankind now came
down to 204. Was this 203? 204. So, we
went from 207 to 204. So, that isn't
what I thought was going to happen, but
that just showed you how wrong you can
be.
Okay, smarty. See? Okay.
Yes. I thought it was going to go up. uh
but it may follow more the way the
evolution of consciousness has on the
planet which tends to dip up and down
over great periods of time as expressed
through the various life forms. So we'll
move on then to the next say and these
are the uh epics
uh earth epics and calibrations thereof
and um h well let's see I don't think I
can see anything over there
oh
you guys can read it it's uh interesting
you know it just shows the great the
very ancient you know the ages of the uh
three and a half billion years ago three
and a half billion years ago etc. So
this is very very ancient uh time and
you see the level of consciousness that
prevailed on the planet on the planet at
that time. So you have the emergence of
protozoa. Now here you have the
beginning of algae algae and lychans and
things like that. And then life becomes
more evolved and more complicated.
And so you see the progression over the
eons archaeologic
uh eras. Yes. Next one.
uh and this is paralleled by the
emergence in the animal kingdom and uh
where life begins then bacteria prozoa
etc and it's very very simple
and what's important about this is for
life to survive see the light of
divinity shown forth as it says in gen
Genesis and consciousness when it
interacts with matter emerges as life
huh
Yeah. So life originates
from consciousness.
Life originates from as a consequence of
consciousness. Resist. As a consequence
of consciousness,
life emerges. So much for bottomup
theories
that that it's all mechanical.
Uh
so we have the lowest forms of life and
of course what was important for them
and what what is the most important
thing for our work in consciousness
research etc is that the the early life
form had to be able to differentiate
uh truth from falsehood.
It had to be able to differentiate that
which is pro-life from that which is
anti-life.
If you can't tell what is poison and
what is not poison then you don't uh
survive. So be because of the these
survived they learned how to tell truth
from falsehood. If a thing smells or
looks or
has a molecular effect on your tongue in
a certain way if you eat that you will
die. So in order to survive you have to
know friend from foe. You have to know
poison from nutrition.
So that's one of the basic things of
consciousness.
So when I hold out her arm and when she
holds out her arm, I'm doing what the
amoeba did.
This is good to eat.
If you made a mistake, he didn't exist
any longer.
So he had to be able to differentiate
between truth from falsehood, that which
is pro-life, that which is anti-life. So
truth is pro-life, falsehood is
anti-life. Uhhuh.
And these each one of these is a very
interesting uh study in itself. I was an
entomologist when I was young and I was
very interested in all these areas. And
here we have the wonderful octopus and
the marvelous sharks
and the famous komodo dragon.
I just want to remind people that
uh singing come by and having picnic
with a with a kimono dragon won't help
you much.
Come by.
What is that that you've got underneath
your belt?
Oh, it's a bomb to blow us all up with.
You cannot be uh stupid. All right. So
there's the difference between being
spiritually forgiving, compassionate,
etc. and being stupid.
Well, there are stupid people out there
saying come by with an ear komodo
dragon.
They forget the nature of reptiles.
Nature of reptiles and dinosaurs. Yeah.
They forget that a predatory mammal is
it's neither good nor evil. He can only
live by eating others. He can only live
by eating others. The lion and the tiger
and of course the mountain lion. The
mountain lion bicycling in the mountains
of California
uh
can bring your life to a quick end.
Yeah.
I only saw one uh mountain lion locally.
He was going down 89A.
alongside the fence and then and the
highway side of the fence with this
mountain line and he was just going
along minding his own business, not
causing anybody any problem.
All right. So then we've learned about
snakes. We've learned about venom. We've
learned about and then we get to the
whales and the dolphins and the
migratory birds. You see the evolution
of consciousness more and more
complicated.
And then we get up to the rhinoceros.
Uh song birds and doves.
I don't I don't believe in dove dove
hunting. I don't believe in dove
hunting.
First of all, what the dove symbolizes.
It seems like every time you kill a
dove, you're negating what the dove
stands for.
The dove of peace. Bum.
What are you going to do with the dove
of peace? We're going to eat them.
You're going to eat them. Get away.
go to Walmarts, buy some hamburger, you
know,
polar bears, who we're all fascinated
with and have a difficult life if you
ask me. I just wouldn't like the life of
a polar bear at all. And black bears who
I've seen around here and they minded
their own business. And the wolves, of
course, the hippopotamus. And they say
the hippopotamus kills more people than
anybody. He just squashes them, I guess.
Then we get to the benign. We get to the
grazers, the zebra, the deer, the bison,
uh the elk. Yeah. And we get to the
dairy cows. And we get to sheep. So here
you see they're all herbivores
and they do not live by killing others.
Yeah. Then we get to the cat, which is
both together. And we get to the family
cat. And there's a new cat on here.
What's the name of that cat? Wonderful
cat that can tell when you're going to
leave this planet within four hours.
Oscar.
Oscar. I think Oscar. Let's see. Os. We
I forgot what Oscar was at. Oscar's at
250. 255. No, he's only 250. Yeah. He's
just a plain old cat. Well,
I wouldn't want him around the house,
you know.
Oh, it says family cat 245 and Oscar's
at 250. Oh, I see. So, he does have
another uh 5% there. Yeah, Oscar is at
250. Uh and they're tracking him. He's
up to number 26, I think. And then you
have the dogs and the family dog. And uh
uh and then the gray parrot uh you know,
Alex, the gray parrot died this week. Oh
Lord, God bless Boral Malik.
Very famous great parrot. And uh the
thing that that intrigued me about him
was that uh that he was training other
parrots to talk and he would train them
to talk and if they used incorrect
English or pronounce things wrong, he
would correct them.
They said protein and said he'd say
pretty pretty. Oh, pretty pretty pretty
not pretty, pretty pretty.
So, that was a very famous parrot and it
sort of all these people grab our heart,
don't they? I mean, like Al when Alex
died, you know, everybody sort of
grieved it, you know. It's like these
famous animals, we take them into our
hearts somehow uh through our own
lovingness.
And of course, here's one that's a
favorite of everyone. uh Coco and the
song bird song at 500. The kitty's purr
and the dog's wagging tail at 500 we
know has the capacity to heal heal
people. When people are sick, I always
ask them especially when they're
depressed. Do you have a dog or a cat?
No. I say, well, if you want me to treat
you, you got to get one or the other
because you got to be something
interested in something other than
looking in the mirror and checking how
you are today.
The caringness for another. So they're
important in raising children. First
thing we do is give them the
responsibility of caring for the pets
and that way they learn cleanliness and
love and compassion. Caring for others.
Yeah. And then you derive a joy from
that. Okay. So that's the animal
kingdom. Uh which I've always loved.
I've always loved the animal kingdom and
it's had a bunch of different kinds of
animals over the years. Okay, we'll go
move to the next one.
All right. So, we come on up through the
300s, which is willingness and, uh,
enthusiasm.
Willingness and enthusiasm. The 300s are
very, very powerful. They energize all
the rescue workers, uh, rescue divers,
firemen,
policemen,
uh, volunteers.
It's a very powerful realm. It's uh
enthusiasm and commitment and
dedication. So the 300s are extremely
powerful.
The 400s just add another layer and that
is the intellectual. So life evolved
became more and more complex. the
capacity to track it then in a linear
dimension uh has to do with the cerebral
cortex and the cerebral cortex
calibrates much higher than does the
animal brain. So the prefrontal cortex
in and of itself only calibrates at 200
but that's just because it's protoplasm.
That's what it calibrates as protoplasm.
Its capacities are to go into the 400s.
These are the great minds uh throughout
uh you know trai western culture and uh
we don't have th all those from the
orient but those that are these are
readily available in our traditional
course of study uh it's a 10 year
10-year program to do the great books of
the western world and um I recommend it
to anyone whether they've uh had a
formal education or not because whatever
you did study you have sort of forgotten
the beauty and wonder of it and as you
begin reading this you you get a re re
uh uh reenthused about the incredible
beauty. So the intellect itself has in
has its own intrinsic beauty. The beauty
of logic and reason and
the great marvelous uh things that have
come out of the 400s of course science
modern science uh physics etc. All
coming out of the 400s
what what is uh interesting there we
have great names of history we have uh
St. Thomas Aquinus, we have Augustine,
we have Aristotle
and Plato, Sir Francis Bacon,
uh Shasser, Capernicus
and Dante's Dante's Inferno. Uh we have
Charles Darwin,
Decart who have played such a critical
part part in understanding the
difference between truth and falsehood.
Um
these are the great names and um Freud
at 499
uh who I'm very familiar with and
Galileo look at all the great names of
history. Uh these are the great beings
of all time you know to whom we owe
modern civilization.
Therefore they are due uh respect
because each one is author an authority
within their own realm. We have the
great Shakespeare. We have Adam Smith.
We have the the intellectual basis of
capitalism. The intellectual basis of
capitalism.
Intellectual basis of capitalism. You
don't have to get up. Yeah. Calibrates
over 440 445.
the intellectual basis of capitalism
calibrates at 440. Uh uh
uh out of it arose uh the the whole
economic structure of western the
western world
and um therefore it's worthy of respect
in its calibration level of 440 tells
you that and then oddly in the midst of
all this but apparently for historical
reasons uh you see Carl Marx at 130 he's
sort of in the wrong pew. too, but
he's in the wrong view. So you see
what evol way to tell what a thing is is
what comes from its branches. Out of
this came the intellectual
grandeur grand grand intellectual
expressions of western world and western
education.
Uh out of that came the great
universities.
uh in Karl Marx at 130 what came out of
Karl Marx
u the death of tens of millions it's
been tried over and over again tried in
China cost 30 million lives everywhere
you try this Marxian dialectic
dialectical materialism you'll find it's
based on faulty logic yeah if it was
based on truth all those would become
thriving wonderful societies you know.
All right. So, anyway, that tends to
bring down the whole level. If you
remove uh this one, then the level
of all of them together jumps up. Okay,
we move on. Um this has to do with um
essence and uh content.
Um the linear versus the nonlinear.
Now
what we do with consciousness
calibration is we discern the difference
between essence essence and uh and
appearance
and we're looking and this depends on
context. So to understand an event,
here's an event.
In order to comprehend the truth of it,
you have to know what is the context.
What were the circumstances? That's the
approximate context and what is the
ultimate context out of which this is to
be understood. So you can't understand
truth unless you understand
uh not only the content by the but the
context.
So enormous amounts political jabbering
goes on uh all based on the convenience
of ignoring context.
You can get into all kinds of make
wrongs if you just go with this and
ignore uh both the approximate and the
infinite context. U the more
sophisticated person wants to know uh
what were the prevailing conditions. One
of the prevailing conditions is the
belief systems of mankind at the time.
The prevailing level of consciousness of
mankind at the time. Uh
Singapore calibrates at 440.
America calibrates at 421.
All right. So
chewing gum on the sidewalk
is illegal.
Is that right or wrong?
depends on whether you're in Singapore.
If it's in Singapore, it'll get you a
$50 ticket.
If you're in New York City, it's not a
not a crime.
So, how can you say chewing gum is legal
or illegal, sinful,
selfish,
antisocial? Is chewing gum antisocial?
Who think is antisocial?
You're in if you're in Singapore, it is
antisocial. You're breaking the law.
People spit their gum on the sidewalk
and you go, "Yeah, everybody's got gum
on their shoe." It shows a complete
disregard for other people, does it not?
So to understand then, it's against the
law to chew gum in public, you got to
know where you are. New York City, it's
okay. Singapore, it is not okay.
Singapore is not okay. Singapore
calibrates at 440.
Singapore doesn't have a drug problem.
Do drugs in Singapore, you're executed
tomorrow morning. It's simple.
What's the problem?
So you see, when things are absolute,
how people respect them, and when you're
wishy-washy,
they violate them.
So the loss of integrity then
sovereignty
uh is important for a country to
maintain its sovereignty. If you want
the allegiance of the public, you have
to establish and guard your sovereignty.
What if you don't respect your own
sovereignty? No one else will. They'll
just walk across your borders and etc.
They don't care anything about you. Uh
because you don't respect yourself. All
right. So it depends on the context to
understand anything in history or the
current political world especially
current current events you have to know
uh what is the approximate what are the
prevailing conditions that directly
influence the thing and what's the
overall context. What's the overall
context?
So if the overall context is to live in
harmony with your fellow human beings,
you respect the law because it's the way
harmony is expressed in this society and
legal language. Okay, we move on to the
next one. Oh yes,
we mentioned this uh before
uh to try and understand the response.
Uh truth makes the body go strong and
falsehood makes it go weak. And this
starts in the amoeba. The amoeba knows
that which is true, that which is good,
which is nutritious and it makes you go
strong. And it finds out that which is
false.
It has to be able to differentiate the
two. So this is a reflection of the
nature of consciousness itself.
And um this um current uh let's see
the current uh book that's best on it is
now published. Henry Stap Oh yes, I
couldn't see it. Henry Stap's book. Uh
it was available online for nothing and
now it's printed out. Printed out.
Mindful universe. That's the name of it.
Mindful universe which calibrates
probably 450 or something at least.
Let's see what mindful universe
calibrates over 450 460
455 460 that's good enough all right
that's intellectual integrity
that's as far as quantum mechanics goes
so
uh what we explained was uh the
potential becomes actual when you
introduce consciousness
uh you collapse the wave function you go
from the the shreddinger equations which
are both time dependent and time
independent tells you the original
condition
then
through the vonoyman process
uh you can collapse the wave function
and now you can calculate it via the
direct equations and this is called the
vonoyman process
all right so you go from one state to
the next state so
the universe moves and evol solution
occurs because a potential becomes an
actual when you collapse the wave
function. The wave function is a
mathematical
uh statement. It has no existent
reality.
The beginning of this was the discovery
by Maxwell that light travels in both
waves and in packets packets of energy
packets and and and waves. So the wave
function then collapses to
uh an actuality
as a consequence of a field and the
field of intention. So the intention
then is what makes things collapse the
wave function and this is how um the
universe gets created and evolves
because the infinite the power of the
level of consciousness
collapses the wave function and the
power of divinity is omnipotent. The
divinity is omnipresent omnition and omn
omnipotent. The infinite power of divine
consciousness means that the entire
universe evolves as a consequence of
potentiality emerging as actuality.
And as your own level of consciousness
evolves, you begin to see that's how
things come about
uh you stop thinking in terms of
causality of this causing it that.
Instead, what you what you witness now
is the constant emergence.
You see the emergence of potentiality
actualizing,
but you don't see like in the Newtonian
dimension a cause and effect. Now, what
makes these two hands go up there? You
see, I have no idea. They just did it by
themselves. I didn't ask them do it.
They just did it, didn't they? I can
jump back to egotism and say, "Well, I
decided to do that." Yes. Well, let
let's see. We'll go back through your
thought processes and see anywhere. Did
you decide in the middle of a lecture to
put both your hands in the air?
No.
The ego will jump in and say yes.
The ego will jump in and say yes. Oh
yes, I must have decided that. But as
the ego dissolves, you realize these
things are all happening spontaneously.
And you're just being dumb, taking
credit for it if it turns out good and
stupid if you blame yourself that it
didn't.
They don't have anything to do with
credit or discredit. The phenomena
happen happen uh spontaneously as a
consequence of potentiality
manifesting as actuality
because the level because consciousness
itself is collapsing the wave function
from potentiality into actuality.
Now you can stop in the middle of it,
pull off the side of the road and get
out your computer and do the direct
equations and the shading equations on
it
or not.
The way you experience it is you say,
"Hey, look, they got corn in the cow for
sale." You pull over.
It's happened before you decide it. You
know, maybe you can interject. Well,
we've already got some at home, but
that's static. That's static. Thinking
this is usually static. Static. Well,
we've got too much corn home. Oh, well,
there won't be any. It'll be all gone.
It's Labor Day. There won't be any more
corn. So,
uh, so anyway, Steph does as good a job
of explaining it as I've read. His new
book is a little more than you really
want to know about it.
Einstein on the other hand stopped at a
certain level and was skeptical of the
role of consciousness
um preferred to think that there is an
existent universe independent of
consciousness.
Staff's work refutes that um it's it is
consciousness itself out of which the
man which the entire universe manifests.
Without consciousness,
there would be no way for potentiality
to actualize. Actualize.
Einstein at 499.
Now, we can understand people
what they're expressing is where they
are at a certain level of consciousness.
It's not necessary to either praise them
or condemn them.
I don't have to go, "Oh, Einstein, wow,
wow, wow." Or I don't have to write a
book that Einstein is a fraud.
I've already mentioned there's a guy in
Phoenix written three or four books that
Einstein is a fraud.
How he explains the atomic bomb in
Nagasaki and Hiroshima. I don't know.
That would pretty much eliminate that he
was a fraud in my mind. The
understanding of the mathematics to let
the nuclear nuclear energy would pretty
much cancel me out. So you can see that
no matter who that is or who that person
is or what they've accomplished, uh
there will be people who attack them and
refute them because they're coming out
of some kind of a competitive uh envy
envy or something. It's not necessary to
either go ooh ooh and praise him nor is
it necessary to attack him. Uh neither
one is necessary.
All right, that brings us to the problem
then is one of paradigm. Uh so is the
next one the next uh hey
um
oh this is how the mind sees things.
Yeah we were talking about qualifying
thinking that something is great or
thinking something is horrible. Um we
just wanted to show that um duality is
is a fantasy that in reality uh
doesn't deal in duality. Uh there are
degrees of thing being so uh such as
dark is not the opposite of light. Uh
dark is the absence of light. So
falsehood then isn't like a thing in and
of itself. Falsehood merely represents
conceptualization or verbalization
that is devoid of the light of truth.
It's not the opposite. So when her arm
goes down,
I'm not getting the opposite of truth.
What I'm getting is that there's no
electricity in the wire. You're getting
non-truth. And non-truth has no
existence.
So when I hold something that's true,
physiologically, she becomes empowered
and her arm goes strong. And if I say
something that's that is false, it has
no reality.
It has no reality. in response to
non-ele electricity her arm does not go
strong.
Now to perfect that technique itself is
takes a little practice and um not you
know less percent of the population can
do it than I thought originally. I
overestimated the capacity of the mind
you have to be simply aligned with
truth. It it's what's important what
what has to get a good answer. You have
I want to know what the truth is and
then then I'll worry about the
consequences of what I discover later.
What the less evolved mind tries to do
is influence the answer so it falls
within what you want. See a more evolved
person says look give me the facts and
then I'll decide about it later. You
know tell me what the loan interest is
and then I'll decide if I can afford
that loan interest. you know, he doesn't
try and say, "Well, the bank is going to
let me have it at 2 and a half% by by
cheating on the arm
because you'd rather be 2 and a half%
than 5%." So, to begin with, the person
has to be integrous. We found the
highest group. Uh friend of mine back
east uh did a whole chart showing the
likelihood of accuracy in doing uh the
ARM test increases as your consciousness
increases. And a group like this tends
to calibrate in the mid 400s and they
should get very good response good 90%
of the time. Anyway, another way to get
accuracy is by asking the question in
different ways, different ways and
different times
uh to ask ask the
truth is concordant. So if this is true
then this should be true. So the way we
check our answers is we check with
alternate ways of approaching it. U this
can't be true if this is if this if its
opposite is true. So one of those is
wrong. Then we look to see what in the
technique we could be doing wrong. There
could be music in the background. You
could have a personal a personal uh
viewpoint on the problem and you're not
able to detach from etc. But people that
that are intellectually active and
intelligent and spiritually seeking uh
should get about 90% 90% of the time uh
should get an answer.
And if you can't you can get somebody
else to do it. Also there's different
ways of doing it. You can't I I've
explained the simplest way I do it. If
I'm in a hurry and I'm home alone, uh
just take a couple encyclopedias. I lift
them up. I say, "Well, so and so
calibrates at so and so." And I lift
them and then I say, "So and so
calibrates at so and so." And then I
lift them. Yeah. And it's usually quite
with very little experience you can get.
Uh it's much heavier when they're when
the answer is false and books are much
lighter uh when you hold truth in your
mind. So that's a simple way. And then
there's the O-ring method that some
people have learned. All those
techniques. Some people just fall
forward with the truth and fall backward
with falsehood. So
and other people just ask their friends
that are good at it.
I say, "What is so and so got calibrated
at?" You know, in the day news. In the
days news, you get pretty skilled after
a while. You know, you try to guess
guess what a thing is at and be
surprised over the years you get pretty
pretty accurate. You can pretty much get
because you see what the underlying
motive is a thing because you learn to
discern perception from essence
and uh so all right
yeah
things are not then
opposites they're absent. So
cold is the absence of heat. It's not
the opposite. Huh? Yeah. Just like
goodness versus evil. You know, you
might say evil is the absence of
goodness. You can see it in examples of
light.
It's either light or not light, but
there's only one variable that's light.
You cannot shine darkness into the room.
Huh? That's a very simple concept, but
it translates very nicely into
understanding truth versus falsehood or
the muscle response.
We'll go to the next slide.
I want to keep track. I have no idea
where I went on time. Huh?
Okay. Okay. And then they turn out the
house lights. Right.
You got 15 minutes.
All right. people that are spiritually
oriented then I are interested when we
do various spiritual practices
um we don't have them all on here but
the ones that are predominant you'll see
they tend to be uh very
uh from the 500 and up yeah
uh the Lord's prayer at 650
the Lord's prayer
How does it go?
>> Our father. It says our father. And the
term father means founder. Doesn't mean
generic gender father. So get off the
sexism.
Founder is the founder. The founder of
uh theology. The founder of bit
mechanical whatever. The founder. The
founder. The founder. The author. The
substrate. The author.
The Lord's prayer. Then calibrates 650.
That sounds like a good thing to do
every day before you go to bed. Ain't
it?
Sounds like a good thing. You could even
do it in the morning, too. Oh, now it's
getting a little heavy.
Too much to remember in the morning.
How many people here believe do the
Lord's prayer night? Right. All right.
Okay. Let's encourage you leards
to join uh at 650. It's worth doing.
You can picture your um your spiritual
charge account, checking account.
Why not throw in an extra 650? All
right.
At the last moment, you'll wish you had.
Oh Lord, please forgive me for my
indolence.
It's laziness, is it? Not spiritual
laziness. It isn't that you wouldn't or
won't or couldn't. It's just you got
more important things to do.
You're running short of dog food and all
kinds of stuff.
Laying in bed. What are you thinking
about? We got to get dog food tomorrow
and and the for low on gas and
all right. 650 is a pretty high level
consciousness. That's a very high level.
650. So
it would be good
to do it.
Yeah.
prudent.
The prudent spiritual student then says,
"Well, doing the Lord's prayer sounds
like it's a pretty good thing." That's
all. And it doesn't take you long to do
the prayer.
Let's see how fast you can do it.
I was high Episcopal which is like
Catholic as a kid. You go to confession
and the priest gives you, you know,
15 uh Lord's prayers and two 22 hail
Marys or whatever. You know, it's
amazing how fast you can do it because
you want to get out and play ball again.
I can do the Lord's Prayer time, man.
Then you had to go back and see the
priest. Did you do them all? Yes. Okay.
penance. All right. So the Lord's prayer
is very very uplifting and as you say it
slowly and savor its meaning it's
wonderful. Uh this sound the sound om
the nearest sound uh nearest thing that
sound of God uh is the infinite sound of
the basis of the universe.
timeless, eternal.
It's not pronounced a u m
that's in a very respectable book, but
it it's not. ism.
Therefore,
shay is 6:30.
Shotti shotty shotty at 650.
Gregorian chants which are enchanting
enchanting to listen to. And if you're
in a Greek cathedral and you can hear
the choir practicing off in the choir
room, it's magical. There you are in
this whole cathedral and you can hear
the sound of the Gregorian chants off in
the distance. It's like timeless. You
were somewhere back centuries centuries
in time.
uh Gregorian chants
japa is also a certain style and uh at
5:15 the Jesus prayer which has become
very well known at 525
saying the rosary at 500 so all these
devotional acts you'll notice they're
all 500 and over uh that denotes the
heart so this is not the intellect then
these don't appeal to the intellect
these have to do with the love of God
and uh the heart saying the rosary then
as a form of devotion. So you'll notice
these are all 515 japa 515
uh Jesus prayer 525 uh they're all in
the 500s
and uh the Lord's prayer however is at
650. So although these are praiseworthy,
I would uh even saying the rosary, you
know, I'd spend a lot of time on the
Lord's prayer. Do those buttons.
The pilgrimage to Mecca because of its
intention is at 390.
There's a yoga, the curtain yoga chant
is at 250.
12 steps of a is 540
which is doing doing very nicely. 540 is
the level of unconditional love.
Unconditional love. So these are all
striving for that. These are all in the
500s.
Uh and then you get up to uh the sound
itself.
So the 12step movements when you
calibrate the impact of the various
religions on current society which I'm
doing in my present book if you
calibrate the impact of all the major
religions
on society
uh they're all around 450 right the
impact on
modern society
of Christianity is over 450 460 60.
Okay. Judaism is over 450. 460.
Buddhism is 455. Yeah. Buddhism a little
higher. The impact. Huh. Okay. Impact is
around 450. Buddhism is a little higher
at 455.
And um
why did I Oh yeah. And surprisingly
12step 12step movements its impact on
society is higher than all of them at
540.
Its impact is silent and shines forth by
an energy. The energy
of the 12 steps. So therefore the 12
steps have been applied to many men's
problems and many things that were
impossible have resolved themselves.
Uh the golden rule, do unto others as
you would have them do unto you. Uh the
prayer of Jabz, walking the labyrinth.
We have we do that here in We do that
here in Sedona at St. Andrews. Uh they
walk the labyrinth. What is it? Once a
week. Yeah, once a week. All right. The
act of genulection. You see kneeling to
pray, the genulection,
uh the prayerful hand class. We're all
at 540. So devotional acts are at level
540. Turning the prayer wheel. People
will say that's idiotic turning that
wheel around. They think they they see
as trying magic. No, it's the devotion
asking for God's
help. The burning of incense, the
wailing of wall, bathing in the Ganges,
the prayer of St. Francis of Aisi, let
me be a channel of thy will Lord at 580.
So
devotional acts therefore
ours would be a different society
if we adopted um the style you see in
the orient.
The charm of Korea was that all people
greet each other thusly and when you get
used to it seems strangely absent. When
you get back to the states it will seem
awfully cold and crude and complete
strangers. You're in a hotel. You walk
up to the counter and she goes sus
they go this way to each other. So in my
mind we go got into the habit of doing
that. So we actually prefer to do that
but uh it makes some people
uncomfortable. I don't know.
Atheists in particular I suppose.
All right. Now what happens is we take a
break. Is that all?
>> We take a break for how long?
>> 15 minutes. We'll be back.
>> All right. And now I don't know if Go
ahead. She has one announcement. Go
ahead.
>> Go ahead.
>> Yes.
>> I can't read.
>> Oh boy. Somebody's a big joy. I don't
know.
>> Okay,
we're going to take a 15 minute break.
Uh, I know that what I've said I've said
before,
but there are certain things I've heard
throughout my life. No matter how many
times I hear them, I I've fallen in love
with hearing it.
So I have I'm trying to share my falling
in love with truth with you. That you
love truth not for its gain but that you
cherish it not just for its gain but for
your love of the truth. The love of the
truth itself then will carry you the
whole way to enlightenment. Amen.
Whoa. The good news
this morning we said 50, what was it?
55% of the people got it.
>> 55. It's risen to 75.
>> Pow. Pow. Pow. Pow. Pow.
The infinite field of consciousness
includes all possibility in all
existence throughout all of time. So if
you know how to tap into it, obviously
you can find out anything about anything
anywhere in time, right? Who's the 20%
who don't get it? Come up here.
Come here.
idiots.
Idiots sit in the front row.
Anybody who doesn't get it, sit on this.
Sit right here.
Come on, be honest.
Who thinks he's full of BS?
Volunteers,
brave hearts.
All right.
>> If it doesn't make sense to you, uh, we
we'll ask again later. And if it doesn't
make sense, it's your obligation to me
to tell me you don't get it. You know
what I'm saying? The obligation, I see
it between spiritual and student is
bilateral.
The teacher is supposed to knock his
brains out to try to get it over. And
the student is knocking his brains out
to get it between the two of you.
That's it. So
the teacher serves the student.
He's the servant of the student.
In response, the student agrees to be
the servant of the teacher by telling
him when he don't get it.
You don't get it. I will not be
offended.
Yeah.
I will not be offended. We just throw
you out bodily. But
we did spiritual practices and there's
some in the new book that they're not in
here, you know, spiritual practices.
Uh one is the sense of humor.
Uh we have permission to do this. Uh
yeah. Uh sense of humor.
uh subserve spiritual progress resist
calibrates over 500 600
550.
Okay. So humor then humor then uh which
which is not doesn't really stand out in
the spiritual religious history of
mankind.
They seem like a pretty grim lot to me.
If you don't do this you're going to go
into hell and fry forever. I mean good
god.
A sense of humor then is a way of
uh recognizing reality in a way that you
can accept. So humor allows the
acceptance of that which would otherwise
presented differently not be acceptable.
Uhhuh. By juxiposition of uh the
opposites etc. It makes comprehensible.
It also disarms it. It disarms it so
that you can laugh at your foibless. You
can laugh at them much easier than
sackcloth and ashes where you got to
wallow in penance for your stupidities.
You see?
All right. So, spiritual practices.
What did humor come out? Fiveome
>> 550. Let's just do it again. Humor.
Humor as a spiritually teaching device
is over 550. 555. Okay. 550. That's good
enough. Oh, humor. That's pretty darn
good, isn't it? Eats a lot of this jab
jab.
Yeah. Take that.
Oh, golly. All right.
Don't trust anybody who doesn't have a
sense of humor.
That's a good warning to you. They don't
have a sense of humor. Look out.
Because they'll turn you in and fry you
because it's their duty.
Okay. Next one.
All right.
This for people who are seeking
enlightenment and I do get letters from
people. It ask for clarification of
this. Um both meditation and
contemplation.
You stop identifying with the content of
consciousness and you begin to
identify with the field.
There's the thought, there's the image,
the memory. But how do you know that
thought or image or memory? So you begin
to identify I am not the content of
thinkingness or what the mind is is
poking around with. I what I am is the
capacity to be conscious, to witness, to
be aware of it. See, I'm the light of
the screen. And what's on the TV set
varies from second to second. Yeah.
But the TV set is not the program that's
running. The TV set is the capacity to
light up the program. You begin to see
that what you are is the capacity to
light up the content of consciousness,
the image, the memory, the thought, etc.
Uhhuh. The symbol, the linear. And so
you go from form that's equals xy^2, you
know, and you see that the only reason
you know this is because you're able to
register. So you say, well, I'm not the
content of what I'm thinking. I'm the
capacity to register it. How do you
register it? You can recognize it. And
how do you watch? How can you recognize
it? Because you're the watcher
experiencer
without too much difficulty. You either
contemplation or meditation. You become
aware that you are that which the
context out of which it all arises.
Yeah. The watcher or the experiencer
is a phenomena that is impersonal goes
on by itself. So you get away from
identifying the ego. I am George Blow.
I'm 42 years old. I was born in Boston
and I have
hives.
How do you know that? Because that which
you really are is this watcher
experiencer.
Is that clear to everyone? What you are
is that which is witnessing and
listening to this today. You're not the
content of what's being said. You are
the capacity to experience it, witness
it, and register it. Is that clear?
Anybody have a problem with that? You're
the capacity. See, unless you turn the
TV set on, there's no way of knowing
what the program is. Well, the programs
vary from moment to moment. They're all
the same anyway.
You know what they're up to.
All right. The watcher experiencer. So,
you can detach from identifying with
form. I am that which is aware. The dog
is standing up here in front of the
audience trying to explain something.
That which I am is aware that that's the
phenomena going on. But that's just a
phenomena.
That's not who I am. Because if I stop
talking, I don't disappear into
nothingness. So this is more permanent.
The watcher, the experiencer. How do you
know what the watcher and experiencer?
What's going on there? And that's
because of the general principle of
awareness. The awareness
you what you are then is the awareness
of the observer or the witness
witnesser of what that which is being
watched and experienced. So you move
from identifying with this which is very
limited and linear. You move to the
obviously you're the observer witness.
Now how does witnessing and observing
come about? I mean you didn't invent it.
you didn't get as a birthday present
when you're 12 or something.
The capacity of observing and witnessing
is coming out of an even more general
uh underlying phenomena. The light of
consciousness itself. It's because you
are lit up that you're aware of what the
observer witness is aware of and that
the what you're experiencing
is registering form. That which you are
is not here at all. That which you are
is back here. You are the light of
consciousness itself.
That's not too hard a joke, right?
That which you are is aware of the body
sitting down listening to the lecture
watching uh the motion on the stage etc.
uh
because of the light of consciousness.
So it's because of consciousness that
any of this can carry on. So I am that
capacity, that quality of consciousness
itself.
This consciousness actually envelops all
that is manifest as allness. And when
you experience it directly, you
experience it as the self
which is like a radiance
of the unmanifest of the godhead
emerging as self. This the self then
with a capital S is the source of the
radiance of the light of consciousness
within you which comes out by virtue of
divine ordinance.
God imminent and transcendent. God
imminent his experience is the self the
consciousness it is self you say I don't
experience God anywhere
who said that
how do you know that
what strange quality do you have that a
piece of stone doesn't have this carpet
cannot say I am
it's lacking something is it lacking
didn't go to school no that's not
Its essence does not include uh the
quality the pure quality of
consciousness itself. Anyway, because of
the divinity within you out of the
unmanifest then arises the manifest as
all of creation. It is out of this that
all of creation arises.
Therefore,
you can progressively let go identifying
with the content of consciousness and
realize that you are the infinite field
out of which all such awareness arises.
That's not a difficult step.
You can in meditation or in
contemplation
if you just remember this this
progression
uh it's relatively easy to move back
here. It's easy to get to observer
witness. It's obvious unless you're very
that you're the obvious that
you're the observer and the witness of
what's going on in your head. You're not
what's going on in your head. Uh, and
therefore what's going on in your head
is sort of stupid to die for, isn't it?
All right. That which you are then is an
emanation of the light of consciousness
itself. Otherwise, you would not even
know that you exist. You would not even
know that you exist. The awareness of
your own existence. The awareness of
your own existence is the primary
underly of all of thinking this. All the
rest of it that goes on. Okay. Huh? Is
that easy enough?
That's very easy.
Very easy.
Everybody agree that's simple, right?
So therefore, you don't have to go some
strange place, ring bells or allied
incense and have draperies hanging and
go and get into mysterious
front of every yoga journal. So some
she's pretty lady.
It's called the glamorization of
spiritual work. You know that was um her
her hair is flowing in the wind.
And and she's diaphanous.
Chunky people apparently don't meditate.
Especially chunky guys. How many chunky
guys do you see? Black chunky guys
meditating.
That was some white daffin.
That's what they call the the Sedona
hoohoos. Woo woo.
The sedon of woo woos.
It looks more like this, folks.
All right. Okay. Then we'll move on. Did
we already do that one? Oh, no we
didn't. All right. Okay. Now, this is
about a great import in understanding
politics, international diplomacy,
understanding the world we're in. I'm
sick of the world we're in because I'm
writing a book. It's called u
I don't know. It's a good book.
reality, spirituality and modern man.
Uh oh. I didn't know what I was getting
into when I got into modern man. Uh I
can't wait till I finish this book.
modern man. You have to uh stay up with
the news, watch the movement of
politics, international diplomacy, the
thinkingness that goes on behind the
scenes and all of this, the mo the the
motives both conscious and unconscious
and trying to decipher it out.
All right. The one unpleasant fact, the
unpleasant truth, the unfortunate, what
is it? The unpleasant truth or something
that people don't want to face. Isn't
that earthwarming? The unpleasant truth
is that half the people on the planet
think with this side of their brain and
half the people think with this side of
the brain. No, actually 85% of the
people think with the animal brain and
only 15%
think with a higher brain. In America
it's about 50/50.
Below you so what we have is the you see
the evolution of consciousness
throughout the animal kingdom.
Well, it had to have a brain to do that.
So it did. And uh therefore
uh this side of the brain uh the input
is processed through the phalamus
uh fast. This is your animal track the
animal track and then there's the delay
through the prefrontal cortex. Now the
prefrontal cortex in and of itself only
calibrates at 200 neither good nor bad
neutral. Okay. So the fast track
then is uh through the left brain and it
sort of slowly dawns on the the
prefrontal cortex.
People are sort of dumb to begin with
you see and then they only slowly get it
and okay and then it hits the emotional
center the amygdala etc. Then it start
in the brain which is the hippocampus.
Well, the brain when a thing happens, it
calls forth the memory of the thing too,
which colors their emotional reaction.
All right. What the importance is?
Let's see what percent of the people on
the planet. We have permission to ask
this. We have permission to ask this
award. The percentage of the people on
the planet dominated by the top figure
is 85%.
90%.
85% should be about 85%.
85% of the people on the planet are
thinking like an animal.
Forget about Kumbaya.
I'm going to kill you, you son of a
That makes sense to him.
The hell would come by you. You know
what I mean? All right. We're trying to
figure out why certain political pus
work and why other political ps don't
work.
All right. So, if you're dealing with an
enemy that is wired, they're wired this
way, you will have to respect the fact
that they are wired this way.
You see, the big fallacy of the western
world is you want to come at these
people from here.
If you come at these people from here,
you look stupid.
stupid.
I told you I paid this guy to get up on
a camel,
make the trip, got around the pyramids,
and it's the end of the trip. He says,
"That'll be I want to get off." He says,
"That'll be $10."
I already contracted with him. I paid
him $10 for the whole camel trip.
At the end, he says, "You owe me $10 to
get off the camel."
I'm up there. I've told you the story
before.
There ain't no way you're going to get
down from the top of a camel by your
lonesome.
From this viewpoint, he's spiritually
and morally in error, is he not? He's
violated his contract.
All the lawyers out there will shiver at
him. He's violated his contract. He's in
violation of his contract. He made a
verbal contract witnessed by others.
It's enforceable in court.
You know what the camel driver thinks
about that?
Give me my 10 bucks, you cheap American.
He kept calling me cheap American. Cheap
American. I said, I paid you $10. Cheap
American. Cheap American. He says, he's
going to let me sit on the camel like
Ferrari. I
Well, I got to pay him the 10 bucks. I
got to sell for 10 bucks. And I showed
you how the camel did it. Oh. Oh. Oh.
The camel should have gotten the $10
easil.
All right. So, when you read the papers
about the failure of international
diplomacy,
what you're talking about is the camel,
huh?
He's saying cheap American, cheap
American. We're blackmailing you all
over the place and you're too dumb to
even know that you're on top of the
camel and you can't get off without
paying $10.
They say, "Yeah, but that's not
righteous
in his world.
That's not only righteous, that's
required. That's the law."
Huh?
There's certain religious laws that
demand that you lie if it will favor
their position. Your obligation is to
lie. It says right there.
I'll tell you the verse. Yeah.
If it's to your advantage,
it's your obligation to lie.
Huh? That's incomprehensible to the
western mind. Now, how are you going to
get concordance between this brain and
this brain? I'll tell you, you're not.
You expected a cheery sermon today. No,
I'm not going to give you one.
No, because this brain is is a different
brain. And for one thing, it uh has an
atheric brain. Now, the condundalini
energy arises at consciousness level
200. It's a spiritual energy. It is not
a physical energy. It runs up the chakra
system, the spiritual energy system and
it begins to influence everything. So
the right brain then is completely
different. Below 200 you have left brain
dominance. Everything is linear stress
adrenaline fight or flight. This is the
Newtonian uh paradigm thymic uh thrust.
So when you're stressed you go
I feel better right? Yeah it's a good
idea.
This is a quick way of relieving stress.
Uh
the negativity disrupture the flow of
your acupuncture system results in
diseases and negative kinesiologic
response. All right. So this is below
200 and this is a different world. This
is a different world in which everything
is seen, experienced and interpreted
totally differently.
With spiritual evolution consciousness
level 200 then the beginning the the
spiritual energy pours forth and shifts
the brain balance. Now the input goes
through as you see a fast track through
the atheric brain very fast to the
emotional level and then back into the
memory. So right brain dominance is
nonlinear.
It produces endorphins which uh make you
feel good and happy. Uh positive
emotions and it supports the stress on
the thymic thymus gland. It puts out
greater number of killer cells.
Therefore, you're more immune. Other
people everybody's got a colder on you
but you don't.
Greater immunity, faster healing. The
acupuncture system is balanced and you
get a positive muscle response.
Uhhuh.
Therefore, you're looking at two
different two different
uh forms of homo sapien.
Uh this is the emergence of
homospiritus.
And this is the homo sapiion. The homo
sapiion merely gets up on his feet and
walks and learns how to manipulate
skills and tools.
Uh but he's still dominated by the
animal. It's only when he's imbued with
the spiritual energy that he becomes
truly human human. And this I call
homospiritus.
It's really a different
uh emergence from this here. Uh this is
a three and a half million year old. How
how old is Lucy? Three and a half
billion years old, right? Lucy is three
and a half billion years old. The oldest
skeleton ever found human skull. Lucy's
three and a half billion years old.
Yeah. And she lives on here in our in
our society.
55% of the people don't think much
differently than Lucy. All right. Then
due to the evolution of consciousness
and good karma um positive karma one
that comes into a spiritual energy. Now
let's just reaffirm the law of karma.
I have permission to do the law of
karma. Lord resist. The law of karma is
absolute resistance. The law of karma is
is absolute.
All right.
People who have never heard or
understand the law of karma are in a
predicament to explain many spiritual
phenomena. It's only when you include
the propensities. Karma is not an
absolute. It's a propensity. A
propensity. And it has to do with
cascading levels of dominance
uh which are physiologically uh
demonstrable and affirmable by modern
medicine. Move on. Next.
The likely if you make certain choices,
if you choose to make certain choices,
the likelihood is that you will make
choices of a similar dimension in the
future. The more often you choose to
forgive somebody, the more likely it is
that you will see that as an option. The
next time somebody cuts you short in
traffic, there's a how the hell he don't
know what he's doing here. So the
willingness to forgive then becomes
almost automatic after a while. And um
you make allowance. So you make
allowance for the fact that 50% of the
of mankind is below 200. and you don't
expect them to let you off the camel
without paying an extra 10.
Instead of being outraged that all these
uh people in Congress and all that
Washington are ripping off right and
left, you say, "Oh, that dirty mess."
You know, that's the way business is
done there.
That's the way business is done there.
How do you get a vote?
You favor something that he wants and
now you got to vote. That's the way it
works. There it's neither right nor
wrong. It's just the way rate it works.
What's the important of spiritual
evolution then is also rate of uh
happiness and and levels. Level of
consciousness 600 and over. Unemployment
is zero. Crime is zero. Poverty is zero.
Happiness is 100% and the rate of
criminality is zero. 0%.
You see about 99% of criminality arises
from down here. All right. From 400 to
500, the rate of unemployment is 2%.
They're probably collecting their
unemployment insurance.
Rate of poverty. You got to work hard at
it. And this is probably due to some
major both your parents got killed in an
automobile wreck or something uh or
prolonged sickness. Uh but even then
happiness is still 70%. The rate of
criminality is only 2%. All right. So
when consciousness double 300 to 400 uh
unemployment is 7%. I haven't studied
the subcultures of this why it would be
even 7%. Because 300 is willingness and
400 is intelligence. So if you're
willing and intelligent,
why are you unemployed? I don't know.
The rate of poverty, however, is 1%. Uh
bad investments.
They invested in WorldCom.
Worldcom caliber rate 190. We weren't
interested in it. Uh happiness is still
very high. So now as you see
consciousness level goes down. Uh the
minute you get below 200 here the rate
of employment is 8% just above 200 it's
8%. The minute you drop below 200 it
jumps from 8% to 50%.
That's the cause of unemployment.
Not evil capitalists
but the fact that the consciousness
level is too low. They can't see the
advantages they're laying around
everywhere. Unemployment is 50%. It's
really you got to really work at being
unemployed in today's world, don't you?
Every every store I go into says help
wanted. Every single one of them.
Unemployment. All right. Rate of poverty
22 15%. Life is okay. You see happiness
has dropped down and criminality is now
up to 50%.
So the crucial line just as we showed on
our chart is
unemployment goes as you cross the level
200 unemployment goes from 8 to 50.
Poverty goes from 1 to 22.
H happiness goes from 40% down to 15%.
Criminality goes from 9% to 50%.
You can see how crucial that level of
200 is. Shift to brain physiology. you
see and experience the world
differently. If the level of
consciousness even gets below that, then
you start running uh close to 100%
unemployment
uh very high poverty, 65%
uh because the government is supporting
them. Life is happy is only 2% down here
at 0%. The rate of criminality is 91%.
the lowest consciousness levels
is almost 100% criminal.
That's amazing, isn't it?
And think of this young boy that shot up
32 people. He calibrated at five.
Five. You can't even get it on here.
It's so low.
Shot up 32 people. Spree killing. That's
Freud. Freud, you know, talked about the
id. The bottom of the id is where all
the most primitive
reprehensible impulses, etc. are buried.
And occasionally it gets loose. Drunken
sprees. You see killing spreees. You see
it in the animal kingdom. Killing
spreees.
All right. So that's the id all the way
down the depth of
it's like the dinosaur the primitive
buried in the you know evolutionary
evolution of the central nervous system
the capacity for spree killing.
You see spree killing and the killing of
the in Manuria the Japanese slaughtering
people in Manuria. You see it in in wild
uh dog fighting and dog fighting uh
hanging dogs till they die etc. That's
the
very calibration around five. So all
right so that is in the depth of the
human psyche and political forces
militaristic ones have learned how to
engineer that. Why? Because what
counterbalances is conscience.
Therefore, if you can dissolve the
conscience into a religiously
phrased okayess, you can release that
primitive uh adivistic trend. And now
you can tie some bombs to yourself and
kill everybody in this room.
As a bomber,
I'm going to kill everybody in this
room. All of you
for the glory of God. Therefore, my
spiritual obligation is to kill you. Is
it not? The fact that I don't kill you,
I'm not living up to my obligation.
There you see two different
civilizations. You understand the clash
of civilizations?
Sounds pessimistic. It is
can't make you happy every time. You
know,
I learned how to get along with
rattlesnakes long time ago.
I learned how to get along with kamoga
dragons a long time ago.
I stay out of their effing cage.
Occasionally a miracle will save you,
you know, and I've related my encounter
with a a big rattlesnake in the top of
the mountain over here. It was mystical,
but u you can't expect the mystical
every moment.
But it was it was an incredible
experience in which time stopped
absolute peace and stillness and I
experienced what I experienced in the
snowbank.
The presence has within itself a
profound gentleness beyond description.
But that gentleness is within itself
infinitely power. Infinite power.
Suspended in time and space. The
rattlesnake was unable to move. Huh? And
when I've been in that space myself,
there's no ability to move. There's no
decisions to be made. There is no
decider, much less it's
all prevails. The infinite field is
infinitely powerful.
All right. Did we do this one?
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.
Halle.
Hallelujah.
Hallelujah.Allelu.