Yes,
I can.
Um
I think that well you've written about
the hypertrophic super ego and um
you you suffered from
aspects of that in your own life. Is
that correct?
>> Yes.
um
>> scrupulosity.
>> I um I know that I have a hypertrophic
super ego because it it manifested a lot
in um judgmentalism towards others. Um
as I develop as I matured um
scopulity refers to yourself, not to
others.
Well, I I I understood it to be
projections onto others in transcending
the levels you during the cou I think
it's in the courage chapter you discuss
sculacity pertains to self-criticism a
hypertrophic super ego overly
self-critical you can't allow yourself
any breathing room to be human make
human mistakes you know so it only
applies to oneself you know
>> okay um so I'm wondering um a a lot of a
lot of um well I recently made what what
I perceive to be an error. I was in I
was feeling very well and then I I made
an error.
>> Um there's been a lot of guilt and self
attack coming up.
>> Yes. Mhm.
>> Now, uh I've heard well in transcending
the levels you mention uh I believe it's
in the grief chapter that anything above
grief should be surrendered but things
below grief you should not surrender.
You should rebuke.
>> No saying that.
>> Well, okay. But I've heard but I've
heard you say elsewhere um for example
that something like the Sedona method
can be useful to spiritual aspirants in
processing out the guilt associated with
sin.
>> Oh yeah.
>> So when when guilt comes up
>> as an inner state not a verbalized
criticism but as an inner feeling.
>> Yeah. Would it be best for me to
surrender that to God and let it welcome
it as you speak of welcoming fear?
>> Let go resisting it.
>> Okay. Until guilt included
>> and see I want more. I want more.
>> And try and unccort it. Yeah. Because
it's a stack.
>> Oh, I see.
>> You know, you've been collecting guilt
for many a lifetime. So, it's quite a
stack when you sit down and say, "All
right, let's feel guilty. More. I want
more. More." What about the time you
didn't thank your mother for the jello
she made for your birthday party?
That's the kind of stuff I used to go
over. I forgot to say thank you to my
mother for making the jello for my
birthday party.
And I confess it to the priest
and he'd say, "You better see the
counselor for sure."
So you're you have to accept the fact
that you're allowed to forgive yourself
for common human error. If you were made
perfect, you wouldn't be a human.
You'd be in divine
realms.
>> But let go of it. Don't carry it.
>> Right. Yeah.
>> Let go of it.
>> Yeah. Let go.
>> Right. I mean this particular one
there's kind of an intellectual um web
around it and uh
well like you so someone asked um with
vows and oaths someone asked am I bound
to it you said no you're not bound to it
because you you were ignorant you were
like a child yet you finished this your
response with the statement you're not
bound to it unless it was of an an
integrous decision unless it was based
upon an injurous decision
>> as a full grown informed adult.
>> Mhm.
>> Make no oath.
>> Okay. I mean, if it's a it's a
formalized vow to oneself based upon a
belief that was that was faulty, is that
don't have to sweat it.
>> I don't get what he's saying.
>> If the if the decision was made
At the time he was ignorant.
>> Yes.
>> That's
>> it's not binding.
>> It's not binding
>> because you're spiritually
>> Thank you, Doc.
Spiritual oaths.
I thought he said oaths. He said
>> oath.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello.
>> Yes.
>> When one has a thought or an intention
to bless,
>> you got to speak closer to the speaker.
>> When one has a thought or an intention
to bless a person or a place or a thing,
uh does that entity benefit from that?
And if so, what are you doing?
>> Shouldn't be of any interest to you.
because you're trying to
control an outcome. You bless it be out
of the lovingness of which which you are
and not uh to bring forth any result.
Okay.
It makes it more powerful prayer.
If you bless something in order to bring
about an effect
>> then you're coming from causality. you
brought your prayer down to the level of
the 400s Newtonian causal. I'm going to
do this and that's going to cause that.
If you surrender it more to God and
picture it as healed and happy and
healthy and all and then it's up to
divine ordinance and uh it's much more
powerful than if you
pray for a person in order for them to
get better.
God doesn't need you to tell tell him
that your aunt Nelly needs help with his
herb butter doesn't really need your
information,
>> right? But if you just use the word to
bless something, anything a country uh
>> if you're to bless something, then it
benefits that which is uh it it benefits
the blesser and perhaps the bless
but not necessarily the bless.
>> All right.
Thank you.
>> Otherwise, you could do other people's
karma. That would make you god, you see.
>> Oh,
>> yes.
>> Doc, I've got a present. Um, I love bag
pipes, too. I heard these anonymous four
four women magical singers. They do
medieval work and they do current work
and I think you're going to love it.
It's that discord and sound. So, I
wanted to give that to you.
>> Yes.
>> Question. Yeah. I think you'll enjoy it.
>> Um, back in August of 2005, not that it
made a big impression on me, but you
told me that my cats were my anchor.
And I've contemplated that since then.
What I what I get so far is that I do
have a greater attachment to outcomes
with animals. I'm able to release more
with love people and other events when I
recognize attachment or whatever.
I want to know if you recall what you
might have meant by that or what you see
now about the cats being my anchor.
>> Well, they're an anchor in several
meanings of the term.
>> Okay.
>> Uh it's a domain in which you are
certain of your role and fulfill the
caring for others. So, it's a spiritual
anchor. Yeah.
it can also become an attachment. So at
a certain level, you'll have to let go
of being the cat lady go. And uh
on the other hand, you're fulfilling a
very wonderful role. You see, a lot of
us fulfill our karmic potential
of givingness, caringness, and all
through love. Yeah. Through through the
animal kingdom. If you watch the animal
channel on television, you know, you see
the caringness,
>> the heart that comes forth through the
people
>> and the animal sewns forth that
lovingness.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I'm surrounded by
>> pers. Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> I am so grateful.
>> Yes. and Susan
doc uh you have calibrated in the course
in miracles the text and the workbook.
>> Yes.
>> But the third book of the course in
miracles is the manual for teachers.
>> Yes.
Some of us are studying the manual for
teachers now and oh yes it would help
clarify where are we
>> and what are we doing
>> in that territory
>> manual for teachers
>> what what good is that
>> are you a teacher
>> no for me it's defining the spiritual
principles of living
>> generally what do you to know about it.
I don't
>> I would like for you to calibrate that.
>> Oh,
let's see. We have permission.
We have permission to calibrate
uh this uh here. Resist. It's over 550.
560.
555.
It's about 555. Yeah, that's manageable.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
We have a world in which hardly
anybody's over 200 and you're worrying
about whether it's 555 or 560. I don't
think
>> I just found that. Good job. I guess
it's in the field.
>> We stated it from the Goodwill.
>> Imagine of course the miracle at the
Goodwill.
>> May I have a picture?
Sorry.
Oh my god.
>> Thank God it's not difficult.
>> Thank you.
>> Beautiful.
>> Well, I knew Bill Feford and Helen all
the people got it going. Great
gratifying.
>> Thank you both profoundly. Yeah. Uh this
year you've talked uh quite a bit about
moral relativism and I've been trying to
contextualize the reason for that.
What's the purpose for a spiritual
student to perhaps see it in oneself?
What could you tell me about that?
>> I would just forget more.
>> Okie do.
It's so often used as a rationalization
for really uh viewpoints that calibrate
quite a bit below 200, you know.
>> Yeah.
>> And the people who use it don't have the
sophistication. It's not that it
couldn't be a tenable workable tool,
>> but the people who are drawn to it lack
the qualities that would make it a
useful tool.
It said it's used to justify
political positions. That's all it's
used for.
>> Yeah.
>> It seems like it could exist within me
because I've been, you know, grown up in
a culture that's got moral relativism
throughout it.
>> I didn't know what you mean by that.
>> Oh. H I don't either.
>> Well, the word relativism vacates that
it's based on any kind of reality.
So you mean you grew up in a world of
morality,
not moral relativism.
>> I guess just this societyy's got a lot
of moral relativism as a part of it.
>> You don't know what the term means. I'm
telling you it's a political statement.
>> I see.
>> Are you intending to make a political
statement or a spiritual statement?
>> I'm not clear.
>> Well, avoid moral relativism because it
becomes nothing but a political
political statement.
>> Good enough. Thank you, sir.
It calibrates very low. Moral relativism
calibrates at 170.
>> Hi,
>> how are you? Um, in our home we talk a
lot about you. we see your DVDs and um
my daughter who is five years old, she
said to uh she made this for you and she
said to um to give it to you. Yeah.
>> Looks like gobbled the goat to me.
>> Oh, she's she's 5 years old.
>> No, it's adorable. Thank you.
>> It's trees with butterflies floating all
over them.
>> Yeah,
>> it's beautiful.
>> That's supposed to be the sun over
there.
>> It's adorable.
>> Yeah, it is. Thank you.
>> All the little butterflies floating over
over the trees, you know.
>> Well, I'm just very very grateful for
your teaching. Um I don't have any words
to
>> to thank you. I mean, just I just can't
believe how you came into my world.
>> Yeah, I'm glad it's had a positive
effect.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yes.
>> And thank you for the butterflies.
>> Adorable little butterflies. child's
mind at work.
>> Hello, doctor.
>> Yes.
>> Since the 1980s,
he's been my teacher since I until I
found you. I would like to know if you
could calibrate him for me. He's no
longer alive. He's on the other side
now.
>> I don't even know where that's supposed
to be.
is supposed to be.
>> Okay. I have permission to calibrate
this entity
who shall remain endless. Nameless. Is
this this nameless entity calibrates
over 200? Thank God. This nameless.
That's good. This nameless entity shall
be over 300. 400.
Over 395.
400. 395. That's very good. High intent.
Good intention.
>> Oh, I'm glad to hear that.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yeah, it's very positive.
>> 300 is
>> high. Yeah, the high 300s are very good.
>> Oh, that's really good to hear.
>> Who's the biggest the biggest selling
book and truck stops of America?
Something rather ordered life.
>> The purpose- driven life, you know.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, that's supportive, positive,
constructive.
High30s are like firemen 911 disaster.
All the people who climbed up ladders
and took out dying people.
>> That's the high 300s.
>> Great.
>> Now I got you as a teacher, I hope.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Oh, closer. All righty.
I can come up. Um,
nobody home.
It
>> he he got rid of his ego and there's
nobody there now.
>> Vacant. Yeah. Go ahead.
>> Um,
I love you very much.
>> That's why I drilled holes in your head.
>> Thank you.
>> I knew you would enjoy it.
Um,
>> yeah. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Yeah, you're doing well.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> Thank you very much.
>> All right.
Hi,
I just want to thank you both.
Um, I have a question about the course
and maybe this has been answered but
>> question about what?
>> The course and I've it's yeah the course
it's probably been answered but I
haven't heard the answer. Um, I've been
doing it for over a year but I'm nowhere
near the final lesson.
So, um, is it okay not to scrupulously
do it every single day if you don't feel
like you're getting it? Sometimes it
takes me a week to soak one of them up.
>> Now, you're doing the workbook.
>> Yeah.
>> The workbook gives you one sentence a
day,
>> right? With the list.
>> You don't have time to do one sentence?
>> No, I have time.
>> Huh?
>> I have time. I just want to feel as
though I've absorbed it and and
sometimes I forget to do the exercise
during the day. So I think I'll do it.
>> Oh, you're talking about Oh, I see.
>> Yeah. No,
>> not just the lesson, but the
instructions that go with the lesson so
that I've absorbed
>> how to Yeah, I see. How to process the
lesson. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Before the next
>> Uhhuh.
>> Is that an okay way to do it
or should I just
>> What works for you is what works for you
because your mind works that way,
>> right?
Okay.
>> I have Would you mind giving this a
little blessing? It's the serenity
prayer.
>> Serenity prayer.
>> Yeah. Would you bless Help me give that?
>> How do you know that's a serenity
prayer?
>> I I put my glasses on and could see
that.
Trust me.
>> I permission to bless that just I have
permission to bless that serenity
prayer. Yeah. Yes. We bless that ser
prayer. We've done it many a time.
>> It's a blessing in and of itself. Okay.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
Grant me the accept the things I can. I
change and the wisdom to change the
things I can.
Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> As much as I love reading your answers
and hearing them here, I'm trying to be
able to make the decisions myself. And
I've tried several different ways of
doing the muscle testing
>> and I'll find sometimes I'll get a yes,
I'll get a no. I'm I'm not trusting and
I don't feel like I'm doing it
correctly. Can you give some
>> instruction on that?
>> I don't see how I could do that.
Sometimes it works, sometimes it doesn't
work. Why don't you try it with a second
person? See how it works
>> instead of just yourself?
>> Yeah. Well, I could go searching for a
second person. I live alone and I
>> Oh, I see. It's not practical. It's not
practical.
>> All right. I'll I'll tell you a simpler
way. You you you take several
encyclopedias.
>> Okay.
>> All right. You hold in mind, let's say
picture of the Lord Jesus and you lift
them. Right.
>> Okay.
>> Now,
in contrast, you hold in louden in mind
and lift them. And notice the difference
in the effort and strength that it
takes. It's quicker and easier. maybe
won't be so prone to error is the ring
ring method.
>> Okay, I'll try that. Thank you.
>> Yeah,
>> thank you. I've been doing this this one
and saying resist. That seems mo more
successful than this or
>> Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Yeah.
>> There's different systems. Try the one I
suggest you.
>> I will. Thank you.
>> Can't do it while you're driving, but
it's
>> Thank you.
I try to be serious.
>> Yeah.
>> Hi.
>> Um,
when I first started coming here, I was
overwhelmed with this sense of bliss and
joy and feeling moved. And, um, in the
last year, I've been letting this stack
of shame and guilt come up. And, um,
it's almost like I feel like it's it's
getting in the way of me feeling that.
and feeling God.
And
>> what's getting in the way?
>> Shame.
>> This stack of She's a whole stack coming
up of shame.
>> Shame. That's what I thought you said.
>> To the point where I'm I feel unworthy
to sit here with you right now. And um
um I've heard your teachings on on
surrender. And
>> so shame has to do with regret.
>> And I there's no logical reason I can
think of in this lifetime. It's just
pervasive feel. It's like I've always
like I've done something wrong and I
can't remember what it is, but I'm
wrong. And um I keep letting it come up
and um
it's narcissistic, but
>> it's a it's uh it's uh everything has a
limit. So if if you hit a big stack, you
just let let go resisting the feeling.
Don't get into the elaboration about the
feeling. Just go for the feeling itself
and stop calling the feeling anything
like regret or grief or anything. You're
calling it a name. It doesn't have any
name.
>> Okay?
>> If you let go of the sensation of it,
just the physical
emotional sensation of it without
labeling it or trying to get away from
it or anything, it will disappear.
You'll
um
release on the whole stack.
>> Okay?
>> Without thinking about it,
>> okay?
>> Just be with the sensation.
the unpleasantness of it. Instead of
running away from the unpleasantness of
it, you just say more, more, more, more.
Eventually, it will come to a stop. It's
not unlimited.
>> Okay?
>> All right. It's a
It's a limited stack. Resist.
>> It's a limited stack. Okay.
>> All right.
>> So, it will come to an end.
>> I was wanting to ask if um because it
seems like maybe it's a karmic undoing
of something. And I wanted to ask if you
would forgive me in the name of God for
whatever error I made that brought this
about.
>> Um, you're presuming that it's coming
from an error. That's a presumption.
>> Okay.
>> That comes from thinking. I told you
don't think about it.
>> Okay.
>> I don't want you to write an essay on
it.
>> Okay.
>> Sorry.
Once this comes up, do you forgive
yourself for it and then let it go or
are you sometimes or is it the same
thing that keeps coming up and up and up
and up?
>> Um, sometimes I can interrupt it and
free myself and other times it just
>> Yeah, but is it the same the same thing?
>> No, it's just a feeling. It's just
>> Yeah. Okay, that's better.
>> An actual reason.
>> No, you're doing the right thing.
>> Okay.
Thank you. I once sat out a stack for I
don't know 10 weeks or was it or 10
months? I forget. Eventually quit.
>> Okay.
>> Either one of us is going to go down and
ain't me.
>> I'm from India.
>> Yes.
>> And uh I read your books and
particularly the calibration of teachers
that you gave in truth versus falsehood.
Yes.
>> And uh based on the calibration that you
gave of Romesh Baler, I went to meet him
and learn from him of who?
>> Romesh.
>> Oh yes. Yes.
>> And uh I find a lot of things that he
teaches u in direct uh conflict with
some of the things that you teach in
terms of first in terms of personal will
and intention.
And
>> I can't understand what he's saying
though.
>> Some of the things that he teaches are
in complete conflict with what you
teach.
>> Oh yeah.
So, uh,
>> you're aware of what happened to Ram?
>> I I I did hear somebody speak, but I'm
personally
>> It's on the internet. You can look it up
for yourself.
>> Okay.
>> It'll answer your question.
>> All right. Thank you very much. It's a
pleasure meeting you. Can I take a
photograph?
>> I spent 10 day 10 days with him.
Yeah. He was in a good good space then.
Yes.
>> Would you help me pray for my sister Pam
for a moment?
>> What do you need help for?
What do I need help for?
>> Do you need me to help you pray for her?
Why? So,
>> because greater likelihood to be
effective. Is that what you're thinking?
>> No. Because when two or more are
gathered together,
>> very good.
>> He is in the midst of us.
>> That's fine. That's
>> I thought you trying to put more air
pressure in the tire. You know,
>> what's the matter with your sister,
honey? Huh?
>> Um, she's had serious migraine headaches
since 5 years old. And she's on
epileptic medications. And as she's
getting older, she's in her 40s now.
She's in pain continually without
medication. And she has sought every
doctor there is.
>> Yeah. She's been on imitatrix
>> probably. I don't know all the names of
the medications myself.
>> Yeah. Well, it's a strange disorder.
Anyway, uh we I I pray for your sister
that she discovered the source of her
migraine headaches.
I pray that she discovers the source.
>> Amen.
>> Thank you.
>> Hello. I just wanted to meet you and say
hello
>> and thank you. Um, and I'm bringing a
few people with me from Australia in my
thinking and um, I'd like to say hello
and thank you from them as well.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thanks.
>> See, migraine is a whole subject in
itself.
You can do rotation diets. You'll find
that the days that you eat wheat, that's
when you get a headache.
You can do conflict ambivalence about
responsibility.
You wonder if they've taken him. Find
out what relieves it.
Hemocrania. That's a whole subject in
itself. Yes.
Yes.
I feel very ashamed. um
that and I would like to I you know when
you tested the karma thing with the your
eyes but I feel very ashamed that I am
and um have never been married. have
never been able or stayed or has it ever
worked out for more than actually maybe
nine months at the most with another
person. Um,
it's just a great shame in my life. And
I know that that it's not I I know all
the logical reasons.
>> Logical
reasons that I shouldn't feel ashamed
and that's just the way it is. And
>> well, aside from that, so you've had
counseling, you know, what the
psychological profile is that underlies
these difficulties.
Um, I've done I've done some counseling.
Um, I've tried all sorts of different
things.
>> Yes.
>> Um,
it's just always the same.
>> And you haven't done any counseling.
>> Oh,
>> you've been avoiding it, right?
>> Um,
>> counseling, you understand your own
psychology and how you contribute to the
failure of these things. So, how could
you have that counseling and not have
any an effect on your relationships?
Then maybe I haven't tried.
>> It doesn't sound to me like you have.
>> A good counselor who sees a pattern
makes you aware of the pattern then out
of your own valition you change the
pattern.
You're making yourself like victim of it
all instead of the master of it.
So you need to look at the pattern and
then what can you do about the pattern
together with you know prayer or group
therapy whatever you want to change the
pattern
but you know you can change the pattern.
>> All right.
>> You haven't told me you've done anything
to change the pattern. Would you please
tell me what have you done to change?
>> What have I changed the pattern?
>> Yeah. Please be real instead.
>> Okay. I've I've done some counseling.
>> Yes.
>> Um it seems to me that it's fear-based.
>> That it's what?
>> It's fear.
>> Fear. Yes.
>> And that I'm terrified
>> of
>> men.
>> Terrified of men. Oh, well, give up on
men then. That was
>> Switch to the other side.
>> I I've thought of that, too.
some other lifetime, you know.
>> Some other Yeah. So,
>> yeah,
>> just incredible fear comes up.
>> Oh,
>> just incredible.
>> Are you afraid of me right now?
>> Fear.
>> No, but
>> Well, I might eat you or attack you or
throw you on the floor. What What is
this man going to do to you? Is he going
to dominate you?
>> Yes.
>> Oh, I see. He's going to dominate you.
>> Okay.
If he does, what would that do?
>> She lose her autonomy.
>> Um,
>> what would that do to you?
>> It will be
degrading.
Um,
I'll be entrapped. Um, actually, my
first response is to you that I'll kill
him.
>> Well, forget about relationship, man.
I feel so
>> some other some other lifetime another
year.
>> Another lifetime. Okay.
>> So, it's okay if I just let it go for
this time.
>> Make good friends and let it go.
>> No, it's something you're going to keep
working on. I can see you're not done
with it yet.
>> You're gonna keep working on it and
You're not done with it yet. Okay.
>> Are you going to handle it? I mean,
you're not a wimp.
>> No, I'm not a wimp. And I really
wouldn't kill him. I just would want to.
>> That's normal.
That's a natural reaction
>> for your first guy. Have it with guy.
Somebody who's small small
and lightweight.
>> Okay.
>> All right.
>> Yeah. Sounds like he needs protection
from you, not vice president.
>> All right. Go ahead.
>> Thank you. No, you're working on it.
You're working on it. You're still
keeping a good uh cheerfulness about it.
>> You're not You haven't vanqu you haven't
been vanquished by it.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. She makes an interesting patient.
Well, you weren't in psychoanalysis or
you would find out what it is about.
Psychoanalysis, you lay on the couch and
whatever comes up in mind. Whatever is
with you and the man is going to come up
with you and the analyst. So, I would
say psychoanalysis is the cure.
However, it's expensive.
>> Hi, thank you Dr. Hawkins. Thank you for
asking those wonderful questions
earlier, Susan. Um, my question is also
about the course of miracles. Um, I've
been doing it for almost a year and I'm
having some blocks and I'm wondering if
it's okay to go on to the next lesson if
you don't feel like you've gotten the
one.
>> Sure.
>> It could take you a lifetime to get one
lesson.
>> Okay. So, my intention is enough to
>> No, you do what you can with each
lesson. You know, you can always go
through the course a second time, you
know.
>> Okay. I've
>> keep going through it. Yeah. I keep So,
you don't break the momentum.
>> Okay. All right. Thank you.
>> If you stop, you may lose the momentum,
you know. put it down and not pick it up
again.
>> Yeah, I've started it over a couple of
times. So,
>> right now I keep going with it.
>> Okay.
>> And uh you pray for God's help to
understand what the lesson means, you
know.
>> I don't believe every single lesson I
read it in in it now even
doesn't calibrated a thousand, you know.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you very much.
Hello.
>> Yes.
>> My question is about children.
>> I understand that they don't come with a
manual and and we do our best.
At what age,
it's a broad question, but what at what
age and how would you present God and
spirituality
to a child?
And
if you could share your personal
experience how you approached it.
>> The uh well the par you see the the
natural way is that the parents it's a
reality and a part of their life pattern
and because the child's a member of your
family they just automatically do that.
You don't have to do anything special at
all. If you go to church on Sundays,
they'll go along to church with you and
they'll like the music. And
so whatever you do
will become their pattern. And that's
the most effortless way. You find
yourself just automatically
looking forward to the Christmas tree.
You don't have to go through Christmas
indoctrination. You know what I'm
saying? Or the manora or whatever the
religion happens to be.
>> I would say they they follow the pattern
of the parents. Now if you want to teach
spirituality to the children but avoid
it yourself, you got a difficult job.
>> No,
now do as I do, do as I say. You know,
>> religion is one thing, but I'm I'm
really concerned with spirituality and
spiritual aspect of it so that they're
not indoctrinated.
Well, you teach you teach then what
you've learned and share what you've
learned and share what the pathways have
been that you found valuable.
>> Okay.
>> And they will begin to see it the same
way.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. And you started pretty So I guess
I think I just got the answer. The
opportunity really presents itself and
as the question is being asked that's
when you teach.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's true.
>> That's what I just Thank you very much.
>> Yeah. Yeah. If you pray they'll say,
"Daddy, why are you doing that?" You
tell them, "Well, there's God." You
explain God why you pray to God. And you
know, it's just you share your own
reality with him.
>> And that's bless your food. And that's a
good way.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. All meals blessing your
food
>> because they're watching all the time,
>> right? They're watching.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's good. Imitation is
the best easiest teacher.
>> Yes.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
>> I first want to say thank you and Susan,
thank you so much. Um, your teachings
have changed my life and I love you
better both for that. Yes, absolutely.
Absolutely.
Um, I recently ran into a situation with
a couple of people that felt very karmic
past lifetime drama drama projected
betrayal. Uh, and the way that I've
chose to handle it is to pray about it,
to release, surrender them to God, to
uh, also take responsibility for
whatever my role might have been for
this life or past lifetimes.
>> You've done you can do
>> and also I've been doing the ho ponop
pona prayer, which is um, I'm sorry,
please forgive me. I love you, I forgive
you. And so, every time they come to
mind, I've been using that as a mantra.
>> Okay? And I feel relatively free of it,
but can I declare this karma over and
complete?
>> Well, I don't know if we want to go that
far.
>> I think I got the lesson, but um can we
say it's over?
>> Do we have that power?
>> Since you're forgiving all the time,
are you saying that they're not
forgiving of this? Whoever this
involves,
>> I feel that their forgiveness towards me
is not yet complete.
>> That's their problem.
>> That's their problem. Yeah.
>> And I feel like it's completely from
past life stuff.
>> Yeah.
>> That's good.
>> So, you can forgive them for not
forgiving you. How's that?
>> Okay. But I mean if you've already done
that
still
>> anyway. Yeah, that's better.
>> Is there any other prayer or
recommendation other than just
>> you can surrender the whole thing to God
and stop messing with it.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Don't stir up the ashes of the Then
sometimes better to leave a thing coent.
>> That's that's
okay.
>> Well, thank you and thank you for your
blessings in my life.
>> I feel your presence
>> in my life and I'm deeply grateful for
that.
>> So, if you let that go, it'll it'll re
it'll release itself.
>> Okay.
>> It'll release itself. All things come to
an end. Good.
>> Thank you. Blessings to you both. Thank
you.
>> Time to call it to an end. I think so.
>> Yes.
>> Hello.
>> I always feel that I need an excuse to
come up here and I come up with a
question.
>> Um, but it seems that it's reverence and
devotion and gratitude and karmic merit
that bring me here. And I guess I want
to set the intention or declaration that
I don't need the literalness
that what the wetness
that's here with you and I and
everything. The allness is with me all
present all the time and I don't need
the literalness although I love it and I
long for it.
>> Yeah. So, I wanted to know if you had
any comments about that
longing and yet knowing it's available
all the time.
>> Longing for what?
>> With you and close up and touch and
>> you own it as your as your own reality
within yourself
>> all that uh that you could do would
bring to your awareness that which
already exists within you. See,
>> and then you acknowledge it from within.
And can you do you have any suggestions
about how we can be better about
acknowledging that within?
>> Um
you just own that it is a reality within
you.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Otherwise you couldn't experience
it. You see in order to experience it it
must already exist within you. Otherwise
you would have no capacity to experience
it.
If I want to play center C on a piano, I
have to have something that vibrates at
440.
So obviously you have it within you.
Otherwise, you couldn't hear the pong
pong.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> You can't hear middle C without a
keyboard. So you have the keyboard.
>> Okay.
>> All right.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Otherwise, you wouldn't be able to
experience it.
>> Thank you. You wouldn't be able to
resonate to it if you didn't have it
already within you. It would just be
foreign to you and meaningless.
>> Seem weird sort of
going there something.
>> That's all I need.
>> Yes.
>> Hello. Uh, I've I've come really just to
say I love you and uh thank you.
>> I um I I I've read your book about five
years ago. Um I guess like a lot of
people I I looked at the the levels of
consciousness
>> and um not knowing anything about it, I
thought, where do I want to be? And I
thought, I want to live in loving
kindness. That's what I want to be. And
it changed my life.
>> Can you translate what she's saying?
>> She said that she looked at the map of
consciousness. And on the map of
consciousness,
>> she looked at it and said she wanted to
be in loving and kind.
>> Yeah. Yes. If you choose that. Yes.
>> Yes. So, she has done that.
>> Good.
>> You know, and she's just thanking for
that. Uh-huh. Yes, that's a choice.
>> Yes. And um uh I was looking forward to
you coming to London and then it got
cancelled, you know, cuz I live in
Cornwall.
>> So um I emptied out my savings account
and I came and I'm just so glad to be
here
>> and um it was just worth it all and I
just want to say I love you both.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
is that we had to deal with.
>> Yeah. And I don't So, and may I have a
photograph?
>> I love London.
>> Yeah, I I did too. I lived there 20
years and I loved But you know, if you
come, Cornwall's even better.
>> And what She says if you come see
better.
>> Oh yes. He's gone in the country.
>> I love London.
>> We have people from all over that come
see us.
>> West Minnesota took overund years to
build.
Or was it a thousand years?
>> It was empty anyway.
>> Or was it a thousand years?
>> I have kind of a hypothetical question.
>> Yes,
>> I know you don't like those,
>> but um it's a little bit of a conflict.
>> So, I'd like to see how you'd react in
this situation. Suppose you're in bed
reading a book or something and uh you
notice like a big spider on the ceiling
over your head. What would you do about
it?
>> What would I do?
>> Yeah,
>> I'd ignore the spider.
>> Yeah, but that's where I'm conflicted.
>> Yeah, but that isn't the answer I want.
>> Well, if he comes down low and then I'd
swat him. How's that?
>> That's better.
>> No, I mean I I want to have the
sacredness. I don't want to hurt the
spider.
>> Why not? I don't want him to crawl on my
face or break.
>> Oh, no. No. You want to predict
yourself?
>> No. You'd chew them away, wouldn't you?
Shoo them.
>> You just shoe them away.
>> Take them outside.
>> That's what you do.
>> That's kind of what I've been trying to
do with there's spiders in my house.
Smaller ones. But if it was a big one,
>> okay, it's the intention, right? Because
the spider's not really going to die.
just gonna or notice
>> it's gonna go out of body and come right
back as another spider.
>> Yeah. So if the fear fear overrides it,
it's kind of okay to
>> to get rid of them.
>> Right. One of my favorite places when I
first came out here to meditate and I
meditated like 10 12 hours at a time
non-stop.
And one time I looked underneath the
couch in which I was sitting
cross-legged, you know, and I looked
under the couch and there were black
widow spiders underneath the couch.
>> Oh my god.
>> They've been living there all that time.
and he didn't bother you?
>> Obviously not or I wouldn't be here.
>> Real quick, what do you think about I
heard you mention about shock therapy
for depression?
>> Yes.
>> What do you think about that for
excessive mentation or thoughtfulness?
>> I haven't heard of it used for excessive
mentation.
There may be other things for excessive
mentation within the psychiatric profile
you know dilant there's all kinds of
things that you could do depending on
what the basis of it is you know
>> just like daydreaming or something with
a thought gets energized might like over
two seconds you shock get shocked or
something just to stop the thought
process
>> uh that's a silence the mind that's a
different thing you know no that's
that's not a psychiatric problem
that's a dismental discipline problem to
withdraw your interest from it.
>> The desire for thinkingness.
>> Yeah. But withdraw your interest from
the phenomena going in going on within
your mind. Yeah.
>> Okay. I get it. Thank you.
>> Seeing it as irrelevant,
boring.
Right below the mind, you'll see there's
an infinite silent space.
Instead of focusing up here on the level
of the TV set, you focus right below the
mind. It's like the thoughts are waves
on the surface of the sea. You look
below the waves to the depth and you'll
see that all is silent and still. Look
beneath underneath the thoughts. You're
focusing up here. Underneath thoughts is
an infinite silence. Focus on the
infinite silence out of which the
thoughts arise like fish out of the
jumping out of the sea.
>> I'm trying. I just get
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, no. You're not trying. You're not
looking or I You never heard what I said
until I just said it.
>> Okay.
>> Isn't that correct?
>> Well, I've read it in your books, but
I've never assimilated it, I guess.
>> All right. So, assimilated.
>> Okay.
>> Right now, underneath our conversation,
there is a nothingness.
There's absolutely nothing. It's also
stupid we're talking about. I don't know
why we're even paying attention to it.
Underneath all this dopey talkingness,
there is an infinite silence with no
beginning and no end.
Do you sense it?
>> Mhm. I do sometimes.
>> Okay. You sense what I'm saying? Mhm.
>> It's a sense that it's there
and you would draw your interest from up
here to the to where the waves are
coming out of. See,
you don't try and stop the waves because
you won't stop the waves.
Won't stop the waves.
>> Thank you.
>> You'll get it. You'll get it. Don't
worry about it. You'll get it. You're
close to it. It's just shifting your
gaze elsewhere. your middle gears.
>> Yes.
>> Hi.
I have some words from roomie that I'd
like to dedicate to the divine beings
who
being you, Doc, and you Susan and all
your staff that have made this presence
available to us.
Burning
with longing fire,
wanting to sleep with my head on your
doors.
My living is composed
only of this trying to be in your
presence.
I have lived on the lip of insanity.
Wanting to know reasons,
knocking on a door,
it opens.
I have been knocking from the inside.
Bless you.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Um, I just have a a
real desire to express my devotion and
love for you and um
and God and um
it's like I I notice I just keep that's
all I want to do every time I come here
now.
>> Nice to hear what
I can't hear what he says.
>> All right. It's all right.
>> Okay.
>> It's all right.
>> I don't hear as well and I don't see as
well.
>> Yeah.
>> So, you'll have to put up with
>> impairments.
>> Okay. Can I um can I hold your hands and
look in your eyes for a moment?
Wow,
that was 142,000 volts.
Wow. Almost fried me.
God bless.
>> God bless you.
Dad, what you seek is already within
you.
You're disowning it.
That which you seek is within.
On the other hand, the outer allows you
to acknowledge it and experience it.
Yes.
I didn't expect that.
Thanks.
Okay. My problem, Doc, is I can see
really well. You know, like you were
talking earlier with Susan about
your vision was partly an agreement to
not be influenced by
the
visual. So, I wanted to talk to you
about um beauty versus
glamour, I guess, like what like you
know a scanly clad women cleavage is
really attractive. I can see it really
well. you know sign
this
flat women with cleavage have been seen
very well and he says you don't you
don't see that so
>> have any advice like get the question
>> you were talking earlier about your
sight and your sight can't see
>> yes he says he sees perfectly Oh, that's
his trouble,
>> right?
>> And he sees everything.
>> Don't Well, don't look at them.
>> Join an ashram. Okay.
There's certain surgical procedures that
might help.
>> He's teasing. He's teasing.
>> See, no evil. All right. It's the
torment of being uh born human.
>> Okay.
>> Driven insane by testosterone.
>> Pretty much. Yeah.
>> It's testosterone that is that will
destroy the planet
>> because it's testosterone that will or
use an atomic bomb.
Estrogen wouldn't do it.
>> All right. So, to start strong.
>> Great. Estrogen supplements. Can I take
some of those?
>> Estrogen.
>> Estrogen supplement.
>> It's a travail.
>> Yeah. And women think men delight in it.
Actually, men don't. To them, it's a
torment.
But they can't do anything about it.
Like a ravenous hunger
>> and drives them insane.
>> Pretty much. you
>> God gave reproduction
for
>> round the clock 365 days a year.
>> I'm not a man,
>> but I'm saying that it is a natural
progression.
>> Oh yeah, you can forgive yourself that
it's part of the animal heritage,
>> right?
>> It's part of our biologic heritage.
That's one of the reason we want to
transcend this realm and move on to
heaven. So you just take a lot of cold
showers where okay
>> where such torments just don't prevail
at least you know.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you
doctor.
>> Garden of Eden. Garden of Eden.
Yes.
>> Hi. I just wanted to thank you both very
much. And I felt the need. I wanted to
both let you know that my three-year-old
son joy joyously listens to all of your
CDs.
>> And what I would like is just a brief
moment of silent transmission from you.
>> I'd like to hold your hand and look in
your eyes.
>> Is that okay?
>> What you want my hand, too?
That's okay.
You sense the infinite beauty of your
reality going back through all the time.
Correct?
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
And so
>> I don't I can see
um
I
don't You have any questions?
would like to thank you both
for everything,
for what you shared this afternoon
between the two of you.
>> It was our joy.
>> It was my joy.
I'm very grateful. The beauty and the
exquisite love
>> surrounded by the love of the group. You
see, surrounded by the love of the
group.
We did what we could do. Without the
love of the group, we never could have
done it.
>> Safe.
>> Very good. Yes.
>> So many questions and resolved
many inner questions I've had. Your
questions.
And I thank you. I like to sit with you
just for a moment. Your eyes
Very good.
>> Thank you.
It's because of you. It's your fault.
>> It's me. They shake and shiver. But you
cry.
>> Hello.
>> Yeah.
I guess it's the loving that drew me
here. I guess you I don't know.
You know, but the one question I did
have was I know that I'm not the body.
And it also seems that I'm not my
thoughts. But
>> correct.
>> To be honest, that scares me.
>> Well, you can hang on to them.
>> What do you want thoughts for?
>> But I thought, is there two
consciousness that are running at the
same time? Because isn't it I am because
I think I am. And now I'm not sure
because they don't. They seem to act on
their own.
>> Well, maybe you aren't.
It's sort of an idiot that says the only
reason I am is because I think that's
pretty stupid really.
>> I think therefore I am is not the most
brilliant thing ever said on the planet
of the face of the earth.
>> It's sort of dumb when you think about
it.
>> Well, why do they just act on their own?
I mean it
>> they seem to just act on their own that
you can be attached to them or not. You
don't have to be. No, most of them are
dumb.
>> True.
>> So why would you be attached to dumb
thoughts?
>> I guess it just scares me
>> because they're yours there. So
precious.
My w was wuzzy little thought.
So sweet and adorable.
Let them go.
>> Get the hints.
>> Thank you.
>> Banish them.
Get the hints.
I think therefore I am such a dumb
thing, but it it's right on a certain
level.
>> Thank you.
>> Oh,
well made him famous. Anyway,
>> I have a question about
uh I had a question.
Oh, yeah. It did come back.
>> Uh oh. Has to do with the um uh the
stacks that come up, the emotional
stacks. And I was wondering if indeed
that uh tapping certain
um acupuncture points would expedite the
uh
>> I would think so.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. That's what I wanted to know for
my No, I I I definitely think so.
>> And uh it's a whole discipline in
itself. Yes.
>> It's a whole discipline in itself.
Therapeutic touch or something.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Well, I'm talking Yeah.
>> No. No. He's talking about touch. Yeah.
Yeah.
>> Acupuncture points.
>> That's right. Yeah. Right. Yeah. For
emotional kinds of conditions.
>> Put your fingers here and then think I
am no longer angry or something. Your
anger disappears if you touch the right
points. Yes.
>> Yeah. That's very useful technique.
>> Yes. Okay.
very useful.
>> I'm not thinking right now.
I'd appreciate some help um expanding
some awareness I have about paradigms
and just the background is that uh I
have to move between paradigms
>> right
>> just to move between paradigms
>> or help others perceive different
>> paradigms closer
>> and the idea is that if we don't learn
to do that then we increase conflict
because we alienate one group against
another. And I'm thinking about that
because my work is with the environment.
>> Is with what?
>> Environment and helping
>> environment.
>> Oh yes.
>> Um
and what I've observed is that when
people have a good time,
they want to do more of that. So we can
help improve the environment by having
people do fun things or find fun in
doing things like planting trees and
>> Yep.
>> and walking instead of
>> uh
>> whatever. But that's um there's a loop
there that our experience drives our
perceptions drives our experience. But
not everybody has the same perceptions
from an experience.
And I'm a little caught because in yoga
there's a an idea that says
you use a thorn to remove a thorn. You
use a process that drives itself
endlessly and eventually it'll root
uproot the thing that is the problem.
But you use the the problem to create
the solution.
And I can't reconcile those two things.
You can't reconcile what?
>> Well, experience can give rise to
different perceptions.
>> She's saying
>> experience can give
>> It's a long formula she's giving. Yeah.
>> Um, you're giving us this formula and
you want us to tell you the answer. So,
cut to the chase. What is the exactly
the
>> Yeah. Yeah.
the concrete instead of abstract.
>> I mean,
Is this about you or is this about the
work you're doing?
>> It's about the work.
>> The work. Yeah.
>> So, are you trying to inspire these
people about this work?
>> What I see happening is that there will
be concrete laws and regulations made to
determine people's behavior. That's the
old paradigm as a top-down kind of
>> Yes.
If we're in another paradigm that honors
people, we will encourage them and help
them to shift voluntarily.
>> Shift to what?
>> Change the behaviors they do or the way
they perceive.
>> Change them to what? What you want them
to be doing?
>> Uh, no.
>> Littering, you know,
>> instead of littering, what's wrong with
littering?
>> It messes up everything.
>> Oh, oh, that's all right. But don't mess
up. Oh, okay. Well, that I
assuming that I don't know what a great
outcome is, but assuming that we would
like to keep the earth as a place to be
a school for learning.
>> Yes.
I don't get what it is you want. You
want to increase people's appreciation
of that.
>> Yes.
>> Oh,
>> well, planting trees is good. Well, that
you know that's a practical way
>> but I mean you know
>> appreciation for the aesthetics of the
life you see
>> but then you know there's people that
will never appreciate those aesthetics
so you have to set those special places
aside so that they can appreciate them
>> because the population keeps expanding
you know all these beautiful places are
being destroyed because we keep
reproducing
>> but I'm confused about this as obvious
I'm confused about this about the uh you
know I have no right to say how things
should be.
>> Yes.
>> So
>> who says you don't have a right to say
how things should be?
>> They should be better.
>> That was better to be better.
>> You don't have a right to say how things
should be. You know, I I personally
think that if we can't control the areas
that we're living in and respect the
beauty of the areas that that we're
living in, then someone has to come in
and control it for us. I mean, that's
why we make laws
so that we can be protect we can protect
areas.
>> But you have a very legal bound society
in this country and I don't see it
>> change the laws in yours. that. No, but
I don't see it it um protecting the
environment very well.
>> I think we're trying to.
>> Is it true?
>> Yeah,
>> I think we are trying to. We don't have
one reason we're having such an oil
problem is we're not allowed to build
refineries here anymore.
>> One reason you have a war problem is
because you use a lot of oil from
overseas.
>> We may use a lot of oil, but we had a
huge
>> The only way you can get rid of the use
of oil is killing people.
If you kill off more people, they won't
use as much oil.
>> That's one. Yeah. And that's one way.
And
>> that's the only way that's got to
happen.
>> And then there's some other options
about transport.
>> But I mean, we do we have more national
parks here in the US than what half of
Europe has.
>> Yeah.
>> So, we are trying to we are trying to
preserve natural beauty here in the US.
I
>> I think I lost the thread.
>> I'm not I'm not trying
>> I don't know what she's driving. I don't
know what she's saying. should be more
environmental.
>> No, she's not saying that.
>> No, I'm not not saying that.
>> What I was
>> I mean my daughter's an environment.
>> She's talking about paradigms.
>> Yeah, I am talking about paradigms and
moving the expansion of awareness from
one to another,
>> right?
>> And so that that's voluntary.
Um
and I I that's what I I got stuck on
that our experience even if it's we have
the same experience but our perceptions
are different and so how can we leave
move from one paradigm to another
without force.
>> Well there's that certainly.
>> What did he say?
>> He said be the change.
>> Be the change. Well
Yeah,
>> we can be the change.
>> I don't know.
>> That's our destiny.
>> It's complicated. And I
>> complicated because you have one country
doing one thing to preserve it. You have
another country doing something else
that isn't.
>> You can't answer it because she's
dealing with an abstraction of
abstraction.
>> Right.
>> All right.
Okay.
>> I mean, we say don't kill the whales and
someone else says kill the whales.
>> So, how do you about that on a world
basis. It's like you're tackling a
problem.
>> I I was asking for a question, not um
>> providing an answer.
>> I don't get what her question is.
>> Well, I think that's
>> what she wants to saw is to be more
aware of
>> Okay, I'm more aware. Now what?
>> So then what?
>> I don't know. Now what?
>> Then what?
>> What else can you use beside experience
to shift awareness? A physical
experience.
>> Why do you want to shift awareness?
Isn't this a fantasy abstraction?
>> The whole world is
>> I don't get what she's trying to do.
>> You want to brainwash everybody into a
certain worldview? Is that right? We all
got to be different than what we are and
we better do it now or we're done for.
Well, what is it you want to convert?
Will you please be specific instead of
vague? And you know, you're just vague
wandering around like
>> I don't mean to be. I I would like to
see a consciousness that valued the
earth so that there was
>> What makes you think that we don't?
>> I look at energy use. I look at
deforestation.
>> None of that's got anything to do with
how you value the earth. We value the
earth tremendously because it produces
oil that makes great deal of monkey
money for the banks.
>> We've we worship this earth. What are
you talking about?
>> It's in terms of money. Yes, in
>> for in terms of usefulness.
>> Well, perhaps I could use the word
sustainability and that would make a
difference.
>> Use the word what?
>> Sustainability. So that we we
>> that we wanted to have the earth intact
its systems of
>> you want to save the world.
>> No, she wants to save the environment of
the world.
You just squeeze it dry of all its
resources and then you let God worry
about it.
>> I mean, people have been talking about
this ever since the first wheel was
developed. So, how are we going to
change it?
>> That's what
>> You can't answer it. It's too big.
>> Yeah. I mean,
>> okay.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Thank you.
you ring it dry and then give it back to
God.
>> All right.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you. Um this is my first time so
um it's wonderful to be here. I recently
watched the video of the seminar, Reason
Versus Truth. And at the end of each
DVD, there's a small video clip. It's
maybe about 45 seconds of us um on our
path.
There's an image of a straw figure with
pink sunglasses and
um some
straw bodies, you know, that we have
shed. Do you know what video I'm talking
about? No,
>> no.
>> What's the point of it?
>> That's what I was going to ask you.
>> I don't know what you're talking about.
>> There's a It's a video clip.
>> Oh, the ranch.
>> The ranch.
>> Is that the ranch?
>> Oh, the straw bodies. You mean the
scarecrows?
>> Scarecrows. The
>> that are laying on the side.
>> The tape.
>> The scarecrows are there. There's a
there's a a straw figure with pink
sunglasses.
>> Yeah, that's ours.
>> What is the meaning behind the video?
>> It's called comedy.
>> When I when I watch that video, it's a
very intense experience.
>> Oh god.
>> So, is it just supposed to be funny?
I have two witches legs that come out
from underneath with red shoes on it.
>> Uhhuh.
>> From the house
>> like the house landed on the pitch.
>> It's called comedy.
>> Okay. And that's the purpose.
>> Comedy.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> That's funny.
>> I didn't know that.
>> I don't know what she's talking about.
Yeah, I know what she's talking about.
It's comedy.
>> How's it going?
>> No, no, I'll tell you later.
>> Um, my question is I've heard you say
that uh there is no such thing as a
personal self
and um
when I first heard that I felt an
expanded sense of self.
However, I still very much feel that you
know
I am I am me. You know, I'm Brian and
how do you transcend that?
Like I still feel I'm here and you're
there and we're two people, you know,
having story, you know,
>> that may take decades.
>> Uhhuh.
It's kind of
sometimes when I feel that expanded
sense of self and then I've go back into
feeling limited again.
>> Yeah. Identifying with self. Yeah.
That's natural,
>> right?
If if you keep going in that direction,
eventually uh you transcend the the idea
of a personal self.
>> Mhm.
>> You see it as a belief system very
limited.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> I'll keep trying. Thanks.
>> Yeah.
>> You're like a movie projector. You can
play any
play any uh
>> Yeah. Right.
Yes.
>> I want to I want to take the chance to
say thanks.
>> Yes.
I uh I live in the Arctic right now.
>> And uh this is uh called a Nukshuk. Oh
yes. The
>> people they put this on the land so when
they traveled they could find their way
>> when they were lost. And uh
I just want to really say thanks.
>> Is that from Alaska?
>> This is from uh Canada. From Northwest
Territories.
>> North where?
>> Northwest Territories.
>> Northwest Territories
>> up around
>> Oh yeah.
>> The ice truckers.
>> Yes. The ice truckers.
The Ice Road Truckers.
>> Ice Roads.
>> Okay. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
>> You know the program Ice Road Truckers?
>> They don't show it up there in Canada.
>> Oh, they don't. Oh,
>> there's a where they take the ice roads
clear up to
>> the Arctic Circle.
>> The Arctic Circle.
>> We were able to see part of that. That's
his favorite show.
Maybe you can look for me next time.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you. This is lovely.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> That is beautiful. Thank you.
>> Oh, is it for 2010?
>> These are
>> Yes. Okay. I've got treasure that. Thank
you.
>> We have to hurry and get out already.
Time it is. You see what time it is?
>> Thank you. Thank you.
years ago, I um they're already signed.
Thank you. Yes.
>> Years ago, I surrendered to the Lord
before I knew about Dr. Hawkins and his
work. And and I noticed that there's
this with through surrender give up all
control there's an amazing pulling and
it goes very very fast the the along the
spiritual pathway more than I ever knew
because at that time when I uh
surrendered I didn't even know what's
enlightenment was I didn't know any of
these things and and now I'm at the
point where I feel like it's um
not just I feel the pull, but yet it
there's a slowing down. And I'm and I'm
okay if the next level, the next stages
don't happen. So the question is
when when a person leaves,
is the possibility of the next stages
they come all of a sudden?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. They may come up all of a sudden.
>> All of a sudden. So you can be out of
out of your body and then boom, you're
like a complete awareness and and and
just everything that
>> Yeah.
>> that I've seen glimpses of I've seen
these glimpses, you know, it's
>> it's not a tease. It's a wonderful
blessing.
>> But uh that's that's great hope to hear
that
>> becomes more permanent.
>> Absolutely.
>> Becomes available.
Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Yes, we got a hustle.
>> Hi.
>> Just want to say thank you.
>> Yes.
>> First time I'm here. Um earlier when you
both were talking about the spiritual
ego and you were talking about the
cities and the higher levels and how
they can have problems with the
spiritual ego. What about somebody just
starting off that's like in the 300s and
just starting to work on all the baggage
and everything to and you're starting to
feel like you're picking up that and and
getting adding that to your other
arrogance that you're starting to work
on. How do you just as you start working
on stuff that should start falling away
as well?
Okay. Thank you.
>> Thank you both.
It was quite easy question.
>> Yes, indeed.
Thank you.
That's it.
>> No, that's it. Okay.
>> Would you lead us on
>> Oh.
Where is it? My microphone. Oh, here it
is. Oh.
Oh.
I love them all the best. That's the
problem.
Give thanks to thee, oh Lord, for that
divine presence.
We give thanks to everyone here.
We've all joined together as a oneness.
We come in together and we live
together.
Everybody's afraid of dying because they
think you're going to die. First of all,
you're not going to die. And secondly,
you're not going to be alone.
It isn't fear of death that's fear of
being alone. See, because we're all
united as one. You cannot be alone. So
there is no such thing as death as the
world looks at it, which means you're
isolated, disconnected,
that you're terminal. That's the end of
the sense of a self. When you go out of
body, you don't even notice any change
of the sense of self. It's the world out
there that looks different. You're not
different. That's what looks different.
So I want to eliminate, you know, for
once and for all any fear of death.
Nail that down.
You're not allowed to have any more fear
of death. You're to see it as a welcome,
a welcome to a whole new chapter and
excitement.
And those of us who get there first will
be waiting impatiently.
There's no point in dragging your feet.
Come on. For God's sake, we want to get
going. We've got other rooms to look and
these stragglers back here. We got to
wait for stragglers.
So, we choose our our love for each
other as the ultimate reality because
our love for each other is the
expression of divinity uh as the source
of who we are. Our own existence is not
different than the love that we feel for
each other. And I give thanks to thee,
oh Lord, oh Lord, for the blessing of
these people here. And I dedicate myself
to thee and to all of the this these thy
servants. Amen.
Wow.
I experienced the group differently They
never before.
>> It's like it's growing.
>> Yeah,
>> it is growing.
>> It is.
I have so much to be thankful for.
It's hard to stand up.
Maybe the strength is
I do already.
>> I'll do it verbally.
I bless all of us here in the name of
Almighty God now and forever. Amen.
And that's enough.
We have to be careful not to fall over.
Thank you so much. It was truly a
wondrous day. Truly a wondrous day.
Truly a wondrous day. And uh
I I dedicate myself to you and and you
are God's gift to me.
So we all win. Amen.
Such a wonderful group. I I am
wonderful.
Look at the beauty of these flowers.
Aren't they unbelievable? Look at that.
So glad to see you all today. God bless
you. God bless you all indeed.
So,
>> thank you all.
All right, we have to get out of here by
a certain time
otherwise we get turned into mice.
Thanks a lot, George. Yes.
It's such a incredible group, you know.
>> Wow.
Unbelievable.
Well,
men are not supposed to cry.
All right. Thank you so much again. Is
this working? I think so.
Uhoh.
Take it away.
>> I can't help but own the child in
myself. You know,
I try to train him to be more
respectful, but
he's hopeless.
The adult in me speaks to him,
"Child,
behave."
And he says, "I am.
I'm behaving like a child."
Yeah. Perfect fulfillment of
childishness is to be childish, is it
not?
Yeah, we own the child.
We own the parent.
We own the adult.
All those aspects of ourel.
So we learn to be kind to the child in
ourself.
We learn to be child to love the child
in ourself.
The child is the divine child,
the Christ child within all of us.
Thank you.
It's a fulfillment of the feeling of
allelujah.
I thank you so much for your gift. Thank
you so much for your love.
Your love is forever.
Your love is forever. Nothing is lost.
Every hair on your head is counted. Your
love is counted forever. And I thank
you.
I rever it. Amen.
We experience the joy of that which we
are.
And other people don't even guess who
they are.
This the joy of our existence
of being with each other is
overwhelming.
If I don't resist it, I will fall on the
floor.
Exquisite beyond all time.
The moment is forever.
Beyond time. Forever.
Every hair on a head is gone.
Including this moment.
This moment is forever.
That's pretty good for an afternoon.
They want us out of here by a certain
time. So, we have to take take charge.
That's a dis that that's the
disadvantage of having a physical body.
The sooner we get rid of it, the better,
right?
Nobody can kick us out of any place.
God bless.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
Hallelu.
Uh yes, this is Clifford. Well, uh we
used to have uh Thanksgiving
And know Halloween, we had parties for
children and we'd have 30 uh kids plus
their parents and uh so it was sort of a
gayla event and we would have uh you
know games and things like that. So we
began to decorate the place with the
scarecrows around uh so just to
celebrate the event and then we sort of
got into the fun of it. So I started
making scarecrows one time. And they're
they're all articulated, you know,
everything works on them. And uh I had
about a dozen made. I had daddy, mama,
and child, you know, and I had them on
display at um local um
uh what do you call it? Greenhouse. Uh
I forget what you call call it where you
sell plants and stuff.
>> Nursery. Yes. So I had them on display
there and had them for sale. Yeah. So
the nursery had a big display on them
and homemade scarecrows.
Halloween decor. Yeah. Yeah.