It is.
>> Mhm.
>> Hi. Mhm.
>> So good to see you.
>> Yes.
>> So good to be here.
>> Well, um I'm in a bit of a dilemma and I
need um some clarification.
Uh we've learned from you that um
holding something in mind and intention
uh can increase the likelihood of
potentiality
actualizing.
>> Probability. Yep.
>> Yeah. It's a probability.
And there is um an idea current right
now um among certain spiritual
communities that um faith and belief um
can have something to do
uh with um increasing likelihoods.
>> Yes.
>> The faith and belief of the individual.
>> And that's so
>> Mhm.
>> Oh, cool. I I um I was in great conflict
about that and and um so you've just
resolved the whole thing for me. Would
that be one of the local conditions?
>> Yes.
>> All right. Cool.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Yes.
Hi.
Um, in an experiment of uh in having a
person who's, you know, at the bottom of
the box, uh, hopeless, you know, even
the ones who are in jail or in
institutions who maybe even have brain
defects that can't allow them to, you
know, learn from their experiences.
What do you think would happen if you
put them in a cell and just played kira
for him for a month?
some music
>> be illegal.
>> I I wonder because it helped me
understand the effects of of the whole
thing and and maybe somebody
>> I I don't know. It's problematic a
hypothetical case. I don't know.
>> Hypothetical.
>> Okay. in um another in another
arena. Um
but people who do archa archaeology,
would they be still be able to find um
remnants or remains of uh
u
Christ servants, you know, like
disciples or the apostles?
>> Is there is there anything left there?
>> Uh the only one I've done is the bones
of St. Peter under the in in the under
the altar in the basilica in Rome
calibrated 900
>> un unreovered though have they have they
all been recovered from under the ground
>> I don't know
okay have a good one
and they calibrated 900 that's pretty
much vindicates that it was one of the
apostles.
>> My question is about the experiencer uh
versus the witness observer. And the
other night I had a dream which I
thought was important. In the morning
when I awakened there was a part of me
analyzing the dream. Another part
simultaneously singing
the chant, "Oh Lord, hear my prayer."
And then a third part that came up an
inner voice that said thank you. So I
know that the an the analyzer was the
experiencer or the ego. What were the
other parts?
>> I I I don't know that you can label them
that distinctly. Uh the phenomena are
were occurring spontaneously. That's one
thing to that you got about it. This is
all spontaneously emerging.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. Not not contrived but spontaneous
unfoldment. Yeah. the they're just
different uh ways of looking at the
clock, you might say. It's not a
different clock. Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
It's better to release the experiencing
of experience than the experiencer
because the experiencer
uh hypothetically proposes an
independent uh agent, a personal self.
There isn't an experiencer. There's
experiencing
and witnessing the experiencing.
But there's nobody doing that.
>> I want to thank both of you for all
you've done for me in my life. And um
last fall you told me that I have
lifetimes of anger built up. So I've
been doing what you have said about
being angrier. And so I have been doing
that.
>> Good.
Get real, babe.
Um, I've got a couple of holes in my
backyard.
>> Oh my god.
>> Um,
is it going to take me lifetimes to
>> No, you can uncquirk.
>> All right. So, what's coming up is
anger.
>> Anger.
>> All right. So, what's holding the anger
down? It's fear of the anger, guilt over
the anger,
uh, reluctance to admit it. Uh if you
let go and let it be okay to be angry
and enjoy it, keep saying more, I want
more of it, more of it. You feel the
anger coming up and you let go resisting
it. Eventually, you'll run out of it.
Also, why you're angry will come up,
what you're angry about. And when you
release that, that stops the anger in
the first place. You see, because you're
not angry for no reason. You're angry
for a reason. And you can let it go. And
you'll have to get rid of the resentment
of God. You see, you're angry at God,
too. Because it weren't for this God,
you wouldn't be going through the
suffering. So, you got to forgive
yourself and forgive divinity. And see
and see that it's uh
just the uh automatic evolution of
consciousness itself unfolding in that
particular curly way there right in that
corner of your life. You know,
>> is there any way to hurry it up and get
it over with? the the more you let go
resisting it, you know, let go resist.
>> So
>> every little bit of anger I feel just be
angrier all the I mean it could be
almost all the time right now.
>> Yeah. You let go resisting it, you'll
run it out.
>> Okay.
>> You you'll run it'll eventually run out.
It's not limitless. It has to be fed all
the time.
>> Okay.
>> And something is feeding it. It'll
certainly jump in your mind what what
it's being fed about.
>> Okay.
It could be that you feel you're being
blamed for something. You're furious
about that or you didn't get something.
So, there's probably some karmic
propensity there.
>> Okay.
>> You're blamed for something. You've been
deprived of something.
>> Some more basic anger.
>> You're angry at being reborn human being
again.
>> Wow.
>> So, it's something like that.
>> Wow. Okay. Well, I'll just dig holes.
>> You promised me heaven and here I am
back on earth again. God, I'm mad as
hell.
>> Wow.
Thank you.
>> You're probably scared to look at being
angry at God, but that may be part of it
basically.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, he's the ultimate responsibility
of God is the ultimate one responsible.
>> Thank you.
>> And a lot of us unconsciously blame God.
We don't want to do it consciously.
Let's see. Um I heard a lecture a few
months ago on uh DVD or CD
and uh somebody asked about calibrating
Sedona and uh after the questioning sort
of brief answer saying um that it's kind
of a a difficult thing to answer. You
mentioned um vortexes and that's a
that's a curiosity I have is what about
the vortexes and
>> ignore them.
>> Okay. So far I have. So
>> they're all airy fairy and newagi and
woo woo woo and magic.
>> All right.
>> You'll see spaceships floating in and
out of them. It's best to just
discontinue that prairie ride.
>> Great. Thank you. And um
>> if if they had magic in them, there'd be
enlightened people all over Sedona.
>> Yep.
>> Reading the nitwit news, right?
in the funny paper logo you did the what
is it the Sedona eccentric or something
>> and just a um another question I had
about um statements more today
>> about what
>> um see about the Trojan horse of
relative be
>> relativism yesu
>> so that sort of seems to be infiltrating
currently
>> yeah that's just bringing down the
calibration Yeah.
>> So, I have some like I have some fear
about what the outcome is going to be.
>> Why should you be afraid? You're not
God. It's not your responsibility,
>> right? Okay. Good.
>> Probably a lot of people going to go off
the road and get wrecked.
>> Okay.
>> See the seduction,
the seduction of it.
>> Mhm.
>> See, the spiritual seeker is naive. He
doesn't realize being surrounded by
seduction all the time.
The Buddha mentions it directly. I
myself have been have experienced it
directly
>> that the higher you get the more that
which oppose which is opposed to
divinity, love and God's truth will come
up and
attack you actually.
>> Okay. So it seems to be
>> seduction through various means. Yes.
>> To be more that the demand is to be more
steadfast in your conviction to the
truth. That's all.
>> Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> I can do that. Okay.
>> But don't I mean you will be challenged.
I don't like to bring it up because it
makes people paranoid.
>> All right.
>> But there will come up a time when you
actually realize that you are being
challenged by the opposite of that which
you are.
>> Okay.
>> Pretty unbelievable. Sounds like a fairy
book, but it happened to me. I said, I
don't believe what's happening, but it
was.
>> Okay. And then if that when that comes
up maybe pray for protection or
guidance.
>> Refuse.
>> Refuse. Okay.
>> It's your karmic uh entitlement
to to refuse. It's as a consequent of
this human lifetime. You already have
the karmic entitlement to refuse uh the
negative. You're karmically entitled to
say get thee, hence Satan.
>> Okay.
>> Right. Thank you. And can I get a
photograph?
>> Yeah.
>> Thanks.
>> No, you're entitled to refuse it. Rebuke
it.
But it comes as a shock. You don't
realize what's happening for a little
while because it seems so outlandish and
bizarre. You can't really believe that
this is actually happening in your own
lifetime.
But I've been confronted with it in its
barest form.
>> It's very shocking.
>> Very shocking.
She wants a photo of you too without her
in it.
>> Smile. Here you go.
>> Thanks.
>> No kissing now.
Smooching in front of the camera.
>> I'll take a smooch.
>> Yeah.
Well, that picture we're going to um I
feel very blessed in this lifetime
because I have a wonderful partner and
um we live in the Blue Ridge of uh
Virginia.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> And we're creating a sanctuary there.
And during this seminar um it came to me
that we need to take some uh photos of
our spiritual teachers
um because we have uh been fortunate
enough to be in the presence of Bob
Monroe who you had calibrated and um and
now we'd like to add you to that. So
when we go back home we're going to put
the
Yes.
>> Oh yeah.
>> A wonderful man.
>> I loved his voice. He had the most
incredible voice.
>> He does.
>> It was like an angel speaking to you.
Something just wonderful about his
voice. Yeah.
>> Yes. Very much so. Very much so.
>> And I hope you're not off sugar because
I brought you a belated Valentine's.
>> Oh,
okay. Thank you.
>> We'll see if we can find a volunteer to
help us.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> And we were back. We were here in June
and I came up and had given you a gift
then and I just had to come up again.
>> Yes.
>> To be in your presence.
>> To have a glance from a person with
unconditional love into my eyes and I'd
love to thank you so much
>> and uh you're a nice messenger for Bob.
You know as I say you had the most
magical voice and I for never forget
when I read his book the first time you
see and I'd had out of body experiences.
Nobody talked about it in those days,
you know, near-death experiences, out of
body. Nobody said anything.
>> And here's his book by Monroe.
>> This poor guy is going out. He's
completely naive, having all these wild
adventures in the astral domains. Comes
back in his body and there is his
beautiful wife lying next to him and
he's guilten.
>> I thought it was so funny. And then with
a scientific engineering mind, he sets
about trying to figure out how to how to
set it up to create an alter state of
consciousness. And in the older state of
consciousness, you can leave the body at
will, you know. Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. That was fun.
>> Y
>> and you are also.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you, Susan. Thank you.
>> We used to go out a body in a group and
decide where we're going to meet in
various domains, you know. Yes,
>> it doesn't make you enlightened, but it
keeps you amused in the meantime.
All kinds of realms you can play around
with out there. Quite a few lifetimes.
Strange entities, too. Really strange.
>> Yep.
>> Hi. Thank you for all you've done. Um, I
have a question. Have you ever
considered illustrating your books?
>> No. No.
um giving it graphic you know
>> no in fact in a way I've sort of avoided
it you know yeah
>> is there a reason behind it
>> it's has to do with academic uh
tradition you read the great books of
the western world not them were
illustrated
>> um I just wondered because a lot of
times if you hold an image in your head
it it you can retain it longer the
information.
>> Oh, that's true.
>> And it's a different style of teaching.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm more academic.
>> Okay.
>> You're more girly type.
I'm more like the boring professor type,
you know.
>> Okay. Could I have a picture?
>> Yeah, sure.
Uh
>> Susan
>> just academic experience.
>> Your book.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yes.
>> My questions have been answered. Thank
you very much. My questions have been
answered.
We have a group of about 25 in uh St.
Louis that meet twice monthly and study
your work.
>> Oh.
>> Oh, nice. Yes.
>> Yes. And could I have a picture?
>> I can't hear what she's saying.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. And
hello.
Here we go.
>> Her group.
>> You want to give her name of her group?
>> Yeah.
>> Hi, Susan.
>> Several years ago,
the only thing I could say to you is
thank you.
Not much has changed.
I have a question about um every time I
get close to
putting attention on the field,
this body seems to come up with a new or
disease or get more serious in the ones
it's got. There's a
>> every time you bring up a new what?
focusing on the field and you know
seriously
>> and um and the silence behind everything
I guess is what I actually focus on.
>> Oh and
>> um out of that
um I've done everything physically,
mentally, spiritually. Yep.
>> Um, we're to the point where it seems
like the thing to do is just to
surrender to God
and let be it.
>> That's true.
>> It gradually crumbles and then it falls
over.
>> Right.
>> From dust you arose and from dust you
will return.
>> And my my main question.
>> Well, that's that's what my main
question was about.
>> You're a dustbuster.
I'm not going to turn to dust. God,
>> you made a protoplasm, a boy.
>> All protoplasm turns to dust. Oh, thank
you, Lord. I don't have to feel guilty
about dying.
>> Yep.
>> So, it's not a We have a a
responsibility
to take care and be good stewards of our
life.
>> Y
>> and thankful for having a life and being
able to even be here with you
>> and realize it's limited,
>> right? And but it's not going against
that to say it's up to you God.
>> No.
>> Okay. That's I that came up somehow and
I thought I clear that.
>> No, it's up to divinity. You have a
certain leeway a few years you can say a
little bit about here a little bit but
you're not going to change the fate of
mankind. So what you've inherited is the
karmic propensities of human existence
which means that protoplasm is temporary
>> just didn't want to leave the group
>> that's all
>> you know
>> without you. So
>> yeah we we we want to hang out and leave
you know within a couple decades of each
other.
>> Okay.
>> Same century anyway. Same half of the
century.
>> Fair enough. I hope you stay around a
long time. Well, at least I've made it
to the year. I don't know whatever it is
now. 20 something.
20 something.
>> 27. Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> So, we'll make it in the first half of
this uh Well, we get, you know, makeover
makeover. You see, about the same time
means the same century. You know what
I'm saying? Because you're talking about
bigger dimensions,
>> right?
>> You know,
>> that's fine.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you very much.
>> We all came in and out generally the
same time, you know. Yeah.
>> Thanks.
Yeah.
>> Okie dokie.
>> Dr. Hawkins, your degree of spiritual
integrity has brought up often fear and
guilt in me for the ways I've I've
lacked integrity.
And um I wanted to come up here and and
as your student as as as you being my
teacher, I wanted to ask your
forgiveness for the wrongs that I've
done in this life and in all all lives.
And I wanted to ask if you would
>> if you
>> Here's what you do. You pray to God. You
you surrender to God.
>> Yeah. You you I would do the 12 steps
like they do in a we admitted we were
powerless
over the mistakes we'd made. turned our
life over to God, made a thorough moral
inventory,
made a decision to correct the things
that we could correct, did this on a
daily basis, then sought through prayer
and supplication to increase our
conscious contact with God. There's
nothing more you can do no matter what
pathway you choose because all the
pathways are going to boil down to that
because that's aligned with inner
honesty.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
Yep.
That's very good.
>> Yes. You know your forgiveness comes
from yourself and God. God says you says
that you were forgiven when you choose
you choose Jesus Christ as your savior.
>> I do.
>> Right. So when you choose Jesus Christ
as your savior, then you must have faith
in that that that Jesus Christ will
stand for you before the father. Those
who turn to me, I will speak for before
the father. So put faith in those words
and they will become yours.
And do the 91st psalm when you get bored
with all that.
Hi Doc.
>> Yeah.
>> Hi.
>> You've you've talked a lot about the
importance of surrendering thinkingness
>> and surrendering thoughts as they arise
>> and you've spoken of how the mind can
come up with thoughts faster than we can
surrender them.
>> Is there something you could share with
us about how to work with that?
>> Yeah. process of thinking is itself and
not thoughts because thoughts are
individual and it'll create endless
arrays of them. The to let go of wanting
of uh the of thinkingness itself
uh to see that it's of no value,
>> a desire.
>> Yeah. And it's coming up because you
want to come up. So you could let go the
basic motive behind thinking this not
the thoughts because they're by the
millions but thinking in this itself
first of all gives you a sense of
continuity of a of a doer of a of an eye
a separate eye within. So you see that
the secret payoff is that there's a
separate individual eye having all these
thoughts. So it like
>> confirms the self as a reality with a
small s.
Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> Thank you.
>> You see that one through?
>> Yeah. Thanks.
>> It's not a hard one. You just look at
it.
>> Play with it. Let it be with you.
>> Yes. Hi. Um, my question I think has to
do with uh the spiritual ego perhaps.
Um, I'm noticing more often that I'll
start crying. I'll be moved with joy and
and uh I'm no sooner am I into three
seconds of crying and joy that I get
real excited that I'm crying and I'm
joyful
and then um
yeah like I'm like I'm dancing you know
what I mean and so and then
>> don't rate yourself these phenomena come
and go.
>> Yeah.
>> You know what sense to rate or value
evaluate them.
>> Yeah.
>> They come and they go. Yeah. And I
wondered if it was like an addiction to
the like the experience of of joy or
something.
>> Don't worry about the higher states.
>> Okay.
>> Don't worry about them.
>> They they come to an end of their own.
>> Okay.
>> Don't worry about getting hooked on the
higher states.
>> Yeah, that's what I was saying. Oh,
because like joy will joy will only run
so far and then you'll see the end of
joy
that you have an option to cop out and
to release it and surrender it.
>> Can I ask another question?
>> You've you've mentioned that reminding
me you say sometimes people will just
sort of go along the path and then
they'll stop at a certain level.
And so I hold the intention of
enlightenment, but I do have that
concern that if I do reach a level of
joy as a dominant level, that'll just
>> stuck in joy. What could be?
>> Yeah, I'm not even in joy.
>> Take them back to the
>> Yeah, don't worry about it.
Each thing has within itself the kernel
of its own solution.
Yes.
>> Hi. It's such an honor to be up here
with both of you. That's really the
reason I'm up here. Um well, you
answered my question about guilt. I I'd
like to ask about um you said in
previous lectures that now is a very
difficult time to be a parent and have
children. Yeah.
>> Um, as my husband and I are looking
towards that questioning that
possibility, I'm wondering if having
children is compatible with the path
towards enlightenment at this time. Your
thoughts on that?
>> I never looked at that. Um,
is it a distraction or is it an
opportunity to further your skills?
>> Exactly.
>> It would be how you hold it. It could be
that the child advances your
consciousness faster because you have to
come to unconditional love rather you
know quickly
>> and your fears about what might happen
to the child. So it brings up a lot of
things that's all.
I don't know that would necessarily
interfere
if you were yes if you were looking at
more monastic drivenness than a child
would be out of the question.
>> Okay. Do you want to or join a holy
order? No.
>> Probably not.
>> No.
>> Thank you.
>> More women are turning to it all of a
sudden. I realize no.
>> Um
>> disillusioned with the world. So those
who turned to the the holy orders in the
past fell way down and now they're
rising again. Yeah, it's interesting.
>> Uh, I came with a question from two of
your students.
Um, their mother seems to go crazy. U
maybe hearing voices
and um, I was there and her personality
was changed and um, her eyes were black
and I tried the testing of the spirits
and it seemed to work. She came back and
her personality changed everything. And
she also said she was not under control
and
>> very good.
>> But um like three or five days later um
it got worse and it seemed she's
listening hearing now three three
voices.
>> Are you are you living with this person?
>> No, no, no.
>> Well, what are you what's your
involvement?
>> Um it's the mother of two of your
students who are asking the question.
I'm here for to ask the question for
them.
>> Let's see. It's the mother of a couple
of students.
>> Yeah. asking the questions about who?
>> Um, the mother. The mother of the
students.
>> The her children are asking about the
mother.
>> Yeah. What is the question again?
>> Um,
>> she's hearing voices.
>> Is she possessed?
>> Well,
>> is that what you're asking?
>> Yeah. Or what
>> demonic possession?
>> Right.
>> Yeah. Could be.
And um also what what the treatment
could be if it's um what they could do
or
>> uh there's several pathways you can
approach it. Everything's physical,
mental and spiritual. You could approach
it through the medical.
>> Yeah. She's in
>> she's hearing voices having
hallucinations.
>> Mhm.
>> There's drugs that will block off
hallucinations and psychotic symptoms.
Yes. She's getting nerptica right now.
>> What?
>> Neurolleptica medicine.
She's already
to hear voices when there's nobody there
is termed, you know, in medicine psych
psychotic conditions usually off due to
abnormal brain chemistry. There's quite
a few medications that will correct
their brain chemistry. Then see what's
still there after that.
>> In other words, every psychotic person
isn't necessarily
possessed,
>> right?
We used to have I used to be in charge
of a hospital where we had 5,000 of
them.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. So if you just put everybody in
the hospital on an antiscychotic drug,
you know, about 35% would leave within a
week or two. All the symptoms would
disappear. You know, did have normal
brain chemistry. So I would check out
abnormal brain chemistry as the easiest,
quickest one to find out.
>> The rest could have heavy duty karmic uh
>> background and I don't think I'd get
involved in it.
>> Of of course. Yeah. But could you maybe
calibrate if it's something else too?
Like if she's possessed?
>> No. No, that isn't the way to go about
it. The way to go about it is to do it
like I said.
>> Okay.
>> Because possession is easy if you're
mentally ill. Many mentally ill people
are first mentally ill. First they
haven't got negative karma, then they're
mentally ill. Then while mentally ill,
they then also get possessed.
Thank you very much.
>> They heard God's voice talking to them,
>> right?
>> At the beginning,
>> the word the hospital used to be full of
people with God's voice talking to them.
And cerebral syphilis was common. Then
we found penicellin. God talking to
people disappeared, fell way down.
Napoleon disappeared. Jesus disappeared.
All that disappeared from the war, you
know. So everything's physical, mental,
and spiritual. So I would take the
simplest one first before you tackle
the far more difficult and esoteric. You
don't want to get involved in that.
>> And could you tell me if I picked
something up or
>> No, you didn't pick anything up.
>> Okay.
>> You're too harmless. Nobody wants you.
>> Thank you.
It wouldn't even kill anybody. What kind
of a capture would he be?
>> Yeah.
>> Hi Doc. Um I'm reading your new book and
you're talking or you're writing about
value, projecting value onto things
>> and um the exercises you've given for um
like focusing on the periphery or
focusing directly on a certain point.
>> Yeah.
>> Have been very helpful. I'm wondering if
there's something similar simple like
that that I can use
to help with the projecting value onto
people or
>> the projection of values.
>> Mhm.
>> Well, the the reality behind it is the
perfection of and ex the absolute
perfection of all that exists. So focus
and pray about the capacity to discern
the perfection
>> of everything.
>> Yes. Of everything.
Even as a killer comes at you, you
realize he's the perfect killer.
Absolute perfection.
Craziness, knife, psychosis,
hallucination,
the ultimate spook coming at you.
So no, try to see the perfection of all
that exists. So that bypass that
particularity and get more to the
generality that eliminates the
particularity, you know. You
>> see you see see what we said about that
did we not
>> you going to tell me that's beautiful or
not beautiful or perfect or defective or
what?
There's nothing you can say about that.
It wouldn't be nonsense.
It's reality.
What it means is that which it is. That
which it is shines forth in stunning
perfection.
There's nothing you have to project upon
it. Correct.
So stop describing things. Stop.
>> They don't need to be described.
>> That's the thinkingness. The
thinkingness. You see
there is what the thing is. That's its
essence. Then it's your how you feel
about it and how you see it. That's
perception.
Yeah. So spiritual awareness eventually
focuses more and more on essence and
less and less on appearance.
Yep.
>> For my work, I do some writing for a
lady here. I'm writing her memoirs and
>> it's very involved. I know it's very
involved in description and very I'm
very locked into words and
>> Oh, yeah.
>> and um
>> appearance I guess right now.
>> Yeah. No, that's fine for that
particular kind of work. It's perfect.
>> But just drop that when I walk away from
the work and
>> Yep.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you. It's okay for work, but it's
a distraction to your own personal
evolution. You know,
>> thank you.
>> Elaboration on it all. You know,
what can I write about that rose? I
could write a whole book about that
rose, what it means, what it signifies,
what it what I remember.
Yeah. Um, I have recently identified a a
repetition of the same the same the same
kind of relationship over and over and
over in my life.
>> Yeah.
>> And I'd like to know if that is a past
life thing and and if it is
what I do if I identify what it is
because it's something I just don't
know.
>> Well, you you look for the motive. You
look for the purpose. You look
>> the motive in me. Look to see what the
pattern is about yourself that
re repeats itself. What is it you're you
need to see about it? Are these
destructive relationships? Yeah.
>> Or boring.
>> Uh no, they're not
>> they're not destructive, but they're
they're not they're a bit destructive to
me. I just don't Yes, they're
destructive to me, I think.
>> Are they destructive to you? They just
don't um they're not sort of uh they're
they're nothing that grows. I think
>> it's got to grow on top of everything
else.
>> No, I mean I mean
>> they're not they're not create they're
not they're not um
>> I don't know in some sense they're not
even real. I feel like I'm sort of
projecting something in these
relationships. They're not um so they
don't sort of develop into real and
creative positive relationships.
>> Relationships got to be creative. You
put heap a lot of stuff on a
relationship. It's supposed to help you
evolve, be creative and be exciting and
have meaning and significance. Whoa boy
for the hill. Can't you just be yourself
and uh have some toast together in the
morning and play the radio or something?
Fried eggs or something? I mean, you
know, does life have to be a major
drama?
>> No. No. So, maybe I'm just
misinterpreting this.
>> Yeah, I think so.
>> Oh,
that's great.
>> When you see the intrinsic reality of a
thing, you see each one is perfect.
>> Okay,
that's great. That's a relief. Okay,
that's great.
>> What mortgage you want?
>> Thank you. Always. Thank you.
A person gives you a glance of trusting
love. There is nothing more in the
universe. What more is there
>> in a relationship? That's what else is
there.
>> Oh boy.
breakfast.
>> Hi.
>> Breakfast.
>> Oh,
>> yep.
>> It's um very nice to meet you in person.
>> Yes.
>> Uh and I'm very very grateful for your
books and your DVDs. Uh I'm I'm
relatively new to uh to to this.
>> Yes.
>> I also find the Course in Miracles very
helpful.
>> Yes.
>> And you answered my main question. It
was it was autism related. Uh so and I
haven't heard a question on course in
miracles and uh so I thought I'd ask you
one there. It relates to uh calibrations
though. Uh the um my understanding is
that Jesus dictated most of the course
of miracles. And uh when I when I read
in truth versus falsehood that the that
the u new testament uh without the book
of revelations calibrates very highly.
>> Yeah.
>> The highest 700s. Yeah. And that the
people at that time calibrated at about
the 100 level. And today in America,
people calibrated 440, but the course in
miracles, the the the textbook
calibrates around 550. It just seems
like a discrepancy. Is it is it was
>> there a discrepancy? Well, it it seemed
like for uh for
with people calibrating so highly today,
why is Jesus's message which was
dictated and written immediately?
>> Well, you don't have to buy that whole
story that it was dictated personally by
Jesus.
Jesus calibrates at a thousand. Of
course, the miracles calibrates at 550
in the book textbook in the workbook is
600. So if Jesus dictated it, we
calibrated a thousand. So it's fudging a
little.
>> That's what it seems like. So I I think
you're answering my question there.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. What the voice probably says
for Jesus. That this is a spiritual
pathway. Speaking for Jesus, but not as
Jesus.
>> I see. Do you have any feeling for what
exactly this voice is?
Yeah, I knew Helen Tripman and uh Helen
got it at what she called
interdictation.
Now there's a similar case of
interdictation that resulted in the
books that are all bound and blue
forget the name of that um
>> yeah Alice Bailey also came in her
dictation. Uh
both of them are sources of a
considerable amount of spiritual
information.
How literally to take it, I don't know.
>> I see.
>> Yeah. Uh when the last one I referred to
comes from the white brotherhood. If you
calibrate is there a white brotherhood,
you'll get yes. And if you say what is
their calibrated level, you get it's
around 650. So there's probably an area
of heaven made up of people devoted to
teaching
that uh that is their function to
respond to prayers and to request for
information.
>> Really
be my guess what's going on. Yeah. Well,
I'm pretty close to the reality of it.
I mean, when you leave the body, you got
options. You're not compelled to go any
place. You're attracted to that which
you are. If you want to learn and teach,
then you would be attracted to a
teaching brotherhood. So, the white
brotherhood
is made up of ascended teachers who
serve better in their capacity
currently than what than they would to
reincarnate. doesn't mean they won't
reincarnate some other time. But don't
forget this Israel's this civilization
going through evolutionary periods. So
you could wait on the other side to a
time when your reappearance here would
serve some higher purpose. Right now you
just get washed out with the waves.
>> Well well thank you. Thank you very
much. That was wonderful. Can I have a
picture?
>> Sure.
>> Okay.
>> Let's let's see if what I said was true.
Uh what I said is a fact resist. Yeah,
it's an intuitive knowing myself.
You have options. You see
how best how best can I serve the old
Lord? By staying in the body, by
refusing to come back in body or waiting
for a better time.
Timing is important in these things. You
come back at a wrong time, you get wiped
out and your message is lost.
>> I'm sorry. Shake your hand.
>> Yes.
>> Nice to meet you.
Yeah,
>> Dr. Hawkins, I'm a medical physician
>> who quit my practice of 21 years last
year
>> in order to heal myself and to
rediscover who I am. Y
>> um I'd like to thank you for being an
inspiration for me. what you talked on
previously earlier today about finding
out what is the best treatment
acupuncture versus medicine versus some
other means is something I've been
thinking about for the past year. Do you
know of anybody I can collaborate with
on getting more information or or to
work on on this sort of thing?
>> Well, there's going to be a meeting here
in Sedona. In fact, I in fact the reason
I'm having a Sedona is because I agreed
I would speak in the morning. I forget
the name of the group, but if you
contact their office,
>> oh, Robert,
it'll be here.
>> We're going to have it in this room. Oh,
it's going to be right here in October.
I forget the name of the group. It's a
medical group
and they're alternative medicine. In
fact, they asked me to speak for it. So,
I'm going to speak, I think, on a
Thursday morning. If you contact our
office through Robert Robert's got it
somewhere at home on on the computer,
>> it'll be right here in this this room
right here.
>> Right.
>> And whether it be doctors in alternative
medicine.
>> Yeah. It's only for a doctor's group.
>> Yeah. Doctors,
no one can sign up.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's just for doctors.
>> The second question I have is um
personal my hypertension. I've tried
medicine. I've tried Reiki. I've tried
acupuncture. I've tried everything.
>> And I don't know where my hypertension
is coming from.
>> Hypertension.
>> Well, everything's physical, mental, and
spiritual. So, you've checked out the
physical,
>> right?
>> Then you look at the mental to see if
there's any conflictual kinds of things.
Repressed anger would be, of course, the
first one you look at
>> or spiritual.
Having done that, then you turn it over
to God and say, "It's your problem."
>> Okay?
>> You take the anti-hypertensive
medicines.
low low salt diet and uh you live as
benign a life as you can. They say the
way to live a long life is to get a
chronic illness and take good care of
it.
>> Thank you. May I get a picture?
>> And if you teeter over, we'll all come
to your funeral and say, "Well, by God,
he tried, didn't he?
He wants to leave leave us back here and
be the first one back home.
>> Yeah. Okay. Good.
>> With absolute surrender, it doesn't make
any difference if the thing gets cured
or it doesn't get cured. If you really
get the course of miracles, you don't
care whether you recover or you don't
recover. You'll let go your intention in
the matter.
If you stay, you stay. And if you don't,
you don't. It's no big deal either way.
>> So, when you completely get the course
of miracles, you don't even look to be
healed anymore.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you for being here today.
>> Yeah.
>> I have a question. Um, how do you get
rid of an attach? Well, I've gotten rid
of an attachment. A specific
>> got rid of what?
>> An attachment. an attachment.
>> Attachment.
>> I've gotten rid of it, but it keeps
coming back because it means harm.
>> It's a he
>> it's it's a person.
>> A he version.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> And I need to know how to block that
out.
>> That's a complicated thing. What you
require a session to sit down, go
through this with you, what this person
means, the nature of the involvement,
whether you feel obligated, whether it's
a commitment, whether there's some
unrealized desire. It may be uh
karmically unfinished to run its course
too. You don't know. So it would take a
little research investigation
to to research what does this fully
mean? Yeah.
>> Okay. And once I am able to do that,
does does that release me to raise my
level of consciousness?
>> Oh, this uh
they're not related in a cause and
effect way. See?
>> All right. to let it go. Maybe what
you're supposed to learn or to learn to
hang on despite the negativity is maybe
what you're supposed to learn. Who's to
know which way it goes? You know,
>> that's a good one.
>> Thank you.
>> You think there's love involved? Love.
>> No.
>> Huh?
>> No, there's no love involved.
>> So, you already answered your own
question.
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Oh, a photo, please.
Yes.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. I was just uh wanted to
ask if I could be with you for a minute
here.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
So grateful for your work. Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Is that what you wanted
the frequency the energy?
>> Yeah.
>> Hello.
I have a question about
the the map of consciousness or the
scale of consciousness. You talk about
um physical death versus actual the
actual death experience and I'm just
curious if that actual death occurs at a
specific LOC or if that can occur at any
point in on the path.
>> Physical death.
>> The the actual death you talk about.
>> Yeah. Desert ego.
>> Yes.
>> Oh, that occurs um past 850. It's a it's
it's I call it the final doorway. It's
really in the 900s
to give up the core of one existence,
one's existence.
And to give up one's life totally
knowing that you're going to die
is in the 900s. I think
it's in the 900s resistance
the 960 or something.
>> I um I misunderstood one of the books
then because I thought that you had
called the final door at 599 or
something. No, final door 599.
>> 599 final door.
>> No, that's the door right before satan
when you let go of the linear. It's uh I
might have misspoken it that way in some
book. I'm not sure.
>> It's it's clear now.
>> Thank you.
>> 599 would be it would be the final door
to enlightenment because the state of
enlightenment starts at 600 and then
goes on.
>> Yeah.
>> So the ego continues past 600.
>> Well, no. No. So the states of
enlightenment begin in 600 and then they
become of a higher and higher dimension.
Yeah. And in this domain you can't go
beyond a thousand.
That's the limit of this domain. Got it.
>> 600 is plenty far to be such.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
Yes.
>> Hello.
>> It's good to be here.
>> Um, I wanted to ask a question about
if you could talk more about the
difference between true humility and
pseudo humility.
>> True humility and zero.
>> Pseudo pseudo.
>> Oh, pseudo humility. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
That's the spiritual ego. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Exactly.
>> Yeah. Spiritual ego.
So
>> uh
pseudo humility is a pose
in which one wants to deny uh the pride
because they feel guilty about it. It's
better to not feel guilty about it. Be
pride be happy than proud how far you've
uh moved along. then be willing to let
it go because you see
from where you were you're very advanced
but from where you got to go you're a
beginner.
>> All right.
>> And that brings you back your humility.
>> Mhm.
>> In the world of idiots you're a genius
but in the world of geniuses you're an
idiot.
>> I like that.
>> So the the end of spiritual pride is the
opening door to humility.
>> Cool.
>> Yeah. So, thank you.
>> There's no point to feel guilty about it
either, you know. It's a It's a natural
thing.
>> Can I have a picture, too?
>> Yeah. It's a natural thing. See,
>> we have all these 15 minutes.
>> I'm moving as fast as I can. What do you
want me to do?
>> Just
talking as fast as I can talk. Hurry up.
Come back. Run. Run. Run. Revit. Run.
Run. Rabbit. Run.
Yeah.
>> Hello.
>> Hi.
>> Um, recently I was in a discussion group
and
>> in the what?
>> A discussion group.
>> Yeah.
>> And we were discussing undoing the
doing.
Who is the doer?
>> Who is the doer? Yes.
>> Um,
and what came up was uh about speech.
How does speech arise?
up to now I would have thought I did
think
>> the languaging of it huh
>> no but speech itself
>> speech itself how speech itself came up
>> oh speech vocalization
>> vocalization
>> yes because I I would I assume that I
was the originator of
>> you're the vocalizer oh I see okay huh
>> I person
I I was asked a question who is speaking
>> yes
>> and I wasn't able to answer.
>> Oh,
>> that's good.
>> Yeah, that's fine.
>> That's really good.
>> I was wondering if you
>> There isn't anybody answering it.
Answering is answering it.
The answering is answering it. There's
no point to hypothecate an entity
is an imaginary entity that you'll then
later have to get rid of. There is no
such entity.
consciousness responded to that
situation out of its autonomous nature
as consciousness.
The fact that you happen to be in the
way of it doesn't mean that you're the
one that did it.
So if speech arises from pure
consciousness
and
it comes out less than that,
what is it that gets in the way of
>> I don't understand the way you phrase
the question?
>> Um,
>> who is the speaker when you speak? Are
you clear about that?
>> No.
>> Who do you presume is the speaker?
>> Me with this
>> me. Yeah. Yet there's an autonomous
separate eye
that is always presumed to be the
initiator of the action, the locust of
the sense of identity, the self with a
small s.
If you identify that that's what thinks
it is,
then you know what you need to transcend
because no such entity exists in
reality.
>> Mhm.
Then the unraveling of that dilemma
is the point that you're at now. How to
unravel that dilemma.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Any tips? Well,
>> it'll take it, you know, a few decades,
but you'll get there.
>> Okay.
>> The endoing of the sense of a personal
self, which is the initiator, the doer,
and the responsible one could take a
lifetime. Of course, otherwise everybody
be enlightened, wouldn't they?
So you're just you're moving in the
direction to transcend that
identification.
>> The the quickest way through is to watch
witnessing observing and see that
witnessing and observing are happening
are phenomena that are happening without
a personal eye.
Personal eye takes credit for it but the
personal eye is not witnessing or
observing.
By the time the personal eye catches on
to it, that thing is over already. So is
is the way to surrender that claim
>> the way to transcend that illusion.
Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> Focus on witnessing and observing as a
phenomena and you'll become aware in no
time. It's happening of its own. There
isn't any I or me or self-witnessing or
observing.
>> Okay.
The breathing of your nose is happening
of its own. You're not thinking, I think
I'll breathe now, now I think I'll
breathe now. It's happening of its own.
Not even voluntary, you know. It's just
autonomous.
Automatic. So see the automaticness of
it. You'll see that it's a autonomous
phenomena.
>> Thank you.
>> There is no personal eye making a
decision to be that.
It happens that way without asking him.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Um, thank you so
much for all that you give us and thank
you for your devotion to your students.
I hope you know of our devotion to you.
>> Thank you.
>> You're welcome. Um, I am committed to
being of service to humanity and I work
with angelic realm energies and I'm
wondering if it's appropriate to just
stay focused in living in the 500s to
the best of my
>> appropriate to what?
>> Stay living in the 500s.
>> Living in the energy of the 500s.
>> Yes, that's perfect. Fine.
>> Okay. And in that level, are we able to
transcend karma?
You transcend karma every time you
choose uh that which is integrous over
that which is not integrous. Yeah. You
whittle away at it. You whittle away at
it and then pretty soon the whole bank
falls down.
Having said no to certain types of
temptation repeatedly they disappear
from you know
no longer feel tempted by them.
>> Good. Thank you. And just a very quick
question I hope a friend of mine is
dying of cancer and she's adopted the
Dawkins philosophy of the god delusion.
>> Yeah.
>> As her truth.
>> And I don't know is there anything I can
do to help her to find peace?
>> Uhhuh.
>> Well, she's found peace in this uh
secularized version. So what she
perceives is that she will be
extinguished. That the personal self
will disappear into oblivion. Okay?
She's looking forward to oblivion.
Resist. She's looking forward to
oblivion.
And if she wants oblivion and loves
oblivion and chooses oblivion, she'll
experience oblivion.
And oblivion is terrific.
>> So if that's what works for her, we can
>> Don't make it personal. That's how it
works. She would stay there forever.
But because it's not the ultimate
reality, you can't stay there forever.
>> Good.
>> Oblivion is not the ultimate reality.
>> So, she'll trans you can stay there for
a few thousand years until you get bored
with oblivion.
>> I don't know what karmically brought it
back, but I came into this world in
oblivion. And frankly, I was reluctant
to see it go. I felt like a loss.
I wasn't happy to cons realize that I
existed again.
It was a shock, not pleasant.
So if living is what you chooses, so let
it be.
>> So let it be.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Let God worry about it.
>> All right. Good. Many blessings to you.
>> We've been taking too much of his work
on lately. He's buming around while we
do all the stuff here. I don't know what
he's doing there. Kicking his toes in
the clouds or what?
I love you.
>> Yeah. If she chooses oblivion, it's
okay.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Because she's being honest about her
choice, is she? She's being honest about
her choice.
>> She's done a lot of self-examination.
>> She's a self self-admitted honest
atheist. So, let her be that.
>> Okay.
>> Yep.
>> Okay. Thank you. Blessings.
There's a place where honest atheists
go.
>> They go to science college up in the
sky.
>> Hello.
>> Write papers on area subjects.
>> Yeah.
>> My friend in California asked me to say
that she sends her love, praise, and
gratitude to you.
>> Okay. Um my question while on retreat
that came up over and over um how does
one transcend the basic what feels like
a basic need of touch?
>> Basic need to what?
>> Touch.
>> Yeah. Like if you're I mean
>> yeah that's the child. Yeah.
>> Oh the child. Okay.
>> The child constantly looking for
reassurance and the animal looking for
orientation.
>> It's the child. Yeah. So, how does one
do look at the child like do the inner
child type thing or
>> it's the child within you,
right? Yes. It's not the adult.
>> Well, this adult sure does feel like she
needs to be touched.
>> Are you talking about something yourself
or somebody else?
>> No, for myself.
>> Yourself? You feel like you have to
touch everybody when you talk to them?
>> No, no, no, no. I'm just talking about
while in in in retreat where I haven't
been haven't had like
>> normal everyday affection, hugs or
whatever like I'm used to.
>> Yeah.
>> And just it's been noticing it and going
well what do how do you you know I don't
I don't know how to transcend it. Where
where how can I so if I look at the
child is do I need to work look at my
child and
>> yeah that's where it's coming from.
Yeah.
So, you got any suggestions for that or
>> Oh, grow it.
>> Okay. So,
>> can't have cookies and milk every day
after school, huh?
>> Oh, I got me on my cookies. Oh, man.
>> It's such a mean world.
>> No. Okay. So,
>> not everybody's a huggy.
>> Well, I'd have a dog or a kitty that I
could hug up, you know, hug up a big
storm all day, every day.
Y
>> so
>> and not look to people all the time
because a lot of people going to think
you're weird if you want to touch them.
>> No, I'm I'm, you know, I don't want to,
you know, I can recognize when people
need that type of thing and others
don't. Uh I'm just trying to resolve it
in myself of, you know, if I'm going to
go off and sit on a rock and stare
>> Yeah.
>> for a while,
>> if this keeps coming up, you know, it's
the one thing that keeps pulling me.
>> Oh, the touchy feeling connection. You
know, it's just like, you know, just I
grew up that way.
>> Yeah. You're reaffirming. Yeah.
Reaffirming the affection. Yes.
>> Yeah. So to transcend that is just
basically I mean is there you got to
like a little
>> let go wanting it. Let go seeing
yourself as needing it and then at the
same time see there's nothing wrong with
it.
>> Well, you're maintaining it by resisting
it. Maybe you should give into it. Say,
well, it's just a natural human
proclivity,
>> right?
So let go.
>> Wanting to change it.
>> Wanting to change that. I want that.
>> Yeah.
>> So basically go into it.
>> Yeah. Stop resisting it. Just let it let
the craving be there.
>> It'll come to you what you're seeking
with it. Reassurance, companionship,
feeling at one with others,
>> overcoming a feeling of being isolated
or alone. You know, it's probably
serving multiple purposes all the time.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I come from a really large
family, so
>> Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> All right.
>> Thank you.
>> Yep.
>> I grew up in a family where kissing and
all that wasn't really what boys did,
you know.
So, it was a different different
environment, but she came from a cuddly
feely family.
So, it's family patterning, too. Family
patterning. Yeah.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Hi. Thank you.
>> Um, I've been on I haven't been on
anything, but uh
there's been a choiceless 40-year
intense need to know.
And uh currently there is uh
there's energy that arises and it arises
it's very pleasant and it arises and
starts low and works all the way
through. And my question coming here was
that in parallel it appears that in
parallel to this more frequent energy
that arises you termed it so beautifully
the uh surrounding of seduction there's
this sense almost a how do you say it
there's this uh
pushpull kind of a thing going on it
appears um
and it's not something that I'm familiar
with um but it's something that's being
observed. So as this I don't know if
there's a correlation between the two
but I have noticed an increase in this
experience of the energy and I have just
also witnessed this
um
different aspects
that come
um
and want to continue to stay in charge.
In other words, on another lower level,
you might say, of drives and so on. And
I've heard you speak here and you've
mentioned several pointers. You know,
you've said um
in some context it's to allow it and not
resist it. Um perhaps just observe it or
in another context it's to say no, I'm
not going there.
>> Refuse it. Yeah.
>> Yes. So my question is um being that
this is being observed uh
which path would you suggest
>> to refuse?
>> To refuse or to allow
>> if you're ambivalent about it, I would
refuse it.
It was not of your choice or not your
religion. Why would you want to comply
with it?
>> Right. No, it is not.
>> Okay.
>> Mhm. Thank you.
>> It sounds like the
>> Yes.
>> No, not just that. No, she talking about
entities,
>> right? But I mean
>> the that sounded it feels as though it's
>> already answered it.
>> She's speaking of entities.
>> Two two two two separate
>> one one is the energy which is very
pleasurable that comes up quite
frequently.
>> Um and then the other
>> handling the energy perfectly normal and
fine. Yeah.
>> Okay. And the other is like a temptation
of something,
>> right? It's pulling you.
>> So I say refuse the temptation.
>> Indeed.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah, you're right.
>> Energy is just kind of leaving.
>> Yes.
>> Mhm.
>> Oops.
right around here.
>> Hello. Um, I'm wondering if you'd be
willing to calibrate this movie. I'm
trying to get out.
>> What did she say?
>> She wants us to calibrate. We don't
calibrate things.
>> Okay.
>> We won't do it here.
>> We can't because we get sometimes we get
wrong things when we calibrate it.
>> Okay. Even if it's something I made,
right?
>> It has to do with the energy of the
audience.
>> Something you made. Is that what you're
saying?
>> Right.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh. I see. Right.
>> You want to know about your own product,
whether it's good.
>> No, I just want to know um there it
seems like there's a lot of blockage in
this film going out and it's a film.
It's a service film on addiction and I'm
just thought I would try to get some
more information of perhaps why it's not
moving, why it's not going out.
>> She wants us to calibrate the movie to
find out what
>> the movie.
>> It's a movie that she made. Oh,
>> and it's about addiction and she wants
to know it isn't it doesn't seem to be
going anywhere.
>> What do you want it to go?
>> Is it based on spiritual principles?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. So, what do you want to do with
it?
>> Um, I I want it to be in treatment
facilities and jails and
>> the competition. You got you got the
world decades of the world's experts and
you're going to run into this
>> and push them off the shelf and put
yourself there. I don't think so.
>> Well, it's not okay. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> You see, a thing a thing gains ground of
its own quality. So,
you you put it out there as being
available. You bring it up in whatever
uh situations it would be appropriate
and then it seeks its own level. like a
quirk. You don't have to struggle
because a cork comes to its own level of
buoyancy. You see,
the quirks without propelling it,
without trying to make it do anything.
If it's prepared and presented with
love, that's all you need to do. The
rest takes place of its own.
People will seek it out.
>> It's hard to swallow.
Yeah, that's again a vested interest.
It's hard to be objective.
I feel once I've written it, my my deed
is done.
I'm done with it. Then what the world
does with it is never.
>> Yeah. Um I just want to say it's an
honor to meet you. Uh
>> yes.
>> And shake your hand. Thank you very
much. And um I'm just going to ask one
quick question and uh just if if you had
to give someone advice and tell them
just one thing they had to hold in mind
>> that would take them if you could give
it um
>> one thing to hold in mind. Yeah.
>> One thing to hold in mind.
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> What would it be?
>> Go ahead.
>> Constantly.
>> Yep.
>> Okay. That's all.
>> That's what you asked me.
>> Okay.
Is that the answer you want?
>> God is the complete answer to every
question.
>> There's no question that can't be
answered
by God.
>> Yes.
>> Hi, Dr. Akins.
>> No questions. I've been wanting to come
for at least three or four years and
today's the day.
>> Oh, good. Good to see you. Thank you.
Yes. Good to meet you. Yeah. Got to meet
him.
>> Three or four years.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hello.
>> I was blessed with finding the 12 steps
30 years ago.
>> Yes.
>> And it took me about six years to work
them like my life depended on it.
>> And then that opened up a spiritual
realm for me. And then I finally went
back to my Catholic roots. But then I
started going on retreats and went
beyond the religion. I mean the the
confines of the religion and that was
really wonderful. And in the course of
that I was listening to tapes of some of
the Catholic um well like um Kading and
Pennington and I was so I was really
doing some eastern practices in my
prayer and that was wonderful. Well,
eventually um
after hooking up with Stannisloff Grath,
which caused some more interchange
>> which caused
>> interchange I mean I had a lot of
experiences. I hooked back up with the
Catholic prayer but because I couldn't
find a retreat center in Las Vegas and I
was always traveling to get a weekend
retreat, there was a Buddhist monk a
mile away from me and I started going
there and I went every day for about
seven years. So, I've had these
wonderful experiences and learned a lot
of things from both. But now, I feel
like I I would never want to give up
what I learned from Buddhism. I had a
great teacher. And yet, I think what I
did was I pushed away the I didn't push
away. I let go of the
um praying to God because that's not
what we did there.
>> You let go of what?
>> God. Praying to God.
>> Praying to God. Let go of praying to
God.
>> And just did the practice of vaposa.
>> You did the practice of what?
>> Vaposana. Insight meditation with the
breath.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Okay.
>> So now I'm at this place where I love
both.
>> Yes.
>> And yet I'm 55 now and I'd like to find
something that
is more directive for me or that gives
me more direction. I feel pulled both
ways and I
>> You feel different. Why do you feel the
different ways? feels the pull of the
Catholic religion and yet she also feels
the pull of of the
>> it's not so much the Catholic it's well
that's just it and why why am I I'm
having this conflict about it
>> well there was a group here when I first
came to Sedona they met where there's
now a big uh resort
>> and uh
where is that resort wherever it is
anyway down village
>> Hilton
>> I forget it was 70 acres or something
anyway it was a retreat center and uh
he was run by an order of Catholic
brothers, monks.
Uh they called themselves uh Zen
Catholicism
>> and they had separate little places.
Everybody lived all by themsel, you see.
>> They also had a meditation ka in the
middle with very thick brick walls and a
thick carpet
>> and one little window. Absolute silence.
Huh?
>> Right.
>> I went there for years and before that
was Sedona wasn't populated yet. You
know, there's only 2 or 3 thousand. They
called themselves Zen Catholicism.
They then when the population of Sedona
began to increase, they moved up to
Colorado. I forget the name of the town.
Colorado.
>> Snow Mass.
>> No, Snow Mass is a different one. I've
been there. That's Benedicting, I think.
>> That's right. Uh, if you track them out,
you can probably find where they moved
to. I forget the name of the town. Uh,
but theirs was a combination of the best
of the two, you know, and they didn't
see any conflict and I don't see any
conflict either.
>> I understand. Thank you.
>> There is no conflict because truth is
truth.
>> So, uh, you know, what kind of wallpaper
you put on it doesn't change the essence
of it.
>> Okay. You know, just because the Buddha
said, "Don't use the term God."
>> We did a diagnosis that the Buddha
experienced the presence of God.
>> Yeah. Let's see. We have permission
here. Resist. The Buddha experienced the
presence of God. Resist.
>> Resist. But you notice he didn't call it
the presence of God.
Why? Because otherwise he couldn't have
reached a thousand. He calibrates at a
thousand. The only way to get to
calibrate at a thousand is if you
experience the reality of the presence
of God.
So although he may verbally say don't
use the term God because everybody's so
cuckoo about the whole subject, you'll
never get there. You'll be chasing your
own definition.
>> Devotion then will take you to the
ultimate truth either way.
>> Thank you.
There's no conflict between the two.
>> Just because the Buddhist said don't use
the term God doesn't mean that there
isn't a God. Just he said don't talk
that way because you'll be misleading
people down all kinds of belief systems.
>> Y
>> thank you so much for all the work
you're doing and for helping make the
nonlinear linear. I appreciate it. Um, I
have a question that has to do with my
health and I've had a lot of eye
problems in the last six years, multiple
eye problems and I I've been in a
spiritual path for many years and I'm
trying to determine and I've been
working with teachers to discover if
this is something karmic, if this is
something uh that a lesson I'm trying to
learn on my spiritual path or if I'm
causing this on some level and if so,
what can I do about it? You're already
doing what you can do about it. You're
researching it on multiple levels
simultaneously.
So you picture yourself,
you picture the issue as resolving. You
surrender to it if it is of a karmic uh
nature. Yeah.
>> You surrender to it.
>> You do all of them at the same time.
>> Okay. How do I surrender if it's karmic?
I'm not sure I understand.
>> How do you surrender what?
>> How do I surrender to it if it's karmic?
If I understood what you said. Is that
correct? like you surrender to anything.
>> Okay. Just turn it over to God
essentially.
>> Let go when to change it. Yes. Picture
it as healing.
>> Okay.
>> Picture it as u and picture it as the
undoing and accept it for what it is.
Huh. And ask for a miracle.
>> You do the course of miracles.
>> I've known about it for 30 years and I
keep keeps coming up. So I think it's
time for me to do it. I saw a lot of
miracles amongst groups of course of
miracles recovery from all kinds of
ailments and ill illnesses
but not all because as you as you say
many have a karmic proponent component
and they are serving a purpose uh
whatever that is happening. Mhm. So you
do what you can physical mental and
spiritual with that the same as any
other ailment you know.
>> Okay. Okay. and then just surrender and
release it and try not to think about
it. I think I tend to dwell on it.
>> Yeah.
>> So, okay. Very good. Thank you so much.
>> If it's possible to recover, you see
some things are possible to recover,
other things are not possible.
Some things are just protoplasmic
deterioration. You know what I'm saying?
>> Right? But nothing seems to be
hereditary or genetic.
>> There be anything that you can do
anything. Okay? So you do with what you
can physical, mental and spiritual and
the rest you surrender to God.
>> Okay. Very good. Thank you so much.
>> The rest is up to God and your own
karma.
>> I'm honored to be here and I am also a
student of the course of miracles. But I
have a
>> um medical question just about
protoplasmic deterioration of the bones
and um I was wondering if Fossomax is
the best thing to do.
>> It could be for you at a specific time
talking about osteoporosis. You got an
internist handling this?
>> Um just my regular general practitioner.
>> I had a bone scan. Yeah.
>> You had a bone density.
>> Yes.
>> Says that you're you got
demineralization.
>> Yes.
>> You can look in DeForio. F O R T EO.
>> Okay.
Forio, which is parathyroid hormone
injections that may increase the
likelihood and rapidity of healing, plus
enough calcium in the diet to take care
of the additional request. Ask your
doctor about 40 fo
t.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, these are shots.
>> That's okay.
>> Shot. You got to give yourself.
>> I hate the the pill.
>> Yep.
>> Um
>> her thyroid hormone plus you take extra
calcium.
Yeah,
>> it's just something to look into.
>> Oh, okay. Good idea.
>> It's just something to look into.
>> All right.
>> Look into 40. It may be an additional
help in your case.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Thanks.
>> There's also a thing called an
anti-gravity machine which uh
uh is used in space um which call it
that are up there.
>> Space station.
>> Yeah. Zero gravity. that bones will
demineralize under zero gravity. So they
have a what they call anti-gravity
machine.
>> It recreates it imitates the impact of
if you were on this planet.
So there's two things you can do. An
anti-gravity
machine and uh try look check out for
those two things together should make a
difference.
>> Thanks.
>> Don't say I told you.
>> Okay.
>> Picture. Hey, you read in a book
somewhere.
>> No,
>> I heard the other day there was
something on TV about it. Don't go
blaming me.
>> I forget how much those anti-gravity
machines are. I don't think they're as
expensive as they once were.
They're cheaper than a car. Anyway,
>> my question
>> my question is how in in your practice,
how do you find the best way to balance
the business world with the spiritual
world and being in peace with that?
>> We don't
>> don't see it don't see it as a conflict.
Don't see it as a conflict. The
business's world is is one way. Uh in
other words, they overlap. You know,
they overlap. Each one can serve the
other. In the business world, you get
the testing of how far you've gotten
spiritually.
And then
in the spiritual world, you get a chance
to influence the business world by
virtue of that which you have become.
>> That's good.
>> By virtue of that which you have become,
you begin to influence it. You know the
famous book Jack, you know Jack,
president of GE or GM or whatever. Yeah.
Right.
what he became be, you know, influenced
the whole industry, didn't it?
>> Right?
>> You remember a picture of him there? I
think he's in his late 60s and he's got
a torso like a like an athlete. You know
what I say? You say, "Well, this guy was
driven to perfection." And uh
>> so he's he stood as a role model of
integrity and reaching the highest level
of performance, you see. So it can be
inspirational. So I don't see the two as
conflictual.
because of spiritual
uh alignment you may you may decline
certain business opportunities that
other people would avail themselves of
>> and I would just say I can't do that you
know right but your department maybe if
you want to do that you know
>> great thank you
>> Milky Ways cure cancer however you want
to sell make money but I wouldn't do it
see you could decline it
>> but make sure they understand you're
declining it for the of the company and
the good and welfare of the organization
too, you know, not just for your own
personal weird weirdness.
>> Okay. Can I have a picture with you
>> so they don't consider you a weirdo? You
know, one of them holy roller weirdo
types.
>> There's 50 cents for a smile.
>> You don't want to
business.
>> I'll sell you a blessing for 50 cents.
Now that's merging spiritual and
business, right?
That's what he just said, didn't he?
That's funny, isn't it?
Oh, put it in the plate at church, you
know.
>> I love this picture.
>> If you go sign up for me. Thank you.
>> Yep.
>> I don't know if this question has been
asked before or if I missed it in one of
your books. Is it possible for someone
to incarnate in this lifetime, be
profoundly mentally challenged, almost
non-verbal,
and still be at 500?
>> I doubt it.
>> You doubt it?
>> I can't sign it there.
You're talking about a person born deaf
and dumb.
>> No, not deaf and dumb, right?
>> But they don't read or write and they
don't speak.
>> What is the diagnosis? Autistic or what?
>> I don't have a diagnosis.
>> Is it some relative?
>> No, I've just had the privilege of being
with a small group for quite a few
months. And there's one gentleman who
just has a beautiful energy field and
twinkle in his eyes and kind of
mischievous and he just seemed like he
was very high vibration.
>> Oh. Oh. Uh-huh.
So it's not really a matter of concern
to you.
>> No.
>> Oh, okay. All right. I didn't
>> I thought there's no resistance to
>> Uhhuh.
>> consciousness. Is it possible?
>> Is it possible? Yes, it possible. Now I
see why what you're asking.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Helen Keller was born deaf, dumb, and
blind.
And I forget what she calibrated, 580 or
something.
>> Hello. Thank you both. Um I'm uh the
father of two daughters, third and fifth
grade, and had question about uh
schooling. Is there um a level
calibration that would be acceptable
that when you look for schools for your
kids?
>> Well, what I'd look for is at least in
the 300s. That's willingness,
helpfulness, cheerfulness,
a good ball team kind of energy.
>> There's 300s. Yeah. And one other quick
question their mother would want to ask
is there a risk put um of with education
getting stuck in the 400s in the
intellectualization
intellectualization.
>> Yeah. But that's not due to the
education. It's just the the person's
interest would stop there. But it's not
due to the education itself. No.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you sis.
Yes,
>> Dr. Hawkins and Susan, I'd like to thank
you both for making yourselves available
to us, uh, continuing to do so. I would
just like to ask for a moment of silent
transmission from my teacher and a
photo.
>> Ah, yes, if
>> I may do that.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Oh, and I also have 50 cents for a
smile. Smile.
>> Smile.
>> Don't quit your day job.
>> I want to We'll put them into play the
church. Yeah.
>> Hi, Doc. You already answered my
question, so I just wanted to hold your
hand and tell you I love you.
>> Thank you. Thank you very much.
>> Oh, hi.
>> Hi.
>> I know we're running really I know we're
running really late, so I um I saw this
after I left in December at the airport.
So, it you won't use it till next
season, but it's so cute.
Oh.
>> So, anyways, that's
>> we love it.
>> Thank you.
>> Favorite time of the year.
>> Thank you. Thank you, Susan.
>> Oh, God.
A
This is our weakness, guys.
>> M. Don't be telling them that
>> these little I have them in the office
and everyone goes, "Oh, no. Here she
comes with a little thing. She's going
to press this and then they're going to
sing all over the place." But we we have
a weakness for these little toys like
this. So,
>> now you wouldn't have said it.
>> I know.
>> You said that we like jello. We have a
whole bathtub full of jello.
>> They are cute.
>> They are indeed.
>> They care for us.
>> Yeah.
>> Well,
I've been going through a psychoanalysis
uh for about a year and I recognize I'm
sitting with so much anxiety like it
feels like it's right here in my stomach
all the time. Um and I realize now that
it's been there for pretty much my whole
life.
It's it's like fear, anxiety. It it it
even came up great
like when I wanted to ask this question,
I almost turned away from it for some
reason. I'm comfortable to talk about it
like oneon-one, but in front of an
audience, it brings that same why it
came up. It brings that same feeling up
of anxiety, fear, it's kind of connected
with that place that I'm walking around
with. And in the analysis, there's so
many specific things that are coming up
that that I've never even looked at
before, but it's comes up all the time.
sometimes so strong
and at times I want to sleep to avoid it
>> and it's just
take I mean even to come up here it just
it's just a uh I can't even explain it's
fearful anxiety and it comes up
sometimes when I'm doing some things
like
>> how often do you see your therapist
>> well I used to see him like twice a week
because it was in Florida I used to see
him twice a week for about two you know
four hours for the week and now like I'm
living in New York. So, I do it on the
phone. I developed a comfort with them.
So, I didn't want to change
um once a week for an hour now, hour and
a half. I feel like it's been really
helpful, but it it's it's uh it's
arduous and I feel like I'm constantly
in myself like in it's always about me.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, and I see value in it because
I'm noticing things that I've denied
before, but it seems like such a
narciss. always about me and I'm
analyzing everything about myself all
the time.
>> Well, that's a phase and then you try
first you understand the ego, you
unravel it.
>> Yeah.
>> Then you take it apart. Once it's been
unraveled, then you see what is how it's
constructed and how it got that way.
>> Then you do more general spiritual work
with it. You forgive yourself for it
being the way it is. And you allow
yourself to be human. You allow yourself
to have defects if you want to view them
as defects.
You view yourself as evolutionary.
Yeah. You view the
understanding u first understand
yourself. It says over the top of the
whatchamacall
know thyself you know know thyself.
So it's important period of
investigation to know understand of
course what you're investigating
primarily is the ego
>> uh but uh to disassemble it uh is first
to become familiar with it. So I think
it's a good adventure you're doing to
become more enlightened about your own
the nature of one's own ego and how it
got to be that way.
the contributions of the various people
and the various cultures and
value systems.
>> It seems like there's like endless
things to overcome. I mean endless. I
get in like I've dealt with a father
complex thing for a while because that
was what I felt like was important. Now
>> you're talking about overcome. No, it
isn't a matter of overcoming. It's a
matter of outdooring, transcending it,
seeing the nature of it, and then
letting it go.
>> Yeah.
>> So familiarizing with it, that's all.
>> Huh. So just becoming more familiar with
it and then
>> yeah because insight itself tends to
release you from the conflict. See
>> insight itself tends to release you.
>> Yeah it has cuz I don't resent my dad
anymore.
>> So you you see if you have a dream and
you understand the elements of the dream
then the the conflict that the dream
represents tends to resolve itself.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> You're working on it. That's
>> You're working on it. That's what's
important. You're not refusing it.
You're not ignoring it, you know. Yes.
>> I'm grateful to be in your presence.
I'm an actor and I love what I do. I
find that it's my calling and I have an
idea that um as an actor sometimes I
have to imagine horrible things and
awful things you know imaginary
circumstances and I I have an idea that
maybe that might be dangerous because
you teach that you know whatever you
hold in mind you manifest.
>> Why is it you have to do this? Is this
acting school or something? Yeah, like
acting classes or when you're in a show
and you're playing someone who might be,
you know, in a horrible situation.
>> Oh, so you're supposed to pick picture
this ugly situation like that respond to
that
>> because it's an artificial thing. It's
just an image in your mind. It's like a
movie. Yes. I don't see why it's any
different than a movie itself
because it's optional. You've chosen to
do that. So, you're in control of it.
>> Okay.
But you also say that consciousness is
naive, you know, and like every time I
go to class or I I honor the work and
and then I I feel depressed
>> because I believe I believe in the
circumstances for that moment and for
the next couple of days I'm depressed.
>> You you believe in the that which you
imagine.
>> Yeah, we're supposed to.
>> They become they become
>> Well, you become that which you're
imagining.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know. I don't have any
experience with that.
Okay.
>> You'd have to have a strong sense of the
reality of that which you are and see
this other is play
and be able to, you know, differentiate
between the two. One is play and the
other is who you are.
>> I have another quick question. And I'm
kind of embarrassed to ask this, but I
also have another worry that once you
leave this world, the average
calibration of mankind will kind of go
under
like below 205 or something. And that's
something that I worry about
>> something I worry about.
>> We surrender the world to God. You see,
we surrender the world to God. and and
uh God's will is what manifests. And
so we surrender our will to God. What
will be will be to thee, oh Lord. You
surrender to thee, oh Lord. Do I
surrender this world and my place in it
and its destiny?
>> Thank you.
This world is a perfect place for
fulfillment of karmic potential, for the
undoing of the negative and the gaining
of the positive,
including surrendering the world to God.
I've never been an enthusiast for saving
the world parades.
First of all, they're too dangerous.
Yeah.
>> Okay. That was the last question.
>> What?
>> That was the last question.
>> Yeah, I knew it was the last question
and I just got through answering it.
>> So that
Oh god.
Thank you again for the tremendous gift
of being with you this entire day. Wow.
What a wonderful gift
to be with all such wonderful people for
a whole day. We share our our experience
of each other. Each one of us is seen
back and forth in the other one's eyes
and reflected back and forth. So as his
eyes look into me and reflect into me,
then I would look into his eyes, they
reflect back. And so we become there's a
certain connectedness that goes back and
forth until we all become sort of enshed
in one unity.
God bless us everyone. We give thanks to
thee oh Lord for thy presence.
I give thanks to thee, oh Lord, for
being
allowed to be the teacher of such
wondrous people. Amen.
YEAH,
I thought I thought everybody had left.
Look out here and you're all still here.
How can you still be here if you just
left?
>> We're not quite ready to detach.
>> Okay. God, love you all so much. I love
you all so much.
>> Thank you so much.
Love you all so much. God bless you.
>> Wow.
Too much.
All right, we're done.
Hallelujah.
Halle
Hallelu.
Hallelujah.