Hello
song.
I
I got
I got the
I got the first
I got the first hug
I got the first hug in
I got the first hug in hug.
Good
Good morning
I got the first hug in hug.
Good morning everyone.
>> The
>> The weather
>> The weather has
>> The weather has changed
>> The weather has changed here.
Nobody
Nobody complains
>> The weather has changed here.
Nobody complains that
Nobody complains that it's
>> The weather has changed here.
Nobody complains that it's always
Nobody complains that it's always hot
and
and sunshiny
and sunshiny here
and sunshiny here now.
So
So the
and sunshiny here now.
So the nose
So the nose is
and sunshiny here now.
So the nose is a
So the nose is a little
and sunshiny here now.
So the nose is a little stuffy.
So the nose is a little stuffy. You'll
have
have to
have to forgive
have to forgive the
have to forgive the nose.
Anyway,
Anyway, it's
have to forgive the nose.
Anyway, it's so
Anyway, it's so wonderful
have to forgive the nose.
Anyway, it's so wonderful to
Anyway, it's so wonderful to see
have to forgive the nose.
Anyway, it's so wonderful to see you
Anyway, it's so wonderful to see you all
again.
again. Every
again. Every every
again. Every every meeting,
again. Every every meeting, every
again. Every every meeting, every time
again. Every every meeting, every time I
look
look around,
it's
it's like
it's like forever,
it's like forever, you
it's like forever, you know.
it's like forever, you know. Everyone
it's like forever, you know. Everyone is
like
like forever
it's like forever, you know. Everyone is
like forever within.
I
I look
I look at
I look at everyone
I look at everyone and
I look at everyone and each
I look at everyone and each one
I look at everyone and each one is
forever.
And
And I
And I realize
And I realize it's
And I realize it's forever,
which
which is
And I realize it's forever,
which is a
which is a nice
And I realize it's forever,
which is a nice thing,
which is a nice thing, isn't
And I realize it's forever,
which is a nice thing, isn't it?
Instead
Instead of
Instead of a
Instead of a temporary
Instead of a temporary brush
Instead of a temporary brush off,
it's
it's nice
Instead of a temporary brush off,
it's nice that
it's nice that we're
Instead of a temporary brush off,
it's nice that we're all
it's nice that we're all sort
Instead of a temporary brush off,
it's nice that we're all sort of
together
together forever.
together forever. We
together forever. We said
together forever. We said came
together forever. We said came in
together forever. We said came in here
together
together and
together forever. We said came in here
together and uh
together and uh then
together forever. We said came in here
together and uh then we'll
together and uh then we'll probably
together forever. We said came in here
together and uh then we'll probably be
leaving
leaving together.
You
You first.
leaving together.
You first. And
as
as you
as you can
as you can see,
as you can see, I'm
as you can see, I'm very
as you can see, I'm very serious
as you can see, I'm very serious about
life
life and
as you can see, I'm very serious about
life and death.
And
And that's
And that's one
And that's one of
And that's one of the
And that's one of the problems
And that's one of the problems with
And that's one of the problems with the
mystic
mystic is
And that's one of the problems with the
mystic is taking
mystic is taking things
And that's one of the problems with the
mystic is taking things seriously.
mystic is taking things seriously. And
the
the world
the world takes
the world takes everything
the world takes everything seriously.
And
And that
the world takes everything seriously.
And that makes
And that makes you
the world takes everything seriously.
And that makes you something
And that makes you something of
the world takes everything seriously.
And that makes you something of a
misfit.
So
So let's
misfit.
So let's be
So let's be seated
misfit.
So let's be seated and
So let's be seated and see
misfit.
So let's be seated and see what
So let's be seated and see what the
speaker
speaker has
speaker has to
speaker has to speak
speaker has to speak about
speaker has to speak about this
speaker has to speak about this morning.
The
The title
speaker has to speak about this morning.
The title says
The title says the
speaker has to speak about this morning.
The title says the mystic
about
about which
about which I
about which I know
about which I know nothing
about which I know nothing at
about which I know nothing at all.
And
And uh
about which I know nothing at all.
And uh but
And uh but it's
about which I know nothing at all.
And uh but it's the
And uh but it's the favorite
about which I know nothing at all.
And uh but it's the favorite the
favorite
favorite subject
favorite subject this
favorite subject this favorite
favorite subject this favorite subject
in
in which
favorite subject this favorite subject
in which uh
that
that which
that which is
that which is linear
that which is linear tries
that which is linear tries to
that which is linear tries to describe
that
that which
that which is linear tries to describe
that which is
that which is nonlinear
and
and doesn't
and doesn't exist.
and doesn't exist. So
other
other than
and doesn't exist. So
other than that,
ambiguities
ambiguities of
ambiguities of language,
ambiguities of language, you
ambiguities of language, you know,
ambiguities
ambiguities of
ambiguities of language, you know,
ambiguities of language.
Uh
Uh first
Uh first we'll
Uh first we'll define
Uh first we'll define what
Uh first we'll define what a
Uh first we'll define what a mystic
Uh first we'll define what a mystic is
and
and how
Uh first we'll define what a mystic is
and how you
and how you get
Uh first we'll define what a mystic is
and how you get to
and how you get to be
Uh first we'll define what a mystic is
and how you get to be one
and how you get to be one and
Uh first we'll define what a mystic is
and how you get to be one and uh
and how you get to be one and uh what's
the
the cure,
the cure, the
the cure, the condition
the cure, the condition anyway.
So
So let's
the cure, the condition anyway.
So let's see.
So let's see. We're
the cure, the condition anyway.
So let's see. We're going
So let's see. We're going to
the cure, the condition anyway.
So let's see. We're going to start
So let's see. We're going to start with
the
the first
the first slide
the first slide and
the first slide and uh
the first slide and uh we're
the first slide and uh we're not
the first slide and uh we're not going
to
to do
the first slide and uh we're not going
to do much
to do much of
the first slide and uh we're not going
to do much of a
to do much of a review
the first slide and uh we're not going
to do much of a review today
to do much of a review today because
the first slide and uh we're not going
to do much of a review today because how
many
many people
many people here
many people here are
many people here are new
many people here are new for
many people here are new for the
many people here are new for the first
time.
Uhhuh.
Uhhuh. Well,
Uhhuh. Well, they'll
Uhhuh. Well, they'll get
Uhhuh. Well, they'll get they'll
Uhhuh. Well, they'll get they'll get
they'll
they'll catch
Uhhuh. Well, they'll get they'll get
they'll catch up.
Well,
Well, we're
Well, we're not
Well, we're not going
Well, we're not going to
Well, we're not going to do
Well, we're not going to do we
Well, we're not going to do we usually
do
do something
Well, we're not going to do we usually
do something of
do something of a
Well, we're not going to do we usually
do something of a review,
do something of a review, you
Well, we're not going to do we usually
do something of a review, you know,
do something of a review, you know, for
half
half an
half an hour
half an hour or
half an hour or so.
half an hour or so. Anyway,
half an hour or so. Anyway, today
half an hour or so. Anyway, today we'll
only
only do
half an hour or so. Anyway, today we'll
only do a
only do a few
half an hour or so. Anyway, today we'll
only do a few slides
only do a few slides just
half an hour or so. Anyway, today we'll
only do a few slides just so
only do a few slides just so that
half an hour or so. Anyway, today we'll
only do a few slides just so that we're
all
all uh
all uh on
all uh on the
all uh on the same
all uh on the same game
all uh on the same game board,
all uh on the same game board, that's
all.
all. So,
all uh on the same game board, that's
all. So, let's
all. So, let's light
all uh on the same game board, that's
all. So, let's light up
all. So, let's light up the
all uh on the same game board, that's
all. So, let's light up the Oh,
all. So, let's light up the Oh, isn't
that
that gorgeous?
that gorgeous? I
that gorgeous? I can
that gorgeous? I can see
that gorgeous? I can see it
that gorgeous? I can see it and
everything.
What
What does
What does that
What does that say?
The
The map
What does that say?
The map of
The map of consciousness
What does that say?
The map of consciousness is
The map of consciousness is a
What does that say?
The map of consciousness is a handy
reference
reference guide
reference guide and
reference guide and it
reference guide and it sort
reference guide and it sort of
reference guide and it sort of has
changed
changed a
reference guide and it sort of has
changed a great
changed a great many
reference guide and it sort of has
changed a great many things
changed a great many things just
reference guide and it sort of has
changed a great many things just to
changed a great many things just to have
a
a point
a point of
a point of reference.
a point of reference. This
a point of reference. This is
a point of reference. This is sort
a point of reference. This is sort of
like
like a
a point of reference. This is sort of
like a scale,
like a scale, a
a point of reference. This is sort of
like a scale, a thermometer,
like a scale, a thermometer, barometer,
uh
uh altimeter,
uh altimeter, it
uh altimeter, it gives
uh altimeter, it gives you
uh altimeter, it gives you some
uh
uh point
uh altimeter, it gives you some
uh point of
uh point of reference
and
and because
and because it's
and because it's stationary,
and because it's stationary, it
and because it's stationary, it forms
and because it's stationary, it forms an
absolute
absolute scale
and because it's stationary, it forms an
absolute scale and
absolute scale and all
and because it's stationary, it forms an
absolute scale and all can
absolute scale and all can be
and because it's stationary, it forms an
absolute scale and all can be calibrated
and
and u
and u placed
and u placed somewhere
and u placed somewhere along
and u placed somewhere along the
and u placed somewhere along the scale
as
as a
and u placed somewhere along the scale
as a number.
as a number. Now
and u placed somewhere along the scale
as a number. Now the
as a number. Now the number
and u placed somewhere along the scale
as a number. Now the number is
as a number. Now the number is not
and u placed somewhere along the scale
as a number. Now the number is not a
judgment.
It's
It's not
judgment.
It's not a
It's not a moral
judgment.
It's not a moral statement.
It's not a moral statement. It's
judgment.
It's not a moral statement. It's just
It's not a moral statement. It's just a
number.
People
People get
number.
People get very
People get very excited
number.
People get very excited about
People get very excited about the
numbers
numbers and
numbers and I
numbers and I always
numbers and I always tell
numbers and I always tell them
numbers and I always tell them it's
numbers and I always tell them it's just
a
a number.
numbers and I always tell them it's just
a number. It
a number. It doesn't
numbers and I always tell them it's just
a number. It doesn't mean
a number. It doesn't mean anything
at
at all
except
except you're
at all
except you're going
except you're going to
at all
except you're going to die
except you're going to die shortly
at all
except you're going to die shortly but
doesn't
doesn't mean
doesn't mean anything.
doesn't mean anything. No.
doesn't mean anything. No. So
doesn't mean anything. No. So the
doesn't mean anything. No. So the number
it
it significance
doesn't mean anything. No. So the number
it significance depends
it significance depends on
doesn't mean anything. No. So the number
it significance depends on the
it significance depends on the context
in
in which
in which you
in which you are
in which you are asking
in which you are asking it.
in which you are asking it. So
in which you are asking it. So the
answer
answer we
in which you are asking it. So the
answer we get
answer we get then
uh
uh depends
uh depends on
uh depends on the
uh depends on the question
uh depends on the question and
uh depends on the question and the
answer
answer having
uh depends on the question and the
answer having an
answer having an equivalent
uh depends on the question and the
answer having an equivalent reality.
answer having an equivalent reality. If
the
the question
the question has
the question has a
the question has a reality,
the question has a reality, you
the question has a reality, you get
the question has a reality, you get a
positive
positive uh
the question has a reality, you get a
positive uh response
positive uh response if
the question has a reality, you get a
positive uh response if it
positive uh response if it has
the question has a reality, you get a
positive uh response if it has no
reality.
reality. So
reality. So that
reality. So that which
reality. So that which is
reality. So that which is false
reality. So that which is false is
reality. So that which is false is only
false
false because
reality. So that which is false is only
false because it
false because it has
reality. So that which is false is only
false because it has no
false because it has no reality.
So
So the
So the test
So the test is
So the test is really
So the test is really not
So the test is really not one
So the test is really not one of
So the test is really not one of truth
versus
versus falsehood.
So the test is really not one of truth
versus falsehood. It's
versus falsehood. It's of
So the test is really not one of truth
versus falsehood. It's of reality
versus falsehood. It's of reality versus
non-reality.
That
That which
non-reality.
That which is
That which is false
non-reality.
That which is false has
That which is false has no
non-reality.
That which is false has no reality
That which is false has no reality in
the
the infinite
the infinite field
the infinite field of
the infinite field of consciousness.
the infinite field of consciousness. So
therefore,
therefore, there's
the infinite field of consciousness. So
therefore, there's no
therefore, there's no response.
the infinite field of consciousness. So
therefore, there's no response. So
therefore, there's no response. So the
test
test is
test is either
test is either on
test is either on or
test is either on or not
test is either on or not on.
test is either on or not on. It's
test is either on or not on. It's not
yes
yes or
test is either on or not on. It's not
yes or no.
yes or no. It's
test is either on or not on. It's not
yes or no. It's either
yes or no. It's either on
test is either on or not on. It's not
yes or no. It's either on or
yes or no. It's either on or not
test is either on or not on. It's not
yes or no. It's either on or not on
which
which correlates
which correlates of
which correlates of course
which correlates of course with
which correlates of course with advanced
theoretical
theoretical quantum
which correlates of course with advanced
theoretical quantum mechanics,
theoretical quantum mechanics, physics
and
and theory
and theory thereof.
Uh
Uh I
and theory thereof.
Uh I don't
Uh I don't know
and theory thereof.
Uh I don't know what
Uh I don't know what all
and theory thereof.
Uh I don't know what all that
Uh I don't know what all that means
and theory thereof.
Uh I don't know what all that means but
it
it sounds
it sounds very
it sounds very good
it sounds very good doesn't
it sounds very good doesn't it?
That
That which
it sounds very good doesn't it?
That which has
That which has existence.
So
So if
So if I
So if I say
So if I say to
So if I say to her
so
so and
So if I say to her
so and so
so and so so
So if I say to her
so and so so and
so and so so and so
So if I say to her
so and so so and so if
so and so so and so if it
So if I say to her
so and so so and so if it if
so and so so and so if it if that
So if I say to her
so and so so and so if it if that is
true
true then
true then the
true then the arm
true then the arm goes
true then the arm goes strong.
Now
Now I
true then the arm goes strong.
Now I don't
Now I don't know
true then the arm goes strong.
Now I don't know whether
Now I don't know whether it's
true then the arm goes strong.
Now I don't know whether it's true
Now I don't know whether it's true or
not.
not. So
not. So it's
not. So it's the
not. So it's the my
not. So it's the my opinion
not. So it's the my opinion and
not. So it's the my opinion and her
opinion
opinion are
not. So it's the my opinion and her
opinion are irrelevant.
You're
You're really
You're really asking
You're really asking the
You're really asking the infinite
You're really asking the infinite field
of
of consciousness
You're really asking the infinite field
of consciousness using
of consciousness using the
You're really asking the infinite field
of consciousness using the mechanism
of consciousness using the mechanism of
quantum
quantum mechanics
to
to collapse
quantum mechanics
to collapse the
to collapse the wave
quantum mechanics
to collapse the wave function
to collapse the wave function from
potential
potential to
potential to actual.
All
All right.
potential to actual.
All right. So,
All right. So, when
potential to actual.
All right. So, when when
All right. So, when when your
potential to actual.
All right. So, when when your question
matches
matches reality,
matches reality, you
matches reality, you get
matches reality, you get a
matches reality, you get a strong
response.
All right.
All right. So,
we'll
we'll uh
All right. So,
we'll uh you're
we'll uh you're all
All right. So,
we'll uh you're all familiar
we'll uh you're all familiar with
All right. So,
we'll uh you're all familiar with this,
so
so we
so we won't
so we won't waste
so we won't waste more
so we won't waste more time
so we won't waste more time on
so we won't waste more time on it.
Uh
Uh what's
so we won't waste more time on it.
Uh what's the
Uh what's the next
so we won't waste more time on it.
Uh what's the next one?
Uh
Uh this
Uh this explains
Uh this explains the
Uh this explains the conditions
Uh this explains the conditions of
Uh this explains the conditions of the
world.
This
This explains
This explains the
This explains the nightly
This explains the nightly news.
Whole
Whole civilization
This explains the nightly news.
Whole civilization shake
Whole civilization shake at
This explains the nightly news.
Whole civilization shake at the
Whole civilization shake at the thought
of
of a
of a teddy
of a teddy bear.
Whole
Whole civilizations
of a teddy bear.
Whole civilizations quick
a
a teddy
a teddy bear.
So
So here's
a teddy bear.
So here's the
So here's the teddy
a teddy bear.
So here's the teddy bear
So here's the teddy bear people
a teddy bear.
So here's the teddy bear people over
here.
They
They shake
here.
They shake with
They shake with teddy
here.
They shake with teddy bears.
Okay.
Okay. And
Okay. And the
Okay. And the people
Okay. And the people here
Okay. And the people here think
Okay. And the people here think it
Okay. And the people here think it com
teddy
teddy bear
Okay. And the people here think it com
teddy bear is
teddy bear is comical.
I
I think
I think that's
I think that's comical.
I think that's comical. Don't
I think that's comical. Don't you,
I think that's comical. Don't you, sir?
So
So what's
I think that's comical. Don't you, sir?
So what's comical
So what's comical here
is
is enough
is enough to
is enough to kill
is enough to kill you
is enough to kill you for
is enough to kill you for here.
is enough to kill you for here. So
is enough to kill you for here. So it
makes
makes quite
is enough to kill you for here. So it
makes quite a
makes quite a difference,
is enough to kill you for here. So it
makes quite a difference, doesn't
makes quite a difference, doesn't it?
The
The calibrated
The calibrated level
The calibrated level of
The calibrated level of consciousness
whether
whether it's
The calibrated level of consciousness
whether it's going
whether it's going to
The calibrated level of consciousness
whether it's going to lead
whether it's going to lead to
The calibrated level of consciousness
whether it's going to lead to amusement
or
or death,
blow
blow you
or death,
blow you up,
blow you up, or
or death,
blow you up, or make
blow you up, or make you
or death,
blow you up, or make you giggle.
These
These people
These people here
These people here giggle.
These people here giggle. These
These people here giggle. These people
here
here blow
These people here giggle. These people
here blow you
here blow you up.
These people here giggle. These people
here blow you up. So
here blow you up. So that
These people here giggle. These people
here blow you up. So that does
here blow you up. So that does make
These people here giggle. These people
here blow you up. So that does make a
difference.
They
They seem
difference.
They seem to
They seem to don't
difference.
They seem to don't seem
They seem to don't seem to
difference.
They seem to don't seem to have
They seem to don't seem to have any
sense
sense of
sense of humor
sense of humor for
sense of humor for God's
sense of humor for God's sake.
Next.
Without
Without a
Without a sense
Without a sense of
Without a sense of humor,
Without a sense of humor, you
Without a sense of humor, you can't
really
really survive
Without a sense of humor, you can't
really survive in
really survive in this
Without a sense of humor, you can't
really survive in this planet.
People
People think
People think they
People think they do,
People think they do, but
People think they do, but they
People think they do, but they didn't
really
really survive
People think they do, but they didn't
really survive just
really survive just because
People think they do, but they didn't
really survive just because their
really survive just because their body's
still
still walking
still walking around.
still walking around. They
still walking around. They think
still walking around. They think they
survived.
So
So this
So this is
So this is the
So this is the the
So this is the the explanation
So this is the the explanation of
So this is the the explanation of it
So this is the the explanation of it in
scientific
scientific terms.
So this is the the explanation of it in
scientific terms. You
scientific terms. You see
So this is the the explanation of it in
scientific terms. You see that
scientific terms. You see that which
So this is the the explanation of it in
scientific terms. You see that which has
reality
reality collapses
reality collapses the
reality collapses the wave
reality collapses the wave function
which
which is
reality collapses the wave function
which is intrinsic
which is intrinsic to
reality collapses the wave function
which is intrinsic to the
which is intrinsic to the whole
reality collapses the wave function
which is intrinsic to the whole response
that
that we
that we use
that we use for
that we use for calibration.
All
All right,
that we use for calibration.
All right, that's
All right, that's enough
that we use for calibration.
All right, that's enough of
All right, that's enough of that.
The
The other
The other implication
The other implication of
The other implication of profound
importance
is
is the
is the impact
is the impact of
is the impact of spiritual
is the impact of spiritual intention
is the impact of spiritual intention on
brain
brain function.
is the impact of spiritual intention on
brain function. And
brain function. And you
is the impact of spiritual intention on
brain function. And you see
brain function. And you see that
the
the 85%
the 85% below
the 85% below 200
uh
uh have
the 85% below 200
uh have a
uh have a different
the 85% below 200
uh have a different brain
uh have a different brain function.
the 85% below 200
uh have a different brain function. I
forgot
forgot my
forgot my pointer.
forgot my pointer. Oh
forgot my pointer. Oh well,
forgot my pointer. Oh well, I
forgot my pointer. Oh well, I know
forgot my pointer. Oh well, I know where
it's
it's it's
forgot my pointer. Oh well, I know where
it's it's in
it's it's in the
forgot my pointer. Oh well, I know where
it's it's in the front
it's it's in the front of
forgot my pointer. Oh well, I know where
it's it's in the front of my
it's it's in the front of my body
forgot my pointer. Oh well, I know where
it's it's in the front of my body bag.
Yeah.
uh
uh the
Yeah.
uh the reason
uh the reason for
Yeah.
uh the reason for compassion
uh the reason for compassion see
Yeah.
uh the reason for compassion see Jesus
Christ
Christ the
Christ the Buddha
Christ the Buddha all
Christ the Buddha all said
Christ the Buddha all said that
Christ the Buddha all said that man's
only
only problem
Christ the Buddha all said that man's
only problem is
only problem is ignorance
Christ the Buddha all said that man's
only problem is ignorance and
only problem is ignorance and and
Christ the Buddha all said that man's
only problem is ignorance and and and
the
the ignorance
manifests
actually
actually in
actually in brain
actually in brain function
actually in brain function the
actually in brain function the reason
actually in brain function the reason to
be
be compassionate
actually in brain function the reason to
be compassionate for
be compassionate for people
actually in brain function the reason to
be compassionate for people that
be compassionate for people that don't
know
know any
know any better
know any better is
know any better is they
know any better is they don't
know any better is they don't they
know any better is they don't they are
not
not able
know any better is they don't they are
not able to
not able to know
know any better is they don't they are
not able to know better
to
to be
to be able
to be able to
to be able to recogize
to be able to recogize ize
to be able to recogize ize truth
to be able to recogize ize truth and
respond
respond and
to be able to recogize ize truth and
respond and and and
respond and and and and
respect
respect it
respect it is
respect it is because
your
your brain
respect it is because
your brain functions
your brain functions this
respect it is because
your brain functions this way.
your brain functions this way. So
respect it is because
your brain functions this way. So this
is
is the
is the brain
is the brain function
is the brain function of
is the brain function of a
is the brain function of a group
is the brain function of a group like
this
compared
compared to
compared to the
compared to the rest
compared to the rest of
compared to the rest of the
compared to the rest of the world.
You're
You're weirdos.
You
You realize
You realize you're
You realize you're in
You realize you're in the
You realize you're in the minority.
Therefore,
Therefore, the
You realize you're in the minority.
Therefore, the whole
Therefore, the whole level
You realize you're in the minority.
Therefore, the whole level survival
Therefore, the whole level survival of
the
the human
the human race
the human race is
the human race is because
the human race is because there
the human race is because there are
enough
enough people
the human race is because there are
enough people at
enough people at the
the human race is because there are
enough people at the top
enough people at the top of
the human race is because there are
enough people at the top of the
enough people at the top of the scale
the human race is because there are
enough people at the top of the scale to
counterbalance
counterbalance the
counterbalance the negativity
uh
uh below
counterbalance the negativity
uh below 200
uh below 200 otherwise
counterbalance the negativity
uh below 200 otherwise humanity
uh below 200 otherwise humanity would
self-destruct.
Uh
so
so you
so you ask
so you ask me
so you ask me how
so you ask me how how
so you ask me how how can
so you ask me how how can you
so you ask me how how can you how
so you ask me how how can you how can
you
you integrate
so you ask me how how can you how can
you integrate these
you integrate these two
so you ask me how how can you how can
you integrate these two different
populations?
You
You can't
the
the book
the book I'm
the book I'm finishing.
the book I'm finishing. I
the book I'm finishing. I can
the book I'm finishing. I can hear
the book I'm finishing. I can hear the
reader's
reader's expectation
the book I'm finishing. I can hear the
reader's expectation rises
reader's expectation rises as
the book I'm finishing. I can hear the
reader's expectation rises as you
describe
describe these
describe these two
describe these two different
describe these two different populations
and
and they're
describe these two different populations
and they're sure
and they're sure by
describe these two different populations
and they're sure by the
and they're sure by the end
describe these two different populations
and they're sure by the end of
and they're sure by the end of the
chapter
chapter you're
chapter you're going
chapter you're going to
chapter you're going to show
chapter you're going to show how
chapter you're going to show how you
chapter you're going to show how you can
how
how you
chapter you're going to show how you can
how you going
how you going to
chapter you're going to show how you can
how you going to all
how you going to all make
chapter you're going to show how you can
how you going to all make friends
how you going to all make friends and
dance
dance around
dance around the
dance around the maple
dance around the maple and
dance around the maple and be
dance around the maple and be happy.
And
And I
dance around the maple and be happy.
And I just
And I just conclude
dance around the maple and be happy.
And I just conclude it's
And I just conclude it's obvious
dance around the maple and be happy.
And I just conclude it's obvious you
can't.
How
How are
can't.
How are you
How are you gonna
can't.
How are you gonna get
How are you gonna get along
can't.
How are you gonna get along with
How are you gonna get along with poison
ivy?
ivy? You
ivy? You ain't
the
the way
ivy? You ain't
the way you
the way you get
ivy? You ain't
the way you get along
the way you get along with
ivy? You ain't
the way you get along with poison
the way you get along with poison ivy
ivy? You ain't
the way you get along with poison ivy is
this
this way.
You
You don't
this way.
You don't dance
You don't dance through
this way.
You don't dance through the
You don't dance through the poison
this way.
You don't dance through the poison ivy
singing
singing la.
Oh,
Oh, we're
singing la.
Oh, we're so
Oh, we're so spiritual.
Spiritual
Spiritual doesn't
Spiritual doesn't mean
Spiritual doesn't mean kindergarten
naivity.
It's
It's realizing
It's realizing that
that
that some
It's realizing that
that some people
that some people have
It's realizing that
that some people have a
that some people have a totally
different
different brain
different brain function
different brain function than
different brain function than the
different brain function than the rest
of
of people
different brain function than the rest
of people and
of people and that
different brain function than the rest
of people and that allows
of people and that allows for
compassion.
compassion. Therefore,
compassion. Therefore, Jesus
compassion. Therefore, Jesus Christ,
compassion. Therefore, Jesus Christ, you
know,
know, said
that
that uh
that uh the
that uh the only
that uh the only problem
that uh the only problem is
that uh the only problem is ignorance.
So
So did
that uh the only problem is ignorance.
So did the
So did the Buddha
ignorance.
But
But this
ignorance.
But this explains
But this explains the
ignorance.
But this explains the phenomena
But this explains the phenomena that
ignorance.
But this explains the phenomena that we
see
see internationally,
see internationally, politics,
religion,
religion, all
see internationally, politics,
religion, all uh
religion, all uh areas
see internationally, politics,
religion, all uh areas of
religion, all uh areas of man's
see internationally, politics,
religion, all uh areas of man's life
religion, all uh areas of man's life are
divided
divided up
divided up really
divided up really between
uh
uh two
divided up really between
uh two different
uh two different kinds
divided up really between
uh two different kinds of
uh two different kinds of brain
function.
That's
That's a
function.
That's a fact.
When
When you
When you study
When you study biology,
When you study biology, there's
When you study biology, there's certain
facts
facts you
When you study biology, there's certain
facts you have
facts you have to
When you study biology, there's certain
facts you have to accept.
facts you have to accept. Understand
When you study biology, there's certain
facts you have to accept. Understand it?
Yes.
Yes. Black
Yes. Black Widow
Yes. Black Widow spider
Yes. Black Widow spider will
Yes. Black Widow spider will not
Yes. Black Widow spider will not be
Yes. Black Widow spider will not be your
friend.
You
You can
You can hold
You can hold him
You can hold him in
You can hold him in your
You can hold him in your hand
You can hold him in your hand and
You can hold him in your hand and tell
him
him he's
You can hold him in your hand and tell
him he's adorable
him he's adorable and
You can hold him in your hand and tell
him he's adorable and you
him he's adorable and you forgive
You can hold him in your hand and tell
him he's adorable and you forgive him
and
and he'll
and he'll kill
and he'll kill you
because
because that's
and he'll kill you
because that's his
because that's his nature
and he'll kill you
because that's his nature to
because that's his nature to kill
and he'll kill you
because that's his nature to kill you.
He's
He's supposed
He's supposed to
He's supposed to do
He's supposed to do that.
He's supposed to do that. If
He's supposed to do that. If he
He's supposed to do that. If he didn't
do
do that,
He's supposed to do that. If he didn't
do that, there
do that, there wouldn't
He's supposed to do that. If he didn't
do that, there wouldn't be
do that, there wouldn't be any
He's supposed to do that. If he didn't
do that, there wouldn't be any black
widow
widow spiders.
Of
Of course,
widow spiders.
Of course, we
Of course, we could
widow spiders.
Of course, we could live
Of course, we could live without
widow spiders.
Of course, we could live without them.
I
I can
I can remember
I can remember one
I can remember one time
I can remember one time I
I can remember one time I I
I can remember one time I I came
I can remember one time I I came out
west.
west. I
I can remember one time I I came out
west. I lived
west. I lived by
I can remember one time I I came out
west. I lived by myself
west. I lived by myself in
I can remember one time I I came out
west. I lived by myself in a
west. I lived by myself in a one-man
monastery.
Six
Six huge
monastery.
Six huge place,
Six huge place, six
monastery.
Six huge place, six bedrooms
Six huge place, six bedrooms and
monastery.
Six huge place, six bedrooms and giant
rooms
rooms and
rooms and a
rooms and a big
rooms and a big fireplace
rooms and a big fireplace and
rooms and a big fireplace and all
rooms and a big fireplace and all just
me.
So
So I
So I spent
So I spent months
So I spent months all
So I spent months all day
So I spent months all day pretty
So I spent months all day pretty much
around
around the
So I spent months all day pretty much
around the clock
around the clock meditating.
One
One time
One time I
One time I dropped
One time I dropped something
One time I dropped something on
One time I dropped something on the
floor.
floor. I
One time I dropped something on the
floor. I went
floor. I went down
One time I dropped something on the
floor. I went down the
floor. I went down the floor
One time I dropped something on the
floor. I went down the floor and
floor. I went down the floor and I
looked
looked under
looked under this
looked under this couch
looked under this couch where
looked under this couch where I'd
looked under this couch where I'd been
meditating
meditating for
looked under this couch where I'd been
meditating for the
meditating for the last
looked under this couch where I'd been
meditating for the last year
meditating for the last year or
looked under this couch where I'd been
meditating for the last year or two.
There
There was
There was all
There was all kinds
There was all kinds of
There was all kinds of black
There was all kinds of black widow
spiders
spiders living
There was all kinds of black widow
spiders living under
spiders living under there.
There was all kinds of black widow
spiders living under there. I've
spiders living under there. I've been
sitting
sitting right
sitting right above
sitting right above black
sitting right above black widow
sitting right above black widow spiders
for
for months
sitting right above black widow spiders
for months and
for months and months
sitting right above black widow spiders
for months and months and
for months and months and months
sitting right above black widow spiders
for months and months and months on
for months and months and months on it.
Meditating.
Meditating. It's
Meditating. It's hysterical.
Well,
Well, we
Meditating. It's hysterical.
Well, we both
Well, we both practice
Meditating. It's hysterical.
Well, we both practice live
Well, we both practice live and
Meditating. It's hysterical.
Well, we both practice live and let
live,
live, you
live, you know.
So,
So, I
live, you know.
So, I guess
So, I guess live
live, you know.
So, I guess live and
So, I guess live and let
live, you know.
So, I guess live and let live
So, I guess live and let live is
live, you know.
So, I guess live and let live is the
best
best resolution.
best resolution. Live
best resolution. Live and
best resolution. Live and let
best resolution. Live and let live.
Let
Let the
best resolution. Live and let live.
Let the black
Let the black widow
best resolution. Live and let live.
Let the black widow spiders
Let the black widow spiders be
best resolution. Live and let live.
Let the black widow spiders be where
they
they are
they are and
they are and you
they are and you stay
they are and you stay where
they are and you stay where you
they are and you stay where you are,
which
which is
they are and you stay where you are,
which is not
which is not where
they are and you stay where you are,
which is not where they
which is not where they are.
they are and you stay where you are,
which is not where they are. That's
which is not where they are. That's the
best
best way
best way to
best way to do.
All right.
All right. So,
best way to do.
All right. So, we'll
All right. So, we'll go
best way to do.
All right. So, we'll go to
All right. So, we'll go to the
best way to do.
All right. So, we'll go to the next
slide.
Oh,
Oh, illumination.
Oh, yes.
Oh, yes. I
Oh, yes. I forgot
Oh, yes. I forgot we
Oh, yes. I forgot we were
Oh, yes. I forgot we were talking
Oh, yes. I forgot we were talking about
what's
what's the
Oh, yes. I forgot we were talking about
what's the lecture
what's the lecture today
Oh, yes. I forgot we were talking about
what's the lecture today about
what's the lecture today about the
Oh, yes. I forgot we were talking about
what's the lecture today about the uh
the
the mystic.
the mystic. Oh,
the mystic. Oh, yes.
Well,
the
the speaker
the speaker today
the speaker today will
the speaker today will describe
as
as best
the speaker today will describe
as best as
as best as possible.
Now,
Now, the
Now, the speaker
is
is really
Now, the speaker
is really an
is really an observer.
Now, the speaker
is really an observer. The
is really an observer. The observer,
Now, the speaker
is really an observer. The observer, the
witness,
witness, the
witness, the observer,
witness, the observer, the
witness, the observer, the witness.
witness, the observer, the witness. So,
the
the the
witness, the observer, the witness. So,
the the mystic
the the mystic solemn
witness, the observer, the witness. So,
the the mystic solemn uses
the the mystic solemn uses the
witness, the observer, the witness. So,
the the mystic solemn uses the pronoun
the the mystic solemn uses the pronoun I
and
and you.
and you. You'll
and you. You'll notice
and you. You'll notice in
and you. You'll notice in fact
and you. You'll notice in fact people
write
write write
and you. You'll notice in fact people
write write me
write write me complaining
and you. You'll notice in fact people
write write me complaining about
write write me complaining about that.
The
The books
The books there's
The books there's no
The books there's no I
The books there's no I and
The books there's no I and you.
Everything
Everything is
The books there's no I and you.
Everything is in
Everything is in the
The books there's no I and you.
Everything is in the detached
Everything is in the detached third
person.
person. You
person. You see,
person. You see, you
person. You see, you witness
person. You see, you witness the
phenomena.
But
But there's
But there's no
But there's no inclusion
But there's no inclusion of
But there's no inclusion of the
But there's no inclusion of the pronoun
I.
The
The average
The average person
The average person says,
The average person says, "It
The average person says, "It was
The average person says, "It was raining
on
on me
The average person says, "It was raining
on me yesterday."
And
And you
And you know,
And you know, the
And you know, the mystic
And you know, the mystic says,
And you know, the mystic says, "It
And you know, the mystic says, "It was
raining
raining yesterday,
And you know, the mystic says, "It was
raining yesterday, but
raining yesterday, but not
And you know, the mystic says, "It was
raining yesterday, but not on
raining yesterday, but not on me."
And you know, the mystic says, "It was
raining yesterday, but not on me." You
see,
so
so the
see,
so the pronoun
so the pronoun is
see,
so the pronoun is left
so the pronoun is left out.
So
So there's
So there's a
So there's a detachment
So there's a detachment because
So there's a detachment because what
you're
you're describing
So there's a detachment because what
you're describing is
you're describing is phenomena
So there's a detachment because what
you're describing is phenomena from
you're describing is phenomena from the
viewpoint
viewpoint of
viewpoint of the
viewpoint of the witness.
The
The witness
viewpoint of the witness.
The witness observes
The witness observes and
viewpoint of the witness.
The witness observes and then
The witness observes and then reports
back
back its
back its observations
without
without making
back its observations
without making critical
evaluations
evaluations of
evaluations of it.
evaluations of it. You
evaluations of it. You see?
All
All right.
evaluations of it. You see?
All right. So
All right. So the
evaluations of it. You see?
All right. So the pathway
All right. So the pathway then
evaluations of it. You see?
All right. So the pathway then is
through
through non-conceptual
non-conceptual
non-conceptual thinking.
So
So the
So the way
So the way of
So the way of Zen
So the way of Zen is
So the way of Zen is to
So the way of Zen is to let
So the way of Zen is to let go
So the way of Zen is to let go of
So the way of Zen is to let go of all
conceptual
conceptual thinking
So the way of Zen is to let go of all
conceptual thinking because
conceptual thinking because it's
So the way of Zen is to let go of all
conceptual thinking because it's all
judgmental
judgmental and
judgmental and it's
judgmental and it's all
judgmental and it's all illusory
judgmental and it's all illusory because
you're
you're only
judgmental and it's all illusory because
you're only talking
you're only talking about
judgmental and it's all illusory because
you're only talking about perception.
You're
You're only
You're only saying
You're only saying about
You're only saying about perception.
All
All right.
You're only saying about perception.
All right. So
All right. So illumination.
You're only saying about perception.
All right. So illumination. I
All right. So illumination. I don't
if
if I've
if I've ever
if I've ever seen
if I've ever seen this.
if I've ever seen this. Have
if I've ever seen this. Have I
if I've ever seen this. Have I ever
if I've ever seen this. Have I ever seen
this?
this? I
if I've ever seen this. Have I ever seen
this? I don't
this? I don't know.
Yes,
technically
technically it
Yes,
technically it begins
technically it begins at
Yes,
technically it begins at level
technically it begins at level 600.
Level
Level 600
Level 600 uh
Level 600 uh is
Level 600 uh is a
Level 600 uh is a state
Level 600 uh is a state of
Level 600 uh is a state of infinite
peace.
peace. It's
Level 600 uh is a state of infinite
peace. It's satananda.
Uh
Uh the
Uh the preceding
Uh the preceding stages
Uh the preceding stages are
Uh the preceding stages are those
Uh the preceding stages are those of
love
love and
Uh the preceding stages are those of
love and then
love and then eventually
Uh the preceding stages are those of
love and then eventually ecstasy
uh
uh great
uh great joy.
And
And then
uh great joy.
And then when
And then when you
uh great joy.
And then when you let
And then when you let go
uh great joy.
And then when you let go of
And then when you let go of all
uh great joy.
And then when you let go of all that
there
there is
there is a
there is a state
there is a state of
there is a state of infinite
there is a state of infinite timeless
peace
uh
uh and
uh and it
uh and it is
uh and it is the
uh and it is the peace
uh and it is the peace of
uh and it is the peace of God
uh and it is the peace of God that
chitananda.
chitananda. So
uh and it is the peace of God that
chitananda. So the
chitananda. So the beginning
uh and it is the peace of God that
chitananda. So the beginning of
chitananda. So the beginning of the
illuminated
illuminated states
illuminated states then
illuminated states then is
illuminated states then is it
calibration
calibration level
illuminated states then is it
calibration level 600?
calibration level 600? Yes.
The
The state
The state is
The state is one
The state is one of
The state is one of inner
The state is one of inner silence,
stillness,
stillness, a
The state is one of inner silence,
stillness, a feeling
stillness, a feeling of
The state is one of inner silence,
stillness, a feeling of completion.
Uh
Uh it
Uh it is
Uh it is luminous.
Uh it is luminous. It's
Uh it is luminous. It's one
Uh it is luminous. It's one of
revelation.
It's
It's all
It's all inclusive
It's all inclusive and
It's all inclusive and it's
It's all inclusive and it's in
intrinsic.
intrinsic. It
It's all inclusive and it's in
intrinsic. It stems
intrinsic. It stems from
It's all inclusive and it's in
intrinsic. It stems from within.
It's
It's motionless.
It's sachetan
It's sachetan meaning
It's motionless.
It's sachetan meaning bliss.
It's sachetan meaning bliss. There
It's motionless.
It's sachetan meaning bliss. There is
It's sachetan meaning bliss. There is an
infinite
infinite presence.
infinite presence. The
infinite presence. The presence
infinite presence. The presence of
infinite presence. The presence of the
infinite
infinite peace
infinite presence. The presence of the
infinite peace of
infinite peace of God
infinite presence. The presence of the
infinite peace of God which
infinite peace of God which is
infinite presence. The presence of the
infinite peace of God which is the
essence
essence of
essence of divinity
essence of divinity unfolding.
essence of divinity unfolding. Oh
essence of divinity unfolding. Oh yes.
It
It says
essence of divinity unfolding. Oh yes.
It says satan
It says satan right
essence of divinity unfolding. Oh yes.
It says satan right there.
It
It it's
It it's an
It it's an emergence.
It it's an emergence. It's
It it's an emergence. It's an
It it's an emergence. It's an affluence.
Uh
Uh it
It it's an emergence. It's an affluence.
Uh it is
Uh it is also
It it's an emergence. It's an affluence.
Uh it is also silent
Uh it is also silent and
It it's an emergence. It's an affluence.
Uh it is also silent and wordless
and
and it
and it is
and it is all-encompassing.
It's
It's transformative
and it is all-encompassing.
It's transformative and
It's transformative and one
and it is all-encompassing.
It's transformative and one realizes
that
that is
that is one's
that is one's identity.
that is one's identity. That's
that is one's identity. That's who
that is one's identity. That's who who
or
or what
that is one's identity. That's who who
or what you
or what you are
that is one's identity. That's who who
or what you are is
or what you are is that
that is one's identity. That's who who
or what you are is that state
or what you are is that state which
that is one's identity. That's who who
or what you are is that state which is
nonlinear
harmonious.
harmonious. It's
nonlinear
harmonious. It's intrinsic.
harmonious. It's intrinsic. It
nonlinear
harmonious. It's intrinsic. It has
harmonious. It's intrinsic. It has no
location.
It's
It's total
and
and it's
and it's unifying.
There
There is
and it's unifying.
There is no
There is no me
and it's unifying.
There is no me as
There is no me as separate
and it's unifying.
There is no me as separate from
There is no me as separate from there.
You
You or
You or separateness
You or separateness disappears
You or separateness disappears and
there's
there's just
You or separateness disappears and
there's just a
there's just a total
You or separateness disappears and
there's just a total oneness
there's just a total oneness within
You or separateness disappears and
there's just a total oneness within the
oneness.
oneness. This
oneness. This oneness
oneness. This oneness takes
oneness. This oneness takes on
linear
linear characteristics.
oneness. This oneness takes on
linear characteristics. It
linear characteristics. It the
oneness. This oneness takes on
linear characteristics. It the mind
linear characteristics. It the mind then
differentiates
differentiates as
differentiates as me
differentiates as me and
differentiates as me and you
differentiates as me and you and
differentiates as me and you and them
etc.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So that's
All right. So that's the
All right. So that's the first
All right. So that's the first slide.
Illumination
is
is level
is level 600.
is level 600. Yes.
is level 600. Yes. All
is level 600. Yes. All right.
is level 600. Yes. All right. So,
is level 600. Yes. All right. So, we'll
go
go to
is level 600. Yes. All right. So, we'll
go to the
go to the next
uh
uh so
uh so we're
uh so we're talking
uh so we're talking today
uh so we're talking today also
uh so we're talking today also about
self-realization.
Uh
all
all this
Uh
all this looks
all this looks very
Uh
all this looks very wordy.
all this looks very wordy. I
Uh
all this looks very wordy. I don't
all this looks very wordy. I don't know
what
what I'm
what I'm going
what I'm going to
what I'm going to do
what I'm going to do about
what I'm going to do about all
what I'm going to do about all that.
>> But
no,
no, no,
no, no, no.
no, no, no. These
no, no, no. These are
no, no, no. These are fine.
uh
uh self
no, no, no. These are fine.
uh self realization
uh self realization because
no, no, no. These are fine.
uh self realization because that's
uh self realization because that's what
we're
we're talking
we're talking about
we're talking about today.
we're talking about today. Um
we're talking about today. Um we're
talking
talking about
we're talking about today. Um we're
talking about mysticism.
talking about mysticism. Well,
essentially
essentially what
essentially what is
essentially what is mysticism?
The
The ordinary
essentially what is mysticism?
The ordinary mind
The ordinary mind is
essentially what is mysticism?
The ordinary mind is thinking
The ordinary mind is thinking mind.
essentially what is mysticism?
The ordinary mind is thinking mind. It
thinks
thinks in
thinks in a
thinks in a linear
thinks in a linear linear
thinks in a linear linear definitions.
It
It has
thinks in a linear linear definitions.
It has pronouns
It has pronouns of
thinks in a linear linear definitions.
It has pronouns of myself
It has pronouns of myself and
thinks in a linear linear definitions.
It has pronouns of myself and and
It has pronouns of myself and and you
and
the
the mystic
and
the mystic uh
the mystic uh state
and
the mystic uh state comes
the mystic uh state comes about
and
the mystic uh state comes about in
the mystic uh state comes about in a
nonlinear.
nonlinear. It
nonlinear. It doesn't
nonlinear. It doesn't come
nonlinear. It doesn't come about
nonlinear. It doesn't come about uh
nonlinear. It doesn't come about uh as
nonlinear. It doesn't come about uh as a
result
result of
nonlinear. It doesn't come about uh as a
result of reason.
Religion
Religion has
Religion has to
Religion has to do
Religion has to do with
Religion has to do with a
Religion has to do with a lot
Religion has to do with a lot of
information
and
and mastering
and mastering the
and mastering the information.
and mastering the information. The
information
information then
and mastering the information. The
information then becomes
information then becomes integrated
and mastering the information. The
information then becomes integrated and
can
can become
can become quite
can become quite sophisticated.
Theology,
advanced
advanced theology
advanced theology is
advanced theology is very
advanced theology is very fascinating
subject
subject and
advanced theology is very fascinating
subject and you
subject and you can
advanced theology is very fascinating
subject and you can spend
subject and you can spend a
advanced theology is very fascinating
subject and you can spend a whole
lifetime
lifetime studying
lifetime studying uh
lifetime studying uh theology.
lifetime studying uh theology. Huh?
In
In the
lifetime studying uh theology. Huh?
In the mystic
In the mystic the
lifetime studying uh theology. Huh?
In the mystic the understanding
In the mystic the understanding comes
about
about in
about in a
about in a different
about in a different way.
The
The under
about in a different way.
The under the
The under the understanding
about in a different way.
The under the understanding is
The under the understanding is an
eulgence.
It's
It's a
eulgence.
It's a revelation.
that
that requires
that requires no
that requires no thinkingness
that requires no thinkingness at
that requires no thinkingness at all.
Doesn't
Doesn't require
that requires no thinkingness at all.
Doesn't require information
and
and that
and that which
ensues
ensues as
and that which
ensues as the
ensues as the mystical
and that which
ensues as the mystical state
ensues as the mystical state doesn't
know
know anything
know anything at
know anything at all
know anything at all about
know anything at all about religion.
Ignorant
Ignorant about
know anything at all about religion.
Ignorant about religion
may
may never
may never have
may never have even
may never have even heard
may never have even heard of
may never have even heard of it.
may never have even heard of it. Right?
I've
I've spoken
may never have even heard of it. Right?
I've spoken of
I've spoken of the
may never have even heard of it. Right?
I've spoken of the inner
I've spoken of the inner states
may never have even heard of it. Right?
I've spoken of the inner states that
occurred
occurred in
occurred in this
occurred in this lifetime
because
because they
occurred in this lifetime
because they exhibit
because they exhibit pretty
occurred in this lifetime
because they exhibit pretty much
because they exhibit pretty much a
occurred in this lifetime
because they exhibit pretty much a lot
of
of the
of the basic
of the basic concepts
of the basic concepts that
of the basic concepts that we
of the basic concepts that we want
of the basic concepts that we want to
cover
cover today.
intention
intention uh
intention uh sets
intention uh sets up
intention uh sets up I
intention uh sets up I think
intention uh sets up I think intention
and
and commitment
probably
probably in
probably in a
probably in a number
probably in a number of
probably in a number of lifetimes
probably in a number of lifetimes sets
up
up the
probably in a number of lifetimes sets
up the likelihood
for
for the
for the mystical
for the mystical events
for the mystical events see
so
so the
for the mystical events see
so the first
so the first mystical
for the mystical events see
so the first mystical event
so the first mystical event which
for the mystical events see
so the first mystical event which I've
related
related before
was
was to
related before
was to come
was to come out
related before
was to come out of
was to come out of nothingness
related before
was to come out of nothingness at
was to come out of nothingness at age
three
three at
three at age
three at age three
three at age three out
three at age three out of
three at age three out of the
three at age three out of the void
nothingness
nothingness non-awareness
three at age three out of the void
nothingness non-awareness non
non-existence.
There
There was
non-existence.
There was suddenly
There was suddenly a
non-existence.
There was suddenly a shock,
There was suddenly a shock, a
non-existence.
There was suddenly a shock, a very
stunning
stunning shock
stunning shock of
stunning shock of suddenly
stunning shock of suddenly the
stunning shock of suddenly the awareness
of
of existence
stunning shock of suddenly the awareness
of existence from
of existence from non-existence
stunning shock of suddenly the awareness
of existence from non-existence to
existence
was
was a
existence
was a stunning
was a stunning shock.
It
It was
It was like
It was like being
It was like being in
It was like being in a
It was like being in a dark
It was like being in a dark cave
It was like being in a dark cave and
suddenly
suddenly all
It was like being in a dark cave and
suddenly all the
suddenly all the cleague
It was like being in a dark cave and
suddenly all the cleague lights
suddenly all the cleague lights are
turned
turned on.
turned on. It
turned on. It was
turned on. It was like
turned on. It was like that
turned on. It was like that stunning
stunningness.
I
I was
I was not
I was not pleased.
Not
Not only
I was not pleased.
Not only did
Not only did I
I was not pleased.
Not only did I exist,
but
but a
but a body
but a body went
but a body went with
but a body went with it.
but a body went with it. And
but a body went with it. And I
but a body went with it. And I think
I've
I've related
but a body went with it. And I think
I've related that
I've related that before.
but a body went with it. And I think
I've related that before. It
I've related that before. It was
but a body went with it. And I think
I've related that before. It was bad
enough
enough to
enough to exist.
enough to exist. And
enough to exist. And then
enough to exist. And then I
enough to exist. And then I looked
enough to exist. And then I looked down
and
and here
enough to exist. And then I looked down
and here is
and here is this
enough to exist. And then I looked down
and here is this little
and here is this little body
enough to exist. And then I looked down
and here is this little body in
and here is this little body in a
enough to exist. And then I looked down
and here is this little body in a wagon
stuck
stuck out
stuck out there
stuck out there by
stuck out there by its
stuck out there by its mother
stuck out there by its mother to
stuck out there by its mother to sit
stuck out there by its mother to sit in
the
the sun.
It
It took
It took uh
It took uh many
It took uh many years
It took uh many years to
It took uh many years to recover
It took uh many years to recover from
the
the shock.
It took uh many years to recover from
the shock. of
the shock. of of
It took uh many years to recover from
the shock. of of discovering
the shock. of of discovering uh
existence.
existence. It
existence. It took
existence. It took some
existence. It took some 36
existence. It took some 36 years
existence. It took some 36 years in
existence. It took some 36 years in fact
and
and was
existence. It took some 36 years in fact
and was the
and was the infinite
existence. It took some 36 years in fact
and was the infinite reality
and was the infinite reality existence
versus
versus non-existence.
And
And this
versus non-existence.
And this is
And this is one
versus non-existence.
And this is one of
And this is one of the
versus non-existence.
And this is one of the coins
And this is one of the coins one
versus non-existence.
And this is one of the coins one of
And this is one of the coins one of the
dilemmas
dilemmas that
dilemmas that you
dilemmas that you pass
dilemmas that you pass uh
dilemmas that you pass uh in
dilemmas that you pass uh in Zen
dilemmas that you pass uh in Zen pathway
is
is reality
dilemmas that you pass uh in Zen pathway
is reality is
is reality is existence
dilemmas that you pass uh in Zen pathway
is reality is existence or
is reality is existence or a
non-existence.
So
So as
non-existence.
So as I've
So as I've said
non-existence.
So as I've said before,
So as I've said before, it
non-existence.
So as I've said before, it took
So as I've said before, it took 36
non-existence.
So as I've said before, it took 36 years
and
and the
and the Zen
and the Zen teachings
and the Zen teachings uh
and the Zen teachings uh are
and the Zen teachings uh are that
and the Zen teachings uh are that any
such
such a
and the Zen teachings uh are that any
such a statement
such a statement in
and the Zen teachings uh are that any
such a statement in itself
such a statement in itself is
and the Zen teachings uh are that any
such a statement in itself is facious
any
any that
any that would
any that would be
any that would be a
any that would be a judgment
any that would be a judgment and
any that would be a judgment and a
concept
concept conceptual
any that would be a judgment and a
concept conceptual thinking.
concept conceptual thinking. So
any that would be a judgment and a
concept conceptual thinking. So existing
is
is a
is a is
is a is a
is a is a concept
is a is a concept with
is a is a concept with no
is a is a concept with no existence
is a is a concept with no existence and
non-existence
non-existence is
is a is a concept with no existence and
non-existence is a
non-existence is a concept
is a is a concept with no existence and
non-existence is a concept with
non-existence is a concept with no
existence.
So
So when
existence.
So when you
So when you let
existence.
So when you let go
So when you let go of
existence.
So when you let go of all
So when you let go of all such
existence.
So when you let go of all such con
contextual
contextual statements
contextual statements uh
contextual statements uh you
contextual statements uh you don't
contextual statements uh you don't have
a
a problem
contextual statements uh you don't have
a problem with
a problem with existence
contextual statements uh you don't have
a problem with existence versus
non-existence
because
because there
non-existence
because there is
because there is no
non-existence
because there is no duality
because there is no duality neither
non-existence
because there is no duality neither one
of
of them
of them having
of them having reality.
So
So one
of them having reality.
So one way
So one way to
of them having reality.
So one way to get
So one way to get rid
of them having reality.
So one way to get rid of
So one way to get rid of problems
of them having reality.
So one way to get rid of problems is
just
just disappear
just disappear their
just disappear their reality
just disappear their reality and
just disappear their reality and now
you're
you're free
just disappear their reality and now
you're free of
you're free of them
and
and you're
and you're free
and you're free and
and you're free and liberated
and you're free and liberated forever.
Oh
Oh boy.
All
All right.
So
that
that awareness
that awareness which
that awareness which is
that awareness which is a
that awareness which is a quite
that awareness which is a quite profound
awareness
awareness it
that awareness which is a quite profound
awareness it really
awareness it really is
that awareness which is a quite profound
awareness it really is not
awareness it really is not resolved
that awareness which is a quite profound
awareness it really is not resolved till
consciousness
consciousness level
consciousness level 850.
consciousness level 850. So
consciousness level 850. So that's
consciousness level 850. So that's a
pretty
pretty advanced
consciousness level 850. So that's a
pretty advanced dilemma.
As
As I
As I say
As I say it
As I say it took
As I say it took some
As I say it took some 30
As I say it took some 30 years
As I say it took some 30 years to
resolve.
The
The next
The next major
The next major event
The next major event was
The next major event was in
The next major event was in this
The next major event was in this level
in
in this
The next major event was in this level
in this consciousness
in this consciousness here
The next major event was in this level
in this consciousness here was
in this consciousness here was um
um
um the
um the the
um the the the
um the the the experience
um the the the experience I
um the the the experience I spoken
um the the the experience I spoken about
in
in the
um the the the experience I spoken about
in the snowbank
that
that uh
that uh as
that uh as a
that uh as a child
that uh as a child I
that uh as a child I was
that uh as a child I was quite
that uh as a child I was quite religious
etc.
etc. But
that uh as a child I was quite religious
etc. But the
etc. But the religion
that uh as a child I was quite religious
etc. But the religion had
etc. But the religion had nothing
that uh as a child I was quite religious
etc. But the religion had nothing to
etc. But the religion had nothing to do
with
with these
with these phenomena.
They
They had
with these phenomena.
They had nothing
They had nothing at
with these phenomena.
They had nothing at all
They had nothing at all to
with these phenomena.
They had nothing at all to do
They had nothing at all to do with
with these phenomena.
They had nothing at all to do with it.
Uh
you
you can
Uh
you can memorize
you can memorize all
Uh
you can memorize all the
you can memorize all the spiritual
literature
literature in
literature in the
literature in the world
literature in the world and
literature in the world and when
literature in the world and when the
mystical
mystical experience
literature in the world and when the
mystical experience occurs
mystical experience occurs it
literature in the world and when the
mystical experience occurs it has
nothing
nothing at
nothing at all
nothing at all to
nothing at all to do
nothing at all to do with
nothing at all to do with everything
nothing at all to do with everything you
spent
spent your
nothing at all to do with everything you
spent your whole
spent your whole lifetime
nothing at all to do with everything you
spent your whole lifetime studying.
They're
They're not
They're not connected.
They're not connected. they're
They're not connected. they're not
They're not connected. they're not in
the
the same
They're not connected. they're not in
the same realm.
the same realm. So,
uh
uh I
uh I think
uh I think as
uh I think as I've
uh I think as I've related
uh I think as I've related before,
uh I think as I've related before, I'm
repeating
repeating it
uh I think as I've related before, I'm
repeating it this
repeating it this morning
uh I think as I've related before, I'm
repeating it this morning because
repeating it this morning because it
fits
fits into
fits into the
fits into the whole
fits into the whole subject
fits into the whole subject of
fits into the whole subject of the
mystic.
Uh,
Uh, one
Uh, one time
Uh, one time in
Uh, one time in a
Uh, one time in a blizzard
Uh, one time in a blizzard I
Uh, one time in a blizzard I in
Uh, one time in a blizzard I in northern
Wisconsin
Wisconsin I
Uh, one time in a blizzard I in northern
Wisconsin I had
Wisconsin I had a
Uh, one time in a blizzard I in northern
Wisconsin I had a paper
Wisconsin I had a paper route
Uh, one time in a blizzard I in northern
Wisconsin I had a paper route and
Wisconsin I had a paper route and uh,
Uh, one time in a blizzard I in northern
Wisconsin I had a paper route and uh, it
was
was cold
was cold and
was cold and windy,
was cold and windy, terribly
was cold and windy, terribly windy
was cold and windy, terribly windy and
terribly
terribly cold
was cold and windy, terribly windy and
terribly cold and
terribly cold and uh,
was cold and windy, terribly windy and
terribly cold and uh, huge
terribly cold and uh, huge snow
was cold and windy, terribly windy and
terribly cold and uh, huge snow banks
terribly cold and uh, huge snow banks on
each
each side
each side of
each side of the
each side of the highway
each side of the highway and
each side of the highway and the
each side of the highway and the snow
banks
banks had
each side of the highway and the snow
banks had been
banks had been there
each side of the highway and the snow
banks had been there some
banks had been there some while
each side of the highway and the snow
banks had been there some while and
there
there was
there was like
there was like a
there was like a crust
there was like a crust in
there was like a crust in the
there was like a crust in the snow
there was like a crust in the snow but
the
the snow
there was like a crust in the snow but
the snow was
the snow was quite
there was like a crust in the snow but
the snow was quite you
the snow was quite you know
there was like a crust in the snow but
the snow was quite you know 8
the snow was quite you know 8 10
there was like a crust in the snow but
the snow was quite you know 8 10 feet
high.
high. So
high. So to
high. So to get
high. So to get out
high. So to get out of
high. So to get out of the
high. So to get out of the wind,
high. So to get out of the wind, I
high. So to get out of the wind, I knock
I
I crushed
high. So to get out of the wind, I knock
I crushed my
I crushed my way
high. So to get out of the wind, I knock
I crushed my way into
I crushed my way into the
high. So to get out of the wind, I knock
I crushed my way into the snowbank
I crushed my way into the snowbank and
quickly
quickly dug
quickly dug out
quickly dug out a
quickly dug out a little
quickly dug out a little cave
quickly dug out a little cave and
quickly dug out a little cave and and
and
and snuck
quickly dug out a little cave and and
and snuck inside
and snuck inside the
quickly dug out a little cave and and
and snuck inside the cave.
and snuck inside the cave. There's
quickly dug out a little cave and and
and snuck inside the cave. There's no
such
such word
such word as
such word as snuck,
such word as snuck, but
such word as snuck, but I
such word as snuck, but I did
such word as snuck, but I did it
such word as snuck, but I did it anyway.
Sneaked
snuck
snuck into
snuck into the
snuck into the Anyway,
snuck into the Anyway, I
snuck into the Anyway, I wanted
snuck into the Anyway, I wanted to
snuck into the Anyway, I wanted to get
out
out of
snuck into the Anyway, I wanted to get
out of the
out of the wind.
snuck into the Anyway, I wanted to get
out of the wind. I
out of the wind. I was
snuck into the Anyway, I wanted to get
out of the wind. I was still
out of the wind. I was still in
snuck into the Anyway, I wanted to get
out of the wind. I was still in good
shape.
shape. I
shape. I have
shape. I have plenty
shape. I have plenty of
shape. I have plenty of physical
shape. I have plenty of physical energy.
It
It wasn't
shape. I have plenty of physical energy.
It wasn't near
It wasn't near death
shape. I have plenty of physical energy.
It wasn't near death or
It wasn't near death or anything
shape. I have plenty of physical energy.
It wasn't near death or anything like
that.
that. On
that. On the
that. On the contrary,
that. On the contrary, I
that. On the contrary, I was
that. On the contrary, I was quite
vigorous
vigorous and
that. On the contrary, I was quite
vigorous and but
vigorous and but I
that. On the contrary, I was quite
vigorous and but I wanted
vigorous and but I wanted to
that. On the contrary, I was quite
vigorous and but I wanted to get
vigorous and but I wanted to get out
that. On the contrary, I was quite
vigorous and but I wanted to get out of
the
the wind.
the wind. Just
the wind. Just a
the wind. Just a little
the wind. Just a little uh
little
little smell
the wind. Just a little uh
little smell of
little smell of relief
the wind. Just a little uh
little smell of relief in
little smell of relief in the
the wind. Just a little uh
little smell of relief in the wind.
little smell of relief in the wind. So
the wind. Just a little uh
little smell of relief in the wind. So I
climbed
climbed inside
climbed inside of
climbed inside of this
climbed inside of this uh
climbed inside of this uh little
climbed inside of this uh little cave
and
and uh
climbed inside of this uh little cave
and uh and
and uh and tried
climbed inside of this uh little cave
and uh and tried to
and uh and tried to relax
climbed inside of this uh little cave
and uh and tried to relax and
and uh and tried to relax and and
climbed inside of this uh little cave
and uh and tried to relax and and then
out
out of
out of nowhere
out
out of
out of nowhere
came
came uh
A
A profound
came uh
A profound infinite
radiance
radiance of
radiance of love
beyond
beyond all
radiance of love
beyond all imagination,
beyond all imagination, beyond
radiance of love
beyond all imagination, beyond human
love,
timeless,
timeless, timeless
love,
timeless, timeless and
timeless, timeless and eternal.
love,
timeless, timeless and eternal. No
beginning
beginning and
beginning and no
beginning and no end.
Closer
Closer than
beginning and no end.
Closer than your
Closer than your own
beginning and no end.
Closer than your own self,
closer
closer to
closer to your
closer to your reality,
closer to your reality, to
closer to your reality, to what
closer to your reality, to what you
think
think of
closer to your reality, to what you
think of yourself
think of yourself than
closer to your reality, to what you
think of yourself than your
think of yourself than your personal
identity
identity as
identity as yourself.
And
And I
identity as yourself.
And I realized
And I realized this
identity as yourself.
And I realized this is
And I realized this is the
identity as yourself.
And I realized this is the core
And I realized this is the core of
identity as yourself.
And I realized this is the core of who
And I realized this is the core of who I
am.
am. It
am. It was
am. It was eternal
foreverness.
foreverness. Foreverness.
And
And you
And you realize
And you realize that
And you realize that that
And you realize that that which
And you realize that that which you
And you realize that that which you are
is
is eternal.
And you realize that that which you are
is eternal. Infinite
is eternal. Infinite love
without
without thought,
without thought, without
without thought, without realization,
with
with no
without thought, without realization,
with no pronouns.
The
The reality
The reality of
The reality of that
The reality of that which
The reality of that which you
The reality of that which you are
is
is not
The reality of that which you are
is not different
is not different is
The reality of that which you are
is not different is infinite
is not different is infinite with
The reality of that which you are
is not different is infinite with no
beginning
beginning and
beginning and no
beginning and no end.
And
And it
beginning and no end.
And it is
And it is not
beginning and no end.
And it is not different
And it is not different than
beginning and no end.
And it is not different than infinite
absolutely
absolutely perfect
absolutely perfect love.
That's
That's the
absolutely perfect love.
That's the revelation
That's the revelation of
absolutely perfect love.
That's the revelation of the
That's the revelation of the truth
absolutely perfect love.
That's the revelation of the truth of
your
your own
your own existence.
your own existence. Let's
your own existence. Let's see
your own existence. Let's see if
your own existence. Let's see if that
applies
applies to
your own existence. Let's see if that
applies to everyone
applies to everyone here.
That's
That's the
That's the truth
That's the truth of
That's the truth of everyone's
That's the truth of everyone's existence
here.
here. Resist.
That's the truth of everyone's existence
here. Resist. That's
here. Resist. That's the
That's the truth of everyone's existence
here. Resist. That's the truth
here. Resist. That's the truth of
everyone's
everyone's existence
everyone's existence here.
everyone's existence here. D
that
that which
everyone's existence here. D
that which you
that which you are
everyone's existence here. D
that which you are infinite
that which you are infinite love
everyone's existence here. D
that which you are infinite love existed
forever
with
with no
forever
with no beginning
with no beginning and
forever
with no beginning and no
with no beginning and no end.
So
So all
So all that's
So all that's left
So all that's left is
So all that's left is to
So all that's left is to realize
So all that's left is to realize that.
Let
Let it
So all that's left is to realize that.
Let it snap.
Go
Go get
Go get a
Go get a snowbank
Go get a snowbank someplace
Go get a snowbank someplace and
Go get a snowbank someplace and dig
Go get a snowbank someplace and dig a
hole
hole in
Go get a snowbank someplace and dig a
hole in it.
today's
today's world
today's world that
today's world that would
today's world that would make
today's world that would make it
today's world that would make it the
holy
holy snowbank
today's world that would make it the
holy snowbank and
holy snowbank and then
today's world that would make it the
holy snowbank and then put
holy snowbank and then put a
today's world that would make it the
holy snowbank and then put a thing
holy snowbank and then put a thing over
it
it and
it and guard
it and guard rail
it and guard rail around
it and guard rail around it.
There
There are
it and guard rail around it.
There are places
There are places like
it and guard rail around it.
There are places like that,
There are places like that, chairs
it and guard rail around it.
There are places like that, chairs where
somebody
somebody sat
somebody sat and
somebody sat and now
somebody sat and now they
somebody sat and now they become
somebody sat and now they become revered
holy
holy chairs,
somebody sat and now they become revered
holy chairs, you
holy chairs, you know.
somebody sat and now they become revered
holy chairs, you know. This
holy chairs, you know. This is
somebody sat and now they become revered
holy chairs, you know. This is where
holy chairs, you know. This is where so
and
and so
and so sat,
and so sat, you
and so sat, you know.
Anyway,
reality
reality being
reality being on
reality being on it
reality being on it is
reality being on it is the
reality being on it is the snowbank
eventually
eventually melted,
reality being on it is the snowbank
eventually melted, of
eventually melted, of course,
reality being on it is the snowbank
eventually melted, of course, so
eventually melted, of course, so it
couldn't
couldn't put
couldn't put a
couldn't put a holy
couldn't put a holy placard
couldn't put a holy placard there
couldn't put a holy placard there in
front
front of
couldn't put a holy placard there in
front of it.
Thank
Thank goodness.
Thank goodness. So
that
that was
Thank goodness. So
that was uh
very
very profound
very profound uh
very profound uh beyond
very profound uh beyond all
very profound uh beyond all learning
having
having nothing
very profound uh beyond all learning
having nothing to
having nothing to do
very profound uh beyond all learning
having nothing to do with
having nothing to do with church
very profound uh beyond all learning
having nothing to do with church or
theology.
theology. Uh
theology. Uh religion
theology. Uh religion was
theology. Uh religion was uh
theology. Uh religion was uh somehow
separate
separate from
theology. Uh religion was uh somehow
separate from it.
separate from it. There
theology. Uh religion was uh somehow
separate from it. There are
separate from it. There are two
different
different boxes.
different boxes. Two
different boxes. Two different
different boxes. Two different boxes.
Religion
Religion was
different boxes. Two different boxes.
Religion was something
Religion was something else.
different boxes. Two different boxes.
Religion was something else. And
Religion was something else. And u
although
although I
although I was
although I was very
although I was very religious
although I was very religious young
although I was very religious young that
religiosity
religiosity had
although I was very religious young that
religiosity had nothing
religiosity had nothing to
although I was very religious young that
religiosity had nothing to do
religiosity had nothing to do with
although I was very religious young that
religiosity had nothing to do with that
experience.
experience. They're
experience. They're two
experience. They're two different
realms.
realms. They're
experience. They're two different
realms. They're not
realms. They're not connected.
experience. They're two different
realms. They're not connected. There
realms. They're not connected. There is
no
no connection
no connection between
no connection between that
no connection between that the
no connection between that the linear
and
and the
no connection between that the linear
and the nonlinear.
and the nonlinear. They
no connection between that the linear
and the nonlinear. They are
and the nonlinear. They are two
different
different realms.
The
The surrendering
different realms.
The surrendering to
The surrendering to the
different realms.
The surrendering to the presence
The surrendering to the presence then
different realms.
The surrendering to the presence then uh
within
within of
within of the
within of the essence
within of the essence and
within of the essence and the
within of the essence and the core
within of the essence and the core and
the
the source
within of the essence and the core and
the source of
the source of your
within of the essence and the core and
the source of your reality
the source of your reality is
within of the essence and the core and
the source of your reality is a
subtlety.
Now
Now the
subtlety.
Now the mis
Now the mis the
subtlety.
Now the mis the knowledge
Now the mis the knowledge of
subtlety.
Now the mis the knowledge of the
Now the mis the knowledge of the mystic
arises
um
um the
arises
um the studying
um the studying and
arises
um the studying and all
um the studying and all that
arises
um the studying and all that only
um the studying and all that only sets
up
up a
up a stage
but
but it's
up a stage
but it's self-revealing.
but it's self-revealing. So
up a stage
but it's self-revealing. So mysticism
is
is surrendering
is surrendering to
is surrendering to the
is surrendering to the self
um
to
to the
to the capacity
to the capacity of
to the capacity of of
to the capacity of of divinity
to the capacity of of divinity within
to the capacity of of divinity within to
reveal
reveal itself.
And
And it
And it reveals
And it reveals itself
And it reveals itself when
And it reveals itself when it
And it reveals itself when it is
karmically
karmically propitious
And it reveals itself when it is
karmically propitious to
karmically propitious to do
And it reveals itself when it is
karmically propitious to do so.
karmically propitious to do so. Not
necessarily
necessarily when
necessarily when you
necessarily when you want
necessarily when you want it
necessarily when you want it to
necessarily when you want it to happen.
It
It can
necessarily when you want it to happen.
It can happen
It can happen at
necessarily when you want it to happen.
It can happen at very
It can happen at very inconvenient
times.
times. You
times. You find
times. You find yourself
times. You find yourself completely
incapacitated
sitting
sitting there
sitting there in
sitting there in a
sitting there in a state
sitting there in a state of
sitting there in a state of bliss
sitting there in a state of bliss on
sitting there in a state of bliss on a
rock
rock and
sitting there in a state of bliss on a
rock and you
rock and you can't
sitting there in a state of bliss on a
rock and you can't get
rock and you can't get up
sitting there in a state of bliss on a
rock and you can't get up and
rock and you can't get up and move
sitting there in a state of bliss on a
rock and you can't get up and move or
leave
leave or
leave or anything.
It
It happened
leave or anything.
It happened to
It happened to me
leave or anything.
It happened to me in
It happened to me in Sedona
leave or anything.
It happened to me in Sedona and
It happened to me in Sedona and sitting
on
on a
on a rock,
on a rock, the
on a rock, the state
on a rock, the state of
on a rock, the state of bliss
on a rock, the state of bliss was
on a rock, the state of bliss was so
profound.
profound. There
on a rock, the state of bliss was so
profound. There was
profound. There was no
on a rock, the state of bliss was so
profound. There was no capacity
profound. There was no capacity to
on a rock, the state of bliss was so
profound. There was no capacity to get
off
off the
off the rock
off the rock and
off the rock and it
off the rock and it seemed
off the rock and it seemed like
that
that would
off the rock and it seemed like
that would be
that would be the
off the rock and it seemed like
that would be the end
that would be the end of
off the rock and it seemed like
that would be the end of the
that would be the end of the trail.
I
I don't
I don't know
I don't know what
I don't know what the
I don't know what the they
I don't know what the they they
I don't know what the they they cart
I don't know what the they they cart you
away,
away, I
I don't know what the they they cart you
away, I guess.
away, I guess. So
I don't know what the they they cart you
away, I guess. So it
away, I guess. So it came
I don't know what the they they cart you
away, I guess. So it came across
away, I guess. So it came across my
I don't know what the they they cart you
away, I guess. So it came across my mind
that
that they
that they cart
that they cart you
that they cart you away.
that they cart you away. I
that they cart you away. I said
that they cart you away. I said well
that they cart you away. I said well so
they
they cart
that they cart you away. I said well so
they cart you
they cart you away
that they cart you away. I said well so
they cart you away then
they cart you away then they
that they cart you away. I said well so
they cart you away then they put
they cart you away then they put you
that they cart you away. I said well so
they cart you away then they put you in
a
a hospital.
a hospital. Well
a hospital. Well then
a hospital. Well then they
a hospital. Well then they put
a hospital. Well then they put you
a hospital. Well then they put you in
a hospital. Well then they put you in a
hospital
no
no matter
no matter what
no matter what prevailed
no matter what prevailed the
no matter what prevailed the state
no matter what prevailed the state of
no matter what prevailed the state of uh
sacha
sacha and
no matter what prevailed the state of uh
sacha and nanda
sacha and nanda nothing
no matter what prevailed the state of uh
sacha and nanda nothing interferes
sacha and nanda nothing interferes with
it.
Now
Now there
it.
Now there was
Now there was no
it.
Now there was no preceding
Now there was no preceding states.
it.
Now there was no preceding states. You
see
see you
see you know
who
who was
see you know
who was the
who was the Indian
see you know
who was the Indian guru
who was the Indian guru that
see you know
who was the Indian guru that fell
who was the Indian guru that fell down
thought
thought he
thought he had
thought he had died
thought he had died and
thought he had died and woke
thought he had died and woke up
thought he had died and woke up in
thought he had died and woke up in a
different
different state.
thought he had died and woke up in a
different state. Ramana
different state. Ramana Mahari.
thought he had died and woke up in a
different state. Ramana Mahari. Yes.
different state. Ramana Mahari. Yes. So
you
you see
you see the
you see the mysticala
you see the mysticala mystic
you see the mysticala mystic occasion
out
out of
you see the mysticala mystic occasion
out of nowhere
out of nowhere at
you see the mysticala mystic occasion
out of nowhere at all
out of nowhere at all he
you see the mysticala mystic occasion
out of nowhere at all he fell
out of nowhere at all he fell down
you see the mysticala mystic occasion
out of nowhere at all he fell down fell
felt
felt he
felt he had
felt he had died
felt he had died and
felt he had died and woke
felt he had died and woke up
felt he had died and woke up in
felt he had died and woke up in a
completely
completely different
felt he had died and woke up in a
completely different state.
And
And if
And if he
And if he hadn't
And if he hadn't been
And if he hadn't been discovered
And if he hadn't been discovered by
others,
others, he
And if he hadn't been discovered by
others, he probably
others, he probably would
And if he hadn't been discovered by
others, he probably would have
others, he probably would have just
starved
starved to
starved to death
starved to death there.
starved to death there. Eaten
starved to death there. Eaten by
starved to death there. Eaten by bugs
and
and dehydration.
starved to death there. Eaten by bugs
and dehydration. And
and dehydration. And because
starved to death there. Eaten by bugs
and dehydration. And because in
and dehydration. And because in that
state
state there
state there is
state there is no
state there is no need
state there is no need for
state there is no need for anything.
No
No need
state there is no need for anything.
No need for
No need for anything
state there is no need for anything.
No need for anything at
No need for anything at all.
Food,
Food, water,
Food, water, no
Food, water, no need
Food, water, no need for
Food, water, no need for anything.
Food, water, no need for anything. It's
a
a state
Food, water, no need for anything. It's
a state of
a state of uh
Food, water, no need for anything. It's
a state of uh absolute
a state of uh absolute completeness.
It
It can
It can last
It can last for
It can last for considerable
It can last for considerable lengths
It can last for considerable lengths of
time.
the
the the
the the profound
the the profound state
the the profound state eventually
the the profound state eventually at
least
least in
the the profound state eventually at
least in this
least in this case
the the profound state eventually at
least in this case one
least in this case one learns
the the profound state eventually at
least in this case one learns how
least in this case one learns how to
deal
deal with
deal with it.
The
The state
deal with it.
The state continues.
The state continues. The
deal with it.
The state continues. The state
continues.
It
It sometimes
continues.
It sometimes gets
It sometimes gets stronger
continues.
It sometimes gets stronger and
It sometimes gets stronger and sometimes
weaker
and
and eventually
weaker
and eventually leads
and eventually leads to
weaker
and eventually leads to depending
and eventually leads to depending on
one's
one's karmic
one's karmic propensities
uh
uh the
one's karmic propensities
uh the capacity
uh the capacity to
one's karmic propensities
uh the capacity to continue
uh the capacity to continue to
one's karmic propensities
uh the capacity to continue to be
uh the capacity to continue to be in
one's karmic propensities
uh the capacity to continue to be in the
world
and
and function
world
and function in
and function in some
world
and function in some kind
and function in some kind of
world
and function in some kind of capacity
about
about which
about which you
about which you yourself
about which you yourself as
about which you yourself as a
about which you yourself as a person
have
have nothing
about which you yourself as a person
have nothing to
have nothing to say.
about which you yourself as a person
have nothing to say. It's
have nothing to say. It's as
about which you yourself as a person
have nothing to say. It's as though
have nothing to say. It's as though the
world
world says
world says do
world says do this
world says do this and
world says do this and therefore
world says do this and therefore the
response
response is
world says do this and therefore the
response is so
response is so you
world says do this and therefore the
response is so you do
response is so you do this,
world says do this and therefore the
response is so you do this, you
response is so you do this, you do
world says do this and therefore the
response is so you do this, you do this.
If
If the
If the world
If the world said
If the world said do
If the world said do this,
If the world said do this, you
If the world said do this, you would
If the world said do this, you would do
that.
The
The world
The world says
The world says uh
The world says uh there's
The world says uh there's no
The world says uh there's no doctor
here.
here. Uh
The world says uh there's no doctor
here. Uh you
here. Uh you world
The world says uh there's no doctor
here. Uh you world needs
here. Uh you world needs you
The world says uh there's no doctor
here. Uh you world needs you to
here. Uh you world needs you to go
The world says uh there's no doctor
here. Uh you world needs you to go back
and
and practice
and practice for
and practice for a
and practice for a while.
and practice for a while. So
and practice for a while. So you
and practice for a while. So you do
and practice for a while. So you do that
then
then they
and practice for a while. So you do that
then they don't
then they don't need
and practice for a while. So you do that
then they don't need you
then they don't need you as
and practice for a while. So you do that
then they don't need you as a
then they don't need you as a doctor
anymore.
anymore. So
anymore. So you
anymore. So you quit
anymore. So you quit that.
It
It doesn't
anymore. So you quit that.
It doesn't make
It doesn't make any
anymore. So you quit that.
It doesn't make any difference.
It doesn't make any difference. One
anymore. So you quit that.
It doesn't make any difference. One is
just
just doing
just doing what
just doing what is
just doing what is autonomous
just doing what is autonomous actually
because
because there
just doing what is autonomous actually
because there is
because there is no
just doing what is autonomous actually
because there is no person
because there is no person doing
just doing what is autonomous actually
because there is no person doing it.
because there is no person doing it. The
doing
doing this
doing this and
doing this and the
doing this and the happeningness
is
is self-emergent
doing this and the happeningness
is self-emergent and
is self-emergent and self-fulfilling.
So
So the
So the role
So the role the
So the role the role
So the role the role of
So the role the role of being
So the role the role of being an
So the role the role of being an an
active
active physician
So the role the role of being an an
active physician is
active physician is just
So the role the role of being an an
active physician is just a
active physician is just a role.
So the role the role of being an an
active physician is just a role. It's
not
not who
not who you
not who you are.
not who you are. You
not who you are. You know
not who you are. You know when
not who you are. You know when you
not who you are. You know when you get
to
to heaven
not who you are. You know when you get
to heaven St.
to heaven St. computer
not who you are. You know when you get
to heaven St. computer doesn't
to heaven St. computer doesn't check
not who you are. You know when you get
to heaven St. computer doesn't check you
in
in under
in under doctors
in under doctors here,
in under doctors here, dentists
in under doctors here, dentists there's
housekeepers
housekeepers there.
in under doctors here, dentists there's
housekeepers there. It's
housekeepers there. It's totally
irrelevant
irrelevant to
irrelevant to your
irrelevant to your inner
irrelevant to your inner reality.
irrelevant to your inner reality. It's
the
the doing
irrelevant to your inner reality. It's
the doing this.
the doing this. So
irrelevant to your inner reality. It's
the doing this. So you
the doing this. So you also
irrelevant to your inner reality. It's
the doing this. So you also do
the doing this. So you also do carpentry
and
and you
and you do
and you do all
and you do all kinds
and you do all kinds of
and you do all kinds of things
and you do all kinds of things you
and you do all kinds of things you know
uh
uh because
and you do all kinds of things you know
uh because those
uh because those are
and you do all kinds of things you know
uh because those are capa
uh because those are capa capacities
and you do all kinds of things you know
uh because those are capa capacities of
that
that uh
that uh of
that uh of the
that uh of the degree
that uh of the degree of
that uh of the degree of linear
that uh of the degree of linear domain
which
which you
that uh of the degree of linear domain
which you learn
which you learn to
that uh of the degree of linear domain
which you learn to operate.
which you learn to operate. So
that uh of the degree of linear domain
which you learn to operate. So the
nonlinear
nonlinear then
nonlinear then is
nonlinear then is operating
nonlinear then is operating in
nonlinear then is operating in a
nonlinear then is operating in a linear
domain.
And
And in
And in the
And in the mystic
And in the mystic there
And in the mystic there is
And in the mystic there is an
And in the mystic there is an automatic
adjustment
adjustment about
And in the mystic there is an automatic
adjustment about it.
adjustment about it. You
And in the mystic there is an automatic
adjustment about it. You don't
adjustment about it. You don't think
about
about how
about how I
about how I will
about how I will be
about how I will be with
about how I will be with that
about how I will be with that in
about how I will be with that in as
about how I will be with that in as much
as
as I'm
about how I will be with that in as much
as I'm not
as I'm not that.
about how I will be with that in as much
as I'm not that. Uh
as I'm not that. Uh the
about how I will be with that in as much
as I'm not that. Uh the being
as I'm not that. Uh the being that
about how I will be with that in as much
as I'm not that. Uh the being that way
happens
happens of
happens of its
happens of its ownness
happens of its ownness just
happens of its ownness just as
happens of its ownness just as the
lecturing
lecturing happens
happens of its ownness just as the
lecturing happens of
lecturing happens of its
happens of its ownness just as the
lecturing happens of its own
lecturing happens of its own known
ownness.
Uh
Uh and
ownness.
Uh and although
Uh and although you
ownness.
Uh and although you can
Uh and although you can put
ownness.
Uh and although you can put put
Uh and although you can put put together
some
some slides
some slides there's
some slides there's no
some slides there's no knowing
some slides there's no knowing what's
going
going to
some slides there's no knowing what's
going to be
going to be said
some slides there's no knowing what's
going to be said at
going to be said at all.
Uh
self-realization.
self-realization. Yes.
Uh
self-realization. Yes. Well,
self-realization. Yes. Well, the
Uh
self-realization. Yes. Well, the levels
we
we tried.
we tried. Oh
we tried. Oh yeah,
we tried. Oh yeah, I
we tried. Oh yeah, I see.
we tried. Oh yeah, I see. We
we tried. Oh yeah, I see. We tried
we tried. Oh yeah, I see. We tried to
give
give it
we tried. Oh yeah, I see. We tried to
give it some
give it some form.
we tried. Oh yeah, I see. We tried to
give it some form. Uh
give it some form. Uh the
we tried. Oh yeah, I see. We tried to
give it some form. Uh the levels
give it some form. Uh the levels 700
we tried. Oh yeah, I see. We tried to
give it some form. Uh the levels 700 and
up.
up. So
up. So Raman
up. So Raman Mahari
up. So Raman Mahari and
up. So Raman Mahari and Mr.
up. So Raman Mahari and Mr. Gadada
Maharaj.
Um
Um if
Um if these
Um if these represent
Um if these represent the
Um if these represent the sage
Um if these represent the sage uh
Um if these represent the sage uh the
realization
realization may
Um if these represent the sage uh the
realization may take
realization may take you
Um if these represent the sage uh the
realization may take you out
realization may take you out of
Um if these represent the sage uh the
realization may take you out of the
world
world or
world or you
world or you may
world or you may remain
world or you may remain within
world or you may remain within the
world or you may remain within the world
and
and then
world or you may remain within the world
and then the
and then the the
world or you may remain within the world
and then the the label
and then the the label you're
world or you may remain within the world
and then the the label you're labeled
the
the sage.
the sage. Your
the sage. Your sage
the sage. Your sage is
the sage. Your sage is one
the sage. Your sage is one who
the sage. Your sage is one who is
realized
realized a
the sage. Your sage is one who is
realized a mystic
realized a mystic who
the sage. Your sage is one who is
realized a mystic who has
realized a mystic who has realized
the sage. Your sage is one who is
realized a mystic who has realized but
stays
stays in
stays in the
stays in the world
stays in the world to
stays in the world to serve
stays in the world to serve a
stays in the world to serve a teaching
function
function or
stays in the world to serve a teaching
function or a
function or a communication
stays in the world to serve a teaching
function or a communication function.
Uh
Uh in
Uh in this
Uh in this what
Uh in this what what
Uh in this what what happens
Uh in this what what happens is
Uh in this what what happens is the
personal
personal sense
Uh in this what what happens is the
personal sense of
personal sense of self
uh
uh unceremoniously
is
is dissolved
uh unceremoniously
is dissolved into
is dissolved into the
uh unceremoniously
is dissolved into the major
is dissolved into the major self.
There's
There's no
There's no warning
There's no warning about
There's no warning about it.
There's no warning about it. It
There's no warning about it. It just
comes
comes on
There's no warning about it. It just
comes on and
comes on and it's
There's no warning about it. It just
comes on and it's beatotific.
comes on and it's beatotific. It
There's no warning about it. It just
comes on and it's beatotific. It really
is.
is. uh
is. uh uh
is. uh uh timeless.
What
What happens
is. uh uh timeless.
What happens is
What happens is you
is. uh uh timeless.
What happens is you stop
What happens is you stop identifying
with
with linear
with linear definition
with linear definition and
with linear definition and instead
with linear definition and instead you
realize
realize that
with linear definition and instead you
realize that you
realize that you are
with linear definition and instead you
realize that you are one
realize that you are one with
with linear definition and instead you
realize that you are one with essence.
One
One sees
One sees the
One sees the world
One sees the world as
One sees the world as a
One sees the world as a oneness.
One sees the world as a oneness. Within
the
the oneness
there
there is
there is definitions
there is definitions definitions
interacting
interacting but
there is definitions definitions
interacting but they
interacting but they are
there is definitions definitions
interacting but they are not
interacting but they are not separate
selves.
selves. They
selves. They are
selves. They are not
selves. They are not separate
selves. They are not separate from
selves. They are not separate from the
all.
all. They're
selves. They are not separate from the
all. They're like
all. They're like a
selves. They are not separate from the
all. They're like a condensation.
all. They're like a condensation. It
would
would be
would be like
would be like the
would be like the sky
would be like the sky darkens
would be like the sky darkens and
would be like the sky darkens and the
fog
fog darkens
would be like the sky darkens and the
fog darkens and
fog darkens and then
would be like the sky darkens and the
fog darkens and then raindrops
fog darkens and then raindrops fall
would be like the sky darkens and the
fog darkens and then raindrops fall out
of
of it,
of it, but
of it, but it's
of it, but it's still
of it, but it's still all
of it, but it's still all the
of it, but it's still all the same
of it, but it's still all the same sky
and
and the
of it, but it's still all the same sky
and the same
and the same weather.
Uh
so
so the
Uh
so the world
so the world is
Uh
so the world is witnessed
so the world is witnessed to
Uh
so the world is witnessed to be
allincclusive.
The
The context
allincclusive.
The context then
The context then is
allincclusive.
The context then is the
The context then is the wholeness
allincclusive.
The context then is the wholeness and
the
the allness
the allness of
the allness of divinity.
And
And you
the allness of divinity.
And you see
And you see the
the allness of divinity.
And you see the perfection
And you see the perfection of
the allness of divinity.
And you see the perfection of all
And you see the perfection of all that
occurs.
Um
the
the perfection
the perfection of
the perfection of all
the perfection of all that
the perfection of all that occurs.
the perfection of all that occurs. How
can
can you
the perfection of all that occurs. How
can you see
can you see perfection
in
in a
in a world
in a world that
in a world that it
in a world that it seems
in a world that it seems to
in a world that it seems to be
imperfect?
It's
It's because
It's because what
It's because what you
It's because what you see
It's because what you see as
It's because what you see as imperfect
is
is the
It's because what you see as imperfect
is the perfection
is the perfection of
It's because what you see as imperfect
is the perfection of that
is the perfection of that particular
program.
Beat
Beat up
program.
Beat up old
Beat up old blind
program.
Beat up old blind crippled
Beat up old blind crippled laying
program.
Beat up old blind crippled laying on
Beat up old blind crippled laying on the
floor
floor is
floor is the
floor is the perfection
floor is the perfection of
floor is the perfection of being
floor is the perfection of being old
and
and laying
floor is the perfection of being old
and laying on
and laying on the
floor is the perfection of being old
and laying on the floor.
Do
Do you
Do you understand
Do you understand that?
Do you understand that? Yeah.
One
One becomes
Do you understand that? Yeah.
One becomes the
One becomes the perfection.
Do you understand that? Yeah.
One becomes the perfection. One
One becomes the perfection. One is
always
always the
always the perfection.
always the perfection. Divinity
within
within is
always the perfection. Divinity
within is called
within is called God
always the perfection. Divinity
within is called God imminent.
The
The state
The state is
The state is comes
The state is comes about
The state is comes about as
The state is comes about as a
consequence
consequence of
The state is comes about as a
consequence of what
consequence of what the
The state is comes about as a
consequence of what the world
consequence of what the world calls
grace.
grace. The
grace. The world
grace. The world has
grace. The world has no
grace. The world has no linear
grace. The world has no linear logical
explanation
explanation of
grace. The world has no linear logical
explanation of why
explanation of why these
grace. The world has no linear logical
explanation of why these states
explanation of why these states should
occur.
We
We know
occur.
We know however
We know however from
occur.
We know however from our
We know however from our own
occur.
We know however from our own studies
that
that committing
that committing your
that committing your life
that committing your life to
that committing your life to God
that committing your life to God through
prayer,
prayer, devotion
that committing your life to God through
prayer, devotion etc.
prayer, devotion etc. precipitates
that committing your life to God through
prayer, devotion etc. precipitates these
states
states eventuating
states eventuating sooner
states eventuating sooner or
states eventuating sooner or later.
They
They can
states eventuating sooner or later.
They can be
They can be subtle,
states eventuating sooner or later.
They can be subtle, they
They can be subtle, they can
states eventuating sooner or later.
They can be subtle, they can be
profound,
profound, they
profound, they can
profound, they can take
profound, they can take you
profound, they can take you right
profound, they can take you right out
profound, they can take you right out of
the
the world
profound, they can take you right out of
the world altogether.
Uh
anyway,
anyway, one
Uh
anyway, one sets
anyway, one sets up
Uh
anyway, one sets up a
anyway, one sets up a karmic
Uh
anyway, one sets up a karmic propensity
then
then the
then the the
then the the response
then the the response is
then the the response is called
then the the response is called grace
because
because it's
then the the response is called grace
because it's non-causal
because it's non-causal and
then the the response is called grace
because it's non-causal and nonlinear.
Yes.
Creation
Creation then
Yes.
Creation then appears
Creation then appears to
Yes.
Creation then appears to you
Creation then appears to you as
Yes.
Creation then appears to you as an
unfoldment.
It's
It's hard
unfoldment.
It's hard to
It's hard to describe
unfoldment.
It's hard to describe the
It's hard to describe the room.
unfoldment.
It's hard to describe the room. This
room
is
is one
room
is one complete
is one complete unity
room
is one complete unity in
is one complete unity in which
room
is one complete unity in which that
which
which looks
which looks like
which looks like separate
which looks like separate individuals
is
is perceptual
which looks like separate individuals
is perceptual only
is perceptual only and
which looks like separate individuals
is perceptual only and not
is perceptual only and not a
which looks like separate individuals
is perceptual only and not a reality.
It's
It's all
It's all one
It's all one complete
It's all one complete total
It's all one complete total united
It's all one complete total united unity
within
within which
It's all one complete total united unity
within which there's
within which there's definitions
It's all one complete total united unity
within which there's definitions as
various
various bodies
various bodies and
various bodies and all
various bodies and all but
various bodies and all but those
various bodies and all but those are
various bodies and all but those are the
expressions
expressions of
various bodies and all but those are the
expressions of the
expressions of the unity.
various bodies and all but those are the
expressions of the unity. The
expressions
expressions of
expressions of the
expressions of the unity
expressions of the unity the
expressions of the unity the expressions
of
of the
expressions of the unity the expressions
of the you
of the you of
expressions of the unity the expressions
of the you of the
of the you of the rain
expressions of the unity the expressions
of the you of the rain are
of the you of the rain are look
expressions of the unity the expressions
of the you of the rain are look like
separate
separate raindrops.
separate raindrops. Uhhuh.
However,
However, the
separate raindrops. Uhhuh.
However, the rain
However, the rain is
separate raindrops. Uhhuh.
However, the rain is one.
However, the rain is one. So
separate raindrops. Uhhuh.
However, the rain is one. So there
However, the rain is one. So there is
separate raindrops. Uhhuh.
However, the rain is one. So there is no
separation.
Uhhuh.
Now
Now we've
Now we've said
Now we've said before
Now we've said before that
Now we've said before that evolution
Now we've said before that evolution and
creation
creation are
Now we've said before that evolution and
creation are one
creation are one and
Now we've said before that evolution and
creation are one and the
creation are one and the same
Now we've said before that evolution and
creation are one and the same thing.
creation are one and the same thing. So
the
the one
the one thing
the one thing we've
the one thing we've emphasized
the one thing we've emphasized in
the one thing we've emphasized in almost
every
every lecture
the one thing we've emphasized in almost
every lecture is
every lecture is to
the one thing we've emphasized in almost
every lecture is to realize
every lecture is to realize that
the one thing we've emphasized in almost
every lecture is to realize that nothing
is
is causing
is causing anything.
is causing anything. So
is causing anything. So one
is causing anything. So one jump
is causing anything. So one jump from
being
being logical
is causing anything. So one jump from
being logical and
being logical and sensible
is causing anything. So one jump from
being logical and sensible and
being logical and sensible and sane
is causing anything. So one jump from
being logical and sensible and sane that
being
being very
being very bizarre
being very bizarre a
being very bizarre a mystic
is
is to
being very bizarre a mystic
is to let
is to let go
being very bizarre a mystic
is to let go that
is to let go that anything
being very bizarre a mystic
is to let go that anything is
is to let go that anything is causing
anything.
Nothing
Nothing is
anything.
Nothing is causing
Nothing is causing anything
anything.
Nothing is causing anything anywhere
Nothing is causing anything anywhere in
the
the world.
Wow.
Wow. Is
the world.
Wow. Is that
Wow. Is that true?
Sounds
Sounds mad
Sounds mad to
Sounds mad to me.
That
That is
Sounds mad to me.
That is true.
That is true. Is
Sounds mad to me.
That is true. Is this
that
that is
that is true
that is true on
that is true on the
that is true on the level
that is true on the level of
that is true on the level of essence.
It's
It's not
that is true on the level of essence.
It's not true
It's not true on
that is true on the level of essence.
It's not true on the
It's not true on the level
that is true on the level of essence.
It's not true on the level of
perception.
perception. On
perception. On the
perception. On the level
perception. On the level of
perception. On the level of perception,
there
there always
perception. On the level of perception,
there always seems
there always seems to
perception. On the level of perception,
there always seems to be
there always seems to be a
perception. On the level of perception,
there always seems to be a this
there always seems to be a this causing
a
a that.
a that. There's
a that. There's always
a that. There's always a
a that. There's always a victim
a that. There's always a victim and
a that. There's always a victim and a
perpetrator.
perpetrator. Yeah.
Where
Where would
Where would politics
Where would politics be
Where would politics be without
Where would politics be without a
Where would politics be without a victim
and
and a
Where would politics be without a victim
and a perpetrator?
There's
There's always
There's always an
There's always an evil
There's always an evil one
There's always an evil one causing
There's always an evil one causing harm
to
to the
There's always an evil one causing harm
to the innocent
to the innocent one.
Anyway,
Anyway, there's
Anyway, there's always
Anyway, there's always causation.
Anyway, there's always causation. Now,
emergence
emergence has
Anyway, there's always causation. Now,
emergence has which
emergence has which we've
Anyway, there's always causation. Now,
emergence has which we've been
emergence has which we've been lecturing
about
about for
about for years
about for years and
about for years and written
about for years and written about
about for years and written about is
about for years and written about is now
becoming
becoming a
about for years and written about is now
becoming a doctrine
becoming a doctrine in
about for years and written about is now
becoming a doctrine in pretty
becoming a doctrine in pretty much
advanced
advanced scientific
advanced scientific theory.
advanced scientific theory. Emergence
advanced scientific theory. Emergence is
now
now becoming
advanced scientific theory. Emergence is
now becoming described
uh
uh as
uh as a
uh as a scientific
uh as a scientific uh
uh as a scientific uh statement
emergence.
So
So evolution
So evolution is
So evolution is creation.
So evolution is creation. So
So evolution is creation. So there's
So evolution is creation. So there's no
conflict
conflict between
So evolution is creation. So there's no
conflict between evolution
conflict between evolution and
So evolution is creation. So there's no
conflict between evolution and creation
because
because evolution
because evolution is
because evolution is creation
because evolution is creation and
creation
creation expresses
because evolution is creation and
creation expresses itself
creation expresses itself as
because evolution is creation and
creation expresses itself as evolution.
So
the
the infinite
So
the infinite field
the infinite field out
So
the infinite field out of
the infinite field out of which
So
the infinite field out of which all
phenomena
phenomena and
phenomena and existence
phenomena and existence arise
phenomena and existence arise is
phenomena and existence arise is the
field
field of
phenomena and existence arise is the
field of consciousness
field of consciousness itself.
phenomena and existence arise is the
field of consciousness itself. The
field of consciousness itself. The field
of
of consciousness
of consciousness itself
of consciousness itself which
of consciousness itself which in
of consciousness itself which in other
ter
ter terminology
of consciousness itself which in other
ter terminology is
ter terminology is called
of consciousness itself which in other
ter terminology is called the
ter terminology is called the Buddha
nature.
nature. The
nature. The Buddha
nature. The Buddha nature
nature. The Buddha nature then
nature. The Buddha nature then is
nonlinear
nonlinear non-defined
nature. The Buddha nature then is
nonlinear non-defined has
nonlinear non-defined has no
nature. The Buddha nature then is
nonlinear non-defined has no content
and
and arises
and arises as
and arises as an
and arises as an awareness
and arises as an awareness when
and arises as an awareness when all
barriers
barriers to
and arises as an awareness when all
barriers to it
barriers to it have
and arises as an awareness when all
barriers to it have been
barriers to it have been removed.
So
So I
So I will
So I will give
So I will give you
So I will give you a
So I will give you a lecture
So I will give you a lecture this
morning,
a
a short
a short lecture,
a
a glorious
a short lecture,
a glorious lecture,
a
a lecture
a lecture of
a lecture of great
a lecture of great profoundity.
You'll
You'll notice
a lecture of great profoundity.
You'll notice all
You'll notice all Zen
a lecture of great profoundity.
You'll notice all Zen masters
You'll notice all Zen masters etc.
always
always give
always give you
always give you a
always give you a flowery
always give you a flowery presentation
of
of what
always give you a flowery presentation
of what they're
of what they're about
always give you a flowery presentation
of what they're about to
of what they're about to say.
You
You will
You will now
You will now hear
You will now hear the
You will now hear the greatest
You will now hear the greatest and
You will now hear the greatest and most
profound
profound teaching
which
which has
which has come
which has come down
which has come down through
which has come down through 18
patriarchs
from
from mount.
from mount. Yep.
In
In which
from mount. Yep.
In which the
In which the great
from mount. Yep.
In which the great master
In which the great master said
from mount. Yep.
In which the great master said the
following.
To
To get
following.
To get it,
To get it, you've
following.
To get it, you've got
To get it, you've got to
following.
To get it, you've got to really
To get it, you've got to really strain
your
your awareness
your awareness and
your awareness and your
your awareness and your will
your awareness and your will to
understand
the
the wisdom
the wisdom that
the wisdom that is
the wisdom that is about
the wisdom that is about to
the wisdom that is about to be
proclaimed.
Go.
That
That is
Go.
That is the
That is the wisdom
Go.
That is the wisdom of
That is the wisdom of the
Go.
That is the wisdom of the infinite
reality
which
which I
reality
which I have
which I have transmitted
reality
which I have transmitted to
which I have transmitted to you.
Therefore,
Therefore, never
Therefore, never say
Therefore, never say that
Therefore, never say that you
Therefore, never say that you were
Therefore, never say that you were not
that
that you
Therefore, never say that you were not
that you did
that you did not
Therefore, never say that you were not
that you did not hear
that you did not hear it.
Did
Did everyone
Did everyone hear
Did everyone hear it?
Ah,
all
all these
all these bodhis
all these bodhis zappas
all these bodhis zappas here,
all these bodhis zappas here, all
all these bodhis zappas here, all the
Buddhas
Buddhas of
all these bodhis zappas here, all the
Buddhas of the
Buddhas of the future.
all these bodhis zappas here, all the
Buddhas of the future. First
Buddhas of the future. First you
all these bodhis zappas here, all the
Buddhas of the future. First you hear
Buddhas of the future. First you hear it
from
from those
from those who
from those who know
from those who know it,
from those who know it, and
from those who know it, and then
from those who know it, and then it's
transmitted
transmitted silently
from those who know it, and then it's
transmitted silently down
transmitted silently down through
from those who know it, and then it's
transmitted silently down through the
ages
ages as
ages as unspoken.
ages as unspoken. Because
ages as unspoken. Because the
ages as unspoken. Because the minute
ages as unspoken. Because the minute you
speak,
speak, it's
ages as unspoken. Because the minute you
speak, it's no
speak, it's no longer
the
the truth.
So
So now
the truth.
So now you
So now you know
the truth.
So now you know this
So now you know this the
the truth.
So now you know this the core
So now you know this the core of
the truth.
So now you know this the core of Zen
Buddhism.
It
It only
Buddhism.
It only took
It only took 30
Buddhism.
It only took 30 years
It only took 30 years of
Buddhism.
It only took 30 years of meditation
It only took 30 years of meditation to
get
get it.
get it. You
get it. You know,
look
look at
get it. You know,
look at all
look at all the
get it. You know,
look at all the black
look at all the black widowed
get it. You know,
look at all the black widowed spiders
look at all the black widowed spiders I
could
could have
could have carried.
All right.
All right. So
the
the self-realization
the self-realization then
the self-realization then is
the self-realization then is autonomous.
It
It comes
the self-realization then is autonomous.
It comes about
It comes about of
the self-realization then is autonomous.
It comes about of its
It comes about of its own.
the self-realization then is autonomous.
It comes about of its own. There
It comes about of its own. There is
the self-realization then is autonomous.
It comes about of its own. There is no
cause.
cause. We
cause. We know
cause. We know that
cause. We know that there
cause. We know that there is
cause. We know that there is like
cause. We know that there is like a
propitious
propitious readiness
cause. We know that there is like a
propitious readiness in
propitious readiness in which
cause. We know that there is like a
propitious readiness in which the
condition
condition is
condition is more
condition is more likely
condition is more likely to
condition is more likely to occur.
Just
Just as
condition is more likely to occur.
Just as it's
Just as it's more
condition is more likely to occur.
Just as it's more likely
Just as it's more likely to
condition is more likely to occur.
Just as it's more likely to occur,
Just as it's more likely to occur, the
rain
rain is
rain is more
rain is more likely
rain is more likely to
rain is more likely to occur
rain is more likely to occur on
rain is more likely to occur on a
rain is more likely to occur on a cloudy
day
day when
rain is more likely to occur on a cloudy
day when the
day when the humidity
rain is more likely to occur on a cloudy
day when the humidity is
day when the humidity is a
rain is more likely to occur on a cloudy
day when the humidity is a certain
level,
level, etc.
level, etc. But
level, etc. But that
level, etc. But that doesn't
level, etc. But that doesn't cause
level, etc. But that doesn't cause it
level, etc. But that doesn't cause it to
rain
rain because
level, etc. But that doesn't cause it to
rain because right
rain because right now
level, etc. But that doesn't cause it to
rain because right now it's
rain because right now it's not
level, etc. But that doesn't cause it to
rain because right now it's not raining.
So
So if
So if it
So if it caused
So if it caused it
So if it caused it to
So if it caused it to rain,
So if it caused it to rain, it
So if it caused it to rain, it would
So if it caused it to rain, it would be
raining
raining right
So if it caused it to rain, it would be
raining right now.
raining right now. So
So if it caused it to rain, it would be
raining right now. So there's
raining right now. So there's other
factors
factors involved.
factors involved. Uh-huh.
factors involved. Uh-huh. Readiness
factors involved. Uh-huh. Readiness and
will
will and
factors involved. Uh-huh. Readiness and
will and karmic
will and karmic propensities
and
and ultimately
and ultimately is
and ultimately is it
and ultimately is it is
and ultimately is it is the
and ultimately is it is the grace
and ultimately is it is the grace of
God.
God. Uhhuh.
The
The grace
The grace of
The grace of God
it's
it's autonomous
and
and it's
and it's a
and it's a state
and it's a state of
and it's a state of awareness.
It's
It's beyond
and it's a state of awareness.
It's beyond cause
It's beyond cause and
and it's a state of awareness.
It's beyond cause and effect.
And
And it
And it is
And it is the
And it is the that
And it is the that which
And it is the that which is
And it is the that which is speaking
And it is the that which is speaking now
is
is what
And it is the that which is speaking now
is what it
is what it is.
And it is the that which is speaking now
is what it is. That
is what it is. That which
And it is the that which is speaking now
is what it is. That which is
is what it is. That which is is
And it is the that which is speaking now
is what it is. That which is is speaking
now
now is
now is an
now is an impersonal
now is an impersonal awareness
knowingness
knowingness which
now is an impersonal awareness
knowingness which has
knowingness which has nothing
now is an impersonal awareness
knowingness which has nothing to
knowingness which has nothing to do
now is an impersonal awareness
knowingness which has nothing to do with
the
the speaker.
Uh
Uh it
the speaker.
Uh it uh
Uh it uh speaks
the speaker.
Uh it uh speaks on
Uh it uh speaks on its
the speaker.
Uh it uh speaks on its own
Uh it uh speaks on its own when
the speaker.
Uh it uh speaks on its own when it's
propitious
propitious to
propitious to do
propitious to do so.
propitious to do so. So
propitious to do so. So if
propitious to do so. So if it
propitious to do so. So if it fulfills
propitious to do so. So if it fulfills a
role
role of
propitious to do so. So if it fulfills a
role of a
role of a teacher
propitious to do so. So if it fulfills a
role of a teacher then
role of a teacher then the
propitious to do so. So if it fulfills a
role of a teacher then the perushia
role of a teacher then the perushia the
speaker
speaker the
speaker the infinite
speaker the infinite self
speaker the infinite self within
speaker the infinite self within will
speak
speak uh
speaker the infinite self within will
speak uh and
speak uh and its
speaker the infinite self within will
speak uh and its speakingness
speak uh and its speakingness is
automatically
automatically correlated
automatically correlated to
automatically correlated to the
automatically correlated to the level
automatically correlated to the level of
the
the listener.
Therefore,
Therefore, something
Therefore, something very
Therefore, something very simple
Therefore, something very simple would
be
be said
Therefore, something very simple would
be said uh
be said uh to
Therefore, something very simple would
be said uh to a
be said uh to a child.
Therefore, something very simple would
be said uh to a child. I
be said uh to a child. I see.
Therefore, something very simple would
be said uh to a child. I see. And
be said uh to a child. I see. And yet
the
the child
the child could
the child could get
the child could get it
the child could get it and
the child could get it and then
the child could get it and then on
the child could get it and then on the
way
way home
the child could get it and then on the
way home pray
way home pray as
the child could get it and then on the
way home pray as George
way home pray as George was
the child could get it and then on the
way home pray as George was telling
way home pray as George was telling me
fact
fact that
fact that it's
fact that it's simple
fact that it's simple doesn't
fact that it's simple doesn't mean
fact that it's simple doesn't mean they
won't
won't get
fact that it's simple doesn't mean they
won't get it
won't get it beyond.
fact that it's simple doesn't mean they
won't get it beyond. So
won't get it beyond. So the
fact that it's simple doesn't mean they
won't get it beyond. So the mystical
won't get it beyond. So the mystical is
autonomous
autonomous spontaneous.
It's
It's a
autonomous spontaneous.
It's a field
It's a field of
autonomous spontaneous.
It's a field of awareness
It's a field of awareness which
autonomous spontaneous.
It's a field of awareness which arises
not
not as
not as not
not as not caused
not as not caused by
not as not caused by phenomena.
So
So listening
not as not caused by phenomena.
So listening here
So listening here on
not as not caused by phenomena.
So listening here on the
So listening here on the way
not as not caused by phenomena.
So listening here on the way to
uh
uh Andrea
uh Andrea Bochelli.
All right.
The
The music
The music of
The music of Andre
The music of Andre Bochelli
uh
causes
causes people
causes people to
causes people to cry.
Now,
Now, it
causes people to cry.
Now, it isn't
Now, it isn't the
causes people to cry.
Now, it isn't the music
Now, it isn't the music that
causes people to cry.
Now, it isn't the music that causes
Now, it isn't the music that causes you
to
to cry.
It's
It's the
to cry.
It's the energy
It's the energy field
to cry.
It's the energy field that
It's the energy field that that
incredible
incredible beauty
incredible beauty brings
incredible beauty brings up
incredible beauty brings up and
incredible beauty brings up and it's
that
that energy
incredible beauty brings up and it's
that energy field
that energy field that
incredible beauty brings up and it's
that energy field that makes
that energy field that makes you
incredible beauty brings up and it's
that energy field that makes you cry.
So,
So, there's
So, there's no
So, there's no point
So, there's no point of
So, there's no point of worshiping
So, there's no point of worshiping the
music
music of
So, there's no point of worshiping the
music of Andrea
music of Andrea Bochelli
So, there's no point of worshiping the
music of Andrea Bochelli because
music of Andrea Bochelli because what
makes
makes you
makes you cry
makes you cry is
makes you cry is not
makes you cry is not the
makes you cry is not the music
makes you cry is not the music but
makes you cry is not the music but the
energy
energy that
makes you cry is not the music but the
energy that arises
energy that arises in
makes you cry is not the music but the
energy that arises in association
energy that arises in association with
it.
Yeah.
So
So the
So the mystical
So the mystical state
So the mystical state is
So the mystical state is more
So the mystical state is more like
So the mystical state is more like an
energy
energy vibration,
a
a field
a field of
a field of consciousness.
a field of consciousness. A
a field of consciousness. A field
a field of consciousness. A field of
consciousness.
So
So at
So at one
So at one of
So at one of his
So at one of his concerts,
everyone
everyone goes
So at one of his concerts,
everyone goes into
everyone goes into an
So at one of his concerts,
everyone goes into an enchanted
everyone goes into an enchanted state.
Enchanted.
Enchanted. It's
Enchanted. It's enchanting.
You're
You're in
Enchanted. It's enchanting.
You're in a
You're in a different
Enchanted. It's enchanting.
You're in a different state.
You're
You're in
You're in a
You're in a different
You're in a different state
because
because the
You're in a different state
because the incredible
because the incredible beauty
You're in a different state
because the incredible beauty of
because the incredible beauty of the
music
music transports
music transports you
music transports you to
music transports you to a
music transports you to a different
state
state of
music transports you to a different
state of consciousness.
state of consciousness. Yes.
It's
It's not
It's not caused
It's not caused because
It's not caused because you
It's not caused because you have
It's not caused because you have to
It's not caused because you have to have
the
the capacity
It's not caused because you have to have
the capacity to
the capacity to respond
It's not caused because you have to have
the capacity to respond that
the capacity to respond that way.
And
And we
And we know
And we know from
And we know from the
And we know from the brain
And we know from the brain physiology
that
that people
And we know from the brain physiology
that people that
that people that whose
And we know from the brain physiology
that people that whose brain
that people that whose brain function
And we know from the brain physiology
that people that whose brain function is
over
over here
over here will
over here will respond
over here will respond by
over here will respond by crying
over here will respond by crying to
beauty.
These
These people
These people will
These people will say
These people will say turn
These people will say turn that
These people will say turn that off
These people will say turn that off for
God's
God's sake.
These people will say turn that off for
God's sake. I
God's sake. I can't
These people will say turn that off for
God's sake. I can't hear
God's sake. I can't hear the
These people will say turn that off for
God's sake. I can't hear the ball
God's sake. I can't hear the ball game.
You
You know
that's
that's true.
I've
I've watched
I've watched people
I've watched people be
I've watched people be very
I've watched people be very annoyed
I've watched people be very annoyed by
beauty,
beauty, demand
I've watched people be very annoyed by
beauty, demand that
beauty, demand that it
I've watched people be very annoyed by
beauty, demand that it be
beauty, demand that it be turned
I've watched people be very annoyed by
beauty, demand that it be turned off.
Turn
Turn that
Turn that turn
Turn that turn that
Turn that turn that off.
Turn that turn that off. Turn
Turn that turn that off. Turn that
Turn that turn that off. Turn that off.
They're
They're listening
Turn that turn that off. Turn that off.
They're listening to
They're listening to the
Turn that turn that off. Turn that off.
They're listening to the most
incredible,
incredible, beautiful
incredible, beautiful music
incredible, beautiful music in
incredible, beautiful music in the
incredible, beautiful music in the whole
world.
world. And
incredible, beautiful music in the whole
world. And it
world. And it makes
incredible, beautiful music in the whole
world. And it makes you
world. And it makes you weep
incredible, beautiful music in the whole
world. And it makes you weep with
world. And it makes you weep with this
beauty
beauty and
beauty and they'll
beauty and they'll say,
beauty and they'll say, "Turn
beauty and they'll say, "Turn that
beauty and they'll say, "Turn that off.
Turn
Turn that
beauty and they'll say, "Turn that off.
Turn that off."
See,
See, that's
See, that's a
See, that's a different
See, that's a different brain
See, that's a different brain function.
Those
Those people,
See, that's a different brain function.
Those people, you
Those people, you know,
See, that's a different brain function.
Those people, you know, are
Those people, you know, are limited.
They
They grew
They grew up
They grew up to
They grew up to here
They grew up to here and
They grew up to here and then
They grew up to here and then they
stopped
stopped there
They grew up to here and then they
stopped there somehow.
stopped there somehow. And
they
they they
they they didn't
they they didn't get
they they didn't get to
they they didn't get to the
they they didn't get to the heart
they they didn't get to the heart yet.
So
So it's
they they didn't get to the heart yet.
So it's like
So it's like the
they they didn't get to the heart yet.
So it's like the the
So it's like the the mystic
they they didn't get to the heart yet.
So it's like the the mystic the
So it's like the the mystic the heart
energy
energy has
energy has now
energy has now risen.
Uh
Uh technically
energy has now risen.
Uh technically uh
Uh technically uh it's
energy has now risen.
Uh technically uh it's called
Uh technically uh it's called the
energy has now risen.
Uh technically uh it's called the eye
the
the third
the third the
the third the Buddha
the third the Buddha body.
the third the Buddha body. So
the third the Buddha body. So the
aetheric
aetheric body
the third the Buddha body. So the
aetheric body you
aetheric body you see
the third the Buddha body. So the
aetheric body you see the
aetheric body you see the energizing
the third the Buddha body. So the
aetheric body you see the energizing of
the
the nervous
the nervous system
the nervous system comes
the nervous system comes about
the nervous system comes about through
the
the atheric
the nervous system comes about through
the atheric body
the atheric body and
the nervous system comes about through
the atheric body and it's
the atheric body and it's a
the nervous system comes about through
the atheric body and it's a level
the atheric body and it's a level 200
and
and up
and up you
and up you develop
and up you develop an
and up you develop an atheric
and up you develop an atheric body.
and up you develop an atheric body. Now
below
below 200
and up you develop an atheric body. Now
below 200 people
below 200 people do
and up you develop an atheric body. Now
below 200 people do not
below 200 people do not have
and up you develop an atheric body. Now
below 200 people do not have an
below 200 people do not have an atheric
body.
I
I don't
body.
I don't know
I don't know how
body.
I don't know how how
I don't know how how they
body.
I don't know how how they get
I don't know how how they get along
body.
I don't know how how they get along but
they
they do.
Under
Under 200
they do.
Under 200 they
Under 200 they do
they do.
Under 200 they do not
Under 200 they do not have
they do.
Under 200 they do not have an
Under 200 they do not have an atheric
body.
How
How do
body.
How do you
How do you like
body.
How do you like that?
So
So you
So you cannot
So you cannot expect
So you cannot expect people
So you cannot expect people who
So you cannot expect people who don't
even
even have
So you cannot expect people who don't
even have an
even have an atheric
So you cannot expect people who don't
even have an atheric body
to
to faint
to faint with
to faint with joy
to faint with joy at
to faint with joy at the
to faint with joy at the sound
to faint with joy at the sound of
to faint with joy at the sound of Andrea
Bochelli
Bochelli because
to faint with joy at the sound of Andrea
Bochelli because they
Bochelli because they don't
to faint with joy at the sound of Andrea
Bochelli because they don't have
Bochelli because they don't have that
which
which vibrates
which vibrates to
which vibrates to it.
which vibrates to it. There
which vibrates to it. There is
which vibrates to it. There is no
resonance
resonance you
which vibrates to it. There is no
resonance you know
resonance you know like
which vibrates to it. There is no
resonance you know like a
resonance you know like a sounding
which vibrates to it. There is no
resonance you know like a sounding board
tuning
tuning fork
tuning fork you
tuning fork you resonate.
tuning fork you resonate. Huh?
tuning fork you resonate. Huh? So
lacking
lacking that
tuning fork you resonate. Huh? So
lacking that capacity
lacking that capacity which
tuning fork you resonate. Huh? So
lacking that capacity which is
lacking that capacity which is genetic.
So
So we
So we see
So we see that
So we see that the
So we see that the majority
So we see that the majority of
So we see that the majority of mankind
is
is unable
So we see that the majority of mankind
is unable to
is unable to respond
So we see that the majority of mankind
is unable to respond to
is unable to respond to beauty,
So we see that the majority of mankind
is unable to respond to beauty, love
is unable to respond to beauty, love and
truth.
truth. Majority.
Okay.
Those
Those are
Those are today's
Those are today's hard
Those are today's hard words.
Those are today's hard words. They
Those are today's hard words. They are
truthful.
truthful. Resist.
That
That is
That is the
That is the unfortunate
That is the unfortunate truth.
A
A lot
That is the unfortunate truth.
A lot of
A lot of competition
That is the unfortunate truth.
A lot of competition for
A lot of competition for the
That is the unfortunate truth.
A lot of competition for the title
A lot of competition for the title of
the
the unfortunate
the unfortunate truth.
The
The unfortunate
the unfortunate truth.
The unfortunate truth
The unfortunate truth unfortunately
the unfortunate truth.
The unfortunate truth unfortunately is
not
not the
not the truth.
not the truth. So
not the truth. So anyway,
not the truth. So anyway, aside
not the truth. So anyway, aside from
that
uh
uh so
uh so this
uh so this is
uh so this is a
uh so this is a capacity
people
people in
uh so this is a capacity
people in this
people in this audience
uh so this is a capacity
people in this audience are
people in this audience are motivated
differently
differently than
differently than the
differently than the rest
differently than the rest of
differently than the rest of the
differently than the rest of the world.
You
You think
differently than the rest of the world.
You think the
You think the rest
differently than the rest of the world.
You think the rest of
You think the rest of the
differently than the rest of the world.
You think the rest of the world
You think the rest of the world is
differently than the rest of the world.
You think the rest of the world is like
you?
you? They
you? They are
you? They are not
you? They are not like
you? They are not like you.
you? They are not like you. First
you? They are not like you. First of
all,
all, he
you? They are not like you. First of
all, he would
all, he would not
you? They are not like you. First of
all, he would not sit
all, he would not sit here
you? They are not like you. First of
all, he would not sit here and
all, he would not sit here and listen
you? They are not like you. First of
all, he would not sit here and listen to
a
a lecture
a lecture on
a lecture on the
a lecture on the mystic
in
in the
a lecture on the mystic
in the linear
in the linear domain.
a lecture on the mystic
in the linear domain. There
in the linear domain. There is
a lecture on the mystic
in the linear domain. There is no
in the linear domain. There is no such
thing
thing as
thing as the
thing as the mystic
thing as the mystic and
thing as the mystic and uh
thing as the mystic and uh the
thing as the mystic and uh the skeptics
people
people like
thing as the mystic and uh the skeptics
people like skeptics
people like skeptics you
thing as the mystic and uh the skeptics
people like skeptics you know
people like skeptics you know uh
thing as the mystic and uh the skeptics
people like skeptics you know uh can't
believe
believe anything
believe anything uh
believe anything uh that
believe anything uh that is
believe anything uh that is beyond
pedestrian
pedestrian and
believe anything uh that is beyond
pedestrian and literal
pedestrian and literal materialistic.
All
All right.
All right. So
the
the reason
All right. So
the reason uh
the reason uh neuroscience
All right. So
the reason uh neuroscience which
investigates
investigates consciousness
investigates consciousness has
investigates consciousness has been
investigates consciousness has been a
total
total failure
investigates consciousness has been a
total failure thus
total failure thus far
investigates consciousness has been a
total failure thus far is
total failure thus far is they
investigates consciousness has been a
total failure thus far is they don't
understand
understand how
understand how it
understand how it works.
The
The energy
understand how it works.
The energy body
The energy body is
understand how it works.
The energy body is so-called
The energy body is so-called atheric
body.
Now
Now if
body.
Now if you
Now if you know
body.
Now if you know Maxwell
Now if you know Maxwell Maxwell
body.
Now if you know Maxwell Maxwell is a
famous
famous scientist
famous scientist discovered
famous scientist discovered that
famous scientist discovered that if
famous scientist discovered that if you
put
put a
famous scientist discovered that if you
put a magnetic
put a magnetic field
famous scientist discovered that if you
put a magnetic field around
put a magnetic field around a
famous scientist discovered that if you
put a magnetic field around a wire
put a magnetic field around a wire it
produces
produces electricity.
produces electricity. Wow.
produces electricity. Wow. That's
produces electricity. Wow. That's how
you
you get
produces electricity. Wow. That's how
you get generators
you get generators going.
produces electricity. Wow. That's how
you get generators going. And
you get generators going. And the
produces electricity. Wow. That's how
you get generators going. And the same
thing
thing happens
thing happens if
thing happens if you
thing happens if you put
thing happens if you put electricity
around
around the
thing happens if you put electricity
around the wire
around the wire you
thing happens if you put electricity
around the wire you get
around the wire you get magnetism.
thing happens if you put electricity
around the wire you get magnetism. Mag
magnetism
magnetism electricity.
So
So the
magnetism electricity.
So the way
So the way the
magnetism electricity.
So the way the human
So the way the human nervous
magnetism electricity.
So the way the human nervous system
So the way the human nervous system and
practically
practically nobody
practically nobody in
practically nobody in this
practically nobody in this whole
practically nobody in this whole world
knows
knows this.
practically nobody in this whole world
knows this. Nobody
knows this. Nobody even
practically nobody in this whole world
knows this. Nobody even knows
knows this. Nobody even knows this
practically nobody in this whole world
knows this. Nobody even knows this is
that
that the
that the atheric
that the atheric body
that the atheric body which
that the atheric body which is
that the atheric body which is the
energy
energy body
which
which exists
which exists independently
which exists independently of
which exists independently of the
physical
physical body.
which exists independently of the
physical body. And
physical body. And people
which exists independently of the
physical body. And people who've
physical body. And people who've been
out
out of
out of body
out of body know
out of body know that
out of body know that very
out of body know that very well.
out of body know that very well. who
out of body know that very well. who you
really
really are
out of body know that very well. who you
really are is
really are is sitting
out of body know that very well. who you
really are is sitting up
really are is sitting up here
out of body know that very well. who you
really are is sitting up here in
really are is sitting up here in the
out of body know that very well. who you
really are is sitting up here in the air
and
and the
and the body's
and the body's over
and the body's over there.
and the body's over there. The
athetheric
athetheric body
and the body's over there. The
athetheric body then
athetheric body then is
and the body's over there. The
athetheric body then is the
athetheric body then is the energy
to
to which
to which the
to which the neurons
are
are now
to which the neurons
are now energized.
are now energized. So
to which the neurons
are now energized. So the
are now energized. So the atheric
to which the neurons
are now energized. So the atheric body
is
is like
is like the
is like the electrical
is like the electrical field
that
that ignites
is like the electrical field
that ignites the
that ignites the response
is like the electrical field
that ignites the response of
that ignites the response of the
neurons.
So
So when
neurons.
So when you
So when you leave
neurons.
So when you leave the
So when you leave the physical
neurons.
So when you leave the physical body,
you
you don't
you don't need
you don't need the
you don't need the physical
you don't need the physical body
you don't need the physical body because
your
your energy
you don't need the physical body because
your energy body
your energy body is
you don't need the physical body because
your energy body is independent
your energy body is independent of
you don't need the physical body because
your energy body is independent of it.
The
The only
The only thing
The only thing it
The only thing it serves
The only thing it serves then
The only thing it serves then is
The only thing it serves then is the
physical
physical body
The only thing it serves then is the
physical body can
physical body can can
The only thing it serves then is the
physical body can can transport
transpose
transpose this
transpose this information
transpose this information and
experience
experience into
transpose this information and
experience into physical
experience into physical languaging
transpose this information and
experience into physical languaging and
verbalizing
verbalizing and
verbalizing and give
verbalizing and give a
verbalizing and give a lecture
verbalizing and give a lecture or
verbalizing and give a lecture or write
a
a book
verbalizing and give a lecture or write
a book on
a book on it.
verbalizing and give a lecture or write
a book on it. However,
a book on it. However, the
verbalizing and give a lecture or write
a book on it. However, the condition
itself
itself is
itself is autonomous.
The
The rising
itself is autonomous.
The rising of
The rising of the
itself is autonomous.
The rising of the condundalini
The rising of the condundalini energy.
So
So the
So the through
So the through the
So the through the through
So the through the through evolution,
you
you finally
So the through the through evolution,
you finally reach
you finally reach a
So the through the through evolution,
you finally reach a state
you finally reach a state where
So the through the through evolution,
you finally reach a state where you're
approaching
approaching being
approaching being the
approaching being the human.
approaching being the human. And
approaching being the human. And now
even
even the
approaching being the human. And now
even the human
even the human advances
approaching being the human. And now
even the human advances through
even the human advances through crew
magnum
magnum man
magnum man and
magnum man and all
magnum man and all the
magnum man and all the early
magnum man and all the early man
magnum man and all the early man that
only
only calibrated
magnum man and all the early man that
only calibrated about
only calibrated about 80.
And
And then
And then you
And then you evolve
And then you evolve to
And then you evolve to the
And then you evolve to the capacity
And then you evolve to the capacity for
spiritual
spiritual awareness.
And then you evolve to the capacity for
spiritual awareness. that
spiritual awareness. that side
And then you evolve to the capacity for
spiritual awareness. that side of
spiritual awareness. that side of the
brain
brain and
brain and you
a
a unique
brain and you
a unique energy
a unique energy which
brain and you
a unique energy which has
a unique energy which has been
brain and you
a unique energy which has been called
throughout
throughout time
throughout time condundolini
throughout time condundolini energy.
throughout time condundolini energy. So
one
one of
throughout time condundolini energy. So
one of the
one of the yoga
throughout time condundolini energy. So
one of the yoga yoga
one of the yoga yoga all
throughout time condundolini energy. So
one of the yoga yoga all the
one of the yoga yoga all the yogas
throughout time condundolini energy. So
one of the yoga yoga all the yogas in
fact
fact emphasize
fact emphasize uh
taking
taking advantage
fact emphasize uh
taking advantage of
taking advantage of of
fact emphasize uh
taking advantage of of the
taking advantage of of the condundolini
energy
energy to
energy to facilitate
energy to facilitate spiritual
awareness.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So we
All right. So we said
All right. So we said it's
All right. So we said it's autonomous.
It's
It's always
All right. So we said it's autonomous.
It's always complete.
It's always complete. It
All right. So we said it's autonomous.
It's always complete. It doesn't
It's always complete. It doesn't go
All right. So we said it's autonomous.
It's always complete. It doesn't go from
incomplete
incomplete to
incomplete to complete.
incomplete to complete. It's
incomplete to complete. It's comp
incomplete to complete. It's comp it's
complete
complete right
incomplete to complete. It's comp it's
complete right from
complete right from the
incomplete to complete. It's comp it's
complete right from the beginning.
complete right from the beginning. When
I
I lay
I lay in
I lay in the
I lay in the snowbank,
I lay in the snowbank, the
I lay in the snowbank, the state
I lay in the snowbank, the state was
complete
complete instantly
I lay in the snowbank, the state was
complete instantly once
complete instantly once and
I lay in the snowbank, the state was
complete instantly once and for
complete instantly once and for all.
I lay in the snowbank, the state was
complete instantly once and for all. It
didn't
didn't start
didn't start get
didn't start get louder
didn't start get louder and
didn't start get louder and louder
didn't start get louder and louder or
creep
creep up
didn't start get louder and louder or
creep up your
creep up your legs
didn't start get louder and louder or
creep up your legs or
anything.
It's
It's like
anything.
It's like you
It's like you were
anything.
It's like you were suddenly
It's like you were suddenly in
anything.
It's like you were suddenly in a
It's like you were suddenly in a totally
different
different realm.
different realm. And
it
it was
different realm. And
it was beautifific.
it was beautifific. I
different realm. And
it was beautifific. I don't
it was beautifific. I don't know
different realm. And
it was beautifific. I don't know if
it was beautifific. I don't know if I
had
had to
had to do
had to do it
had to do it over
had to do it over again,
had to do it over again, I
had to do it over again, I would
had to do it over again, I would I
had to do it over again, I would I would
have
have just
had to do it over again, I would I would
have just left
have just left the
had to do it over again, I would I would
have just left the body
have just left the body there.
That
That was
That was would
That was would have
That was would have been
That was would have been the
That was would have been the best
That was would have been the best thing
to
to do.
That was would have been the best thing
to do. However,
to do. However, I
That was would have been the best thing
to do. However, I had
to do. However, I had a
That was would have been the best thing
to do. However, I had a father
to do. However, I had a father and
That was would have been the best thing
to do. However, I had a father and he
went
went looking
went looking for
went looking for me
went looking for me and
went looking for me and our
went looking for me and our old
went looking for me and our old model
went looking for me and our old model a
Ford
Ford where
went looking for me and our old model a
Ford where was
Ford where was the
went looking for me and our old model a
Ford where was the boy
Ford where was the boy on
went looking for me and our old model a
Ford where was the boy on his
Ford where was the boy on his paper
road.
road. He
road. He traced
road. He traced the
road. He traced the paper
road. He traced the paper road.
road. He traced the paper road. And
road. He traced the paper road. And so
road. He traced the paper road. And so I
was
was in
road. He traced the paper road. And so I
was in this
was in this state
road. He traced the paper road. And so I
was in this state of
was in this state of bliss
road. He traced the paper road. And so I
was in this state of bliss and
was in this state of bliss and next
thing
thing I
thing I know
thing I know my
thing I know my father
thing I know my father is
thing I know my father is shaking
thing I know my father is shaking my
ankle.
ankle. Shaking
thing I know my father is shaking my
ankle. Shaking my
ankle. Shaking my ankle.
thing I know my father is shaking my
ankle. Shaking my ankle. Dave.
ankle. Shaking my ankle. Dave. Dave.
And
And I
And I could
And I could see
And I could see he
And I could see he would
And I could see he would have
And I could see he would have been
griefstricken
griefstricken if
And I could see he would have been
griefstricken if I
griefstricken if I had
And I could see he would have been
griefstricken if I had not
griefstricken if I had not breathed
again.
Uh
Uh and
again.
Uh and so
out
out of
out of love
out of love for
out of love for him
out of love for him I
out of love for him I breathe
and
and reowned
out of love for him I breathe
and reowned the
and reowned the body.
And
so
the
the only
the only alternative
to
to love
the only alternative
to love then
to love then was
the only alternative
to love then was uh
to love then was uh was
the only alternative
to love then was uh was another
to love then was uh was another form
the only alternative
to love then was uh was another form of
love
love personal
love personal love
love personal love and
love personal love and and
love personal love and and placing
placing
placing it
love personal love and and placing
placing it in
placing it in front
love personal love and and placing
placing it in front of
placing it in front of divine
love personal love and and placing
placing it in front of divine love.
placing it in front of divine love. All
right.
right. So
right. So it's
right. So it's beyond
right. So it's beyond cause
right. So it's beyond cause and
right. So it's beyond cause and effect.
It's
It's called
right. So it's beyond cause and effect.
It's called mystical
It's called mystical because
right. So it's beyond cause and effect.
It's called mystical because it's
It's called mystical because it's not
linear.
linear. a
linear. a very
linear. a very there's
linear. a very there's a
linear. a very there's a good
linear. a very there's a good um
varieties
varieties religious
linear. a very there's a good um
varieties religious experience
varieties religious experience which
linear. a very there's a good um
varieties religious experience which is
a
a very
a very famous
a very famous book
a very famous book uh
a very famous book uh has
a very famous book uh has a
a very famous book uh has a very
a very famous book uh has a very good
section
section on
a very famous book uh has a very good
section on mysticism
section on mysticism and
a very famous book uh has a very good
section on mysticism and uh
section on mysticism and uh it's
a very famous book uh has a very good
section on mysticism and uh it's is
section on mysticism and uh it's is very
well-known
well-known book
also
also the
well-known book
also the encyclopedia
also the encyclopedia bratannica
well-known book
also the encyclopedia bratannica has
also the encyclopedia bratannica has a
surprisingly
surprisingly good
surprisingly good section
surprisingly good section on
surprisingly good section on mysticism
surprisingly
surprisingly good
surprisingly good section on mysticism
surprisingly good Britannica
surprisingly good Britannica calibrates
very
very high
very high you
very high you know
very high you know because
very high you know because every
very high you know because every article
is
is written
very high you know because every article
is written by
is written by an
very high you know because every article
is written by an expert
is written by an expert in
very high you know because every article
is written by an expert in that
is written by an expert in that field
very high you know because every article
is written by an expert in that field so
The
The section
The section on
The section on mysticism
The section on mysticism is
The section on mysticism is quite
The section on mysticism is quite good.
Varieties
Varieties of
The section on mysticism is quite good.
Varieties of religious
Varieties of religious experience.
The section on mysticism is quite good.
Varieties of religious experience. I
forget
forget who
forget who William
forget who William James
is
is a
forget who William James
is a classic
is a classic and
forget who William James
is a classic and uh
is a classic and uh his
forget who William James
is a classic and uh his description
is a classic and uh his description is
also
also quite
also quite accurate
also quite accurate that
also quite accurate that the
also quite accurate that the state
arises
arises of
also quite accurate that the state
arises of its
arises of its own
also quite accurate that the state
arises of its own with
arises of its own with no
also quite accurate that the state
arises of its own with no cause
whatsoever.
All
All right.
whatsoever.
All right. Uh
it's
it's the
it's the state
it's the state is
it's the state is innate.
Um
I
I think
I think it
I think it comes
I think it comes about
I think it comes about it's
I think it comes about it's facilitated
by
by people
I think it comes about it's facilitated
by people who
by people who are
I think it comes about it's facilitated
by people who are very
by people who are very interested
I think it comes about it's facilitated
by people who are very interested in
truth
truth you
truth you see
truth you see because
truth you see because you
truth you see because you cannot
truth you see because you cannot really
divide
divide truth
truth you see because you cannot really
divide truth love
divide truth love and
truth you see because you cannot really
divide truth love and divinity
divide truth love and divinity uh
because
because they
because they are
because they are all
because they are all really
because they are all really much
because they are all really much the
same.
You
You can
You can get
You can get to
You can get to God
You can get to God through
You can get to God through any
You can get to God through any one
You can get to God through any one of
these
these pathways.
You can get to God through any one of
these pathways. If
these pathways. If you
You can get to God through any one of
these pathways. If you do
these pathways. If you do nothing
You can get to God through any one of
these pathways. If you do nothing but
worship
worship truth,
worship truth, you
worship truth, you will
worship truth, you will get
worship truth, you will get to
worship truth, you will get to God
because
because God
worship truth, you will get to God
because God and
because God and truth
worship truth, you will get to God
because God and truth are
because God and truth are one
worship truth, you will get to God
because God and truth are one and
because God and truth are one and the
same.
You
You can
same.
You can get
You can get there
same.
You can get there through
You can get there through devotion
same.
You can get there through devotion as
well
well and
well and one
well and one seems
well and one seems to
well and one seems to facilitate
well and one seems to facilitate the
other.
other. Devotion
well and one seems to facilitate the
other. Devotion seems
other. Devotion seems to
well and one seems to facilitate the
other. Devotion seems to facilitate
other. Devotion seems to facilitate uh
truth
truth and
truth and vice
truth and vice versa.
So
So enlightenment
truth and vice versa.
So enlightenment the
So enlightenment the enlightened
truth and vice versa.
So enlightenment the enlightened state
then
then is
then is statistically
statistically
statistically rare.
Uh
Uh for
Uh for what
Uh for what reason?
Uh for what reason? I
Uh for what reason? I don't
Uh for what reason? I don't know.
I
I don't
Uh for what reason? I don't know.
I don't know
I don't know why.
uh
uh because
uh because many
uh because many people
uh because many people are
uh because many people are quite
religious
religious and
uh because many people are quite
religious and yet
religious and yet religiosity
uh
uh is
uh is insufficient.
Uh
self-realization
self-realization can
self-realization can come
self-realization can come to
self-realization can come to the
self-realization can come to the highly
religious
religious and
self-realization can come to the highly
religious and so
religious and so there's
self-realization can come to the highly
religious and so there's a
religious and so there's a crossover.
There
There are
There are some
There are some people
There are some people who
There are some people who are
There are some people who are highly
religious
and
and they
and they just
and they just stay
and they just stay highly
and they just stay highly religious.
And
And then
and they just stay highly religious.
And then there
And then there are
and they just stay highly religious.
And then there are some
And then there are some people
and they just stay highly religious.
And then there are some people who
And then there are some people who are
highly
highly religious
highly religious and
highly religious and all
highly religious and all of
highly religious and all of a
highly religious and all of a sudden
what
what all
highly religious and all of a sudden
what all that
what all that means
highly religious and all of a sudden
what all that means sweeps
what all that means sweeps them
highly religious and all of a sudden
what all that means sweeps them away.
And
And they
And they pass
And they pass out
And they pass out with
And they pass out with joy
And they pass out with joy and
And they pass out with joy and ecstasy
and
and awe
And they pass out with joy and ecstasy
and awe because
and awe because what
And they pass out with joy and ecstasy
and awe because what they
and awe because what they have
And they pass out with joy and ecstasy
and awe because what they have just
studied
studied all
studied all these
studied all these years
studied all these years is
studied all these years is now
studied all these years is now an
experiential
experiential reality.
studied all these years is now an
experiential reality. And
experiential reality. And that's
studied all these years is now an
experiential reality. And that's the
lives
lives of
lives of many
lives of many of
lives of many of them
lives of many of them are
lives of many of them are very
well-known
well-known saints.
lives of many of them are very
well-known saints. So
well-known saints. So saintthood
lives of many of them are very
well-known saints. So saintthood arises
then
then when
then when that
then when that which
then when that which is
then when that which is intellectual
becomes
uh
uh the
uh the awareness
uh the awareness of
uh the awareness of that
uh the awareness of that which
uh the awareness of that which you
uh the awareness of that which you are
as
as lovingness.
So
So the
So the sage
So the sage or
So the sage or the
So the sage or the teacher
So the sage or the teacher then
So the sage or the teacher then is
So the sage or the teacher then is um
whether
whether to
So the sage or the teacher then is um
whether to stay
whether to stay in
So the sage or the teacher then is um
whether to stay in the
whether to stay in the world.
So the sage or the teacher then is um
whether to stay in the world. So
whether to stay in the world. So once
the
the person
the person becomes
the person becomes enlightened
the person becomes enlightened they
the person becomes enlightened they can
leave.
leave. Most
the person becomes enlightened they can
leave. Most leave.
leave. Most leave. Most
the person becomes enlightened they can
leave. Most leave. Most people,
leave. Most leave. Most people, most
devotees
devotees when
devotees when they
devotees when they get
devotees when they get to
devotees when they get to 600
devotees when they get to 600 leave.
Great
Great majority
devotees when they get to 600 leave.
Great majority leave.
Great majority leave. And
devotees when they get to 600 leave.
Great majority leave. And there's
Great majority leave. And there's hardly
any
any on
any on the
any on the planet
any on the planet ever
any on the planet ever really.
any on the planet ever really. There's
only
only probably
any on the planet ever really. There's
only probably three
only probably three right
any on the planet ever really. There's
only probably three right now.
only probably three right now. Calibrate
over
over 600.
over 600. But
over 600. But you
over 600. But you see,
over 600. But you see, because
over 600. But you see, because they're
of
of their
over 600. But you see, because they're
of their energy,
of their energy, they
over 600. But you see, because they're
of their energy, they counterbalance
everything
everything else.
everything else. Uh
everything else. Uh there's
everything else. Uh there's three
everything else. Uh there's three on
everything else. Uh there's three on the
planet.
planet. Somebody
everything else. Uh there's three on the
planet. Somebody asked
planet. Somebody asked us
everything else. Uh there's three on the
planet. Somebody asked us the
planet. Somebody asked us the other
everything else. Uh there's three on the
planet. Somebody asked us the other day.
Is
Is that
Is that so?
Is that so? Isn't
Is that so? Isn't that
Is that so? Isn't that so?
Is that so? Isn't that so? There's
Is that so? Isn't that so? There's three
on
on the
Is that so? Isn't that so? There's three
on the planet.
on the planet. It
Is that so? Isn't that so? There's three
on the planet. It was
on the planet. It was good.
Is that so? Isn't that so? There's three
on the planet. It was good. All right.
So
So there's
So there's only
So there's only a
So there's only a few
So there's only a few that
So there's only a few that leave.
So there's only a few that leave. So
most
most leave
So there's only a few that leave. So
most leave and
most leave and uh
So there's only a few that leave. So
most leave and uh I
most leave and uh I almost
So there's only a few that leave. So
most leave and uh I almost left
most leave and uh I almost left every
time
time that
time that kind
time that kind of
time that kind of a
time that kind of a state
time that kind of a state uh
time that kind of a state uh occurred
uh
because
because there's
because there's no
because there's no purpose
because there's no purpose to
because there's no purpose to continue
on
on uh
because there's no purpose to continue
on uh with
on uh with physicality.
because there's no purpose to continue
on uh with physicality. So
on uh with physicality. So the
because there's no purpose to continue
on uh with physicality. So the these
states
states are
states are witnessed.
states are witnessed. So
states are witnessed. So the
states are witnessed. So the reason
the
the mystic
states are witnessed. So the reason
the mystic doesn't
the mystic doesn't talk
states are witnessed. So the reason
the mystic doesn't talk about
the mystic doesn't talk about me
states are witnessed. So the reason
the mystic doesn't talk about me and
the mystic doesn't talk about me and you
and
and personal
and personal pronouns
and personal pronouns very
and personal pronouns very much
and personal pronouns very much is
because
because the
and personal pronouns very much is
because the only
because the only thing
and personal pronouns very much is
because the only thing left
because the only thing left of
and personal pronouns very much is
because the only thing left of the
person
person is
person is the
person is the witness
person is the witness that
person is the witness that which
person is the witness that which was
person is the witness that which was the
person
person persist
person is the witness that which was the
person persist now
person persist now is
person is the witness that which was the
person persist now is the
person persist now is the witness
observer.
Uh
Uh but
observer.
Uh but there
Uh but there isn't
observer.
Uh but there isn't any
Uh but there isn't any eye
observer.
Uh but there isn't any eye that's
experiencing
experiencing it.
experiencing it. Yeah.
experiencing it. Yeah. the
experiencing it. Yeah. the witnessing
until
until the
experiencing it. Yeah. the witnessing
until the end.
until the end. This
experiencing it. Yeah. the witnessing
until the end. This becomes
until the end. This becomes now
experiencing it. Yeah. the witnessing
until the end. This becomes now another
problem
problem you
problem you have
problem you have is
problem you have is the
problem you have is the loss
problem you have is the loss of
problem you have is the loss of desire
and
and wantingness.
problem you have is the loss of desire
and wantingness. So
and wantingness. So we'll
problem you have is the loss of desire
and wantingness. So we'll go
and wantingness. So we'll go to
problem you have is the loss of desire
and wantingness. So we'll go to the
and wantingness. So we'll go to the next
uh
uh next
uh next uh
uh next uh slide.
uh next uh slide. Uh
now
now this
uh next uh slide. Uh
now this was
now this was all
uh next uh slide. Uh
now this was all review
now this was all review before
uh next uh slide. Uh
now this was all review before we
now this was all review before we get
uh next uh slide. Uh
now this was all review before we get to
the
the mystic
the mystic slides
the mystic slides full
the mystic slides full enlightenment.
the mystic slides full enlightenment. Uh
so
um
the
the re
um
the re the
the re the realization
um
the re the realization that
consciousness
consciousness and
consciousness and the
consciousness and the source
consciousness and the source of
consciousness and the source of life
consciousness and the source of life and
infinite
infinite oneness
consciousness and the source of life and
infinite oneness and
infinite oneness and divinity
consciousness and the source of life and
infinite oneness and divinity are
infinite oneness and divinity are all
the
the same.
the same. The
the same. The infinite
the same. The infinite oneness
the same. The infinite oneness is
the same. The infinite oneness is really
consciousness
consciousness itself.
Timeless
um
consciousness
consciousness in
consciousness in and
consciousness in and of
consciousness in and of itself
consciousness in and of itself is
consciousness in and of itself is the
omniscience
omniscience of
consciousness in and of itself is the
omniscience of God.
omniscience of God. God
consciousness in and of itself is the
omniscience of God. God is
omniscience of God. God is omnisient,
omnipotent,
omnipresent.
Consciousness
Consciousness as
Consciousness as omniscience
Consciousness as omniscience is
Consciousness as omniscience is all
knowing.
knowing. If
Consciousness as omniscience is all
knowing. If it's
knowing. If it's all
Consciousness as omniscience is all
knowing. If it's all knowing,
knowing. If it's all knowing, then
Consciousness as omniscience is all
knowing. If it's all knowing, then I
should
should be
should be able
should be able to
should be able to ask
should be able to ask any
should be able to ask any question
should be able to ask any question about
anything
anything anywhere
should be able to ask any question about
anything anywhere in
anything anywhere in time
should be able to ask any question about
anything anywhere in time and
anything anywhere in time and get
should be able to ask any question about
anything anywhere in time and get an
answer.
But
But that's
answer.
But that's been
But that's been our
answer.
But that's been our experience
But that's been our experience thousands
and
and thousands
and thousands of
and thousands of times
and thousands of times per
and thousands of times per year.
Anything
Anything can
and thousands of times per year.
Anything can be
Anything can be asked
and thousands of times per year.
Anything can be asked about
Anything can be asked about anything.
Occasionally
Occasionally you'll
Occasionally you'll get
Occasionally you'll get a
Occasionally you'll get a no
Occasionally you'll get a no to
Occasionally you'll get a no to not
Occasionally you'll get a no to not ask
it
it and
Occasionally you'll get a no to not ask
it and that's
it and that's a
Occasionally you'll get a no to not ask
it and that's a different
it and that's a different problem.
Conscious
Conscious consciousness
Conscious consciousness is
Conscious consciousness is then
Conscious consciousness is then the
source
source of
Conscious consciousness is then the
source of life.
source of life. And
Conscious consciousness is then the
source of life. And as
source of life. And as we've
Conscious consciousness is then the
source of life. And as we've said
before,
omnipotence
omnipotence is
before,
omnipotence is represented
omnipotence is represented in
before,
omnipotence is represented in the
omnipotence is represented in the linear
domain
domain by
domain by the
domain by the realization
domain by the realization that
domain by the realization that one
domain by the realization that one cubic
centimeter
centimeter of
domain by the realization that one cubic
centimeter of infinite
centimeter of infinite space
domain by the realization that one cubic
centimeter of infinite space has
centimeter of infinite space has more
the
the power
the power in
the power in one
the power in one cubic
the power in one cubic centimeter
the power in one cubic centimeter of
space
is
is greater
is greater than
is greater than its
is greater than its equivalent
is greater than its equivalent as
is greater than its equivalent as the
total
total mass
is greater than its equivalent as the
total mass of
total mass of the
is greater than its equivalent as the
total mass of the universe.
That's
That's what
That's what you
That's what you call
one
one tiny
That's what you call
one tiny bit
one tiny bit of
That's what you call
one tiny bit of space.
one tiny bit of space. Its
That's what you call
one tiny bit of space. Its equivalent
one tiny bit of space. Its equivalent in
matter
is
is greater
matter
is greater than
is greater than the
matter
is greater than the total
is greater than the total mass
matter
is greater than the total mass of
is greater than the total mass of the
entire
entire universe
which
which is
entire universe
which is really
which is really a
entire universe
which is really a way
which is really a way of
entire universe
which is really a way of just
which is really a way of just saying
it's
it's infinite.
it's infinite. It's
it's infinite. It's really
it's infinite. It's really just
it's infinite. It's really just saying
that
that it's
it's infinite. It's really just saying
that it's infinite.
that it's infinite. Yes.
So
So divinity
So divinity therefore
So divinity therefore is
So divinity therefore is innate
So divinity therefore is innate to
So divinity therefore is innate to all
existence.
Everything
Everything fueled
Everything fueled by
Everything fueled by which
consciousness
consciousness is
Everything fueled by which
consciousness is then
consciousness is then the
Everything fueled by which
consciousness is then the source
consciousness is then the source of
Everything fueled by which
consciousness is then the source of life
and
and we
and we we
and we we we
and we we we come
and we we we come back
and we we we come back again
and we we we come back again to
and we we we come back again to the
rediscovery
that
that it
that it is
that it is impossible
that it is impossible to
that it is impossible to destroy
that it is impossible to destroy life.
Life
Life is
that it is impossible to destroy life.
Life is indestructible.
Life is indestructible. So
that it is impossible to destroy life.
Life is indestructible. So the
Life is indestructible. So the law
that it is impossible to destroy life.
Life is indestructible. So the law of
the
the preservation
the preservation of
the preservation of energy
the preservation of energy and
the preservation of energy and of
matter.
matter. And
the preservation of energy and of
matter. And the
matter. And the third
the preservation of energy and of
matter. And the third great
matter. And the third great one
the preservation of energy and of
matter. And the third great one which
man
man has
man has not
man has not paid
man has not paid attention
man has not paid attention to
the
the immunity
man has not paid attention to
the immunity of
the immunity of life.
man has not paid attention to
the immunity of life. Uhhuh.
the immunity of life. Uhhuh. So
man has not paid attention to
the immunity of life. Uhhuh. So life
cannot
cannot be
cannot be destroyed.
cannot be destroyed. Let's
cannot be destroyed. Let's see.
cannot be destroyed. Let's see. Let's
see
see if
cannot be destroyed. Let's see. Let's
see if that
see if that we
cannot be destroyed. Let's see. Let's
see if that we have
see if that we have permission
cannot be destroyed. Let's see. Let's
see if that we have permission to
see if that we have permission to ask
that.
that. Life
that. Life cannot
that. Life cannot be
that. Life cannot be destroyed
that. Life cannot be destroyed like
matter,
matter, like
that. Life cannot be destroyed like
matter, like energy.
matter, like energy. It
that. Life cannot be destroyed like
matter, like energy. It can
matter, like energy. It can only
that. Life cannot be destroyed like
matter, like energy. It can only change
form.
form. Life
form. Life can
form. Life can only
form. Life can only change
form. Life can only change form.
So
So much
form. Life can only change form.
So much for
So much for being
form. Life can only change form.
So much for being afraid
So much for being afraid of
form. Life can only change form.
So much for being afraid of death
So much for being afraid of death then
because
because you
because you can't
because you can't die,
because you can't die, idiot.
Dumb
Dumb dumb.
You're
You're not
You're not going
You're not going to
You're not going to die.
You're not going to die. You
You're not going to die. You can
You're not going to die. You can just
suddenly
suddenly you're
You're not going to die. You can just
suddenly you're looking
suddenly you're looking at
You're not going to die. You can just
suddenly you're looking at the
suddenly you're looking at the body
You're not going to die. You can just
suddenly you're looking at the body and
that
that stupid
that stupid thing's
that stupid thing's lying
that stupid thing's lying there
that stupid thing's lying there and
that stupid thing's lying there and you
got
got your
that stupid thing's lying there and you
got your chance
got your chance to
that stupid thing's lying there and you
got your chance to go
got your chance to go on
that stupid thing's lying there and you
got your chance to go on further
got your chance to go on further and
angels
angels are
angels are around
angels are around telling
angels are around telling you
angels are around telling you what
angels are around telling you what to
angels are around telling you what to do
anyway.
Come
Come with
Come with us.
The
The energy
Come with us.
The energy of
The energy of life
Come with us.
The energy of life is
The energy of life is not
Come with us.
The energy of life is not subject
The energy of life is not subject to
destruction
destruction because
destruction because it's
destruction because it's not
destruction because it's not different
than
than divinity
destruction because it's not different
than divinity itself.
than divinity itself. Consciousness
destruction because it's not different
than divinity itself. Consciousness is
not
not is
not is nothing
not is nothing but
not is nothing but an
not is nothing but an aspect
not is nothing but an aspect of
divinity.
divinity. So
not is nothing but an aspect of
divinity. So how
divinity. So how could
not is nothing but an aspect of
divinity. So how could it
divinity. So how could it be
not is nothing but an aspect of
divinity. So how could it be destroyed?
God
God would
God would be
God would be destroying
God would be destroying himself.
So
that's
that's enough
that's enough of
that's enough of this.
that's enough of this. We'll
that's enough of this. We'll go
that's enough of this. We'll go to
that's enough of this. We'll go to the
next
next chart.
We
We have
We have to
We have to get
We have to get to
We have to get to the
We
We didn't
We have to get to the
We didn't even
We didn't even get
We have to get to the
We didn't even get get
We didn't even get get there
We have to get to the
We didn't even get get there yet.
Oh,
Oh, all
Oh, all right.
The
The inner
Oh, all right.
The inner state
The inner state of
Oh, all right.
The inner state of the
The inner state of the mystic
Oh, all right.
The inner state of the mystic then
The inner state of the mystic then it
cannot
cannot be
cannot be described.
cannot be described. It's
transformative.
It's
It's like
It's like a
It's like a light
It's like a light has
It's like a light has gone
It's like a light has gone on
It's like a light has gone on that
illuminates
illuminates all
It's like a light has gone on that
illuminates all of
illuminates all of existence.
And
And you
And you learn
And you learn how
And you learn how to
And you learn how to live
And you learn how to live with
And you learn how to live with it
And you learn how to live with it in
And you learn how to live with it in a
semi-normal
semi-normal fashion
with
with concentration.
with concentration. You
with concentration. You can
with concentration. You can fool
with concentration. You can fool most
with concentration. You can fool most of
the
the people
with concentration. You can fool most of
the people most
the people most of
with concentration. You can fool most of
the people most of the
the people most of the time.
You
You look
You look at
You look at them
You look at them respectfully.
You look at them respectfully. You
You look at them respectfully. You say,
"Oh,
"Oh, yes.
You look at them respectfully. You say,
"Oh, yes. Uhhuh.
"Oh, yes. Uhhuh. That's
You look at them respectfully. You say,
"Oh, yes. Uhhuh. That's right."
"Oh, yes. Uhhuh. That's right." Uhhuh.
Yeah.
All right.
All right. We'll
Yeah.
All right. We'll move
All right. We'll move to
Yeah.
All right. We'll move to the
All right. We'll move to the next
Yeah.
All right. We'll move to the next slide.
Okay.
Okay. Now,
Okay. Now, we're
Okay. Now, we're finally
Okay. Now, we're finally get
Okay. Now, we're finally get to
Okay. Now, we're finally get to today's
lecture.
lecture. All
Okay. Now, we're finally get to today's
lecture. All the
lecture. All the rest
Okay. Now, we're finally get to today's
lecture. All the rest was
review
review and
review and all.
review and all. How
review and all. How much
review and all. How much time
review and all. How much time we
review and all. How much time we got
review and all. How much time we got for
a
a break?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, good.
>> Oh, good. That's
>> Oh, good. That's all
>> Oh, good. That's all we
>> Oh, good. That's all we need.
>> Oh, good. That's all we need. We
>> Oh, good. That's all we need. We can
complete
complete all
>> Oh, good. That's all we need. We can
complete all of
complete all of time
>> Oh, good. That's all we need. We can
complete all of time in
complete all of time in the
>> Oh, good. That's all we need. We can
complete all of time in the universe
complete all of time in the universe and
human
human destiny
human destiny and
human destiny and God
human destiny and God and
human destiny and God and infinity
human destiny and God and infinity in
human destiny and God and infinity in 20
minutes.
minutes. No
human destiny and God and infinity in 20
minutes. No problem.
So
So in
So in contra
So in contra distinction
So in contra distinction to
So in contra distinction to uh
So in contra distinction to uh the
intellectual
intellectual approach
So in contra distinction to uh the
intellectual approach to
spiritual
spiritual religious
spiritual religious education
uh
uh the
spiritual religious education
uh the mysticism
uh the mysticism is
spiritual religious education
uh the mysticism is the
uh the mysticism is the inner
spiritual religious education
uh the mysticism is the inner path.
It
It it
It it arises
It it arises from
It it arises from within.
In
In this
It it arises from within.
In this experience
In this experience of
It it arises from within.
In this experience of this
In this experience of this entity
It it arises from within.
In this experience of this entity here
it
it was
it was never
it was never preceded
it was never preceded by
it was never preceded by any
it was never preceded by any warning.
it was never preceded by any warning. It
just
just came
it was never preceded by any warning. It
just came on
just came on out
it was never preceded by any warning. It
just came on out of
just came on out of the
it was never preceded by any warning. It
just came on out of the blue
just came on out of the blue each
it was never preceded by any warning. It
just came on out of the blue each time.
Overwhelming,
Overwhelming, profound,
Overwhelming, profound, everlasting,
eternal,
eternal, and
Overwhelming, profound, everlasting,
eternal, and transformative
eternal, and transformative with
Overwhelming, profound, everlasting,
eternal, and transformative with no
advanced
advanced warning.
advanced warning. No
advanced warning. No advanced
advanced warning. No advanced warning.
Nobody
Nobody said
advanced warning. No advanced warning.
Nobody said open
Nobody said open the
advanced warning. No advanced warning.
Nobody said open the windows
Nobody said open the windows and
advanced warning. No advanced warning.
Nobody said open the windows and turn
Nobody said open the windows and turn on
the
the air
the air conditioner.
the air conditioner. It
the air conditioner. It just
the air conditioner. It just took
the air conditioner. It just took over.
So,
So, mysticism
the air conditioner. It just took over.
So, mysticism is
So, mysticism is called
the air conditioner. It just took over.
So, mysticism is called the
So, mysticism is called the inner
the air conditioner. It just took over.
So, mysticism is called the inner path.
Now,
Now, the
Now, the ecclesiastic
Now, the ecclesiastic approach,
Now, the ecclesiastic approach, the
classic
classic uh
Now, the ecclesiastic approach, the
classic uh Religious
classic uh Religious education
is
is not
is not can
is not can set
is not can set the
is not can set the the
is not can set the the the
is not can set the the the state
is not can set the the the state for
is not can set the the the state for it
but
but it
is not can set the the the state for it
but it does
but it does not
is not can set the the the state for it
but it does not cause
but it does not cause it.
is not can set the the the state for it
but it does not cause it. You
but it does not cause it. You can
is not can set the the the state for it
but it does not cause it. You can study
theology
theology day
theology day in
theology day in and
theology day in and day
theology day in and day out
theology day in and day out and
theology day in and day out and that
will
will not
theology day in and day out and that
will not necessarily
will not necessarily precipitate
theology day in and day out and that
will not necessarily precipitate it.
However,
However, an
However, an interest
However, an interest in
However, an interest in religion
However, an interest in religion and
then
then you
However, an interest in religion and
then you add
then you add to
However, an interest in religion and
then you add to it
then you add to it a
However, an interest in religion and
then you add to it a certain
then you add to it a certain motivation
and
and now
and now that
and now that becomes
and now that becomes activated
and now that becomes activated and
and now that becomes activated and the
great
great saints
and now that becomes activated and the
great saints of
great saints of Christianity
uh
uh represent
uh represent that
uh represent that in
uh represent that in which
uh
uh the
uh represent that in which
uh the study
uh the study and
uh represent that in which
uh the study and the
uh the study and the worship
uh represent that in which
uh the study and the worship and
uh the study and the worship and the
devotion
devotion to
uh
uh religion
devotion to
uh religion then
uh religion then ends
devotion to
uh religion then ends up
uh religion then ends up as
devotion to
uh religion then ends up as a
uh religion then ends up as a mystical
inner
inner awareness.
inner awareness. Suddenly
inner awareness. Suddenly the
inner awareness. Suddenly the words
become
become the
inner awareness. Suddenly the words
become the inner
become the inner truth,
inner awareness. Suddenly the words
become the inner truth, experiential
truth.
It's
It's called
truth.
It's called the
It's called the inner
truth.
It's called the inner path.
It's
It's characterized
It's characterized by
It's characterized by union
It's characterized by union with
It's characterized by union with the
divine.
divine. And
It's characterized by union with the
divine. And therefore,
divine. And therefore, union
It's characterized by union with the
divine. And therefore, union with
divine. And therefore, union with the
divine
divine in
divine in Christianity,
divine in Christianity, it's
divine in Christianity, it's called
unionomstica,
uniono,
uniono, the
uniono, the mystical
uniono, the mystical union
of
of self
uniono, the mystical union
of self and
of self and divinity.
uniono, the mystical union
of self and divinity. It
of self and divinity. It comes
uniono, the mystical union
of self and divinity. It comes about
through
through uh
through uh infinite
through uh infinite love
through uh infinite love actually
through uh infinite love actually most
likely
likely most
through uh infinite love actually most
likely most easily
union
union with
union with the
union with the divine.
union with the divine. It's
union with the divine. It's called
a
a special
union with the divine. It's called
a special name.
a special name. Yeah.
union with the divine. It's called
a special name. Yeah. It
a special name. Yeah. It is
union with the divine. It's called
a special name. Yeah. It is actually
a special name. Yeah. It is actually a
very
very god
very god imminent
very god imminent is
very god imminent is a
very god imminent is a radical
subjectivity.
subjectivity. It's
very god imminent is a radical
subjectivity. It's a
subjectivity. It's a radical
subjectivity.
The
The source
subjectivity.
The source of
the
the essence
the essence of
the essence of one
the essence of one awareness
then
then becomes
illuminated
illuminated as
illuminated as div
illuminated as div as
illuminated as div as divinity.
So
So illumination
illuminated as div as divinity.
So illumination is
So illumination is very
illuminated as div as divinity.
So illumination is very very
characteristic.
You
You can
characteristic.
You can read
You can read a
characteristic.
You can read a thing
You can read a thing many
characteristic.
You can read a thing many many
You can read a thing many many times
characteristic.
You can read a thing many many times and
one
one day
one day you're
one day you're walking
one day you're walking through
one day you're walking through the
one day you're walking through the woods
and
and all
one day you're walking through the woods
and all of a
and all of a sudden
the
the profoundity
the profoundity of
the profoundity of the
the profoundity of the full
the profoundity of the full meaning
shines
shines forth
the profoundity of the full meaning
shines forth of
shines forth of its
the profoundity of the full meaning
shines forth of its own.
Nothing
Nothing is
Nothing is ever
Nothing is ever the
Nothing is ever the same
Nothing is ever the same again.
Nothing is ever the same again. It
shines
shines forth
Nothing is ever the same again. It
shines forth of
shines forth of its
Nothing is ever the same again. It
shines forth of its own.
shines forth of its own. Not
Nothing is ever the same again. It
shines forth of its own. Not as
shines forth of its own. Not as a
Nothing is ever the same again. It
shines forth of its own. Not as a result
of
of causality.
Yeah.
So
So it's
So it's a
So it's a radical
So it's a radical subjectivity.
It
It may
So it's a radical subjectivity.
It may reveal
It may reveal itself
So it's a radical subjectivity.
It may reveal itself as
It may reveal itself as agape
So it's a radical subjectivity.
It may reveal itself as agape which
It may reveal itself as agape which is
the
the lovingness
the lovingness for
the lovingness for all
the lovingness for all existence.
the lovingness for all existence. Uh
it's
it's called
the lovingness for all existence. Uh
it's called bliss
it's called bliss also.
the lovingness for all existence. Uh
it's called bliss also. So
it's called bliss also. So the
the lovingness for all existence. Uh
it's called bliss also. So the real
state
state of
state of agape
state of agape it
state of agape it really
state of agape it really calibrates
around
around 600.
state of agape it really calibrates
around 600. Before
around 600. Before you
state of agape it really calibrates
around 600. Before you get
around 600. Before you get to
state of agape it really calibrates
around 600. Before you get to that
however
however you
however you have
however you have unconditional
however you have unconditional love.
Unconditional
Unconditional love
however you have unconditional love.
Unconditional love then
Unconditional love then is
however you have unconditional love.
Unconditional love then is a
Unconditional love then is a very
profound
profound state.
profound state. One
profound state. One for
profound state. One for which
profound state. One for which we
profound state. One for which we should
be
be very
profound state. One for which we should
be very thankful.
be very thankful. Those
profound state. One for which we should
be very thankful. Those of
be very thankful. Those of us
profound state. One for which we should
be very thankful. Those of us who
experience
experience a
experience a lovingness
experience a lovingness for
experience a lovingness for all
experience a lovingness for all it,
experience a lovingness for all it, you
know,
know, it
experience a lovingness for all it, you
know, it shows
know, it shows itself
experience a lovingness for all it, you
know, it shows itself as
know, it shows itself as a
experience a lovingness for all it, you
know, it shows itself as a lovingness
for
for nature,
a
a sensitivity
for nature,
a sensitivity to
a sensitivity to the
for nature,
a sensitivity to the beauty
a sensitivity to the beauty of
everything
everything that
everything that exists.
everything that exists. Uh
everything that exists. Uh a
everything that exists. Uh a lovingness
for
for the
everything that exists. Uh a lovingness
for the animal
for the animal kingdom.
You
You can
You can love
You can love one
You can love one animal
You can love one animal easily
You can love one animal easily as
You can love one animal easily as well
as
as another.
You can love one animal easily as well
as another. And
as another. And uh
so
so there's
so there's a
so there's a lovingness
so there's a lovingness for
so there's a lovingness for all
so there's a lovingness for all of
so there's a lovingness for all of life
and
and all
so there's a lovingness for all of life
and all of
and all of its
so there's a lovingness for all of life
and all of its expressions.
Uh
Uh uh
uh
uh bliss
Uh uh
uh bliss ecstasy
you
you transcend
you transcend the
you transcend the personal
you transcend the personal eye
you transcend the personal eye and
you transcend the personal eye and you
transcend
transcend the
you transcend the personal eye and you
transcend the idea
transcend the idea that
you transcend the personal eye and you
transcend the idea that there's
transcend the idea that there's really
separate
separate others.
The
The word
separate others.
The word the
The word the personal
separate others.
The word the personal eye
The word the personal eye as
separate others.
The word the personal eye as a
The word the personal eye as a pronoun
doesn't
doesn't keep
doesn't keep interfering
doesn't keep interfering all
doesn't keep interfering all the
doesn't keep interfering all the time.
Why?
Why? Because
doesn't keep interfering all the time.
Why? Because you're
Why? Because you're you
doesn't keep interfering all the time.
Why? Because you're you are
Why? Because you're you are now
doesn't keep interfering all the time.
Why? Because you're you are now the
witness.
That
That which
witness.
That which is
That which is the
witness.
That which is the witness
That which is the witness and
witness.
That which is the witness and the
observer
observer is
observer is about
observer is about as
observer is about as close
observer is about as close as
observer is about as close as you
observer is about as close as you can
get
get to
the
the reality
the reality of
the reality of the
the reality of the inner
the reality of the inner life
the reality of the inner life of
the reality of the inner life of the
mystic
mystic uh
the reality of the inner life of the
mystic uh and
mystic uh and and
the reality of the inner life of the
mystic uh and and getting
mystic uh and and getting along
the reality of the inner life of the
mystic uh and and getting along in
mystic uh and and getting along in the
world
world as
world as the
world as the observer
world as the observer witness.
world as the observer witness. Then
world as the observer witness. Then one
can
can participate
world as the observer witness. Then one
can participate without
can participate without actually
world as the observer witness. Then one
can participate without actually being
involved
involved without
involved without actually
involved without actually being
involved.
You're
You're involved
You're involved operationally
You're involved operationally but
there's
there's no
You're involved operationally but
there's no cost
there's no cost involved.
The
The way
The way it
The way it works
The way it works is
The way it works is if
The way it works is if you
The way it works is if you win,
The way it works is if you win, you
The way it works is if you win, you win
and
and that's
The way it works is if you win, you win
and that's great.
and that's great. And
The way it works is if you win, you win
and that's great. And if
and that's great. And if you
The way it works is if you win, you win
and that's great. And if you don't
and that's great. And if you don't win,
that's
that's great.
So
So people
that's great.
So people get
So people get very
that's great.
So people get very passionate
So people get very passionate about
winning
winning here
winning here and
winning here and winning
winning here and winning there
winning here and winning there and
winning
winning there.
winning here and winning there and
winning there. And
winning there. And all
winning here and winning there and
winning there. And all you
winning there. And all you can
winning here and winning there and
winning there. And all you can do
winning there. And all you can do is
winning here and winning there and
winning there. And all you can do is go
along
along with
along with it
along with it and
along with it and say,
along with it and say, I
along with it and say, I appreciate
their
their enthusiasm.
along with it and say, I appreciate
their enthusiasm. So
their enthusiasm. So I
along with it and say, I appreciate
their enthusiasm. So I joined
their enthusiasm. So I joined it
along with it and say, I appreciate
their enthusiasm. So I joined it because
of
of the
of the enthusiasm.
It's
It's not
of the enthusiasm.
It's not going
It's not going to
of the enthusiasm.
It's not going to change
It's not going to change anything
of the enthusiasm.
It's not going to change anything one
way.
way. I've
way. I've been
way. I've been rich.
way. I've been rich. I've
way. I've been rich. I've been
way. I've been rich. I've been poor.
I've
I've lived
way. I've been rich. I've been poor.
I've lived in
I've lived in the
way. I've been rich. I've been poor.
I've lived in the country.
I've lived in the country. I've
way. I've been rich. I've been poor.
I've lived in the country. I've lived
I've lived in the country. I've lived in
the
the city.
the city. None
the city. None of
the city. None of it
the city. None of it profounded
the city. None of it profounded the
interstate
interstate of
the city. None of it profounded the
interstate of none
interstate of none of
the city. None of it profounded the
interstate of none of it
interstate of none of it affected
the city. None of it profounded the
interstate of none of it affected the
interstate
interstate of
interstate of happiness.
interstate of happiness. Whether
interstate of happiness. Whether you've
got
got a
interstate of happiness. Whether you've
got a place
got a place out
interstate of happiness. Whether you've
got a place out in
got a place out in the
interstate of happiness. Whether you've
got a place out in the sticks
got a place out in the sticks here
interstate of happiness. Whether you've
got a place out in the sticks here in
the
the middle
the middle Arizona
the middle Arizona or
the middle Arizona or you've
the middle Arizona or you've got
the middle Arizona or you've got an
estate
uh
uh in
uh in the
uh in the upper
uh in the upper class
uh in the upper class sections
uh in the upper class sections and
uh in the upper class sections and a
apartment
apartment on
uh in the upper class sections and a
apartment on Fifth
apartment on Fifth Avenue,
uh in the upper class sections and a
apartment on Fifth Avenue, it's
apartment on Fifth Avenue, it's all
uh in the upper class sections and a
apartment on Fifth Avenue, it's all the
same
same because
same because that
same because that capacity
same because that capacity for
same because that capacity for happiness
lies
lies within
same because that capacity for happiness
lies within you.
When
When you're
When you're happy,
When you're happy, no
When you're happy, no matter
When you're happy, no matter what's
When you're happy, no matter what's for
dinner,
dinner, it
When you're happy, no matter what's for
dinner, it tastes
dinner, it tastes great.
ain't
ain't so
because
because happiness
ain't so
because happiness and
because happiness and love
ain't so
because happiness and love transforms
everything
everything into
everything into a
everything into a positive
everything into a positive experience.
All
All right.
everything into a positive experience.
All right. So
All right. So you
everything into a positive experience.
All right. So you don't
All right. So you don't have
everything into a positive experience.
All right. So you don't have anything
riding
riding on
riding on outcomes.
The
The the
riding on outcomes.
The the classic
The the classic way
riding on outcomes.
The the classic way through
The the classic way through this
riding on outcomes.
The the classic way through this is
The the classic way through this is the
pgation
pgation of
pgation of of
pgation of of desires.
pgation of of desires. It's
pgation of of desires. It's really
it's
it's really
pgation of of desires. It's really
it's really the
it's really the purification
pgation of of desires. It's really
it's really the purification of
it's really the purification of the
pgation of of desires. It's really
it's really the purification of the will
by
by letting
by letting go
by letting go attractions
by letting go attractions and
by letting go attractions and aversions.
letting
letting go
by letting go attractions and aversions.
letting go of
letting go of attractions
by letting go attractions and aversions.
letting go of attractions and
letting go of attractions and aversions.
And
And the
And the key
And the key to
And the key to letting
And the key to letting go
And the key to letting go of
And the key to letting go of attractions
is
is the
And the key to letting go of attractions
is the understanding
is the understanding that
And the key to letting go of attractions
is the understanding that all
attractions
attractions are
attractions are a
attractions are a projection
attractions are a projection of
attractions are a projection of that
energy
energy field
attractions are a projection of that
energy field that
energy field that was
attractions are a projection of that
energy field that was called
energy field that was called glamour.
One
One of
One of the
One of the best
One of the best most
One of the best most helpful
One of the best most helpful books
One of the best most helpful books ever
written
written that
One of the best most helpful books ever
written that you
written that you imbue
One of the best most helpful books ever
written that you imbue it
written that you imbue it you
One of the best most helpful books ever
written that you imbue it you imbue
written that you imbue it you imbue it
with
with that
with that attraction.
with that attraction. You
with that attraction. You think
with that attraction. You think the
attraction
attraction exists
with that attraction. You think the
attraction exists within
attraction exists within it.
You
You think
You think the
You think the attraction
You think the attraction is
You think the attraction is in
You think the attraction is in the
cheeseburger?
No.
No. It's
No. It's that
No. It's that you
No. It's that you think
No. It's that you think a
No. It's that you think a cheeseburger
is
is a
No. It's that you think a cheeseburger
is a wonderful
is a wonderful thing.
For
For a
For a person
For a person who
For a person who doesn't
For a person who doesn't like
cheeseburgers,
cheeseburgers, they're
For a person who doesn't like
cheeseburgers, they're not
cheeseburgers, they're not attractive,
right?
right? They
right? They hate
right? They hate them.
It's
It's meat.
right? They hate them.
It's meat. Meat
It's meat. Meat will
right? They hate them.
It's meat. Meat will kill
It's meat. Meat will kill you.
right? They hate them.
It's meat. Meat will kill you. Meat
causes
causes gas
causes gas on
causes gas on the
causes gas on the planes.
That's
That's one
causes gas on the planes.
That's one of
That's one of the
causes gas on the planes.
That's one of the funniest
That's one of the funniest things
causes gas on the planes.
That's one of the funniest things I
That's one of the funniest things I ever
heard.
We'll
We'll all
heard.
We'll all become
We'll all become vegetarian
heard.
We'll all become vegetarian and
We'll all become vegetarian and save
heard.
We'll all become vegetarian and save all
that
that methane
that methane on
that methane on the
that methane on the planes
that methane on the planes and
that methane on the planes and then
that methane on the planes and then the
earth
earth will
that methane on the planes and then the
earth will cool
earth will cool down.
that methane on the planes and then the
earth will cool down. Oh
earth will cool down. Oh my
that methane on the planes and then the
earth will cool down. Oh my god,
that
that is
that is the
that is the that's
that is the that's wonderful.
All right,
All right, the
that is the that's wonderful.
All right, the pgation
All right, the pgation of
that is the that's wonderful.
All right, the pgation of bodily
desires.
desires. The
desires. The Buddhist
desires. The Buddhist said
desires. The Buddhist said you're
attached
attached via
desires. The Buddhist said you're
attached via your
attached via your senses.
desires. The Buddhist said you're
attached via your senses. So
attached via your senses. So the
desires. The Buddhist said you're
attached via your senses. So the first
project
project that
project that he
project that he outlined
project that he outlined was
project that he outlined was not
project that he outlined was not to
project that he outlined was not to you
can't
can't disconnect
project that he outlined was not to you
can't disconnect from
can't disconnect from the
project that he outlined was not to you
can't disconnect from the senses
can't disconnect from the senses but
project that he outlined was not to you
can't disconnect from the senses but you
can
can stop
can stop being
can stop being ruled
can stop being ruled by
can stop being ruled by them.
can stop being ruled by them. You
can stop being ruled by them. You can
decide
decide against
can stop being ruled by them. You can
decide against them.
decide against them. you
can stop being ruled by them. You can
decide against them. you regain
decide against them. you regain your
freedom.
Things
Things are
freedom.
Things are done
Things are done through
freedom.
Things are done through purification
Things are done through purification of
the
the will
the will and
the will and all
the will and all this
the will and all this comes
the will and all this comes about
the will and all this comes about as
the will and all this comes about as a
result
result of
the will and all this comes about as a
result of the
result of the illumination
the will and all this comes about as a
result of the illumination of
result of the illumination of the
the will and all this comes about as a
result of the illumination of the mind.
Unification
Unification with
Unification with the
Unification with the with
Unification with the with the
Unification with the with the divine
which
which we
Unification with the with the divine
which we said
which we said is
Unification with the with the divine
which we said is called
which we said is called uniommystica.
What
What is
What is called
What is called enlightenment
What is called enlightenment in
What is called enlightenment in Hindu
What is called enlightenment in Hindu or
Buddhism
uh
uh etc.
uh etc. in
uh etc. in Christian
uh etc. in Christian theology
uh etc. in Christian theology is
uh etc. in Christian theology is called
unionom
unionom mystica.
uh etc. in Christian theology is called
unionom mystica. the
unionom mystica. the union
uh etc. in Christian theology is called
unionom mystica. the union of
unionom mystica. the union of with
uh etc. in Christian theology is called
unionom mystica. the union of with the
divine.
And
And at
divine.
And at that
And at that point,
divine.
And at that point, the
And at that point, the self
divine.
And at that point, the self with
And at that point, the self with a
divine.
And at that point, the self with a small
S
S dissolves
S dissolves into
S dissolves into the
S dissolves into the self
S dissolves into the self with
S dissolves into the self with a
S dissolves into the self with a large
S.
S. And
S dissolves into the self with a large
S. And every
S. And every time
S dissolves into the self with a large
S. And every time it's
S. And every time it's happened,
it's
it's been
it's been the
it's been the same.
it's been the same. There
it's been the same. There is
it's been the same. There is no
it's been the same. There is no personal
pronoun.
pronoun. In
it's been the same. There is no personal
pronoun. In fact,
pronoun. In fact, one
it's been the same. There is no personal
pronoun. In fact, one has
pronoun. In fact, one has to
it's been the same. There is no personal
pronoun. In fact, one has to learn
pronoun. In fact, one has to learn how
to
um
um imagine
to
um imagine one
um imagine one to
to
um imagine one to the
um imagine one to the point
to
um imagine one to the point that
um imagine one to the point that it
to
um imagine one to the point that it it
is
is at least
is at least an
is at least an operational
is at least an operational reality.
The
The world
is at least an operational reality.
The world sees
The world sees that
is at least an operational reality.
The world sees that you
The world sees that you as
is at least an operational reality.
The world sees that you as a
The world sees that you as a personal
individual
individual self
individual self and
individual self and I
individual self and I think
individual self and I think as
individual self and I think as I've
related
related before
individual self and I think as I've
related before one
related before one time
individual self and I think as I've
related before one time when
related before one time when it
individual self and I think as I've
related before one time when it happened
most
most profoundly
it
it took
most profoundly
it took me
it took me a
most profoundly
it took me a long
it took me a long time
most profoundly
it took me a long time to
it took me a long time to get
most profoundly
it took me a long time to get used
it took me a long time to get used to
the
the altered
the altered state
the altered state of
the altered state of consciousness.
the altered state of consciousness. It
took
took years
the altered state of consciousness. It
took years actually.
took years actually. But
the altered state of consciousness. It
took years actually. But the
took years actually. But the first
the altered state of consciousness. It
took years actually. But the first thing
that
that it
that it was
that it was bothersome
that it was bothersome was
that it was bothersome was everybody
that it was bothersome was everybody was
talking
talking to
that it was bothersome was everybody was
talking to this
talking to this body
that it was bothersome was everybody was
talking to this body and
talking to this body and calling
that it was bothersome was everybody was
talking to this body and calling it
talking to this body and calling it you.
I
I didn't
I didn't know
I didn't know who
I didn't know who the
I didn't know who the hell
I didn't know who the hell they're
talking
talking about.
I didn't know who the hell they're
talking about. I
talking about. I had
I didn't know who the hell they're
talking about. I had no
talking about. I had no connection
I didn't know who the hell they're
talking about. I had no connection with
the
the body
the body whatsoever.
the body whatsoever. It'd
the body whatsoever. It'd be
the body whatsoever. It'd be like
the body whatsoever. It'd be like to
the body whatsoever. It'd be like to see
a
a body
the body whatsoever. It'd be like to see
a body sitting
a body sitting there
the body whatsoever. It'd be like to see
a body sitting there and
a body sitting there and people
the body whatsoever. It'd be like to see
a body sitting there and people were
talking
talking to
talking to it
talking to it calling
talking to it calling it
talking to it calling it Dave.
talking to it calling it Dave. I
talking to it calling it Dave. I said,
"Isn't
"Isn't that
talking to it calling it Dave. I said,
"Isn't that strange?
"Isn't that strange? I
talking to it calling it Dave. I said,
"Isn't that strange? I mean
"Isn't that strange? I mean why
talking to it calling it Dave. I said,
"Isn't that strange? I mean why why
"Isn't that strange? I mean why why are
they
they talking
they talking to
that
that which
they talking to
that which I
that which I I'm
they talking to
that which I I'm I'm
that which I I'm I'm over
they talking to
that which I I'm I'm over here
that
that which
that which I
that which I call
that which I call the
that which I call the the
that which I call the the central
that which I call the the central self
self
self with
that which I call the the central self
self with a
self with a capital
that which I call the the central self
self with a capital S
self with a capital S is
that which I call the the central self
self with a capital S is witnessing
self with a capital S is witnessing it
and
and the
and the world
and the world is
and the world is talking
and the world is talking to
and the world is talking to this
and the world is talking to this body
there
there it
and the world is talking to this body
there it is
there it is very
and the world is talking to this body
there it is very strange
there it is very strange and
and the world is talking to this body
there it is very strange and it
there it is very strange and it took
quite
quite a
quite a while
quite a while really
quite a while really to
quite a while really to make
quite a while really to make a
quite a while really to make a shift
quite a while really to make a shift and
uh
uh begin
quite a while really to make a shift and
uh begin to
uh begin to identify
quite a while really to make a shift and
uh begin to identify with
uh begin to identify with that
physicality
not
not be
physicality
not be surprised
not be surprised when
physicality
not be surprised when people
not be surprised when people talk
physicality
not be surprised when people talk to
not be surprised when people talk to But
so
so you
so you arrive
so you arrive at
so you arrive at this
so you arrive at this through
purification
purification of
so you arrive at this through
purification of the
purification of the will
so you arrive at this through
purification of the will and
purification of the will and that's
assisted
assisted by
assisted by the
assisted by the illumination
assisted by the illumination of
assisted by the illumination of the
assisted by the illumination of the mind
which
which if
assisted by the illumination of the mind
which if it
which if it continues
assisted by the illumination of the mind
which if it continues leads
which if it continues leads you
assisted by the illumination of the mind
which if it continues leads you to
divine
divine love.
divine love. So
divine love. So these
divine love. So these stages
divine love. So these stages are
divine love. So these stages are pretty
well
well covered
divine love. So these stages are pretty
well covered in
well covered in in
divine love. So these stages are pretty
well covered in in the
well covered in in the book
divine love. So these stages are pretty
well covered in in the book called
transcending
transcending the
transcending the levels
transcending the levels of
consciousness.
consciousness. This
transcending the levels of
consciousness. This is
consciousness. This is the
transcending the levels of
consciousness. This is the levels
consciousness. This is the levels of
transcending the levels of
consciousness. This is the levels of the
500.
500. So
500. So people,
500. So people, we
500. So people, we got
500. So people, we got many
500. So people, we got many people
500. So people, we got many people in
these
these groups
500. So people, we got many people in
these groups here
these groups here that
500. So people, we got many people in
these groups here that have
these groups here that have come
500. So people, we got many people in
these groups here that have come in
through
through 12step
through 12step groups,
through 12step groups, course
through 12step groups, course of
miracles,
miracles, v
through 12step groups, course of
miracles, v various
miracles, v various other
through 12step groups, course of
miracles, v various other uh
miracles, v various other uh ways
through 12step groups, course of
miracles, v various other uh ways of
arriving
arriving at
arriving at uh
arriving at uh divinity.
arriving at uh divinity. Uh
arriving at uh divinity. Uh because
those
those are
arriving at uh divinity. Uh because
those are steps
those are steps whereby
arriving at uh divinity. Uh because
those are steps whereby you
those are steps whereby you let
arriving at uh divinity. Uh because
those are steps whereby you let go
those are steps whereby you let go of
self-centeredness,
self-centeredness, selfishness
and
and eventually
self-centeredness, selfishness
and eventually you
and eventually you evolve
self-centeredness, selfishness
and eventually you evolve into
and eventually you evolve into the
self-centeredness, selfishness
and eventually you evolve into the level
of
of 500s
of 500s uh
of 500s uh lovingness
of 500s uh lovingness and
of 500s uh lovingness and then
of 500s uh lovingness and then you
perfect
perfect the
of 500s uh lovingness and then you
perfect the lovingness
perfect the lovingness and
of 500s uh lovingness and then you
perfect the lovingness and the
lovingness
lovingness becomes
lovingness becomes unconditional
lovingness becomes unconditional love.
unconditional
unconditional love
lovingness becomes unconditional love.
unconditional love calibrates
unconditional love calibrates I
lovingness becomes unconditional love.
unconditional love calibrates I think
540 huh
uh
uh and
540 huh
uh and saintthood
uh and saintthood around
540 huh
uh and saintthood around 570
540 is
540 is unconditional
540 is unconditional love
uh
uh unconditional
540 is unconditional love
uh unconditional love
uh unconditional love it's
540 is unconditional love
uh unconditional love it's typical
uh unconditional love it's typical of
the
the 12step
the 12step groups
the 12step groups so
the 12step groups so when
the 12step groups so when we
the 12step groups so when we calibrated
the
the impact
the 12step groups so when we calibrated
the impact of
the impact of various
the 12step groups so when we calibrated
the impact of various religions
on
on society
uh
uh Christianity
on society
uh Christianity uh
uh Christianity uh uh
on society
uh Christianity uh uh Judaism
uh Christianity uh uh Judaism uh
on society
uh Christianity uh uh Judaism uh all
uh Christianity uh uh Judaism uh all of
them
them were
them were about
them were about 450
them were about 450 uh
them were about 450 uh and
them were about 450 uh and u
them were about 450 uh and u the
them were about 450 uh and u the 12step
groups
groups calibrated
them were about 450 uh and u the 12step
groups calibrated at
groups calibrated at 540.
So
So the
So the impact
So the impact on
So the impact on society
So the impact on society of
So the impact on society of the
So the impact on society of the 12step
groups
groups is
So the impact on society of the 12step
groups is greater
groups is greater than
So the impact on society of the 12step
groups is greater than that
groups is greater than that of
So the impact on society of the 12step
groups is greater than that of the
groups is greater than that of the more
classic
classic established
classic established religions.
classic established religions. Why?
Because
Because it
classic established religions. Why?
Because it is
Because it is dealing
classic established religions. Why?
Because it is dealing with
Because it is dealing with the
classic established religions. Why?
Because it is dealing with the nonlinear
unconditional
unconditional love.
unconditional love. And
unconditional love. And you
unconditional love. And you know
unconditional love. And you know my
favorite
favorite joke
unconditional love. And you know my
favorite joke about
favorite joke about AA
and
and I
and I know
and I know lots
and I know lots of
and I know lots of people
and I know lots of people in
and I know lots of people in the
and I know lots of people in the A
and I know lots of people in the A for
many
many years
and I know lots of people in the A for
many years is
many years is this
and I know lots of people in the A for
many years is this guy
many years is this guy comes
and I know lots of people in the A for
many years is this guy comes to
many years is this guy comes to a
meeting
meeting and
meeting and he's
meeting and he's crying
meeting and he's crying and
meeting and he's crying and blubbering
over
over there.
meeting and he's crying and blubbering
over there. Somebody
over there. Somebody said
meeting and he's crying and blubbering
over there. Somebody said what's
over there. Somebody said what's the
matter?
matter? He
matter? He says
matter? He says my
matter? He says my children
matter? He says my children run
matter? He says my children run over
matter? He says my children run over and
all
all killed.
matter? He says my children run over and
all killed. My
all killed. My house
matter? He says my children run over and
all killed. My house burned
all killed. My house burned down.
matter? He says my children run over and
all killed. My house burned down. I
all killed. My house burned down. I got
fired
fired and
fired and my
fired and my brother-in-law
fired and my brother-in-law got
fired and my brother-in-law got stabbed
to
to death.
Then
Then the
Then the guy
Then the guy says
Then the guy says to
Then the guy says to him,
Then the guy says to him, "Yeah,
Then the guy says to him, "Yeah, but
that
that was
Then the guy says to him, "Yeah, but
that was yesterday.
That's
That's profoundly
That's profoundly the
That's profoundly the 12step
That's profoundly the 12step group.
That's profoundly the 12step group. That
was
was yesterday.
That's profoundly the 12step group. That
was yesterday. Quit
was yesterday. Quit blubbering
That's profoundly the 12step group. That
was yesterday. Quit blubbering today.
Live
Live one
Live one day
Live one day at
Live one day at a
Live one day at a time
Live one day at a time and
Live one day at a time and you
Live one day at a time and you know
people
people blubbering
Live one day at a time and you know
people blubbering today
people blubbering today what
Live one day at a time and you know
people blubbering today what happened
yesterday
yesterday trying
yesterday trying to
yesterday trying to milk
yesterday trying to milk us
yesterday trying to milk us all
yesterday trying to milk us all for
sympathy
sympathy and
yesterday trying to milk us all for
sympathy and work
sympathy and work us
yesterday trying to milk us all for
sympathy and work us all
sympathy and work us all you
yesterday trying to milk us all for
sympathy and work us all you know.
sympathy and work us all you know. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. We
Okay. We feel
Okay. We feel sorry
Okay. We feel sorry for
Okay. We feel sorry for you
Okay. We feel sorry for you now.
Okay. We feel sorry for you now. You
Okay. We feel sorry for you now. You can
let
let go
Okay. We feel sorry for you now. You can
let go of
let go of it.
Okay. We feel sorry for you now. You can
let go of it. Okay.
Through
Through the
Through the evolution
Through the evolution of
Through the evolution of consciousness
in
in this
Through the evolution of consciousness
in this then
in this then an
Through the evolution of consciousness
in this then an autonomous
in this then an autonomous state
Through the evolution of consciousness
in this then an autonomous state reveals
itself
itself effortlessly.
It
It may
itself effortlessly.
It may have
It may have preceding
itself effortlessly.
It may have preceding warnings
It may have preceding warnings that
itself effortlessly.
It may have preceding warnings that it's
going
going to
going to come
going to come on.
going to come on. Eventually,
going to come on. Eventually, it
going to come on. Eventually, it takes
over
over and
going to come on. Eventually, it takes
over and may
over and may take
going to come on. Eventually, it takes
over and may take you
over and may take you out
going to come on. Eventually, it takes
over and may take you out of
over and may take you out of the
going to come on. Eventually, it takes
over and may take you out of the world.
Took
Took me
Took me out
Took me out of
Took me out of the
Took me out of the world.
Took me out of the world. I
Took me out of the world. I gave
Took me out of the world. I gave up
Took me out of the world. I gave up uh
the
the largest
Took me out of the world. I gave up uh
the largest psychiatric
the largest psychiatric practice
Took me out of the world. I gave up uh
the largest psychiatric practice of
the largest psychiatric practice of his
kind
kind in
kind in the
kind in the United
kind in the United States.
kind in the United States. 100
kind in the United States. 100 uh
kind in the United States. 100 uh people
working
working for
kind in the United States. 100 uh people
working for us,
working for us, 2,000
kind in the United States. 100 uh people
working for us, 2,000 patients,
working for us, 2,000 patients, etc.
walked
walked away
walked away from
walked away from it,
walked away from it, came
walked away from it, came out
walked away from it, came out and
walked away from it, came out and sat
cross-legged
cross-legged all
walked away from it, came out and sat
cross-legged all by
cross-legged all by myself
walked away from it, came out and sat
cross-legged all by myself for
cross-legged all by myself for a
walked away from it, came out and sat
cross-legged all by myself for a couple
years
years on
years on top
years on top of
years on top of the
years on top of the black
years on top of the black widow
years on top of the black widow spiders
and
and remembered
years on top of the black widow spiders
and remembered to
and remembered to eat
years on top of the black widow spiders
and remembered to eat once
and remembered to eat once in
years on top of the black widow spiders
and remembered to eat once in a
and remembered to eat once in a while.
And
And I've
And I've told
And I've told you
And I've told you stories
And I've told you stories about
And I've told you stories about that
before.
before. All
And I've told you stories about that
before. All by
before. All by yourself,
And I've told you stories about that
before. All by yourself, the
before. All by yourself, the body
disappears
disappears and
disappears and uh
disappears and uh and
disappears and uh and you
disappears and uh and you walk
disappears and uh and you walk past
disappears and uh and you walk past the
mirror
mirror and
disappears and uh and you walk past the
mirror and suddenly
mirror and suddenly you
disappears and uh and you walk past the
mirror and suddenly you go
mirror and suddenly you go into
disappears and uh and you walk past the
mirror and suddenly you go into shock.
mirror and suddenly you go into shock. I
can
can remember
can remember going
can remember going into
can remember going into a
can remember going into a shock
can remember going into a shock stunned
that
that there
can remember going into a shock stunned
that there was
that there was somebody
can remember going into a shock stunned
that there was somebody in
that there was somebody in the
can remember going into a shock stunned
that there was somebody in the mirror
and
and another
and another time
and another time walking
and another time walking into
and another time walking into the
and another time walking into the wall.
Walk
Walk right
and another time walking into the wall.
Walk right smack
Walk right smack into
and another time walking into the wall.
Walk right smack into the
Walk right smack into the wall.
I
I was
I was going
I was going to
I was going to walk
I was going to walk right
I was going to walk right through
I was going to walk right through it.
The
The spirit
I was going to walk right through it.
The spirit would
The spirit would just
I was going to walk right through it.
The spirit would just walk
The spirit would just walk through
I was going to walk right through it.
The spirit would just walk through it
and
and the
and the physical
and
and the physical body
and the physical body went
and
and the physical body went right
and the physical body went right against
the
broke
broke my
the
broke my nose
broke my nose and
the
broke my nose and everything.
broke my nose and everything. All
the
broke my nose and everything. All right.
So
So the
So the choice
So the choice the
So the choice the choice
So the choice the choice is
So the choice the choice is you
So the choice the choice is you can
leave
leave the
So the choice the choice is you can
leave the world.
leave the world. You
So the choice the choice is you can
leave the world. You can
leave the world. You can leave
So the choice the choice is you can
leave the world. You can leave the
world.
world. There's
world. There's another
world. There's another alternative
world. There's another alternative uh
world. There's another alternative uh is
you
you can
world. There's another alternative uh is
you can stay
you can stay in
world. There's another alternative uh is
you can stay in the
you can stay in the world
world. There's another alternative uh is
you can stay in the world but
you can stay in the world but yeah
world. There's another alternative uh is
you can stay in the world but yeah more
or
or less
or less like
or less like an
or less like an ashram
you
you don't
or less like an ashram
you don't participate
you don't participate in
or less like an ashram
you don't participate in the
you don't participate in the world
however
you're
you're available
however
you're available and
you're available and people
however
you're available and people come
you're available and people come and
visit
visit you
visit you and
visit you and uh
visit you and uh you
visit you and uh you see
visit you and uh you see people
visit you and uh you see people from
visit you and uh you see people from all
over
over the
visit you and uh you see people from all
over the world
so
so you
so you can
so you can lead
so you can lead the
so you can lead the life
so you can lead the life of
so you can lead the life of a
contemplative
quiet
quiet retired
quiet retired from
quiet retired from the
people
people come
quiet retired from the
people come to
people come to visit
quiet retired from the
people come to visit you
people come to visit you and
quiet retired from the
people come to visit you and what
people come to visit you and what they
looking
looking for
looking for really
looking for really is
looking for really is to
looking for really is to pick
looking for really is to pick up
looking for really is to pick up that
energy,
energy, pick
looking for really is to pick up that
energy, pick up
energy, pick up that
looking for really is to pick up that
energy, pick up that energy.
energy, pick up that energy. So
sometimes
sometimes what
sometimes what you
sometimes what you do
sometimes what you do is
sometimes what you do is you
sometimes what you do is you return
sometimes what you do is you return to
teaching
teaching so
sometimes what you do is you return to
teaching so that
teaching so that you
sometimes what you do is you return to
teaching so that you can
teaching so that you can be
sometimes what you do is you return to
teaching so that you can be available
for
for others
for others to
for others to reach
for others to reach that
for others to reach that energy
for others to reach that energy because
not
not everyone
for others to reach that energy because
not everyone is
not everyone is capable
for others to reach that energy because
not everyone is capable of
traveling
traveling long
traveling long distance
traveling long distance and
traveling long distance and the
traveling long distance and the and
traveling long distance and the and the
expense
expense and
traveling long distance and the and the
expense and the
expense and the money
traveling long distance and the and the
expense and the money is
expense and the money is such
traveling long distance and the and the
expense and the money is such a
expense and the money is such a thing.
So
So Ramano
So Ramano Mahari
So Ramano Mahari and
So Ramano Mahari and Nagadana
So Ramano Mahari and Nagadana Maharaj
So Ramano Mahari and Nagadana Maharaj uh
serve
serve that
serve that m
serve that m the
serve that m the mystic
serve that m the mystic who
serve that m the mystic who then
serve that m the mystic who then has
serve that m the mystic who then has a
limited
limited uh
serve that m the mystic who then has a
limited uh role
limited uh role serves
serve that m the mystic who then has a
limited uh role serves as
limited uh role serves as a
serve that m the mystic who then has a
limited uh role serves as a teacher
limited uh role serves as a teacher for
those
those who
those who seek
those who seek him
those who seek him as
those who seek him as a
those who seek him as a teacher
those who seek him as a teacher but
don't
don't necessarily
those who seek him as a teacher but
don't necessarily go
don't necessarily go out
those who seek him as a teacher but
don't necessarily go out into
don't necessarily go out into the
those who seek him as a teacher but
don't necessarily go out into the world
and
and make
and make it
and make it available
and make it available to
and make it available to any
and make it available to any large
numbers
numbers of
and make it available to any large
numbers of people.
My
My own
My own uh
My own uh inner
My own uh inner capacity
My own uh inner capacity was
My own uh inner capacity was always
My own uh inner capacity was always the
relieving
relieving of
My own uh inner capacity was always the
relieving of suffering.
relieving of suffering. That's
My own uh inner capacity was always the
relieving of suffering. That's why
relieving of suffering. That's why I
became
became a
became a physician.
became a physician. That's
became a physician. That's why
became a physician. That's why I
became a physician. That's why I had
became a physician. That's why I had a
special
special relationship
became a physician. That's why I had a
special relationship with
special relationship with animals
to
to the
to the relief
to the relief of
to the relief of suffering.
to the relief of suffering. Whether
to the relief of suffering. Whether it's
a
a beagle
to the relief of suffering. Whether it's
a beagle flipping
a beagle flipping his
to the relief of suffering. Whether it's
a beagle flipping his legs
a beagle flipping his legs upside
to the relief of suffering. Whether it's
a beagle flipping his legs upside down,
the
the compassion
the compassion leads
the compassion leads you
the compassion leads you to
the compassion leads you to then
the compassion leads you to then become
a
a physician
the compassion leads you to then become
a physician or
a physician or a
the compassion leads you to then become
a physician or a healer.
I
I could
I could have
I could have been
I could have been a
I could have been a very
I could have been a very good
I could have been a very good uh
I could have been a very good uh doctor,
animal
animal doctor.
And
And the
And the observation
And the observation of
And the observation of the
And the observation of the totality
And the observation of the totality of
human
human suffering
And the observation of the totality of
human suffering is
human suffering is what
And the observation of the totality of
human suffering is what fully
human suffering is what fully motivated
my
my staying
my staying in
my staying in the
my staying in the world.
my staying in the world. As
my staying in the world. As I
my staying in the world. As I remember
one
one time
my staying in the world. As I remember
one time I
one time I was
my staying in the world. As I remember
one time I was highly
one time I was highly religious.
my staying in the world. As I remember
one time I was highly religious. I
walked
walked through
walked through the
walked through the field
walked through the field uh
walked through the field uh thinking
about
about nothing
walked through the field uh thinking
about nothing at
about nothing at all
walked through the field uh thinking
about nothing at all and
about nothing at all and suddenly
walked through the field uh thinking
about nothing at all and suddenly the
totality
of
of human
totality
of human suffering
of human suffering throughout
totality
of human suffering throughout all
of human suffering throughout all of
time
was
was like
time
was like revealed.
was like revealed. It
time
was like revealed. It was
was like revealed. It was staggering
staggering
staggering beyond
staggering beyond all
staggering beyond all description.
staggering
staggering in
staggering beyond all description.
staggering in its
staggering in its enormity.
staggering beyond all description.
staggering in its enormity. Yeah.
staggering in its enormity. Yeah. And
its
its consequence.
And
And in
its consequence.
And in that
And in that instant
its consequence.
And in that instant is
And in that instant is when
its consequence.
And in that instant is when I
And in that instant is when I became
its consequence.
And in that instant is when I became an
atheist.
atheist. And
atheist. And I
atheist. And I told
atheist. And I told you
atheist. And I told you about
atheist. And I told you about my
atheist. And I told you about my years
as
as an
atheist. And I told you about my years
as an atheist
because
because I
because I thought
because I thought it
because I thought it was
because I thought it was God
because I thought it was God that
because I thought it was God that had
created
created all
because I thought it was God that had
created all this
created all this suffering.
because I thought it was God that had
created all this suffering. And
created all this suffering. And I
because I thought it was God that had
created all this suffering. And I didn't
realize
realize that
realize that all
realize that all that
realize that all that suffering
realize that all that suffering I
realize that all that suffering I was
seeing
seeing was
realize that all that suffering I was
seeing was the
seeing was the consequence
realize that all that suffering I was
seeing was the consequence of
seeing was the consequence of the
realize that all that suffering I was
seeing was the consequence of the human
ego.
ego. It
ego. It wasn't
ego. It wasn't the
ego. It wasn't the creation
ego. It wasn't the creation of
ego. It wasn't the creation of divinity.
It
It was
ego. It wasn't the creation of divinity.
It was the
It was the creation
ego. It wasn't the creation of divinity.
It was the creation of
It was the creation of the
ego. It wasn't the creation of divinity.
It was the creation of the human
It was the creation of the human ego.
And
And therefore
And therefore I
And therefore I finally
And therefore I finally transcended
And therefore I finally transcended it
with
with that
And therefore I finally transcended it
with that realization
with that realization that
And therefore I finally transcended it
with that realization that it
with that realization that it was
And therefore I finally transcended it
with that realization that it was the
human
human ego.
human ego. But
human ego. But nevertheless,
human ego. But nevertheless, the
human ego. But nevertheless, the desire
to
to relieve
human ego. But nevertheless, the desire
to relieve suffering
to relieve suffering in
human ego. But nevertheless, the desire
to relieve suffering in all
to relieve suffering in all of
human ego. But nevertheless, the desire
to relieve suffering in all of its
capacities
capacities is
capacities is why
capacities is why I
capacities is why I had
capacities is why I had such
capacities is why I had such a
capacities is why I had such a large
clinic
clinic and
capacities is why I had such a large
clinic and tried
clinic and tried all
capacities is why I had such a large
clinic and tried all kinds
clinic and tried all kinds of
capacities is why I had such a large
clinic and tried all kinds of innovative
approaches,
approaches, anything
approaches, anything that
approaches, anything that would
approaches, anything that would help
approaches, anything that would help the
patient.
patient. Uh
approaches, anything that would help the
patient. Uh not
patient. Uh not all
approaches, anything that would help the
patient. Uh not all of
patient. Uh not all of it
approaches, anything that would help the
patient. Uh not all of it conventional,
a
a lot
a lot of
a lot of it
a lot of it non-conventional
a lot of it non-conventional and
a lot of it non-conventional and the
non-conventional
non-conventional things
a lot of it non-conventional and the
non-conventional things were
non-conventional things were extremely
uh
uh useful.
uh useful. Therefore,
uh useful. Therefore, scientism
uh useful. Therefore, scientism and
skepticism
skepticism and
uh useful. Therefore, scientism and
skepticism and all
skepticism and all are
uh useful. Therefore, scientism and
skepticism and all are very
self-limiting
self-limiting because
self-limiting because the
self-limiting because the clinician
self-limiting because the clinician uses
things
things other
self-limiting because the clinician uses
things other than
things other than academic
self-limiting because the clinician uses
things other than academic medicine.
things other than academic medicine. He
uses
uses intuitive
uses intuitive understanding
and
and the
uses intuitive understanding
and the how
and the how much
uses intuitive understanding
and the how much you
and the how much you care
uses intuitive understanding
and the how much you care for
and the how much you care for the
patient
patient has
patient has an
patient has an impact.
patient has an impact. I'm
patient has an impact. I'm not
patient has an impact. I'm not talking
about
about counter
patient has an impact. I'm not talking
about counter transference,
about counter transference, but
patient has an impact. I'm not talking
about counter transference, but who
about counter transference, but who you
are
are to
are to the
are to the patient
are to the patient has
are to the patient has a
are to the patient has a profound
effect.
effect. And
are to the patient has a profound
effect. And I
effect. And I myself
are to the patient has a profound
effect. And I myself were
effect. And I myself were cured
are to the patient has a profound
effect. And I myself were cured of
effect. And I myself were cured of many
ailments.
Uh,
Uh, I
ailments.
Uh, I remember
Uh, I remember I
ailments.
Uh, I remember I had
Uh, I remember I had a
ailments.
Uh, I remember I had a chronic
intractable
intractable uh,
intractable uh, perforating
intractable uh, perforating ulcer
intractable uh, perforating ulcer that
was
was perforating
intractable uh, perforating ulcer that
was perforating into
was perforating into the
intractable uh, perforating ulcer that
was perforating into the pancreas
was perforating into the pancreas and
potentially
potentially lethal
potentially lethal and
potentially lethal and uh,
potentially lethal and uh, acupuncture
was
was just
potentially lethal and uh, acupuncture
was just brand
was just brand new
potentially lethal and uh, acupuncture
was just brand new in
was just brand new in the
potentially lethal and uh, acupuncture
was just brand new in the United
was just brand new in the United States.
first
first the
first the first
first the first acupuncture
first the first acupuncture patients
first the first acupuncture patients I
was
was one
first the first acupuncture patients I
was one of
was one of the
first the first acupuncture patients I
was one of the first
was one of the first ones
first the first acupuncture patients I
was one of the first ones in
was one of the first ones in the
first the first acupuncture patients I
was one of the first ones in the whole
United
United States
United States and
United States and after
United States and after three
United States and after three treatments
three
three treatments
United States and after three treatments
three treatments and
three treatments and I
United States and after three treatments
three treatments and I remember
three treatments and I remember the
needle
needle going
needle going through
needle going through after
needle going through after three
treatments
treatments in
needle going through after three
treatments in a
treatments in a chronic
needle going through after three
treatments in a chronic intractable
ulcer
ulcer of
ulcer of 30
ulcer of 30 years
ulcer of 30 years duration
life-threatening
life-threatening was
ulcer of 30 years duration
life-threatening was cured
life-threatening was cured in
ulcer of 30 years duration
life-threatening was cured in exactly
three
three acupuncture
three acupuncture treatments.
So
So all
three acupuncture treatments.
So all the
So all the people
three acupuncture treatments.
So all the people that
So all the people that boo,
three acupuncture treatments.
So all the people that boo, you
So all the people that boo, you know,
boo
boo boo
boo boo and
boo boo and make
boo boo and make fun
boo boo and make fun of
boo boo and make fun of acupuncture
boo boo and make fun of acupuncture as
being
being unscientific,
I
I say,
I say, well,
I say, well, just
I say, well, just count
I say, well, just count your
I say, well, just count your count
I say, well, just count your count your
lucky
lucky cards
I say, well, just count your count your
lucky cards that
lucky cards that you
I say, well, just count your count your
lucky cards that you don't
lucky cards that you don't need
acupuncture
yet
because
because other
because other days
because other days are
because other days are coming.
because other days are coming. I
because other days are coming. I hate
because other days are coming. I hate to
tell
tell you.
So
So u
So u wisdom
So u wisdom has
So u wisdom has spoke.
So u wisdom has spoke. Thank
So u wisdom has spoke. Thank you,
wisdom.
wisdom. It
So u wisdom has spoke. Thank you,
wisdom. It said
wisdom. It said it's
So u wisdom has spoke. Thank you,
wisdom. It said it's time
wisdom. It said it's time for
So u wisdom has spoke. Thank you,
wisdom. It said it's time for a
wisdom. It said it's time for a break.
And
And how
And how long
And how long does
And how long does the
And how long does the break?
>> About
>> About 15
And how long does the break?
>> About 15 minutes.
>> About 15 minutes. about
And how long does the break?
>> About 15 minutes. about 15
>> About 15 minutes. about 15 minutes.
The
The reason
The reason we're
The reason we're five
The reason we're five minutes
The reason we're five minutes late
The reason we're five minutes late is
The reason we're five minutes late is so
that
that all
The reason we're five minutes late is so
that all the
that all the people
The reason we're five minutes late is so
that all the people who
that all the people who are
The reason we're five minutes late is so
that all the people who are five
that all the people who are five minutes
late
late won't
late won't feel
late won't feel guilty
late won't feel guilty about
late won't feel guilty about it.
Well,
Well, people
late won't feel guilty about it.
Well, people various
Well, people various things
late won't feel guilty about it.
Well, people various things come
Well, people various things come up
about
about the
about the mystic.
about the mystic. So,
about the mystic. So, we'll
about the mystic. So, we'll have
about the mystic. So, we'll have some
interesting
interesting discussion
about the mystic. So, we'll have some
interesting discussion about
interesting discussion about it
about the mystic. So, we'll have some
interesting discussion about it later.
The
The mystic
The mystic is
The mystic is the
The mystic is the closest
The mystic is the closest to
The mystic is the closest to our
our
our approach
The mystic is the closest to our
our approach to
our approach to spiritual
The mystic is the closest to our
our approach to spiritual education.
What
What we've
What we've done
What we've done in
What we've done in all
What we've done in all the
What we've done in all the lectures
What we've done in all the lectures and
books
books is
What we've done in all the lectures and
books is really
books is really prepare
What we've done in all the lectures and
books is really prepare prepare
books is really prepare prepare you
What we've done in all the lectures and
books is really prepare prepare you for
the
the mystical
the mystical experience.
the mystical experience. We
the mystical experience. We tried
the mystical experience. We tried to
remove
remove all
the mystical experience. We tried to
remove all the
remove all the barriers
to
to facilitate
to facilitate the
to facilitate the sudden
to facilitate the sudden emergence
to facilitate the sudden emergence of
the
the awareness
to facilitate the sudden emergence of
the awareness of
the awareness of the
to facilitate the sudden emergence of
the awareness of the reality
the awareness of the reality of
to facilitate the sudden emergence of
the awareness of the reality of that
which
which you
which you are.
So
So the
which you are.
So the purpose
So the purpose of
which you are.
So the purpose of all
So the purpose of all the
which you are.
So the purpose of all the consciousness
research
research has
research has been
research has been to
research has been to transcend
research has been to transcend the
levels
and
and thereby
and thereby you
and thereby you open
and thereby you open the
and thereby you open the door
and thereby you open the door for
revelation
revelation to
and thereby you open the door for
revelation to occur.
revelation to occur. Mhm.
and thereby you open the door for
revelation to occur. Mhm. It's
revelation to occur. Mhm. It's not
something
something you
something you cause
something you cause but
something you cause but by
something you cause but by removing
something you cause but by removing the
obstacles
obstacles it
something you cause but by removing the
obstacles it happens
obstacles it happens spontaneously.
Uh
Uh so
a
a group
Uh so
a group like
a group like this
Uh so
a group like this is
um
will
will now
um
will now have
will now have a
um
will now have a propensity
to
to become
to become mystics
to become mystics and
to become mystics and if
to become mystics and if you
to become mystics and if you don't
to become mystics and if you don't do
to become mystics and if you don't do it
this
this lifetime
to become mystics and if you don't do it
this lifetime you'll
this lifetime you'll be
to become mystics and if you don't do it
this lifetime you'll be doing
this lifetime you'll be doing it
to become mystics and if you don't do it
this lifetime you'll be doing it next
soon.
soon. So
soon. So because
soon. So because once
soon. So because once you
soon. So because once you remove
soon. So because once you remove the
barriers
barriers thinking
soon. So because once you remove the
barriers thinking that
barriers thinking that the
soon. So because once you remove the
barriers thinking that the personal
barriers thinking that the personal eye
is
is who
is who you
is who you are,
is who you are, once
is who you are, once that
is who you are, once that illusion
is who you are, once that illusion is
removed,
removed, the
is who you are, once that illusion is
removed, the truth
removed, the truth and
is who you are, once that illusion is
removed, the truth and the
removed, the truth and the reality
floods
floods in
floods in floods
floods in floods in
it
it can
floods in floods in
it can have
it can have some
floods in floods in
it can have some hair
it can have some hair raising
experiences
experiences along
experiences along the
experiences along the way.
experiences along the way. uh
experiences along the way. uh but
experiences along the way. uh but I've
also
also prepared
experiences along the way. uh but I've
also prepared you
also prepared you for
experiences along the way. uh but I've
also prepared you for them
also prepared you for them uh
experiences along the way. uh but I've
also prepared you for them uh that
also prepared you for them uh that you
can
can have
can have some
can have some hair
can have some hair raising
can have some hair raising experiences
and
and I've
can have some hair raising experiences
and I've given
and I've given you
can have some hair raising experiences
and I've given you the
and I've given you the answers
can have some hair raising experiences
and I've given you the answers and
and I've given you the answers and uh
when
when the
when the when
when the when the
when the when the moment
when the when the moment arrives
when the when the moment arrives that
you
you need
when the when the moment arrives that
you need that
you need that information
uh
uh it
uh it will
uh it will be
uh it will be there
uh it will be there you
uh it will be there you won't
uh it will be there you won't remember
it
it but
uh it will be there you won't remember
it but suddenly
it but suddenly you'll
uh it will be there you won't remember
it but suddenly you'll know
it but suddenly you'll know it
uh it will be there you won't remember
it but suddenly you'll know it and
it but suddenly you'll know it and you
won't
won't remember
won't remember where
won't remember where it
won't remember where it came
won't remember where it came out
won't remember where it came out of
won't remember where it came out of but
it
it came
won't remember where it came out of but
it came from
it came from the
won't remember where it came out of but
it came from the reality
it came from the reality of
won't remember where it came out of but
it came from the reality of having
it came from the reality of having lived
through
through it.
Where
Where are
through it.
Where are we
Where are we on
through it.
Where are we on the
Where are we on the slides
through it.
Where are we on the slides anymore?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> Huh?
Anyway,
Anyway, during
Anyway, during during
Anyway, during during the
Anyway, during during the break,
Anyway, during during the break, we
solved
solved the
Anyway, during during the break, we
solved the uh
solved the uh the
Anyway, during during the break, we
solved the uh the the
solved the uh the the international
problem.
We
We solved
problem.
We solved all
We solved all international
problem.
We solved all international problems.
We'll
We'll have
We'll have B29s
We'll have B29s loaded
We'll have B29s loaded with
We'll have B29s loaded with teddy
We'll have B29s loaded with teddy bears
with
with no
We'll have B29s loaded with teddy bears
with no explanation.
It
It rains
It rains teddy
It rains teddy bears.
Oh
Oh god.
So
So a
So a sense
So a sense of
So a sense of humor
So a sense of humor is
So a sense of humor is necessary
So a sense of humor is necessary uh
So a sense of humor is necessary uh in
order
order to
So a sense of humor is necessary uh in
order to get
order to get along
So a sense of humor is necessary uh in
order to get along in
order to get along in this
So a sense of humor is necessary uh in
order to get along in this world.
order to get along in this world. A
sense
sense of
sense of humor
sense of humor about
sense of humor about it
sense of humor about it all.
sense of humor about it all. I don't
know.
know. Take
sense of humor about it all. I don't
know. Take it
know. Take it all
sense of humor about it all. I don't
know. Take it all with
know. Take it all with a
sense of humor about it all. I don't
know. Take it all with a ounce
know. Take it all with a ounce of
sense of humor about it all. I don't
know. Take it all with a ounce of uh
ounce
ounce of
ounce of uh
ounce
ounce of
ounce of uh
ounce of something
ounce of something rather.
All
All right.
All right. Now,
All right. Now, I
All right. Now, I wanted
All right. Now, I wanted to
All right. Now, I wanted to go
All right. Now, I wanted to go through
the
the inner
All right. Now, I wanted to go through
the inner process
the inner process of
All right. Now, I wanted to go through
the inner process of the
the inner process of the mystic.
All right. Now, I wanted to go through
the inner process of the mystic. How
many
many sides
many sides do
many sides do we
many sides do we have
many sides do we have on
many sides do we have on the
many sides do we have on the mystic
many sides do we have on the mystic so
many sides do we have on the mystic so I
don't
don't get
many sides do we have on the mystic so I
don't get lost
don't get lost in
many sides do we have on the mystic so I
don't get lost in jabberness?
>> Four
>> Four al
>> Four al together.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. All right.
>> Oh
>> Oh my
>> Oh my god.
>> Oh my god. Five.
>> Oh my god. Five. I
>> Oh my god. Five. I better
>> Oh my god. Five. I better hustle
>> Oh my god. Five. I better hustle up.
All
All right.
>> Oh my god. Five. I better hustle up.
All right. So,
All right. So, and
>> Oh my god. Five. I better hustle up.
All right. So, and we'll
All right. So, and we'll see
>> Oh my god. Five. I better hustle up.
All right. So, and we'll see we'll
All right. So, and we'll see we'll test
out
out this
out this group
out this group and
out this group and see
out this group and see how
out this group and see how well
out this group and see how well we
out this group and see how well we meet
these
these criteria.
Uh
first
first of
Uh
first of all,
first of all, the
Uh
first of all, the inner
first of all, the inner process
Uh
first of all, the inner process towards
enlightenment,
enlightenment, towards
enlightenment, towards revelation,
towards
towards becoming
enlightenment, towards revelation,
towards becoming a
towards becoming a mystic
enlightenment, towards revelation,
towards becoming a mystic is
towards becoming a mystic is uh
enlightenment, towards revelation,
towards becoming a mystic is uh I
towards becoming a mystic is uh I call
it
it ignition.
Ignition,
Ignition, initiation,
it ignition.
Ignition, initiation, attraction.
Ignition, initiation, attraction. First
of
of all,
of all, you
of all, you hear
of all, you hear of
of all, you hear of it.
of all, you hear of it. Most
of all, you hear of it. Most people
become
become interested
of all, you hear of it. Most people
become interested in
become interested in enlightenment
of all, you hear of it. Most people
become interested in enlightenment when
they
they hear
they hear of
they hear of it.
they hear of it. Oh,
they hear of it. Oh, they
they hear of it. Oh, they hear
they hear of it. Oh, they hear that
there
there is
they hear of it. Oh, they hear that
there is such
there is such a
they hear of it. Oh, they hear that
there is such a pathway.
They
They begin
They begin to
They begin to uh
They begin to uh so
They begin to uh so you
They begin to uh so you can
They begin to uh so you can then
They begin to uh so you can then you
then
then seek
They begin to uh so you can then you
then seek out
then seek out a
They begin to uh so you can then you
then seek out a spiritual
then seek out a spiritual group
They begin to uh so you can then you
then seek out a spiritual group that
then seek out a spiritual group that is
aligned
aligned with
aligned with reaching
aligned with reaching enlightenment.
So
So there's
aligned with reaching enlightenment.
So there's ignition.
So there's ignition. First
aligned with reaching enlightenment.
So there's ignition. First you
So there's ignition. First you hear
about
about it.
about it. Then
about it. Then there's
about it. Then there's the
about it. Then there's the initiation
which
which is
about it. Then there's the initiation
which is occurs
which is occurs in
about it. Then there's the initiation
which is occurs in the
which is occurs in the energy
about it. Then there's the initiation
which is occurs in the energy field
which is occurs in the energy field of
the
the atheric
the atheric body.
the atheric body. You
the atheric body. You become
the atheric body. You become attracted
to
to it
the atheric body. You become attracted
to it and
to it and you
the atheric body. You become attracted
to it and you begin
to it and you begin to
the atheric body. You become attracted
to it and you begin to hang
to it and you begin to hang out
the atheric body. You become attracted
to it and you begin to hang out with
holy
holy people.
When
When you
holy people.
When you do,
When you do, you
holy people.
When you do, you pick
When you do, you pick up
holy people.
When you do, you pick up the
When you do, you pick up the energy
field.
field. Uh
field. Uh and
field. Uh and classically
field. Uh and classically the
field. Uh and classically the energy
field
field of
field. Uh and classically the energy
field of the
field of the enlightened
field. Uh and classically the energy
field of the enlightened teacher
field of the enlightened teacher that
transmits
transmits to
transmits to the
transmits to the energy
transmits to the energy field
transmits to the energy field of
transmits to the energy field of the
atheric
atheric body
uh
uh of
uh of the
uh of the student
uh of the student and
uh of the student and may
uh of the student and may stay
uh of the student and may stay there
uh of the student and may stay there for
many
many generations
uh of the student and may stay there for
many generations many
many generations many life
uh of the student and may stay there for
many generations many life physical
lifetimes
lifetimes and
lifetimes and then
lifetimes and then when
lifetimes and then when you
lifetimes and then when you need
lifetimes and then when you need it
lifetimes and then when you need it it's
there.
there. So
lifetimes and then when you need it it's
there. So that's
there. So that's see
lifetimes and then when you need it it's
there. So that's see the
there. So that's see the purpose
lifetimes and then when you need it it's
there. So that's see the purpose of
there. So that's see the purpose of the
teacher
teacher then
teacher then is
teacher then is not
teacher then is not to
teacher then is not to to
teacher then is not to to impart
teacher then is not to to impart wisdom
but
but to
teacher then is not to to impart wisdom
but to just
but to just stand
teacher then is not to to impart wisdom
but to just stand there
but to just stand there and
teacher then is not to to impart wisdom
but to just stand there and pay
but to just stand there and pay pay
attention
attention to
attention to kicking
attention to kicking things
attention to kicking things off
attention to kicking things off the
heart.
The
The energy
The energy field
The energy field of
The energy field of this
The energy field of this this
The energy field of this this entity
here
here uh
The energy field of this this entity
here uh when
here uh when I
The energy field of this this entity
here uh when I needed
here uh when I needed it
The energy field of this this entity
here uh when I needed it was
here uh when I needed it was picked
The energy field of this this entity
here uh when I needed it was picked up
more
more than
more than five
more than five lifetimes
more than five lifetimes ago.
more than five lifetimes ago. more
more than five lifetimes ago. more than
seven,
seven, more
more than five lifetimes ago. more than
seven, more than
seven, more than eight,
more than five lifetimes ago. more than
seven, more than eight, more
seven, more than eight, more than
more than five lifetimes ago. more than
seven, more than eight, more than 10,
more
more than
more than eight.
more than eight. More
more than eight. More than
more than eight. More than eight
lifetimes
lifetimes ago,
this
this entity
this entity now
this entity now speaking
this entity now speaking picked
this entity now speaking picked up
this entity now speaking picked up from
the
the aura
this entity now speaking picked up from
the aura of
the aura of a
this entity now speaking picked up from
the aura of a great
the aura of a great teacher.
this entity now speaking picked up from
the aura of a great teacher. I
the aura of a great teacher. I never
asked
asked who
asked who the
asked who the teacher
asked who the teacher was
asked who the teacher was because
asked who the teacher was because it's
irrelevant.
So
So the
So the energy
So the energy field
So the energy field then
So the energy field then stays
So the energy field then stays there
So the energy field then stays there as
a
a vibration
So the energy field then stays there as
a vibration in
a vibration in the
So the energy field then stays there as
a vibration in the atheric
a vibration in the atheric body
So the energy field then stays there as
a vibration in the atheric body in
a vibration in the atheric body in the
highest
highest levels
highest levels of
highest levels of the
highest levels of the atheric
highest levels of the atheric body
and
and when
highest levels of the atheric body
and when it's
and when it's needed
highest levels of the atheric body
and when it's needed it
and when it's needed it summons
highest levels of the atheric body
and when it's needed it summons forth
and
and when
and when it
and when it comes
and when it comes forth
and when it comes forth it
and when it comes forth it comes
and when it comes forth it comes forth
as
as a
and when it comes forth it comes forth
as a conviction
as a conviction and
and when it comes forth it comes forth
as a conviction and knowingness
and
and we've
and we've said
and we've said before
and we've said before that
and we've said before that knowingness
can
can only
and we've said before that knowingness
can only arrive
from
from the
from the energy
from the energy field
from the energy field of
from the energy field of someone
from the energy field of someone who
from the energy field of someone who has
lived
lived it.
It
It can't
It can't be
It can't be something
It can't be something you
It can't be something you read
It can't be something you read in
It can't be something you read in a
book.
book. So
It can't be something you read in a
book. So the
book. So the power
It can't be something you read in a
book. So the power of
book. So the power of the
It can't be something you read in a
book. So the power of the field
uh
arises
arises from
uh
arises from one
arises from one who
uh
arises from one who has
arises from one who has lived
uh
arises from one who has lived it
arises from one who has lived it to
uh
arises from one who has lived it to let
go
go and
go and go
go and go through
go and go through the
go and go through the death
go and go through the death of
go and go through the death of the
personal
personal eye
leads
leads to
leads to a
leads to a conviction
leads to a conviction of
leads to a conviction of enormous
leads to a conviction of enormous power.
And
And when
leads to a conviction of enormous power.
And when it
And when it comes
leads to a conviction of enormous power.
And when it comes time
And when it comes time for
leads to a conviction of enormous power.
And when it comes time for the
And when it comes time for the death
leads to a conviction of enormous power.
And when it comes time for the death of
the
the personal
the personal eye,
it
it it
the personal eye,
it it can
it it can be
the personal eye,
it it can be terrifying.
it it can be terrifying. And
the personal eye,
it it can be terrifying. And to
counterbalance
counterbalance it,
counterbalance it, one
counterbalance it, one needs
counterbalance it, one needs absolute
conviction.
Not
Not something
Not something that
Not something that somebody
Not something that somebody read
somewhere
somewhere in
Not something that somebody read
somewhere in a
somewhere in a book,
Not something that somebody read
somewhere in a book, but
somewhere in a book, but the
Not something that somebody read
somewhere in a book, but the knowingness
that
that of
that of having
that of having lived
that of having lived through
that of having lived through it,
that of having lived through it, that
it's
it's possible
that of having lived through it, that
it's possible to
it's possible to do
that of having lived through it, that
it's possible to do it.
it's possible to do it. So
that of having lived through it, that
it's possible to do it. So that
knowingness
knowingness then
knowingness then is
knowingness then is transmitted
as
as an
knowingness then is transmitted
as an ignition
as an ignition part
knowingness then is transmitted
as an ignition part of
as an ignition part of the
knowingness then is transmitted
as an ignition part of the initiation
and
and when
and when it
and when it gets
and when it gets attracted
and when it gets attracted to
um
spiritual
spiritual groups
through
through the
spiritual groups
through the so
through the so you
spiritual groups
through the so you have
through the so you have the
spiritual groups
through the so you have the motivation
uh
uh then
uh then you
uh then you have
uh then you have curiosity
uh then you have curiosity uh
uh then you have curiosity uh I
uh then you have curiosity uh I mean
that's
that's really
uh then you have curiosity uh I mean
that's really interest
also
also get
also get inspired
also get inspired you
also get inspired you get
also get inspired you get inspired
also get inspired you get inspired by
the
the presence
also get inspired you get inspired by
the presence of
the presence of others
also get inspired you get inspired by
the presence of others non-verbally
and
and you
and you get
and you get inspired
and you get inspired by
and you get inspired by the
and you get inspired by the truths
and you get inspired by the truths that
you
you hear
and you get inspired by the truths that
you hear from
you hear from other
and you get inspired by the truths that
you hear from other people.
So,
So, it's
So, it's communicable.
They
They say
So, it's communicable.
They say 12step
They say 12step groups
So, it's communicable.
They say 12step groups know
They say 12step groups know this
So, it's communicable.
They say 12step groups know this very
well.
well. They
well. They say,
well. They say, uh,
well. They say, uh, don't
well. They say, uh, don't worry
well. They say, uh, don't worry about
anything.
anything. Just
well. They say, uh, don't worry about
anything. Just bring
anything. Just bring the
well. They say, uh, don't worry about
anything. Just bring the body.
Just
Just bring
Just bring the
Just bring the body.
Just bring the body. That's
Just bring the body. That's true.
Just bring the body. That's true. And,
uh,
uh, people
Just bring the body. That's true. And,
uh, people are
uh, people are so
Just bring the body. That's true. And,
uh, people are so sick
uh, people are so sick and
Just bring the body. That's true. And,
uh, people are so sick and all,
uh, people are so sick and all, they
can't
can't even
can't even sit
can't even sit up.
can't even sit up. So,
can't even sit up. So, I
can't even sit up. So, I tell
can't even sit up. So, I tell them,
can't even sit up. So, I tell them, go
lay
lay in
can't even sit up. So, I tell them, go
lay in the
lay in the corner
and
and just
and just shut
and just shut up.
and
and they
and just shut up.
and they get
and they get it
and just shut up.
and they get it by
and they get it by osmosis.
and just shut up.
and they get it by osmosis. Sure
and they get it by osmosis. Sure enough,
sooner
sooner or
sooner or later
sooner or later one
sooner or later one day
sooner or later one day they've
sooner or later one day they've had
sooner or later one day they've had it
and
and suddenly
sooner or later one day they've had it
and suddenly the
and suddenly the inspiration,
sooner or later one day they've had it
and suddenly the inspiration, the
knowingness
knowingness charges
knowingness charges forth
knowingness charges forth into
knowingness charges forth into their
knowingness charges forth into their and
they
they become
knowingness charges forth into their and
they become sober
they become sober and
knowingness charges forth into their and
they become sober and recover
they become sober and recover after
knowingness charges forth into their and
they become sober and recover after many
years
years of
years of being
years of being hopeless.
All
All right?
years of being hopeless.
All right? So
All right? So there's
years of being hopeless.
All right? So there's a
All right? So there's a certain
contagion
contagion then
contagion then the
contagion then the energy
contagion then the energy field
uh
uh that's
contagion then the energy field
uh that's picked
uh that's picked up
contagion then the energy field
uh that's picked up through
uh that's picked up through and
contagion then the energy field
uh that's picked up through and this
uh that's picked up through and this is
the
the the
the the value
the the value of
the the value of stay
the the value of stay with
the the value of stay with holy
the the value of stay with holy company
stay
stay with
the the value of stay with holy company
stay with holy
stay with holy with
the the value of stay with holy company
stay with holy with company
stay with holy with company means
the the value of stay with holy company
stay with holy with company means that
you
you have
you have a
you have a group
you have a group aura
you have a group aura that
you have a group aura that is
you have a group aura that is now
you have a group aura that is now are
quite
quite powerful
and
and again
and again as
and again as a
and again as a as
and again as a as a
and again as a as a comparative
and again as a as a comparative uh
common
common knowledge
and again as a as a comparative uh
common knowledge the
common knowledge the 12step
and again as a as a comparative uh
common knowledge the 12step groups
common knowledge the 12step groups are
that
that way
that way when
that way when a
that way when a person
that way when a person says
that way when a person says I
that way when a person says I don't
that way when a person says I don't need
anymore
anymore I
that way when a person says I don't need
anymore I can
anymore I can do
that way when a person says I don't need
anymore I can do it
anymore I can do it on
that way when a person says I don't need
anymore I can do it on my
anymore I can do it on my phone
that way when a person says I don't need
anymore I can do it on my phone and
anymore I can do it on my phone and they
leave
leave the
leave the group.
leave the group. That's
leave the group. That's the
leave the group. That's the last
leave the group. That's the last thing
you
you hear
leave the group. That's the last thing
you hear from
you hear from them.
You
You get
You get a
You get a call
You get a call from
You get a call from the
You get a call from the hospital
that
that so
You get a call from the hospital
that so and
that so and so
You get a call from the hospital
that so and so is
that so and so is in
You get a call from the hospital
that so and so is in a
that so and so is in a straight
You get a call from the hospital
that so and so is in a straight jacket.
You
You know,
I
I knew
You know,
I knew I
I knew I knew
You know,
I knew I knew one
I knew I knew one of
You know,
I knew I knew one of one
I knew I knew one of one of
You know,
I knew I knew one of one of them
I knew I knew one of one of them and
You know,
I knew I knew one of one of them and he
had
had a
had a he
had a he collapsed
had a he collapsed and
had a he collapsed and landed
had a he collapsed and landed back
had a he collapsed and landed back in
the
the hospital.
had a he collapsed and landed back in
the hospital. And
the hospital. And well,
had a he collapsed and landed back in
the hospital. And well, there
the hospital. And well, there he
had a he collapsed and landed back in
the hospital. And well, there he is
standing
standing there
standing there in
standing there in a
standing there in a straight
standing there in a straight jacket
standing there in a straight jacket and
and
and the
standing there in a straight jacket and
and the doctor
and the doctor says
standing there in a straight jacket and
and the doctor says to
and the doctor says to him,
standing there in a straight jacket and
and the doctor says to him, "I
and the doctor says to him, "I hear
standing there in a straight jacket and
and the doctor says to him, "I hear you
have
have a
have a problem
have a problem with
have a problem with alcohol."
have a problem with alcohol." He
have a problem with alcohol." He says,
"Not
"Not me.
have a problem with alcohol." He says,
"Not me. He's
"Not me. He's standing
have a problem with alcohol." He says,
"Not me. He's standing there
"Not me. He's standing there in
have a problem with alcohol." He says,
"Not me. He's standing there in a
straight
straight jacket.
Not
Not me.
straight jacket.
Not me. No.
So
So by
So by contagion,
So by contagion, by
So by contagion, by education,
So by contagion, by education, by
discovery,
which
which leads
which leads to
which leads to introspection,
which
which leads
which leads to introspection,
which leads to
which leads to awakening
and
and there's
and there's karmic
and there's karmic uh
and there's karmic uh consequences.
As
As we
and there's karmic uh consequences.
As we just
As we just researched,
and there's karmic uh consequences.
As we just researched, how
As we just researched, how long
and there's karmic uh consequences.
As we just researched, how long ago
As we just researched, how long ago was
it
it the
it the energy
it the energy of
it the energy of the
it the energy of the enlightened
it the energy of the enlightened master
was
was picked
it the energy of the enlightened master
was picked up
was picked up in
it the energy of the enlightened master
was picked up in this
was picked up in this uh
it the energy of the enlightened master
was picked up in this uh consciousness
here?
here? What
here? What did
here? What did we
here? What did we say?
here? What did we say? Eight
here? What did we say? Eight lifetimes
ago.
ago. Yeah.
here? What did we say? Eight lifetimes
ago. Yeah. Well,
ago. Yeah. Well, well,
here? What did we say? Eight lifetimes
ago. Yeah. Well, well, they
ago. Yeah. Well, well, they were
probably
probably short
probably short lifetimes.
In
In those
probably short lifetimes.
In those days,
In those days, hardly
probably short lifetimes.
In those days, hardly anybody
In those days, hardly anybody lived
probably short lifetimes.
In those days, hardly anybody lived past
30.
30. 35.
40,
40, you're
30. 35.
40, you're an
40, you're an old
30. 35.
40, you're an old man.
40, you're an old man. The
30. 35.
40, you're an old man. The days
40, you're an old man. The days of
ancient
ancient Rome,
ancient Rome, I
ancient Rome, I don't
ancient Rome, I don't think
ancient Rome, I don't think anybody
ancient Rome, I don't think anybody got
to
to 40.
ancient Rome, I don't think anybody got
to 40. If
to 40. If you
ancient Rome, I don't think anybody got
to 40. If you weren't
to 40. If you weren't dead
ancient Rome, I don't think anybody got
to 40. If you weren't dead by
to 40. If you weren't dead by 35,
ancient Rome, I don't think anybody got
to 40. If you weren't dead by 35, you
were
were probably
were probably a
were probably a wimp
supposed
supposed to
were probably a wimp
supposed to be
supposed to be out
were probably a wimp
supposed to be out there
supposed to be out there with
were probably a wimp
supposed to be out there with swords
supposed to be out there with swords and
killing
killing and
killing and being
killing and being killed
killing and being killed and
all right.
Now
Now the
Now the whole
Now the whole situation
Now the whole situation is
Now the whole situation is precipitated
is
is is
Now the whole situation is precipitated
is is exhilarated
is is exhilarated by
Now the whole situation is precipitated
is is exhilarated by devotion,
is is exhilarated by devotion, by
prayer,
prayer, by
prayer, by supplication
prayer, by supplication and
prayer, by supplication and by
dedication.
dedication. So
prayer, by supplication and by
dedication. So those
dedication. So those things
prayer, by supplication and by
dedication. So those things are
very
very powerful.
very powerful. You
very powerful. You know,
very powerful. You know, you
very powerful. You know, you say
when
when you
very powerful. You know, you say
when you pray
when you pray to
very powerful. You know, you say
when you pray to God
when you pray to God for
very powerful. You know, you say
when you pray to God for enlightenment,
I
I pray
I pray to
I pray to be
I pray to be uh
I pray to be uh thy
I pray to be uh thy servant.
I pray to be uh thy servant. And
I pray to be uh thy servant. And I
always
always pray
I pray to be uh thy servant. And I
always pray to
always pray to be
I pray to be uh thy servant. And I
always pray to be a
always pray to be a servant
I pray to be uh thy servant. And I
always pray to be a servant of
always pray to be a servant of God,
I pray to be uh thy servant. And I
always pray to be a servant of God, to
serve
serve God's
serve God's self
serve God's self and
serve God's self and fellow
serve God's self and fellow man.
serve God's self and fellow man. To
serve
serve thee,
serve God's self and fellow man. To
serve thee, oh
serve thee, oh Lord,
that
that which
that which is
that which is called
that which is called the
that which is called the self
that which is called the self and
that which is called the self and my
fellow
fellow man.
that which is called the self and my
fellow man. And
fellow man. And by
that which is called the self and my
fellow man. And by becoming
fellow man. And by becoming all
that which is called the self and my
fellow man. And by becoming all that
fellow man. And by becoming all that you
can
can become,
can become, you
can become, you automatically
can become, you automatically serve
can become, you automatically serve your
fellow
fellow man.
Automatically
Automatically serve
Automatically serve your
Automatically serve your fellow
Automatically serve your fellow man.
Automatically serve your fellow man. You
become
become a
Automatically serve your fellow man. You
become a living
become a living example,
Automatically serve your fellow man. You
become a living example, living
demonstration.
demonstration. And
demonstration. And we
demonstration. And we influence
demonstration. And we influence other
people
people by
demonstration. And we influence other
people by that
people by that which
demonstration. And we influence other
people by that which we
people by that which we have
demonstration. And we influence other
people by that which we have become,
people by that which we have become, not
what,
what, not
what, not what
what, not what we
what, not what we do,
not
not what
what, not what we do,
not what we
not what we say,
what, not what we do,
not what we say, but
not what we say, but by
what, not what we do,
not what we say, but by that
not what we say, but by that which
what, not what we do,
not what we say, but by that which we
have
have become.
have become. Silently
have become. Silently against
have become. Silently against that
have become. Silently against that there
is
is no
have become. Silently against that there
is no defense.
If
If you
If you begin
If you begin talking,
If you begin talking, people
If you begin talking, people can
If you begin talking, people can argue
with
with you.
It's
It's best
It's best to
It's best to just
It's best to just drop
It's best to just drop the
It's best to just drop the teddy
It's best to just drop the teddy bears
and
and say
It's best to just drop the teddy bears
and say nothing.
Actions
Actions speak
Actions speak louder
Actions speak louder than
Actions speak louder than words.
Actions speak louder than words. Huh?
Actions speak louder than words. Huh? So
by
by that
Actions speak louder than words. Huh? So
by that which
by that which we
Actions speak louder than words. Huh? So
by that which we have
by that which we have become,
Actions speak louder than words. Huh? So
by that which we have become, we
by that which we have become, we are
saying
saying to
saying to people,
you
you know,
saying to people,
you know, the
you know, the teddy
saying to people,
you know, the teddy bear
you know, the teddy bear is
saying to people,
you know, the teddy bear is saying,
"Look
"Look to
"Look to your
"Look to your heart.
"Look to your heart. Look
"Look to your heart. Look to
"Look to your heart. Look to your
"Look to your heart. Look to your heart.
Look
Look to
"Look to your heart. Look to your heart.
Look to your
Look to your heart."
"Look to your heart. Look to your heart.
Look to your heart." That's
Look to your heart." That's what
"Look to your heart. Look to your heart.
Look to your heart." That's what the
teddy
teddy bear
teddy bear is
teddy bear is saying.
teddy bear is saying. Once
teddy bear is saying. Once you
teddy bear is saying. Once you look
teddy bear is saying. Once you look to
your
your heart,
teddy bear is saying. Once you look to
your heart, you
your heart, you can't
teddy bear is saying. Once you look to
your heart, you can't kill
your heart, you can't kill people
anymore.
anymore. So
anymore. So one
anymore. So one thing
anymore. So one thing the
anymore. So one thing the warrior
anymore. So one thing the warrior does
is
is forbid
listening
listening to
listening to the
listening to the heart.
listening to the heart. The
listening to the heart. The Japanese
cruel
cruel and
listening to the heart. The Japanese
cruel and savage
cruel and savage and
listening to the heart. The Japanese
cruel and savage and sadistic.
cruel and savage and sadistic. They
weren't
weren't allowed
weren't allowed to
weren't allowed to show
weren't allowed to show the
weren't allowed to show the slightest
kindness.
kindness. Any
weren't allowed to show the slightest
kindness. Any kindness
kindness. Any kindness towards
weren't allowed to show the slightest
kindness. Any kindness towards the
prisoner
prisoner would
prisoner would get
prisoner would get you
prisoner would get you killed.
So
So the
prisoner would get you killed.
So the guard,
So the guard, if
prisoner would get you killed.
So the guard, if you
that
that a
that a kind
that a kind gesture
that a kind gesture towards
that a kind gesture towards the
prisoner,
prisoner, the
that a kind gesture towards the
prisoner, the guard
prisoner, the guard got
that a kind gesture towards the
prisoner, the guard got killed.
Any
Any kindness
Any kindness is
Any kindness is designed
Any kindness is designed as
Any kindness is designed as weakness.
And
And we
Any kindness is designed as weakness.
And we hear
And we hear that
Any kindness is designed as weakness.
And we hear that in
And we hear that in today's
uh
uh war
uh war is
uh war is any
uh war is any kindness
uh war is any kindness is
uh war is any kindness is considered
uh war is any kindness is considered a
weakness
weakness and
uh war is any kindness is considered a
weakness and non-masculine.
weakness and non-masculine. So
uh war is any kindness is considered a
weakness and non-masculine. So such
excessiveness
excessiveness comes
excessiveness comes aart
excessiveness comes aart through
doubting
doubting one's
excessiveness comes aart through
doubting one's own
doubting one's own adequacy
excessiveness comes aart through
doubting one's own adequacy especially
one's
one's masculinity.
If
If your
one's masculinity.
If your masculinity
If your masculinity is
one's masculinity.
If your masculinity is very
If your masculinity is very fragile
everything
everything is
everything is an
everything is an affront
everything is an affront to
everything is an affront to your
masculinity.
If
If your
If your sense
If your sense of
If your sense of adequacy,
not
not masculinity,
If your sense of adequacy,
not masculinity, but
not masculinity, but adequacy
is
is strong,
is strong, nothing
is strong, nothing challenges
is strong, nothing challenges you.
Nothing
Nothing challenges
is strong, nothing challenges you.
Nothing challenges you.
People
People have
People have the
People have the right
People have the right to
People have the right to be
People have the right to be wrong.
I
I can
People have the right to be wrong.
I can remember
I can remember one
People have the right to be wrong.
I can remember one political
I can remember one political figure
People have the right to be wrong.
I can remember one political figure who
is
is no
is no longer
is no longer important
is no longer important and
is no longer important and he
is no longer important and he seemed
is no longer important and he seemed to
be
be completely
is no longer important and he seemed to
be completely unfased
be completely unfased by
is no longer important and he seemed to
be completely unfased by anything
be completely unfased by anything that
the
the critics
the critics said
the critics said about
the critics said about him.
the critics said about him. He
the critics said about him. He said,
"Well,
"Well, you
the critics said about him. He said,
"Well, you can't
"Well, you can't really
the critics said about him. He said,
"Well, you can't really pay
"Well, you can't really pay much
attention
attention to
attention to them."
And
And I
attention to them."
And I used
And I used to
attention to them."
And I used to just
And I used to just watch
attention to them."
And I used to just watch him
And I used to just watch him and
attention to them."
And I used to just watch him and marvel.
Not
Not that
Not that I
Not that I was
Not that I was agreeing
Not that I was agreeing with
Not that I was agreeing with what
Not that I was agreeing with what he
Not that I was agreeing with what he was
saying,
saying, but
Not that I was agreeing with what he was
saying, but I
saying, but I said,
Not that I was agreeing with what he was
saying, but I said, "That
saying, but I said, "That must
Not that I was agreeing with what he was
saying, but I said, "That must be
saying, but I said, "That must be a
marvelous
marvelous state
marvelous state of
marvelous state of mind."
marvelous state of mind." You
marvelous state of mind." You know what
I
I mean?
marvelous state of mind." You know what
I mean? Here
I mean? Here he's
marvelous state of mind." You know what
I mean? Here he's doing
I mean? Here he's doing something
marvelous state of mind." You know what
I mean? Here he's doing something very
unpopular
unpopular with
unpopular with at
unpopular with at least
unpopular with at least half
unpopular with at least half the
American
American population
unpopular with at least half the
American population and
American population and he's
unpopular with at least half the
American population and he's saying,
"Oh,
"Oh, you
"Oh, you can't
"Oh, you can't really
"Oh, you can't really listen
"Oh, you can't really listen to
"Oh, you can't really listen to you
can't
can't really
"Oh, you can't really listen to you
can't really give
can't really give them
"Oh, you can't really listen to you
can't really give them much
can't really give them much time
"Oh, you can't really listen to you
can't really give them much time or
attention.
Just
Just didn't
attention.
Just didn't phase
Just didn't phase him
attention.
Just didn't phase him at
Just didn't phase him at all."
All
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, through
All right. So, through devotion,
All right. So, through devotion, you
develop
develop a
All right. So, through devotion, you
develop a persistence
develop a persistence and
All right. So, through devotion, you
develop a persistence and a
develop a persistence and a pursuit
All right. So, through devotion, you
develop a persistence and a pursuit of
the
the truth.
And
And uh
the truth.
And uh the
And uh the only
the truth.
And uh the only desire
And uh the only desire you
the truth.
And uh the only desire you have
And uh the only desire you have left
the truth.
And uh the only desire you have left is
a
a desire
a desire to
a desire to serve
a desire to serve God,
a desire to serve God, your
a desire to serve God, your fellow
a desire to serve God, your fellow man,
and
and yourself
a desire to serve God, your fellow man,
and yourself with
and yourself with a
a desire to serve God, your fellow man,
and yourself with a capital
and yourself with a capital S.
a desire to serve God, your fellow man,
and yourself with a capital S. And
and yourself with a capital S. And you
do
do this
do this through
do this through meditation,
contemplation,
contemplation, and
do this through meditation,
contemplation, and reflection.
So
So these
So these are
So these are all
So these are all subjects
So these are all subjects in
So these are all subjects in and
So these are all subjects in and of
themsel,
themsel, the
So these are all subjects in and of
themsel, the various
themsel, the various yogas,
So these are all subjects in and of
themsel, the various yogas, the
themsel, the various yogas, the various
meditation
meditation techniques.
meditation techniques. And
meditation techniques. And as
meditation techniques. And as I
meditation techniques. And as I say,
meditation techniques. And as I say, I
sat
sat in
meditation techniques. And as I say, I
sat in silent
sat in silent meditation
meditation techniques. And as I say, I
sat in silent meditation for
sat in silent meditation for uh
meditation techniques. And as I say, I
sat in silent meditation for uh years,
which
which not
which not everybody
which not everybody can
which not everybody can do,
which not everybody can do, you
which not everybody can do, you know,
which not everybody can do, you know, in
the
the middle
which not everybody can do, you know, in
the middle of
the middle of busy
which not everybody can do, you know, in
the middle of busy place.
the middle of busy place. You
which not everybody can do, you know, in
the middle of busy place. You just
the middle of busy place. You just don't
eat
eat much
eat much and
eat much and you
eat much and you don't
eat much and you don't need
eat much and you don't need much
eat much and you don't need much money
and
and don't
eat much and you don't need much money
and don't go
and don't go anywhere.
eat much and you don't need much money
and don't go anywhere. So
and don't go anywhere. So you
eat much and you don't need much money
and don't go anywhere. So you don't
and don't go anywhere. So you don't need
gas
gas and
gas and you
gas and you just
gas and you just meditate.
gas and you just meditate. Keep
gas and you just meditate. Keep away
from
from the
gas and you just meditate. Keep away
from the black
from the black go
gas and you just meditate. Keep away
from the black go spiders.
from the black go spiders. That's
gas and you just meditate. Keep away
from the black go spiders. That's all.
When
When not
When not meditating,
When not meditating, there's
When not meditating, there's a
When not meditating, there's a you
When not meditating, there's a you begin
to
to precipitate
When not meditating, there's a you begin
to precipitate a
to precipitate a a
When not meditating, there's a you begin
to precipitate a a reflective
uh
uh contemplation.
So
So this
uh contemplation.
So this reflective
So this reflective nature
uh contemplation.
So this reflective nature now,
So this reflective nature now, even
though
though you're
though you're walking
though you're walking about
though you're walking about in
though you're walking about in the
though you're walking about in the world
and
and doing
though you're walking about in the world
and doing one
and doing one thing
though you're walking about in the world
and doing one thing or
and doing one thing or another,
though you're walking about in the world
and doing one thing or another, you
and doing one thing or another, you walk
into
into the
into the supermarket
into the supermarket and
into the supermarket and you're
into the supermarket and you're quite
aware
aware of
into the supermarket and you're quite
aware of the
aware of the friendliness
into the supermarket and you're quite
aware of the friendliness of
aware of the friendliness of the
into the supermarket and you're quite
aware of the friendliness of the clerk,
of
of the
of the neediness
of the neediness of
of the neediness of various
of the neediness of various people.
You're
You're pretty
of the neediness of various people.
You're pretty much
You're pretty much aware
of the neediness of various people.
You're pretty much aware of
You're pretty much aware of where
everybody
everybody is
everybody is at.
And
And uh
everybody is at.
And uh I
And uh I I've
everybody is at.
And uh I I've noticed
And uh I I've noticed and
everybody is at.
And uh I I've noticed and I've
And uh I I've noticed and I've mentioned
before
before in
before in other
before in other lectures
before in other lectures that
before in other lectures that when
before in other lectures that when when
you
you express
before in other lectures that when when
you express your
you express your gratitude
before in other lectures that when when
you express your gratitude to
you express your gratitude to people
before in other lectures that when when
you express your gratitude to people who
are
are in
are in the
are in the service
are in the service professions,
are in the service professions, you
know,
know, the
are in the service professions, you
know, the packager
know, the packager packaging
are in the service professions, you
know, the packager packaging up
know, the packager packaging up your
things
things in
things in the
things in the supermarket,
things in the supermarket, and
things in the supermarket, and you
things in the supermarket, and you say
to
to them,
things in the supermarket, and you say
to them, "Gee,
to them, "Gee, thanks
things in the supermarket, and you say
to them, "Gee, thanks a
to them, "Gee, thanks a lot.
things in the supermarket, and you say
to them, "Gee, thanks a lot. That's
to them, "Gee, thanks a lot. That's a
terrific
terrific job."
terrific job." They
terrific job." They go,
you
you say
terrific job." They go,
you say to
you say to the
terrific job." They go,
you say to the clerk
you say to the clerk in
terrific job." They go,
you say to the clerk in the
you say to the clerk in the post
terrific job." They go,
you say to the clerk in the post office,
you
you say,
you say, "God,
you say, "God, thank
you say, "God, thank you
you say, "God, thank you so
you say, "God, thank you so much
you say, "God, thank you so much for
taking
taking care
you say, "God, thank you so much for
taking care of
taking care of me."
you say, "God, thank you so much for
taking care of me." They
taking care of me." They go,
Just
Just expressing
Just expressing lovingness
Just expressing lovingness towards
people
people knocks
Just expressing lovingness towards
people knocks them
people knocks them out
Just expressing lovingness towards
people knocks them out because
people knocks them out because they're
just
just not
just not used
just not used to
just not used to it.
just not used to it. And
just not used to it. And people
just not used to it. And people are
instead
instead critical.
just not used to it. And people are
instead critical. Why
instead critical. Why don't
just not used to it. And people are
instead critical. Why don't you
instead critical. Why don't you wrap
that
that a
that a little
that a little faster
that a little faster and
that a little faster and I
that a little faster and I think
that a little faster and I think you
that a little faster and I think you got
it
it all
that a little faster and I think you got
it all wrong
it all wrong and
that a little faster and I think you got
it all wrong and this
it all wrong and this and
that a little faster and I think you got
it all wrong and this and that.
it all wrong and this and that. So
people
people are
people are all
people are all on
people are all on guard.
people are all on guard. So
people are all on guard. So when
people are all on guard. So when you
people are all on guard. So when you are
loving
loving towards
people are all on guard. So when you are
loving towards them,
uh
uh they
uh they drop
uh they drop their
uh they drop their guard
uh they drop their guard and
uh they drop their guard and you'll
uh they drop their guard and you'll see
great
great gratitude.
uh they drop their guard and you'll see
great gratitude. And
great gratitude. And I've
uh they drop their guard and you'll see
great gratitude. And I've done
great gratitude. And I've done it
uh they drop their guard and you'll see
great gratitude. And I've done it for
years
years with
years with clerks,
years with clerks, you
years with clerks, you know,
years with clerks, you know, who
years with clerks, you know, who are
busy
busy running
years with clerks, you know, who are
busy running their
busy running their cash
years with clerks, you know, who are
busy running their cash register
busy running their cash register and
years with clerks, you know, who are
busy running their cash register and you
say,
say, "Gee,
say, "Gee, thank
say, "Gee, thank thanks
say, "Gee, thank thanks a
say, "Gee, thank thanks a lot."
say, "Gee, thank thanks a lot." And
say, "Gee, thank thanks a lot." And they
go,
go, "Huh?
It
It like
It like stops
It like stops them
It like stops them right
It like stops them right in
It like stops them right in their
tracks."
So
So reflection
So reflection becomes
So reflection becomes a
So reflection becomes a kind
So reflection becomes a kind of
So reflection becomes a kind of you
develop
develop a
So reflection becomes a kind of you
develop a contemplative
develop a contemplative lifestyle.
A
A contemplative
A contemplative lifestyle.
A contemplative lifestyle. So
A contemplative lifestyle. So meditation
is
is a
A contemplative lifestyle. So meditation
is a strict
is a strict formality.
It
It is
It is also
It is also an
It is also an informality.
But
But contemplation
It is also an informality.
But contemplation is
But contemplation is really
It is also an informality.
But contemplation is really a
But contemplation is really a lifestyle.
So
So meditation
So meditation formally
So meditation formally sitting
So meditation formally sitting down
meditation
meditation for
So meditation formally sitting down
meditation for instance
meditation for instance uh
So meditation formally sitting down
meditation for instance uh is
meditation for instance uh is limited
and
and the
and the reason
and the reason people
and the reason people give
and the reason people give it
and the reason people give it up
and the reason people give it up sooner
or
or later
and the reason people give it up sooner
or later is
or later is they
and the reason people give it up sooner
or later is they don't
or later is they don't have
and the reason people give it up sooner
or later is they don't have the
or later is they don't have the time.
and the reason people give it up sooner
or later is they don't have the time. So
uh
uh so
uh so you
uh so you meditate
uh so you meditate regularly,
uh so you meditate regularly, you
uh so you meditate regularly, you take
uh so you meditate regularly, you take a
class
class on
uh so you meditate regularly, you take a
class on meditation
class on meditation and
uh so you meditate regularly, you take a
class on meditation and boy
class on meditation and boy are
uh so you meditate regularly, you take a
class on meditation and boy are you
class on meditation and boy are you ever
regular
regular and
regular and three
regular and three years
regular and three years later
regular and three years later well
you
you had
regular and three years later well
you had to
you had to catch
regular and three years later well
you had to catch the
you had to catch the bus
regular and three years later well
you had to catch the bus every
you had to catch the bus every morning
so
so there
so there goes
so there goes meditation.
But
But contemplation
so there goes meditation.
But contemplation means
But contemplation means uh
so there goes meditation.
But contemplation means uh realizing
But contemplation means uh realizing the
importance
importance of
importance of of
importance of of reflection
importance of of reflection because
reflection
reflection opens
importance of of reflection because
reflection opens the
reflection opens the door
importance of of reflection because
reflection opens the door to
reflection opens the door to the
importance of of reflection because
reflection opens the door to the main
pathway
pathway of
pathway of the
pathway of the mystic
pathway of the mystic because
pathway of the mystic because the
pathway of the mystic because the mystic
arises
arises the
pathway of the mystic because the mystic
arises the knowingness
arises the knowingness of
pathway of the mystic because the mystic
arises the knowingness of the
arises the knowingness of the mystic
arises
when
when when
arises
when when the
when when the barriers
arises
when when the barriers to
when when the barriers to it
arises
when when the barriers to it have
when when the barriers to it have been
removed
and
and as
removed
and as I've
and as I've said
removed
and as I've said in
and as I've said in the
removed
and as I've said in the previous
lectures
lectures is
lectures is a
lectures is a very
lectures is a very yin
lectures is a very yin position
lectures is a very yin position a
lectures is a very yin position a very
yin
yin position
lectures is a very yin position a very
yin position of
yin position of allowing
lectures is a very yin position a very
yin position of allowing this
and
and you
and you ask
and you ask the
and you ask the Holy
and you ask the Holy Spirit,
and you ask the Holy Spirit, you
and you ask the Holy Spirit, you ask
almighty
almighty God,
and you ask the Holy Spirit, you ask
almighty God, Jesus,
almighty God, Jesus, whoever
um
um for
um for an
um for an understanding
um for an understanding of
um for an understanding of a
um for an understanding of a certain
thing.
thing. You
um for an understanding of a certain
thing. You know,
thing. You know, I
um for an understanding of a certain
thing. You know, I I
thing. You know, I I pray
um for an understanding of a certain
thing. You know, I I pray to
thing. You know, I I pray to thee,
um for an understanding of a certain
thing. You know, I I pray to thee, oh
Lord,
Lord, to
Lord, to understand
Lord, to understand this
Lord, to understand this differently.
And
And then
Lord, to understand this differently.
And then you
And then you let
Lord, to understand this differently.
And then you let it
And then you let it go.
Lord, to understand this differently.
And then you let it go. You
And then you let it go. You don't
Lord, to understand this differently.
And then you let it go. You don't um
tell
tell God
tell God how
tell God how you
tell God how you want
tell God how you want it
tell God how you want it handled.
tell God how you want it handled. It's
called
called outlining.
And
And you
And you don't
And you don't uh
And you don't uh so
And you don't uh so you
And you don't uh so you don't
And you don't uh so you don't tell
And you don't uh so you don't tell God
how
how you
And you don't uh so you don't tell God
how you want
how you want it
And you don't uh so you don't tell God
how you want it handled.
how you want it handled. You
And you don't uh so you don't tell God
how you want it handled. You you
how you want it handled. You you turn
And you don't uh so you don't tell God
how you want it handled. You you turn it
over
over to
over to God.
over to God. Sometimes
over to God. Sometimes the
over to God. Sometimes the lesson
over to God. Sometimes the lesson is
over to God. Sometimes the lesson is it
doesn't
doesn't work
over to God. Sometimes the lesson is it
doesn't work out.
Remember
Remember my
Remember my grandfather
Remember my grandfather used
Remember my grandfather used to
Remember my grandfather used to buy
teeth
teeth mail
Remember my grandfather used to buy
teeth mail order.
He
He wouldn't
He wouldn't buy
He wouldn't buy them.
He wouldn't buy them. The
He wouldn't buy them. The dentists
He wouldn't buy them. The dentists were
too
too expensive.
He wouldn't buy them. The dentists were
too expensive. You
too expensive. You could
He wouldn't buy them. The dentists were
too expensive. You could get
too expensive. You could get them
He wouldn't buy them. The dentists were
too expensive. You could get them for
too expensive. You could get them for a
mail
mail order.
mail order. I
mail order. I think
mail order. I think they're
mail order. I think they're $2.50.
mail order. I think they're $2.50. So
what
what you
mail order. I think they're $2.50. So
what you did
what you did is
mail order. I think they're $2.50. So
what you did is you
what you did is you bit
mail order. I think they're $2.50. So
what you did is you bit down
what you did is you bit down on
mail order. I think they're $2.50. So
what you did is you bit down on some
paper
paper and
paper and you
paper and you mailed
paper and you mailed this
paper and you mailed this to
paper and you mailed this to this
company
company and
paper and you mailed this to this
company and they
company and they mailed
paper and you mailed this to this
company and they mailed you
company and they mailed you false
paper and you mailed this to this
company and they mailed you false teeth
and
and then
and then he
and then he would
and then he would whittle
and then he would whittle them.
and then he would whittle them. So
and then he would whittle them. So I
spent
spent my
and then he would whittle them. So I
spent my my
spent my my his
and then he would whittle them. So I
spent my my his youth
spent my my his youth watching
and then he would whittle them. So I
spent my my his youth watching grandpa
whiddling
whiddling his
whiddling his his
whiddling his his false
whiddling his his false teeth.
whiddling his his false teeth. He
whiddling his his false teeth. He put
him
him in.
Get
Get him
Get him just
Get him just right.
Well,
Well, he
Get him just right.
Well, he did.
Well, he did. He
Get him just right.
Well, he did. He would
Well, he did. He would whittle
Get him just right.
Well, he did. He would whittle his
Well, he did. He would whittle his teeth
and
and be
and be like,
and be like, "Right."
I
I don't
and be like, "Right."
I don't know
I don't know what
and be like, "Right."
I don't know what brought
I don't know what brought that
and be like, "Right."
I don't know what brought that up,
I don't know what brought that up, but
anyway.
I
I don't
anyway.
I don't know
I don't know what
anyway.
I don't know what whittling
I don't know what whittling your
anyway.
I don't know what whittling your false
teeth
teeth had
teeth had to
teeth had to do
teeth had to do with
teeth had to do with anything,
teeth had to do with anything, but
I
I don't
teeth had to do with anything, but
I don't ask
I don't ask God
teeth had to do with anything, but
I don't ask God why
I don't ask God why he
teeth had to do with anything, but
I don't ask God why he says
I don't ask God why he says other
things.
It'll
It'll be
things.
It'll be revealed
lying
lying in
lying in bed
lying in bed and
lying in bed and I'll
lying in bed and I'll get
lying in bed and I'll get ah
lying in bed and I'll get ah I
lying in bed and I'll get ah I see
lying in bed and I'll get ah I see why
grandpa
grandpa in
lying in bed and I'll get ah I see why
grandpa in his
grandpa in his false
lying in bed and I'll get ah I see why
grandpa in his false teeth
grandpa in his false teeth came
lying in bed and I'll get ah I see why
grandpa in his false teeth came up.
So
So this
So this is
So this is a
So this is a positionality
you're
you're where
So this is a positionality
you're where your
you're where your life
So this is a positionality
you're where your life becomes
you're where your life becomes a
supplication
supplication and
supplication and as
supplication and as I've
supplication and as I've uh
supplication and as I've uh said
supplication and as I've uh said your
life
life becomes
supplication and as I've uh said your
life becomes the
life becomes the prayer.
supplication and as I've uh said your
life becomes the prayer. It's
life becomes the prayer. It's not
supplication and as I've uh said your
life becomes the prayer. It's not what
you
you do
you do and
you do and not
you do and not what
you do and not what you
you do and not what you have
you do and not what you have it's
you do and not what you have it's what
you
you have
you do and not what you have it's what
you have become.
All
All of
All of all
All of all of
All of all of nature
All of all of nature knows
All of all of nature knows who
All of all of nature knows who you
All of all of nature knows who you are.
All
All of
All of all of nature knows who you are.
All of nature
All of nature knows
All of all of nature knows who you are.
All of nature knows what
All of nature knows what you
All of all of nature knows who you are.
All of nature knows what you are
All of nature knows what you are and
All of all of nature knows who you are.
All of nature knows what you are and the
trees
trees know.
trees know. You
trees know. You walk
trees know. You walk through
trees know. You walk through the
trees know. You walk through the woods,
all
all living
trees know. You walk through the woods,
all living things
all living things know
trees know. You walk through the woods,
all living things know what
all living things know what you
trees know. You walk through the woods,
all living things know what you are.
all living things know what you are. A
silent
silent awareness
that
that that
silent awareness
that that which
that that which is
silent awareness
that that which is close
that that which is close to
silent awareness
that that which is close to the
that that which is close to the divinity
is
is walking
is walking by
is walking by and
is walking by and they
is walking by and they know
is walking by and they know it.
All
All living
is walking by and they know it.
All living things
All living things realize
is walking by and they know it.
All living things realize that
All living things realize that those
is walking by and they know it.
All living things realize that those who
have
have aligned
have aligned with
have aligned with God
have aligned with God are
have aligned with God are aligned
have aligned with God are aligned with
life
life and
have aligned with God are aligned with
life and the
life and the tree
have aligned with God are aligned with
life and the tree leans
life and the tree leans forward
have aligned with God are aligned with
life and the tree leans forward and
life and the tree leans forward and then
goes
goes back
goes back when
goes back when that
goes back when that which
goes back when that which hate
goes back when that which hate is
hateful
hateful of
goes back when that which hate is
hateful of life.
hateful of life. Uhhuh.
I
I once
I once went
I once went into
I once went into an
I once went into an advanced
I once went into an advanced state
I once went into an advanced state of
consciousness
consciousness in
I once went into an advanced state of
consciousness in which
consciousness in which all
I once went into an advanced state of
consciousness in which all that
consciousness in which all that became
almost
almost psychedelic.
almost psychedelic. You
almost psychedelic. You walk
almost psychedelic. You walk through
almost psychedelic. You walk through the
woods
woods and
almost psychedelic. You walk through the
woods and you
woods and you could
almost psychedelic. You walk through the
woods and you could see
woods and you could see the
almost psychedelic. You walk through the
woods and you could see the lighting
woods and you could see the lighting up
of
of the
of the flowers
of the flowers and
of the flowers and the
of the flowers and the lighting
of the flowers and the lighting up
of the flowers and the lighting up of
the
the shrubs
of the flowers and the lighting up of
the shrubs and
the shrubs and the
of the flowers and the lighting up of
the shrubs and the lighting
the shrubs and the lighting up
of the flowers and the lighting up of
the shrubs and the lighting up of
things.
Oh
Oh god.
Your
Your life
Your life then
Your life then is
Your life then is a
Your life then is a supplication
Your life then is a supplication in
which
which you
Your life then is a supplication in
which you are
which you are constantly
Your life then is a supplication in
which you are constantly asking
which you are constantly asking by
Your life then is a supplication in
which you are constantly asking by the
mudra
mudra by
mudra by that
mudra by that which
mudra by that which you
mudra by that which you are.
mudra by that which you are. You're
constantly
constantly asking
mudra by that which you are. You're
constantly asking and
constantly asking and opening
mudra by that which you are. You're
constantly asking and opening to
constantly asking and opening to the
grace
grace of
grace of God.
grace of God. Your
grace of God. Your openness
grace of God. Your openness then
grace of God. Your openness then invites
revelation
revelation to
grace of God. Your openness then invites
revelation to occur.
revelation to occur. Uhhuh.
The
The aesthetic
becomes
becomes constantly
The aesthetic
becomes constantly attractive.
The
The best
The best propensity
The best propensity towards
The best propensity towards spirituality
and
and later
The best propensity towards spirituality
and later life
and later life is
The best propensity towards spirituality
and later life is I've
and later life is I've told
The best propensity towards spirituality
and later life is I've told many
and later life is I've told many a
mother
mother is
mother is the
mother is the appreciation
mother is the appreciation for
mother is the appreciation for beauty
mother is the appreciation for beauty in
all
all of
mother is the appreciation for beauty in
all of its
all of its form.
mother is the appreciation for beauty in
all of its form. uh
all of its form. uh ballet
mother is the appreciation for beauty in
all of its form. uh ballet aesthetics
beauty
beauty Andrea
beauty Andrea Bachelli
uh
uh nature
the
the grace
the grace and
the grace and aesthetic
the grace and aesthetic beauty
of
of all
the grace and aesthetic beauty
of all that
of all that exists
eventually
eventually becomes
eventually becomes a
eventually becomes a constant
eventually becomes a constant awareness
one's
one's aware
there
there is
there is an
there is an intrinsic
there is an intrinsic beauty
there is an intrinsic beauty to
everything
everything that
there is an intrinsic beauty to
everything that exists
the
the funny
the funny shoes
the funny shoes he's
the funny shoes he's got
the funny shoes he's got on
See?
See? And
the funny shoes he's got on
See? And see
See? And see her
the funny shoes he's got on
See? And see her shoes.
See? And see her shoes. How
the funny shoes he's got on
See? And see her shoes. How cute
See? And see her shoes. How cute they
are.
are. And
are. And look
are. And look at
are. And look at these.
are. And look at these. These
are. And look at these. These are
are. And look at these. These are like
boots
boots or
are. And look at these. These are like
boots or something.
boots or something. And
are. And look at these. These are like
boots or something. And there's
wonderful
wonderful shoes.
Super
Super shoes.
wonderful shoes.
Super shoes. Those
Super shoes. Those are
wonderful shoes.
Super shoes. Those are Dr.
Super shoes. Those are Dr. Whatcham
calls,
calls, aren't
calls, aren't they?
Less
Less than
calls, aren't they?
Less than 20
Less than 20 bucks.
calls, aren't they?
Less than 20 bucks. I
Less than 20 bucks. I know
calls, aren't they?
Less than 20 bucks. I know that.
I
I spend
I spend more
I spend more than
I spend more than 20
I spend more than 20 bucks
I spend more than 20 bucks for
I spend more than 20 bucks for shoes.
No.
No. Too
I spend more than 20 bucks for shoes.
No. Too cheap.
No. Too cheap. Hay
I spend more than 20 bucks for shoes.
No. Too cheap. Hay band.
No. Too cheap. Hay band. You
I spend more than 20 bucks for shoes.
No. Too cheap. Hay band. You get
No. Too cheap. Hay band. You get them
I spend more than 20 bucks for shoes.
No. Too cheap. Hay band. You get them by
mail
mail order.
perfect
perfect shoes.
You
You begin
You begin to
You begin to see
You begin to see the
You begin to see the beauty
You begin to see the beauty and
You begin to see the beauty and the
aesthetic
aesthetic pleasure
You begin to see the beauty and the
aesthetic pleasure of
aesthetic pleasure of all
You begin to see the beauty and the
aesthetic pleasure of all that
aesthetic pleasure of all that exists.
Just
Just the
Just the way
Just the way people
Just the way people are
Just the way people are dressed
Just the way people are dressed and
Just the way people are dressed and the
way
way they
Just the way people are dressed and the
way they do
way they do their
Just the way people are dressed and the
way they do their hair
way they do their hair and
Just the way people are dressed and the
way they do their hair and the
way they do their hair and the way
Just the way people are dressed and the
way they do their hair and the way they
sit.
sit. And
sit. And each
sit. And each one
sit. And each one has
sit. And each one has their
sit. And each one has their own
sit. And each one has their own unique
way
way of
sit. And each one has their own unique
way of being
way of being in
sit. And each one has their own unique
way of being in the
way of being in the world.
Nobody's
Nobody's like
Nobody's like you
Nobody's like you except
Nobody's like you except you.
Nobody's like you except you. There
anybody
anybody looks
Nobody's like you except you. There
anybody looks or
anybody looks or is
Nobody's like you except you. There
anybody looks or is like
anybody looks or is like you
Nobody's like you except you. There
anybody looks or is like you anybody
else
else like
else like you
else like you either.
There's
There's nobody
else like you either.
There's nobody like
There's nobody like you.
else like you either.
There's nobody like you. There's
There's nobody like you. There's nobody
like
like any
like any one
like any one of
like any one of you
like any one of you is
like any one of you is just
like any one of you is just stunningly
uniquely
uniquely beautiful
like any one of you is just stunningly
uniquely beautiful as
uniquely beautiful as you
like any one of you is just stunningly
uniquely beautiful as you are.
uniquely beautiful as you are. See,
that's
that's why
that's why we're
that's why we're glad
that's why we're glad to
that's why we're glad to see
that's why we're glad to see somebody
that's why we're glad to see somebody we
haven't
haven't seen
that's why we're glad to see somebody we
haven't seen for
haven't seen for years.
that's why we're glad to see somebody we
haven't seen for years. I
haven't seen for years. I haven't
that's why we're glad to see somebody we
haven't seen for years. I haven't seen
some
some of
some of these
some of these people
some of these people from
some of these people from Korea
some of these people from Korea for
years.
years. And
some of these people from Korea for
years. And then
years. And then suddenly
some of these people from Korea for
years. And then suddenly they
years. And then suddenly they show
some of these people from Korea for
years. And then suddenly they show up
and
and another
and another person
and another person I
and another person I haven't
and another person I haven't seen
and another person I haven't seen for
years.
years. There's
and another person I haven't seen for
years. There's a
years. There's a joy
and another person I haven't seen for
years. There's a joy a
years. There's a joy a joy
and another person I haven't seen for
years. There's a joy a joy at
years. There's a joy a joy at what?
and another person I haven't seen for
years. There's a joy a joy at what? At
the
the other
the other the
the other the other's
the other the other's existence.
It's
It's their
the other the other's existence.
It's their existence.
It's their existence. They're
the other the other's existence.
It's their existence. They're not
It's their existence. They're not doing
something
something to
something to please
something to please you.
something to please you. They're
something to please you. They're not
giving
giving you
something to please you. They're not
giving you cookies.
giving you cookies. They're
something to please you. They're not
giving you cookies. They're not
giving you cookies. They're not shining
your
your shoes.
your shoes. They're
your shoes. They're not
your shoes. They're not giving
your shoes. They're not giving you
your shoes. They're not giving you a
haircut
haircut just
your shoes. They're not giving you a
haircut just that
haircut just that they
your shoes. They're not giving you a
haircut just that they are.
haircut just that they are. Isn't
your shoes. They're not giving you a
haircut just that they are. Isn't that
right?
right? There's
right? There's a
right? There's a lot
right? There's a lot of
right? There's a lot of people
right? There's a lot of people you
right? There's a lot of people you just
feel
feel good
right? There's a lot of people you just
feel good because
feel good because they
right? There's a lot of people you just
feel good because they are.
So
So you
So you lighten
So you lighten up
So you lighten up the
So you lighten up the world
So you lighten up the world by
So you lighten up the world by that
which
which you
So you lighten up the world by that
which you have
which you have become.
So you lighten up the world by that
which you have become. Therefore,
your
your own
your own spiritual
your own spiritual progress
your own spiritual progress serves
not
not only
your own spiritual progress serves
not only yourself
not only yourself as
your own spiritual progress serves
not only yourself as far
not only yourself as far as
your own spiritual progress serves
not only yourself as far as reaching
not only yourself as far as reaching for
enlightenment,
enlightenment, but
enlightenment, but it
enlightenment, but it serves
enlightenment, but it serves God
enlightenment, but it serves God and
your
your fellow
enlightenment, but it serves God and
your fellow man.
your fellow man. So
enlightenment, but it serves God and
your fellow man. So the
your fellow man. So the purpose
enlightenment, but it serves God and
your fellow man. So the purpose of
spiritual
spiritual work
spiritual work then
spiritual work then is
spiritual work then is to
spiritual work then is to serve
spiritual work then is to serve God
yourself
yourself and
spiritual work then is to serve God
yourself and your
yourself and your fellow
spiritual work then is to serve God
yourself and your fellow men.
yourself and your fellow men. Gloria
spiritual work then is to serve God
yourself and your fellow men. Gloria and
excelsius.
Glory
Glory be
excelsius.
Glory be to
Glory be to thee,
excelsius.
Glory be to thee, oh
Glory be to thee, oh Lord,
excelsius.
Glory be to thee, oh Lord, that
Glory be to thee, oh Lord, that my
existence
existence may
existence may be
existence may be of
existence may be of service
existence may be of service to
existence may be of service to thee.
All
All right.
This
This lends
This lends a
This lends a certain
This lends a certain grace
This lends a certain grace to
This lends a certain grace to one's
presence
without
without being
without being aware
without being aware of
without being aware of it.
without being aware of it. There
without being aware of it. There are
some
some people
without being aware of it. There are
some people who
some people who around
without being aware of it. There are
some people who around whom
some people who around whom we
without being aware of it. There are
some people who around whom we somehow
feel
feel better
feel better and
feel better and then
feel better and then there's
feel better and then there's other
people
people around
feel better and then there's other
people around whom
people around whom we
feel better and then there's other
people around whom we feel
people around whom we feel worse.
So
So you
So you try
So you try to
So you try to become
So you try to become one
So you try to become one of
So you try to become one of the
So you try to become one of the people
that
that feel
So you try to become one of the people
that feel better
that feel better around.
All
All right.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.
Halle.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu