How do you like semiotics?
Isn't there a nice new word?
Anybody know what semiotics means?
At least we've got an audience.
That's the science of structure of language, yeah?
Languaging and the science of labels and structure.
What is truth?
It depends on language wording.
There's a man who's written a book all about words
and the importance that it plays in politics.
It's whether you call people illegals or undocumented.
Totally changes the picture, yeah?
Think of all the war, political wars that go over.
Are they undocumented or are they illegal?
Well, I solved it very simply.
I said they're both.
They're undocumented illegals.
Then they jump.
Well, therefore, you must be anti-Mexican.
You see how they distort it.
It's got nothing to do with being Mexican.
Nothing to do with being Mexican.
All Americans I know are crazy about them, love them.
We all use them, hang out with them, and chat with them, and love them.
It has nothing to do with being Mexican at all.
It has to do with the fact that as an employer,
you can get into big trouble if you hire them.
That's what it's about.
All you want to know is do they have a green card or not?
Because if they don't, you can get busted.
So semiotics, that means politically,
you play with the words to try and create a different impact.
And I forget the name of the book.
The guy's an advisor to a lot of political groups, I guess,
on how to use a different word.
A different word will give a different inference.
So just your selection of vocabulary already changes the reality
or the seeming reality just by semiotics.
Semiotics is the science of how language,
and vocabulary is structured.
What is truth depends on your own intention,
your dedication, and your humility.
Now realizing that God and truth are one and the same thing,
that God is really the highest truth possible.
If you just take things, calibrate everything in the universe,
and keep following whichever calibrates the highest,
you will end up with God.
So just following truth itself will eventually,
take you to divinity.
Divinity is the ultimate then, and it calibrates at infinity.
So if you follow truth itself, truth itself even just intellectually,
you end up with divinity.
You end up with the obvious things that it is impossible for non-life to create life.
So the materialist is stuck with the fact that life, how does life arise?
Reductionist, semiotics, you cannot get life from non-life.
And people say, well, all the chemicals just fell together and life suddenly happened.
Except that life is of a different dimension.
They're not the same dimension.
So that's mixing levels.
The material non-living matter itself is a different level than life.
So matter cannot be destroyed.
It can only change.
Form life itself cannot be destroyed.
We can't repeat that too often.
Uh, I have permission to ask this.
It is impossible for life to be destroyed.
Resist that is true at the level of infinity.
Resist at the level of infinity.
And thank you.
We've done this many times to confirm because it's a very important understanding.
Life can only change form.
It cannot be destroyed.
Therefore,
at physical,
at physical death where dust returns to dust,
you can't die because death is not a possibility.
You can only change form.
In an infinite universe then,
with no beginning and no end and no intrinsic causality,
the only thing that can happen is it changes form.
So the law of conservation of energy is that energies can only change form.
Law of conservation of matter is that matter can only change form.
The law of conservation of life,
which seems starkly obvious,
is that you cannot destroy life.
It can only change form.
Yeah.
So, you don't have to feel so guilty about swarming the fly.
No.
Whack.
He just leaves his physical body and his etheric body and he doesn't even notice.
The fly doesn't even notice.
Resist.
He goes flying in his etheric body and that's what he experiences as me all along.
So nothing's changed.
Resist.
A couple of times I went out of body.
I'd never even heard of being out of body.
I was out of body and never even heard of it.
Being gravely ill.
Suddenly found myself outside the body.
Never heard of it.
Nothing changed.
I was still me.
I was myself.
I had all my faculties.
I could see, hear.
I could move around in the room.
I could be up in the ceiling looking down at the audience now.
So if I laid down and went out of body,
I could go up there and watch the audience there.
I could go over there.
I could then go over here.
It's very neat.
You don't have to drag your body with you.
And of course a lot of research has been done on this because of its implications for surgery.
And people may have made agreements.
If they go out of body, they'll go up on top of the bookcase there and tell you what's on.
And they come back after the surgery, come back in the body,
and they'll tell you what's on top of the bookcase.
So anyway, death is not a possibility.
You don't get death at zero at all.
You get neutrality at 200.
So the ashes that you return to calibrate at 200,
and your spirit stays the same as whatever it was when you left the world.
So you go to the spirit world where below 200 are the levels of hell.
And did I say that?
That kid who calibrated at the lowest I've ever calibrated anything,
the Green River Killer was about 10 or 20.
This kid was 5.
5.
I never saw a demon like that.
That's a demon.
So you go to that which you are.
You only obviously gravitate when you leave the body.
You can only gravitate to that which you are.
You can't gravitate to that which you are not, could you?
You cannot become an impossibility.
You can only fulfill a potentiality and a possibility.
So you merely experience yourself
at the level of who you are and what you are,
whether the body is there or not.
In fact, you won't even like the body.
And I've noticed the times that I did go out of body,
I had no attraction to it whatsoever.
You'd think, gee whiz, I'd be wanting to get back in the body.
I looked at Dave laying in the bed and I thought,
God almighty, he looks poorly.
I had no ambition at all to reconnect with it.
You don't connect with that body laying there as you at all.
You have no attraction to it, see?
I have more attraction to a kitty.
I'd be in a panic if my kitty was gone.
But my own body was no attraction to it at all.
And I went out of the body several times.
Then I later learned how to do it,
as many as some of the people in the group here have done that,
and gone to the Western Recall Institute.
Who wrote Journey?
Eh?
Monroe, yeah.
Journey's Out of the Body, yeah.
By Monroe, yeah.
So after I went out of the body, I read that,
and then I learned how to do it,
and learned how to do it.
Learned how to do it in a hypnotic state,
and then I went and studied it at the Monroe Institute.
And so that removes any doubt in your mind,
whether you're a physical entity or a spirit.
Because the minute you're out of the body,
you realize that you're not that body.
So death is not a possibility.
We say that over and over again,
because mankind has such a belief in death.
So the capacity for comprehension,
in the abstract categories,
the Kantian categories,
and that's another mistake that academia,
well, it's not academia, it's the far left,
and its impact on academia,
is that they mix categories.
What's true at one level is not true on another,
not only spiritually,
but the abstract levels.
A family and a genus and a species,
you can't just mix them up.
A species is not a genus, and a genus is not...
You can't mix levels of truth.
So your intention then,
your dedication,
is to truth for its own sake.
So if we do a calibration,
the mind has no interest in the outcome.
Because I'm just as curious
what's going to come up as she is.
Both of us here, we don't have any idea.
We can often guess it,
having done it so many times.
And I looked at the cement,
it looked like 200 to me.
I mean, 200 came to my mind.
It's just because having done it so many times.
So you get better and better at it as you do it.
The higher your consciousness evolves,
the better you are at it.
And of course, like riding a bicycle,
practice makes perfect.
Practice makes perfect.
So what we do is I ask,
do we have permission to do this?
And I ask it mentally if I don't verbalize it.
I have permission to do this.
I have to get a yes.
Then I put it in the form of a statement.
I don't ask a question.
I put it in the form of a statement.
And the statement is either true or false.
The energy runs down our arm
like electricity very rapidly.
So you can't ask the question
and then hang out and scratch on yourself
and then push down.
I'm trying to help people get better results.
You have to be dedicated to the truth
and not a positionality.
You have to really want to know what is the truth.
I tell people,
first find out what is the truth
and then worry about what you're going to do about it later.
That the stock that you just bought
calibrates at 160.
And now worry about it later.
But don't try and influence the arm
so that that stock you just bought
calibrates over 200.
It's better to know the truth
because you can sell it long or short or some trick.
And get rid of it.
Besides they got lawyers now that advertise
if you lost money on the stock market call me up.
They must have the busiest offices in the world.
If you lost any money in investments
call Fregit and Fregit and Fregit.
Wow, I don't know how they can put up an ad like that.
Alright, so your dedication to God
and reality has to be high.
Your capacity for comprehension
abstract categories.
And you cannot jump the Kantian categories.
The Kantian categories have to do phylum,
class, species, etc.
Right?
Those are all paradigms too.
You can't mix them
and say that a fish is a better bird.
A fish is a bird without feathers.
You can't say that.
That's what the far left does.
They say a fish is a bird without feathers
and it's not right.
So we'll pass a law.
They love the law.
We'll get the ACLU to handle it.
Alright.
Sue in the right of birds.
Epistemology, sophistication, education and priorities
will influence the result.
The capacity to do consciousness calibration
arises with more education, the more dedication,
the more spiritual evolution.
Of all of those, the spiritual evolution
is the most important.
Education would really give you sophistication
in how to best phrase the question.
How to best phrase the question.
So by sophisticated phrasing
then you're likely to get more truth
just because you're expressing the question.
Which would be reflective somewhat of IQ.
Another thing that may interfere is personality blocks.
You know, opposition.
Oppositionalism, contrariness and hostility.
Contrariness, contrariness.
And oppositionalism.
There are oppositional, contrary people.
There are people who have compartmentalized personalities.
I'm thinking of one now.
It calibrates around 395.
And then he's got a compartmentalized personality
that calibrates about 90 or so.
So one part of him is reasonable
and sensible and normal.
And one part of him is sort of a black alter ego
that writes nasty blogs.
I guess that would be fun to write nasty blogs.
I could write nasty blogs.
I never thought of doing that.
Fun thing, you know, fun thing.
Let's see.
What haven't you done in the world that would be fun?
Well, how about writing nasty blogs?
All right.
Well, because of your own sophistication
and education and priorities,
you wouldn't find yourself able to do that.
But IQ does give you a chance to think of things
that other people would not think of.
That's really what it amounts to.
They would not think of it,
but you would instantly see the connection.
So personality blocks,
there's a lot of personality disorders.
I forget what percentage
in the latest American Psychiatric Association.
Something like 29%.
Something like 29% of the public
have personality disorders.
Passivity, aggression, oppositionalism,
contrariness, innate hostility.
Some people are just hostile all the time.
The best thing to do is just avoid them.
The problem in today's society is via the media,
everything is supposedly fair and balanced.
Now the problem, as you can see,
is probably going to lead to the downfall
of democracy over time.
If you give falsehood equal power to truth
and equal validity to truth,
you will end up at a gridlock.
What is the current Congress?
It's called Gridlock Congress.
Whatever this one wants to do, the other blocks.
You have a do-nothing Congress.
I was in this Congress to do anything.
Nothing of any importance anyway.
They can't even put a fence around the in-house
so the coyotes don't get them.
We do that.
We put a fence around our chicken coop.
Why?
Because we have bobcats that come and eat them.
And we have coyotes that come and eat them.
So we put a fence around them.
People say, well, a fence wouldn't work.
Works around a penitentiary, don't it?
Works around the playground.
Works in my backyard.
Works around the doghouse.
Keeps the javelina out of my tomatoes.
Is that prejudice?
No, not unless you mislabel it as prejudice.
It's got nothing to do with prejudice.
Got nothing to do with nationality.
Those are all the distortions.
Distortions.
Doesn't have anything to do with Mexicanism
or any other kind of ism.
It has to do with what you consider sovereignty.
See, every time the government breaks
its own and fails to obey its own laws,
it loses its sovereignty.
A government to function has to have sovereignty.
So to be gridlocked, what happens is you end up losing
your sovereignty.
The sovereignty.
And you lose the respect to the populace.
If the government doesn't respect its own laws,
why should we?
If the cop don't obey the law,
I might as well steal a couple of hamburgers myself.
Oh, yeah.
So the calibrated level of consciousness then would fall.
If you pass a law and do not obey it or implement it,
the consciousness level and your power drops.
So if you constantly negate yourself,
constantly self-negation,
you eventually put yourself out of the game.
All right.
So we talked a lot about postmodernism
and the fallacy of moral equivalency,
because this is the moral equivalency is the game of,
of falsity and multiculturalism.
All these things calibrate below 200.
Why?
Because they sound, they sound good,
but then when implemented,
you realize they're based upon relativistic falsities.
The fall of academia we already spoke about.
You've got delusional professors.
I can't believe paying somebody thousands of dollars
to give a lecture when he's frankly psychotic.
We used to put them away in the back,
in the back ward,
put them on penicillin to cure their brain syphilis
or anti-psychotics.
Now they get $50,000 to lecture at the university.
I cannot believe what goes on.
I keep pinching myself.
I said I can't believe what goes on in Colorado
and various universities,
even good old University of Wisconsin.
God help us, University of Wisconsin.
Let us all pray for the University of Wisconsin.
Texas A&M calibrates at 440.
Duke University, less than 180.
So where do you send your kids?
Big 10.
But University of Wisconsin,
I'm going to send them a letter
that I'm dropping them for my will.
I am not, after all,
going to leave them $10 million.
But that would be a lie.
I just wanted to retaliate.
I still got to put a psychotic professor on them,
pay out good taxpayer money.
Good old University of Wisconsin.
Oh, golly.
University of Wisconsin.
All the stories we could tell about college days, right?
So, anyway,
I was going to tell you a story about University of Wisconsin,
but I better not, okay?
My friend, my friend...
My friend Hooper and I,
Hooper is now a deceased college friend.
We met in the service,
and after the service,
we were going to college,
and my first car,
I paid $35 for a Chevy,
two-seater coupe,
and it ran out of oil on the highway
and blew, blew the block,
blew the block.
Anyway, so we ended up at the...
It was homecoming weekend
at the University Rathskeller.
Between the...
People were so poor in those days,
you folks wouldn't even believe it.
Between the two of us,
we had 10 cents, period.
He had a nickel, I had a nickel.
So we bought a schooner beer for 10 cents.
We're sitting there,
overlooking Lake Mendota
at the Rathskeller,
and we're sitting there outside in the sunshine,
and all of a sudden, ploop.
Damn, bird pooped right in the middle of the schooner beer.
It isn't like he had another dime,
and you can say...
Yeah, I looked at Hooper,
and I said...
He said, I'll get a spoon.
So we got...
We got a soup spoon from the Rathskeller,
and it floated like a glob
right in the middle of the beer.
And carefully scooped it out and flipped it.
And said, won't kill us anyway.
So we split it.
That's why I like the La Boheme,
I think, you know,
the La Boheme in the movie.
The starving students in the...
They're breaking up the furniture
to keep the place warm.
Having lived the penniless student days, you know.
I said, well, it won't kill us.
I mean, the bird doesn't have anything like syphilis
or to be or something.
Okay.
So we've had enough delusional professors
at Duke University, University of Wisconsin.
Colorado is, of course, the most...
When you hear what those guys are getting paid a year,
then it gets you peed a little bit.
You know, 150,000 a year to do nothing
except walk around pouting delusions,
which calibrate 160 or something like that.
There's the...
We have to deal with the fall of consciousness level
in the U.S. and the Western civilization
and the world of recent times.
You know, even since we began giving these lectures...
All right, permission to ask in front of this group.
Even since we began giving these lectures,
the consciousness level of the United States
has dropped over four points,
five points, six points.
The consciousness level of the U.S.
has dropped five points.
All right.
The consciousness level of man,
mankind,
has dropped over four points,
five points.
Four points, mankind.
So it's Western civilization.
Okay, Western civilization has dropped over four points,
five points.
The fall of level of consciousness
of Western civilization
and its expression in America,
four or five points,
doesn't sound like much,
but four or five points can make quite a bit of difference.
If you raise the level of the sea
four and a half, five, five percent,
you're going to affect all the ships afloat.
So we have to be attentive
to the integrity of the intellectual level,
not just the spiritual level,
not the political level,
but the scholasticism of the great books of the Western world.
And we have an authority on it right now,
sitting in the corner,
who reports back on what's going on in academia.
So academia can't pull the wool over any...
on Neo anymore,
because I have my own spy right in their midst.
He told me about...
I wrote that book on capitalism, 1770-something.
Wealth of Nations.
So I've got my own informants
right in the...
locked into academia.
So they're not going to get away with anything
without our knowing about it.
So I just want you to know,
I'm not just talking from hearsay,
that I've got my own informants,
but I've got my own informants.
What a thing looks like depends on how it's contextualized.
And in modern terminology,
it's talked about the impact of framing.
The same picture in this frame
conveys a completely different message than in this frame.
And this is one of the political manipulations of fallacy.
You take this image,
you put it in this frame.
Oh, God, isn't that awful?
You put it in a different frame.
Oh, isn't that swell?
The content, the truth hasn't changed.
It's just that you put it in a different framework.
Now it looks horrible.
People made such and such amount of money.
Yes.
In that framework,
compared to the U.S. economy,
it sounds very little.
Compared to what I lived on as a student,
let's say compared to what other cultures live on,
it's a lot.
Is it a lot or is it a little?
Well, it depends on how you want to frame it.
The other framing, of course, is over time.
Over time.
And this history of the United States,
you know, is based on
the significance of the things that were written
and their impact has to be framed
in tension of the founders of the country.
The country was founded by pilgrims
who were looking for religious freedom.
This country was founded by pilgrims.
Pilgrims.
Of course, then they go on to say,
and they killed all the Indians.
So how you want to frame it then
makes it look either good or not so good.
The impact of framing,
and this is where ingenuity, cleverness,
and we're having a person
who really knows how to lie with expertise.
This is the way you lie with great expertise.
I pick sequence.
You know that 50%
of the personal ideas of criminal suspects
are fallacious.
The error in recognizing
the guilty from the non-guilty is 50%.
So that recent thing that arose
because of the DNA that went around to the
death throes of all the prisons.
What's the name of that?
The something project.
Huh?
Innocence project, is it?
All right.
So they found what?
97 people condemned to death
and the DNA proved
there wasn't even a possibility for that.
So they're going to have to admit the perpetrator.
So the error rate just in visual recognition
is already 50%.
The impact of the framing.
The sequence in which you show the,
let's say the supposed witness.
The sequence in which you show him
the photographs of possible suspects
already influences
who they think is the culprit.
You know, the sequence in which you look at the pictures
will now influence what you think.
Oh yeah, he looks just like the guy.
If you framed him a different way,
he wouldn't look like the guy.
So you see the chance of error.
Without consciousness calibration,
you can't really know the truth of anything.
I guess that's what it all amounts to.
This is from ancient Greece.
There are three things involved
in conveying information.
Logos, ethos, and pathos.
One has to do with the integrity of the speaker.
Integrity of the speaker.
How to calibrate the speaker.
Calibrate the level of truth of the speaker.
Then, the efficacy of the speech.
It's one thing to know a matter.
It's another to convey it.
How efficacious is the presentation?
And the third thing is in classic Greece
called pathos.
That is the receptivity of the listener.
It doesn't do any good to explain
the advanced theoretical physics.
The school of idiots with IQs of 70.
So it means you have to have the capacity
to comprehend.
Then you have to have the capacity to express.
And you yourself must come from integrity.
So to be a convincing speaker then,
this was used to train politicians,
also trained to teach them how to evade that.
How do we evade that?
And so,
this is how convincing is his honesty.
This is how efficacious is his message.
And this is the listenability of the audience.
And when you listen to political speeches
it's always good to just run those three through your mind.
The way you develop a scholastic education
is you get just an important concept
and then you apply it in everyday life
until you begin to see it through those eyes.
There are politicians that are just great.
They're great out there.
And there are people that are very logical,
integrous,
but nobody's willing to listen to them.
Pathos.
So they miscalculated the audience.
You can't give a lecture on this level
to an audience on that level, okay?
Logos, ethos, and pathos means then.
And we can think of very prominent politicians
that are very slick at their presentation,
but unconvincing.
And some that are very logical.
And then some that are not logical,
but you'll love them anyway.
And what did you say?
Huh?
One minute?
Okay.
Deism, atheism, and accountability.
We've already somewhat...
I wouldn't trust anybody
that doesn't believe in God on a certain level.
Why?
Because they're not answerable.
They're not answerable.
If you're lucky, they have intellectual integrity.
Intellectual integrity.
So it's possible to be an atheist
and to be quite accountable.
Because he's thinking of it more or less like a class
in which you're debating class.
So at least he has allegiance to intellectual excellence.
So the intellectual can certainly satisfy criteria
by being intellectually accountable.
But in the long run,
it's only...
It's only the inner knowingness
that every hair on your head shall be counted
that keeps you strictly pulled back
to the magnet of truth.
Every hair on you...
We have permission to do this.
It is an absolute truth at the level of infinity.
Every hair on your head shall be counted.
Resist.
In case there's any doubt.
We've done this over and over.
It says,
every hair on your head shall be counted.
Wow.
So when you take responsibility
for the significance and meaning of that.
So the reason you can't trust atheists at a certain level
is because they do not think they're going to be accountable.
You can screw your brother,
get high like hell and get away with it,
and you're going to get away with it.
You're not accountable.
Now, I'm not going to teach anything of really great truth
to anybody that doesn't respect it,
and they're not going to respect it
because they're not accountable.
So you see people out there selling out.
I don't know how some of these so-called groups,
these gurus that were so famous,
have crashed so badly.
I mean, how can you ignore the fact
that you know you're accountable?
I don't really get that.
You mean these spiritual teachers
were actually atheists all the time?
I don't know what goes on.
Some world-famous gurus, you know,
full stunts that are just,
make you aghast, you know.
And the only explanation I can give for it
is a satanic attack.
Because they were in a high place
and influencing goodness,
karmically or someplace,
they had a chink in their armor,
and zap, the demons got them.
So as we move ahead in consciousness
and our own spiritual illusion,
we watch for the demons.
What is the temptation?
That's just a fancy word for temptations.
What is the temptation here?
I remember the knowingness
that now I am beyond all karma.
Now I'm beyond karmic accountability.
I remember that came as a silent knowingness.
Out of absolute stillness.
All power is yours.
You're not accountable.
There is no karma.
Own it.
And I saw who'd owned it.
And I saw who went through this high pass.
Not many.
And I saw Jesus Christ denied it.
And I saw who denied it.
And this is all in absolute silence.
There's no thinkingness or knowingness,
thoughtness.
It's just a knowingness of who passed through this pass.
It's a high level pass.
All power is yours.
Own it.
Wow.
Talk about the temptation.
That is the temptation that they fell for.
All power over others.
You see, if you negate love as a reality,
now nobody has any power over you
because a decent person will stop just out of lovingness.
They won't torture a dog to death
just out of lovingness for all of life.
If you say, well, that's just an attachment,
that's just wanting to control.
So we'll negate that.
Now you can torture dogs and not feel guilty about it.
All power is yours.
You're not answerable.
So that's a high pass, last ditch temptation.
And it's one of the demons that attacked the Buddha,
attacked Jesus Christ.
All power is yours.
There's no accountability.
Uh-huh.
Well, I don't know what happens.
I don't know what happens if you take the wrong turn there.
I hate to think of the consequences.
Anyway, the fact that you're accountable then is what a safeguard.
So it isn't that you want to live fearfully,
fearful of making a mistake or fearful of a sin or something
because along with accountability also goes forgiveness.
Jesus Christ died for you to be easier.
He speaks for you.
And because forgiveness is part of your inheritance.
So as a devoted spiritual student,
you've then karmically earned the right to forgiveness
should you make a mistake.
And one mistake that we've all made was we were too young at the time.
We were too young at the time to know better.
Does that apply to everyone here?
Yeah, we're all too young.
So we forgive ourself because we're evolutionary creatures.
And out of our love for God,
we say, well, thank you, Lord,
for the opportunity to grow and evolve
and to earn that which we become.
So we'll meet you after lunch.
Turned on?
You just turned on?
They made us late.
Oh, my nose just got longer.
Oh, oh, oh.
Oh, my nose keeps getting longer.
No, they did not make us get late.
Oh, my nose just shrunk again.
Things are a little slower than we expected at lunch anyway.
All right.
Now, do you remember where we were, dear?
Oh, okay.
Yes, accountability means if you tell a lie,
your nose gets longer.
So you can't sneak into heaven without their seeing your nose.
He needs to go to the bookstore.
Art?
But you say it.
We need Art Tarby to go to the bookstore for us, please.
Art.
Art, at the next break.
Art Tarby.
Art.
That's a good name.
Well, we certainly sound like we know what we're talking about here, don't we?
Logos, ethos, and pathos.
We could ask all our politicians and ask them to explain those three concepts and see how
many.
All right.
We covered deism, atheism, and accountability, you see.
That's why people who won't take a pledge of allegiance to God and country, I always
make them sit separately.
They may have a bomb in their pocket.
I don't know what they're up to, but people who don't want to swear by God and country
really should elsewhere.
It doesn't mean nationalism.
It means because to love your fellow, to love your fellows is coming from the heart.
Coming from the heart.
Pledge of allegiance is coming from the heart.
So you're not asking them to come from their mental self or their political self.
You're asking them about their heart.
Do you have a heart for your fellow man?
A heart for your country?
Like they say, the reason a man was so dead.
Who never to himself has said, this is my own, my native.
To just say it brings up tears.
Yeah.
So that's the heart of mankind.
You're bringing up the universal heart.
Just like when you hear the bagpipes, the same heart of mankind comes up and you weep
to the bagpipes.
You say, what am I crying for?
And yet everybody who has a heart does.
Yeah.
Except the English, I guess.
You don't want to hear the sound of the bagpipes coming over the hill.
The last thing you want to hear is the sound of the bagpipes coming over the hill.
Make sure your will is finalized and I'll leave my watch to, you know.
The heart of mankind then is the great power of the heart.
And if that's dead in a person, that's not too good.
Languaging, labels and semionics.
We already did that one.
That's number three.
Now where's number four?
Oh, here we are.
Yeah.
Okay.
We're fine.
I know where we are.
The impact of framing.
That is a thing can be made, turned from true to false by simply framing it in a different
context.
And then you get away, you get away with that one because you say literally it's the truth.
But how you position the truth, you turn the difference.
Yeah.
You turn it into a falsehood.
So that's part of ingenuity, being ingenious.
And devious.
Devious.
Now deviousness is not an American tradition.
It's a foreign culture in which deviousness is respected and cultivated.
In our culture, deviousness is not a praiseworthy character trait.
To be devious is a derogatory comment.
In others, it's considered to be an asset.
Well, the accountability of mankind has been known, you know, throughout all of time in
separate cultures, Native American culture, all the great cultures of the world, ancient
Egypt.
In ancient Egypt, you know, Osiris is the god of, the lord of the underworld.
And when you die, your heart is weighed on the scale.
And so it's the truth, the heart of truth.
And for the degree with which you have represented the truth, you either go this way or thumbs down.
So you are, every hair on your head again is counted in a totally different culture and a different context of ancient Egypt.
And Osiris is the god then who guards the underworld.
And you either go to heaven or hell depending on its impact.
The weighing of the heart of truth then is something that should make people hesitate before they walk a devious pathway.
Because the realization that you're accountable in and of itself brings about integrity.
Brings about integrity.
The weighing of the heart.
And there's, I saw that when I was in Egypt.
Yeah.
You could buy a very interesting diagrams of it.
I was in Egypt.
We had an appointment to meet.
Well, he got assassinated before we got there.
Yeah.
So I got to meditate in the Great Pyramids and spent all night meditating in the Great Pyramid.
Interesting experience.
And I thought the ventilation, the ventilation left much to be desired.
Yeah.
And in the King's Chamber there's a sarcophagus that's been empty for a couple thousand years, I guess.
And people have to go to the bathroom.
Well, there's no bathroom.
So they just go in the sarcophagus.
So as the centuries go by, centuries of people having to take a quick pee in there.
And the Egyptian government, I thought, you know, you could run a cylinder of air and just pump air all the way up into the King's Chamber.
And flush that air out.
And I thought, I don't know why they don't do that.
Well, I see many, many years later they finally have done that.
And they don't remove the graffiti.
Written in a crayon is somebody, the guy's name, and it says 1937.
And they just leave it there.
Disagreeing a great monument like that.
They just leave the graffiti instead of washing it off the wall.
And I think I told you one time.
Yeah.
Behind the door someplace there in Egypt was a bunch of scrap, you know, paper and crumpled up stuff.
And that has been there since Napoleon.
They haven't swept the floor since Napoleon was there.
And then after you go up the Nile and one of the heads had fallen off, one of the gods lined up along there.
And then they, because the ice went down, they were raising the level of water.
So they had to move everything up, you know.
So at great expense, it was multinational effort to move everything up because the water was going to rise.
And they carefully put it all back with the same god with his head falling off in the same place.
They didn't put his head back on.
I think it's so funny, you know.
A totally different culture.
Americans would view that.
You know, we'd carefully put it back on.
We'd take off the graffiti.
Yeah, there's the head laying there in the same place.
It was funny.
And you had to leave the upper Nile by noon or 11 o'clock because it was 120 in the valley of death or whatever it was.
If you're a tourist, you had to get out of there because they don't want tourists passing out from the heat and littering the place all over.
And that was the place I told you where I had a ride in a camel.
I guess I've told you these stories before.
Anyway, the camel, it was $10.
He said, $10.
So I rode around, you know, all over in this camel.
And the camel is very high.
When you get on a camel, I mean, you are up in the air, you know, like on a horse.
You're way up there.
And then when it came time to get off, he bought another $10.
I said, I already paid you $10, huh?
Oh.
So anyway, so I wanted to get off the camel.
And I said, I already paid you $10.
So he says, cheap American.
So deviousness and ripping you off is endemic.
He doesn't feel guilty about that.
And if he didn't work you for another $10, he'd probably be ashamed to go home and tell his mother that he didn't get that extra $10 out of you.
And, of course, you have to have a camel driver.
You have to have the camel kneel down so you can get off.
So finally I decided I'll have to pay whether I like it or not, see?
So he starts bringing the camel down.
And the camel goes, .
That's Susan's fault.
She put me up to it.
She said, do the camel.
Do the camel.
One time we were in San Francisco or Chicago, and I did the octopus.
And I haven't done the octopus since then.
You know, I can't do the octopus today.
I did the camel already.
Oh, all right.
No more animals now.
The camel and the octopus on one day.
All right.
So that's ancient Egypt.
With wisdom, you learn discretion.
And prudence.
Not everything can be said at all times without some responsibility of discretion and prudence.
So this is the area of wisdom in which you begin to take moral responsibility.
To be loving towards the obligation is threefold, to yourself, to God, and to your fellow human beings, in my view.
Those are your three obligations for which you're accountable.
That is correct.
Those are the three primary realms.
That's my understanding.
The three primary realms.
Love your neighbor as yourself.
Sermon on the Mount.
Love God.
Love your neighbor as yourself.
So your obligation is that your life is a gift to your own spiritual evolution.
So you have an obligation to yourself.
And to fulfill your...
obligations and responsibilities.
And to serve fellow man to the best of your ability.
And by thus doing that, you serve God as well.
Yeah?
To yourself, to God, and to your fellow man.
All of creation is divine.
So therefore, I include the animal kingdom in it.
To be kind to all that lives.
As well as you can.
So wisdom and discretion then.
Because of prudence, we develop...
The gray hairs of age are earned.
They are earned.
Allegiance to God versus mammon.
And that, of course, is the big conflict.
God versus Caesar.
Spiritual versus material.
Whether to do a thing for financial gain.
I found you don't have to do anything for financial gain.
That fulfilling your obligation to yourself, to God and your fellow man.
That which you need emerges.
It comes out of nowhere.
It just seems to happen.
And without seeking it, you see.
So if you write something of great excellence.
People want to read it, etc.
So you don't have to promote yourself.
You don't have to...
So the desire for worldly gain in a way blocks...
The realization that you already have it.
As you evolve, you let go of desires and wants and attachments to the world.
And what happens is you create a space for it to emerge of its own.
You see, because the universe is really non-causal.
The potentiality emerges as the fulfillment of that potentiality.
So, although there were times...
When you had to steal food from the hospital.
That was a little skinny.
But I ask God for forgiveness of that.
I got $100 a month for 100 hours a week.
That's 25 cents an hour.
All night, every other night and all day.
Seven days a week.
$100 a month.
So, midnight they would serve this...
Whoever's on at midnight.
They would have sandwiches with ham and stuff like that.
So I'd make one to eat.
And then I'd purposely put enough on my plate.
And I'd take a paper napkin and quick put it in there and put it in my pocket.
And that was dinner the next night.
Dinner the next night.
So, that was thievery.
I've confessed my sins.
Mistakes and errors are unwitting.
Unwitting.
Mistakes and errors.
So sometimes people don't want to give allowance for mistakes and errors.
They think that an integrous person must be perfect.
Must be perfect.
No, mistakes and errors are not only possible.
They're almost certain.
Because of the karmic propensities.
Karmic propensities plus the limitation of humans in general.
And ourselves in particular.
Mistakes and errors are things for which we forgive ourselves.
I learned that in counseling.
I told you I had moral...
Moral...
Whatever it was.
Moral over-conscience.
Over-conscience.
So I would berate myself for making the slightest mistake or error.
You know.
Scrupulosity.
That's what they called it.
Moral scrupulosity.
So moral scrupulosity is not being spiritual.
It's being neurotic.
So I had to see a gopher counseling about moral scrupulosity.
That error is intrinsic to the human.
And therefore the willingness to forgive yourself and forgive others.
Forgive yourself and forgive others.
So the guy who cuts in front of you in traffic, you know, is showing poor judgment.
And if you do nothing about it, you'll meet him down the highway upside down.
And I remember cars passing me on what is now a lovely road.
On a gravel road and a curve.
And as I got around the corner, it was a lovely sports car.
He was upside down.
With his wheels still spinning.
So the Buddha said you don't have to do anything against your enemies.
Because they will bring themselves down of their own nature.
So we all live within a cultural morality of expectation and parameters.
Of what's expected, what's permissible, what's forgivable, what's unforgivable.
We have an idea of what is important.
So morality is also judgmentalism.
And that is you're trying to decide priorities of morality.
Which is more moral?
This move or that move?
And these are determined by our culture and our heritage.
And I think the reason for emphasizing.
The heritage of the United States is it shows up in the Constitution.
Which calibrates in the amazing 700s.
And it shows up in the Bill of Rights.
It's represented by the pilgrims seeking religious freedom.
So our cultural morality is based on centuries of spiritual integrity.
This reversal of truth takes place and affects the brain.
Now you can say which is primary?
Which is primary?
Is the brain physiology?
The limitation of brain physiology causing this impairment?
Or is it the other way around?
The person's intention affects the brain physiology.
Let's ask.
We have permission to ask this.
It's the person's intention that affects the brain physiology.
Resist.
It's not the other way around.
All right.
So you're not the victim of your brain.
You're not the victim of your brain function.
So we are not the victim of our brain physiology.
We are the determinant of it.
Thank you.
Oh, good.
I'm glad that's clarified.
So whether you become left brain or right brain,
you know, the map of brain physiology shows different pathways.
So what you have chosen to become then reflects itself
in your brain physiology and not the other way around.
Huh.
Well, that removes that cop out.
Just my brain physiology, Your Honor.
All right.
So we choose good or evil.
We choose it.
And people choose evil because at the higher levels because there's gain.
But at the lower levels because they get a certain great pleasure from it,
a certain glee.
The glee of being bad is its own payoff.
Huh?
Uh-huh.
Using conscience as one's guide then, you need a rational conscience.
So the more sophisticated you become, religious and philosophically and spiritually,
the conscience becomes a greater and greater source of reliability.
So, you know, I was in a Freudian school.
I was in a Freudian psychoanalysis.
And Freud talked about the ego differently than we do in spiritual work.
The ego was a strength that balanced the superego, which is the conscience, against the id,
against the id, which is the animal impulsivity.
It's one sense of reality.
So the conscience then is what berates you.
Uh-huh.
What's that?
Oh, she's gone mad, Your Honor.
She's gone mad.
Conscience, let your conscience be your guide.
Hopefully you have a mature and educated conscience, which is interested in integrity rather than
just morality because moralism, becoming moralistic, being moralistic can be a great hindrance.
And I pulled up from the universal archetype.
When I was doing truth versus falsehood, I mean, I spent a lot of months outside clearing the stuff that got pulled up from the collective.
Indignant.
Indignant evil.
So the spiritual night came up.
The archetype of the night would come up and the spleen of the spiritual night would be an indignation.
Indignation.
You know, the way a dog fighting right now.
When you see a dog fighting, you see these dogs rip to shreds.
First, what comes up in you is the spleen of indignation.
You know, you're indignant and angry.
How they could exploit dumb animals like that.
So that's one of the last things to really clear out, the thing that took the longest.
And when I was doing truth versus falsehood,
you see one indignation after another.
You know, with this bull baiting, a dog fighting or some form of rampant cruelty was always something I found very difficult to handle.
Especially cruelty, willful cruelty to animals, you know.
And they train these dogs.
They take the victim dog and tape its mouth shut.
Put tape around its snout so it can't defend itself.
And let the other dogs have at them.
That don't bring up the spleen of indignation.
Moral indignation in yourself, you see.
It's enough to bring up a rage.
So as we said, on judgment day, every hair should be counted.
We do that over and over again.
Because somehow, we get that unconsciously.
It becomes innate.
It becomes prioritized.
The likelihood of that awareness coming up becomes increasingly so.
And it becomes a great guide to a reasonable conscience.
And we call that, you know, the more often you make a certain choice,
the more likely you're going to make that choice again.
So realizing that every hair on your head is counted.
And the picture of Osiris weighing the heart.
And realizing our accountability.
Is not to frighten us.
But to make us realize our moral responsibility.
And the consequences thereof.
Because our decisions affect everyone around us.
Our decisions.
Because there is a collective consciousness.
So every time we choose the higher,
we tend to lift the level of the water of the sea of the collective consciousness.
Now, mankind collectively has been making a lot of bad,
what we call bad,
non-integral,
non-aggress decisions.
Because we see the level of consciousness of mankind has gone down recently.
Especially western civilization.
So that makes us aware that our inner decisions
is affecting the level of the sea.
Every time we make a decision,
we're affecting all of mankind.
People like to think of themselves separately.
But that's narcissism.
We're all part of the one of humanness.
Mankind.
Every one of our decisions affects everyone alive.
So to counteract the descendant of non-integrity,
it's more and more important that a group like this exists.
And that we calibrate it before.
In other classes,
this group alone counterbalances
something like millions of people.
This group here.
We have permission to ask.
This group,
we have permission to ask.
Counterbalances relatively millions of people in the negative domain.
This group alone counterbalances millions.
Because this group is so much power.
High energy power.
A group like this literally counterbalances millions
of people devoted to negativity, hatred, etc.
Yeah.
Ain't we something, huh?
Guess that shows them, huh?
Guess that shows those folks where to go.
Now it's just interesting that it's impersonal.
Why?
Because it's what you've become.
Not what you do, what you think, what you say.
What you have become is the reality of your essence.
And that essence shines forth.
All that exists radiates forth an energy.
All that exists.
All that ever existed radiates forth an energy forever.
Therefore, we can ask about anything, anywhere in time, distance, space, and history.
Because all that ever existed, that radiation is still there.
And I think we did it in one class, huh?
We calibrated Napoleon before he went into the pyramid
and Napoleon after he left the pyramid, huh?
Yeah.
Yeah, because he saw,
he had a vision of
Waterloo.
He had a vision,
a vision that he was not invincible
and saw the vulnerability.
So the Napoleon who walked into the pyramid
was not the same Napoleon who walked out.
That's very interesting.
So you can calibrate his energy before he went in
and after he came out and had that vision.
Sort of a pre-vision of coming events.
Now the narcissistic glorification of free speech
is probably the biggest threat.
In my view of it,
to Western civilization in general
and the US of A in particular.
The glorification of free speech.
Now free speech is not God.
You see a society in which we have
Godified free speech.
Anything is okay as long as it's free speech.
Free speech.
Hatred, lying, extortion, blackmail.
Anything is okay so long as it's free speech.
So we have come to worship.
Free speech is one of the niceties of democracy.
But it is not the peak of the pyramid.
I'm not going to die for free speech.
I don't give a damn if you never express your opinion.
I don't even care what your opinion is.
Am I going to die for your opinion
so you can get out there and write a nasty blog site?
Give me a break.
Free speech is not the highest.
It's the greatest good which mankind can reach.
Knowing when to shut up, I think, is better.
We have permission to ask that.
Discretion of speech is a higher good.
Discretion of speech.
Using your speech for goodness,
for love, for that which is beneficial.
Free speech for its own sake
is nothing but narcissistic self-indulgence.
You get up there and make
multi-millions of dollars a year
having a daily hate panel
in which you get to sit up there and spew forth hate.
Am I dying for that?
Did I die for that?
I'm not going to die for that.
Was I in World War II for that?
I was on hazardous duty, blow up any second.
Was I willing to do that for that woman to say that?
No.
No, I'm not.
I wasn't.
Nor do I dedicate all that risk
to the misuse of free speech.
The exploitation and the degradation of free speech,
so free speech has become a degradation
to express hate and vilification and untruth.
So a society which gives equal time,
equal time to both sides,
means that they end up with no truth about anything.
So this misuse of free speech
is a narcissistic self-indulgence.
To build up your own self-esteem
of your narcissistic ego.
Narcissistic glorification of free speech.
So free speech during the 50s,
when I was growing up,
free speech calibrated at 255.
Free speech now, due to degradation,
calibrates at 180.
Let's see what happened to free speech.
I remember President Ford,
is it Ford that stumbled?
Yes.
You know, Roosevelt,
they were all smokers by the way,
Roosevelt had polio and he was crippled.
And so the press,
the photographers just did not focus
on his crippled licks, you see?
Here you're fighting for survival of America, etc.
It's not the greatest time.
So with discretion, with discretion,
not due to loss of freedom,
but out of discretion,
nobody focused on it.
I saw the end of that era
when President Ford,
was it Ford?
Yes?
Yes.
I remember the change in the era.
Ford was coming out of US-1
or whatever that airline is.
And he got down about five or six steps
and he stumbled.
Now, in the old days,
they would just leave the clip out.
You don't need that clip in there.
But the media focused on it.
You saw Ford trip,
and then the TV an hour later,
Ford trip, Ford trip.
You think that was the biggest event,
world event,
that he merely stumbled a bit on a step or two.
And then in that instant I knew
they just put the dagger in the heart of freedom.
They just put the dagger in the heart.
Do we have the legal right to see it?
Of course.
You got the legal right to do a lot of things.
I can take my pants off
as long as I got my shirt on.
I got the legal right to do that.
Is that wisdom?
Is that discretion?
I saw the press go down right then
for a headline for a few more seconds
of the Observer.
They took down Ford's dignity.
So to take down the dignity
of the head of your own country
is suicidal.
That's imbecility
and the glorification of narcissism.
And that's what Ford did.
And of course we've been doing it ever since.
Every president,
God help him if he sneezes.
Imagine what would happen
if the president sneezed
right in the middle of an interview.
You know what would happen.
The news would keep it right on,
wouldn't they?
We could all laugh at him sneezing
and blowing his nose.
They would.
It's good for a few more watchers.
So the narcissistic glorification
of free speech to me
is the Achilles heel,
Achilles heel of our current society
in the Western world
and in America in particular.
If free speech means equal time,
equal weight
to the enemies of our own culture,
doesn't it?
It's like,
without sounding like a sexist,
it's like a woman getting up there.
I always get a woman, Muslim,
glorifying Islamic law, Sharia.
It says it takes two to three women
to make one man.
And she wants to inculcate that
in our culture.
Women are created dumber than men
and it takes two or three women
to equal one man.
And here's this woman championing this.
She needs a good doctor.
Why would a woman want to champion
an ideology that ridicules them,
makes them inferior,
and some kind of cheap property
that you don't even have to account for?
More or less like dog fighting, yeah?
If you beat a woman, it doesn't count.
It doesn't matter if you beat a woman.
It's just like beating a dog.
So why a person would want to bring that
into the United States
and make it the law of the land is beyond.
But that's part of free speech.
And the downside of free speech
is that it's a two-edged sword.
It can cut falsehood,
but it can also cut yourself.
It's a two-edged sword.
That's why the Course in Miracles
talks about forgiveness
as a one-edged sword.
Forgiveness, it's incapable.
It only cuts in one direction.
So forgiveness then.
So we forgive people that are brainwashed
and sort of indoctrinated
with concepts that all calibrate below 200.
Bloggerism seems to be just an expression
of this desecration of what to me
should be revered.
Free speech should be revered.
Bloggerism is just the means of destroying it.
There's one blogger site
that ends with cos, K-O-S.
Anyway, it calibrates at 90.
90.
What have you got to say to the world?
The world wants to hear it.
It calibrates at 90.
The daily cos, you know, daily cos.
Let's see.
Daily cos calibrates.
We have permission over this one.
Calibrates at 90.
95.
90.
Dedicated to evil and its promulgation.
All right, so evil and its promulgation
calibrated at 90
has equal time, equal time, equal importance
with truth, which calibrates in the 400s.
All right, so we saw in my lifetime
free speech dropped from 255,
which is respect for the responsibility
of free speech,
to 180,
which is the misuse of it
for really subserving what the world
has traditionally called eagle.
Eagle.
Ego evil.
Ego evil, yeah.
The other thing bloggers do is they salt the mine.
They plant a story in one place
so they can then quote that as an authority
for the other site.
As quoted from Blah Blah,
like it's not their fault,
as quoted from so and so.
So that's called salting the mine.
There's professional people out there
who for a price,
who for a price
will become a poison pen
and dream up and try to seek out
anything negative they can about you.
Let me see.
That you once got a parking ticket.
He is reportedly a lawbreaker.
That's the way it comes across.
Reportedly a lawbreaker.
You add reportedly,
so you sound like you're being very sensible
and balanced about it.
You're not going to say something nasty about him.
Reportedly a lawbreaker.
That's what it says.
Senator so and so is reportedly a lawbreaker.
Reportedly a lawbreaker.
Reportedly.
Or known locally as a lawbreaker.
See, that way you can't pin anybody down.
So,
there are people out there
that are paid big money,
big money from the far left,
big money to shoot down integrity
using the mechanisms of salting the mine.
The other one is the straw man
and of course the sheep's clothing.
So you plant a story
in one part of bloggerdom.
You then go to another blog site
and you quote this blog
as the authority from which
you can now say this
because you didn't say it,
you're just quoting them.
The fact that you planted it,
it's forgotten.
That's called salting the mine.
It's done.
I've had personal experience with it
and I'm an authority on how it works.
In fact, I can spot professionalism.
I know it's a professional job.
You can tell right away.
He claims,
he claims to be a doctor.
He claims.
Not that he is.
The word claims appears all over.
Claims.
So this is to cast aspersion
by subtle innuendo.
You see?
He claims this,
claims to be a law abider
and yet we see
that he has broken the law in the past.
In fact, I'm going to confess my past.
Ready?
I got a parking ticket in Cottonwood
for parking too close to a loading zone.
This was 20 years ago.
I got a ticket
and I had to go to magistrate's court.
I went to magistrate's court.
Well, what was happening,
there's a red loading zone
and you're supposed to park away
from the red loading zone
and I parked a little over the red loading zone.
Not used to the air here, I guess.
I would ordinarily not park near the end of a loading zone.
So somehow I must have been,
but I did,
I did park next to this loading zone.
A red paint thing that said loading zone.
So I took my ticket,
I took it home
and it gave me my appearance state
before the magistrate.
I'm hanging out my dirty linen
so you can dirty laundry.
So I don't get hit with it there
that I was covering up anything.
A law breaker.
And so I drove back down to Cottonwood
on the magistrate's court date.
Showed up in the courthouse there on Main Street
and went in and found the magistrate's court
and I told him I had this ticket
that I wished to pay.
And he looked at me and said,
for a parking ticket?
I said yes.
He said the fine will be one dollar
and we'll waive it.
He couldn't believe that a guy actually showed up in court
to answer a one dollar parking ticket.
But it said you were supposed to appear
in the magistrate's court so I did.
You know what I'm saying?
However,
that is the confession of my law breaking days.
That's all of it.
So,
so anyway,
for a certain price,
uh, uh,
you can destroy anybody for a certain price.
And I know exactly what the price is
and how it's paid.
It's transferred electronically.
It's not even paid by check.
And for that price,
they get a professional chopper
who can take anything in your make,
life and make it sound derogatory.
So and so has a weight problem.
I understand he once had a financial problem
and of course,
he has a legal record.
I mean,
he did get a,
you know,
you don't tell you it's a parking ticket.
And then,
so everything gets exaggerated
out of thing.
So when you calibrate those things,
you'll find they're 190.
They're all 190.
And their source is 190.
Sometimes they'll give themselves
a religious name as a source.
You calibrate them at 190
and then you find out using our method of telling truth
how much they got paid for the story.
I suppose a lot of people would do it
for that kind of money.
All right.
So,
in as much as we're answerable
throughout all of time,
for the consequences of our actions,
not out of fear,
not out of superstition,
not out of being brainwashed,
but out of free choice,
we own the dignity and greatness
of our own reality.
We give it the respect that it is due.
Your life is a gift from almighty God.
That's hardly a small thing.
If God gave you a great big China thing,
you know,
you wouldn't be sticking it up
where the wind can blow it over,
would you?
You'd be putting it,
God gave me this.
You know,
this is almighty God gave me this thing.
I mean,
you would be very careful with it.
So,
you grant the same respect to your own life.
And intrinsically,
I know the worth of others
and I see that their weakness,
the weakness to make money,
the pleasure in maligning other people,
the pleasure in maligning people,
that's what they get off on.
They get sort of a
glee some joy out of wickedness
for its own sake.
Wickedness for its own sake.
That explains these bloggers
and the people that they pay
to do those kind of hatchet jobs
is the pleasure out of wickedness,
per se,
resist.
See,
there's no cause.
There's nothing causing them to do that.
They're expressing the wickedness
of what they are.
When you get that,
you get away from causality,
the whole Newtonian thing,
the whole Newtonian idea,
the whole politicalization
that it's society's fault,
it's always the majority's fault,
or something like this.
Everybody's been the minority.
I've been the minority a million times.
Yeah.
So,
whoever you decide you are,
everybody else then becomes the majority,
don't they?
How many middle-aged,
retired school teachers are there,
age 46,
who taught Latin?
You're a minority.
All of us are a minority of one.
We're all a minority of one.
Yeah?
Everybody is a minority of one.
So,
you defend your fellow man,
you defend your own self,
and because that's what you intuit
is your responsibility to divinity.
Your responsibilities are ending up today
with fulfilling your sensibility to yourself
because your life is your responsibility
and your life is a gift from God
and your own recognition
of the importance of your own spirit.
You recognize your responsibility
towards your fellow man
to relieve suffering whenever you can,
to do what you can,
and to God
because your responsibility to God
is like forever.
Forever.
Forever is sort of quite a while.
The respect for divinity,
for God,
for truth and all the things
that I talk about
is considerably intensified
by my own experience of the depths of hell.
I think I already told you in previous lectures.
At the bottom of ultimate despair
and at the time I was an atheist
and having given up all hope
of ever finding anything that recognized truth,
I went into the very root and source
of knowingness, consciousness,
thinking, life, energy, consciousness itself,
and I went wherever it would lead.
I went into a dark and infinite space
and as I went in,
I recognized I was going into hell
because there were demons everywhere
screaming to people being tortured,
much like the screams of these dogs
that are allowed to kill each other.
People who allow that
are going to hear the screams.
They're going to hear the screams
in the same place I heard the screams.
You hear the screams of the agony
of the suffering you brought others.
And you think this is hell.
It is hell,
but it's only the jacks for openers.
It's only the very top level of hell.
And as I've said before,
like Donnie's Inferno,
as you go further and further into hell,
what happens is the agony now is no longer linear.
It's a knowingness of abandonment
to the agony of being deserted
of all hope ever, forever.
And in that,
in that depths of the pits of hell,
you get what forever means.
Means always, always.
Continuous, unstopping, never always.
The agony of the soul,
completely abandoned,
is beyond description.
Time there stops,
and therefore the experientially,
just like at the top space in the presence of God,
there is foreverness.
At the bottom in the pit is foreverness.
So you experience the agony of the soul,
forever.
Goes on for eternity.
Experientially,
you experience the eternity of the damnation of the soul.
And out of the very ultimate depths of that,
arose a voice from this consciousness,
not from the person,
because the person was long gone.
If there is a God,
I ask him for help.
And then oblivion.
And then suddenly,
the glory of God.
She went forth.
In full splendor,
as all of that,
that which is the essence of all existence.
And the transformation,
was incredible.
The reason I repeat this story about hell,
is because I don't want anybody to take the slightest chance of going there.
It's merely to underscore,
the value of integrity for its own sake.
Not out of fear of hell,
but out of knowing that,
we are completely,
and truly answerable to God.
We are answerable to all God.
So that adds a certain,
sincerity and importance.
You begin to see that your decisions are not just frivolous.
They're not just jokes.
They're not just immaterial.
That your life counts.
And therefore,
every decision in your life counts.
So you begin to own the worth,
the impact of your own life.
You see,
when you dismiss everything as nothing,
and everything is a joke,
and everything is just a TV thing and all this.
When you trivialize your life,
you're trivializing that which is the most valuable thing that you own,
and that is your life.
So I say this only to,
underscore,
to guard the sacredness of your life.
Your life is sacred.
It's because it's sacred,
you have the capacity to uplift,
everyone on the planet.
By just what you have become.
To verify the sacredness of your life then,
is to verify the sacredness of everyone's life,
and thereby you lift the level of the sea,
and relieve the suffering of others,
who are on the other side of the world,
and don't even know that you exist.
So,
as we forgive and,
send forth that love,
I always picture before I go to bed,
the relief of the suffering of all sentient beings,
and the animal kingdom.
I picture a little child laying somewhere,
hopeless and next to death,
feeling abandoned,
or some animal,
laying there suffering.
Then I realize,
that our intention,
at that last moment,
it can handle the suffering.
It can handle it.
It can.
Because of us.
So that's our gift.
Back to thee,
oh Lord.
Amen.
We'll take a break,
and then we're going to reassemble,
and have a dialogue.
Thank you.
Dialogue, questions and answers,
and the part I like the most,
chatting with all the people here,
the individuals,
and see what's rattling in their coconut.
So we'll see you shortly,
as soon as we get reset up.
Okay.
Hello, Doc.
Speak, sir.
Hello.
Would you please explain,
would you please explain,
you've explained about Luciferic,
and demonic energies.
Yeah.
Would you please explain,
something you talked about,
as far as the energy of confusion,
and how that affects us?
Generally the negative energies,
are considered to be Luciferic.
It's pridefulness,
arrogance,
seeking dominance, etc.
Seeking power for its own sake.
And satanic,
which is evil,
pain, and suffering,
and torture.
I think it's an esoteric concept.
There's a third,
and that is the energy of confusion.
Which is called the Braxic.
A-B-A-R-A-A-X-I-S-I-C.
I think it comes out of Alice Bailey.
Anyway,
it's the energy of confusion.
Confusion.
And disorder.
Everything goes wrong.
Nothing's on time.
Your zipper won't zip.
Everything is screwed up.
And no matter what you tell people,
they get it all wrong.
And,
it's an Abraxic energy.
The way you clear it is,
you deny its reality,
you deny its sovereignty.
But,
it's a Braxic energy.
And,
you deny its sovereignty.
And you say,
my life is under the control of divine order and harmony.
The reality of the self,
or the capital S,
is divine order and harmony,
rules my life.
And,
I hereby reject
confusion and disorder as a reality.
Yeah.
But,
you can see,
if you want to take over a population,
first thing you do is confuse them.
So,
that's what the political strategists do.
They have opposing grits of
power,
lock and then out of that confusion out of that confusion you can take control of the field
so if all the players are running in different directions it's obvious anybody's got his head
screwed on can take over dominance of the field it's called the bractic energy thank you thanks
for asking me that thank you doctor thank you susan that's enough hi doc yes i just want to
let you and susan know first of all that i really really love you guys and i so appreciate everything
that you are thank you um i have a comment for you and then a question um over the past few years i've
had the opportunity once a year to go to south africa and to teach workshops and i wanted to
teach workshops oh yes and i wanted you to know how that people are becoming aware how they're
reading your work
and the growth in consciousness that is happening there there is now
in cape town a study group south africa yes yes that's right they do correspond with us yes and
it's been beautiful to see um i have a question for you about mixing levels could you perhaps
elucidate a little bit more how to work with um the issue of mixing levels in a counseling setting
to help
help the client
understand especially when they don't have a very good framework of your work
in order to help them understand and get clarity
well
you can use uh... under what conditions is that
instead of level
you can say
under what conditions is this oh expected or
appropriate eh
and sometimes people mix levels and end up with confusion but so how do you understand 沒有
because what's appropriate or true in one context is not in another so I asked
them to refine the definitions okay and then in the definition of that which you
simply apply to the physical to their personal lives rather than the spiritual
context because some people don't seem to have as much of that spiritual
context to relate well they're just along the pathway mm-hmm you can use
simpler language you know okay you can create another big as-if or make-believe
situation and say now in that situation what would you do Oh how would you see
it so you can create an alternative and ask them how things look if that were so
in other words using their own framework to mirror it back to them yes or for
teaching purposes you can create a different framework okay you know I'd
say would you do something like that and then you can create a different framework
and then you can create a different framework okay you know I'd say if you're
if your life depended on it would you oh okay you will say I cannot give up a
certain thing or cannot give up a certain desire or something and I say
with the gun at your head now could you oh yes I could so the problem is not
that you can't is that you wouldn't well that makes it a different cup of tea say
I can't that closes the box it's not I can't is that I won't or I wouldn't I don't want to
it's that I won't or I wouldn't I don't want to
okay but you could thank you very much so what there you're trying to show them
that they have greater freedom than what they appreciate or what they're owning
as a possibility if they're not limited and how do you address the fragmentation
that sometimes happens when there is not adherence to our hair principle it seems
sometimes that the mixture of levels leads to fragmentation tremendous
fragmentation and confusion in the understanding yeah it does and they're
for you have to separate the levels and state them more differently you know
people say government monitoring your overseas emails that's an infringement of
freedom it's an infringement of freedom in peace times in war times I would
expect the government to do that yeah yeah hi doc thank you yes I have
something that's been coming up over the last well year and a half since I've
been to Sedona that is begins here this happens in group meditations and I've
been through a few levels of trying to identify what is this and surrender that
it's a physical energy it comes in as a like where you keep pointing to your
throat right well you mean is something experience in your throat it is and it
leads to a choking and a cough
do it talking well in us in a group silent meditation is when it's erupting
you feel like energy coming up to speak no it's lodged in your throat why do you
keep going like this what do you say because it comes in as like a sharp hot
piece directly right here and you yourself attacked your throat by teeth
no what is it you're describing can you please describe what you're describing
well as a
as it began arising I've flashed one time on a lifetime where I'd been hung
my head it drooped and fluids like this and forgave the one in myself the next
thing to come up was myself in a lifetime very devotionally praying I am
a sinner I'm a sinner yes and the guilt that
came on the heels of that was for some reason I haven't been able to lead an
was
I really needed your work
alright so give up being the center
yes
ok that's narcissism
when that
faded it's been a while
since it's come up and then
recently in a group
meditation boom here it was back up
in my face
and I'm wondering what is
the propensity through
that I'm plugging into
you said through your own past
lives you can sort of intuit it
so I would just meditate
on that sensation
and ask God to reveal to you
what it means
what it's symbolizing
yes
not so specific
as bringing up
the scenes of past lives that look
connected to it
I would be more gentle in prayer
more gentle
I would ask the Holy Spirit for the miracle
to understand
what it is that you're experiencing and what it means
that's all you have to do
ask for a miracle
to see it in a greater light
to reveal consciously
to my conscious mind
is there any significance in that
it will
be dependable within a group
setting
as I meditate alone
this doesn't arise
mhm
alright so that's the being
part of a group
and with others somehow
okay
that gives you sort of hints
but
yeah
you really need a revelation
to become aware of it
I do
yeah
help
thank you sweetheart
thank you dog
it comes forth of its own
when it's ready
yes
you can rattle the gates of heaven
a little bit
I think I'm ready
thank you
yes
I really just wanted to meet you
in person
yes
I've come from Australia
I've travelled around the world
yes
and
I am
extraordinarily happy to be here
with everybody
and
I wanted to thank you for your work
and for being in my life
and
I also wanted to ask
for a blessing
for myself
and for my friend James
and for everyone connected
thank you
I'm holding it in mind
God bless the divinity within you
and make you aware of that divinity
amen
blessing comes from the divinity within you
owning it and recognizing it
yeah
thank you
it's not different than life itself
yeah
thank you too
to have life itself
is the order to be blessed
is it not
yes
what was it
to have life itself
to realize that
one is
the
experience
the expression of divinity within oneself as
as life
that life and divinity are one and the same
life is indestructible
yeah
that's the one thing you're gonna have
is life
not gonna have the body
but you can have life
yeah
with life goes awareness
oh
that's divine gift
what do you want me to do
where did I get this
yes sir
yes indeed
look to Ron and here's this lady looking at me right there
laughter
she had a body somewhere
couldn't it be just a spirit
a lot of body
all the way from Australia
wow
I just came from down the street
but I also wanted to say thank you so much
laughter
thank you so much
thank you so much Susan
I've never had a picture with you
can I have one too
yes
thank you
well they took off the supersonic jets
which I've been mad about ever since
just cause a plane lost a tire on the runway
they gotta take off all the jets
not fair
oh you better
laughter
that's it
we blew it out somehow
didn't we
laughter