in excelsis Deo. Praise to thee, O Lord. Amen. Today we have a shocking subject. Unpopular
in current world. Very unpopular politically. The name of the subject is truth. So let's
see. We have the slides set up. And how many people here are new? Okay. All right. So in
that case, we'll recapitulate some of the beginning slides as usual. So we can set the
context. We always start with the map of consciousness. As you know, we evolved a relative scale from
one to a thousand. And it was possible then to calibrate everything that existed now or
ever on a calibratable scale. What the scale differentiates is essence rather than
scale. And that's the difference. And that's the difference between essence and
appearance. This is sort of a difficult concept. I noticed some people who have
attended lectures who don't get it. What a thing looks like and what it is are
often different. So we'll do slide 111 and then we'll go back to the map
because what people don't get conceptually I think they can get
visually. Don't tell me how wonderful somebody who calibrates at 120 is. Thank
you. So when we calibrate we're getting what is the essence and this is the
appearance and to differentiate the two happens automatically in the
conscious level about 600. The opening of the third eye of the Buddhic body it's
called esoterically. From that point on a person's picks up essence but until
below that it's very easy to fool them.
With illusion. Okay I just wanted to do 111 because it's such a cute slide. It's a
real find. So we go back to the slides the way they're supposed to be. Anyway
what we discovered is that people who are integrous will go weak in response
to that which is negative and strong in response to that which is positive. This
is a very fast response.
And in the acupuncture system we tend to get that we need to do three things.
One is we need to balance ourselves and the other is we need to do the exact
same thing we need to do a couple of things and the acupuncture system
quickly rebalances rebalances you. So you look at something horrific you go
weak for a second. However the body quickly corrects itself. So the response
that we use the strength of the muscle is a very fast response and a lot of
I have to quick touch her, because if you wait long enough, you lose the reflex.
So it's very, very quick.
Also, you can merely hold it in mind.
I can say what I'm holding in mind calibrates over 200, 250, 300, et cetera.
I don't have to tell her what I'm holding in mind.
That negates the suspicion that it's a suggestion or something.
But it's just an innate response, and we've given that its origin is in early emergence of animal life,
that the most primitive animal forms have some way to detect sources of energy.
So what we're calibrating are levels of energy.
And if an amoeba didn't know that that was negative or evil, he died.
So we don't have any amoebas that are stupid.
Because all the dumb ones kill themselves off.
You can only eat arsenic so many times, and then there won't be any more amoeba around.
So anyway, it was a means of protoplasm getting advanced information.
So you might say consciousness samples that which it witnesses
and differentiates that which is pro-life from that which is anti-life.
Now, people below 200 cannot.
They cannot do this because they are aligned not with life, but with that which is anti-life.
The lie, non-integrity, scheming, dishonesty, rape, pillage, murder, killing, et cetera.
So only people who calibrate high.
And the higher the people calibrate, the more accurate they are.
Some recent research came across my desk that was quite interesting.
The likelihood of error goes down as your own level of consciousness goes up.
All right.
That's enough chit-chat on all that.
Anyway, the map is finished worldwide.
It's used in a great variety of ways and about to be used even in some more significant ways.
All right.
It gives us the level of truth of an integrity.
It tells us what the essence, and that's enough about that.
Okay.
We'll move on to the next one.
Calibrated skill of consciousness.
Now, these are the circle slides, right?
Okay.
All right.
As you can see, those that calibrate the highest have to do with divinity, which are infinite, infinite.
These are all infinite.
And then they come down to the worldly realm, a thousand, et cetera.
These are the levels of enlightenment.
Now, you can see that we have a means of confirming.
All the aspects of divinity, all the aspects and qualities of divinity.
So you can see that the atheistic people would not be happy about this work.
And they aren't.
And every time you read a critical blog or something, I'll say, the originator of this blog believes in God.
No.
If you negate the source of truth, then you don't have the gift of truth.
You see?
So the way to tell whether somebody is integrous, and this is going to be coming up soon, I'll say,
are you willing to swear allegiance to God and your fellow man and your country?
And if the person refuses, they go in this pile over here.
You can't use a weight that doesn't have any springs in it.
You know what I'm saying?
Because there was somebody who was so dead.
Who hasn't said, this is my own, my native land.
Being unable to even love your fellow man puts you behind the eight ball when it comes to truth.
So in America, 50% of the people calibrate below 200.
Worldwide, it's more like 85%.
That's the bad news.
Okay, we'll move on to the next.
So this realm, this is the energy as you go up the scale of consciousness.
This is the energy.
This is the energy in microwatts.
So the power goes up the higher the level of truth and the higher the level of frequency.
And as one would expect from this, the calibration of God's power is infinite.
So we'll move to the next.
78% of the world's population, around 80% calibrates below 200.
We just want to show how this is the mass of humanity.
My father used to call it the great unwashed.
To my father, if you'd never read the great books of the Western world and didn't know Plato from Aristotle,
you belong to the great unwashed.
All right, so next slide.
This is the balance then, distribution of levels of consciousness of mankind.
And you see, this is the great mass of humanity, is it not?
And it's counterbalanced by just this small little cap here.
And the way this happens, the reason,
we don't self-destruct as a race,
is because the power of the few is greater than that of all the masses.
So the next slide shows that.
So the people who do calibrate high are so enormously more powerful
that they hold off the great masses who calibrate low, yes?
That's fortunate for survival, yeah.
We'll go on to the next.
Percent of...
Every last time, the evolution of consciousness,
this is a graph, which we'll have to correct
because now it's going to show a hook over here.
So we'll have to...
Because it went down again a little bit,
three or four points in the last few years.
Okay, next.
Then we see that the evolution over time,
these are archeologic ages,
we see how the energy field of life
rose progressively over great eons of archeologic time.
From the...
From the most primitive protozoa on up to the higher levels.
And next.
Then it evolved as well as you would expect in the animal kingdom.
And therefore you see bacteria, we use bacteria as one.
Protozoa, crustaceans, insects, arachnids, fish,
and the friendly octopus.
Then you get to the vipers, the Komodo dragon.
They always wear shoes when you get in there.
Cage.
Then you come to the predatory mammals, you see.
So at the lower levels, they live by the death of others.
Then we get to the level of 200.
And there you see a transition to the herbivores,
people who are benign
and live not at the cost of the life of others.
So the herbivores are the grazers,
and they form the feedstuff for the more voracious ones.
And you get up to farmhorses and racehorses.
You get to dogs.
Now what can you say about people who hate dogs?
I don't know.
It's really hard to handle a 245.
And of course a dog's wagging tail is 500.
Right now there's people that abuse dogs in the news, right?
Right.
Getting them to fight with each other.
So family dog.
The family dog calibrates at 250.
So once a cat or a dog, or I suppose other pets,
are around human beings, their consciousness evolves.
Their consciousness evolves.
So a family dog calibrates higher than a wild dog.
And the monkeys, of course, we love them.
And then we have the gorillas and the chimps.
And then we have these exceptional animals, Coco, the trained gorilla,
and remember the gorilla picking up the child that fell into the cage.
I mean, it was really quite something.
Then we come to the capacity for love.
You see, the cat's purr and the dog's wagging tail is actually love.
The kitty loves you.
You love the kitty.
And they actually love you back.
They love you back.
Isn't that amazing?
An animal can love you.
So you're safe.
You're safer with a loving kitty and a loving wagging tail dog
than you are with over 50% of the people on the planet.
That's enough to give you a moment of thought, right?
You're safer with a cat and a dog than you are with 50% of the people on the planet.
Wow.
So you want to avoid naivete.
Naivete.
Okay.
Realizing that, you won't be taken advantage of and become a victim.
The great books of the Western world, as I've already mentioned,
represent scholasticism, the best thinking from ancient Greece,
down through time, through the period of the Enlightenment.
The last one, I think, in this series is Freud.
Right.
But they set intellectual excellence.
And it was, this was the backbone of the liberal education and the best universities.
All calibrated around 440, 450.
Because you can see the mean of all this is around 450.
Darwin is 450.
Then you have some exceptionals, like Descartes is at 490.
And then the only dropouts here are Marx at 130 and Engels.
And if you look at the...
If you look at the impact of the work of Marx on mankind,
you'll see the difference of the impact of 130.
Tens of millions, hundreds of millions of people starved to death
due to Marxism, North Korea, China, wherever it's been tried.
So it's in the eating of the pudding.
So the eating of the pudding here has been, represents what, 130 as a lifestyle.
So these are the great names.
These are the names of history and the world I grew up in, liberal education.
You were supposed to be familiar with the contents of, at least the gist of all this work.
The source of capitalism, calibrates at 440, published in 1817 by, Gabe knows.
Gabe, who published it?
Huh?
Smith.
What's his first name?
Adam Smith.
Yes, yes, yes.
So the essence of capitalism calibrates at 440.
The structure of it is at 440.
And Marxism, the structure of it is at 130.
So you would just say, sight unseen without a field test,
I think I'll put my money, I think I'll put my money here.
People who calibrated Enron and Brocom,
remember all the overnight millionaires on their computers,
I've made millions and millions buying these stocks on margin.
Well, they calibrated at 190, Brocom and Enron.
And Walmart, everybody hates Walmart, calibrated at 400, no, 360.
So if you put your money in Walmart at 360 or you put it in Enron or Brocom,
you can see that these numbers are, you can see that these numbers are,
these numbers have a very real significance and usefulness.
They're not just hypothetical, they're theoretical.
So there's many utilizations of this, and we'll cross some more next.
This is something else that's difficult to convey, that there is content.
You see a thing happening in the world, but that thing is not happening in a vacuum.
That thing is happening within an overall energy,
energy field of local phenomena, and then of infinite phenomena called context.
So content is what's happening, but content is subject to context.
This is going to be important when we discuss truth,
because the world has tried to describe truth without appreciating the fact that
a thing is only true within a certain context.
What this looks like depends on the,
the shadow and the coloration, whether you're at war or not at war,
for instance, changes it all together.
Okay, next.
This is important, we'll get to it later.
Quantum mechanics.
You see, the world was pretty Newtonian, cause and effect,
it still is in the majority of science.
Quantum mechanics came along and expanded the paradigm of the universe,
and most importantly for our people with a spiritual understanding,
we're going to talk about quantum mechanics.
What's happening?
Is the Heisenberg effect.
The Heisenberg uncertainty principle is that potentiality can collapse to actuality,
the collapse of the way function from wave to particle.
Those, so things can exist as a potentiality
as a wave, or you can collapse it to an actuality, the particle.
And what does this is intention.
so an observed phenomena is different than an unobserved phenomena and once a
phenomenon is observed it's already been changed and there's a you'll find
Henry's step you can get his new book for free on the internet expands our
paradigm of reality to include the field of consciousness itself and the theory
is that what keeps the universe in its current form is that it is representing
an expression of consciousness move on next yep the difference between the two
populations in the world is not just hypothetical theoretical it's actual
because it results in different brain physiology
integrus people energized by love
love
the brain functions their brain puts out endorphins endorphins they're able to
conceive of the nonlinear domain the skeptic can't even conceive of the
nonlinear domain and because endorphins bring pleasure and peace you end up with
a healthier body as well below 200 you you're dealing with your animal brain so
as you see the animal
brain is set for fight or flight it's going to react with adrenaline and
hatred anger and wanting dominance speaking of hegemony or hegemony all of
nature seeks to dominate every wolf pack every civilization even every intellectual
pattern seeks to dominate because that's the law of survival the tribe that dominates survives
so it's instinctual to want to dominate but within limits so here you see the left brain that is
releasing and door adrenaline all the time and it's catabolic the right brain is anabolic and
tends to bring about love and nonlinear capacities to understand spiritual reality so the spiritual
students center people who have crossed over from this paradigm to this paradigm and are operating
off this paradigm okay the rate of happiness aside from sociological theories we see that the rate of
happiness is almost a hundred percent aligned with a person's level of consciousness if I know what
a person's level of consciousness I could tell you the likelihood of their being happy at 100 only
10% of the people are happy.
Here are some very famous people
on current television
talk shows,
130 to 160.
Their chances of being happy are around 12%.
So, anyway.
The rate of happiness, then,
is not due to something out there,
but it's due to what you have
become. So you can
be happy under miserable circumstances
and commit suicide
in the midst of luxury.
So the rate of
happiness, then, is a direct
result of one's level
of consciousness.
As you move up, you need less and less.
You want less and less.
Somebody says, is there anything you want
today?
No.
Anything you need. I got it.
So what you need and have,
you know, you got already.
So the chance of being happy, then,
is pretty good.
All right. So we'll move on.
If you want nothing,
then you get along
with less and less.
You get along with less and less.
When I first came out here, as I told you,
I had a six-pack of Pepsi and a piece of cheese in the fridge
and celebrated Saturday night
by splitting an apple with a friend of mine.
I said,
tonight we'll have an apple. Oh, wow, he says.
Big time, have an apple.
All right. So now we'll get to
the actual subject for today.
What is truth?
All right. Truth is different than
the last lecture was on reality,
which is linear
and has to do with facts.
Has to do with facts. Provable facts.
Truth, as you can see,
is more abstract.
More abstract. It's more than
just a fact.
Truth is a more
abstract notion
with sort of philosophic,
metaphysical overtones.
Huh?
First,
the first thing we notice
in the great books of the Western world,
I mentioned Descartes,
who pointed out the difference between
perception and essence
between the lamb
and the sheep and the wolf.
He said,
Descartes,
the problem is the difference
between res interna and res
externa, meaning
the world as you see it
as compared to the world
as it is.
And there's a barrier there between.
So the capacity to see what actually is,
is limited and relatively unusual.
Most people go by opinion.
Res interna, that is my idea of the world,
the way I see the world.
And of course, that's the famous argument
referred to in Plato.
Protagoras says, well, the world I see is my reality
and the world that you see is your reality.
And then he made the incorrect assumption.
Therefore, there is no ultimate reality.
He should have said,
which proves that I am dumb.
And the fact that people have different opinions
doesn't mean there's different realities.
They're just different perceptions.
Yeah.
Okay.
Socrates' dictum is all that any spiritual student needs.
Socrates' dictum was that man chooses
only the good.
And it's just that he doesn't know
how to comprehend the difference between the real good
and the illusory good.
But every man is choosing the good.
So if you think it's good to blow you all up,
then that's his idea of good.
Good is killing all such people because you're all infidels.
So to be able to forgive would require, then,
a recognition of that inner reality,
that each person is seeking what
they believe to be the good and, therefore,
capable of salvation.
Yes?
In today's world, however, popularity
reigns and the herd instinct, the media bias,
and, of course, the memes, which are the repeated phrases that
are repeated often enough.
If you take a lie and repeat it often enough,
people will believe it.
People will believe a lie if you just repeat it often enough.
You say, oh, no, I wouldn't do that.
Yes, you will, under experimental conditions.
By the end of the experiment, I'll
have you convinced that your front is your back
and your back is your front.
All right.
Of course, the world's great dictators
have depended on this, you see.
Media bias.
And, of course, the extraordinary popular
Delusions and the Madness of Crowds
by Mackie.
It was written, I don't know, in the late 1700s, I think.
Gives examples of how the whole world believes a certain thing
and it turns out to be illusion.
And, of course, he used the tulip craze in Holland.
I like this because you say, well, everybody
couldn't be wrong.
Certainly, global warming is due to man,
extraordinary popular delusions.
Everybody believes that.
It's man that causes global warming.
Right, yeah.
All right, so everybody believes it.
It's a popular delusion.
Everybody believes it, yeah.
And it's due to the slant.
It's due to ignoring the fact that these things are,
that the temperature of the Earth,
it reflects the magnetic activity
on the surface of the sun for tens of thousands of years.
And what man is doing is contributing contamination,
contamination.
But contamination is not warming, global warming.
If you fly over the United States,
you quickly leave the populated area.
And you then fly for hours and hours over nothingness,
thousands and thousands of miles of nothing.
There's no people there creating pollution.
So pollution is caused by people,
and global warming is due to something else.
All right, so that makes you a heretic, you see.
Very people.
Few people care to be a heretic and considered a madman.
That's because of political slant.
So in our world, truth is overridden by political slant.
And as Bush said, money trumps peace, right?
Money trumps peace.
Politics and money, then, dominate our society.
So the confusion of truth with these previous things
is that it's confused with opinion and faith and belief
systems and data, which is often false.
Secondhand smoke is also another illusion.
And the federal court actually threw it out
as stupid junk science.
Smoking's bad for you, but secondhand smoke
has no bad effect whatsoever.
So anyway, that makes you a heretic, you see,
because the ordinary popular delusions has people convinced.
And this has to do with the fact that we're not going to be
able to get rid of the fact that these studies are well funded.
So if I want to get some money out of the government,
I just conjure up something.
The secondhand smoke causes schizophrenia, right?
And I'll get the money.
If I put out a paper that secondhand smoke is not
related to schizophrenia, you won't get any money.
So political slant, then, influences science, you know?
So that's what we mean by falsified data.
Falsified data, I could give you better selections
of falsified data, which the medical world doesn't even
know, and the world doesn't even know.
They'll say, well, a certain treatment only
works 5% of the time.
So it's worthless.
Or another treatment only works 50% of the time.
What they fail to see is from that selected population, the 5%
is 100% of that group.
If you know how to select in the group,
the recovery rate is 100%.
If I tell people who are depressed,
stop eating sugar and sweets,
probably 40% will recover.
Let's see how many will recover.
If we take people that walk into the clinic,
they're depressed,
over 30% of function hypoglycemia,
35%, 40%.
Okay, so about 35% of people
will recover from depression
if they stop eating sugar and sweets.
So in that subgroup,
your recovery rate is 100%.
So you can't say sugar-free diets are worthless.
If you try them in a large group of people,
you'll get a small recovery,
the population at large.
But amongst the select group,
your recovery rate is 100%.
So the clinician is one who can intuit
and by lots of experience over many years,
sort of get which group
to choose.
Which this person falls into, see?
Which one he falls into.
And when I used to get appointments made by phone,
I'd say stop eating sugar and sweets
and take a lot of vitamin B3
and I'll see you in a week, see?
And about half the time,
by the time they walked into the office,
I'd say, I don't know why I'm here, doc.
It's cool now.
Anxiety attacks and depression
are very often functional hypoglycemia.
The body puts out too much insulin.
All right, so you want to avoid things
that create insulin.
So if you switch from glucose and sucrose to fructose,
the hypoglycemia goes away.
Fruit sugar does not stimulate an insulin response.
So you see, it doesn't cost anything at all.
The cost to the taxpayer is nothing.
And the likelihood of success is extremely high
if you know how to pick the subgroup.
So I'm just pointing out the source,
the fallacies of data.
The data will say that, well, this is no good.
It only cures 10%.
But that 10%, the cure rate is 100.
It's an historic human deficiency,
the incapacity to tell truth from falsehood.
We now corroborate truth by calibration.
So for the first time really in history,
we have an objective means of verifying truth.
And as you can see from that previous diagram,
truth is dependent on context,
and understanding of truth is level of consciousness.
To truly know a thing is actually to be aware.
To know a thing is to be aware.
Rather than to know about it.
So lots of people know about certain subjects,
but to know it, you have to become it.
You have to become it.
To know, you know about hermits,
but unless you're a hermit,
you don't know what it is to be a hermit.
It's very hermity to be a hermit, yes.
In our society, you have the impact of the media,
which is enormous,
and caters to narcissism.
And narcissism, what is that?
It's projectionism.
It's projected self-interest.
In other words, you've already salted the mind,
you've already decided on the outcome,
and now you go back and cite some incident.
This typifies our current society,
is almost 100% narcissistic.
Almost 100%.
Media are completely narcissistic.
Everything is sold.
The Me Tube, the iTube, the YouTube.
You're in nature.
YouTube, there's only Me Tube.
So narcissism is self-interest.
And the bias that comes across is just constant.
And if you're aligned with truth and integrity
and logic,
it's just very difficult listening to the news.
Because almost every single political statement
is distorted.
Almost every political statement leaves out
a key word that would totally change your picture.
And that's why they purposely leave that out.
Yeah.
So a projected self-interest.
You could say, why is everybody so interested
that the whole world should agree with them
and that the world should go along with what they think?
You know what I mean?
I mean, what's the gain?
What's the gain?
There isn't any.
It feeds on itself.
Narcissism feeds on itself.
If everybody agrees with you,
now your sense of importance goes up.
So it's your sense of importance
that dominate the field.
It creates a sense of self-interest.
In the animal world,
dominate brings about survival.
it doesn't necessarily lead to survival at all.
It very often leads to its opposite.
Narcissism distorts.
Projected self-interest.
And all you get out of it is a sense of grandiosity.
A sense of grandiosity.
If everybody agrees with my research,
then I'm a great and happy person.
And if they don't,
then I'm a miserable failure, right?
I mean, that's the way the ego works.
So people then want to propagate
their own belief systems on others
because they get an immediate payoff.
Everybody has to think the way they think.
All mentation, however,
reflects a limitation.
The mind is really unable, by its design,
to be able to discern truth from falsehood.
The brain is like a hardware of the computer.
And the mentation is like the software.
All mentation reflects limitation.
So whatever you think is already a limitation.
Whatever you think.
It's what you are
that transcends the limitation.
The capacity to know truth is already limited,
as you can see from the diagram on brain physiology,
that brain function itself
limits the capacity to understand
and comprehend reality and truth
amongst people that are below 200.
Half the population, therefore,
is frankly, intrinsically,
by virtue of brain physiology,
unable to comprehend abstract truth,
anything 200 and up.
And that has to do with context.
So the errors that you see
day after day after day on the television
has to do with this limitation of brain function,
of calibration levels below 200,
who have their own heroes
and political parties and belief systems
and their own cheering sections.
They have their own block sites.
The worst block site I know of calibrates at 90.
And it sort of specializes in hatred.
Specializes.
I won't even tell you the name,
but it's so awful,
I don't want you to even glance at it.
Specializing in hatred.
Specializing in hatred, you can see.
Now what could people get out of putting
all that hateful stuff on there?
All of it lies, all of it hateful,
all of it derogatory,
all of it fallacious.
What could a person get out of that?
They get being who they are.
The naivete, the human mind.
Or I was saying, what's their motive?
Folks, they don't have any motive.
We're the few people on the planet
to understand this.
They don't have any motive at all.
There isn't a motive.
There's a guy named, what was his name, KOS,
that killed all the people in some university
and had a hate video that he put on
and he just ranted hate.
Wasn't he the Virginia Tech killer or somebody?
Lowest I've ever calibrated.
Five.
People say, well, he must have had a troubled childhood.
His mother must have had a troubled childhood.
What's the motive of a serial killer?
What's the motive behind wickedness?
There isn't any.
They're just being what they are.
There's no motive.
There's no bad childhood
that caused their resentment,
that caused maybe so-and-so,
and if we just get them a good therapist,
he'll be okay.
As one of those people,
what would I do with a therapist?
I'd kill them.
They deserve to die
because they're saying there's something wrong with me.
So I will have to kill them.
Why?
Because that's who I am.
Identity defines essence.
Tell them the story about the frog.
The frog and something rides on his back.
Who rides on his back?
Tell us the story.
Oh, the scorpion rides on the back of the frog.
Wasn't that it?
Tell them the story.
Come on, tell them that story.
I demand it.
I can't remember.
It's been so long since I told you.
Tell me that story.
How does that go?
There was a frog and a scorpion,
and the scorpion went across the pond.
So he got on top of the back of the frog.
Oh.
And as they're going across the pond,
the scorpion, he says,
now, you will not sting me, will you?
And the scorpion says,
no, I won't sting you.
I won't sting you.
And they're going across the pond,
and all of a sudden,
the scorpion stings the frog.
And of course, he's dying,
and he says,
you said you wouldn't sting me.
He says, why'd you sting me?
And he goes,
that's because that's what I am.
That's right.
That's what people don't get.
Because I am a scorpion.
That's why.
That's because that's what I am.
So you see,
in dealing with,
in dealing with people and political systems
which wish to extinguish you,
extinguish you all,
everybody in here is an infidel.
Everybody.
You all deserve to die.
That's the proclamation
of America's enemies right now.
All right.
Is there a motive?
Not really.
Because that's what that energy does
and how it sees the world.
I can't say it's anybody's fault,
nor do I wish to blame anybody at all.
But it,
sometimes spiritual alignment
leads to a naivete and a denial
and sort of a wimpism
that's supposed to be peace marches and all.
Best thing to do, folks,
with a peace march
is to blow them the hell up.
All right.
To call a spade a spade
is not politically popular in today's world
where euphemisms are used to distort images
and cover up the underlying reality.
Okay.
So we'll go to the next slide.
So what we believe to be truth
is subject to programming
and indoctrination.
And of course,
one of the dangers of today's world
is the indoctrination of the youth
of other people,
other cultures
that are out to kill us.
Huh?
Programming and indoctrination.
And today's,
this week's news
is the Mickey Mouse cartoon
currently in Islam.
Mickey Mouse
for a long time
just shouted,
shouted Haiti of America.
But Mickey Mouse became
liked by the children
over in those Islamic societies.
And in the last edition
a week ago,
the Israelis murdered Mickey Mouse.
So the news media
all over now
is how horrible
Americans and Israelis
and all are.
They murdered,
they slaughtered him.
They murdered Mickey Mouse.
If I was some little kid
in another culture
and watched Mickey Mouse
being slaughtered,
I would hate those people,
wouldn't you?
All right.
So that's,
that's inculcated hatred,
inculcated hatred.
And Nazi propaganda minister Goebbels
was the world's best at that.
He compared Jews to worms
and mice and rats
and things like this.
And he did it visually.
So a picture,
you've already been programmed.
I just want you to get
how fast your mind is programmed.
The minute you see that picture,
you just got programmed.
You say, nobody's programming me.
You've already been programmed.
It's got programmed.
All I have to do
is one image of that.
You just had it.
You just got imprinted
with that image.
Yeah.
Therefore,
the chances of arriving
at a capacity
to discern truth
and stand for truth
and live a life of truth,
you see how slim it is
in today's world
under the sheer media barrage.
So the human mind
is subject to programming
and constant indoctrination,
constant indoctrination.
Truth is different than,
truth has to do with
what does the thing mean.
You can define a thing,
you can give its linear definition,
but then,
what does it mean?
So that brings us
to the hermeneutics of abstraction.
Hermeneutics.
That's the science
or philosophy of meaning.
What does a thing mean?
Hermeneutics.
Remember I discussed
the problematic hermeneutics
of relativistic epistemology?
I've never gotten a blog
or an email
criticizing me for that.
Not a one
has ever contested.
Sometimes,
then I get an answer,
but I don't know
what the answer is.
I don't know
Sometimes,
then I get a nasty email.
I said,
well,
you'll find that out
if you study the
problematic
hermeneutics
of relativistic epistemology.
Yeah,
that's right.
You can't criticize a thing
until you understand it.
That doesn't keep
bloggers from off there.
I don't know
what they do with themselves
all evening.
I say that,
but to me,
a blogger is somebody
who reads something
they don't like
and they just go,
snort.
Well,
if you,
you dumb AA,
which immediately gets
picked on everybody's
blog site
and quoted.
So,
you can't criticize
the thing
unless you can first
comprehend it.
So,
when people criticize
some things I've written,
I'll say,
first read the book,
then let me hear it from you.
And when we use
the RMI,
we ask,
do they read the book?
We always got to know.
All the people
who criticize it,
over 2%
have read it.
Over 3%,
5%,
4%,
3%,
3%
have at least
tried to read the book.
It's hard reading,
I know.
So,
meaning,
and we know
what the fact,
we know
what the facts are,
and we know
what the truth is,
but what does that mean?
What does that mean?
What's the implication?
So,
when you talk
about meaning,
you're talking
about now levels
of abstraction.
What does
it mean?
Well,
it means
it's one thing
to this
or that,
but what does it
actually mean?
So,
that's the
capacity
for abstraction.
Now,
below 200,
the people
do not have
the capacity
for abstraction.
They are,
deal only
in the pedestrian,
limited
idea
of causality,
reductive
materialism.
So,
if it's not
provable
within a very
limited
paradigm,
then it's
fallacious.
And you know
that famous
guy that was
in the
Phoenix newspaper
that's written
four or five
books claiming
that Einstein
is a fraud.
And he keeps
writing more
books about
Einstein being
a fraud.
What he doesn't
get is that
he doesn't
understand
Einstein's
work.
He doesn't
understand it.
Okay.
All right.
Hermeneutics
of abstraction
is the
context,
context.
And to be
pedestrian
means to
only see
the content,
to see
the linear
concrete
content.
What does it
mean?
It can only
be viewed
from the
level of
consciousness
itself.
Meaning is
like significance.
What is the
significance
of that
for mankind
or for
myself?
This is
a
question
that
I
have
been
asked
a
number
of
times
in my
life.
I
have
been
asked
a
number
of
times
in my
life.
And I
have
been
asked
a
number
of
times in
my life
to
see
the
context
of
what
I
feel
about
myself.
And I
think
that
really
changes
the
likelihood
of
your
making
certain
choices.
So a
tension
set
live one day at a time, you know. Forgive and forget. Live one day at a time. Easy does it.
Live and let live. Paddle your own canoe. Instead of trying to paddle others. So
this becomes a mental habit, a mental habit, and it influences probability,
whereas mathematically the probability is of a different dimension. Once the
attention set begins to set in, probability is that you're going to pick
a peaceful solution more and more often. Also you will not be happy with the
resentment. You may get over resentment, you may juice it for a little while, but
eventually you find that you don't like living with it. So instead of getting
even with the person, what you do is say, I can see that that person just couldn't
know any better at the time, at the time. In the situation area, and that's the way
it seemed to them, it seemed to them, you know, that they
should get even with you, or get that parking space, or whatever it is. Buy the
last copy of, what's the name of the book that's out now? Harry Potter. Get to the
bookstore, the last Harry Potter just got sold out. So attention set then
influences our habitual choice, and we favor that which is more and more
peaceful and loving. So peacefulness and lovingness then give it to be habitual.
So that's why people say what can I do for world peace and to solve the world's
problems, etc. And I would say to be as loving as possible towards all that
exists, and to walk over the little black beetle instead of squishing him. You're
already serving God in the world by saving his little life, because out of
compassion you don't want to extinguish life unless you're actually forced to. So
the influence of attention set is actually a
physiologic,
neurologic phenomena so by consistently making certain choices your neurologic
set your neurologic propensities the way the neurons are being to fire begin to
fire more and more favorably in a certain direction the more often you
pick something negative the more likely it is you're going to pick the negative
again and we notice that negative human behaviors tend to be rather fixed the
way to pick up a criminal is to stop any car on the road at night that has a
taillight out any couple theta the sign of a criminal is a taillights out why
because that's the whole lifestyle and it's a dead giveaway and hitchhikers on
the highway it's the same so attention set then influences choice now the
context of the problem is that the way you pick up a criminal is to stop any
content is subject to context and part of context is time and history before you
make a thing wrong you have to look what it were the circumstances so a better
word might be circumstances the person said that under duress or they said that
because they were running for president whatever if you're ready for president
then you can buy anything you're running for public office you can lie about
anything and everybody says well I don't know I don't know I don't know I don't
know but you'll be funny when you get here like to do this yes that's the
context of the problem and so you just have to look it over the history and
you'll be funny when you get here you'll be funny and you'll be funny yeah
what does that exactly mean to do so you're trying to do this on the right
path and all of a sudden if you're standing on the road you just have to
listen you're just going to say this is not the right path you're not gonna do
it and you're going to have to deal with it and you're gonna have to think about
not subject to time or circumstances.
What is intrinsically so and true forever through all time?
You might say that God is the creator of the universe,
is so under all circumstances for all time.
The fact that every hair on your head should be counted is true.
Whether you believe it or not is different,
but the truth is not subject to circumstances.
Let's just reconfirm that one because I like that one.
You're responsible.
Every hair on your head should be counted.
Resist.
See?
That's why it's risky to trust people who don't believe in God
because people who believe in God know they're accountable.
Judgment day will arrive, et cetera.
People who don't believe in God, what's the consequences of lying?
Nothing.
If a person doesn't believe in God, why not lie?
You should lie.
There are whole cultures that tell you that you should lie,
and if you don't lie, you get beaten when you get home.
You're supposed to tell the tourists that this is a genuine antique
and get $50 for it.
It's mass produced.
It costs them $1.50.
But if you don't convince them that it's a real antique and get $50,
you actually get beaten when you get home, right?
So that's a different kind of a culture.
You're not answerable to God at all,
and therefore you can say and do anything you want.
So you can't really trust on a certain level.
You can trust their likelihood of their behaving a certain way,
but in the ultimate, you can't really trust
because if you're not accountable to God for your behavior,
then you're only into pragmatic using others.
So Werner had a very interesting definition,
and I remembered it all those years.
I forget when Werner was around.
Back in the early 70s, I think.
Wasn't it early 70s?
71, 72?
Everybody did Est.
It was a great experience.
It got people.
The purpose of Est was to get people over 200,
to stop giving alibis, to stop being fake,
and accept the fact that, yeah, you are,
you are a rotten father, or you're a bum teacher.
That's a fact.
Stop pretending you're a big star.
Yeah.
What is so all the time everywhere?
So there is a statement that's independent of context
and timing and sequence.
Truth then brings up the subjective and experiential
that's within versus that which is demonstrable.
So truth can be an existent reality,
but it's subjective and not provable.
The experience of the mystic is not provable.
It's confirmable by consciousness calibration,
but it's not provable.
So the subjective and the experiential
is a whole different field of reality,
reality and truth,
from that which is demonstrable and linear.
This brings up paradigm allegiance.
People become confined to a certain stratosphere,
you might, a certain content, context rather,
in which they try to corral all their,
their understandings of everything.
They try to put it in a certain paradigm.
The pedestrian, materialistic reductionism,
which deals with provable content in the notorious sense,
which deals with content in the Newtonian paradigm,
then, is a paradigm allegiance.
And people become very disturbed
if you try to talk to them about more abstract concepts.
And they'll say that's all, whoa, whoa.
I got a job one time in a clinic.
I covered for psychiatrists being gone.
I covered a clinic in Codwood Friday afternoons
because they were short of doctors there.
And when the guy who ran the place asked me where I lived,
I said, uh, it's Sedona.
He says, oh, all the woo-woos.
I had to be careful not to talk about anything
that wasn't literal concrete.
He would think that I'm a woo-woo.
Well, it's true.
There are a lot of woo-woos in Sedona.
They're always seeing flying saucers and stuff.
There are a lot of woo-woos in Sedona, yeah.
Yeah, that's true.
Anyway, I'll never forget his saying that.
He looked at me.
He said, woo-woos.
That's the way he said it.
Meaning not practical, not down to earth.
So there's a certain paradigm allegiance.
And there's a limitation of paradigm of what's possible
and what's real.
I'm trying to present some work right now to a group
that's probably pretty just Newtonian ordinary consciousness
that entails comprehending quantum mechanics.
And...
The problem is not in explaining it.
The problem is my understanding how would you present
advanced quantum theory to somebody who is still Newtonian
in their thinking pattern.
You see, because when we do consciousness calibration,
there's no here and there.
In the quantum, infinite quantum reality,
which is identical with consciousness itself,
the field of consciousness,
there is no here or there.
There is no now or then.
There is no future or past.
An infinite universe has no center.
There is no middle of everythingness.
There's no beginningness.
There's no endingness.
There's no here and there.
There's then and now and no future.
And all time is now.
All time is now.
All places are here.
Everybody get that?
Everywhere, wherever you are,
it's the same as anybody else because
here I'm the center of the universe,
in an infinite universe,
but here I'm also in the center of the universe
because an infinite universe has no center.
That's why consciousness calibration works.
It's because you're picking up essence,
and essence is not dependent on
time, location, or causality.
With consciousness calibration,
what you're doing is you're reading the essence
of a thing at a distance.
At a distance, you're holding the concept
of what I'm looking at right now.
Then I don't have to go from here to there,
and I can, because I've done it millions of times,
thousands of times, I can just about guess
what it's going to calibrate.
I can just guess because I've done it a lot of times.
What I'm looking at calibrates over 200, 201, 205.
What I'm looking at calibrates at 200,
is what I got when I looked at it,
the cement pillar.
The human body calibrates at 200,
so does nature, and so does planet Earth.
Forget the divinity of planet Earth,
it calibrates at 200.
It's dirt.
Oh, Lord, oh, dirt.
We should lay down human life to serve dirt.
Environmentalists, burn up houses,
kill people for the sake of dirt.
Dirt.
Dirt's 200.
It's not worth killing a rabbit for dirt.
Rabbit calibrates harder than dirt.
The human body, there's no point in worshipping that either.
The human body calibrates at exactly 200.
The human body calibrates from dust you arise
and from dust you return.
So there's no point in being a narcissistic,
worshipping the human body and all its glory,
and all its glory.
She's going to be dust in a few years.
Came from dust, baby, you're going back to dust,
so forget all that fancy stuff, you know.
Your body is the same as cement, dirt,
roots of weeds.
200, yeah.
200 is neutral on the level of consciousness.
It's neutral.
So what you make of it is up to you from here.
You can plant flowers in it,
or you can dump refuse in it.
So it's really respect for your fellow man,
not for the earth.
A lot of people think that humanity should be eliminated
so that we can return the earth to its pristine nature.
A lot of environmentalists think that, you know.
Man should be destroyed.
I think PETA, the guy who founded that,
who's a woo-woo.
That's a real woo-woo.
Intellectuals.
There's a book, Intellectual Morons,
which I just love the book,
because it just gives you the details
on idiots that you know are idiots,
but you didn't know all the details of how the...
PETA, yeah.
We should kill all humans,
kill all humans so we can give the world back
to the dinosaurs, I guess.
Dinosaurs like to eat people.
There weren't many people around at the time of dinosaurs.
The dinosaurs ate them all.
People are nummy.
So let's see.
Cultural norms.
So we have paradigm allegiance.
Cultural norms decide what's right and wrong
and unfortunately are also used to define truth and falsehood.
So a cultural norm is very much a propagandized politicalization
and therefore what's normal in one environment
is not normal in another.
Cultural norms.
Dictate, then, behaviors.
So what would pass as okay on a beach here
would get you arrested over in an Arabic country,
put away, probably killed,
stoned to death, actually.
You try that over there and you get put away.
The allegorical versus the literal,
which means the letter versus the spirit of the law.
The letter versus the spirit of the law.
And one of the most frequent,
most frequent political tricks
is to distort the spirit of the law
under the guise of being the letter of the law or vice versa.
The letter versus the spirit of the law.
Right now, there are signs everywhere.
If you see anything suspicious, please report it.
That instantly brought up, as was put into the design.
Let's just see if that was a design.
That was a conscious design,
what I'm holding in mind, resist.
Huh?
Five more minutes.
We have five more minutes of what?
She's always telling me the end of the world is at hand
and she's always been wrong, you know.
The world's going to end in five minutes.
All right.
An evolved mind instantly spots fallacy.
Let's take the flying M.M.s.
The flying M.M.s.
Flying M.M.s.
was complete deception
from the origination.
Resist.
It was all preset.
Care set up the legal reaction to it.
The whole thing was designed and advanced.
So, the thing with the integrious people
is they tend to be naive.
If you're not held together by truth,
then deviousness becomes a standard tool.
A standard tool.
You set these people up to imitate
what in history was a devastating experience
in the United States.
You set them up to imitate
because you know what the response will be.
Care already was set up to soothe the people
who, you know,
picture these guys as being dangerous.
Imitating it to the point of the seat belt extenders.
They weren't just wandering down the aisle saying,
gee, I need a seat belt extender, folks.
None of them were fat.
So, the weakness of America is this naiveness.
It doesn't think in devious,
diabolical terms.
It doesn't think how can I set this up
so as to create a reaction.
And out of that reaction,
you won't be able to ever finger a terrorist again
because you'll always be racial profiling.
If they're all coming from a certain culture,
you can't say anything about any of them
without being sued.
So, the defenders came up on television the other night
and said, yes,
I love the protection of a court of law.
You've never been sued, folks.
You're going to lose your house.
You're going to lose your car.
There's going to be arguments.
You're going to end up with a divorce.
It's not whether you're going to win in court.
Lawyers get $300 an hour.
We get billed $300 an hour.
They say, can't you fax this guy
and tell him, no, we can't do it within 30 days?
They do.
You get a bill for $80.
So, the idea of this new law
was to keep you from being sued
so that you don't get wiped out
by being sued because you're reporting.
All the signs in the airports,
they report anything suspicious, don't they?
Having a gun in your pocket,
is that suspicious?
Anyway, there you see a naivete sets us up.
So, you can see goodness in itself,
to some degree,
but there's a certain downside
in that if you just become going to denial
because of your own good inclinations towards others.
So, to be spiritual doesn't mean to be stupid.
That's all I'm telling you this morning.
To be stupid doesn't mean you got to be dumb.
Stupid.
You don't have to be blind.
You don't have to be ignorant.
You can be very bright and alert.
So, the more your consciousness evolves,
the more you're willing to look at the downside of things
and say to yourself,
hey, looks to me like a setup.
It's because you yourself are integrous and honest
that you want to know what the truth is.
I don't want to make them wrong at it.
On the contrary, I compliment them.
It was a beautiful piece of stage work.
Beautiful. Beautiful.
It also tells you how cunning what you're up against.
The impact, how they would respond,
the legalities, the counter suit.
And what you're seeing was totally calculated in advance.
Completely calculated in advance.
So, I'm just saying not to be naive
just because you're spiritual.
Sometimes people are spiritually going to denial and naivete.
They're worried about the, you know,
the things that are never going to happen
and saving the earth and all those things.
So, we just wanted to use the artistic of truth.
And talk about some of the things in today's world.
Because spiritually evolved people and students
don't live in a vacuum.
We don't all live in an ashram someplace
detached from the world.
We all are subject every day to this pounding by the media
and the politicized media.
So, we have, how do you become,
how do you stay in a spiritual alignment with truth
in a world that is not aligned with truth
is the problem of modern man.
And that's the subject of the book I'm working on
and finishing right now.
Spirituality and Modern Man.
So, we'll take a break, yeah?
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
Well, we've already revealed more than all the world
has known throughout all of time.
Which is a good start for the morning.
Questions arise in people's minds.
And of course we'll have questions
and answers this afternoon.
But if there's anything really pressing
just put your hand up and we'll stop the locomotive
and try to handle something pressing.
Pressing, pressing.
Something that you think would be of interest to the crowd.
Okay, so where were we on our phantasmagoria?
I had a great aunt who used to call something
that was wonderful a monster polypheme.
It was like a Christmas present you got
that's so big they had a blanket over it
like a tricycle or something.
She'd say, oh that's probably a monster polypheme.
Word she made up.
A monster polypheme.
So our work is sort of a monster polypheme.
So we talked about paradigm allegiance.
It's difficult to get people who are pedestrian
in their thinking below 200
to understand the abstract.
Abstract.
Because if you can't prove it.
So a lot of debunkers are there.
This is the home of debunkers.
They're into Newtonian materialistic linearity.
And anything that goes beyond that
they consider fraudulent.
So they set out to debunk it, debunk it.
I've been debunked all over the place.
Debunkers.
One of the great debunkers is actually a stage
magician, a stage magician.
And of course occasionally they are useful.
Occasionally they're useful.
Not that they aren't.
All right.
So things have to fall within a certain paradigm
to be accepted as possibly real.
And that's pretty much set by your whole culture.
The culture in which you grew up.
The culture that we are currently bombarded with.
What is within the norms?
Now consciousness calibration itself is not within cultural norms.
The world thinks in terms of linear local causality.
The fact that you can read the essence of something
at a great distance
is not within their paradigm of possible.
Therefore you would expect criticisms to come from people
who are literal and pedestrian
in their thinking because they're not capable of thinking
in abstract terminology.
They think in terms of content and not context, etc.
The fact that you can read anything anywhere in time.
So the thing that's mind-boggling about consciousness calibration
is that you can know anything about anything
anywhere in time or space
so long as you get permission.
So I tell people when you use it,
I always ask, I have permission to ask this question.
And occasionally you'll get a no.
I do it silently all the time with Susan
so as not to take up the audience's time
but I should verbalize it.
Because occasionally you'll get a no.
Sometimes you can find out the reason for the no
and other times you can't.
Usually it's very seldom we get a no
but many people do get a no.
And one reason you get it is because of karmic reasons.
The reason people below 200 can't get the truth
with this methodology
is because if you follow truth
what you end up with is God.
God and truth are one and the same thing.
So if you're an atheist, you negate God
and you're not able to do kinesiology.
And some well-known professors
who attack kinesiology
I couldn't figure out why do they
he calibrates 190.
Why does he calibrate 190?
Because he's an atheist.
So then I got why it is.
Anyway, we quit using the term.
We don't do kinesiology anymore.
We just do muscle testing.
People don't like the term so I'll throw it out.
I only mentioned the term begin with
out of respect for the teacher in which
whose class I saw how it worked.
I instantly got it.
He saw it as local.
I saw it as non-local.
But I thought I would honor him by that reference.
However, if they don't take it that way
I'll win.
I need kinesiology like a hole in it.
Kinesiology actually is muscle testing
to diagnose physical conditions
by physical response.
And of course we're using it in a different paradigm.
Sorry I ever brought the word in.
We've eliminated it from the reproduction
of all the new books.
We just eliminate it.
If people don't like it, take it out.
Don't want to offend anyone.
Alright, so the human mind of course.
We talked about hermeneutics of abstraction.
Attention set.
You can't understand the content
unless you add the context.
Is a certain thing legal and okay in the United States?
It depends.
It depends are you at war or not at war.
Certain things went on during World War II.
After the war was over they were eliminated.
But they were necessary at the time.
And we did Werner's, Werner Erhard's definition
which I always like.
True all the time.
So the understanding depends on your brain physiology,
indoctrination, and your paradigms of reality
which are a reflection of what's normal in your culture.
Allegorical versus literal.
Letter versus sphere of the law.
We gave that example right before the break.
Current litigation, the current laws
that are under argumentation.
Which to me, try to use the letter of the law
to escape the spirit of the law.
So very often the letter of the law
is used to defeat the spirit of the law.
The spirit of the law,
report anything suspicious in the airport,
is quite obvious to see.
All right.
So the fallacy of mixing levels
is what is true at one level
is not necessarily true at another.
And render unto Caesar that which is Caesar's.
And unto God which is God's
is a way of expressing the different levels.
Sometimes we see spiritual error
because they try to apply a spiritual dictum
which is appropriate in this context
but not appropriate in another context.
The fallacy of mixing levels.
The letter versus the spirit of the law.
The fallacy of mixing levels
is the basis for a lot of spiritual error.
Especially in New Ages
when there is a lot of materialism.
Limitations of science,
we gave the example of junk science.
And how it becomes politicized,
it becomes a whole big world enthusiasm.
And mass delusions and madness of crowds
is the only way to explain that.
People get carried away with grandiosity about it all.
And of course the money pours in.
You have festivals all over the world
to overcome something that doesn't even exist.
You get a lot of TV coverage.
People do anything to get a few moments on television.
Anything.
Including lying through their teeth.
Alright, so the distortion of relativism,
rhetoric and sophistry
has been noted in ancient Greece.
And therefore,
part of being an educated spiritual student
I think is to have some
at least superficial understanding
of the philosophy of ancient Greece.
Because our culture is
a Greco-Judo-Christian.
And our emphasis on reason and rationality
is part of that ancient tradition.
There are whole cultures, you know,
which are not,
we just presume everybody's like us.
There are whole cultures that forbid reason.
We say they're dumb and not reasonable.
They forbid reason and the basis is
that reason may interfere with faith.
If you start using reason
on a lot of religious concepts
you throw them out as not being reasonable.
So reason is seen as a jeopardy to faith.
Now St. Thomas Aquinas,
who was a doctor of divinity,
said the opposite.
That reason supports faith.
And he saw reason and faith supporting each other.
And it certainly,
you can create a very logical reason
for divinity and the explanation.
Advanced quantum mechanics
and its theory
certainly supports divinity
just intrinsically.
There's an infinite field of energy
out of which all arises
as a consequence of emergence of potentiality
in the actuality,
which is what we've been lecturing
since the first lecture.
The things don't happen by cause,
a linear Newtonian causality.
But an infinite potentiality
becomes an actuality
when local conditions are appropriate.
So we don't see creation.
We don't see evolution.
That's the next lecture.
I can't talk about it.
So junk science prevails.
Junk science prevails.
Because it's politically popular
and it's profitable.
I can get a grant on anything anywhere
because I know the prejudice
and all I have to do is calibrate the review committee
and I can get a grant to study anything.
Because what I do is I put the end result that they want
and I say, you know,
a secondhand smoke will cause crib deaths,
cause psoriasis in old people.
No matter what I want to write,
I can get a grant for it.
And you can't run your department
or university without a grant.
You can't keep your position as a professor
unless you write papers.
So you can see how it's rigged.
You've got to write papers,
you've got to get a grant.
To get a grant,
you've got to write something politically pleasing
in order to get the money,
so you tell them what they want to hear.
The distortion of relativism,
it's said we've already had a whole lecture on relativism
and its expression as rhetoric and sophistry.
And why it contributes so heavily
to the decline of current academia.
This is the energy field.
Somebody argued with me in a previous lecture about it.
Let's look at the Duke University incident.
The Duke University incident.
Three innocent men, proven innocent by DNA.
A faculty of 87 members signed a denunciation
of these three men.
Three young men, convicting them in advance,
even though the DNA layer proved them
not only innocent but impossible
for them to have been the ones.
Now, it's bad enough that that condemnation
was racist and sexist.
Let's calibrate the Duke University 87 professors.
Calibrate over 120, 140, 135.
Calibrate 135.
People would dispute with me
whether academia has fallen.
The entire Duke...
135.
Duke University faculty
all signed their names for posterity,
calibrated at 135.
All right, after the three gentlemen
were proven innocent via DNA,
and the guy who first prosecuted them
I thought was gonna get defrocked.
Anyway, God knows what'll come of it all.
Having been proven wrong,
did the Duke faculty retract?
They did not.
Not only dishonest to begin with and warped,
but totally lacking in integrity.
As an academic, if I made a mistake,
the first thing I'm gonna tell you,
I'll tell you it's a mistake.
Just like I'm telling you this morning,
I never used the word kinesiology.
It throws people in the wrong direction.
So why not admit a mistake, you know,
carried away by the enthusiasm
and the fun of making people wrong, you know?
Think of all that sexism in there.
Poor black girl. Poor black girl.
Abused by these rich white boys.
They just jumped on that wagon.
It was so tempting.
Gotta condemn these bad...
Yeah, it isn't, you know,
making a mistake is one thing,
in the poor judgment of the...
But not retracting it later.
To this day, they have not retracted it.
So we got what the condemnation calibrated, huh?
The failure to retract.
The failure to retract that.
Calibrates over 90, 95.
To say it in the first place is 135.
To not retract it is 95.
One of the commandments, one of the Ten Commandments,
which is enough to make every politician shudder,
is to bear false witness against your brother.
To bear false witness
is breaking one of the Ten Commandments.
I don't think people should just break
the Ten Commandments willy-nilly
and then consider themselves politically superior
that they've done so, or lead, or something.
So that's why academia has gone down.
That's just a typical example, huh?
But the politicalization of just about everything
insinuates itself into such things as...
What do they call it? Radical math now.
You don't add up two things.
Two plus two plus two.
You add up two starving Africans.
Two starving African white or dark ladies.
And then you come up with social injustice.
What the mentally impaired don't get
is that this is an unjust world.
We're all born unequal.
There's not two people in here that are equal.
I was born tall and handsome.
And then there's short guys.
Some people are born rich.
They used to come up to school in a Cadillac.
We had a little old used car,
and I'd tell my dad,
drop me off in the block away.
The kids are all going to jeer at you.
Didn't have any money,
so my grandmother knit me sweaters.
You know what they did?
They'd grab the back of your sweater
and look to see if there was a lapel there,
and say, oh, his mother made it.
So nowadays a handmade sweater costs you a couple hundred.
And a machine made one.
But in those days the status was
nothing in this world is created equal, see?
So we can't chop all the tall people off at the legs.
Remember the war in Africa,
the Bantu against the Watussis?
And the Bantu that were the midges,
the small ones, right?
They cut the Watussis' legs off
so they'd be the same height.
Oh, God.
So what the far left politically doesn't get
is that we are created equal,
and we're all unequal,
and it's not anybody's fault.
It's just the way it is.
It doesn't have to make it somebody's fault.
There's no point to create a finger.
You try to find what is the basis
of what can be corrected,
and you correct it.
You correct it.
Some people are born with very high IQs,
and other people are not.
That's why the far left does not like
the whole subject of IQ.
Some kids should follow an academic road
and others should follow a vocational road.
I mean, you know,
I'd rather be a well-to-do machinist
than a broke college dropout.
The last time I had something made
by a machinist in Flagstaff,
it cost me a fortune.
I wanted a couple of four-inch bearings
made for a great big waterwheel.
I had to have them special made.
I tell you,
machinists make plenty of money.
If you can't buy it at Walmart,
don't get a machinist.
Yeah, so what is truth?
Truth is subject to programming
and indoctrination.
The hermeneutics of abstraction,
it's limited by attention set.
We talked about the letter
versus the spirit of the law,
the fallacy of mixing levels.
See, what is truth in one paradigm
is not true in another.
What's fair and equal in one sub-level of society
is not fair and equal in another.
You can't just sort people
according to race, sex, age,
gender and all that kind of stuff
because you're mixing levels.
Then we talked about junk science
and its popularization.
It's very, very big payoff.
Distortion of relativism,
we already covered with the whole lecture.
And as compared to absolutism,
and I got a kick out of some critic
that wrote something about to warn them,
warn them,
about the books I write,
warning,
you're warned in advance
that he's an absolutist.
Warning, he's an absolutist.
A bad word.
A bad word means you don't,
you're not run by relativism.
It means the truth is not just what you think it is.
And it opposes the narcissistic position
that if I think it or believe it,
it must be true.
And it denies the existence of God.
Which of course is the whole basis of absolutism.
Yes, there is an absolute scale.
And in fact,
the calibrated levels of consciousness are absolute.
They absolutely go from one to a thousand.
And they absolutely calibrate God at infinity.
That's enough to boil the blood of any relativist.
We'll move on to the next one.
How many slides do we have on truth?
And don't lie to me.
How many?
Okay.
All right.
That tells me.
Yeah.