we all found out where it is.
We must be where we're supposed to be
because otherwise we wouldn't be here, right?
All right, so we'll start with the slides.
How many people here are new?
Huh?
Oh, quite a few.
All right, so we do a review of the basics
for the people who are here for the first time.
And the more often truth is repeated,
it becomes automatic.
You don't have to think about it.
So hearing it over and over again
is less laborious than trying to memorize it.
It's hard to find your way around a strange city
by memorizing the map.
But if you've been driving there a while,
you automatically go to where you're supposed to be.
So that's the difference between left brain
and right brain learning.
So in the lectures, I do justice to the left brain,
but I'm counting on the fact that you've heard it before
that you'll understand what it is
because you're also processing it with the right brain.
All right.
So we'll start with the slides.
We'll start with, let's see, this stays up this high, right?
Or it has to stay up this high.
Okay.
Up there.
On this map, God is this way.
And you know who is this way.
Anyway, heaven is going green anyway, I hear.
Heaven is going green, yes.
God bless heaven.
And smokers this way, non-smokers this way.
Are you going to get there?
All right.
The map of consciousness has become pretty well known
around the world because it's so convenient,
so handy, so simple, so obvious.
It's like barometric pressure.
It's like an altimeter.
And it's a simple means of discerning where you are
and as in relationship to reality.
Okay.
Today, the lecture is reality,
which is actually a very unpopular subject.
In today's world, reality is at the bottom of the list.
Nobody is really interested in reality or truth, you know.
They're interested in the media presentation
and what it looks like, virtual reality, but not real reality.
So today will be sort of culture shock.
You're used to it.
If you watch,
you know, TV or much, you know, you learn to live in virtual reality.
Behind the virtual reality, there's also a real reality
and that's what we'll be trying to discern from virtual, from the real.
All right.
So this is just extremely useful.
It's pragmatic.
It's practical.
It's quick.
It's easy.
And it gives you answers to the unknowable.
So late at night on TV, you'll see the mystery
of the great ruins of something or other.
And the man has never known what it means or what went on there, et cetera.
But at home, we just, we find out in about two seconds.
But the world has never been able to discover, you know,
the lost city of something or other, you see.
So you have access to the unknowable, which makes it sort of exciting, doesn't it?
When you think of it.
You think of all Amelia Earhart.
You think of all the mysteries.
The great Jack the Ripper, et cetera.
All the mysteries that are mystical and legendary.
Stonehenge, et cetera.
So all the mysteries that man has never been able to decipher,
we find out in about three seconds.
Also criminal trials.
We have to be careful.
Criminal trials.
Is someone so guilty or so?
You know, the world is puzzling over it, you see.
It takes you about two seconds to answer the unanswerable.
Why is that?
First of all, using the method is not possible for people that are atheistic, we discovered.
If you're an atheist, you've denied the source of all truth,
so you don't have the privilege of access to it.
We discovered that, yeah.
So.
But the accuracy in using the method we use is based on your capacity
to be abstractly interested in truth for its own sake instead of trying
to convince yourself or the world about some positionality.
The number is just a number.
So when we ask for the number of a thing, all we're getting is a number.
All we get is a number.
And sometimes I see myself quoted as saying, he said so and so.
He didn't say so and so at all.
The number came out.
It came out at a certain number.
Now why should I care what the number is?
You know? You have no vested interest in the number.
It's just a number.
Then what it means you can puzzle out later.
So it's extremely useful pragmatically.
Also, if you keep following that which calibrates the highest.
So every crossroad of decision you come to in life, one way leads up and one way leads down.
So if you constantly follow that which is the most integrous, if you follow nothing but truth,
without anything else, not faith, not religion, nothing, if you keep following truth,
you'll end up at divinity.
If at this intersection you take truth as this way and this intersection
and truth is this way, you eventually end up with divinity.
All paths of truth lead to God.
So therefore, you can see why denying God,
means that you can't have access to a tool based on seeing the divinity of truth itself.
All right, so you're all familiar with the calibrated levels and I don't know if anybody
has any questions about it and it all arose accidentally as an observation and then the
significance of the observation became obvious and it was sort of overwhelming to be able
to tell the truth about anything, anywhere.
All right.
Thank you.
The question of whether time and time or space is so mind-boggling that very few people get it.
It's because of the infinite nature of consciousness itself.
It has no dimensions.
The mind is used to thinking in terms of causality of this causing of that in a linear time documented sequence,
you know, like creation or something.
Actually, nothing comes about in that manner.
And, you know,
actually, quantum mechanics, and we'll have a slide on that, is a demonstration, so, of how things come about.
Not as sequence, not as causal, but as a manifestation of potentiality into actuality.
All things come about.
So to save a great deal of time in trying to advance one's consciousness, you just accept the fact that all things come about spontaneously as an emergent process.
Therefore, creation and evolution are one and the same thing.
The field of consciousness has no beginning and no end.
One cubic centimeter of space contains more energy than the total mass of the universe.
One cubic millimeter of space has within it the potential of more energy greater than the mass of the universe.
So the reason the mind can't quite grasp that you can know the truth about anything
is because it's a completely different way of processing.
It's a way of facilitating.
So the only reason an answer arises when our arm goes strong is because there is truth to the statement.
There's either truth or not truth.
There is no such thing as false.
There is nothing negative or false in nature.
The thing is either true or not.
Truth or not true, but it is not false.
There is no such thing as falseness any more than you can say.
You cannot send falseness down an electrical wire.
You can only send electricity.
So the electricity is either on or off.
It's either on or not on.
That's how truth is.
So in nature, there is no negation in nature.
Nature is unable to say no.
Doesn't make any sense to nature to say no.
No, what does that mean?
All right, so that's enough jabber on that.
Shut up the jabber.
We'll go to the next one.
Can you all see that okay there?
Wow.
Oh, this is the energy fields of the energy done in microwatts of the various levels of consciousness.
The lowest levels of consciousness are very deficient in power and in energy,
but then as you get to the higher levels, especially the 400,
you see a rapid rise and then a very rapid decline.
A rapid rise.
500, which is the level of the heart, up to 600, which is the level, first level of enlightenment
and the opening of the Buddhic body, third eye of the Buddhic body.
And from there, you see the power goes up enormously rapidly.
And when it's graphed in microwatts, let's go to the next one.
The distribution of the world's population, I think this is out of date now, anyway, you
see the great mass.
Of the population, this is the population, you see the great mass, I think it's 85% now,
right?
Let me see.
That 78 should be 85, resist.
Yeah, because the world has gone down.
When I did this, 78% of the population was below 200, now it's 85%.
Evolution is not doing too well.
I want my money back.
I bet my money on evolution.
Anyway, I thought that, you know, human evolution was going to go up and up and up and continue
up, and all of a sudden it took a dip down.
So in the last three years or so, the level of consciousness has decreased in the world
overall, and in America as well.
So we'll have to change this, make a note that we'll have to bring this up to date.
All right.
So anyway, at the time we did this, it was, actually it's only 15%.
Now at the top.
Oh, these are really out of date, aren't they?
I didn't realize it.
All right.
So these will, there's actually only 15% that calibrate over 200, and they counter, their
power is such that they counterbalance the rest of mankind.
If it were not for, so forget these figures, this is supposed to be 22, so it's a smaller
pyramid.
Go to the next slide, and then I'll make it obvious what we're talking about.
So we'll have to change this.
So we'll have to change these figures.
Well, we did change it for the new book, but I forgot the slides.
Approximately 15% of the world's population calibrates over 200, and it counterbalances
the negativity of the 85% that calibrate below 200.
So you can see mankind is really not all that evolved, is it, huh?
Realizing that, we can be more compassionate for human error and say, well, what else can
you do?
What else can you do?
So compassion comes out of accepting the reality.
The reality is that 85% of the planet cannot tell truth from falsehood, cannot tell the
real from the illusionary, illusionary, illusionary, illusory.
Stop making up new words, David.
Okay.
We'll move to the next exciting, oh yes, and here's where I thought, well, I'll have to
revise some of these.
I thought the percent of elapsed time, the level of consciousness, was rapidly going
up, especially in the late 80s, and I thought it was just going to continue up, but it did
not.
So apparently there's going to be a little dip when we redo the graph.
We'll have to make a note to redo these, update them.
Okay.
The next exciting thing is consciousness evolved from the very beginning of life.
It evolved from the very beginning of life on this planet.
The light of divinity shone forth, and its impact on organic matter was to precipitate
the emergence of life.
Yes.
That's how life came about.
Resist.
All right.
So much for the bottoms-up theory of evolution of life.
Not bottom-up.
So much for mechanistic reductionism.
Yes.
All right.
So then when we checked over the archeologic ages, and we get the level of consciousness
of life on the planet altogether, we see it started out back here with bacteria, first
signs of life calibrating at one.
So life started at one, the most simple forms of life, and that is very significant.
Because for life to evolve, for protoplasmic life to evolve, see chlorophyll, as I've
explained in previous lectures, chlorophyll, if you're a plant, all you have to do is sit
in the sun, and you thrive because the chlorophyll processes the sun energy, and you grow and
thrive, and all you have to do is sit there.
But animal life, and we're all animal life.
Protoplasmic.
Protoplasmic has to find a source of energy.
This is the inner secret of the source of the ego.
Because protoplasmic life does not have within itself a source of energy, replenishing energy.
It must seek it out.
It must be able to search, test, qualify.
Yep, that's good.
Now if you make a mistake, I think that's good, and it wasn't.
Bonk.
So only life that gets right is alive today.
Life that gets wrong.
So the ego then, it developed out of this necessity to constantly test the environment
for that which supports life and that which does not.
The kinesiologic test, when the arm goes strong, it means that the arm is strong.
It means that that which you're asking about supports life.
When it goes weak, it's saying that does not support life.
So falsehood does not support life.
Falsehood does not support life.
Yes.
So those who made mistakes are not here.
The evolutionary lines based on falsehood quickly extinguish themselves.
So only that which is alive.
Only that which is alive which was successful.
So the ego's mechanism then subserves a biologic necessity.
So there's no point in demonizing it.
If it wasn't for your ego, you wouldn't be here long enough to start feeling guilty about your ego.
Be happy you have an ego.
Thank you, ego.
If it wasn't for you, sweetheart, I wouldn't even be alive to complain.
All right.
So here we went through the archeologic ages and you see the evolution of consciousness overall.
So the consciousness level of the world overall right now, the consciousness – you can stay seated.
The consciousness level of the world overall right now is at 204, 205, 204.
Consciousness level of the world overall, 204.
All right.
Truth is 200 and up.
It's a thin line.
You know, we're very close to falling back below 200 again.
And, of course, in the evolution of consciousness, it stayed below 200.
It was only in the late 1980s, now about 1987, that it jumped from 190 where it had been for centuries to over 200.
So there was a recent advance in the late 80s and it went up as far as 207 overall.
The level of consciousness now is down to 204, 204.
All right.
So the next thing was this shows the evolution of consciousness throughout the animal kingdom.
These are our cousins and friends.
These are our family because we're a protoplasmic mammalian animal.
And this is where we – how we evolved.
And as you can see, there's a match through the evolution of time as well as the complexity of time.
The animal is – the complexity and sophistication of the animal.
So as the animal's consciousness rises, you can see the lower levels live by predation.
They live solely by predation and alligators and dinosaurs and all.
So you're not supposed to get into a cage with a dinosaur, you know, or –
Being friendly to them won't help you any.
Today's political thing is if you're nice to dinosaurs, they'll be nice to you.
After saying that, he disappeared.
And the dinosaur gave a big swallow.
All right.
So you see that predate goes from predation to the herbivorous, so consciousness level 200.
You see the emergence of the grazer who does not have to kill others in order to survive.
Below 200.
You live by killing others.
From 200 and up, you have the option of the elk and the pig and the deer and the gorillas and dogs and family dogs.
And the family dog is at 250.
That's higher than a great many people on the planet.
If you're nice to people that are over 200, you'll get a feedback of a wagging tail.
If you're nice to people under 200, they'll eat your leg while you're talking to them.
Oops.
What happened to my leg?
I was being nice.
So much for accommodation.
All right.
So then we come all the way up.
We see Alex, the trained African gray parrot who died recently and had a very major obituary.
Alex got a lot of attention in the press.
Uh-huh.
Just like that dog that can tell when you're going to leave.
When you're going to leave the planet.
And Coco, the trained gorilla.
The cats.
And here we have something which includes a mystery which I have not solved yet.
Why is it that the cat's purr and the dog's wagging tail is at 500?
Man's best companion, the dog, he calibrates his wagging tail is at 500.
You have to meet a lot of people before you find one at 500.
A lot of people.
They'll eat you alive, skin you alive.
Yeah, the chick's good.
Uh-huh.
Thank you.
So the cat's purr and the dog's wagging tail reflects back to us love.
Don't wrap that on the floor.
I've got your message.
Yes.
So there's a certain specialness.
Here's a talking parrot and trained gorilla's cat's purr.
The cat's purr and the dog's wagging tail.
And mysteriously, it calibrates higher than most of the people on the planet.
How can that be?
Therefore, I don't trust a culture that hates dogs.
Do I?
If you hate that, which is 500.
Yeah?
Yep.
And God knows what they do with cats.
Eat them, I guess, or something.
All right.
So we'll go to the next.
We can philosophize about any of these things.
This is the classic education.
Which is in the mid-400s, the Renaissance, out of the Dark Ages, came the area edition,
the intellectual area edition of the great books of the Western world, which I've spoken
about many times.
And this is a listing of all the great books.
And we calibrated every one of them.
I have them all at home.
I got a good buy on the whole set one time from the library.
$150 or something.
A library sale.
I got all the books in the Western world.
A hundred bucks or whatever it was.
So here you see all the great names.
And out of this arose Western civilization.
Out of ancient Greece, Socrates, Plato, the great minds of ancient Greece.
And then the Renaissance, the reawakening of philosophic, intellectual, integrous truth.
And much can be learned by just becoming acquainted with this list.
And looking at those various names.
And here we see of great significance is Darwin at 450.
So Darwinian science is to be respected at 450.
And here you have this whole scientific paradigm of causality.
The Newtonian paradigm.
Where is Sir Isaac?
Isaac.
Sir Isaac.
Where are you, Sir?
Sir Isaac?
Hey.
Where are they going?
Well, he was up there.
Anyway, Newton.
There he is.
$499.
Yes, he's memorable because he and Freud and Einstein all calibrated $499.
Which is the limit of the human intellect.
The human intellect can only go up as far as $499.
And then it has to shift paradigms of reality.
So this is still the world of causality.
Out of it arose all of science, the classic education.
So the liberal arts education of traditional America had to do with at least acquaintanceship,
if not familiarity, with all these great names.
Of significance to today's world, of course, is they included Marx and Engels.
Well, Engels is at 200.
But unfortunate for America and for the world, Marx is only at 130.
Dialectical materialism then.
So modern, postmodern philosophy is based on the dialectical materialism of Marx.
And its propagators removed the name Marx because it might cause a political resistance.
But kept alive dialectical materialism.
The dialectical materialism is political correctness.
An interesting article on what happened to Antioch College in this week's, I think, Weekly Standard.
Yeah, I think Weekly Standard.
That which calibrated in the high 400s has now collapsed by following dialectical materialism.
Well, when followed politically, it's brought disaster and widespread starvation.
When introduced to academia, it has had a disastrous effect.
And the recent closure of Antioch College is typical.
Okay, so we'll move on to the next.
We were speaking about the potentiality becoming an actuality.
And the potentiality then is actualized by the field of energy around it.
And that's now called the Heisenberg principle.
The Heisenberg principle is simply that all comes about as the result of a potentiality becoming an actuality.
So the muscle test we use to discern truth from falsehood is simply a yes versus a not yes.
As you can see, it is not between a yes and a no.
Nature cannot say no.
It can only say yes or not yes.
So when I test her arm, truth makes her arm strong.
And that's a yes.
Falsehood, there is no truth to make it strong.
So because there's no current running down the wire, her arm goes weak.
So it's not between yes and no.
It's between yes and not yes.
Yes and not yes.
A very important thing to comprehend.
That nature cannot say no.
Nature cannot say no.
Okay, we'll go to the next thing.
You cannot say no, can you, honey?
That's the way I get her to say yes.
The evolutionary significance, the evolution of consciousness in the human brain is also of profound significance in today's world.
Today the subject is reality as compared to non-reality.
Alright, the capacity to discern reality.
So we have two different kinds of brains.
Two different kinds of brain function.
Left brain is animal dominated and it's highly energized by emotion.
Really, the cortex doesn't pay too much attention to the cortex.
What it really mainly pays attention to is emotion.
So the left brain is primarily an animal, instinctual brain.
And the fast track then is to the emotional center.
And so therefore, below 200, consciousness level 200, people get very vociferous and carried away by their feelings.
By their feelings.
See?
When I'm waiting for my change in the store, I don't care about their feelings.
I just want my money.
But in today's world, they have to tell you,
Oh, I feel terrible about that.
Everybody has to emotionalize.
So that's the virtual reality.
Or emotionality.
So that's left brain and that's typical below 200.
Alright.
As you get above 200 then, you switch to a different style of brain processing called right brain.
In which processing information through the cerebral cortex and especially through the etheric brain is very fast.
And the emotion is minimal.
Okay.
So the capacity to discern truth then requires a detached attitude in which what you're interested in is the truth of the matter.
I always tell people, you know, first get the truth of the matter and then worry about how to handle that answer later.
But first get what the truth of it is.
And don't start arguing until you've gotten a different look at it.
So below 200 then we have everybody processes things in linear causality.
What's the cause of that?
And that's had a very negative impact on sociology.
Because they look outside the person to find some kind of a cause.
If somebody's flunking in school, they look around the neighborhood.
Alright.
Left brain dominance is linear.
And it releases stress, adrenaline.
It's fight or flight.
And causes stress to the endocrine system, the thymus stress.
And it disrupts the acupuncture meridians.
Therefore, harm goes weak.
It's also associated with disease and a negative response.
Alright.
Now, with spiritual endeavor, what happens?
At consciousness level 200, the kundalini energy, the spiritual energy, we'll have to invent a better sounding name.
What's classically been called the kundalini energy, begins to arise within the etheric body, the etheric brain.
And what happens now, above 200, is you switch to a non-linear way of knowingness, right brain dominance.
The person is peaceful and it releases endorphins.
Endorphins are what make you feel good.
Therefore, the dog's wagging tail and the kitty's purr.
Right?
The kitty's purr makes you feel happy.
The kitty's happy.
The dog's happy.
And you're happy.
Because you're all releasing endorphins.
Positive emotions.
And that supports the thymus gland and resistance to disease.
There's increased killer cells.
Therefore, bacteria get killed off.
There's greater immunity, greater propensity to healing.
And a positive kinesiologic response, positive muscle response.
So the tracks to the emotion is then slower.
And you go through the prefrontal cortex so that people above 200 tend to think.
And you assume that everybody thinks.
Don't you?
The majority of the world doesn't think.
It reacts.
Oh, I hate that girl.
I like that.
I'll kill that son of a bitch.
Give me that girl.
I want her.
I don't know.
Let's kill those people on the other side of the border.
The first thing people do when they get power is become aggressive.
They have to invade the nearby territories.
How does that make it different than a wolf pack?
So below 200 people live like a wolf pack.
Hegemony or hegemony or whatever you call it is an animal response.
You give people power.
Aren't they happy?
You think they'd be happy.
Smoke your power or eat it or sleep with it or what?
Instantly, they have to invade the neighbor's houses and become dominant, you know?
Oh, God.
So you look through history.
The minute somebody gains power, they have to immediately invade all the territories around it.
Why can't they just be satisfied?
You know, we dominate half of Asia.
Isn't that good enough?
No, you got to do that.
So everybody wants to capture the world and be king of the hill.
So that's a mammalian response.
The males, oh, then it's even more than a mammalian.
Anyway, the desire to dominate others seems to be intrinsic within the ego.
Therefore, people can make fun of hegemony or whatever you want,
but they're forgetting that it's an innate animal response,
the alpha male to dominate the alpha female, et cetera.
And conflict is inevitable because this is a world run by the animal.
The animal brain.
The animal brain, the minute it gets the dominance of a hill,
it wants to dominate the other hills around it.
So you can watch, what's that, Muscat Randall?
What's that one we watch?
The little deer cat, Meerkat Manor, yeah.
So if you want to, I mean, human civilization is no different than Meerkat Manor.
They're all like this.
As soon as they get some more members, now they have to dominate these people and chase them away.
Meerkat doesn't say, gee, we'll live here, you live there.
So now we understand human behavior, international relationships, Iran, the whole thing.
Iran, Egypt, where else is there, probably Turkey, everybody.
Everybody's doing the Meerkat Manor.
When you see that it's just Meerkat Manor dominated by the animal left brain,
you develop compassion.
Instead of saying, oh, isn't that awful?
Or hating them or calling them evil.
That's where those Meerkats are at.
Okay, next.
The level of, I can't read.
Oh, rate of happiness.
All right.
See, the Marxian dialectic always thinks in terms of victim and perpetrator.
Although there isn't any out there in the world.
There isn't any out there in the world.
It's projected as positionality.
And now you can see everything in terms of victim and perpetrator.
When projected into sociology, you will always find a perpetrator and a victim.
And so a lot of political ideology in today's world is based on this victim perpetrator.
It's really the Marxian dialectic.
Yep.
All right.
The rate of happiness then should be related, if that is true,
to external conditions.
Poor people should all be miserable.
Rich people should all be happy.
All right.
So now we found that the level of consciousness,
what happiness and unemployment,
rate of poverty, happiness,
and rate of criminality,
it is all directly related to level of consciousness and to nothing else.
Not related to poor upbringing.
Bad education.
Those people tend to get born into that kind of environment
because of the karmic propensities.
All right.
Here's the levels of consciousness.
Less than 50.
These are serial killers.
They calibrate around 30.
That famous one that kills all the other students,
he calibrated about 10, about the lowest I've ever seen.
Five even, I think he was.
All right.
The lowest levels,
the lowest levels are less than 50 in prisons.
Prisons are often, you know.
The rate of unemployment is almost 100%.
The rate of poverty is 65%.
That's because they're good at criminality.
And the happiness, life is okay, is 0%.
Ain't nobody happy.
Mama ain't happy.
Nobody ain't happy.
The rate of criminality is close to 100%.
So.
All right.
Then we see the level of consciousness
as we go up 50 to 100.
The rate of unemployment is 75%.
Rate of poverty, 40%.
They're still pretty good at theory.
Happiness, life is okay, 2%.
Rate of criminality, 91%.
So you see all these indicators are not sociologic.
It's not caused by environment.
It's nothing to do with any of those.
It has nothing to do with any of that.
As the level of consciousness goes up,
the rate of unemployment goes up.
Here, right, it goes down, right.
All right.
At consciousness level 200,
you see below 200,
unemployment is 50% or over.
Above 200, and then it drops to 8%.
A huge drop.
So the minute you go over 200,
unemployment drops from 50 to 8%.
Rate of poverty drops from 22% to 1.5%.
Life is okay, happiness.
Here is only 15%.
Jumps to 40%.
And the rate of criminality,
which is very significant in criminology,
is the level of consciousness,
the minute it goes over 200,
criminality drops from 50% to 9%.
Uh-huh.
So the criminal can't really help being
other than they are, can they?
Huh?
Unless you can use Pavlovian conditioning.
Every time they do something,
you should give them a shock, you know.
Condition reflected.
All right.
As you go up then,
by the time you get to an intelligent,
integrous group of people,
certainly the 400s are very representative
in our society,
intelligent, integrous people,
spiritually oriented,
the rate of unemployment drops to 2%.
And their external reasons may play a part.
The rate of poverty drops to 0.5%,
or 1%.
I can't read from here.
Happiness jumps from over 50% up to 70%.
The rate of criminality drops to 5 or 2%.
I can't see well enough.
See up there.
Anyway, what it really demonstrates,
you don't need all the details,
uh,
that the unemployment here
at consciousness level 500
is 0%.
Zero.
There ain't no such thing as
not having something to do,
or a job,
or some employment.
The rate of poverty is 0%.
0%.
Not low.
No, none.
Okay.
Happiness, 98%.
2% need a psychiatrist.
Ha ha.
And again, criminality drops to less than 1%.
So all these things,
which are attributed
through the Marxian dialectic,
dialectical materialism,
as perpetrator and cause,
you can see perpetrator and cause
is in the mind of the observer
projected into the world.
Uh, in the woods.
There's a big tree and a small tree.
So the Marxian says,
look how the big tree is stealing
the little tree's sun.
The little tree is the victim
of the big tree.
Ha ha.
Now you have the secret
of the Marxian dialectic
and the modern political dialogue,
is that the big tree is stealing
the little tree's sun.
Ha ha ha.
Therefore it must be bad and evil.
Yeah.
All right.
So we'll go to the next one.
Uh, I can't read this.
What does it say?
What does that say?
Rate of happiness?
I don't know what it says, honey.
What does it say?
No, this is the field of
levels of consciousness.
Oh, I see.
Correlation of levels.
And the rate of happiness?
Oh, golly.
Well, that makes me happy to realize that.
I get what it means.
The happier you are,
the happier you are.
Ah, that's what I wondered.
No wonder I couldn't get it.
The happier you are,
the happier you are.
Ha ha ha.
It's funny how,
I do this all the time, you know.
I go in the kitchen,
the kitty's there.
And I just stand there and I go,
hmm.
And pretty soon the kitty goes,
purr, purr, purr, purr, purr.
Ha ha ha.
And I'm just looking at the kitty.
You can do it with a dog.
You just go over and you look at old Rover.
Ha ha ha.
The sensitivity to love.
Oh, wow.
All right.
So what you feel sorry for,
of the people under 200,
is they don't have that sensitivity to love.
We're all transformed by the love that is around us.
A group like this,
which is mutually loving,
is so powerfully supporting
that it transforms your perception.
You see?
The valuing of love.
To love life in all of its expressions.
You see?
To value life in all its expressions
is the beginning of spiritual enlightenment.
Yes.
Okay.
So we can go on to the next,
say.
Hmm.
The true nature of,
oh,
the nature of divinity.
Yes.
Ha ha.
Well,
these are the levels of consciousness
of the higher levels,
over 600.
Which,
the book,
Transcending Levels of Consciousness,
we get into discussing.
They,
they are some sort of abstract
during a lecture.
But these are the,
the levels of consciousness
of the higher levels
over 600,
which,
the book,
Transcending Levels of Consciousness,
we get into discussing.
So these are the,
the levels of divinity,
omniscience,
omnipresence,
omnipotence,
allness.
And then we can verify
what is,
on the scale of one to a thousand,
where does the Buddha come out?
Where does Jesus Christ come out?
Where does God come out?
Where does divinity come out?
Where does the creator come out?
And they all come out
at infinity.
Ha ha.
The great avatars calibrate
on this scale,
a thousand.
And beyond that
are the divine,
the divine,
and the infinite realms
which go on up to infinity.
So that's just to document
the scale,
the,
the range
within the field
of consciousness.
Yes.
So anybody who is an atheist,
I'll,
I'll do the arm for them.
Anybody want,
anybody,
any,
any atheists here?
Want me to calibrate God?
What can you do?
Can't even find an atheist
around here anymore.
Ha, ha,
ha, ha.
Okay,
we'll go to the next,
huh?
Ah,
these are the depictions
and the great spiritual teacher of history.
Because, you see, by using the calibrated scale
and examining everything in human life throughout history,
you get like a topographical map of reality and human life over the ages.
And it gets rid of about 100% of questions.
The qualities that we assign to God all calibrate as true.
They all calibrate as true.
Whether you call God Shiva, Krishna, Brahma, Vishnu, Durga, Zvara, Rama,
the God of Moses, the God of Abraham.
All of these calibrate at infinity.
The Christ, the Christ consciousness.
Then we come to the self with a capital S.
We see that's infinite.
So that's divinity imminent.
God is described both as transcendent and imminent.
The mystic, the enlightened person,
becomes dominated by the divinity imminent
rather than becoming preoccupied with God as transcendent.
So the evolution of consciousness,
the people on the pathway to enlightenment then,
are following spiritual rules and logic and techniques, et cetera,
to remove the obstruction to the awareness of the presence of divinity within.
That's the pathway of the mystic.
And we've had students come and study with us now, professors,
that are writing books on the role of the mystic in Christendom
because the mystic is not part of a traditional or ordinary Christendom.
And now a doctor from Redwoods is writing a book on the subject.
And then I was invited to a meeting in a week or two or somewhere on mysticism.
Though the mystic has not been prominent in Christianity.
Of course, the mystic is the whole core of Buddhism and the Sufis.
All right.
So these are just validations.
Okay.
So we'll move on.
And the angels and the archangels get, uh-oh.
Oh, dear.
How did Karl Marx get in here?
All right.
The Marxian dialectic, which is translated into all kinds of postmodern political argumentation,
is to confuse these two realms.
This is what a thing looks like.
This is what it can be described as.
And this is the essence of the thing.
So.
The difficulty with its translation into philosophy, or actually what I call pseudo-philosophy,
is it loses the distinction between perception and essence.
What a thing looks like and what it is.
So when we calibrate the level of consciousness of a thing,
what we're calibrating is its essence and not its appearance.
So when we calibrate this picture, you know, we get that this is the level.
And this.
So.
The discernment, the difference between perception and essence is crucial.
And it's crucial to survival.
In today's world, it's crucial to survival.
It's crucial to survival.
They say, well, we can let him on board.
He's only a lamb.
Boom.
Can you imagine having a bomb under your shoe?
That is the craziest stunt I ever heard of.
That's the craziest stunt I ever heard of.
Yeah.
Anyway, people will do anything for anything they believe in.
So let's see.
What's the next slide, eh?
Huh?
Spiritual survival.
Reality.
All right.
Now we're getting to what the lecture's about.
Is everybody happy with what we've described so far?
I've tried to boil it down to the perpetrator.
Feminine dominance.
That's the only side for women.
You see who's boss.
Why do happy people do what they do?
Well, they do what they do because of their love for each other, yeah?
That's what dominates a material relationship.
If the motivation is out of love for each other, they'll do anything.
Anything, really.
If it's serious, they actually will do anything for the sake of love.
So you see how profoundly powerful love is.
And people will do anything for love.
All right.
So this is the talk.
We're giving today now.
Did I blow a lot of time?
I can't see my watch.
All right.
So we'll get on with reality.
I can't use my pointer anymore?
If mama ain't happy, nobody's happy.
That's the first lesson, young men.
This is a standard truth amongst men.
When there's no women around, the guys will look at each other and say,
I'm not happy.
Nobody's happy.
Your male friend says, okay, in that case, we'll paint the whole house green
and take the shutters off and move the lawn to the rear.
Okay.
All right.
So love will move mountains, will it not?
Love enables you to do things you never could or would do before.
All right.
Now, there's nothing we can do about it.
So let's see.
This is about reality.
Reality is of levels of consciousness.
Ah, we did cover that.
The realities.
So as we go up on the level of consciousness, the level of reality increases.
But it also moves into a different paradigm.
Reality, as people talk about it, operationally, is primarily a mental presumption.
If I say to anybody here, are you capable of discerning reality?
They'll say yes.
Everybody presumes that their experience is reality.
And, of course, Protagoras brought that up in ancient Greece and said, you know,
my reality is real to me, and your reality is real to you.
Therefore, all reality is subjective, and there is no such thing as objective reality.
That was simplistic.
But.
Experientially, one would tend to agree with Protagoras, you know, that my reality and
your reality are not the same.
And, of course, the compromise we make in the modern world is we've created a virtual
reality in which reality itself is really immaterial.
It's what a thing looks like, what it sounds like, and what people believe about it.
And people will sell their soul for it.
For one moment.
On TV, ba-dum, they're willing to give up integrity, morality, and virginity, their
whole life, their money.
A moment in virtual reality is worth a million.
Okay.
So, people will do anything.
So, don't tase me, okay?
Okay.
Yeah.
Now, it says, reality is a subjective mental perception.
Presumption.
Everybody automatically, mentally assumes that their experience is reality.
So, everybody does subjectively live within a personal reality, which is called solipsism,
that my reality is the world I live in, and your reality is the world you live in.
That's called solipsism.
And it doesn't replace the fact that there is an objective, discernible reality that
is discoverable.
The fact that you can't, you're not aware of it doesn't mean it doesn't exist, it just
means you're not aware of it, you know?
So, if you think you can jump from a 30-story building and make it to the bottom, that's
your reality, which is changed at the bottom, and you say, oops, in the next lifetime you
just don't jump from buildings anymore.
Remember during the LSD days, you know, people would think they could fly and jump out way
out of windows?
Remember people were flying, jumping out windows on the LSD thinking they could fly, because
they went out of body, and in their astral body they thought they could fly, but their
physical body was still here.
Their astral body made it, but their physical body didn't, you know?
So, after a while people learned if you take LSD don't jump out windows, because your body's
still real, even though you're not in it.
Oh.
Reality is…
Linear versus non-linear, that's the basis of much discord because reality, according
to certain paradigms, is linear and it's only a pedestrian provability, and that's really
the limitation of science, traditional science, is the world of causality.
So reality is one thing and truth is another.
Why?
Because there are different levels of abstraction, different levels of abstraction.
So the other error we see in society is mixing levels of abstraction.
When you ask, who is the me, is the me real, is the me real?
I am, I think, therefore I am.
Other people say, I feel, therefore I am.
And you can hear it in public on the morning show or some other show.
What's the view show?
But I feel is what's real.
So in the view, you see the propagation of the drama of meanness, the dominance of narcissism.
I feel that so-and-so is right or wrong or something.
In reality, who cares what you feel?
I don't really care what people are, unless they're in the office and they got a problem.
What do I care what people feel like or what they think?
Because there's no reality to it, other than for them, that's their subjective state of consciousness,
which they're stuck with, you see.
So ours has become the society of narcissism, of course.
And everybody is now aware of that.
And the virtual reality of the media tend to amplify that narcissism.
And, you know, the blogger land is what I think or what I feel or what I see as true.
And what I feel should dominate.
The world should change because of what I feel.
Isn't that true, honey?
No?
The world should change because of what I feel.
The world is wrong because it doesn't change.
I'm never going to make it on The View.
I think everybody's wrong, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
That gets you a couple million dollars a year.
Holy boy.
So the media become what I call a freak show.
Yeah.
Demented professors with all the delusions.
9-11, America did 9-11.
They don't have any trouble getting big money and getting on TV.
In the world I grew up with, they would be, you know, in an institution.
I first started in psychiatry as a resident.
And it was the asylum for the insane.
Milwaukee County Asylum for the Insane.
That's what it said.
And you drove under the thing.
And they didn't use euphemisms.
Then part of my residency in neurology was at Downstate, Brooklyn.
And that was the hospital for the ruptured and crippled.
People did not suffer from a neurotic sensitivity.
If you're a crip, you're a crip.
So what's the big deal?
Stumpy, they call you Stumpy.
Come on, Stumpy.
You didn't feel bad about it.
You didn't feel insulted.
You didn't sue them for hurting your sensitive feelings.
Oh, sensitive.
Oh, our world is so sensitive.
I don't want to hurt their feelings by telling them they're being sensitive.
The narcissistic generation is so exalts.
Exalts the inner ego that it's insulted all the time.
It's always insulted.
If you're insulted, don't try and change the world.
Try to transcend your ego.
The world and the universe evolution is not going to cater to your personal ego now or ever.
It's never going to cater to your ego.
It doesn't care about your ego.
Only you have to grow up.
So when I grew up in traditional America, it was your job to handle your sensitive feelings.
It wasn't society's job.
And if you didn't get over it by the time you got a job, you'd get over it on the job.
Everybody called each other Wop, Bo, Hunk.
The guys got over your sensitivity.
You know, Shorty, I was called Shorty.
What about my sensitivity?
I called my lawyer.
I've been insulted.
They called me Shorty.
That was my name.
Shorty, climb up this mast.
And so they would lift me up.
And I'd sit on the bosun's chair.
And up there in the bosun's chair, the bosun's maid said, Shorty, don't look down.
I said, I'm afraid of heights.
She says, just don't look down.
I went all the way to the top of the mast.
And I just couldn't resist.
I looked down.
Oh!
That was a mistake.
Because I thought the intelligent volitional mind ruled things, but it didn't.
At that moment, my entire body went into muscular spasm to the mast.
I could not let it go.
It came up with a bosun's chair.
They had a bosun's chair.
And he said, Shorty, all you got to do is let go.
The bosun's chair will take you down.
And I said to him, Jimmy, I said, he was champion boxer of the third fleet.
I said, I can't let go.
My body won't let go.
He says, Shorty, I'll have to cold cock you.
I said, Jimmy was my best friend, so I didn't mind.
He'd knocked me out once before anyway.
So I said, OK, Jimmy, go ahead.
So he pulled back.
He had the fastest, most dreadful left jab in the third fleet.
He was champion of the third fleet.
His left jab, he would just down everybody in the whole bar and wipe them out with left
jabs.
And if you got a right cross, goodbye.
The ambulance had to come get you.
So anyway, he said, he pulled back, and I knew he was going to knock me out.
So as he pulled back and was about to knock me out, left jab.
I said, I can't let go.
He had to knock me out.
The body let go of its own.
It was non-volitional.
It wasn't that I was afraid of being knocked out.
He'd knocked me out before.
There's nothing to it.
One minute you're awake, the next minute you're not.
Nothing easier than getting knocked out.
So that was the I that I was having trouble with.
We're going to get to the more sophisticated understandings of I because it has to do with
the pathways to enlightenment.
Is the I the chooser?
Is it volition?
Is it the witness?
Is it the will?
You'll find the human will, people will say, well, I've tried willpower.
The will of the average person calibrates at the same level as their level of consciousness.
What I just said is a fact.
All right.
So if your consciousness is 205 and you use willpower.
The power of your willpower is going to be 205.
Let's reaffirm that.
That is correct.
All right.
So when we say people should use willpower, we put them down, they should use willpower
for this or willpower for that, but your willpower is only as good as your muscles, you might
say, your mental muscles.
On the other hand, let's say you surrender it to divine will, God's will.
I have my soul.
I have my soul, O Lord.
I'm unable.
I surrender to thee, O Lord.
I turn my life over to thee, O Lord.
Amen.
That calibrates over 800, 900, 905.
That calibrates at 900.
So surrendering to God, the secret of the 12-step program and other such programs is
by your personal will, you can't do it.
You're wasting your time.
By surrendering to divine will.
Now you open up a consciousness level of 900.
So the impossible becomes possible.
The unlikely begins to happen and we see the whole world of the miraculous open up.
And there are quite a few people in this room that are here as consequent to the miraculous.
How many people here ascribe the fact that you are alive today to the miraculous?
Yes.
I, myself, was saved by the miraculous.
And it's interesting when we watch the Weather Channel, which I've spoken about before, people
in hurricanes.
The people who survived the hurricanes, 99% of them prayed to God, 99%.
Then there are some, there's a few who were lifted up in the eye of the hurricane.
I remember this woman, still in her chair.
Huh?
Oh, tornado, yeah, anyway, a twister, lifted a couple hundred feet in the air, suspended
in mid-air in the middle of this tornado.
And in it, she said, I went into a state of infinite profound peace.
In the middle of the tornado, suspended a hundred feet over the ground.
So we have permission to ask God.
Her consciousness level was over 600, 605 when you surrender to God.
So she surrendered her fear.
She surrendered her fear to God and said, I'll leave it up to Thee, O Lord, and went
into a state of profound peace.
She was unhappy when the storm was over.
She slowly got settled down.
But it calibrated at 600.
And that's the first level of enlightenment, and 600 is a magnificent, beautiful level
in which nothing is needed, nothing is lacking, et cetera, a world of perfection.
So the miraculous then.
The miraculous then expresses itself even in daily life.
Therefore surrendering to God's will in a matter or asking God's help.
So prayer is powerful.
You of your own volition can only pull up 200 volts, 200 volts to do the job.
And if you surrender to God through prayer and supplication, I surrender this to Thee,
O Lord, and accept Your will for me, you're pulling in like 600 to 900 power, you know?
You surrender to God.
So because of the quantum reality of that, the likelihood of potentiality actualizing
is empowered, of course, by the field of consciousness, the whole Heisenberg effect.
So the likelihood of this becoming a this or a this, at 600 it will be, at let's say
200, it will become here.
Let's say you cry out out of fear.
And then you use reason.
You use reason, then you use intelligence, then you surrender.
So by virtue of the power of the field, the likelihood of what you're holding in mind
increases in likelihood of manifesting.
And by the time the miraculous, and many people here have experienced the miraculous and witnessed
it, about level 540 to 570, the miraculous starts to become commonplace.
You think a thought and it happens.
Not as cause and effect.
But if you hold it in mind, it's a likelihood.
The higher the level of consciousness, the more this happens.
And if you need a parking space in front of the Lincoln Center, you just drive there and
as you drive there, a car pulls out and you pull there.
Right in the first parking lot right next to the Lincoln Center.
Numero uno.
One.
out just as you pull it and but that's the way the life becomes so the spiritually committed
life is a totally different life you don't live in the same reality that other people do
other people below 200 live in an alternate reality
pitts the columnist pitts calls it an alternate reality
lou calls it something similar to anyway below 200 then the people live in a different reality
a different reality an alternate reality therefore to understand other people that you find puzzling
or conflictual if you accept the fact they live in a alter a different reality than you do
then it's easy to forgive them it's hard to forgive them if you presume that their sense
of reality is the same as yours but if you accept the fact that they live in a different reality
is the same as yours that would make them evil willful awful illegal deserving of the worst you
can think of but they don't live in your reality they live in their reality and in their reality
it's perfectly okay what they're doing so that makes it a little easier to live in the world
which is so divided as it is politically and militarily etc how their people are living
in a different reality is the same as yours that would make them evil willful awful illegal
deserving of the worst you can think of but they don't live in their reality and in their reality
and it's not your reality so the i'm dubious about political systems you know good old america
wave the flag and we're going to make everybody just like us we think that democracy is the most
wonderful thing god's gift to mankind they think it's stupid that all those dumb peasants who
haven't even graduated from grade school vote you gotta be cuckoo so
the fact that other people don't become enthused about our reality is because they live in a
different reality so our downside is we don't understand and have respect for the fact that
people live in a different reality it's not the same reality as yours it's neither bitter or worse
it's just different a different reality and don't think people out in the cosmos thinks
that planet earth is you know you're from where planet earth they all go oh
oh that's why you're so stupid yeah you folks live in an alternate reality so the different
views of the world you know one view of the world is the world is what it is because we have the
option because we have the option so freedom really means from its higher meaning the freedom
of choice and therefore we can transcend negative karma and gain positive karma so this world if as you
see this world spiritually this world spiritually is perfect the way it is perfect you have maximum
opportunity to gain positive merit and undo negative karma so this world is perfect the way it
is anybody want to change it all right i got you
it's perfect the way it is all right so all right so we'll take a break for how long 15 minutes okay