anti-religious. See, it's one thing to
be a religious. it's another to be
anti-religious.
So anti- relligionism
uh calibrates much lower.
Uh you could just you could be honest
and say I really don't understand what a
religion is all about. It either appeals
to me or it doesn't appeal to me. But
you don't have to take a stance against
it
like goodness, love, and honor. You
don't have to be that way, but you don't
have to be against goodness, love, and
honor.
Uh
you don't have to be against compassion.
All right? So, anti- relligionism then
calibrates much less than skepticism or
calibrates much less than atheism
because it's a it's a hostility. So
anti- relligionism
is really a hostility. Yes. It's really
a hostility. Resist.
Yeah. So it's not uh it's not u
objective at all. Uh it sort of hates
religion and we have a lot of that in
our current society.
People that just hate hate it.
uh and and especially hate any reference
divin to divinity.
And why should it hate hate divinity or
any reference divinity?
Because of the core of of the of the ego
is narcissism.
And the narcissistic core of the ego
hates anything that denies its own
divinity.
The narcissistic core of the ego
secretly thinks it is God.
secretly thinks it is God and hates
anything that refute refutes
uh its divinity. It wants to see itself
as the infinite power of the universe
and hates anything other than that. So
you see that narcissism is at its core
uh grandiose megalomaniac
and hates anything that that makes it
aware that it is not divinity.
We already said that evolutionary
psychology has a certain pragmatism to
it. So it calibrates and the levels of
pragmatism. The low the 200s are
pragmatic levels and therefore it's
useful within its own domain.
The growth of psychological mechanisms
as a qu consequence of evolution
uh is of fact is factual. And you see
it's really not it's not hostile. It's
not controversial. It doesn't negate
that guy could exist. It says that one
psychologically man mankind has
benefited and evolved psychologically as
a consequence of his own evolution.
Atheism of course calibrates at 165. So
we know that the atheist atheists and
people calibrate below 200 cannot do
consciousness calibration. They cannot
do consciousness calibration.
If you've negate truth and the source of
truth, which is divinity,
then you might say as a karmic
consequence, you're unable to use truth.
So if you hate truth,
God doesn't give you a truth meter.
You say, "Where's my truth meter?" Well,
you deny you deny truth. So you don't
get a truth meter. Okay? So these people
wander through the world uh not knowing
that they live in a sort of a dark
understanding or dark lack of
understanding.
Um deism and theism
of course means the belief in a divine
being without being a religionist.
So the founders of the constitution in
the United States of America were the
theists and deists but not religionists.
Consequently, we are free of religion.
Uh so the government will shall not
impose any kind of religion on people.
On the other hand, where does freedom of
speech come from? It comes from the
creator. Because of the equality of
man's creation, all men are equal. That
comes out of deism and theism, but not
religion. So this is ours is not a
religious
uh society. However, it is deistic and
theistic. So when we talk about free
speech, the paradox is free speech comes
out of disism and theism.
So then the use of free speech to vilify
divinity and all is paradoxically
extremely stupid and it calibrates very
low because your right to free speech
arises from disism and theism. Without
theism or theism you don't have any free
speech.
That's a true true resist.
Now, isn't that a message?
Without theism and theism, you don't
have any free speech.
So, aris that man.
He doesn't believe in the source of the
validity of free speech. Why should he
enjoy it? I would arrest everybody who
was a, you know, arrest everybody,
put them in rehab.
Therefore, the theistic and theistic
foundation of the constitution and
American free society is the very origin
of free speech. Without it, you have no
free speech. without it you have no free
speech.
So the deification of free speech has
now reached uh the level of absurdity
where of course you can use it to vilify
theism and theism.
So that's the paradox of it.
We already said that the bottom up
mechanistic reductionism calibrates at
185 185
and the top down is from infinity.
Godhead as the light of life. The light
of life is in uh the truth of that is
infinity. Divinity is the source of
life. Life cannot be destroyed. It can
only take form.
So,
I don't want anybody to be afraid of
death anymore because it's not a
possibility. You cannot die. Oh, that's
God's got his problems, too.
You can go to realms where you think
you're dead.
Okay.
You can go to realms
where you believe you're dead. Resist.
Oh, so if you want to die, you can.
You might spend some huge amounts of
time there.
People do spend huge amounts of times in
self- negation resist. So you have the
option even of dying if you want to die.
That's a fact.
That's a fact. Wow.
If you want to be dead, you can just
become like a nothing. Wow.
Oh boy.
I was scared for a while you couldn't
die. I thought
if you believe firmly in death as
non-existence,
then you negate and you negate
consciousness and become unconscious.
Wow. You can void yourself right into
void. Okay? You can void yourself into
void. Don't go to that neighborhood.
Look out for the voids there.
Turn a corner and there's a void. You
know,
come and join me into nothingness.
All right. So
to uh value one's existence then
because you begin to see its infinite
potential
the infinite love of God as you begin to
experience the infinite love of God then
the option that you choose is love and
lovingness as it becomes uh infinite is
overpowering
to have discovered nothingness.
I discovered nothingness at age four.
Yes. Came back into this lifetime in the
void of nothingness.
Yes.
I wouldn't recommend it. On the other
hand, I wouldn't knock it.
Nothingness is nothingness.
Anyway, the void is not the ultimate
reality. The ultimate reality. So as you
reach advanced states of consciousness,
what you look for is love. The love is
what differentiates nothingness from
allness, divinity from
from the void.
Godhead as the light of life calibrates
as in infinite. Now the Scopes trial was
in 1926.
Uh I was born 27. So it was a year
before I got born. That's how I remember
it. Anyway, it was put on by James
Bowwin who calibrates at 180. Now, the
reason Bowwin put it on was he was
trying to get publicity for the ACLU. He
was the founder of the ACLU
and the town where they presented it was
in was interested in increasing its
local business.
So, a local teacher uh voluntarily
taught uh evolution in the school.
uh and got himself arrested. Well,
anyway, we all know the story of the
Scopes trial. Uh Daryl calibrated at
450. Now, he was a very brilliant
lawyer.
Uh Daryl was a very brilliant lawyer. He
later came to play a role in the Leupold
and Lobe case. Leopold and Lo, you
remember with two rich kids that for
kicks decided they would murder somebody
and they were condemned to death.
Darl discerned that in school they were
being taught the philosophy of Nietz
neg you know the negative philosophy of
Nietz and it's therefore appeal to the
judge. She says these boys have been
brainwashed in our educational system
and to fail their capacity their reality
capacity has diminished as a result of
indoctrination
by false philosophies
and therefore their death sentence was
canled.
This has a very interesting application
uh to today's academia where falsehood
is taught routinely huh as an
indoctrination rather than an education.
So Daryl played a very significant role
there. Now Darl was very intelligent and
also very logical. You can see 450. So
he was integrous. He said logic is the
ultimate reality and the Bible does not
meet the requirements. See,
Brian was very famous at 510. Uh Brian w
was uh a religionist. So he represented
uh each one represented this in the
Scopes trial. Each one was a perfect
representative of the argument. Darl did
indeed stick to logic and Brian did
stick stick to faith. So it was faith
against logic
and Darl used logic against faith and
ridicule things in the Bible see which
are
you might say myth mythologic
representations
uh
that's not the right word.
certain things are taught by analogy by
uh mythology because there is no way you
can describe it in a linear domain.
Anyway, what happened was
Darl attacked that which is mythologic
you might say. Anyway, Baldwin later on
went to found the ACLU.
The ACLU is of course evolidly atheistic
uh hates religion and and ethics and
morality and all that kind of stuff. So,
uh, Bowwin then got publicity for the
ACLU. The ACLU right now calibrates. Do
we have another slide after this? All
right. So, we have a moment. Let's see
what the ACLU calibrates.
>> What?
>> Oh, ACLU permission to do that here.
Calibrates over 140,
150,
145.
150 ACO calis right so it is lined up
with atheism and anti-religionism and
it's uh so so Baldwin's
uh ambition was uh successful
we say that things are happening
autonomously rather than as a result of
intention things are happening because
of that which you are and the field in
which you live.
So there's both the linear versus the
nonlinear contextualization of
descriptions of creation.
The big big bang theory calibrates at
450.
Back hole theory calibrates at 455.
Inflation these are all theories of the
beginning of the universe calibrated
450. So they are not talking about the
underlying reality. They are talking
about the me mechanistic consequences of
the underlying reality. The fact that
there are multiple universes calibrates
as true.
Multiple universes. In fact, there's an
infinite number of universes.
Infinite number of universes. We we did
ask that before, but in a somewhat
different context. There's an infinite
potentially there's an infinite number
of universes produced. Yes. Because God
is omnisient, omnipotent, omnipresent,
there would be no limitation to what
could be created as a result of the
underlying reality.
Parallel universe theory is false. That
that's a limitation that there's another
universe just like our universe and it's
parallel and uh that is a falsehood
resist. Sort of like a doppelganger.
You know what doppelganger is? Huh?
How many people know what doppelganger
is? Okay, thank you. So that's a the
sort of a theory of doubles that the the
doppelganger is like a double.
So the parallel universe theory uh
calibrates out as faults. So I' I've
tried to cover the basics now of what is
uh an ongoing see the Scopes trial is is
with us today.
with us today in the political dialogue
when we get home and watch the news
tonight. There'd be something in which
there's a contrast between these two
paradigms of reality. Two paradigms of
reality.
These two paradigms, one is below 200
and the other is above 200. There are
actually two different civilizations
occupying this planet. Two different
human civilizations.
those that are above 200 and those that
are below 200.
Now, how can you bring them together?
You can't.
Hate to tell you the facts, buddy, but
you can't. Yeah, that's true. Yeah, they
live in different paradigms of reality.
And you saw the from this morning that
their brain physiology is different. So
when I said it's better you say it's
better to love them and let them go that
makes sense to me to somebody who's a
fundamentalist a radical fundamentalist
forgive them he says it's better to kill
them my duty is to kill infidels and my
duty here with this side of my brain is
to forgive them Lord Jesus said said the
only sin is the only error is one of
ignorance and so did the Buddha so we
can say if they don't know any better,
then forgive them because they don't
know any better. See, that's this side
of the brain. There's a large segment on
our planet now that says don't forgive
them, kill them.
Our duty is to kill non-believers. Kill
them. Shall we forgive them or shall we
kill them?
Depends on which side of your brain is
operative.
Shall we kill them?
Shall we forgive them?
Each one of us has to make that decision
within us. There's an interesting new
book out the the politics of Jesus
Christ.
Politics of Jesus Christ is really all
about the sermon on the mount and how
that manifests in our current society
and its laws and the constitution,
the rights of man, etc. Very
interesting. It's quite a contrast to
the to teachings that say the exact
opposite. And how how are you gonna get
the two to blend? I don't think you
will.
Well, there goes our meridy do and dozy
do fantasy of the if we all just nice to
each other, we'll all get along fine.
No, we won't.
Crash. There was your kindergarter.
My fouryear-old just bit the dust.
Why? Because that would not serve the
purpose of this world.
The purpose of this world is maximum
karmic benefit. You have to have the
choice of this or this. So how would we
have any karmic benefit in which there
was no choice of this? And you were
forced to always eat lollipops and be
good to your mom.
All right. So, the purpose of the world.
I just finished the last book I'm
working on. I've been at it for over a
year. I'm absolutely exhausted.
But any we have about 35 different ways
of looking at the world. You know the
world is a optimum maximum karmic
opportunity
to gain good karma and undo bad karma.
That's
we'll ask that right now. We have
permission to ask that that calibrates
at infinity.
The purpose of this year world is not to
eliminate badness at all. This is not
supposed to be a heavenly domain. If
this was heaven, we'd be in the 600
range in other realms.
This is where we evolve and gain karmic
merit. Yeah. We say no to the negative
and yes to the positive. This requires
discernment. Discernment means the
capacity to tell truth from falsehood,
illusion from reality. Therefore, the
purpose of all these lectures is that we
will then have what we need to make the
correct decisions at all times, which in
itself is a rare gift, is it not? I to
me it was a rare gift to be able to
discover. Thank God you can tell truth
from false. I mean, I I was boggled by
it and I only share it with you because
I was boggled by it.
I share it. That's my obligation is to
share it and to devote myself to your
spiritual evolution. And therefore,
we'll take a break for lunch. God bless
you. And then
Well, we saved the tough time for last.
>> Okay.
>> Someone I know well has questions.
I I've never really asked any questions,
but there's some qu there's some
questions.
>> There's some questions that I think that
we should go over that everybody is
interested in. And
I want to know how does one pray for
self-healing or someone else's
self-healing?
So you're bringing up uh prayer alto
together.
>> Prayer altogether.
>> Yeah. Prayer alto together. And then
prayer that's directed
and uh the acknowledgment that God's
will is sovereign.
If it is thy will, if it is in accord
with thy will, oh Lord, I pray for the
relief of uh something or other.
Then I also pray uh in my own sake u for
a greater awareness of the meaning of
what it is that I'm praying for.
You know is it something of karmic
propensity uh something that uh can be
gone beyond uh by the greater by
affirming the greater truth? Can a
lesser truth be subordinated? You know
what I'm saying?
Uh so at all times the there's the
acknowledgment of God's sovereignty and
what we call linguistically divine will
uh of course which is just a a
verbalization. Huh? If it is uh within
if it is your will for me. So for
instance in the 12st step groups people
uh uh pray for God's will pray for
knowledge of God's will for me and the
power to carry it out.
>> So that acknowledges the sovereignty of
of God rather than just the wishfulness
of the human ego. Otherwise you just end
up with dear god I want a new car and uh
you know
>> I want to win the lottery you know
>> I want to win the lottery right
so the reason that you know when we in
this book we just finished we calibrated
the impact of many of all religions on
our current society Christianity is
about 450 Judaism is about 450
um and Um I think it was about 450 and
then Buddhism is about five points
higher than that. But then highest of
all much to my amazement the impact of
the 12step groups on human on American
society is greater than the higher
calibration than even the churches. You
know
>> it makes no claims. It sets up no it has
no opinions and outside issues. It has
no uh enemies. So, so how would you
start out this prayer?
>> Give give me an example of a prayer. You
know, we're all taught by different
religions on as to how to pray and we
have certain, you know, uh Bible phrases
and things that we, you know, say as a
prayer. But how would you start out of
prayer?
>> I think the way you're you you've grown
up will give you a certain comfort. So,
you feel comfortable praying in a
certain style.
You know, I had a traditional
uh Christian upbringing and uh that many
things were part of it. Uh saying the
rosary for one thing, etc.
>> Uh propitiation for one's sins.
>> Uh so, you know, praying is to
propitiate for sins.
uh it's to acknowledge the sovereignty
of God to to acknowledge uh your
awareness that uh the destiny of the
soul is uh
you know aligned with your choices in
this world and lifetime. Yeah.
>> So would you start out
asking for what you want or do you ask
for you know guidance? I mean how do you
start out? That's my question. Well, um,
in in in the case of the person not
speaking, uh, there's first the the
acknowledgment of the so of sovereignty
of God,
>> right?
>> I pray to thee, oh Lord,
creator and, uh, source of all mercy and
wisdom, etc.
And if it is in accord with
>> divine will or
>> divine will,
>> I prayed uh for help with you know some
person who seems to need healing. You
know seems to need in my in my vision
appears to need healing.
>> Now that person may be undoing some very
negative karma. So
you know what you see needs to be healed
may not be what needs to be healed at
all. You know,
>> what needs to be healed maybe is your
ignorance about what it's all about. You
know,
>> okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Well,
>> so then wouldn't you wouldn't so then
you would ask to see it differently?
>> Yes. Uh I also am more specific and then
I always ask is there a karmic uh is
this is this a is there is there a
karmic precedent to this?
>> Okay.
>> See because so anything that is like
seems to be an affliction
now I've lost vision in one eye and poor
vision in the other. So I ask oh Lord
uh I pray for forgiveness for any
impairment of the vision of others that
I may have brought about about willingly
or unwittingly. Okay.
>> So first I assume it's a karmic
consequence.
>> Right.
>> All right. So let's just do it for real
right now. The the visual loss uh has to
do with karmic propensity.
It has to do with impairing the vision
of others in past lives. Resist.
>> No. No.
The vision of others.
>> So, it wasn't a past
you don't need to see now.
>> Well, I I I'll get to that.
>> Uh is it something I have permission to
research right here and now?
>> Yes.
>> Uh so it it has a karmic uh antecedent
has to do with physical vision. Resist.
>> Oh, does not have to do with spiritual
vision.
>> Okay. Okay. So, all right. The one in me
who let's say blinded others in other
lifetimes
uh is clear.
>> Okay.
>> The one who well let's see what could
you what could a person have done that
loss of vision would be the karmic
consequence.
>> Well, when you lose your vision, you
have a basically I would think that you
would go more inward. So maybe that's
what this is going to lead to.
>> Okay. So I see. All right. So it could
be a reflection of aversion to the
world. Oh, I got it.
>> Uhhuh.
>> It's an aversion to the attractions of
the world. Resist.
>> Yeah,
>> that was interesting. Th this is how we
solve little problems.
>> Well, you see the the as a Buddhist, I
uh I I choose to let go all attractions
and aversions. to see part of Zen
meditation etc.
uh to get rid of all attractions and
aversions.
So, oh I see. So, this was something I
pronounced upon myself. Oh, this is
something the higher self pronounced
upon myself. Resist.
>> Okay.
>> Uhhuh.
>> So, it does make sense.
>> All right. So, you see you you become
entrapped
by the linearity of the world. All
right. So this is an escape from the
trap of the linearity of the world.
Seduction by the world. Aha.
>> Especially you and it's sexual
expressions too. Resist. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> See because
uh because of form uh one gets attracted
be beyond one's will
>> because of uh endocrine function. So
you're an animal. You see? All right. So
this is a way of negating the dominance
of the animal. Resist. Wow.
>> It's a way of negating the dominance of
the animal. See, the animal sees and
wants. Huh.
Huh. Interesting, huh? And if you can't
let go of it one way, you're going to
let go of it the other. Well, of course,
I have been letting go, right?
>> Otherwise,
>> uh, right now I find my way around
spatially. I remember spatially where
thing is. I just grabbed this cup out of
spatial memory, but I don't see it.
>> So, Oh, that's interesting. Uhhuh.
>> I thought maybe that the reason that
we're talking about his loss of sight in
one eye. Um, I thought maybe it might be
that you were supposed to it was written
to be more of inward um meditation, you
know, at this.
>> Yes, I agree. Okay. So it it's also to
promote
uh inwardness of attention exist.
>> Yeah.
>> Because it's bothered me writing this
book. I've had to go back in the world
so-called uh reality, spirituality, and
modern man. So what is the world of
modern man? I had to look at the world
of modern man. Well, I ignored the world
of modern man for decades and decades. I
never looked. I never listen to the
radio. I never got a newspaper. I never
read a magazine. I remember I didn't
know that Reian had been shot until like
a month or two later in a restaurant
somebody's talking about Rean
>> getting shot. I never even heard of it,
you know, assassinated, attempted or
something.
So then to do this book, I had to look
at the world and it was frankly disme
on the internet,
>> you know, on on a b, you know, on a
business on a business website, you get
smuggled with smothered with with
pornography.
>> Here you got a business Ben say, you
know, Ben and Jerry's bicycle repair and
the pornography is coming in.
>> I'm sure all of you have had that at
home.
>> Yeah. So
I I had a dim view of freedom of speech
for a while.
>> Yeah. I believe is you know as Socrates
said you give people enough freedom
they'll just drown themselves with it
and vote themselves into poverty and
dissolution and therefore a democracy is
not going to last more than two or 30
hund years.
>> Okay so getting back to prayer I'm going
to back into that.
>> Okay
>> that is prayer. All right.
So, so getting going back to prayer then
what what you would what you would do
what you would do is then you would you
know you approach the God Almighty
whoever
>> yes
>> whatever term you use
>> then do you then ask for what you want
to or to ask to see it differently or
how how what is the progression I'm
trying to get
>> it could be wishing to see it either way
and doing the chapters on the nature of
the book I mean the nature of the world
I ask constantly to see it differently.
>> Okay.
>> To see it differently. To see it
differently.
>> Uhhuh. And uh
I you know the spiritual night came up
again. You know
>> the
spleen of the spiritual night came up.
Indignation
that you give people freedom and this is
what they do with it. use it for
desecration and obscinity and perversion
and decadence.
>> Yeah. And then I realized this is not
the this is not heaven. This is not a
heavenly realm.
If this is a purgatorial realm, then
that's perfect. Okay. Let me just see if
that's So if this is a purgatorial
realm, then that's perfect. Is this?
Yeah. Because you got to have choice.
Otherwise, how can you get rid of
negative karma and choose positive
karma? Well, it's like good and evil,
constant bad,
>> right? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Of everything.
>> Uhhuh.
>> So, it would make sense.
>> There there's also you're asking about
prayer and uh there's also
I don't know how to describe this, but
it's um
a way of being with God. It's as though
that which you are becomes thus
to thee, oh Lord, if it is thy will, I
ask for. So it's like a supplication.
It's like a yin position.
So a lot of people have prayer is very
yang. Uh please help us win the ball
game and punish the evildoers.
But the yin position is uh very is
equally powerful as the yang. See? And
uh
so the masculine archetype tends to
think in terms of yang type of praying.
>> Uh please help us win over our enemies.
The yin position is the infinite
feminine. the feminine has equal power
and the feminine
uh does thusly and summons God's will
instead of demanding it or trying to
force it to thee, oh Lord. So your life,
you know, the sermon I always give has
to do with um making your life a prayer.
Yeah.
>> Well, another question that I have is
there's so much talk about manifesting
things into your life. Oh,
>> all right. Um, there's so much talk
right now about, you know, if you will,
things that they eventually come into
your life. Well, if karma is involved in
that, then that would not be so.
>> Well, the degree to which it's
fulfilled, of course,
>> right?
>> The power of manifestation, isn't that
some kind of a rig thing they sell? Um,
>> yeah, I think so. I don't know. Um, but
I'm just saying
>> power of choice or something like that.
you know the power you know that you
have
>> I got it yeah
>> you know the
>> the law of attraction
>> it's like a marketed concept
>> a marketed concept
>> and I want you to speak on that because
we're having so much of that right now
>> well the ego loves it
>> yes
the spiritual ego just thrives on it
>> it does yeah well that's a beginning
phase so
>> so what you hold in mind tends to
manifest as an old truism there's
nothing new about it one of the First
things I learned you know was what you
hold in mind tends to manifest
and then later on you realize it's not
due to the human will. Uh but like goes
to like kind of a universal uh balance
of energy. It's more of an energy
balance and it becomes impersonal
what you hold in mind.
So eventually what you hold in mind
becomes more and more
detached from personal valition. So when
it starts out people I I want to
uh what was there
her song? I want to BMW or I want to
>> Oh Janice Jofflin.
>> Janet Joplin.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh Lord what you mean? Mercedes Benz.
Yeah.
>> All right. So we we were talking about
the it's what is it called? They market
it as the law of attraction. Okay. The
law of attraction. We have permission to
calibrate it. The law of attraction as
it is currently popularized calibrates
over 250 300
260 255. All right. So that's above 200
200. All right. So what you hold in mind
then tends to manifest you know uh and
of course you learn that
you learn that when you catch hives in
the
>> so anyway
>> well I was just curious about that
because you know a lot of people are
confusing that right now with
>> you know if they
>> manifest it hard enough that'll bring it
into their life but also karma it's your
own karma would have to do with this
too.
>> Of course, you know, as a Buddhist, I
look at it, all it does is increase
one's attachment to the world of wanting
this.
>> Well, if you were saying that you wanted
all right, for instance, let's say
someone says, okay, I want
enlightenment.
>> All right. So, you would be attracted to
all those things that would lead you to
the path of
>> enlightenment. Yes.
>> Right. Mhm.
>> But whether or not you actually have
attained it would be your karmic
destiny.
>> Is that right?
>> It would be your karmic destiny to make
such a choice in the first place because
the chance of making that decision.
>> But I mean whether or not you obtained
it in that lifetime even though you did
all these things to obtain it that would
still be up to the karma, wouldn't it?
>> It would certainly would be up to karma.
I mean the number of people who choose
enlightenment as the ultimate uh uh goal
of their life is what less than one in
10 million.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Let's see. We have permission on
this. It's less than one in 10 million.
It's less than one in 50 million. Less
than one in a 100 million.
>> Okay.
>> One in 90 million.
>> No.
>> One in 85 million.
One in 80 million. Approximately the
chances of choosing you know being
serious about reaching enlightenment is
one in 80 million.
You can see how rare this kind of a
group is and why when we calibrate it
this group counterbalances a huge amount
of the negativity of mankind just this
small group here
because that's a choice hardly anybody
makes you know 90 thou 90 million
people.
>> So when we say well your kind of your
theme is live your life like a prayer.
Yes.
>> Okay. So in other words, what you're
saying is that all of us should open up
and
literally turn our life over to God or a
higher being so that we'll be able to to
live that daily as a prayer.
>> Is that correct?
>> I think uh well I my I tend to position
it sort of in a yin
>> yin kind of a manner. See
>> in other words you present the question
and then step back. I try to be that
which would attract that which I
consider desirable. But then I also ask
God if it is uh you know for the highest
good. If that is for the highest good.
>> So when we ask a question of the arm we
always ask I ask it silently all the
time.
>> Right.
>> Uh in the name of the highest good you
know.
>> Okay. But I was a little bit more
concerned about yeah you know
>> what how we really place a prayer how we
lead into it how you know and then it of
course it's up to God whether it's
answered in karma and everything else
that's involved in it.
>> Then we have these people who are saying
that all you have to do is man manifest
all these things and they come to you
you know and it's almost even without
prayer which is kind of it kind of goes
against my grain when I hear that.
>> Yeah I know what you mean. Uh,
I don't know. There isn't anything I
want. So, I don't I don't try it out
because
you might get what you ask for. You know
what I mean? Camel. You ask for a camel
and they around the block. You know what
I mean? But if it's if you're if you are
for instance when we said that people
that are on the karmic path they they
pick a group you know that are likely to
think the same way they do and they
proceed on their path to becoming
enlightenment. Yet fewer than 80
>> and yet what
>> fewer than one in eight what was it one
and eight 80 million choose that path
you know. So it's really
>> well just to choose enlightenment itself
amongst the common people of the world
is one in 90 million. Then out of those
who choose the path the chances of
becoming enlightened today and
considerably because of the work we've
done are now 1,000 times greater than at
any time in history.
>> Okay?
>> Because in the old days you had to
figure out what's the pathway to truth.
Well, you had to go by uh by cultural
tradition.
Um
good luck with the guru. Uh all kinds of
ways how you need good luck with
>> that is really kind of serious.
>> Calibrate all the prominent gurus and
you see what I see.
>> Yeah.
>> Anyway, so the chances even if you chose
enlightenment were slim.
>> Yeah. And then you've got the karmic uh
uh factors to take care of. Then you
have to sacrifice many things. You see,
or it seems to you like a sacrifice. Uh
let go of wanting a lot of things. So
after you learn how to manifest things,
you don't bother with anymore because
you know anything that you really need
or want, you know, you have it.
>> So if you have everything, uh what could
there be to want? You know, nothing less
want. If you're if you're of a higher
spiritual nature, you wouldn't want
anything anyway.
>> You reach that point eventually
where you're complete and total at every
second. Like if you ask me right now,
>> what do I want right now?
>> Um,
well,
must be something I want.
I give you a million dollars if you want
something. Okay. I will. God said he'll
give me a million dollars if I want
something. Okay.
I want to be free of the temptation of a
million dollars.
You see the the Hollywood hotties fall
into the
uh I don't know how they ever get out of
it because the glamour of all that
wealth and publicity, you know.
>> Okay. If some if someone you knew, you
know, um say
You can't intervene with someone else's
karmic destiny.
>> That's correct. Right.
>> So your question is when then what good
is prayer? Huh?
>> Yeah.
>> So your your prayer on that person's in
that person's behalf
is a consequence of their positive
karma.
>> I see. Okay. the wicked are not being
prayed for by anyone. Let's see if
that's true. That's true. So, if you've
got positive karma and say, I I I pray
for my grandmother,
>> you know, who was so sweet and loving
and uh you pray in her behalf,
>> she has the karmic positive credit
balance. I see
>> that your prayer is going to make a
difference.
>> Okay.
>> So, my grandmother's on the opposite
side all the time. And I'd say
I just did to grandma, thank you
>> for reading me Shakespeare when I was a
kid.
She used to put me on a lap, you know,
and read Shakespeare
>> and she loved classical music. So we
would listen to opera and she would read
me Shakespeare.
Well, that affects the neuronal
connections uh in your brain. You
understand? So these neurons uh are
constantly forming and being left uh to
die if they're unused. And so these
neurons when you come along with certain
energies such as beauty and music and
that kind of thing, those neurons then
begin to connect and they they they they
form networks with each other. So when
people say, "What can I do to increase
spirituality?" Surround yourself with
beauty, the beauty of music. Notice the
beauty of all that exists.
Um, and my grandmother did it with my
father while she he was still in the
womb and everybody my my mother didn't
believe in that. She laughed at my
grandmother. It's so oldfashioned. But
my grandmother listened to beautiful
music while my father was in her
uterine. See, as it turned out, my
father was a great musician, very
famous, well-known musician and uh did
have great musical ability and all the
family had musical ability. We all we
had a couple pianos in the house was a
violin and gun as well. So that uh that
intention then uh tends to increase the
likelihood. You increase likelihood. So
you you could also look at prayer as
likelihoods increasing likelihood
>> that
>> within karmic parameters you know within
per permission karmic permission.
>> Yeah. Because I mean they did this whole
who was it someone did this whole thing
on prayer whether or not prayer healed
and or it didn't heal and they felt that
it didn't make any difference.
>> Yes.
>> But that was it was set up incorrectly.
The whole way it was set up was set up
incorrectly.
>> Yes. All right. So the prayer study we
have permission to ask about it.
Calibrates over 190 195
prayer study calibrated 190.
>> So it was under 200
>> cost temple a million dollars for that
study. And uh Templeton itself
calibrates at 500,
>> right?
>> Templeton Foundation is very integrous.
So somebody took their money and ran
with it and used it for other reasons,
you know.
>> Well, it could be the way that the
scientific community wanted it set up
too. You know how it is when you set up
>> Well, the thing I like about conscious
calibration is you can check out a
research design before you do the
experiment.
>> You don't have to run the experiment
through which may cost a million dollars
and take five years. M
>> you can say you know what is the what is
the level of this research design as
we've set it up if it's 190 you can save
yourself a couple million dollars in
several years and the brains of all the
scientists working on something that's
facious by design and designs the defect
in designs is usually quite subtle
>> so I'm going to put you on the spot
>> yes oh spot uh oh
boy
>> can can you tell me whether prayer does
help the ill.
>> I say prayer does help the ill. Yes.
Because first of all it sets up a
context. It sets up an energy field.
Uh
first I'll answer it and then we'll ask
the arm on it.
>> Okay.
>> Uh it increases the likelihood of uh of
healing,
>> right?
>> Because you're also dealing with that
person's karma. Well, yeah, but you're
also part of the collective, you know.
So, the you're also part of the
collective consciousness.
>> So, within the collective consciousness,
there's also that which is aligned with
goodwill
>> and that which is positive and healing.
So, when we pray for someone, uh, we
have permission to ask this. We have
permission to ask this. When we pray for
somebody, we increase the likelihood of
their healing. Resist. Yes, we increase
the likelihood of their healing.
The 12step groups do it all the time.
You know, in 12step groups, it's very
common to pray for the pray for the one
who's still suffering, the one who's
still trying to make it, the one who's
lost it and is in pain trying to regain
it. You know, play pray for the relief
of suffering and uh it creates an energy
field. So, people that are spiritually
oriented tend to get attracted to a
positive energy field.
>> Okay?
>> You know, like when we go over Mhm. Did
we mention the U bag pipers?
>> Mm-
>> Oh, well, the first
>> Oh, we forgot to mention that.
>> The first Sunday in December
in St. Andrews, the the bag pipers will
be there that Sunday morning. Forgot to
mention
>> Yeah, the first the first um Sunday in
December at St. Andrews um they will
10:00 a.m. they will have uh bag pipers
there. But we had the bag pipers here
and yes,
>> we brought them here and uh
>> so they will be there and we did forget
to mention that and I wanted to bring
that up.
>> Some people love them because to me the
sound of the bag pipe is the sound of
the heart of mankind.
The heart of mankind.
People break into tears at the sound of
them. And they say, "Why am I crying?"
Um
when you say live your life like a
player, a prayer and you say
um but you also say do it in um what?
Be contemplative.
>> In other words, it's very hard to do
everything you're supposed to do in a
day and still have this contemplation in
the back of your mind.
>> Well, that's a trick. Yes.
So tell us the trick.
>> All right.
>> To do this
>> by commitment and alignment.
The first thing in the morning and say,
"I pledge my life to thee, oh Lord, and
I and I pray for your knowledge of your
will for me and the power to carry it
out." Let's say all right. So you've set
up for yourself a context of all the
subsequent events. Contemplation
means becoming uh to me at least as
sensitive to the yin side of things. See
the yang side is very ego and very
linear.
>> You know, I'm going to feed the kitties
and then I'm going to take their kitty
can out and then I'm going to
>> you know so and so and I'm we're going
to you're going to clean the kitty box.
So that that's very linear. So in the
nonlinear the nonlinear is
simultaneously going on as the witness.
So there's the doingness and then
there's the witnessing of it. And the
witnessing of it is seeing,
you know, the caringness about life in
all these expressions.
>> Okay?
>> In other words, as you busy yourself
around in the morning,
>> I'm very aware of the caringness about
the quality of life around you. You're
always trying to improve the quality of
the kitty's life, the quality of the
kitty's dirty sandbox, the quality of
something you're going to make for
dinner. There's always that, you know,
you might say feminine, but that's not
really right. Feminine. It's more
appreciating the value of life and
trying to enhance it. You know, you're
always trying to enhance uh the
experience of life for others. You see,
and that's a certain dedication in
itself. prophecy dedication itself.
>> So that's why you what you mean when you
say uh contemplate
in the back of your mind as you're doing
your daily task to have this
contemplation.
>> Yeah. It is a witness
>> always as a witness in the back of your
mind in order to become more spiritual.
So as you're frying eggs, you're the the
witness of you is witnessing you frying
eggs which makes you aware of the
lovingness which is behind the service
which you provide to those that you you
love. See? Okay.
>> So there's the witnessing. So I would
say the the what you're asking has to do
with simultaneously witnessing
>> and yet still being able to function in
>> you do and you witness at the same time
that you do. like we're witnessing being
seated at a table
>> talking uh and then
vaguely aware in the background that
there is an audience listening you see
but there's really the awareness that
this is a unique experience for us which
I greatly appreciate and I really love
the fact that you you suggested it that
we you and I get a chance to share
togetherness and the witnessing of the
phenomena
>> and share it with the
That was a wonderful idea.
Is there um I'm trying to think if
there's I mean you answered basically uh
everything that I had to ask. I didn't
know if anyone else had a specific
question.
>> So
>> just
>> it's a way of being in the world.
>> So yeah,
>> so in other words, what our how we can
best serve
this information that you have given us
is to
go out into the world and be what you
have taught us to be. show that your
existence becomes a blessing to the
world instead of a curse.
Some people's existence is like a curse
to the world
>> and others people just their existence
is like a blessing
by consequence of that which they are.
>> Well, see we're we're dealing with so
many you know we we deal with a very
structured religious foundation. you
know, you go to church, you have a
minister, you pray at church, you do
this. We're dealing we're we're dealing
in a very formalized and
>> ours is more informal. So, you know,
it's kind of hard to take you from
something that's a formal
religion and then take you into
something that's informal
>> and yet still feel like you're doing
something.
>> Well, spiritual is informal, religion is
formal. So religion is the formalization
of the spiritual and we tend to value it
because of its historical tradition
>> and its wording. You know the 91st psalm
it has a very specific wording. You see
>> but then out of the wording you get
within here the essence of the
significance.
>> Okay. And if I can say it without
breaking up, I'll say it. Those who turn
to me are mine, said the Lord.
So said Krishna also.
Those who turn to me are mine.
So
by prayer
we become
those who belong to God.
Krishna says those who summon me are
mine.
91st Psalm says, "Those who turn to me
are mine,
which summons forth
from within
uh something that is beyond the form of
the verbalization."
And you and I both cry as we say it
because
we're fully cognizant
of what we're saying.
>> Yes.
So your life becomes a prayer by virtue
of the fact
that you've called upon God
to be and acknowledge him as the
supreme.
>> That already changes your life. The
minute you've done that, your life has
already changed and all your karmic
propensities have already changed.
Yeah. By changing the color of the
painting, everything in the landscape
gets tinted with that.
We start the meeting with glory and
excelsius dio which is already a
statement of our intention, our
alignment.
Yes. Yes.
>> And therefore a group like this becomes
endowed with uh a degree of spiritual
energy that many do not. You see?
>> Yes.
Because everyone is here due to the
freedom of their will, not by coercion
by society,
not by compulsive loyalty due to
upbringing etc.
>> But out of free choice. Huh.
So I think you know I like that's why I
like the 91st psalm and uh because you
acknowledge your devotion to God and
your alignment with divine order
and divine order is nothing but the
expression of the presence of God within
the linear domain.
>> Yes. And we say well if it wasn't the
divine order we wouldn't have gotten a
flat tire tire. with the flat tire is
the expression of divine order. Divine
order is if you get a tag in it, it goes
flat.
>> Yeah.
>> The laws of of existence
doesn't mean you can get a tag in the
tire and not get a flat tire, which is
what people think. Well, God was looking
after me. I wouldn't have gotten a flat
tire. They never think, well, I got a
flat tire because God is looking after
me. What does that mean? It means that
the linear domain is dependable.
If you could stick a nail in a tire and
not have it go flat, then you would not
be able to use the same laws of the
linear domain in your behalf like taking
a tumor out with a scalpel.
The tumor could refuse to respond to the
scalpel. So you see the laws of the
linear are operative in a beneficial way
too, you know.
>> Yes.
Do you think men and women approached
spirituality uh differently?
>> That's you think their style of approach
or application
is different?
>> Yes.
>> I have to say yes.
>> Yeah. Because you remark about it
periodically.
I do think um
I think uh women are more emotional when
it comes to spirituality and um men are
emotional but there it's just it's like
an undercurrent
of emotion.
>> But then logic comes on top
>> but then logic comes on top.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um I've noticed that uh at our
lectures we have which I like is that if
you've ever gone to other spiritual
teachers you'll notice that 90% of the
audience are women
>> and it's because those teachers are
usually talking on an emotional level.
So it attracts the women. Well, your
your uh talks are
um not really um they're flam.
They can they can be a little
flamboyant.
uh
in your expressions
of things
a little raw in the language department
sometimes
but we we have you reach both men and
women and I don't think God or Jesus
spoke to just women or just men. I
thought he spoke to both sectors.
>> He certainly did. Sermon on the mount
did have that was without any gender in
it. So, you know, I'm thinking that, you
know, uh we need to take a close look
at maybe some of the teachers that we
are seeing come to the forefront and and
take a good look at what is being taught
at this time.
I'll tell you, we we originally picked
>> I mean, I hate to say that as us being
teachers, you know, but yeah,
>> I see so many um imitations and
repackaging and that it's out there that
it's it's very it's in commercialization
that it's really very discouraging
>> to see that come about.
uh
not just in
non I mean it's also in structured
religions also it's not just in you know
>> well I uh
>> nonstructured
>> I was listening to a speaker well-known
spiritual teacher and it just didn't
ring true although although the words
were correct
>> right
>> did not ring true
>> and I said uh what the hell is wrong
here you know verbatim verbally It's
correct. And yet the And yet the person
and the energy.
>> Mhm.
>> And I got what it was. It's the
glamorization of spirituality. The
glamorization of enlightenment. Buddhist
uh literature. A lot of it popularized
gets foot of that.
>> It's the glamorization of enlightenment.
So they're not speaking from or about
enlightenment. They're speaking about
the glamorization of the oo of it. you
did
>> well-known speakers coming to Sedona you
know and uh so anyway the thing about it
that I got is that it's been glamorized
ah to be enlightened has become
glamorized
>> but it's so hard to
>> it's like a Cadillac
>> right but it but it's so hard to it's
you know you hear you hear these you
hear these teachers you you hear these
teachers and they say the right thing
>> they do
>> and they well Yeah, they say all the
correct things that you think are
>> they must know.
>> No, it's because it's become a program.
>> Okay.
>> It's become a program and and that's the
difficulty with reading and becoming
intellectually familiar with spiritual
realities long before you're really
ready for them
>> is that they then become a program. They
become a so it's an indoctrination of a
program.
Oh, I have to pursue my higher self.
>> What do you mean by your higher self?
You don't even know what you're talking
about your higher self.
>> Well, they throw these terms around like
that. What? And they throw the terms.
>> Yeah, they throw the terms around.
>> See, they throw these terms around and
you think, well, they must really know
what they're talking about. But then
when you really get into it, all of a
sudden they'll say, "That's $100."
Brother, you see a a very disciplined if
if we were going to establish a real
institution for spiritual learning, I
would not present any of the data
prematurely.
In other words, let the person come to
the awareness that is the next step to
them.
>> Help them remove the step because if you
read it in advance, it now becomes a
program.
>> I see. So they they become indoctrinated
and the paradox is what they're
indoctrinated with is the truth, but
they're holding it as a a belief system
rather than an experiential subjective
reality.
>> I got it. So they say the right things
and some are extremely glib and very
useful at it with the right accent and
all this and it sounds so persuasive and
yet you get how come and how come they
don't calibrate at that that level you
know they're still below 200
>> okay
>> because it's very easy to be sucked into
it.
>> Well also they become victims. You see
it isn't like it's a fault on their
part. It's like uh they have become
themselves unaware that they have become
programmed by spiritual belief systems
and because they correlate with reality
they jump that therefore that's not
reality there. That's my reality. It's
not their reality. It's their spiritual
belief system.
>> Okay. Here this draws me to this.
>> Yeah.
I get very discouraged with sometimes
the use of the map of consciousness
because people come to us and they say,
you know, I'm in the 500s. I'm in the
downside of it.
>> I'm in, you know, when in actuality,
if they were in that, they wouldn't be
telling anybody that they were in it.
Well,
this is a natural uh a natural downside
to it that people are are naturally out
of curiosity going to want to know what
do I calibrate at? So, that is only
normal. You might say like people want
to know when they grow up what is my IQ,
>> you know, how much do I weigh? Uh
>> right,
>> how many pounds can I lift? Uh these are
rated self-rating systems.
Um,
>> but the map of consciousness was not
designed for that. It was designed to
give you a basis as where you could be
or where you should be at certain times
in your life. It wasn't designed to say
I'm higher than you.
>> Well, I didn't design it for for people
to use about themsel.
>> It was about what goes on in the world.
>> Okay? So when I said you know uh certain
politician I'm holding in mind
calibrates over so and so I I was
thinking of finding you know the
difference between perception and
essence.
>> Okay.
>> So to me the the levels were how to
discern perception from essence.
>> Right?
>> Because unless the third eye of the
Buddha body opens up at a level 600 you
cannot see the difference between
perception and essence. Perception looks
to you like essence.
>> I see. You know, you can, you know, you
can look at a person and say, "Oh, he's
a sweet, wonderful person." And I know,
you know, he's killed six relatives and
tortured three women to death. You know,
but uh so I used it to discern truth
from falsehood out there in the world
and differentiate perception from
essence. And I never used it or thought
of it using it for yourself because it
didn't seem to me it would work. Why?
Because your intention was already out.
>> Right? You see you the intention of why
am I calibrating myself already negates
the answer it's out of egotism and so
your your intention is below 200
if you want to know what am I
calibrating at you know you're already
below 200 because you know you surrender
to God you don't well not always but but
very often very often the ego so you
could ask with the arm you say can I ask
is it permissible for me to ask about
what my calibration is because it also
could be very helpful You think that
you're very low and actually, you know,
>> you're quite high.
>> Yeah, sure. And I consider, you know,
anything over 200
>> perfectly fine
>> and the 300s are wonderful and the 400s
are very unusual to be spiritually
oriented in the high 400s, you know, is
extremely rare and this that's why this
group is very rare. Intelligent,
educated, aligned and you know.
>> All right. Next thing is the spiritual
ego. Now you've talked to us over and
over and over about the spiritual ego.
>> Yes.
>> At at times I myself feel like oh no I'm
not that way but I know that at
different times yes I am that way.
>> Right.
>> All right. So
would you say by
self evaluation
that you know your awareness comes up
that you know there is a certain amount
of payoff but you have to be a certain
level before you even recognize that
there's a payoff that you're getting
from even
>> yes
>> seeing that so that
>> so you know it's very difficult for
>> I gota
>> yeah Now the purpose of a spiritual
teacher is to make people aware of these
that the spiritual ego is always waiting
for you and uh you can see the gurus
that have fallen where the spiritual ego
uh you know was glamorized and began to
believe its own uh publicity and all
that. So
the spiritualist student that you know I
try to educate students to become aware
of the spiritual ego you know why all
these famous gurus have fallen I mean
just you know in the last 10 years you
know they're stacked up all over the
around the woodwork you know one fallen
guru after another so I feel it was the
fault of their teacher their teacher did
not teach them let's say about the
you know about the miraculous about the
cities. You know, I've spoken many times
and I try to put it in all the books
that at about level 570, the miraculous
is going to start to appear, in fact,
become the pattern of how things happen.
Everything begins to happen via the
miraculous.
Uh, and not to fall into the idea that
it there is a me that is bringing that
about because there is no person causing
the miraculous. But
>> as you get in the high 500s, the
miraculous begins to occur. Uh, in fact,
in 12 step groups, you see the
miraculous every day. I think, well, so
what's that? You know, just another guy
got silver. Statistically, medically,
mathematically, and from logic, and
reason, his chances are less than zero.
And yet, here's this guy walking around
and feeling fine. So, the miraculous is
every day. So, the spiritual teacher
should make people be aware of the
spiritual ego. uh not claim the
miraculous when they begin to have the
cities says they begin to happen are
quite impressive. It's very very
impressive. I mean it can be very
impressive but a well educated person
doesn't claim them as my no person
create performs miracles. Let's just
reaffirm that that is a fact resist. No
person performs miracles.
So if you're gonna see Master Boua, the
miracle worker down in whatchamacalla
country,
uh there ain't no such item.
>> However, you're saying because of the
>> we just we just wait a second. We just
watched that one thing, you know, not
too long ago about someone that
>> that was supposedly a healer. And um
don't you feel though that when someone
goes to a healer that it's actually
their own faith that heals them that it
has nothing to do with the healer that
it is just their own faith and their own
belief system that heals them?
>> I think so.
>> Okay.
>> Also they've earned it karmically
>> and they've earned it karmically. So the
energy of certain entities, people,
healers
>> or teachers
>> tends to facilitate
the likelihood of the miraculous. But it
was because of the karmic intention in
seeking seeking it in the first place
that the person experiences the healing
like Lord's like the miracles at Lords.
Mhm.
>> Miracles at Lords, you know, don't come
about because of the water or the
scenery,
but the power of the faith to begin with
and then the collective energy of all
those who have gone through there,
>> right?
>> So, we didn't do the miracles at Lords.
>> We have permission to do that. The
reported miracles of Lords are primarily
true. Is it just that you like to know
that?
They're not figures. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I was
>> the power of belief and faith and uh
>> uh karmic destiny, you know.
>> When you go to Lords, what what is
there? There's just you and God. Period.
That's it.
>> No doctors, no.
>> It's the last call. The last call.
And by resignation you could say if it
is thy will for me oh lord then I ask
for such and such
>> okay
>> to remove even your will
you know
you can't strongarm god into performing
a miracle just to make you happy you
know
>> right well that yeah
>> yeah the intention of your will
I don't know all in the end I
surrender will in entire matter and then
picture the desired what seems like a
desirable outcome.
Relie all intention
and picture
that puppy happy and healed.
>> See where he's been chained and the skin
is all torn off his neck and he's in
agony. a picture
and blessed and happy and loved by by by
divinity.
So then the outcome of that is up to
divinity. So I've already envisioned
happy healthy dog was found a home to
lose and his neck is all healed up and
he said you know bouncing around with
his tail wagon.
>> So by
>> I should have been a veterinarian. So,
so by visualizing by visual there is a
certain amount to visualize
>> things but it only goes so far and then
it's up to karma and divine will and
other things that are involved. So in
other words, all these things about the
secret and all these different um what
was it you said that power of well the
power of intention that's a little bit
different though law of attraction.
>> Well they they tend to become magical
manipulations
to to willfully make a thing happen.
>> Right?
>> So
>> but if we're not able to perform
miracles then we can't willfully make it
happen. Right?
>> So there there's a paradox in it.
>> Okay?
>> And that it's it's so that what you hold
in mind tends to manifest depending on
karmic conditions etc. But it is not
causality. It's because of what you have
become. So if you if you witness the
beauty and the fulfillment of the
potential of all things, this includes
the likelihood of there manifesting
that. But not not within the realm of
causality.
>> Okay.
>> So what you're holding as mind is not
causing what's happening out there.
>> It's the context in which the likelihood
of that is greater.
>> I see.
>> In a loving household, a puppy's more
likely to heal than in a household that
gives the same medicine but not as
loving.
>> Just the sheer lovingness, the power of
love tends to manifest.
Yeah.
Well, I noticed that when I ran a big
clinic, you know, I had a huge clinic
and I noticed that certain uh therapists
and c certain psychiatrists and social
workers had very high recovery rates and
others didn't. I noticed that some
people just everybody seemed to get
better whoever saw them and even if they
weren't better, they felt better. You
know what I mean?
And then I discovered that it was the
the consciousness of the therapist, the
lovingness of the consciousness of the
therapist had a healing power. So some
therapists are healers and others are
not. Some doctors are healers
and of course I hired many over the
years and I watched and some doctors had
very high recovery rates and others had
very low recovery rates. What was the
difference? Well, it was the caringness.
It's the caringness.
You're cautioned against having a
positive counter transference.
>> But if you don't care about the patient
enough to worry about him a little bit
now and then if you don't care enough
about the patient, then the likelihood
of their getting well is less than a
mechanical doctor who says, "Well, we're
taking the tumor out and you know, we've
done what we have to do."
uh so caringness and lovingness made a
difference in the recovery rates of the
patients. Yeah.
>> And so when I had to assign patients I
was aware who had what high recovery
rates of what kind of patient what kind
of patient.
>> So if you combine prayer
>> and a healing say physician and say all
these things and the likelihood
of
that
>> yes
>> would be more
in other area. Okay.
>> So, it's not causality, but it certainly
is likelihood,
>> right?
>> You know,
>> you presented it with all the conditions
so that this could take place.
>> You
>> just like in your spiritual evolvement,
you you presented it with all these
different
things, you know, followed these
different paths.
>> Yeah.
>> To produce this likely outcome. It it
you it's not that you do it to produce
it, but but it's, you know, I I I gave
up.
>> Well, it's like you set the stage for it
happening.
>> You got it. You got it. You got it.
You're right.
>> In other words, you you go ahead and you
follow these teachers and you're on this
path and you do these different things,
but you're you're setting the stage, I
guess you'd say, for the likelihood for
this to occur.
>> There you go. And then if it does or it
doesn't
>> is
>> whether karma is involved or other
things. Yeah.
>> But when I tapered off my practice,
there wasn't any psychiatrist around. So
I went back into practice and I had
quite a sizable practice for somebody
who's retired from practice. But anyway,
uh then I finally had some I had
part-time private patients too that and
I wanted to quit, you know, but I had a
couple of patients who I knew the
positive transference of what was
keeping them alive.
>> Yes.
>> And I couldn't, you know, so people say,
"When are you going to quit?" I said,
"What? They're pretty old ducks." I
said, "When they when they go, then I'll
quit."
>> So they finally
>> quit.
>> Teetered over.
>> And so I quit.
it it's almost time to I'm sorry I took
up
>> but that's the fact you know I said he's
almost 90 he's going to go to go pretty
soon
>> and uh then he show up week after week
>> I don't know if there's anything else
you wanted to say but those were some of
the questions I wanted to
>> No I really thank you for uh for this
opportunity it's a unique opportunity
we've never done it before
>> no
>> and u and you you brought up really
wonderful things to look at you know
what you really do is bring up things to
look at rather than a yes or no kind
just verbal response. You're asking
for us to look at a thing and discuss it
and hold it up for view for everyone to
look at it.
>> Right.
>> And I thank you very much.
>> Thank you.
Is that what I want? I don't know.
>> Hello.
>> That was good. I like that. Very
awesome.
>> Uh, I'd like your understanding on a
quote from N Argarata.
He said uh
prior to conception
whatever state that is that state always
prevails
>> the potentiality
>> become all
>> so he's he's describing the unmanifest.
Is that what he's getting at?
>> Yes. The unmanifest. Mhm.
The self with a capital S expressing
itself as the self with a small S.
>> So
>> the infinite potentiality comes the
expression of the particularity. Yeah.
>> I remember saying uh if you ponder on
that you will get instant solution was
what he was saying. It was just I don't
know it kind of hit me funny.
>> If you ponder on that you will what?
>> Get instant solution he was saying. So
that really hit me when he described it
that way and I wanted your clarification
on that.
>> He's using time in a different way
because all time is now. If you hold it
in mind it'll
become a realization. Uhhuh.
Don't forget he didn't speak for you
know he's speaking at 700.
>> Yeah.
So
>> So prior to consciousness
what am I?
There is no such thing as prior to
consciousness.
>> Sir, can you
>> besides you don't have to worry about it
>> is there any can you expand on that any
whatsoever or is it possible to expand
on that any
>> No,
>> it doesn't make any sense.
Yes.
>> As expressed, it doesn't make sense to
me. What are you prior to consciousness?
>> So, like I've kind of I think I've heard
>> I mean it's not it's a hypothetical. I
think on a lecture once I remember I
could be wrong but um you stating that
uh that which I am is before
consciousness like consciousness is like
late in the game and that which you are
is the ultimate
>> oh I see what you're talking to a
different level all right see the
godhead uh uh is prior to God as
radiation or will or any other
expression of divinity
>> the godhead is the source out of which
godness arises
Yeah.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Makes sense.
>> Thank you, D.
That's what it says in Genesis.
out of the godhead
radiated the light of divinity out of
which arose all of life and existence.
>> Hi Susan. Hi Doc.
>> Yes. Um Susan got most of the 15
questions I had running around in my
mind. Um
but something you said um just created a
little interest in me. Um it's almost
like a dichotomy. um that men
um approach spirituality differently
because of the logic. And I know that
logic can really get in the way. And
it's kind of interesting that men have
the wiring for
>> both
they have the wiring for both, but also
the but they have the high wiring for
the higher energies. And yet there is
that. So is it a dichotomy? Is the is
the logic a dichotomy or does it fit in
with enlightenment
or is it just something to be
transcended? It's just another piece to
be transcended.
>> I don't get the question.
>> Well, you were talking
>> Let him Let me
All right. Go ahead. Explain what he's
saying.
>> She's got it.
>> What he was saying was he was saying
that men basically
logic women is what he's saying which
isn't so they approach it from two
different angles. Women approach
approach spirituality from an emotional
angle
>> first. First, yeah,
>> men approach it from the logic,
>> right? You're right.
>> But they both have both characteristics.
>> Oh, yes.
>> The yin and the yang is both.
>> I was
>> It's just that women approach it from
the emotional angle first and then
logical and men approach it from logical
and then emotional.
>> Okay.
>> All right.
>> Great. Thank you.
He leads with his dukes and she leads
with her powder puff.
>> And may I have your blessing?
>> Thank you.
>> The yin and the yang of it. Yes. Well, I
>> I didn't use that terminology this
morning, but I should have talked about
it.
>> I have a question on neither attractions
nor aversions.
And whether this includes everything
like uh love, witnessing or the states
they call illumination
>> that includes what
>> called illumination
>> or love.
>> That that's a that's a point of uh
confusion. Love is as an attachment. A
love of this for that is an attachment.
Love in all capital lover letter letter
letters is an aspect of divinity
without subject or object.
Love as a god a you and a me becomes an
attachment.
Love with a capital L as a way of being.
Lovingness is an aspect of divinity.
So there's an error. There's an error.
In fact, it was commonly taught around
this town that love is an attachment.
Let go of all attachments and therefore
negate the spiritual validity of love.
That's an error. That'll take you right
to the void of nothingness.
You get stuck in nothingness.
>> Um,
>> love is one of the characteristics of
divinity.
Love as an emotional attachment
is a tither that needs to be
relinquished.
>> And um what's let's say about the states
that are called illumination is is there
just an attraction and aversion to them
like it's just an experience that passes
by like any other experience or is it
what one eventually becomes?
>> I don't understand the question.
>> The state of illumination. Yes.
>> Is that what one
>> eventually becomes? Yes.
>> That state.
>> Yes.
>> Or is it just another phenomena that
>> No, it's not just another phenomena.
>> Okay. So eventually that's where you
stay forever like is that what you are?
>> Yes,
>> I believe so.
>> Yes. The radi the radiance is who is
within at all times. It's the so-called
perushia of the teacher
self with the capital S got imminent.
And um could one stay in this state also
within uh somebody's in in the body or
>> what?
>> Um
>> uh in this state what
>> um can somebody be in this state while
be at the same time in the body?
>> Yes. Because you're not really in the
body. That's on your mind.
>> So one would be in this state where the
body would go about it business.
>> Yes. The body goes about its business.
I've got nothing to do with it.
>> Okay?
>> You see, the body h handles itself. It
doesn't need me at all. I don't pay
attention to it. It just does what it's
supposed to be doing.
Like a trained dog, you know, it just
does what it's supposed to do.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you very much for everything.
>> Yeah.
Um I've been um doing uh practicing
onepointedness.
>> You've been practicing onepointedness of
mind? Oh yes.
>> And um I just want to know which which
um like I've been doing staying with the
sense of I
>> Yes.
>> Uhhuh. And then and then so um I'll say
okay but maybe I am is a little easier
or and then I'll switch it to something
else. Um but like that drive to stick
with something is getting greater. I
want to know what you would recommend
for me to stick with.
>> Um you stick I would stick with the yin
positionality
of thusness.
>> Mhm.
>> You don't have to verbalize it.
>> Okay.
>> Don't give it a name. I don't believe I
mean uh Ramano Maharshi I respect a
great deal but I would not ask who am I?
that instantly throws you into the mind.
Conjecture,
languaging.
Besides, there isn't a who there anyway.
>> Mhm.
>> There's only a what.
So, I I say that better than who am I
is to try to intuit it what am I
otherwise you end up with another
identity and then you got to release
that identity.
My question
>> there isn't any who that there isn't any
who.
>> So what do I hold it just
>> like what is what does it feel like or
>> the the whatness? The whatness?
>> Uhhuh.
>> I would look in your case for the
witness of witness. Witnessing. What is
it that's witnessing
>> so that you begin to identify and see
that you are not different than that
which is consciousness. And then that
takes you to the source of consciousness
itself, which is divinity. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. No, you're in a good track.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Send me a postcard when you get there.
>> Yes.
>> I wanted to give you this as a sign of
my gratitude.
Oh, thank you, love.
>> I just wanted to say thank you for being
such a great teacher and I feel very
honored.
>> Thank you.
>> Volume
the volume on uh who's mic on that mic.
>> Dr. Hawkins, you have written that they
are actually split seconds in which the
options present themselves.
>> Written that what?
>> There's split seconds in which the
options present.
>> Yes. Mhm. It's constant.
>> Could Could you explain that?
Whether you like it or not,
choice and decision
is continue a continuous process.
Every instant you're presented with
options. What to think, what to do, what
to say, how to feel, where to move.
So choosing is a constant.
One is always constantly choosing.
And therefore the mind is constantly
presented with a question mark which way
to choose what to choose. And that's how
the karmic track get sets itself up by
what you
what you choose.
What you choose also tends to increase
the likelihood of choosing that which is
similar.
That's you might call it the law of
intention.
If you con constantly choose that which
is
forgiving a benign,
loving, nurturing, the likelihood is
statistically
due to the quantum mechanics etc
involved that you will make the same
choice the next time. So the oftener you
choose to be loving, the greater the
likelihood is that your next choice will
also be loving.
There's a cascades of uh of dominance
neur neurologically. It's been studied
by John Madina Ma. And don't ask me
where his stuff is because I won't tell
you.
It's hard hard to find on the internet.
He writes articles in the psychiatric
times in which he tracks the neurologic
basis of what I just said.
The often you choose forgiveness, the
greater the likelihood is that you will
choose it next time.
Your writing uh goes on to say that the
miracle happens in that gap.
>> That what
>> a miracle could happen in that gap
>> and the the Holy Spirit is present and
available then.
>> Yes.
>> The miracle is that you're choosing
forgiveness all the time. The likelihood
of that happening in the general
population is less than 50%.
50% of the population is before below
200.
The likelihood of their choosing
forgiveness is very slim.
The more you're evolved you become, the
greater the likelihood and dominance of
that choice.
>> Yes, sir.
>> There's also mathematical reasons have
to do with quantum mechanics.
Uh I think uh Snap's new book does
probably
uh address that the
Zeno effect.
>> It I think I interpreted the statement
to have something to do with
enlightenment. The options for
enlightenment were presenting
themselves.
>> No.
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know either, Susan. Yeah.
See, enlightenment is just a condition
that replaces the prior condition,
>> right?
>> And so as you let the old condition go,
uh, new replaces it.
And in the new, certain options no
longer are even there much. They're not
only unappealing, they're not even there
anymore,
>> right?
It wouldn't even come to your mind, you
know, to run over the dog. It wouldn't
even enter your mind. Should I run over
that little lost dog or not? Wouldn't
even enter your mind. There's plenty of
people, I've watched them right in front
of me, swerve out of their way to hit an
animal. Swerved out of their way up on
two wheels in order to kill a dog or a
cat or a squirrel.
up on two wheels at high speed in order
to kill that animal. See,
>> so for you that would not be an option.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Yeah, I couldn't believe my eyes went up
on two wheels in order to kill this
forget it was the squirrel or some
little animal.
Hi.
>> Yes.
>> Hi Susan. In moving from formalized
religion to informal spirituality,
does it serve the highest good to have a
permanent structure?
>> Permanent what?
>> Structure or based on the 12step model?
>> Well, the 12 steps is not a structure.
>> I know.
Let me get the question again.
>> What is the question?
>> In moving from formalized religion,
>> yes.
>> To informal spirituality,
>> Does it serve the highest good to have
like a permanent building structure
for people of like mind to meet? You're
talking about like a with a meditation
center, ashram, something like that. I
think it serves a certain practical
function. Yes. I mean, it's certainly
traditional.
People have done so for many centuries
and I think they re tend to reinforce
each other's intentions
and uh fulfillment.
I I think it serves a certain practical
function
but spiritual groups have done so you
know over the over the centuries you
know
>> yes
>> retreat centers and ashrams and
meditation centers
>> George I'm sorry I have to ask the
question
>> in attraction versus promotion
>> right
>> does it serve the highest good for um
one to attract promotion if that serves
the highest good.
>> That's a tough one.
>> Yes.
>> Dave draws a fine line when it comes to
promoting the work.
>> Yes.
>> All right.
Um,
usually he wants it to go by word of
mouth, but to to actually take out an ad
or put it in a paper. You probably won't
see us do that.
>> No,
>> I'm talking about specifically for the
building structure,
not the teachings, the building
structure.
>> It's up to the group, whatever they want
to be.
>> See, we have we just have a fine line
there.
Whether we feel that we need to
>> obligation is to make it available
>> and speak it.
>> That's it. Period.
>> Thank you, Dr.
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> So, the the place would belong to the
community that lives there,
>> right? You know, they would it'd be
their their corral,
>> which sounds wonderful.
>> Thank you. you there Carell.
Hallelujah.