At this time, I want to introduce Dr.
At this time, I want to introduce Dr. Hawkins.
Gloria in excelsius deal.
Gloria in excelsius deal. We're here today to fulfill our
We're here today to fulfill our
We're here today to fulfill our potential to God ourself and our fellow
potential to God ourself and our fellow
potential to God ourself and our fellow human beings.
human beings.
human beings. And after you do that, you can leave the
And after you do that, you can leave the
And after you do that, you can leave the planet.
H so it's uh wonderful to have you all
H so it's uh wonderful to have you all here and I bless you all and give great
here and I bless you all and give great
here and I bless you all and give great thanks for your love. Yeah,
thanks for your love. Yeah,
thanks for your love. Yeah, today's lecture and uh is going to go on
today's lecture and uh is going to go on
today's lecture and uh is going to go on over till next uh it's going to be a
over till next uh it's going to be a
over till next uh it's going to be a two-month lecture.
We're gonna cover the entire panorama of
We're gonna cover the entire panorama of the human experience.
We're going to wander through the house
We're going to wander through the house of mirrors,
of mirrors,
of mirrors, a human dilemma. So today's lecture is
a human dilemma. So today's lecture is
a human dilemma. So today's lecture is called the human dilemma
called the human dilemma
called the human dilemma and uh
and uh
and uh it will cover quite a few
it will cover quite a few
it will cover quite a few uh subjects because uh humanity right
uh subjects because uh humanity right
uh subjects because uh humanity right now seems to me uh to be lost in a house
now seems to me uh to be lost in a house
now seems to me uh to be lost in a house of mirrors.
of mirrors.
of mirrors. can't tell the reflection from the
can't tell the reflection from the
can't tell the reflection from the reality and different lights are shown
reality and different lights are shown
reality and different lights are shown on different mirrors and people think
on different mirrors and people think
on different mirrors and people think that what it is is the light instead of
that what it is is the light instead of
that what it is is the light instead of the image in the mirror. So we can all
the image in the mirror. So we can all
the image in the mirror. So we can all sit down and uh relax.
sit down and uh relax.
sit down and uh relax. You don't have to listen uh
You don't have to listen uh
You don't have to listen uh not necessary to strain to understand
not necessary to strain to understand
not necessary to strain to understand anything.
anything.
anything. So we'll start with the number one
So we'll start with the number one
So we'll start with the number one slide. Oh, how many people here are new?
slide. Oh, how many people here are new?
slide. Oh, how many people here are new? Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. Oh, some new newsies. New. Okay. All
Oh, some new newsies. New. Okay. All
Oh, some new newsies. New. Okay. All right. Then we'll do a quick review of
right. Then we'll do a quick review of
right. Then we'll do a quick review of the basics.
the basics.
the basics. Uh and if you pay attention, you see
Uh and if you pay attention, you see
Uh and if you pay attention, you see it's simple.
As soon as you get it, you got it. I
As soon as you get it, you got it. I mean, you more could you want? Uh we
mean, you more could you want? Uh we
mean, you more could you want? Uh we start out with the for orientation the
start out with the for orientation the
start out with the for orientation the map of consciousness as you're aware we
map of consciousness as you're aware we
map of consciousness as you're aware we we calibrated the the possible levels of
we calibrated the the possible levels of
we calibrated the the possible levels of consciousness on an arbitrary
consciousness on an arbitrary
consciousness on an arbitrary logarithmic uh map of one to a thousand
logarithmic uh map of one to a thousand
logarithmic uh map of one to a thousand and then we asked so after a
and then we asked so after a
and then we asked so after a considerable research uh we emerged with
considerable research uh we emerged with
considerable research uh we emerged with a map of levels of consciousness which
a map of levels of consciousness which
a map of levels of consciousness which is concordant with psychoanalytic theory
is concordant with psychoanalytic theory
is concordant with psychoanalytic theory psychiatric practice uh human experience
psychiatric practice uh human experience
psychiatric practice uh human experience and uh the classic uh the classic chain
and uh the classic uh the classic chain
and uh the classic uh the classic chain of being. So if you research for
of being. So if you research for
of being. So if you research for yourself the levels of consciousness,
yourself the levels of consciousness,
yourself the levels of consciousness, you'll recapitulate the classic chain of
you'll recapitulate the classic chain of
you'll recapitulate the classic chain of being. So on the left hand side is the
being. So on the left hand side is the
being. So on the left hand side is the way we view God from these various
way we view God from these various
way we view God from these various levels, the way we view our self.
levels, the way we view our self.
levels, the way we view our self. Uh and then it has a logarithmic number
Uh and then it has a logarithmic number
Uh and then it has a logarithmic number and then the emotion that goes with
and then the emotion that goes with
and then the emotion that goes with that. And then over on the right we have
that. And then over on the right we have
that. And then over on the right we have what is the process going on in
what is the process going on in
what is the process going on in consciousness
consciousness
consciousness uh at that level.
uh at that level.
uh at that level. Uh this is an extremely simple
Uh this is an extremely simple
Uh this is an extremely simple uh linear
uh linear
uh linear I mean one to a thousand we it's just
I mean one to a thousand we it's just
I mean one to a thousand we it's just like uh taking people's temperature
like uh taking people's temperature
like uh taking people's temperature taking the temperature of anything. So
taking the temperature of anything. So
taking the temperature of anything. So you look at these flowers and you say,
you look at these flowers and you say,
you look at these flowers and you say, "What is it? What are their what are the
"What is it? What are their what are the
"What is it? What are their what are the temperature? What's the temperature of
temperature? What's the temperature of
temperature? What's the temperature of those flowers?"
those flowers?"
those flowers?" As you can see, they look to me like
As you can see, they look to me like
As you can see, they look to me like stunning beauty. Yes.
stunning beauty. Yes.
stunning beauty. Yes. If you have fa hay fever, you might say,
If you have fa hay fever, you might say,
If you have fa hay fever, you might say, "Man, those are ugly. I got to get out
"Man, those are ugly. I got to get out
"Man, those are ugly. I got to get out of here."
of here."
of here." So there's the subjective warp.
So there's the subjective warp.
So there's the subjective warp. Subjective warp.
Subjective warp.
Subjective warp. about 55%
about 55%
about 55% of people in the United States calibrate
of people in the United States calibrate
of people in the United States calibrate below level 200. So level 200 is you
below level 200. So level 200 is you
below level 200. So level 200 is you might call an alternate reality
might call an alternate reality
might call an alternate reality uh
uh
uh evolutionary uh we start at the bottom
evolutionary uh we start at the bottom
evolutionary uh we start at the bottom and we move up. So it's where mankind
and we move up. So it's where mankind
and we move up. So it's where mankind has evolved up to this particular point.
has evolved up to this particular point.
has evolved up to this particular point. about half the people in the in the US
about half the people in the in the US
about half the people in the in the US cross the line at 200. 200 and up is
cross the line at 200. 200 and up is
cross the line at 200. 200 and up is truth and various levels of integrity
truth and various levels of integrity
truth and various levels of integrity uh below 200
uh below 200
uh below 200 uh
uh
uh falsehood. Now
falsehood. Now
falsehood. Now below 200 the way to stay above 200 is
below 200 the way to stay above 200 is
below 200 the way to stay above 200 is you follow the ten commandments
you follow the ten commandments
you follow the ten commandments and you avoid the seven deadly sins.
and you avoid the seven deadly sins.
and you avoid the seven deadly sins. That's pretty simple. Nobody worries
That's pretty simple. Nobody worries
That's pretty simple. Nobody worries about salvation. That's all you got to
about salvation. That's all you got to
about salvation. That's all you got to do. Follow the ten commandments and
do. Follow the ten commandments and
do. Follow the ten commandments and avoid the seven deadly sins.
avoid the seven deadly sins.
avoid the seven deadly sins. Put you right up near the top. People
Put you right up near the top. People
Put you right up near the top. People say, "How can I get up to the top?"
say, "How can I get up to the top?"
say, "How can I get up to the top?" Well, it was spelled out thousands of
Well, it was spelled out thousands of
Well, it was spelled out thousands of years ago
years ago
years ago thousands of years ago.
thousands of years ago.
thousands of years ago. You avoid cravingness and wantingness,
You avoid cravingness and wantingness,
You avoid cravingness and wantingness, desiringness,
desiringness,
desiringness, demandingness, etc. You give up pride in
demandingness, etc. You give up pride in
demandingness, etc. You give up pride in the narcissism. the narcissism that it's
the narcissism. the narcissism that it's
the narcissism. the narcissism that it's based on. You give up resentments and
based on. You give up resentments and
based on. You give up resentments and angers and you stop craving everything.
angers and you stop craving everything.
angers and you stop craving everything. You give up being fearful. You say,
You give up being fearful. You say,
You give up being fearful. You say, "Well, if you drop dead right now,
"Well, if you drop dead right now,
"Well, if you drop dead right now, goodbye." So, what's the problem?
You know, I told you I traded that right
You know, I told you I traded that right in the middle of uh the South Pacific.
in the middle of uh the South Pacific.
in the middle of uh the South Pacific. There we were about ready to blow up.
There we were about ready to blow up.
There we were about ready to blow up. And he says, "You know, we we might get
And he says, "You know, we we might get
And he says, "You know, we we might get killed." And I said, "Well, so then we
killed." And I said, "Well, so then we
killed." And I said, "Well, so then we die." And he looked at me, he said,
die." And he looked at me, he said,
die." And he looked at me, he said, "You're right. Took care of it.
"You're right. Took care of it.
"You're right. Took care of it. Acceptance." So that's called
Acceptance." So that's called
Acceptance." So that's called acceptance.
acceptance.
acceptance. Once we accept that our life is
Once we accept that our life is
Once we accept that our life is temporal, then we can give up, you know,
temporal, then we can give up, you know,
temporal, then we can give up, you know, the fear, fear of leaving this world.
the fear, fear of leaving this world.
the fear, fear of leaving this world. All right? So then you can go all the
All right? So then you can go all the
All right? So then you can go all the way down to fear and things that are
way down to fear and things that are
way down to fear and things that are grief, hopeless, apathy,
grief, hopeless, apathy,
grief, hopeless, apathy, uh that which is dedicated to evil, and
uh that which is dedicated to evil, and
uh that which is dedicated to evil, and that which is hateful. Hateful. Hateful.
that which is hateful. Hateful. Hateful.
that which is hateful. Hateful. Hateful. What does hateful look like?
What does hateful look like?
What does hateful look like? What was it? The Virginia something or
What was it? The Virginia something or
What was it? The Virginia something or other massacre. It was done by a fellow
other massacre. It was done by a fellow
other massacre. It was done by a fellow named Cho or something. And he had a
named Cho or something. And he had a
named Cho or something. And he had a long videotape that he made of himself.
long videotape that he made of himself.
long videotape that he made of himself. He calibrated five.
He calibrated five.
He calibrated five. Lowest one I've gotten so far. Worse
Lowest one I've gotten so far. Worse
Lowest one I've gotten so far. Worse than the Green River Killer.
than the Green River Killer.
than the Green River Killer. Green River Killer had it for quite for
Green River Killer had it for quite for
Green River Killer had it for quite for quite a while, but show beat him out.
quite a while, but show beat him out.
quite a while, but show beat him out. All right. So
All right. So
All right. So when you discover you've made a bad
when you discover you've made a bad
when you discover you've made a bad mistake, you got to come around and uh
mistake, you got to come around and uh
mistake, you got to come around and uh try it all over again. All right. So
try it all over again. All right. So
try it all over again. All right. So that that's the basic orientation.
that that's the basic orientation.
that that's the basic orientation. Everything and anything can be
Everything and anything can be
Everything and anything can be calibrated on a level of 1 to a,000. Now
calibrated on a level of 1 to a,000. Now
calibrated on a level of 1 to a,000. Now when we're calibrating something, what
when we're calibrating something, what
when we're calibrating something, what we are doing is getting its essence, not
we are doing is getting its essence, not
we are doing is getting its essence, not its appearance.
its appearance.
its appearance. Some people still don't get that. That
Some people still don't get that. That
Some people still don't get that. That what a thing looks like is not what it
what a thing looks like is not what it
what a thing looks like is not what it is. The book is not the cover. The map
is. The book is not the cover. The map
is. The book is not the cover. The map is not the territory.
is not the territory.
is not the territory. So how can we get to the essence of a
So how can we get to the essence of a
So how can we get to the essence of a thing? So when we do the muscle test,
thing? So when we do the muscle test,
thing? So when we do the muscle test, what we're asking for is the level of
what we're asking for is the level of
what we're asking for is the level of the essence. We already know what the
the essence. We already know what the
the essence. We already know what the appearance is. Uh but what is the
appearance is. Uh but what is the
appearance is. Uh but what is the essence? And um
essence? And um
essence? And um the muscle response that we get is ultra
the muscle response that we get is ultra
the muscle response that we get is ultra simple. There's no point in trying to
simple. There's no point in trying to
simple. There's no point in trying to complicate it. All you have to if you
complicate it. All you have to if you
complicate it. All you have to if you really want to understand it, all you
really want to understand it, all you
really want to understand it, all you have to understand is quantum physics,
have to understand is quantum physics,
have to understand is quantum physics, quantum mechanics.
quantum mechanics.
quantum mechanics. And uh
And uh
And uh which I'll explain to you in a couple
which I'll explain to you in a couple
which I'll explain to you in a couple sentences.
sentences.
sentences. Uh in the infinite field of
Uh in the infinite field of
Uh in the infinite field of consciousness, which was the light of
consciousness, which was the light of
consciousness, which was the light of God, the light of God shown forth, isn't
God, the light of God shown forth, isn't
God, the light of God shown forth, isn't it? It's infinitely powerful. One cubic
it? It's infinitely powerful. One cubic
it? It's infinitely powerful. One cubic inch of infinite space
inch of infinite space
inch of infinite space is equal is greater than the total mass
is equal is greater than the total mass
is equal is greater than the total mass of the entire universe.
greater than the total mass of the
greater than the total mass of the entire universe. That's power. So
entire universe. That's power. So
entire universe. That's power. So in an infinite timeless space there is
in an infinite timeless space there is
in an infinite timeless space there is no beginning there is no end. There is
no beginning there is no end. There is
no beginning there is no end. There is no here there is no there. There's no
no here there is no there. There's no
no here there is no there. There's no now or then.
now or then.
now or then. Consequently
Consequently
Consequently the field of consciousness is omnisient
by virtue of being all that has ever
by virtue of being all that has ever been or can can be. So when we do
been or can can be. So when we do
been or can can be. So when we do essence
essence
essence what happens is we collapse the wave
what happens is we collapse the wave
what happens is we collapse the wave function. See in quantum mechanics you
function. See in quantum mechanics you
function. See in quantum mechanics you have the Heisenberg principle. You go
have the Heisenberg principle. You go
have the Heisenberg principle. You go from the
from the
from the uh trading equations of the hypo the
uh trading equations of the hypo the
uh trading equations of the hypo the possible uh time dependent or time
possible uh time dependent or time
possible uh time dependent or time independent
independent
independent and then the wave function which is
and then the wave function which is
and then the wave function which is really a mathematical formula uh
really a mathematical formula uh
really a mathematical formula uh potentiates and you can collapse the
potentiates and you can collapse the
potentiates and you can collapse the wave function meaning you go from energy
wave function meaning you go from energy
wave function meaning you go from energy to particle. It was discovered of course
to particle. It was discovered of course
to particle. It was discovered of course uh in trying to research the basic uh
uh in trying to research the basic uh
uh in trying to research the basic uh nature of light itself.
nature of light itself.
nature of light itself. It occurs in waves, particles. So the
It occurs in waves, particles. So the
It occurs in waves, particles. So the potential becomes an actual
potential becomes an actual
potential becomes an actual only if there is a reality.
only if there is a reality.
only if there is a reality. Only if there's a reality. So if I make
Only if there's a reality. So if I make
Only if there's a reality. So if I make a statement that has a reality to it,
a statement that has a reality to it,
a statement that has a reality to it, this affects the quantum potential and
this affects the quantum potential and
this affects the quantum potential and collapses the wave function and the
collapses the wave function and the
collapses the wave function and the person goes strong.
person goes strong.
person goes strong. If I pose a question that is false, it
If I pose a question that is false, it
If I pose a question that is false, it has no correlary in reality. Therefore,
has no correlary in reality. Therefore,
has no correlary in reality. Therefore, it has no power and it does not collapse
it has no power and it does not collapse
it has no power and it does not collapse the wave function and arm goes weak. So
the wave function and arm goes weak. So
the wave function and arm goes weak. So truth makes the body go strong for
truth makes the body go strong for
truth makes the body go strong for reasons we've mentioned in previous
reasons we've mentioned in previous
reasons we've mentioned in previous lectures. And falsehood does not make
lectures. And falsehood does not make
lectures. And falsehood does not make make the body go weak. It just does not
make the body go weak. It just does not
make the body go weak. It just does not make it go strong. So the answer is not
make it go strong. So the answer is not
make it go strong. So the answer is not yes or no. The answer is always yes or
yes or no. The answer is always yes or
yes or no. The answer is always yes or not yes.
not yes.
not yes. The quantum potential is a yes.
The quantum potential is a yes.
The quantum potential is a yes. Collapses the wave function. Your arm
Collapses the wave function. Your arm
Collapses the wave function. Your arm goes strong.
goes strong.
goes strong. So the what we're asking is yes or not
So the what we're asking is yes or not
So the what we're asking is yes or not yes. Yes or not yes. Yes or not yes.
To make it even better, you ask
To make it even better, you ask permission before you ask the question.
permission before you ask the question.
permission before you ask the question. We have permission to ask.
We have permission to ask.
We have permission to ask. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. Oh, no. I'm not gonna ask that. But
All right. I wanted to review the basic
All right. I wanted to review the basic concept. Uh we used to mention we that I
concept. Uh we used to mention we that I
concept. Uh we used to mention we that I learned it in the kinesiology class, but
learned it in the kinesiology class, but
learned it in the kinesiology class, but that brought us all kinds of static. So
that brought us all kinds of static. So
that brought us all kinds of static. So we kinesiology is now an outword.
muscle test. Okay, you have to be very
muscle test. Okay, you have to be very careful in today's world as we will see.
careful in today's world as we will see.
careful in today's world as we will see. So, all right, we'll move on to the next
So, all right, we'll move on to the next
So, all right, we'll move on to the next uh the world's population uh about 80%
uh the world's population uh about 80%
uh the world's population uh about 80% of the world's population is below 200.
of the world's population is below 200.
of the world's population is below 200. 80% of the world's population. So when
80% of the world's population. So when
80% of the world's population. So when you're talking about truth and integrity
you're talking about truth and integrity
you're talking about truth and integrity and honesty, you're talking about 15% of
and honesty, you're talking about 15% of
and honesty, you're talking about 15% of the world uh even knows what that is.
the world uh even knows what that is.
the world uh even knows what that is. Uh okay, we'll move on to the rest. So
Uh okay, we'll move on to the rest. So
Uh okay, we'll move on to the rest. So this is the way the levels of
this is the way the levels of
this is the way the levels of consciousness are distributed in the
consciousness are distributed in the
consciousness are distributed in the human domain.
human domain.
human domain. 15% 20% rather.
15% 20% rather.
15% 20% rather. These are the people that calibrate
These are the people that calibrate
These are the people that calibrate above 200. As you can see numerically,
above 200. As you can see numerically,
above 200. As you can see numerically, they're in the minority.
they're in the minority.
they're in the minority. giving everyone equally a vote, you can
giving everyone equally a vote, you can
giving everyone equally a vote, you can see the consequences
which explains a lot of the world's
which explains a lot of the world's phenomena. Yeah.
phenomena. Yeah.
phenomena. Yeah. Anyway, because because these are
Anyway, because because these are
Anyway, because because these are logarithmic numbers, the power of this
logarithmic numbers, the power of this
logarithmic numbers, the power of this of these people here counterbalances
of these people here counterbalances
of these people here counterbalances all the rest of mankind, which we'll see
all the rest of mankind, which we'll see
all the rest of mankind, which we'll see on the next slide.
on the next slide.
on the next slide. So this percent that calibrates above
So this percent that calibrates above
So this percent that calibrates above uh 200 uh counterbalances the totality.
uh 200 uh counterbalances the totality.
uh 200 uh counterbalances the totality. It's as though these people are
It's as though these people are
It's as though these people are lightweights and these people are
lightweights and these people are
lightweights and these people are heavyweights.
heavyweights.
heavyweights. These are the people you don't want to
These are the people you don't want to
These are the people you don't want to get mad at you. No,
get mad at you. No,
get mad at you. No, actually they don't get mad at you. They
actually they don't get mad at you. They
actually they don't get mad at you. They forgive you because they realize that
forgive you because they realize that
forgive you because they realize that everyone is created at a specific level
everyone is created at a specific level
everyone is created at a specific level of consciousness and that they're
of consciousness and that they're
of consciousness and that they're evolving. Everyone is evolving. All
evolving. Everyone is evolving. All
evolving. Everyone is evolving. All right. So a few this is the evolution of
right. So a few this is the evolution of
right. So a few this is the evolution of consciousness in percent of elapsed
consciousness in percent of elapsed
consciousness in percent of elapsed time. And as you can see
time. And as you can see
time. And as you can see huge amounts of eons of time went by and
huge amounts of eons of time went by and
huge amounts of eons of time went by and only recently has the level of
only recently has the level of
only recently has the level of consciousness on this planet begin to
consciousness on this planet begin to
consciousness on this planet begin to rise to a noticeable level. Okay, next
rise to a noticeable level. Okay, next
rise to a noticeable level. Okay, next slide. And what we do is we review the
slide. And what we do is we review the
slide. And what we do is we review the earth epics and you can see the level of
earth epics and you can see the level of
earth epics and you can see the level of consciousness
consciousness
consciousness from the beginning of uh
from the beginning of uh
from the beginning of uh non-organic to organic matter matter and
non-organic to organic matter matter and
non-organic to organic matter matter and then the infinite power of consciousness
then the infinite power of consciousness
then the infinite power of consciousness encountered organic matter and life was
encountered organic matter and life was
encountered organic matter and life was spawned. So life can only come from
spawned. So life can only come from
spawned. So life can only come from life. It cannot come from non-life.
life. It cannot come from non-life.
life. It cannot come from non-life. Let's see if that's true.
Let's see if that's true.
Let's see if that's true. We have permission to ask that life
We have permission to ask that life
We have permission to ask that life originates only from life cannot arise
originates only from life cannot arise
originates only from life cannot arise from non-life resistance. So organic
from non-life resistance. So organic
from non-life resistance. So organic matter and life cannot arise from
matter and life cannot arise from
matter and life cannot arise from inorganic
inorganic
inorganic uh
uh
uh so that takes care of the bottom up
so that takes care of the bottom up
so that takes care of the bottom up theory of evolution.
It comes from top down. So life
It comes from top down. So life originates from top down from the
originates from top down from the
originates from top down from the radiance of divinity shining forth
radiance of divinity shining forth
radiance of divinity shining forth through the power of the field of
through the power of the field of
through the power of the field of consciousness which then emerges as
consciousness which then emerges as
consciousness which then emerges as life. And over the eons what we did was
life. And over the eons what we did was
life. And over the eons what we did was calibrate the level of energy of life on
calibrate the level of energy of life on
calibrate the level of energy of life on the planet uh over these prehistoric
the planet uh over these prehistoric
the planet uh over these prehistoric eons of time. And you see it starts out
eons of time. And you see it starts out
eons of time. And you see it starts out at level one. Uh probably the first
at level one. Uh probably the first
at level one. Uh probably the first prozzoa
prozzoa
prozzoa uh first amieba and then it progresses.
uh first amieba and then it progresses.
uh first amieba and then it progresses. We'll move to the next slide. This is
We'll move to the next slide. This is
We'll move to the next slide. This is old hat for some people. But again just
old hat for some people. But again just
old hat for some people. But again just to review it
to review it
to review it the emergence of life you see a bacteria
the emergence of life you see a bacteria
the emergence of life you see a bacteria calibrates at one crustaceian at three
calibrates at one crustaceian at three
calibrates at one crustaceian at three insects at six rachnids and fish octopus
insects at six rachnids and fish octopus
insects at six rachnids and fish octopus vipers komodo dragon
vipers komodo dragon
vipers komodo dragon reptiles and then you see the predatory
reptiles and then you see the predatory
reptiles and then you see the predatory mammals hyena lion and tiger the snakes
mammals hyena lion and tiger the snakes
mammals hyena lion and tiger the snakes and the alligators the dinosaurs
and the alligators the dinosaurs
and the alligators the dinosaurs and all these
and all these
and all these marvelous creatures evolved over great
marvelous creatures evolved over great
marvelous creatures evolved over great eons of time and then you see about
eons of time and then you see about
eons of time and then you see about level 200
level 200
level 200 uh the nature of life is no longer
uh the nature of life is no longer
uh the nature of life is no longer voracious and starts to become benign.
voracious and starts to become benign.
voracious and starts to become benign. You reach the herbivores,
You reach the herbivores,
You reach the herbivores, the giraffe, the zebra, the deer, do the
the giraffe, the zebra, the deer, do the
the giraffe, the zebra, the deer, do the mystic pigs, the elk and you see that
mystic pigs, the elk and you see that
mystic pigs, the elk and you see that they do not live uh they're not forced
they do not live uh they're not forced
they do not live uh they're not forced to kill others to live. They can be her
to kill others to live. They can be her
to kill others to live. They can be her herbivores. We have the farm animal, the
herbivores. We have the farm animal, the
herbivores. We have the farm animal, the cats, and uh the cats are at 240. And
cats, and uh the cats are at 240. And
cats, and uh the cats are at 240. And Oscar Oscar's at two uh Oscar's at 250,
Oscar Oscar's at two uh Oscar's at 250,
Oscar Oscar's at two uh Oscar's at 250, is he? Oscar.
is he? Oscar.
is he? Oscar. Yeah, cats are at 240.
>> Where where are cats? Well, here they
>> Where where are cats? Well, here they are. 240. Cats are 240. But Oscar, the
are. 240. Cats are 240. But Oscar, the
are. 240. Cats are 240. But Oscar, the cat that's been in the news, he's a very
cat that's been in the news, he's a very
cat that's been in the news, he's a very famous cat. That's the one that predicts
famous cat. That's the one that predicts
famous cat. That's the one that predicts with 100% accuracy whether you're about
with 100% accuracy whether you're about
with 100% accuracy whether you're about to leave the the planet. And yeah, in
to leave the the planet. And yeah, in
to leave the the planet. And yeah, in that nursing home when Oscar curls up
that nursing home when Oscar curls up
that nursing home when Oscar curls up next to you in bed, you're
uh every single time he's done it,
uh every single time he's done it, they've died within four hours. He's
they've died within four hours. He's
they've died within four hours. He's done it 26 times in a row without making
done it 26 times in a row without making
done it 26 times in a row without making a single mistake. Oscar knows when it's
a single mistake. Oscar knows when it's
a single mistake. Oscar knows when it's time to leave. And um all of us who live
time to leave. And um all of us who live
time to leave. And um all of us who live cats think, well, what could be nicer
cats think, well, what could be nicer
cats think, well, what could be nicer way to go than the kitty sitting on your
way to go than the kitty sitting on your
way to go than the kitty sitting on your on your stomach and purring away as you
on your stomach and purring away as you
on your stomach and purring away as you float away and the angels say bye.
float away and the angels say bye.
float away and the angels say bye. So Oscar knows you're you're going.
So Oscar knows you're you're going.
So Oscar knows you're you're going. That's sort of amazing. He's been in the
That's sort of amazing. He's been in the
That's sort of amazing. He's been in the news. Uh, so I just thought I'd mention
news. Uh, so I just thought I'd mention
news. Uh, so I just thought I'd mention Oscar. He's a 250, the family dog. And
Oscar. He's a 250, the family dog. And
Oscar. He's a 250, the family dog. And that's why people are so outraged at the
that's why people are so outraged at the
that's why people are so outraged at the dog, uh, the bad dog story now, baiting
dog, uh, the bad dog story now, baiting
dog, uh, the bad dog story now, baiting dogs and all, uh, because they calibrate
dogs and all, uh, because they calibrate
dogs and all, uh, because they calibrate at 250. So, the lovingness of these
at 250. So, the lovingness of these
at 250. So, the lovingness of these animals. So, the dog wagging tail
animals. So, the dog wagging tail
animals. So, the dog wagging tail calibrates at 500, which is love. Just
calibrates at 500, which is love. Just
calibrates at 500, which is love. Just like a kitty's purr calibrates at 500,
like a kitty's purr calibrates at 500,
like a kitty's purr calibrates at 500, which is love. Uhhuh. Kitty's purr and a
which is love. Uhhuh. Kitty's purr and a
which is love. Uhhuh. Kitty's purr and a dog's wagging tail are at 500. Yes.
dog's wagging tail are at 500. Yes.
dog's wagging tail are at 500. Yes. Therefore, they make great companions.
Therefore, they make great companions.
Therefore, they make great companions. As I say, I used to if somebody was
As I say, I used to if somebody was
As I say, I used to if somebody was alone and depressed, I told them I
alone and depressed, I told them I
alone and depressed, I told them I wouldn't treat them unless you get a dog
wouldn't treat them unless you get a dog
wouldn't treat them unless you get a dog or a cat.
or a cat.
or a cat. You can't get out of depression being
You can't get out of depression being
You can't get out of depression being that self-centered that you're not even
that self-centered that you're not even
that self-centered that you're not even willing to share your life with a kitty
willing to share your life with a kitty
willing to share your life with a kitty kitty or a dog, you know. All right. So,
kitty or a dog, you know. All right. So,
kitty or a dog, you know. All right. So, next uh the intellectual evolution.
next uh the intellectual evolution.
next uh the intellectual evolution. Here's the great renaissance that the
Here's the great renaissance that the
Here's the great renaissance that the great development of the intellect which
great development of the intellect which
great development of the intellect which is the level of the 400s really emerged
is the level of the 400s really emerged
is the level of the 400s really emerged in ancient uh ancient Greece.
in ancient uh ancient Greece.
in ancient uh ancient Greece. Ancient Egypt also had of course a very
Ancient Egypt also had of course a very
Ancient Egypt also had of course a very sophisticated theology.
sophisticated theology.
sophisticated theology. Uh but the intellectual uh realm really
Uh but the intellectual uh realm really
Uh but the intellectual uh realm really is birthed in ancient Greece. Plato and
is birthed in ancient Greece. Plato and
is birthed in ancient Greece. Plato and uh all the great masters. So the great
uh all the great masters. So the great
uh all the great masters. So the great books of the western world
books of the western world
books of the western world uh they have a study uh study course uh
uh they have a study uh study course uh
uh they have a study uh study course uh spread over 10 years. You spend 10 years
spread over 10 years. You spend 10 years
spread over 10 years. You spend 10 years studying the great books of the western
studying the great books of the western
studying the great books of the western world and you'll have the intellectual
world and you'll have the intellectual
world and you'll have the intellectual basis and background of
basis and background of
basis and background of uh the intelligent educated people of
uh the intelligent educated people of
uh the intelligent educated people of the world. Yeah.
the world. Yeah.
the world. Yeah. uh at one time this is where the
uh at one time this is where the
uh at one time this is where the universities
universities
universities calibrated
calibrated
calibrated last night or the night before they had
last night or the night before they had
last night or the night before they had a report on the top six or eight
a report on the top six or eight
a report on the top six or eight um universities in the United States all
um universities in the United States all
um universities in the United States all the big names what do they call those
the big names what do they call those
the big names what do they call those fancy ones Harvard and Yale and all
fancy ones Harvard and Yale and all
fancy ones Harvard and Yale and all those
those
those >> ugly
>> ugly
>> ugly >> ugly okay we have permission to ask this
>> ugly okay we have permission to ask this
>> ugly okay we have permission to ask this question
question
question the list that we saw the other And
the list that we saw the other And
the list that we saw the other And television calibrates over 250
250 245
245 250.
How can you get from the great books of
How can you get from the great books of the western world
the western world
the western world down to 250
down to 250
down to 250 >> 245
>> 245
>> 245 it's a wonder that high.
it's a wonder that high.
it's a wonder that high. All right. So the intellectual
All right. So the intellectual
All right. So the intellectual deterioration we'll get to that later.
deterioration we'll get to that later.
deterioration we'll get to that later. So th this is the intellectual basis of
So th this is the intellectual basis of
So th this is the intellectual basis of western the western civilization.
western the western civilization.
western the western civilization. This is the civilization that is
This is the civilization that is
This is the civilization that is currently in decline.
currently in decline.
currently in decline. The pope said and he's correct that
The pope said and he's correct that
The pope said and he's correct that western civilization is currently in
western civilization is currently in
western civilization is currently in decline
decline
decline uh due to the impact of Islam plus the
uh due to the impact of Islam plus the
uh due to the impact of Islam plus the impact of relativism
impact of relativism
impact of relativism the
the
the philosophy of relativism. All right. So
philosophy of relativism. All right. So
philosophy of relativism. All right. So these are the great names of history u
these are the great names of history u
these are the great names of history u and includes a great many of the great
and includes a great many of the great
and includes a great many of the great uh scientists as well and uh these are
uh scientists as well and uh these are
uh scientists as well and uh these are uh Plato at 485 Platinus at 503. So
uh Plato at 485 Platinus at 503. So
uh Plato at 485 Platinus at 503. So these are the great names. All right,
these are the great names. All right,
these are the great names. All right, we'll move on to the next
we'll move on to the next
we'll move on to the next uh oh, we mentioned the uh the the
uh oh, we mentioned the uh the the
uh oh, we mentioned the uh the the the reason for the muscle test to work
the reason for the muscle test to work
the reason for the muscle test to work is because the universe is in a state of
is because the universe is in a state of
is because the universe is in a state of suspended potentiality
suspended potentiality
suspended potentiality and then to collapse the wave function
and then to collapse the wave function
and then to collapse the wave function as an actuality
as an actuality
as an actuality uh is well stated by Henry Stap and
uh is well stated by Henry Stap and
uh is well stated by Henry Stap and people that are very interested in it, I
people that are very interested in it, I
people that are very interested in it, I tell them look up Henry's staff on the
tell them look up Henry's staff on the
tell them look up Henry's staff on the internet. His new book is out and you
internet. His new book is out and you
internet. His new book is out and you just punch a button and your whole book
just punch a button and your whole book
just punch a button and your whole book prints out. I don't know how you do that
prints out. I don't know how you do that
prints out. I don't know how you do that but it sounds very good.
So you move from one state to another if
So you move from one state to another if the question
is a truth that's matched by the reality
is a truth that's matched by the reality of the universe.
If what I ask is a statement that's
If what I ask is a statement that's matched by a reality and that exists in
matched by a reality and that exists in
matched by a reality and that exists in the universe,
the universe,
the universe, then our arm goes strong.
then our arm goes strong.
then our arm goes strong. If the statement has no correlary, no
If the statement has no correlary, no
If the statement has no correlary, no match anywhere in the universe because
match anywhere in the universe because
match anywhere in the universe because it's not true, then the arm goes weak.
it's not true, then the arm goes weak.
it's not true, then the arm goes weak. So it's very simply yes or not yes.
So it's very simply yes or not yes.
So it's very simply yes or not yes. All right. Oh okay then we'll move on to
All right. Oh okay then we'll move on to
All right. Oh okay then we'll move on to the next
the next
the next um the other difficulty uh we have in
um the other difficulty uh we have in
um the other difficulty uh we have in trying to resolve the world's
trying to resolve the world's
trying to resolve the world's difficulties
difficulties
difficulties is that the two levels of consciousness
is that the two levels of consciousness
is that the two levels of consciousness function differently. The brain function
function differently. The brain function
function differently. The brain function is different. The animal dominated brain
is different. The animal dominated brain
is different. The animal dominated brain versus uh the spiritualized brain. And
versus uh the spiritualized brain. And
versus uh the spiritualized brain. And as people evolve spiritually, the
as people evolve spiritually, the
as people evolve spiritually, the condundalini energy which is a unique
condundalini energy which is a unique
condundalini energy which is a unique spiritual energy arises in the atheric
spiritual energy arises in the atheric
spiritual energy arises in the atheric body. And what happens is you alter
body. And what happens is you alter
body. And what happens is you alter brain function.
brain function.
brain function. So that below 200 you get a left brain
So that below 200 you get a left brain
So that below 200 you get a left brain linear
linear
linear uh dominance and as you move higher in
uh dominance and as you move higher in
uh dominance and as you move higher in consciousness you begin to move into the
consciousness you begin to move into the
consciousness you begin to move into the nonlinear.
nonlinear.
nonlinear. Lon linear is the context and the
Lon linear is the context and the
Lon linear is the context and the meaning uh the space in which something
meaning uh the space in which something
meaning uh the space in which something exists that gives reflects as its
exists that gives reflects as its
exists that gives reflects as its meaning and significance.
meaning and significance.
meaning and significance. And many people um
the people who criticize the work I do
the people who criticize the work I do or the work we do as a group or even the
or the work we do as a group or even the
or the work we do as a group or even the test that we use all the time are always
test that we use all the time are always
test that we use all the time are always below 200 and they they can only think
below 200 and they they can only think
below 200 and they they can only think in a pedestrian linear kind of a
in a pedestrian linear kind of a
in a pedestrian linear kind of a causality. They're stuck in the
causality. They're stuck in the
causality. They're stuck in the Newtonian paradigm of linear cause and
Newtonian paradigm of linear cause and
Newtonian paradigm of linear cause and effect.
effect.
effect. What gives our life meaning of course as
What gives our life meaning of course as
What gives our life meaning of course as we're going to see in today's lecture is
we're going to see in today's lecture is
we're going to see in today's lecture is significance. It's you know a fact is a
significance. It's you know a fact is a
significance. It's you know a fact is a fact. So what?
fact. So what?
fact. So what? So what I mean who cares about a fact? I
So what I mean who cares about a fact? I
So what I mean who cares about a fact? I don't care about facts at all. Do you
don't care about facts at all. Do you
don't care about facts at all. Do you care about facts?
care about facts?
care about facts? Any here care about facts?
Any here care about facts?
Any here care about facts? Can't sell a fact today?
Can't sell a fact today?
Can't sell a fact today? Sophisticated audience. Because it isn't
Sophisticated audience. Because it isn't
Sophisticated audience. Because it isn't the fact, it's what it means, isn't it?
the fact, it's what it means, isn't it?
the fact, it's what it means, isn't it? Huh?
Huh?
Huh? Who cares if the gas tank is empty
Who cares if the gas tank is empty
Who cares if the gas tank is empty except that it means you're going to run
except that it means you're going to run
except that it means you're going to run out of gas on the road. It's what it
out of gas on the road. It's what it
out of gas on the road. It's what it means that activates you. The fact the
means that activates you. The fact the
means that activates you. The fact the gas tank is empty is, you know, almost
gas tank is empty is, you know, almost
gas tank is empty is, you know, almost empty uh is irrelevant except that it
empty uh is irrelevant except that it
empty uh is irrelevant except that it it's going to get stalled on the
it's going to get stalled on the
it's going to get stalled on the highway. Go to the next one and we'll
highway. Go to the next one and we'll
highway. Go to the next one and we'll get around to what we're going to talk
get around to what we're going to talk
get around to what we're going to talk about today. Um the rate of happiness is
about today. Um the rate of happiness is
about today. Um the rate of happiness is completely related to the level of
completely related to the level of
completely related to the level of consciousness.
consciousness.
consciousness. Therefore, all these social engineering
Therefore, all these social engineering
Therefore, all these social engineering attempts to make people happy,
attempts to make people happy,
attempts to make people happy, uh, you can't force people to be happy.
uh, you can't force people to be happy.
uh, you can't force people to be happy. There was some king that forced his
There was some king that forced his
There was some king that forced his people, he told him if if they weren't
people, he told him if if they weren't
people, he told him if if they weren't happy and didn't love him, he'd kill
happy and didn't love him, he'd kill
happy and didn't love him, he'd kill them.
them.
them. He would beat Oh, he would beat them
He would beat Oh, he would beat them
He would beat Oh, he would beat them until they loved them. That was it. He
until they loved them. That was it. He
until they loved them. That was it. He would beat them until they loved.
would beat them until they loved.
would beat them until they loved. So the rate of happiness is correlated
So the rate of happiness is correlated
So the rate of happiness is correlated with the level of consciousness and as
with the level of consciousness and as
with the level of consciousness and as we see below the level 200 how uh only
we see below the level 200 how uh only
we see below the level 200 how uh only 22% of the people are happy. If you live
22% of the people are happy. If you live
22% of the people are happy. If you live a life based on pride and narcissism the
a life based on pride and narcissism the
a life based on pride and narcissism the chances of being happy and feeling
chances of being happy and feeling
chances of being happy and feeling fulfilled and satisfied are extremely
fulfilled and satisfied are extremely
fulfilled and satisfied are extremely slim. Okay, we'll move up to the next.
slim. Okay, we'll move up to the next.
slim. Okay, we'll move up to the next. We got to hurry up. Oh,
I knew the evil doers were somewhere
I knew the evil doers were somewhere hidden in the sheep's clothing. And
hidden in the sheep's clothing. And
hidden in the sheep's clothing. And that, of course, is going to be a big
that, of course, is going to be a big
that, of course, is going to be a big part of the house of mirrors. The house
part of the house of mirrors. The house
part of the house of mirrors. The house of mirrors. You see, people say, "Well,
of mirrors. You see, people say, "Well,
of mirrors. You see, people say, "Well, that's such a nice, lovable sheep. Let's
that's such a nice, lovable sheep. Let's
that's such a nice, lovable sheep. Let's go and hug it." Oh, he's missing a leg
go and hug it." Oh, he's missing a leg
go and hug it." Oh, he's missing a leg now.
now.
now. All right, so we'll move on. That's such
All right, so we'll move on. That's such
All right, so we'll move on. That's such a great slide.
The human dilemma. So, here we're going
The human dilemma. So, here we're going to take a cruise through the entire
to take a cruise through the entire
to take a cruise through the entire totality of the human experience. It'll
totality of the human experience. It'll
totality of the human experience. It'll take up today's lecture and probably the
take up today's lecture and probably the
take up today's lecture and probably the next one as well.
next one as well.
next one as well. uh we we come up of course the first
uh we we come up of course the first
uh we we come up of course the first thing that when begin to say about the
thing that when begin to say about the
thing that when begin to say about the reality of being a human being is uh how
reality of being a human being is uh how
reality of being a human being is uh how do we know that we are and where did we
do we know that we are and where did we
do we know that we are and where did we come from? Well, we showed from the
come from? Well, we showed from the
come from? Well, we showed from the mamlian viewpoint where we came from uh
mamlian viewpoint where we came from uh
mamlian viewpoint where we came from uh evolutionary
evolutionary
evolutionary uh but evolutionary wise you still don't
uh but evolutionary wise you still don't
uh but evolutionary wise you still don't end up as a human being. you uh end up
end up as a human being. you uh end up
end up as a human being. you uh end up as a sophisticated homminid which is
as a sophisticated homminid which is
as a sophisticated homminid which is different than being human. So what
different than being human. So what
different than being human. So what makes the human human course is the
makes the human human course is the
makes the human human course is the spirit and the atheric body. So
spirit and the atheric body. So
spirit and the atheric body. So once did we come
once did we come
once did we come is usually being asked in a linear time
is usually being asked in a linear time
is usually being asked in a linear time dimension. You know did we come from
dimension. You know did we come from
dimension. You know did we come from highway 89A or did we
highway 89A or did we
highway 89A or did we did we come from the zebra? I mean we're
did we come from the zebra? I mean we're
did we come from the zebra? I mean we're they're speaking in terms of a
they're speaking in terms of a
they're speaking in terms of a causality. So they're really asking a
causality. So they're really asking a
causality. So they're really asking a question in causality.
question in causality.
question in causality. Uh h how did we get here? Whence did we
Uh h how did we get here? Whence did we
Uh h how did we get here? Whence did we come? Uh and of course the answer of the
come? Uh and of course the answer of the
come? Uh and of course the answer of the spiritually evolved person uh is quite a
spiritually evolved person uh is quite a
spiritually evolved person uh is quite a bit different than the materialist. The
bit different than the materialist. The
bit different than the materialist. The materialist is very happy with an animal
materialist is very happy with an animal
materialist is very happy with an animal evolution which we covered in the
evolution which we covered in the
evolution which we covered in the lecture on evolution versus creation
lecture on evolution versus creation
lecture on evolution versus creation is very happy with um uh
is very happy with um uh
is very happy with um uh a linear Newtonian explanation.
a linear Newtonian explanation.
a linear Newtonian explanation. Who are we to a spiritual person means
Who are we to a spiritual person means
Who are we to a spiritual person means quite a different thing. To a linear
quite a different thing. To a linear
quite a different thing. To a linear person the we means the animal me. Where
person the we means the animal me. Where
person the we means the animal me. Where did this uh bodiness come from? The more
did this uh bodiness come from? The more
did this uh bodiness come from? The more evolved person that we means the human
evolved person that we means the human
evolved person that we means the human community. It means the spirit of the
community. It means the spirit of the
community. It means the spirit of the human. So even the question you see does
human. So even the question you see does
human. So even the question you see does not mean the same thing. The creationist
not mean the same thing. The creationist
not mean the same thing. The creationist says well Darwin explained the whole
says well Darwin explained the whole
says well Darwin explained the whole thing. You know it's all mechanistic.
thing. You know it's all mechanistic.
thing. You know it's all mechanistic. All mechanistic.
All mechanistic.
All mechanistic. Uh
so the top down of course God created
so the top down of course God created man. God created man
man. God created man
man. God created man created man.
created man.
created man. So the bottom up then says you're just a
So the bottom up then says you're just a
So the bottom up then says you're just a sort of a chemical accident over time.
sort of a chemical accident over time.
sort of a chemical accident over time. And the spiritually evolved person
And the spiritually evolved person
And the spiritually evolved person realizes that you're not just a
realizes that you're not just a
realizes that you're not just a physicality.
physicality.
physicality. You have consciousness and awareness
You have consciousness and awareness
You have consciousness and awareness and you came from top down, not from
and you came from top down, not from
and you came from top down, not from bottom up. And Genesis, the explanation
bottom up. And Genesis, the explanation
bottom up. And Genesis, the explanation from Genesis,
from Genesis,
from Genesis, uh, calibrates, I think 600 or over.
uh, calibrates, I think 600 or over.
uh, calibrates, I think 600 or over. Wait a minute. Let's see.
Wait a minute. Let's see.
Wait a minute. Let's see. Man, we have permission to ask this. Man
Man, we have permission to ask this. Man
Man, we have permission to ask this. Man was created by God. Resist. Calibrates
was created by God. Resist. Calibrates
was created by God. Resist. Calibrates at a thousand. Resist. Calibrates at a
at a thousand. Resist. Calibrates at a
at a thousand. Resist. Calibrates at a thousand. Okay. Dar Darwinian
thousand. Okay. Dar Darwinian
thousand. Okay. Dar Darwinian evolutionary theory calibrates at 440
evolutionary theory calibrates at 440
evolutionary theory calibrates at 440 445.
445.
445. All right. So
All right. So
All right. So we were created then by an act of
we were created then by an act of
we were created then by an act of special creation. Every one of us then
special creation. Every one of us then
special creation. Every one of us then is a child of God. Everyone here is a
is a child of God. Everyone here is a
is a child of God. Everyone here is a child of God. Therefore everyone out
child of God. Therefore everyone out
child of God. Therefore everyone out there is our brother or our sister.
there is our brother or our sister.
there is our brother or our sister. say
say
say and uh
and uh
and uh whence did we come from then depends on
whence did we come from then depends on
whence did we come from then depends on top down an act of creation by God uh or
top down an act of creation by God uh or
top down an act of creation by God uh or an accident of evolution
an accident of evolution
an accident of evolution then to ask where did we come we ask who
then to ask where did we come we ask who
then to ask where did we come we ask who are we are we body or are we spirit
are we are we body or are we spirit
are we are we body or are we spirit and you can see there's an arbitrary
and you can see there's an arbitrary
and you can see there's an arbitrary languaging with no basis in reality ity
languaging with no basis in reality ity
languaging with no basis in reality ity is there isn't any duality of body or
is there isn't any duality of body or
is there isn't any duality of body or spirit.
spirit.
spirit. Yeah. Body or spirit. Are we body or
Yeah. Body or spirit. Are we body or
Yeah. Body or spirit. Are we body or spirit? It means primarily are we only a
spirit? It means primarily are we only a
spirit? It means primarily are we only a physicality
physicality
physicality when this body this protoplasm topples
when this body this protoplasm topples
when this body this protoplasm topples over. Is that the end of the story?
over. Is that the end of the story?
over. Is that the end of the story? Is that the end of the story? A lot of
Is that the end of the story? A lot of
Is that the end of the story? A lot of people hope so.
I think they're going to be
I think they're going to be disappointed. Are we body or spirit?
disappointed. Are we body or spirit?
disappointed. Are we body or spirit? So we're a spiritualized body and we see
So we're a spiritualized body and we see
So we're a spiritualized body and we see the difference in brain function of left
the difference in brain function of left
the difference in brain function of left brain versus right brain uh as the
brain versus right brain uh as the
brain versus right brain uh as the effect of the spiritual energy. The
effect of the spiritual energy. The
effect of the spiritual energy. The spiritual energy then lights up the
spiritual energy then lights up the
spiritual energy then lights up the levels of awareness
levels of awareness
levels of awareness the spiritualized person. So the minute
the spiritualized person. So the minute
the spiritualized person. So the minute you become spiritually committed you
you become spiritually committed you
you become spiritually committed you pray to God and say dear God I ask you
pray to God and say dear God I ask you
pray to God and say dear God I ask you to help me. I ask for your will for me.
to help me. I ask for your will for me.
to help me. I ask for your will for me. You've already brought up an energy that
You've already brought up an energy that
You've already brought up an energy that now enables you to understand the
now enables you to understand the
now enables you to understand the answer.
answer.
answer. Understand the answer. So you finesse a
Understand the answer. So you finesse a
Understand the answer. So you finesse a whole field of awareness
whole field of awareness
whole field of awareness and become much more much empowered as a
and become much more much empowered as a
and become much more much empowered as a human being and you realize that you're
human being and you realize that you're
human being and you realize that you're a spiritualized body not just a physical
a spiritualized body not just a physical
a spiritualized body not just a physical body. Then we ask well do animals have
body. Then we ask well do animals have
body. Then we ask well do animals have spirits?
spirits?
spirits? Anybody
Anybody
Anybody want to vote? Do animals have spirits?
want to vote? Do animals have spirits?
want to vote? Do animals have spirits? All in favor?
All in favor?
All in favor? Okay. All those against.
Um, animals. We have a person to ask
Um, animals. We have a person to ask this. Animals do have spirits. Resist.
this. Animals do have spirits. Resist.
this. Animals do have spirits. Resist. Animals do have spirits. They have a
Animals do have spirits. They have a
Animals do have spirits. They have a spirit. Anybody has a dog knows that
spirit. Anybody has a dog knows that
spirit. Anybody has a dog knows that knows that. Anybody who has a kitty
knows that. Anybody who has a kitty
knows that. Anybody who has a kitty knows that. Anybody who has a
knows that. Anybody who has a
knows that. Anybody who has a um cocoa,
um cocoa,
um cocoa, anybody who has an African gray parrot
anybody who has an African gray parrot
anybody who has an African gray parrot knows that. Obviously, the animal has a
knows that. Obviously, the animal has a
knows that. Obviously, the animal has a spirit and it quickly reads you and
spirit and it quickly reads you and
spirit and it quickly reads you and reads you where you're at. Quickly reads
reads you where you're at. Quickly reads
reads you where you're at. Quickly reads where you're at.
where you're at.
where you're at. So, seeing as we just figured out where
So, seeing as we just figured out where
So, seeing as we just figured out where we came from and that we're both body or
we came from and that we're both body or
we came from and that we're both body or spirit, the next question is whence do
spirit, the next question is whence do
spirit, the next question is whence do we go? Whence do we go? Well, let's just
we go? Whence do we go? Well, let's just
we go? Whence do we go? Well, let's just ask the arm again.
ask the arm again.
ask the arm again. I don't know where we go. Uh, we don't
I don't know where we go. Uh, we don't
I don't know where we go. Uh, we don't go any place. Resist.
No wonder people can't figure out where
No wonder people can't figure out where are they going to go.
are they going to go.
are they going to go. You ain't going nowhere.
But you what happens is you transform
But you what happens is you transform uh into a different energy field. That
uh into a different energy field. That
uh into a different energy field. That which is your atheric body becomes now
which is your atheric body becomes now
which is your atheric body becomes now your primary body. Yeah. Your your
your primary body. Yeah. Your your
your primary body. Yeah. Your your primary location. Yes. People who have
primary location. Yes. People who have
primary location. Yes. People who have been out of body. How many people here
been out of body. How many people here
been out of body. How many people here have been out of body? Oh, whoop they
have been out of body? Oh, whoop they
have been out of body? Oh, whoop they do. Okay.
do. Okay.
do. Okay. It's really a fun thing. And uh and of
It's really a fun thing. And uh and of
It's really a fun thing. And uh and of course you can learn to do it with a
course you can learn to do it with a
course you can learn to do it with a little training you can learn to do it
little training you can learn to do it
little training you can learn to do it at will. And some people have trouble
at will. And some people have trouble
at will. And some people have trouble staying in their body. They have to
staying in their body. They have to
staying in their body. They have to learn how to stay there and they drift
learn how to stay there and they drift
learn how to stay there and they drift off. And uh so there's the spiritual
off. And uh so there's the spiritual
off. And uh so there's the spiritual saying, keep your mind where your body
saying, keep your mind where your body
saying, keep your mind where your body is. Keep your mind where your body is
is. Keep your mind where your body is
is. Keep your mind where your body is because Sedona was same as for space
because Sedona was same as for space
because Sedona was same as for space cadets when I first got here.
If you said Sedona, they said, "Oh,
If you said Sedona, they said, "Oh, space cadetses,
space cadetses,
space cadetses, all the woo woos.
all the woo woos.
all the woo woos. All the woowoos."
All the woowoos."
All the woowoos." So to not space out then to uh continue
So to not space out then to uh continue
So to not space out then to uh continue to function, where do we go and why are
to function, where do we go and why are
to function, where do we go and why are we in this world? And that would of
we in this world? And that would of
we in this world? And that would of course depend on what is the purpose of
course depend on what is the purpose of
course depend on what is the purpose of life. Uh why are we in this? And so the
life. Uh why are we in this? And so the
life. Uh why are we in this? And so the purpose of human human life has been
purpose of human human life has been
purpose of human human life has been debated all the great books of the
debated all the great books of the
debated all the great books of the western world and epistemology and
western world and epistemology and
western world and epistemology and theology and metaphysics.
theology and metaphysics.
theology and metaphysics. Uh why are we here? What did you do with
Uh why are we here? What did you do with
Uh why are we here? What did you do with my question?
Oh, I thought I said where are we in
Oh, I thought I said where are we in this world? Oh, we're here.
this world? Oh, we're here.
this world? Oh, we're here. Why are we in this world? The answer is
Why are we in this world? The answer is
Why are we in this world? The answer is we're not.
You're not in this world. That is that
You're not in this world. That is that correct?
correct?
correct? But let's see.
But let's see.
But let's see. It's a fact. You're not in this world.
It's a fact. You're not in this world.
It's a fact. You're not in this world. Resist. This world is in you. Resist.
Resist. This world is in you. Resist.
Resist. This world is in you. Resist. The world is in you. You're not in the
The world is in you. You're not in the
The world is in you. You're not in the world. Whoa.
world. Whoa.
world. Whoa. So that sort of repackages the whole
So that sort of repackages the whole
So that sort of repackages the whole deal, don't it?
The world is in you. Why? Because it's
The world is in you. Why? Because it's only consciousness that is even aware of
only consciousness that is even aware of
only consciousness that is even aware of the world. It's consciousness that is
the world. It's consciousness that is
the world. It's consciousness that is aware that you are. Yeah. So
aware that you are. Yeah. So
aware that you are. Yeah. So uh
uh
uh you don't have to worry about leaving
you don't have to worry about leaving
you don't have to worry about leaving the world. Yeah. You can't leave the
the world. Yeah. You can't leave the
the world. Yeah. You can't leave the world. So what happens then when the
world. So what happens then when the
world. So what happens then when the body topples over is you maintain you
body topples over is you maintain you
body topples over is you maintain you maintain
maintain
maintain uh that which is the real self. That
uh that which is the real self. That
uh that which is the real self. That which is the real self.
which is the real self.
which is the real self. Why are we in this world? It seems
Why are we in this world? It seems
Why are we in this world? It seems obvious from just looking at history.
obvious from just looking at history.
obvious from just looking at history. The purpose is to support our evolution
The purpose is to support our evolution
The purpose is to support our evolution to support the evolution of our
to support the evolution of our
to support the evolution of our consciousness. to give us the m this
consciousness. to give us the m this
consciousness. to give us the m this world gives us the maximum opportunity
world gives us the maximum opportunity
world gives us the maximum opportunity to grow and develop spiritually. Let's
to grow and develop spiritually. Let's
to grow and develop spiritually. Let's see if that's true. This world gives us
see if that's true. This world gives us
see if that's true. This world gives us maximum opportunity to grow and develop
maximum opportunity to grow and develop
maximum opportunity to grow and develop spiritually. Resist. Therefore, as the
spiritually. Resist. Therefore, as the
spiritually. Resist. Therefore, as the Buddhist said, this is a karmic gift.
Buddhist said, this is a karmic gift.
Buddhist said, this is a karmic gift. Resist. Rare it is to be born a human.
Resist. Rare it is to be born a human.
Resist. Rare it is to be born a human. You know, rare it is to be
You know, rare it is to be
You know, rare it is to be rare still to be born a human. A great
rare still to be born a human. A great
rare still to be born a human. A great gift. Everyone is here because of good
gift. Everyone is here because of good
gift. Everyone is here because of good karma.
karma.
karma. Everyone here is here because of good
Everyone here is here because of good
Everyone here is here because of good karma. It's a great gift. Rare it is to
karma. It's a great gift. Rare it is to
karma. It's a great gift. Rare it is to be born a human being. Rare. Therefore,
be born a human being. Rare. Therefore,
be born a human being. Rare. Therefore, let's just you don't have to get up
let's just you don't have to get up
let's just you don't have to get up every time. Uh it is significant of
every time. Uh it is significant of
every time. Uh it is significant of excellent good karma. Resist. It's a
excellent good karma. Resist. It's a
excellent good karma. Resist. It's a gift from God. Resist.
gift from God. Resist.
gift from God. Resist. Because of the excellence of your good
Because of the excellence of your good
Because of the excellence of your good karma. Therefore, we have to respect
karma. Therefore, we have to respect
karma. Therefore, we have to respect each other because somewhere someplace
each other because somewhere someplace
each other because somewhere someplace sometime you must have been okay about
sometime you must have been okay about
sometime you must have been okay about something.
something.
something. even that you're horrible, ugly, and
even that you're horrible, ugly, and
even that you're horrible, ugly, and mean, and I hateful now.
Probably did a good turn for somebody.
Probably did a good turn for somebody. You saw the little my famous black
You saw the little my famous black
You saw the little my famous black beetle flopping his little legs upside
beetle flopping his little legs upside
beetle flopping his little legs upside down and and you walked by and you said,
down and and you walked by and you said,
down and and you walked by and you said, "Oh, oh."
"Oh, oh."
"Oh, oh." And you turned him over and he walked
And you turned him over and he walked
And you turned him over and he walked away happy. And that's why you got to
away happy. And that's why you got to
away happy. And that's why you got to get born a human being.
get born a human being.
get born a human being. Just one act of kindness. One act of
Just one act of kindness. One act of
Just one act of kindness. One act of kindness.
kindness.
kindness. Random act of kindness. Random, you
Random act of kindness. Random, you
Random act of kindness. Random, you know, was such a very significant trend
know, was such a very significant trend
know, was such a very significant trend there for a while. You heard quite a bit
there for a while. You heard quite a bit
there for a while. You heard quite a bit about it. Now you don't hear as much
about it. Now you don't hear as much
about it. Now you don't hear as much about it. Random acts of kindness. Not
about it. Random acts of kindness. Not
about it. Random acts of kindness. Not because there's any gain, but just
because there's any gain, but just
because there's any gain, but just because that's who you are.
because that's who you are.
because that's who you are. I mean, nobody's going to give you a
I mean, nobody's going to give you a
I mean, nobody's going to give you a gift because you turned the beetle over
gift because you turned the beetle over
gift because you turned the beetle over and nobody's even going to see it.
and nobody's even going to see it.
and nobody's even going to see it. Nobody's even going to know it.
Nobody's even going to know it.
Nobody's even going to know it. You say to yourself, "That's ridiculous.
You say to yourself, "That's ridiculous.
You say to yourself, "That's ridiculous. It's just a beetle for God's sake." And
It's just a beetle for God's sake." And
It's just a beetle for God's sake." And you walk around and your conscience, you
you walk around and your conscience, you
you walk around and your conscience, you can't handle it. Oh, heck with it. Turn
can't handle it. Oh, heck with it. Turn
can't handle it. Oh, heck with it. Turn them over.
Guess we won't kill him. All right.
Guess we won't kill him. All right. What is the purpose of human life then?
What is the purpose of human life then?
What is the purpose of human life then? Is it facilitates the evolution of
Is it facilitates the evolution of
Is it facilitates the evolution of consciousness
consciousness
consciousness to the realization of our ultimate
to the realization of our ultimate
to the realization of our ultimate reality? Uh it's a part of the pathway
reality? Uh it's a part of the pathway
reality? Uh it's a part of the pathway to enlightenment.
to enlightenment.
to enlightenment. Therefore, the question then arises, how
Therefore, the question then arises, how
Therefore, the question then arises, how how did this world arise? How did this
how did this world arise? How did this
how did this world arise? How did this world arise? All depends on what you
world arise? All depends on what you
world arise? All depends on what you mean by this world.
mean by this world.
mean by this world. You mean the planet? You mean humanity,
You mean the planet? You mean humanity,
You mean the planet? You mean humanity, the human experience.
the human experience.
the human experience. Some people think that mankind should be
Some people think that mankind should be
Some people think that mankind should be eliminated
eliminated
eliminated and only the planet should survive.
and only the planet should survive.
and only the planet should survive. They are they're environmentalist sort
They are they're environmentalist sort
They are they're environmentalist sort of mad people that think all of ma all
of mad people that think all of ma all
of mad people that think all of ma all of humankind.
of humankind.
of humankind. What's important is the planet not
What's important is the planet not
What's important is the planet not humans.
humans.
humans. Yes. And if they could they would
Yes. And if they could they would
Yes. And if they could they would eliminate all humans and to turn it back
eliminate all humans and to turn it back
eliminate all humans and to turn it back to the nature and the planet.
So that would sort of say be saying that
So that would sort of say be saying that the purpose of the planet is strictly
the purpose of the planet is strictly
the purpose of the planet is strictly material rather than spiritual. So the
material rather than spiritual. So the
material rather than spiritual. So the world as we experience then the world
world as we experience then the world
world as we experience then the world that we're talking about is a state of
that we're talking about is a state of
that we're talking about is a state of consciousness. We're not talking about a
consciousness. We're not talking about a
consciousness. We're not talking about a planet. The planet and the origin origin
planet. The planet and the origin origin
planet. The planet and the origin origin of the planet is quite obvious from the
of the planet is quite obvious from the
of the planet is quite obvious from the history of science. You can see it on
history of science. You can see it on
history of science. You can see it on the history channel any night. It reruns
the history channel any night. It reruns
the history channel any night. It reruns the birth of the universe.
the birth of the universe.
the birth of the universe. How did this world arise then?
How did this world arise then?
How did this world arise then? Physically
Physically
Physically uh karmically it arose as a karmic
uh karmically it arose as a karmic
uh karmically it arose as a karmic benefit as a reward for
benefit as a reward for
benefit as a reward for not a not a give and take reward but as
not a not a give and take reward but as
not a not a give and take reward but as an automatic consequence of that which
an automatic consequence of that which
an automatic consequence of that which we have become.
we have become.
we have become. Intrinsic to the human experience
Intrinsic to the human experience
Intrinsic to the human experience and so prominent in today's world is the
and so prominent in today's world is the
and so prominent in today's world is the birth of morality and right versus right
birth of morality and right versus right
birth of morality and right versus right and wrong. right and wrong.
and wrong. right and wrong.
and wrong. right and wrong. People would like to ridicule morality.
People would like to ridicule morality.
People would like to ridicule morality. The other night somebody had a black
The other night somebody had a black
The other night somebody had a black side criticized some commentator and
side criticized some commentator and
side criticized some commentator and said, "You sound oh so 1950ish."
said, "You sound oh so 1950ish."
said, "You sound oh so 1950ish." That was really oh so 1950ish.
That was really oh so 1950ish.
That was really oh so 1950ish. That was the era of the great
That was the era of the great
That was the era of the great generation.
generation.
generation. It was an era of ethics and morality.
It was an era of ethics and morality.
It was an era of ethics and morality. Ethics and morality.
Ethics and morality.
Ethics and morality. And uh you remember when Elvis Presley
And uh you remember when Elvis Presley
And uh you remember when Elvis Presley came along?
came along?
came along? He was on last night. The story of
He was on last night. The story of
He was on last night. The story of Elvis, they had towns that banned him.
Elvis, they had towns that banned him.
Elvis, they had towns that banned him. It was illegal to play Elvis Presley.
It was illegal to play Elvis Presley.
It was illegal to play Elvis Presley. Uh so the birth of morality and right
Uh so the birth of morality and right
Uh so the birth of morality and right versus wrong.
versus wrong.
versus wrong. Uh people think that's a human
Uh people think that's a human
Uh people think that's a human invention. It's not. It's right and
invention. It's not. It's right and
invention. It's not. It's right and wrong is very very definitely stated
wrong is very very definitely stated
wrong is very very definitely stated throughout the entire animal kingdom.
throughout the entire animal kingdom.
throughout the entire animal kingdom. You make one mistake and the other the
You make one mistake and the other the
You make one mistake and the other the other uh the other will kill you. Uh
other uh the other will kill you. Uh
other uh the other will kill you. Uh Mircat Manor is on Friday night on the
Mircat Manor is on Friday night on the
Mircat Manor is on Friday night on the animal planet.
animal planet.
animal planet. Mircat Manor, you know, is following
Mircat Manor, you know, is following
Mircat Manor, you know, is following these Mircats in in Africa, the
these Mircats in in Africa, the
these Mircats in in Africa, the whatchamacallit desert there. But the
whatchamacallit desert there. But the
whatchamacallit desert there. But the Mircats are very interesting, you know,
Mircats are very interesting, you know,
Mircats are very interesting, you know, because they have a a very neat way of
because they have a a very neat way of
because they have a a very neat way of being and each one has sort of an
being and each one has sort of an
being and each one has sort of an assigned function, but they hang
assigned function, but they hang
assigned function, but they hang together as as a group.
together as as a group.
together as as a group. So, there's one Mircat uh culture and
So, there's one Mircat uh culture and
So, there's one Mircat uh culture and then there's a rival Mircat culture that
then there's a rival Mircat culture that
then there's a rival Mircat culture that lives across the field, across the
lives across the field, across the
lives across the field, across the desert, across the woods. And these
desert, across the woods. And these
desert, across the woods. And these mircats are constantly in rivalry trying
mircats are constantly in rivalry trying
mircats are constantly in rivalry trying to grab the other one's territory.
to grab the other one's territory.
to grab the other one's territory. And they can't survive without a nice
And they can't survive without a nice
And they can't survive without a nice safe place for their little baby baby
safe place for their little baby baby
safe place for their little baby baby mircats. So, anyway, they have to defend
mircats. So, anyway, they have to defend
mircats. So, anyway, they have to defend their territory.
their territory.
their territory. And uh so they posted one guy to be on
And uh so they posted one guy to be on
And uh so they posted one guy to be on guard. These mircats were off here.
guard. These mircats were off here.
guard. These mircats were off here. These were off here. And this guy was
These were off here. And this guy was
These were off here. And this guy was supposed to be on guard, but he was
supposed to be on guard, but he was
supposed to be on guard, but he was lazy. He left his post. Left his post.
lazy. He left his post. Left his post.
lazy. He left his post. Left his post. And then the other mircats came in and
And then the other mircats came in and
And then the other mircats came in and started grabbing his these ter their
started grabbing his these ter their
started grabbing his these ter their territory.
territory.
territory. So there you see humankind,
So there you see humankind,
So there you see humankind, current civilization.
current civilization.
current civilization. You know, you could call one of the
You know, you could call one of the
You know, you could call one of the clans of Mirkat's
clans of Mirkat's
clans of Mirkat's uh what are they call them in in Iraq?
uh what are they call them in in Iraq?
uh what are they call them in in Iraq? The Winnies and the Wooies or what are
The Winnies and the Wooies or what are
The Winnies and the Wooies or what are the two?
the two?
the two? >> What are they?
>> What are they?
>> What are they? Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. >> Oh, the Shiites and the Shuites. The
>> Oh, the Shiites and the Shuites. The
>> Oh, the Shiites and the Shuites. The Shiites and the
Shiites and the
Shiites and the Anyway,
Anyway,
Anyway, uh so you see the recapitulation
uh so you see the recapitulation
uh so you see the recapitulation uh and current neuroscience thinks that
uh and current neuroscience thinks that
uh and current neuroscience thinks that morality is hired hardwired into the
morality is hired hardwired into the
morality is hired hardwired into the anatomy and physiology of the nervous
anatomy and physiology of the nervous
anatomy and physiology of the nervous system. You can't find any place out
system. You can't find any place out
system. You can't find any place out there any in the human I mean in the
there any in the human I mean in the
there any in the human I mean in the animal kingdom that morality doesn't
animal kingdom that morality doesn't
animal kingdom that morality doesn't apply. You certainly see it in the wolf
apply. You certainly see it in the wolf
apply. You certainly see it in the wolf pack. You see the struggle for the alpha
pack. You see the struggle for the alpha
pack. You see the struggle for the alpha male, the alpha female, the struggle for
male, the alpha female, the struggle for
male, the alpha female, the struggle for dominance and he hegemony.
So there's certain philosophers who
So there's certain philosophers who don't calibrate very high uh would like
don't calibrate very high uh would like
don't calibrate very high uh would like to try to condem condemn condemn it.
to try to condem condemn condemn it.
to try to condem condemn condemn it. It's a basic law of life throughout
It's a basic law of life throughout
It's a basic law of life throughout nature. One uh tends to dominate the
nature. One uh tends to dominate the
nature. One uh tends to dominate the other. Uh the strongest country will
other. Uh the strongest country will
other. Uh the strongest country will dominate as far as it can dominate. Why?
dominate as far as it can dominate. Why?
dominate as far as it can dominate. Why? Because that's the nature of life
Because that's the nature of life
Because that's the nature of life itself. So somehow survival and
itself. So somehow survival and
itself. So somehow survival and morality, right and wrong, are like
morality, right and wrong, are like
morality, right and wrong, are like inborn, wired into the uh nervous
inborn, wired into the uh nervous
inborn, wired into the uh nervous system, right versus wrong.
system, right versus wrong.
system, right versus wrong. And a society that tries to reverse
And a society that tries to reverse
And a society that tries to reverse right versus wrong will go through a
right versus wrong will go through a
right versus wrong will go through a period of great confusion and collapse
period of great confusion and collapse
period of great confusion and collapse because now it's trying to change uh the
because now it's trying to change uh the
because now it's trying to change uh the identifications of right and wrong. And
identifications of right and wrong. And
identifications of right and wrong. And we see that in today's world. What was
we see that in today's world. What was
we see that in today's world. What was right in 1950 is now old hat. Old hat.
right in 1950 is now old hat. Old hat.
right in 1950 is now old hat. Old hat. Uh it's no longer necessary to tell the
Uh it's no longer necessary to tell the
Uh it's no longer necessary to tell the truth.
truth.
truth. no longer necessary to tell the truth.
no longer necessary to tell the truth.
no longer necessary to tell the truth. The only thing is important is don't get
The only thing is important is don't get
The only thing is important is don't get caught in the lie.
Right versus wrong then is hardwired
Right versus wrong then is hardwired into
into
into uh human and animal life. And the birth
uh human and animal life. And the birth
uh human and animal life. And the birth of morality, you would have to say it's
of morality, you would have to say it's
of morality, you would have to say it's somewhere back back in history many
somewhere back back in history many
somewhere back back in history many millions of years. many millions of
millions of years. many millions of
millions of years. many millions of years ago.
Those organisms that live at the bottom
Those organisms that live at the bottom of the sea,
of the sea,
of the sea, it guards its it guards its place there.
it guards its it guards its place there.
it guards its it guards its place there. God help any other scuttlefish that
God help any other scuttlefish that
God help any other scuttlefish that tries to get in there
because I'm squirting with black ink.
because I'm squirting with black ink. Get away. Jason White. So you see
Get away. Jason White. So you see
Get away. Jason White. So you see the morality is on a certain level uh
the morality is on a certain level uh
the morality is on a certain level uh primitive and a certain level primitive
primitive and a certain level primitive
primitive and a certain level primitive at its highest level of very advanced uh
at its highest level of very advanced uh
at its highest level of very advanced uh spiritual understanding.
spiritual understanding.
spiritual understanding. All right versus wrong and the birth of
All right versus wrong and the birth of
All right versus wrong and the birth of morality is intrinsic within the animal
morality is intrinsic within the animal
morality is intrinsic within the animal kingdom. Now all the definitions of
kingdom. Now all the definitions of
kingdom. Now all the definitions of these things what's real, what's not
these things what's real, what's not
these things what's real, what's not real, what's right, what's wrong, uh
real, what's right, what's wrong, uh
real, what's right, what's wrong, uh changes. So, not only is it constantly
changes. So, not only is it constantly
changes. So, not only is it constantly changing, it changes with the decade, it
changing, it changes with the decade, it
changing, it changes with the decade, it changes with the media, but it changes
changes with the media, but it changes
changes with the media, but it changes throughout life. What's right and wrong
throughout life. What's right and wrong
throughout life. What's right and wrong in infancy now won't do that in
in infancy now won't do that in
in infancy now won't do that in childhood, which again won't do that in
childhood, which again won't do that in
childhood, which again won't do that in adolescence, which won't do that in
adolescence, which won't do that in
adolescence, which won't do that in adulthood,
adulthood,
adulthood, which is no longer appropriate in middle
which is no longer appropriate in middle
which is no longer appropriate in middle age and no longer appropriate in old
age and no longer appropriate in old
age and no longer appropriate in old age. So,
age. So,
age. So, a person here who imitates this kind of
a person here who imitates this kind of
a person here who imitates this kind of behavior or these values would look
behavior or these values would look
behavior or these values would look idiotic. So you're expected to not only
idiotic. So you're expected to not only
idiotic. So you're expected to not only master all these things, you're supposed
master all these things, you're supposed
master all these things, you're supposed to show an evolution of your
to show an evolution of your
to show an evolution of your comprehension and your behaviors to
comprehension and your behaviors to
comprehension and your behaviors to reflect this. And this of course is
reflect this. And this of course is
reflect this. And this of course is where education education is supposed to
where education education is supposed to
where education education is supposed to be of great help.
be of great help.
be of great help. Uh
Uh
Uh how to be daughtering and not let it
how to be daughtering and not let it
how to be daughtering and not let it bother you. how to not complain about
bother you. how to not complain about
bother you. how to not complain about it.
it.
it. All of these things now change depending
All of these things now change depending
All of these things now change depending on the state of sickness or health.
on the state of sickness or health.
on the state of sickness or health. Sickness or health, you automatically
Sickness or health, you automatically
Sickness or health, you automatically can excuse a lot of these roles because
can excuse a lot of these roles because
can excuse a lot of these roles because you're sick. Therefore, these duties,
you're sick. Therefore, these duties,
you're sick. Therefore, these duties, these obligations, right versus wrong,
these obligations, right versus wrong,
these obligations, right versus wrong, suddenly changes its definition.
suddenly changes its definition.
suddenly changes its definition. Common agreement on all of these things
Common agreement on all of these things
Common agreement on all of these things brings about social accord and enables
brings about social accord and enables
brings about social accord and enables governance. Without agreement, there's
governance. Without agreement, there's
governance. Without agreement, there's difficulty if not impossibility of
difficulty if not impossibility of
difficulty if not impossibility of governance.
governance.
governance. And what changes the whole picture once
And what changes the whole picture once
And what changes the whole picture once you think you've got this all down pat
you think you've got this all down pat
you think you've got this all down pat uh then comes politicalization.
uh then comes politicalization.
uh then comes politicalization. So all the definitions of right and
So all the definitions of right and
So all the definitions of right and wrong uh what's moral what's appropriate
wrong uh what's moral what's appropriate
wrong uh what's moral what's appropriate uh the answer to all the things of life
uh the answer to all the things of life
uh the answer to all the things of life are now re-edited. So politicalization
are now re-edited. So politicalization
are now re-edited. So politicalization is a way of constantly re-editing
is a way of constantly re-editing
is a way of constantly re-editing everything.
everything.
everything. And in our today's world everything
And in our today's world everything
And in our today's world everything there's a blue uh light or there's a red
there's a blue uh light or there's a red
there's a blue uh light or there's a red light I guess. and everything that
light I guess. and everything that
light I guess. and everything that exists, you can shine a blue light or a
exists, you can shine a blue light or a
exists, you can shine a blue light or a red light. And that says whether you're
red light. And that says whether you're
red light. And that says whether you're right or left. Politicalization.
right or left. Politicalization.
right or left. Politicalization. So right and wrong is now politicalized.
So right and wrong is now politicalized.
So right and wrong is now politicalized. So that all these definitions of what's
So that all these definitions of what's
So that all these definitions of what's real, what's valuable, what's
real, what's valuable, what's
real, what's valuable, what's worthwhile,
worthwhile,
worthwhile, uh what's moral now can be completely
uh what's moral now can be completely
uh what's moral now can be completely redefined by politicalization.
redefined by politicalization.
redefined by politicalization. uh what's popularized uh what goes now
uh what's popularized uh what goes now
uh what's popularized uh what goes now depends on
depends on
depends on um bloggerism more than anything. So we
um bloggerism more than anything. So we
um bloggerism more than anything. So we used to have God, now we got bloggers.
used to have God, now we got bloggers.
used to have God, now we got bloggers. We used to worry about pleasing God. Now
We used to worry about pleasing God. Now
We used to worry about pleasing God. Now we worry that we might offend some
we worry that we might offend some
we worry that we might offend some bloggers.
bloggers.
bloggers. So whole political parties go to a
So whole political parties go to a
So whole political parties go to a convention and something they don't
convention and something they don't
convention and something they don't really believe in because they're scared
really believe in because they're scared
really believe in because they're scared to that that the bloggers will be after
to that that the bloggers will be after
to that that the bloggers will be after them. So we have a manipulation via the
them. So we have a manipulation via the
them. So we have a manipulation via the fear of hate. Hatred is a new
fear of hate. Hatred is a new
fear of hate. Hatred is a new manipulative tool. Uh not just fear of
manipulative tool. Uh not just fear of
manipulative tool. Uh not just fear of destruction but hatred itself. So by
destruction but hatred itself. So by
destruction but hatred itself. So by threatening or utilizing the tools of of
threatening or utilizing the tools of of
threatening or utilizing the tools of of hatred now everything has become
hatred now everything has become
hatred now everything has become politicalized.
politicalized.
politicalized. The language, the words, every
The language, the words, every
The language, the words, every inflection and gesture now becomes
inflection and gesture now becomes
inflection and gesture now becomes politicalized.
And you have to be careful how you
And you have to be careful how you phrase things because you use one wrong
phrase things because you use one wrong
phrase things because you use one wrong word and there you've just had it.
word and there you've just had it.
word and there you've just had it. So we have the we have the dictatorship
So we have the we have the dictatorship
So we have the we have the dictatorship now by bloggerized hatred.
now by bloggerized hatred.
now by bloggerized hatred. We used to be afraid of the Nazi
We used to be afraid of the Nazi
We used to be afraid of the Nazi totalitarian the Japanese imperialism.
totalitarian the Japanese imperialism.
totalitarian the Japanese imperialism. Now what everybody's afraid of is uh
Now what everybody's afraid of is uh
Now what everybody's afraid of is uh negative hate logerism.
which have replaced the world's
which have replaced the world's religions, haven't they? It's how you're
religions, haven't they? It's how you're
religions, haven't they? It's how you're obligized. Yeah. The impact of the
obligized. Yeah. The impact of the
obligized. Yeah. The impact of the world's religions, of course, we've gone
world's religions, of course, we've gone
world's religions, of course, we've gone through extensively in previous lectures
through extensively in previous lectures
through extensively in previous lectures and they are still extremely dominant.
and they are still extremely dominant.
and they are still extremely dominant. They are also dominant also by negation.
They are also dominant also by negation.
They are also dominant also by negation. The fact you don't believe in any of the
The fact you don't believe in any of the
The fact you don't believe in any of the world's great religions now become
world's great religions now become
world's great religions now become secularism.
secularism.
secularism. And so we have instead of world
And so we have instead of world
And so we have instead of world religions we have world non-religion
religions we have world non-religion
religions we have world non-religion but it's either the presence or absence
but it's either the presence or absence
but it's either the presence or absence of religion that signifies a change of
of religion that signifies a change of
of religion that signifies a change of life.
life.
life. As we said all the levels above 200 in
As we said all the levels above 200 in
As we said all the levels above 200 in fact enlightenment itself can be reached
fact enlightenment itself can be reached
fact enlightenment itself can be reached by following the sermon on the mount.
by following the sermon on the mount.
by following the sermon on the mount. The sermon on the mount is actually a
The sermon on the mount is actually a
The sermon on the mount is actually a political statement and uh there's a new
political statement and uh there's a new
political statement and uh there's a new book out called the political teachings
book out called the political teachings
book out called the political teachings of Jesus.
of Jesus.
of Jesus. Political teachings of Jesus and what it
Political teachings of Jesus and what it
Political teachings of Jesus and what it really amounts to is the sermon on the
really amounts to is the sermon on the
really amounts to is the sermon on the mount and its social applications.
mount and its social applications.
mount and its social applications. Social applications significance and
Social applications significance and
Social applications significance and meaning of the sermon on the mount. So
meaning of the sermon on the mount. So
meaning of the sermon on the mount. So all a person has to do then if you want
all a person has to do then if you want
all a person has to do then if you want to end up in a good place at the end of
to end up in a good place at the end of
to end up in a good place at the end of this whole trip is uh study the sermon
this whole trip is uh study the sermon
this whole trip is uh study the sermon on the mount apply it in your daily life
on the mount apply it in your daily life
on the mount apply it in your daily life uh follow the ten commandments and avoid
uh follow the ten commandments and avoid
uh follow the ten commandments and avoid the 10 greatly is it 10 deadly sins
the 10 greatly is it 10 deadly sins
the 10 greatly is it 10 deadly sins seven
seven
seven they didn't jump it on me did they
they didn't jump it on me did they
they didn't jump it on me did they think I hope there's only seven anyway
think I hope there's only seven anyway
think I hope there's only seven anyway you keep the ten commandments and avoid
you keep the ten commandments and avoid
you keep the ten commandments and avoid the seven deaths they sense and uh the
the seven deaths they sense and uh the
the seven deaths they sense and uh the sermon on the mount pretty much covers
sermon on the mount pretty much covers
sermon on the mount pretty much covers it for everyone including Buddhists and
it for everyone including Buddhists and
it for everyone including Buddhists and uh anybody else who is spiritual. It was
uh anybody else who is spiritual. It was
uh anybody else who is spiritual. It was Christ that said it but uh to love your
Christ that said it but uh to love your
Christ that said it but uh to love your fellow man as yourself to serve become
fellow man as yourself to serve become
fellow man as yourself to serve become the greatest that you can become to
the greatest that you can become to
the greatest that you can become to serve your fellow man and God is all
serve your fellow man and God is all
serve your fellow man and God is all that one anyone can do. Huh? As you
that one anyone can do. Huh? As you
that one anyone can do. Huh? As you understand God.
understand God.
understand God. So the huge impact of the world
So the huge impact of the world
So the huge impact of the world religions we could spend the whole rest
religions we could spend the whole rest
religions we could spend the whole rest of the year talking about and uh each
of the year talking about and uh each
of the year talking about and uh each one of them has a a fascinating history.
one of them has a a fascinating history.
one of them has a a fascinating history. Then you have uh the divisive this is
Then you have uh the divisive this is
Then you have uh the divisive this is supposed to be divisive divisiveness of
supposed to be divisive divisiveness of
supposed to be divisive divisiveness of races, colors and nationalities to make
races, colors and nationalities to make
races, colors and nationalities to make this all complex. All this applies in
this all complex. All this applies in
this all complex. All this applies in very different ways depending on your
very different ways depending on your
very different ways depending on your nationality,
nationality,
nationality, uh the color of your skin. They forgot
uh the color of your skin. They forgot
uh the color of your skin. They forgot your sexual orientation
your sexual orientation
your sexual orientation uh uh and gender. So all of this has to
uh uh and gender. So all of this has to
uh uh and gender. So all of this has to be completely changed if you change
be completely changed if you change
be completely changed if you change gender. Uhhuh.
gender. Uhhuh.
gender. Uhhuh. And
the education and the IQ add another
the education and the IQ add another layer. You can see how complex trying to
layer. You can see how complex trying to
layer. You can see how complex trying to understand human behavior is now. We're
understand human behavior is now. We're
understand human behavior is now. We're piling mirrors upon mirrors upon
piling mirrors upon mirrors upon
piling mirrors upon mirrors upon mirrors. all the original questions of
mirrors. all the original questions of
mirrors. all the original questions of all the underlying reality
all the underlying reality
all the underlying reality uh the politicalizations then uh and of
uh the politicalizations then uh and of
uh the politicalizations then uh and of course you're impacted by the profound
course you're impacted by the profound
course you're impacted by the profound influence of all the world's religions
influence of all the world's religions
influence of all the world's religions you can hardly underestimate uh I don't
you can hardly underestimate uh I don't
you can hardly underestimate uh I don't know what a secular person does in this
know what a secular person does in this
know what a secular person does in this world uh in the United States of America
world uh in the United States of America
world uh in the United States of America seeing as the entire constitution bill
seeing as the entire constitution bill
seeing as the entire constitution bill of rights and every uh the rule of law
of rights and every uh the rule of law
of rights and every uh the rule of law is based on a world religion
is based on a world religion
is based on a world religion Uh so then you get internal conflict
Uh so then you get internal conflict
Uh so then you get internal conflict over who's going to have uh the the say
over who's going to have uh the the say
over who's going to have uh the the say so. So here's the power struggle which
so. So here's the power struggle which
so. So here's the power struggle which you see throughout the animal kingdom.
you see throughout the animal kingdom.
you see throughout the animal kingdom. So politicalization then is a
So politicalization then is a
So politicalization then is a sophisticated way of seeing the animal
sophisticated way of seeing the animal
sophisticated way of seeing the animal conflict that goes on between the
conflict that goes on between the
conflict that goes on between the mircats.
mircats.
mircats. So, I'm trying to help everybody out
So, I'm trying to help everybody out
So, I'm trying to help everybody out so you won't get mad anymore or upset
so you won't get mad anymore or upset
so you won't get mad anymore or upset about politics. I just want you to
about politics. I just want you to
about politics. I just want you to realize they're all mircats.
realize they're all mircats.
realize they're all mircats. And the minute somebody says something
And the minute somebody says something
And the minute somebody says something you don't agree with, you just go,
"What's Lady Clinton's first name?
"What's Lady Clinton's first name? What's her name?"
What's her name?"
What's her name?" >> Hillary. Hillary. Hillary Clinton.
Then there's boom bomb bama. Boom bum
Then there's boom bomb bama. Boom bum bama.
Hillary doesn't know you know what from
Hillary doesn't know you know what from hot rock.
hot rock.
hot rock. Obama's just wet behind the ears.
I think on Wikipedia Bush has more pages
I think on Wikipedia Bush has more pages than anybody in history.
than anybody in history.
than anybody in history. That whole volume
That whole volume
That whole volume bushes him. Oh god, how will the world
bushes him. Oh god, how will the world
bushes him. Oh god, how will the world recover? I don't know who we're going to
recover? I don't know who we're going to
recover? I don't know who we're going to beat on without him. Good old Bush
beat on without him. Good old Bush
beat on without him. Good old Bush Bushy.
Bushy.
Bushy. I mean, without Bush to beat on, who can
I mean, without Bush to beat on, who can
I mean, without Bush to beat on, who can who can we beat on? You know, you can't
who can we beat on? You know, you can't
who can we beat on? You know, you can't beat on a lady. You can't beat on
beat on a lady. You can't beat on
beat on a lady. You can't beat on Hillary. She's a woman. You can't beat
Hillary. She's a woman. You can't beat
Hillary. She's a woman. You can't beat on ladies.
on ladies.
on ladies. And Obama's dark skinned. You can't beat
And Obama's dark skinned. You can't beat
And Obama's dark skinned. You can't beat on him either.
on him either.
on him either. Who the hell can you beat on anymore?
Uh, so we have racism and sexism. Yeah.
Uh, so we have racism and sexism. Yeah. On top of this called the problem of
On top of this called the problem of
On top of this called the problem of races and colors and nationalities.
races and colors and nationalities.
races and colors and nationalities. Races and colors and nationalities.
Races and colors and nationalities.
Races and colors and nationalities. Uh I was
Uh I was
Uh I was full full grown adult before I realized
full full grown adult before I realized
full full grown adult before I realized that there was uh prejudice against
that there was uh prejudice against
that there was uh prejudice against color people. The world I grew up in uh
color people. The world I grew up in uh
color people. The world I grew up in uh there was no such thing. They were just
there was no such thing. They were just
there was no such thing. They were just people like everybody friends. Nobody
people like everybody friends. Nobody
people like everybody friends. Nobody segmented them. But
segmented them. But
segmented them. But uh according to race and color,
uh according to race and color,
uh according to race and color, nationality, there's a great deal of
nationality, there's a great deal of
nationality, there's a great deal of segmentation
segmentation
segmentation uh in many parts of the country.
uh in many parts of the country.
uh in many parts of the country. We always like diversity and the reason
We always like diversity and the reason
We always like diversity and the reason is we didn't call it diversity.
is we didn't call it diversity.
is we didn't call it diversity. The Polish guys told funny Polish jokes.
The Polish guys told funny Polish jokes.
The Polish guys told funny Polish jokes. The Jewish people told funny Jewish
The Jewish people told funny Jewish
The Jewish people told funny Jewish jokes. And you wouldn't want to be
jokes. And you wouldn't want to be
jokes. And you wouldn't want to be without any of them. The Jewish people
without any of them. The Jewish people
without any of them. The Jewish people went away. Where would you hear good
went away. Where would you hear good
went away. Where would you hear good Jewish jokes? What's that short guy with
Jewish jokes? What's that short guy with
Jewish jokes? What's that short guy with a heavy Jewish accent? He's so funny.
a heavy Jewish accent? He's so funny.
a heavy Jewish accent? He's so funny. Anyway, who would make such? So anyway,
Anyway, who would make such? So anyway,
Anyway, who would make such? So anyway, we never saw it as a negative. It was
we never saw it as a negative. It was
we never saw it as a negative. It was only in the big city.
only in the big city.
only in the big city. Uh the social strata now changes all of
Uh the social strata now changes all of
Uh the social strata now changes all of this. You have to change each time we
this. You have to change each time we
this. You have to change each time we mention a new factor you've got to
mention a new factor you've got to
mention a new factor you've got to change the color of the whole screen. Uh
change the color of the whole screen. Uh
change the color of the whole screen. Uh so social social strata will change all
so social social strata will change all
so social social strata will change all of this.
of this.
of this. What's appropriate at one level in
What's appropriate at one level in
What's appropriate at one level in social society is gross and
social society is gross and
social society is gross and inappropriate and vulgar at another.
inappropriate and vulgar at another.
inappropriate and vulgar at another. Huh.
Huh.
Huh. Elvis Presley was vulgar.
Elvis Presley was vulgar.
Elvis Presley was vulgar. Anyway, so social strata people don't
Anyway, so social strata people don't
Anyway, so social strata people don't like to think in terms of classes
like to think in terms of classes
like to think in terms of classes because it's not uh politically uh
because it's not uh politically uh
because it's not uh politically uh correct. But on the other hand, that's
correct. But on the other hand, that's
correct. But on the other hand, that's all they talk about is social classes
all they talk about is social classes
all they talk about is social classes and but they don't cause social classes.
and but they don't cause social classes.
and but they don't cause social classes. Uh all they're talk about in the
Uh all they're talk about in the
Uh all they're talk about in the so-called
so-called
so-called uh ultra liberals is social. All they're
uh ultra liberals is social. All they're
uh ultra liberals is social. All they're talking about all the time is social
talking about all the time is social
talking about all the time is social strata. How they're pictured, how
strata. How they're pictured, how
strata. How they're pictured, how they're viewed, how they're calibrated.
they're viewed, how they're calibrated.
they're viewed, how they're calibrated. All right? And all of this in again is
All right? And all of this in again is
All right? And all of this in again is influenced by education and not the
influenced by education and not the
influenced by education and not the least bit is also IQ. So IQ when I grew
least bit is also IQ. So IQ when I grew
least bit is also IQ. So IQ when I grew up was important. Uh this teacher always
up was important. Uh this teacher always
up was important. Uh this teacher always wanted to know it. The school
wanted to know it. The school
wanted to know it. The school psychologist because it had to do with
psychologist because it had to do with
psychologist because it had to do with vocational guidance. If your IQ was
vocational guidance. If your IQ was
vocational guidance. If your IQ was sufficient, you could make it in
sufficient, you could make it in
sufficient, you could make it in college. They guided you into an
college. They guided you into an
college. They guided you into an academic type of curriculum. if your IQ
academic type of curriculum. if your IQ
academic type of curriculum. if your IQ wasn't high enough that you would be a
wasn't high enough that you would be a
wasn't high enough that you would be a success in in college, they tried to
success in in college, they tried to
success in in college, they tried to steer you towards vocational. vocational
steer you towards vocational. vocational
steer you towards vocational. vocational um I don't think I don't know if that's
um I don't think I don't know if that's
um I don't think I don't know if that's done anymore but vocational meant that
done anymore but vocational meant that
done anymore but vocational meant that you didn't have to study all this
you didn't have to study all this
you didn't have to study all this academic stuff like the great books of
academic stuff like the great books of
academic stuff like the great books of the western world and memorize all that
the western world and memorize all that
the western world and memorize all that which is irrelevant which is relevant uh
which is irrelevant which is relevant uh
which is irrelevant which is relevant uh if you're working in a tool and die shop
if you're working in a tool and die shop
if you're working in a tool and die shop and machinist you know I found out the
and machinist you know I found out the
and machinist you know I found out the hard way machinists make a lot of money
hard way machinists make a lot of money
hard way machinists make a lot of money I had a couple of things made for a for
I had a couple of things made for a for
I had a couple of things made for a for a big water wheel. You know, they were
a big water wheel. You know, they were
a big water wheel. You know, they were 400. These bearings were $400 a piece. I
400. These bearings were $400 a piece. I
400. These bearings were $400 a piece. I said I said, "How much are they?" He
said I said, "How much are they?" He
said I said, "How much are they?" He said, "400." I thought he meant for the
said, "400." I thought he meant for the
said, "400." I thought he meant for the pair. He meant a piece. 4inch bearing
pair. He meant a piece. 4inch bearing
pair. He meant a piece. 4inch bearing $400 to have it made by a machinist. All
$400 to have it made by a machinist. All
$400 to have it made by a machinist. All right. And he made two of them. So,
right. And he made two of them. So,
right. And he made two of them. So, you're looking at $800. So uh therefore
you're looking at $800. So uh therefore
you're looking at $800. So uh therefore the voca the vocational the trade the
the voca the vocational the trade the
the voca the vocational the trade the trades uh to my mind are equal. When you
trades uh to my mind are equal. When you
trades uh to my mind are equal. When you need uh somebody to help you with the
need uh somebody to help you with the
need uh somebody to help you with the trades you need it bad. You can do
trades you need it bad. You can do
trades you need it bad. You can do without the the the thinker people. You
without the the the thinker people. You
without the the the thinker people. You can do without the thinker people. When
can do without the thinker people. When
can do without the thinker people. When you need it when the plumbing is shot
you need it when the plumbing is shot
you need it when the plumbing is shot man you I don't care whether he's got a
man you I don't care whether he's got a
man you I don't care whether he's got a graduate degree.
Can you fix the buddy thing
Can you fix the buddy thing right now on what channel is it? The
right now on what channel is it? The
right now on what channel is it? The History Channel. Anyway, there's ice
History Channel. Anyway, there's ice
History Channel. Anyway, there's ice truckers. Ice road truckers. Ice road
truckers. Ice road truckers. Ice road
truckers. Ice road truckers. Ice road truckers. A whole society up near north
truckers. A whole society up near north
truckers. A whole society up near north of Canada trucking these giant monster
of Canada trucking these giant monster
of Canada trucking these giant monster trucks. In the winter time, the lake
trucks. In the winter time, the lake
trucks. In the winter time, the lake freezes over and you can get up to the
freezes over and you can get up to the
freezes over and you can get up to the Arctic where the big diamond mines are.
Arctic where the big diamond mines are.
Arctic where the big diamond mines are. And so three months out of the year,
And so three months out of the year,
And so three months out of the year, these truckers come out and come from
these truckers come out and come from
these truckers come out and come from all over, drive these huge trucks and 24
all over, drive these huge trucks and 24
all over, drive these huge trucks and 24 in of ice. Not me, thank you. But they
in of ice. Not me, thank you. But they
in of ice. Not me, thank you. But they this monster truck had nothing but this
this monster truck had nothing but this
this monster truck had nothing but this much ice under him. And you can hear it
much ice under him. And you can hear it
much ice under him. And you can hear it cracking as he goes.
cracking as he goes.
cracking as he goes. But he makes $1,000 a trip. $1,000 a
But he makes $1,000 a trip. $1,000 a
But he makes $1,000 a trip. $1,000 a trip. So, uh, he had $1,000 a trip. I
trip. So, uh, he had $1,000 a trip. I
trip. So, uh, he had $1,000 a trip. I guess we won't joke about truckers
guess we won't joke about truckers
guess we won't joke about truckers anymore.
anymore.
anymore. I don't get $1,000 a trip. So, education
I don't get $1,000 a trip. So, education
I don't get $1,000 a trip. So, education and IQ then, but we tend to, you know,
and IQ then, but we tend to, you know,
and IQ then, but we tend to, you know, this has certain meanings to us. Uh, and
this has certain meanings to us. Uh, and
this has certain meanings to us. Uh, and the, you see, what we're talking about
the, you see, what we're talking about
the, you see, what we're talking about are values. All these things now, uh,
are values. All these things now, uh,
are values. All these things now, uh, not only exist in their own right, how
not only exist in their own right, how
not only exist in their own right, how there first there is a reality, then
there first there is a reality, then
there first there is a reality, then there's how they're viewed,
there's how they're viewed,
there's how they're viewed, but then you have the value of it. In
but then you have the value of it. In
but then you have the value of it. In some places, education is of course
some places, education is of course
some places, education is of course absolutely required.
absolutely required.
absolutely required. And a high IQ just happens to be a birth
And a high IQ just happens to be a birth
And a high IQ just happens to be a birth accident, a genetic accident. And people
accident, a genetic accident. And people
accident, a genetic accident. And people admire a high IQ, but it is a curse to
admire a high IQ, but it is a curse to
admire a high IQ, but it is a curse to those that are born with extremely high
those that are born with extremely high
those that are born with extremely high IQ. A lot of them have to go for
IQ. A lot of them have to go for
IQ. A lot of them have to go for therapy.
Next, one,
Next, one, they have to go for therapy because
they have to go for therapy because
they have to go for therapy because they're not well adjusted. Other people
they're not well adjusted. Other people
they're not well adjusted. Other people think in certain ways and they can't
think in certain ways and they can't
think in certain ways and they can't understand how they can think that way.
understand how they can think that way.
understand how they can think that way. How can they think that way? And how can
How can they think that way? And how can
How can they think that way? And how can they find that interesting? Going around
they find that interesting? Going around
they find that interesting? Going around and around in a circle with a little
and around in a circle with a little
and around in a circle with a little rubber ball. I mean,
rubber ball. I mean,
rubber ball. I mean, when you got a new interpretation of
when you got a new interpretation of
when you got a new interpretation of Plato sitting next to you to read, how
Plato sitting next to you to read, how
Plato sitting next to you to read, how could that be?
could that be?
could that be? Anyway, the human dilemma.
Anyway, the human dilemma.
Anyway, the human dilemma. So, we talk about all these variable
So, we talk about all these variable
So, we talk about all these variable factors. As you can see, they if you if
factors. As you can see, they if you if
factors. As you can see, they if you if you put them together and recombine
you put them together and recombine
you put them together and recombine them, we've already covered thousands of
them, we've already covered thousands of
them, we've already covered thousands of possibilities and variations on the
possibilities and variations on the
possibilities and variations on the human dilemma. Uh in the in the house of
human dilemma. Uh in the in the house of
human dilemma. Uh in the in the house of mirrors, you see we're constantly
mirrors, you see we're constantly
mirrors, you see we're constantly walking through everybody. Anybody who's
walking through everybody. Anybody who's
walking through everybody. Anybody who's been in a house of mirrors?
been in a house of mirrors?
been in a house of mirrors? Oh, that's okay. More common than I
Oh, that's okay. More common than I
Oh, that's okay. More common than I Yeah. Well, you can get lost in there
Yeah. Well, you can get lost in there
Yeah. Well, you can get lost in there and they have to come and find you.
They have to come and find you. Well,
They have to come and find you. Well, they can tell where you are because they
they can tell where you are because they
they can tell where you are because they got trackers now. Uh but it is of course
got trackers now. Uh but it is of course
got trackers now. Uh but it is of course constantly puzzling at every turn. So
constantly puzzling at every turn. So
constantly puzzling at every turn. So every turn uh then you begin to see
every turn uh then you begin to see
every turn uh then you begin to see things differently. Every turn you see
things differently. Every turn you see
things differently. Every turn you see where you are in relationship to
where you are in relationship to
where you are in relationship to everything else differently. You can see
everything else differently. You can see
everything else differently. You can see how complex human life is. Therefore, we
how complex human life is. Therefore, we
how complex human life is. Therefore, we honor human life because for any human
honor human life because for any human
honor human life because for any human being to walk on to me uh deserves
being to walk on to me uh deserves
being to walk on to me uh deserves admiration. It takes a a huge amount of
admiration. It takes a a huge amount of
admiration. It takes a a huge amount of will and devotion to life to just keep
will and devotion to life to just keep
will and devotion to life to just keep walking on with your head head up held
walking on with your head head up held
walking on with your head head up held high.
high.
high. The levels of consciousness as we know
The levels of consciousness as we know
The levels of consciousness as we know are karmic propensities. karmic
are karmic propensities. karmic
are karmic propensities. karmic propensities.
propensities.
propensities. Uh some of them are gifts of God and uh
Uh some of them are gifts of God and uh
Uh some of them are gifts of God and uh the purpose of human life is really the
the purpose of human life is really the
the purpose of human life is really the evolution of consciousness etc. And then
evolution of consciousness etc. And then
evolution of consciousness etc. And then the capacity for the adaptational stress
the capacity for the adaptational stress
the capacity for the adaptational stress to change is constant in our society.
to change is constant in our society.
to change is constant in our society. Nothing lasts very long. It's old hat.
Nothing lasts very long. It's old hat.
Nothing lasts very long. It's old hat. It's a pass. It's no longer in uh it's
It's a pass. It's no longer in uh it's
It's a pass. It's no longer in uh it's not even for sale anymore.
not even for sale anymore.
not even for sale anymore. adaptational stress to change is
adaptational stress to change is
adaptational stress to change is continuous. So we have to change with
continuous. So we have to change with
continuous. So we have to change with each uh additional factor
each uh additional factor
each uh additional factor with age you have to be as you age you
with age you have to be as you age you
with age you have to be as you age you have to constantly change your
have to constantly change your
have to constantly change your expectations of yourself and others uh
expectations of yourself and others uh
expectations of yourself and others uh your social roles. So you're constantly
your social roles. So you're constantly
your social roles. So you're constantly shifting your understanding of the
shifting your understanding of the
shifting your understanding of the interaction of this enormous complexity.
interaction of this enormous complexity.
interaction of this enormous complexity. Uh on top of that we have to on top of
Uh on top of that we have to on top of
Uh on top of that we have to on top of the stress of change uh we have
the stress of change uh we have
the stress of change uh we have different forms of government and they
different forms of government and they
different forms of government and they imply different kinds of accountability
imply different kinds of accountability
imply different kinds of accountability different forms of government and the
different forms of government and the
different forms of government and the constant argument over which is the best
constant argument over which is the best
constant argument over which is the best form of government and how to define
form of government and how to define
form of government and how to define that government as it's defined in the
that government as it's defined in the
that government as it's defined in the Senate and the in the the ruling uh
Senate and the in the the ruling uh
Senate and the in the the ruling uh departments of our country. uh that is a
departments of our country. uh that is a
departments of our country. uh that is a constant form of conflict. Every news
constant form of conflict. Every news
constant form of conflict. Every news every night reflects some different some
every night reflects some different some
every night reflects some different some conflict uh having to do with government
conflict uh having to do with government
conflict uh having to do with government agencies. Of course, right now
agencies. Of course, right now
agencies. Of course, right now immigration and legality of immigration
immigration and legality of immigration
immigration and legality of immigration and all that. Uh in the end however we
and all that. Uh in the end however we
and all that. Uh in the end however we know that we are accountable. So
know that we are accountable. So
know that we are accountable. So spiritual responsibility
spiritual responsibility
spiritual responsibility begins with the realization that you are
begins with the realization that you are
begins with the realization that you are accountable.
accountable.
accountable. A person who will not accept personal
A person who will not accept personal
A person who will not accept personal accountability
accountability
accountability then is why they calibrate extremely
then is why they calibrate extremely
then is why they calibrate extremely low. It's why it's why atheists cannot
low. It's why it's why atheists cannot
low. It's why it's why atheists cannot do uh the muscle test for truth.
do uh the muscle test for truth.
do uh the muscle test for truth. There's a famous professor that knocks
There's a famous professor that knocks
There's a famous professor that knocks it and said it doesn't work. And I
it and said it doesn't work. And I
it and said it doesn't work. And I thought how come he's such a famous
thought how come he's such a famous
thought how come he's such a famous professor and so and then I found out he
professor and so and then I found out he
professor and so and then I found out he calibrates 195. He's a basically an
calibrates 195. He's a basically an
calibrates 195. He's a basically an atheist. So if you deny the reality of
atheist. So if you deny the reality of
atheist. So if you deny the reality of truth, then you're not allowed to
truth, then you're not allowed to
truth, then you're not allowed to benefit uh from truth. You can't benefit
benefit uh from truth. You can't benefit
benefit uh from truth. You can't benefit from that which you deny that which you
from that which you deny that which you
from that which you deny that which you especially that which you denounce.
especially that which you denounce.
especially that which you denounce. So if you denounce divinity which is the
So if you denounce divinity which is the
So if you denounce divinity which is the ultimate source of truth. All right? So
ultimate source of truth. All right? So
ultimate source of truth. All right? So if you look at life you can see we have
if you look at life you can see we have
if you look at life you can see we have endless thousands and thousands of
endless thousands and thousands of
endless thousands and thousands of decisions uh from second to second.
decisions uh from second to second.
decisions uh from second to second. Now every every branch in the tree you
Now every every branch in the tree you
Now every every branch in the tree you can choose
can choose
can choose uh every every
uh every every
uh every every decision you make every second and you
decision you make every second and you
decision you make every second and you have to make them continuously. You can
have to make them continuously. You can
have to make them continuously. You can either go in this direction you come to
either go in this direction you come to
either go in this direction you come to a Y in the road uh till I have an apple
a Y in the road uh till I have an apple
a Y in the road uh till I have an apple or not have an apple. Yes or no? If I
or not have an apple. Yes or no? If I
or not have an apple. Yes or no? If I have an apple I might get so and so so
have an apple I might get so and so so
have an apple I might get so and so so each one leads to another one. All
each one leads to another one. All
each one leads to another one. All right.
right.
right. If you start out in the middle of
If you start out in the middle of
If you start out in the middle of ignorance
ignorance
ignorance asking questions, but every time you
asking questions, but every time you
asking questions, but every time you come to a Y in the road, let's say we
come to a Y in the road, let's say we
come to a Y in the road, let's say we calibrate every decision you have to
calibrate every decision you have to
calibrate every decision you have to make. You know, I need more gas in the
make. You know, I need more gas in the
make. You know, I need more gas in the car. Yes. No. If we calibrate every
car. Yes. No. If we calibrate every
car. Yes. No. If we calibrate every decision, if you always follow the yes
decision, if you always follow the yes
decision, if you always follow the yes answer, you will end up going up the
answer, you will end up going up the
answer, you will end up going up the tree this way. Yep. Shall I pay my
tree this way. Yep. Shall I pay my
tree this way. Yep. Shall I pay my income taxes on time? Should I try and
income taxes on time? Should I try and
income taxes on time? Should I try and screw the government? Uh no
screw the government? Uh no
screw the government? Uh no if you keep going if you keep choosing
if you keep going if you keep choosing
if you keep going if you keep choosing the yes the higher consciousness level
the yes the higher consciousness level
the yes the higher consciousness level you will end up in a completely
you will end up in a completely
you will end up in a completely different place than a person who always
different place than a person who always
different place than a person who always chooses the no. You can see that
chooses the no. You can see that
chooses the no. You can see that following truth will take you ultimately
following truth will take you ultimately
following truth will take you ultimately to God.
to God.
to God. If you do nothing but know how to
If you do nothing but know how to
If you do nothing but know how to discern truth and falsehood and follow
discern truth and falsehood and follow
discern truth and falsehood and follow the answer that's true every time, you
the answer that's true every time, you
the answer that's true every time, you will automatically end up through the
will automatically end up through the
will automatically end up through the decision tree process which is
decision tree process which is
decision tree process which is continuous. You can't even choose
continuous. You can't even choose
continuous. You can't even choose whether to make decisions or not. You're
whether to make decisions or not. You're
whether to make decisions or not. You're not free to make that choice
not free to make that choice
not free to make that choice that you realize every second you have
that you realize every second you have
that you realize every second you have to make a decision. Every second, this
to make a decision. Every second, this
to make a decision. Every second, this very second, shall I listen to what he's
very second, shall I listen to what he's
very second, shall I listen to what he's saying? Shall I try to understand it?
saying? Shall I try to understand it?
saying? Shall I try to understand it? Screw it. How it's not all crazy. It's
Screw it. How it's not all crazy. It's
Screw it. How it's not all crazy. It's too complex for me. I mean, life is
too complex for me. I mean, life is
too complex for me. I mean, life is simple. Why put all that stuff together?
simple. Why put all that stuff together?
simple. Why put all that stuff together? I got a reason not to even listen to
I got a reason not to even listen to
I got a reason not to even listen to myself.
myself.
myself. That's why don't bother.
I don't know what he's thinking. It's
I don't know what he's thinking. It's irrelevant. You know that which I am is
irrelevant. You know that which I am is
irrelevant. You know that which I am is what I am.
what I am.
what I am. So we just keep following
So we just keep following
So we just keep following truth to where truth will lead you. And
truth to where truth will lead you. And
truth to where truth will lead you. And if you keep doing this continually, if
if you keep doing this continually, if
if you keep doing this continually, if you keep following the levels of
you keep following the levels of
you keep following the levels of consciousness, if you choose choose love
consciousness, if you choose choose love
consciousness, if you choose choose love over hatred, if you choose humor over
over hatred, if you choose humor over
over hatred, if you choose humor over mourningful mourningfulness, etc., you
mourningful mourningfulness, etc., you
mourningful mourningfulness, etc., you will automatically end up with divinity.
will automatically end up with divinity.
will automatically end up with divinity. Automatic. All roads lead to God. All
Automatic. All roads lead to God. All
Automatic. All roads lead to God. All roads lead to God. So long as you take
roads lead to God. So long as you take
roads lead to God. So long as you take the right fork.
the right fork.
the right fork. If you take the wrong fork, it leads
If you take the wrong fork, it leads
If you take the wrong fork, it leads elsewhere.
elsewhere.
elsewhere. I won't mention it where
places you don't want to be.
places you don't want to be. So truth in in other words is its own
So truth in in other words is its own
So truth in in other words is its own pathway to God. There are 10,000
pathway to God. There are 10,000
pathway to God. There are 10,000 pathways to God. I see. Love, service,
pathways to God. I see. Love, service,
pathways to God. I see. Love, service, karma, yoga, all the classic yogas, etc.
karma, yoga, all the classic yogas, etc.
karma, yoga, all the classic yogas, etc. The pathway of truth then is for maybe
The pathway of truth then is for maybe
The pathway of truth then is for maybe an intellectual person who just uh has
an intellectual person who just uh has
an intellectual person who just uh has to always have a word or description or
to always have a word or description or
to always have a word or description or definition can't just accept because
definition can't just accept because
definition can't just accept because they're not to the nonlinear domain yet
they're not to the nonlinear domain yet
they're not to the nonlinear domain yet where just lovingness would would be
where just lovingness would would be
where just lovingness would would be meaningful to them. They think your
meaningful to them. They think your
meaningful to them. They think your lovingness like how can you love such a
lovingness like how can you love such a
lovingness like how can you love such a sob like that? Huh?
sob like that? Huh?
sob like that? Huh? So lovingness won't work for a lot of
So lovingness won't work for a lot of
So lovingness won't work for a lot of people because the lovingness is in the
people because the lovingness is in the
people because the lovingness is in the 500s. person who is just getting into
500s. person who is just getting into
500s. person who is just getting into the spiritual levels is you know not up
the spiritual levels is you know not up
the spiritual levels is you know not up to 200 yet. So by constantly following
to 200 yet. So by constantly following
to 200 yet. So by constantly following that which calibrates high versus low
that which calibrates high versus low
that which calibrates high versus low following truth you will eventually end
following truth you will eventually end
following truth you will eventually end up at God like all roads lead to Rome.
up at God like all roads lead to Rome.
up at God like all roads lead to Rome. truth all roads lead to God uh to
truth all roads lead to God uh to
truth all roads lead to God uh to divinity
divinity
divinity and uh
and uh
and uh if it doesn't well
I guess it leads you to the other place.
I guess it leads you to the other place. So it's helpful then to recontextualize
So it's helpful then to recontextualize
So it's helpful then to recontextualize the world. We'll just take a break in a
the world. We'll just take a break in a
the world. We'll just take a break in a second. I want you to see everyone as a
second. I want you to see everyone as a
second. I want you to see everyone as a mircat.
>> Okay, Mircats, I'll see you after the
>> Okay, Mircats, I'll see you after the break.