Thank you.
Hi I have a question about self-healing.
>> About what?
>> Self-healing.
>> Huh?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh,
>> I've read or I've listened to your tapes
on self-healing and I've tried to follow
>> Get too close to the micro. Try being a
little farther.
>> Just try. Okay. Go ahead and try it
again.
>> Okay. I've listened to your CDs on
>> Okay.
>> self-healing. Yeah.
>> And I've tried to follow your advice and
I know that you used to have a lot of
illnesses that you canled the thought
form and you're now free of them.
And I want that for myself.
>> And what?
>> She wants herself. She wants to be free.
>> Oh, free of illnesses. Yeah.
>> So, I'm wondering if you can give me the
Cole's notes version of how to do that.
I I mean, in that I know there's a lot
to it and
it hasn't worked for me.
>> I'm not hearing her.
>> She's not having success.
>> What illness is
>> that's too big in general? Uh,
ulcerative colitis.
>> Huh?
>> Ulcer.
>> No, colitis.
>> Colitis.
>> Yeah. Okay. Have you done Have you done
acupuncture?
>> Some.
>> You did acupuncture for it?
>> Uh-huh.
>> And you do diet
and uh antis-pspasmotics.
>> Uh
steroids.
>> No, not steroids. Anispasmotics.
>> No, I haven't tried that.
>> The cure is anasmmonics.
uh meditation and um
I find acupuncture uh three treatments
cures the whole deal.
>> Wow. Okay. I guess just related to that,
do I need to get to the level of 500?
>> Too close to the mic again. I can't
hear.
>> You get you get feedback when you put
your mouth right on the mic, you know.
>> Do I need to get to the level of 540 to
be able to selfheal?
>> No, I didn't say that.
>> Okay.
>> See, there's karmic propensities for one
thing.
karmic propensities. Then there's uh or
uh organ language, you know, uh who's
the
lady who
metaphysical
healing.
What's her name? The lady who wrote the
famous book.
>> Lay.
>> Louise Haye. Right. Yeah. You're
familiar with her books, too. Yes. All
right. You're working on it. So the rest
of it takes time.
>> Okay.
>> Took me years to get over all those
things.
But it was diet and acids.
Uh not letting things and people get to
your guts. That's what you're doing now.
You're letting situations and people
tear at your guts.
So you got to detach and distance
yourself from them. Even if you have to
leave them
or you're going to let them rip their
guts out.
Okay.
>> So, who is it in your life that's
ripping your guts out?
>> No one. I think I'm just emotional
talking to you.
>> Yeah. It's wonderful to meet you.
>> Thank you.
>> Her life is easy. There isn't anybody
she's got to run away from.
>> Those things take time, you know.
>> Hi. My my question is quite
straightforward. Have you ever
calibrated the work of Nicholas Tesla?
>> Nicholas.
>> Tesla.
>> Tesla. Yeah.
>> Well, Tesla would be my guess would be
the high 400s.
>> All right. Tesla. I have permission to
do Tesla or 470. 475. Yeah, high 400s.
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> A genius.
>> Yes, I think so too.
>> Yes. Well, never mind. That's history.
Yeah, Tesla with Virginia.
>> Oh.
Um, one of the slides you had up
earlier, you mentioned that um,
herbivores are higher up on the scale of
consciousness.
>> Herbivores are higher
>> the scale of consciousness.
>> How does that relate?
>> No, they're generally more benign. You
don't hit the herbivores till you get
the 200s.
>> Okay. And humans, if they eat meat, does
it slow down? No.
Humans eating meat.
>> Yes. Is that detrimental to spiritual
advancement?
>> No, doesn't affect you one way or the
other.
>> Thank you.
>> Vegetarianism calibrates at 210.
>> Okay.
>> Great. Thank you very much. Thank you.
>> Jesus was vegetarian.
God gave man dominion over the animal
kingdom.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. I recently moved to
Sedona a few months ago, and since I've
been here, everything in my life has
changed.
>> Yes.
>> And um it seems like a lot of things are
going out of my life, like people
washing away and and I've left a job. So
my question to you is when you're in
that state and things have like your
decks have cleared but you don't see
what's coming next. Yes.
>> What is your guidance for swimming
through that time?
>> What is what
>> your what would you suggest as guidance
for swimming through that time when
>> things have fallen away?
>> Well, you hold in mind uh that which you
would be uh most pleased with.
Picture yourself as that and own that
in your in yourself
and then the opportunity will present
itself.
>> Okay.
>> What you hold in mind tends to manifest.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Like goes to like
Where these books keep coming from?
>> Hello.
>> I guess my question is a little bit
similar to one of the earlier questions
about transcending the intellect. Um I
think a search for a more synchronistic
purpose in life led me to contemplation
and intellectually trying to understand
life. Then intellect has become the the
biggest hurdle to
>> a big what?
>> A big the biggest hurdle to transcend.
Yeah.
>> Intellectualizing thinkingness.
>> That's cuz you're enamored and you're in
love with your own thinkingness.
>> Yeah. Probably.
>> Yeah.
>> And I've been trying to peel back the
layers of
self-imposed.
>> You tell yourself that what you think
about things is like opinions. You know
how much opinions are worth to me?
Hey,
>> what?
>> Nothing at all. Lovely.
>> Every idiot walking the street has an
opinion. The man in the street with the
microphone and what do you think about
the international situation? I mean, you
know what I'm saying? Had even read a
newspaper in three months and what's his
opinion?
Who cares what his opinion is? What you
want to know is what's the reality?
What's the facts? You know, what's the
reality of the situation? Yeah. Well,
what I'm really trying to get to is a
more intuitive
sense of connection to
>> Oh, that's different. Yes. Yes.
>> And getting beyond the intellect into
more of a heartfelt experience of life
rather than,
>> you know, you get more into the field.
>> Yeah.
>> Than the content of the field. That's
right.
>> So, it's trying to find the the key to
be able to get that more heartfelt
experience of life rather than an
intellectual. dedicate yourself to uh
appreciating and uh seeing the beauty of
nature
all of its expression. That's all you
got to do.
>> You don't need a complicated formula to
follow because you get lost in the
formula.
>> I think there's a beautiful shade of
green,
>> do you?
>> Sure. Well, not really. I haven't
noticed.
>> You're not very observant. Yeah, if you
get more obserant, you'll see the it's a
beautiful green.
>> Mhm.
>> And how this brown contrasts with it,
how that contrasts with their the bless
and then there's this cream color on the
top. So this you're aware of in in the
audience being here.
>> Mhm.
>> It one is aware of all that without ever
looking at it or thinking about it. You
just grasp the totality of the
situation. The totality.
>> Okay. look at totalities instead of
specifics,
>> the particulars.
>> But I guess we all come in with a karmic
uh
karmic issues to try and peel back and
address in as we evolve. So I mean
there's a number of layers I'm assuming
that you have to try and figure out as
you go through this lifetime to unravel
what's gone on before you have to worry
about it. presents itself.
>> So just deal with it as
>> address each issue as it arises.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> Yes.
Over
the last three or four years, it's feel
I've been on almost a quest to learn, to
grow spiritually, to evolve. I've been
through lots. I've been through all, you
know, all of your material, everything.
And I would in just that continuing
education and growing
I
would like to ask about the raw material
as challenged as challen channeled
through Carla Rukart if that is good
material to continue with
>> what uh what's the name again
>> the raw material
>> of who?
>> Uh the channeler Carla Rukart
>> I don't know Carla
>> the LL research group you don't you
don't know them. Okay, that's just in
the continuum. But I just this drive to
continue to keep growing now.
>> Investigative. You're in the
investigative phase. Yeah.
>> And it just seems like it's, you know, I
can't stop.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Once you get that spiritual drive,
you start reading through teachers,
reading works, visiting classes,
>> it's investigative. Yeah.
>> Yes.
Well, they did that now. Hey, that'll be
a dollar now.
>> Hi, Doc.
>> Okay.
>> Uh, hi Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes.
>> Um,
I didn't want to ask question, but it
just came to me. Uh the the per if
somebody wants to advance
spiritually
a real spiritual work
comparing
all spiritual advancement
on the world comparing with 12 step. Can
we calibrate that?
>> Calibrate what?
>> Uh
>> 12 steps.
>> No. Um
>> comp uh I mean so many people are asking
if we go here course in miracles
Buddhism
it doesn't matter where
uh the fastest progress
of spiritual progress is real in 12
steps I think available
>> is real in 12 12 steps he's finding the
fastest spiritual
>> oh yeah the 12 steps because it's around
one around the clock every day comparing
with all spiritual practices of the
whole world.
>> Oh yeah. Mhm.
>> You would say so?
>> I agree.
>> Thank you.
>> It has the biggest impact on our society
actually
>> because people don't just practice it on
Sunday morning. You have to be that way
seven days a week if you want to
survive.
>> Yeah.
>> Consequently, you practice the program
in all your affairs all day every day.
>> Not just compartmentalized.
>> Thank you for bringing me. That's right.
Influences our society. Unseen. Unseen.
>> Okay.
>> The effect is unseen.
Yes.
>> Um, would you be able to test for me
whether it's in the highest good for me
to move back to Chicago?
No way. All right, I'll ask another
question then.
Um,
in in AA, the sober alcoholic, you know,
they talk about dual diagnosis,
mental illness, and alcoholism. How do
you tell the difference? Because the
symptoms of untreated alcoholism, like
grandiosity, resentment are the same as
bipolar disorder.
>> Well, you become mental. You get crazy
from booze,
>> right?
>> Yeah. But when you get when you quit
drinking then the psychosis goes away.
If you have a bipolar disorder even
though you stop drinking the mental
illness does not go away. You have to
treat that in addition or otherwise.
>> Okay. Um because there's some people in
a who say that you're not sober if you
take medication because
>> and they don't know what they're talking
about.
Everything is physical, mental, and
spiritual.
So, who appointed them to be AA's pope?
>> All right.
Thank you.
>> If they're the pope of AA, I want to
meet them. You know,
I knew Bill Wilson and he wasn't a pope,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
No, everything is physical, mental, and
spiritual. And you treat each one in
accordance with that.
So if your doctor says you must take
medication, then who are you to say no?
That would be egotism. So out of
humility, uh you respect the
recommendation and you do what they tell
you.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. All right. Thank you. Uhhuh.
>> Dr. Hawkins, for the serious spiritual
student of enlightenment, how important
is it that he have a teacher who's
living on the earth today?
>> A teacher who's what?
>> Living on the earth today
>> in the flesh.
>> Someone who is very spiritually. Well,
to have encountered one in your in your
spiritual adventures is highly valuable
through many lifetimes.
>> Okay.
>> Yep.
>> Is it necessary for enlightenment to
have a teacher who's alive?
>> Actually, I think it is. Yeah. It's
necessary to have encountered a teacher
to reach the enlightened state. Resist.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> It lights up that energy fuel.
I didn't expect that answer.
>> Good afternoon, Dr. Hawkins. Thank you
for your life-changing work.
>> My question is, is there a correlation
between
calibration and IQ?
>> No.
>> So, we can have somebody who is at 95
and be very smart and dangerous.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
useful fools, Lennon called them.
Then there's the chess geniuses
who get into all kinds of trouble
politically and stuff,
make idiot political decisions.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Um, I have a question.
What is your inner state of experience
at this very moment and mundane every
day?
What' you say?
>> What's your inner state of experience
>> at this very moment?
>> As well as mundane every day
>> like as well as
mundane every day.
>> I know. I'm sure I understand what she
means.
>> Yeah. Can you be more specific?
>> What does she She's asking about my
subjective state or everyone's
subjective state. um your own experience
of experiencing this phenomena material
being in a body and what is your state
of consciousness that you're
experiencing
this everything at this very moment
being present in your body
>> it's too general to answer
how do I experience my own existence you
mean me personally
>> yes
>> oh I see
that that which speaks does So
autonomously
because that's a function of uh isness
and beingness
in this dimension at this time. You see
well about which you have nothing to say
which I have nothing to say.
Everything is happening autonomously and
spontaneously.
There is no personal eye that is the
originator of anything. You see it's
neither the giver nor the receiver nor
the controller.
The phenomena are all occurring
spontaneously. As you see, these flowers
are here spontaneously, are they not? Do
you see the flowers doing anything?
They're just they just are. They are
what they are. And as you can see, I am
a flower.
Pelotropism.
Oh.
Oh, I love the sun.
And now the sun is slowly setting
and slowly
fading away.
And so the helotropism
disappears.
Whoop.
That's helodopropism.
>> So the sun is you see the flower is
automatically attracted by the sun.
There isn't a personal cell. So that
says me flower me like a mu son me going
to follow you. It just is a consequence
of that which it is. It automatically
follows the sun. So when you're ready
for spiritual learning for instance that
which radiates the kind of a learning
that you wish to attain will begin to
attract the person. So it isn't there
there's no control no deciding no doing
you're attracted by that for which you
are ripe and ready you might say you
know
>> thank you so much. Um would you mind oh
okay thank you
>> tropism. I like that one.
They come out of the blue, you know.
Helot tropism just came out of the blue.
I didn't ask helotropism to come from
anywhere.
It just merges. Yeah.
Yeah. I was uh wondering
why you chose to use awareness and
consciousness as you do because for
decades I've used them in the opposite
way.
Uh what's this question?
>> He says how you chose to use awareness
and consciousness the way you do because
he says in for decades he's used them in
the opposite way.
>> What do you mean the opposite way?
>> I don't know. Ask him.
>> I don't get with the question. You tried
to stay unconscious. Is that what you're
saying?
>> No, I'm not saying that.
>> What are you saying?
Well, you you say the consciousness of
light and I would say the awareness of
light and you use the if you use the
words, they're just words, but they have
a vibration and an importance. I'm sure
you know. So, u the explanation would be
kind of long and I don't think that it's
appropriate. So, if you have no answer,
it's okay.
>> I don't understand your question.
>> It's all right. Don't worry about it.
You don't either. Okay. Okay.
>> Thanks.
>> Neither one of us understand.
>> Good evening, sir.
>> Hello.
Prior to lunch,
you were talking about bin Laden and you
were talking about United States and
Australia calibrating. I think it was
around 420 or so
and you showed um I think it one of the
countries in Africa at 40 and some other
ones at 180. My question is, and it
doesn't matter to me who the president
would be or the leader, Republican,
Democrat or whatever, but in that
position, you are charged with
protecting in this case the United
States.
And h my quandry after that
was
>> your quandry after what
>> after that portion of your discussion
was how as president for example of the
United States
>> well the bush
>> would you deal well I don't mean Bush or
just anybody
>> wait after what portion and I pointed
out various countries calibrate
different levels is that what you s oh
okay yes after that
>> so if you're dealing with someone at 40
or a leader such as bin laden at Yes.
>> Would be of low caliber. Oh, okay.
>> How as president of the United States or
prime minister of England or whatever
that would be charged with protecting
that nation's security,
would you be able to deal in a manner in
which for example bin Laden would
understand which I would presume would
require military force or something of
that nature without adversely affecting
the entire belief system of the nation.
that got you to the 430 in the first
place.
>> In other words, to go to war, you would
have to lower your calibration.
>> No, not necessarily.
How do how do you
>> integrate that requirement to protect
and perhaps use force and violence
with trying to maintain the uh belief
systems and the um calibration levels at
a seeking the higher level?
>> I don't understand the question. What
he's saying is
>> to defend yourself if you're attacked,
you're going to have to do things that
don't calibrate high, such as defend
yourself from death.
>> If if if
>> you're gonna have to defend yourself if
you're attacked. Is that correct?
>> Yes, sir. I would
>> that's part of your integrity. Part of
your integrity
is to hold sacred your own existence. Uh
to stand up for truth. All right. To
stand up for truth. Calibrates over 490
495. Stand up for truth is around 490 or
495, right? Louden probably calibrates
around, you know, 80 or something like
this. So who the reality of who you are
would respond appropriate to the
conditions
of what the other person is, if it's a
rattlesnake or not.
>> I've done several things with
rattlesnakes because the conditions were
different. I have carefully avoided
them. I've also inadvertently come into
contact with them. I've also
inadvertently gone into an incredible
spiritual state in your presence, you
know. So, it would depend on the
context, the timing, the sequencing,
you're asking too general a question.
>> Well, if the context required you to use
physical force for self-defense, whether
it's an individual or a na nation,
>> and you use that self-de self-defense,
you use violence, killed the
rattlesnake, whatever. Yeah,
>> then that doesn't you're just accepting
that that was the context and so that
doesn't impact on your calibration or
your your uh enlightenment level.
>> You're always going to I can't explain.
You're going you're always going to be
expressing that which you are in the
context of that incident. Yes, you're
you're level of consciousness is not
going to change. You may feel at one
level you may feel called upon to be a
pacifist and lie down and let them roll
over you and mush you. At another you
may feel uh you're you see it depends on
which of the archetypes you're coming
from out of the collective unconscious.
Jung's archetype will if you're coming
out of the spleen of the warrior
you're going to chop the son of a
into pieces and make him wish he'd never
bothered you. See? So
it depends on what your level is. If
you're a monk and you're trying to be
peaceful and and what and as the
airplanes come and bomb you, you just
bless the kamicazi pilots. So it all
depends on what your spiritual trip is
at that moment. It's appropriate to pray
for the kamicazi pilots. I myself see
their innocence. In fact, I see their
devotion to the emperor. I see their
devotion to God that they're willing to
sacrifice their life for the for the
emperor.
So it depends there. You can't make such
a generality. Everything is specific. In
this instance, in this context, when I'm
at this point of the evolution of my
spiritual development, this would be
appropriate. Depending on what lesson
I'm learning to to learn, a lot of
people confuse spirituality with
passivity.
Passivity is deadly.
Deadly.
The way to start a war is just lay down
and invite the aggressor to mangle you.
And you know what he does? He mangles
you.
>> Right. Right. That's exactly
>> including your wife and children and
wrecks your garden and everything.
>> It's hard to grow tomatoes in a
minefield. You know what I mean?
>> I don't know what the Iraqis eat for
God's sake. I mean, where do they do
farming? They're so busy blowing each
other up. I don't know how you even get
produce to market. You know what I mean?
>> All right. Thank you. If I may.
>> Yeah.
Oh, yes. Well, I didn't bring that up.
Yes. That that war is the opportunity to
own the warrior to to cross above the
level of integrity to be willing to
sacrifice your personal life for the
good and the welfare of all for honor
and country and wife and family and in
all is is the way out of cowardice and
bravery. The traditional way is through
the way of the warrior.
The way of the warrior. Yes.
You come out of fear and cowardice and
bravery. And even if it cost you your
life, you walk into the bullets for God
and country.
And then you've broken over the line
forever.
You never have to prove it again.
Once you break that line, you never have
to prove it again.
That's the sound of the bag pipes, is it
not?
me.
>> It's called Valor. V A L O R. Valor.
Yeah.
>> I just like to make the comment uh that
I appreciate your humor very much.
>> It certainly adds to the uh to the uh
the whole seminar. My question has to do
>> uh in the eye. Uh you mentioned the use
of muscle testing for clinical diagnosis
identifying affected organs and you go
on to say that uh further muscle testing
uh will identify the negative attitudes
or or beliefs associated
>> well if you just know how to do the
simple for I don't practice kinesiology
and I've eliminated that word
>> right
>> okay so it's simple muscle testing by a
series of questions. Then we can arrive
at a diagnosis. We can arrive at a
likely therapeutic modality.
Uh we can investigate our psychological
factors affecting us here. Uh family
members affecting us here. Uh is it diet
affecting us here?
>> Um is there a strong karmic propensity
here?
>> So you know you can do research. So the
the quickness of it allows you to do
extensive research
>> and you start to get a feel for where it
is. You know, it sounds like it's pretty
emotional, but it's also some kind of a
food allergy and it's also hereditary
genetic. You know, your mother had a
million allergies, your sister had a
million allergies and you got a million
allergies.
>> So you begin to see it's a composite of
multiple factors, each no one of which
would cause it. But when you put them
all together, you know, allergies ran in
my family, everybody had allergies.
But the second sentence had to do with
uh if I understood it correctly uh had
to do with identifying the negative
attitudes and beliefs. Yes.
>> That impeded progress.
>> Oh yes. Well, you check out, you know,
if you if you knew the technique like we
do. So we'll say, in fact, if anything
goes wrong around the house, we'll say
there's something out about this, right?
Don't we? We say something out about
this. Uh there's some kind of an energy
of resentment here. We'll check it out.
And um and then I think who was here
lately? Oh yes. No. Uh did resentment
come up? Yes. There was some kind of a
complaint there. So you begin to to
track down what is the energy that's out
here? I mean, is there an unforgiven
resentment? You see, the guy promised to
have your car ready by Friday. This is
two weeks later and your car isn't fixed
yet.
>> Yes. That's a fact in my life right now.
>> Yes, I understand.
>> Let's see.
I have a resentment about that
resistance.
>> The the last part of that sentence said
that uh
>> reparative affirmations are prescribed.
>> Yeah. Well, you you uh
uh instead of having resentment, your
willingness to forgive, you're ex
willing to accept the extingencies of
life. So, you affirm the antidote.
>> Mhm. Is is psych
a credible source of these services?
>> What
>> a company called Psych K?
>> I don't know any about them.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you for asking me. Yes,
you could use the arm on it and see if
they may have some good ideas.
>> Hi, Doc.
>> Hello.
>> I forgot what I was going to ask. Um,
okay. Um, what does it feel like when
you're attacked by demons?
>> What do you feel like? What?
>> When you're attacked by the demons that
you talk about?
>> Feel like attacked by the demons.
>> Oh, it's just that negativities come up.
Um,
despair, anger, resentment,
nothing's working right, disgruntlement,
self-pity.
Uh these are all negative energies and
uh you can pick them up from other
people
>> and you have to go
>> and clear their energy.
>> Okay.
>> Because the your aura is picking up
their negativity. You see?
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you, Doc.
>> Huh?
>> Yeah.
>> Let's all do it.
Ha ha.
Take that demons.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> They went flying out of here like woof.
>> Thank you, sweetheart, for bringing it
up.
>> Hi.
I was interested when you talked about
uh how unwise it is to take an oath or
make a promise
>> and I was wondering if you could tell me
if I've ever taken an unwise oath in a
past life.
>> Oh, you're going to get neurotic about
it now. I never should imagine it.
>> And and if I have, is there any way to
say an affirmation now to avoid the
consequences?
>> Yes. You just re rebuke all things that
maybe were made out of a lack of
education or ignorance and that you're
no longer bound.
Just like a child outgrows anything he
commits to when he's a child, you know.
Uh you're not you're not bound by it
unless it's an integrous decision, you
know.
>> But you can't tell me if I have.
>> Okay.
>> Don't worry. All
right. Thank you.
>> If you lose your thumb, look into it.
She's clear of any such energy. Resist.
She is clear of it. I want you to stop
being neurotic. But you are clear of
such an energy. Don't be so fearful.
On the other hand, I understand it.
I was fearful of making a mistake to
tell you that you got nothing to be
fearful about.
That's a fact. I had to ask if do I have
it okay to say tell that
>> good to meet you
>> yes
>> uh my question is about harmonic
convergence what it is and what brings
it about
>> oh that's uh you have to understand the
astrology
in astronomy there are times when there
when viewed from here there seems to be
a constellation the concordance of it's
an astrologic event
doesn't have any particular meaning
except that a lot of times things are
sort of concordant around 8 19 what I've
lost what century we're in here 19
87 I think it was8 yeah
>> yeah some sometimes there seems to be a
simultaneity but it's not due to
causality it's a simultaneity
that the timing of certain things is
more synchronous to go along like this.
You see
>> this is not causing this but it is more
optimal.
So it was an 87 mankind jumped from 190
to 204.
Then around 204 or so it jumped to 207.
Then around 205 or so or 206 I don't
know where it dropped back down to 204
again. Yeah.
>> Great. Thank you. If it drops any lower
than that, move out of town.
You don't want to be in a big city. If
it drops below 200, no way.
Well, it was at 190 for many centuries.
Of course, during those centuries,
mankind was not at peace ever. It was
continuous war.
>> Huh?
Cameras are talking. Oh,
>> yes.
>> With thanks and love, I would like to
ask for your blessing.
>> Yes,
indeed. You have it now. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Forever more.
Down through the centuries. Isn't that
amazing?
I forget how many lifetimes ago it was
with me. 20 years
old all size life. Yes.
>> Who are some of the important spiritual
teachers and thinkers who are alive
today in the 21st century that haven't
made it onto your list yet?
>> Who are some of the people that uh
>> haven't made it onto our list?
>> I don't know. Why should I care?
>> You might like us to know about them.
Well, go look look them up yourself.
>> Thank you.
>> There's a hundred. And if they won't do
you, I don't know. By the time you
finish the works of that hundred, then
you can look for some other teachers.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> My question is, I've been an active
alcoholic for a little over 35 years.
I'm about four months sober now.
>> Yeah. involved in AA. Um, I've done
steps one through seven. Um, and what
I'm wondering is the obsession and
desire to drink has not yet left me and
I have not sensed conscious contact yet.
This new in sobriety, I'm not even sure
I'd know it if I did. Um, what should I
look for? And what suggestions would you
have about
>> a miracle?
>> I'll tell you about the obsession about
dream. Yeah, it is. What you're desiring
is an image in your mind.
You'll find you can let go of any
obsession, sex, drugs,
money, fame,
alcohol.
that before you get the desire for the
drink, there's the image of the drink.
You got to catch it 1/10,000 of a
second.
You don't crave a drink out there. You
crave your inner image of a drink and
what a drink will do for you. So, you
don't have to worry about out there. The
problem isn't out there. The problem is
your attraction to it and your own
mental imaging.
Whether it's a sexual hotsy
or a hot fudge sundae and your problem
is diabetes and you're supposed to not
get off sugar,
you're not desiring a chocolate fudge
sundae. You're desiring the image of the
chocolate fudge sundae that then leads
you to the chocolate fudge Sunday. So
you cannot help it. By the time you get
to the fudge Sunday already, you're a
goner already.
You can catch it at the minute that you
image it.
See, the trouble with television is you
cannot choose the images that you don't
want to be programmed with. You're
programmed with it already.
The minute the image come across, you
just got solicited and seduced by it and
trapped by it and tempted by it.
So
you watch it, you'll see before any
desire comes up, the desire is always of
an image of it.
And you can let go of the image of it
that you have control over in dominion.
And uh if you do that, you won't get get
carried away.
All right. There was in the AA book,
there's a guy was sober 13 years. He
walks across the cocktail lounge. After
13 years of sobriety,
it comes into his mind how a a cold
martini would be a great idea.
Cost him 13 years of sobriety. All
right. The minute the idea of a cold
martini crossed his mind at that moment,
he could have eliminated with half an
ounce of energy, but he let it grow. So
that that image will grow and and gain
energy. When it gets this much energy,
you're going to have to go to the bar.
You could have eliminated it here.
So never ignore the temptation. The
minute it arises, cross it out. Picture
it crossed out. Deny it. Refuse it.
Picture it's alternate. Okay. Take
something else to get addicted to. Hot
fist Sunday. You can worry about that
later.
I had to beat hot fud Sundays. Oh man,
it almost kill me.
Double chocolate hot Sunday, man. And I
got to give those up for God.
This too. Oh Lord. Oh no.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> You try it. You can snip it in the butt.
The minute it's only an image.
>> See?
>> Yep.
>> Okay.
That's a secret. Don't tell anybody.
But it's easy. You can kill it with one
ounce of energy and if you wait, it
takes a pound of energy and you can't do
it.
>> Dr. Hawkins,
>> Dr. Hawkins. Um I was uh raised a
Christian
um have gone through the spiritual
seeking
and um am now a student of the course in
miracles
and along the way I felt that I had um
eliminated confusion about heaven, hell,
you know, purgatory, all those
realms.
And uh now I find I'm studying Dr.
Hawkins and I'm really confused
because we've introduced ideas like
other realms,
the void and so forth.
>> Well, don't forget these are subjects in
a progression of books.
When you get to that subject, if you've
read the previous book, it's just a
natural move to the next space.
Are you saying that each book explains
that realm?
>> They're written in a progression. If you
read them in the progression in which
they're written, each one, you know,
like transcending the levels of
consciousness, each one is
self-explanatory as you move along. So,
what is your question again? I don't get
the question.
>> My question was how to remove the
confusion I have about that. And I think
>> what is the confusion? The Christianity
versus the
>> Well, it's not verses. What do you mean
verses? There's not any verses.
>> Okay.
>> Heaven is heaven. Heaven calibrates 600
and over. What's
>> so is heaven in my psyche or is heaven?
>> The Jesus said, "Heaven is within you."
So, as you become enlightened, you
experience the inner heavenliness, which
is the self with a capital S, which is
divinity
uh as the source of your own existence.
Yes.
>> So, hell is in my psyche. What?
>> Oh, certainly.
>> Okay,
>> that helps.
>> Yeah, the void.
>> They're also dominions. There's also
dominions of hell.
>> So, let's be people. Well, you you're a
Christian, right?
>> Yes.
>> Teachings of heaven and hell, does it
not?
>> Yes.
>> All right. So, a person who leads a
godly life and tries to obey the
commandments and
etc. Then, and Christ is one savior.
Therefore, in the heavenly realm, Christ
is your advocate before the father will
speak for you before the father. Yeah,
no problem.
>> No problem.
>> And if you say if you ignore all that
and go in the opposite direction, you
experience hell.
>> Okay.
Thank you.
>> It's simple. Heaven or hell?
>> Yes.
>> You pick.
It's
>> up to you, baby. Heaven or hell? Yeah.
Yeah. Heaven or hell.
>> Yes.
>> My question has to do with different uh
methods of meditation.
>> Yes. There are three different methods
that I have practiced over the last 30
35 years.
>> Yes.
>> Um one is the method of transcendental
meditation but using
>> yes
>> another is breath meditation.
>> Breath
>> breath meditation
>> on it.
>> Uh well no it it's sort of like doing
transcendental meditation but you're
focusing on the breath rather than on a
mantra. And then there's the inner
lights meditation in the backs of your
eyes that you describe.
>> Okay.
>> And my question is are one of these
methods better? Do they calibrate higher
than others?
>> Oh,
>> so it doesn't matter which of those
three
>> prana calibrates at 190. So I don't
recommend pranayana and I don't
recommend necessarily all kinds of
awkward
postures. You picture the energy flowing
up the chakra system to the crown. You
see? Yeah. And then there are beyond
that in the atheric body other the
Buddha body and others you know.
Uhhuh. And um those are just energy
assists
but uh they're really under the control
of what you have become.
So being a wicked person you can sit
around meditating and doing pranayyana
all day and I don't think it's going to
get you there.
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
Give up all wickedness.
Good prisonhood.
You see, it's not only the meditation,
it's the intention of the meditation
which gives it its power. Intention.
>> I just like to thank you for the work
that you're doing and for who you are.
What did she say?
>> Oh,
>> and I would like to ask for your
blessing. The blessing of the teacher.
>> Ask me what, dear.
>> Oh,
>> God bless you. And I'm very happy for
you. I see the joy in your eyes. Thank
you for that. Amen.
>> Thank you.
>> Is that hers? Yes.
Okay,
Susanna,
>> thank you very much.
I have a question to see whether you
could clarify to me the subject you
touch upon on the eye of the eye visav
creation
and when we move from the unmanifest to
the manifest and the question is can you
clarify why at one point in time if at
all there was a reason for this move
from the unmanifest into the manifest
world. I don't understand what he says.
>> It's a why question.
>> Yes.
>> Forget all why questions. Your name why
>> just is
>> well move from the unmanifest to the
manifest. How what triggers that
move? Is it your own spirituality?
What would trigger?
That's not a correct uh
>> so what
>> what makes the unmanifest become
manifest is intention and decision and
the energy field when conditions when
local condition conditions are
appropriate you cannot turn an elephant
into a mouse. So the local conditions
also are prevailing. The possible be the
potential becomes the possible.
Um by an act of the will you know or in
ordinary
earning good karma might say by an act
of the will you uh
choose not to hate and instead to see
that the person can't help but be uh as
they are. So you choose forgiveness.
Yeah.
The option is up to you. You can either
hate them or choose to forgive them.
Yeah. Okay.
People cannot help being but uh being
the way they are.
And the idea that they could be
different is an illusion. That's a
hypothetical. And the hypothetical is
always wrong. If they could be, they
would be. So by definition, they are
not. Therefore, they can't be.
Therefore,
you don't you you know I can't hate I
can't hate that fellow Cho. He just re
he just writhed with hatred and venom
and he's obviously you know demonp
possessed. You know what I'm saying?
>> Mhm.
>> And uh I feel sad that his soul got so
stolen. I don't know what he did. Got a
body and some demon took it over or
what? But so I don't have to hate him.
Uh you know I don't even want to see him
in jail necessarily. I just want to
leave everyone alone.
I'd put them out in the desert someplace
and stay there.
You go out there by yourself.
So you you see you cannot help but be
being who he is.
>> He's like possessed by hatred and
possessed by demons really, you know.
How can he help it at a calibrated level
five? What could he know?
He probably doesn't even realize there
is any other way to be, you know, except
to hate.
So through understanding comes
compassion.
And then through understanding comes
compassion for yourself as well.
Because if you'd known better, you
wouldn't have made a lot of the
decisions in your life that you've
regretted since then.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
If I could only know we what knew then
what we know now. Yeah. I don't know.
We've got 15 minutes. Okay. Well, we
we'll do fine. Run run run run run
rabbit run.
Thank you.
>> Hi.
Um my question is is I am pregnant and
um as a soontobe mother, do you have any
words of advice on
teaching my child consciousness um
calibrating
um and maybe what age to start or
anything?
>> Yeah, you play classical music. uh
appreciation of beauty, uh nature,
beauty, caring for pets and animals,
caring for others,
uh nurturance, have grown how to grow
plants and grow little hatch baby
robins, anything that's nurturing and uh
beauty and u music,
the arts, ballet,
>> yeah, intellectual Shakespeare. Yeah.
Socrates.
>> Huh?
>> Socrates.
>> No, Socrates. Of course. Plato. Yeah,
>> that's for more advanced.
>> Yeah. Excellent. Excellent.
>> Yes. Uh Shakespeare. Uh beautiful
symphonies.
>> Uh the great operas.
>> Well, good. I guess I've started
>> low grin. Tan the overture to Tanhoer.
The overture of Loen Grin. Tristan and
Zalda.
So does that
the mother's intention in saturating
herself in beauty and harmony
>> uh influence the consciousness level of
the embryo resist? Yes, it does.
>> I learned that from my grandmother and
everybody laughed at her.
and she would read Shakespeare and play
classical music when she was pregnant
with my father. And my father was a
great classic musician and then a
professional musician, etc.
>> Well, good. My husband tries to wake me
up with classical music.
>> So, what you're doing is correct.
>> Can I get a
>> stay away from hiphop and all that?
>> Thank you.
>> Yes. The appreciation for beauty
realines their neurological connections.
You see the neurons are always forming
and dying. Forming and dying
>> and then when beautiful music comes
along they don't they don't die they
they form that connection. They form
that connection. So as the infantile
brain is is organizing it's organizing
correlated with the exquisite balance of
beauty of music. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> The greatest things you can do for a
child is religious any kind of spiritual
upbringing
>> and exposure to aesthetics and beauty
and nature. Yeah,
>> perfect.
>> And then give them something to love and
cuddle like a bird or a dog or a puppy
or something. You can't cuddle a bird
much.
>> Thank you.
>> You bet.
>> Can I get
>> Yeah, you're doing the right thing.
You're doing the right thing.
>> See the energy of classic music. Five
more ask.
Yeah.
Wow. Isn't that something?
>> Oh my gosh. Little secret songs.
>> Well,
yes. Hi, Dr. Hines. Hi, Susan.
I'm going to be a new father.
>> He's going to be the new father.
>> You're going to be a new father.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh, I see.
>> And
>> that that Oh, I see. Okay. Thank you.
>> I was going to ask about advice on
fatherhood, but I think I got most of
that.
>> It's now just like your blessing.
>> Oh, yes. God bless you and God bless the
child. You see? Uhhuh.
I just finished writing, you know, the
the masculine and the feminine within
the yungian archetypes. There is the
archetype of the feminine and the
archetype of the masculine. Each one
serves. See, and the perfect balance is
the balance between the two. You see,
our society is maternal welfare for the
disabled, etc. It's also a meritocracy.
You get what you work for harder than
earn. See? So it's a ad mixture of both
uh feminine and masculine principles you
know and I think in America they are
beautifully well balanced because of a
meritocracy are country puts out a huge
product because of that huge product the
maternal principle can now operate and
make sure that all children share
equally. See to the maternal principle
all children are equally entitled. See
to the meritocracy to the man you got to
earn your way. See, so there is a
beautiful harmony and balance. Out of
meritocracy comes great wealth. Out of
that great wealth, now the maternal
principle can operate to provide for all
of her children. Uh they don't have to
earn it. See, to the mother, all
children are entitled equally just
because they are balance of the maternal
and the and the paternal.
To the paternal, the maternal looks like
weakness and some being soft, you know.
So that's the downside as he sees it. To
the maternal the meritocracy of the
paternalism seems too much like too
hard. You can't have anything unless you
work for it and earned it and suffered
for it and all. So a happy mixture of
the two is why we have both two parents.
We have a father who's strict and a
mother says well okay maybe one more
cookie.
Yeah. So that's fun being a father.
Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Almost as much fun as having puppies.
>> It's an honor.
>> Well, you don't have to change diapers
on puppies.
>> It's an honor to meet both of you. And
I'm here as uh the student to get the
blessing from the teacher.
>> Yes, indeed. And that's my honor, my
joy. That's my joy.
>> Thank you. And when is your next book
coming out?
>> Oh, I don't know. Hopefully the end of
the year.
>> Yeah.
>> I'll pray for that.
>> I need prayers to finish it.
>> And I am
>> just when I think I have it settled
down,
uh something will come on the
television. And I say, well, I should
maybe slant it a little bit differently
because of this impact. You know that
what you're dealing with is the enormous
impact of the media.
Enormous impact to the media. You find,
you know, 90% of the population believes
something that's absolutely facious.
They only believe in it, but they're
willing to die for it. How can you
present, you know, the truth in such a
mixture?
picture.
>> Yes, we're moving along as fast as we
can. As fast as our widows can handle
us.
>> A widow.
>> A widows.
>> Hi.
>> Yes.
It's an honor to be with you today. You
remind me of George Carlin.
>> Oh, sorry.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, where did the ego originate? Why did
we separate
>> me? The very beginning of life because
the plants had chlorophyll. All they had
to do is sit in the sun and they got
enough energy to live.
But not so the animal world. The animal
world has to get. In order to get, you
have to do constant research, curiosity,
and now if you're going to get, you want
to know what's edible from what is not
edible. If you eat the wrong things,
you're going to die like right away. And
you won't evolve or even live long
enough to, you know. So
the fact that the uh animal organism
beginning with the amoeba the protozoa
does not have intrinsically a source of
uh energy. It has to go without to get
it.
>> Yeah.
>> But we were all originally part of the
divine. Originally
>> we were all part of the divine.
>> Well that's
>> why did we separate? Oh that's all
theoretical.
>> Okay. Thank you.
We got thrown out.
>> I was wondering about that. What' I do?
>> Well, the biblical thing is we got
trapped in the linear domain. Heaven was
a nonlinear domain
and along came temptation and form of
the linear domain. Oh, the difference
between right and wrong and good and
evil.
So it was the curiosity that trapped.
>> It was curiosity. Okay. I give up.
>> How are you?
>> Yes.
>> Good. Um,
my question for you is in regards to
the best way to balance
uh the devotion and love
uh required
on the path towards enlightenment
with the devotion and love required to
raise and support a family.
What is the question?
>> How's what's the best way to balance
that? Because sometimes
>> there anything to balance. They're not
separate.
>> It's all all
>> lovingness. Lovingness is a capability
whether it's loving and then your
lovingness extends to God, to all of
creation, to all living things.
>> Well, let me let me elaborate. Um
sometimes
uh I feel the need to displace myself
from the society that I live in and I
don't see that being conducive to a
family setting to just take off and be
simply with myself, you know, with a
family.
>> Well, the timing isn't right for you to
become a monk.
>> Yeah.
>> Where the kids grew up, then there's
timing to monk monkize yourself.
>> Got it. Monkified.
>> All right.
>> Monkification.
>> Yeah, I think you're
>> you can be a part-time monk.
>> Fair enough.
>> Well, through meditation, you know, I
meditated very, you know, very involved
in the world. I had a huge psychiatric
practice, the largest United States. And
yet I meditated an hour in the morning
and an hour at night. So there was two
hours. And then while I was driving, I
did meditative exercises. You know,
you know,
>> do that.
>> Yeah. Anyway, so you can combine the
two.
>> Yeah.
>> And then when your family obligations
dwindle away, you can spend in more time
>> and leave the ordinary world, you know.
>> Excellent. Thank you. You definitely
>> just a matter of time. You got a whole
lifetime to devote to it, you know.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
Yeah.
>> All these new fangle gadgets, I tell
you. Yep.
>> Okay. I was wondering uh how do you
remove blocks when you're moving into uh
the medical field and trying to decide
uh what endeavor to pursue if your
ultimate goal is uh
>> how do you remove blocks when you're
>> like I just find that
>> the medical field
>> I just find right now there's a fear
when you go in there's a like you have a
responsibility for helping others and a
fear of
>> uh making a mistake.
>> Yes. I'm I'm kind of wondering how to
transcend that uh like mental uh block.
>> Oh, the fear of making a mistake.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh yes, it is a fear. And uh what you do
is try to perfect yourself to the degree
that it's unlikely
that it's unlikely.
>> Okay.
>> And you work with others and uh so
there's a feedback, you know, of what's
rational expectancy, etc. I don't know
what else to tell you. And um if you're
doing all you can within all your best
effort.
Yeah. And if you're meeting the
standards of the profession and I
believe in having a mentor. I've always
I always had a mentor.
>> Uh somebody you consult with, you know,
once a month or something, a colleague.
And you can discuss your concerns about
certain things and I don't know if I got
the dose too high. I don't know if that
my it's my fault. I don't know if I
should have them in group therapy.
because you can have a mentor with whom
you can kick the case around too.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Medicine is a stress but it's it's
also a very strong calling you know the
desire to help others and relieve pain
and suffering. Is there one style that
calibrates higher than another if you go
to herbal or like
>> no no no
I think anything you know my life was
always dedicated to relief of suffering
in one way or the other as through the
physical about being a physician psychi
psychiatric about being through psych uh
mental you know psychoanalytic through
the psychological and then spiritual
through the spiritual and through energy
field consciousness to try and relieve
uh suffering in all of its exper
expressions, you know.
>> So, it's the intention behind it that
makes it what it is.
>> Okay.
>> Yep. Thank you.
>> Anything that relieves suffering is of
equal worth, acupuncture or surgery or
Yeah. I just wouldn't have a brain
surgeon operate on me who calibrates at
180. That's all.
People elect politicians who calate 180.
Would you let a brain surgeon raise the
180 work on you though?
>> What do you got there?
>> I made that for you.
>> As if I didn't know. Oh. Oh. Oh. Yes.
>> And this too.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you very much indeed.
>> Kitties. Yes, we love kitties. Yeah.
Well, I just am very grateful to you and
the work
>> kitties.
>> And when you're having a hard time with
that book, just think of the joy.
>> Think of the kitties, right? Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> It's because you have to look at that
which in a way Jesus said, don't even
look at it, you know, avoid it.
But it's sort of for a force to address
it.
because you're talking about spiritual
emergence in modern man and but you have
to discuss the world he lives in. You
can't just to pretend that he's uh you
know living in a retreat center.
>> Thank you.
>> How do you make spiritual progress in in
the world of today?
Yeah.
>> Dr. Hawkins.
Uh, since reading your books, I've
realized that the, uh, one basic fear
behind all my other fears is this state
of non-existence.
Thank you. But what what can I do about
that?
>> It's what?
>> Yes.
>> Well, there's two different things.
Death is one thing. Non-existence is
another.
>> This goes beyond the fear of death. I
thought it was the fear of death
>> but then after reading your book
it became this fear of nothingness
non-existence.
>> Yeah. If nothing exists then there's
nothing to experience the anguish of
non-existence. So you know it solves
itself.
>> Thank you.
Ain't going to be nobody to suffer it.
>> That's like talking double time.
>> Yeah. Well, he knows what I mean.
>> I Yeah.
Something must exist to think that it is
non-existent. You see what I'm saying?
>> Otherwise, the question wouldn't even
arise.
Uh I wanted to ask you a question about
uh what would be your advice that I can
use uh spiritually and mentally
to heal myself of a autoimmune disorder
to cure myself of what
>> of what?
>> Of autoimmune disorder.
>> Yeah. Well, you use the same as any
other disorder.
You know we have a book coming out in
fact on self-healing and the various
modalities
uh together with clinical experience and
my own personal experience autoimmune
would just be a different classification
in which you do the same thing you go
through everything you can do about it
physical mental and spiritual
>> including spiritual including the course
of miracles etc. Yeah.
>> It's not believing that you have an
autoimmune disease. That's some kind of
insanity that you've been told. Yeah.
>> Right. Yes. I believe that.
>> Depending on how you look at it.
No such thing can exist in reality. Only
in the world of illusion.
>> Yeah.
>> You follow the course of miracles and
you follow all the things that can
transcend it. And people doing the
course of miracles, I've seen them
recover from every illness on the
planet.
>> Yeah.
When will your book be out, do you
think?
>> Oh, end of the year.
>> Okay.
>> I'll lie pretty good, won't it?
Hopefully the end of the year. I'll be
more truthful.
>> I'm afraid it'll probably come out right
around Christmas.
>> Use the co, you know, course of
miracles. Stop labeling it. There is no
such thing as autoimmune disease, man.
That's some kind of craziness.
>> Yeah, that's
>> some kind of insanity that has taken
that particular form. So you use denial,
you use transcendence, you use
meditation, you ask God for relief of
relief, you see, and then the rest is up
to karma.
>> Okay.
Thanks for the opportunity to discuss my
health with 300 of my close personal
friends.
>> I know
that you have
>> picture
a picture of the two of you. And if you
got bum kama, forget it.
>> Get bar insurance. All right.
>> Ah, thank you.
I love it. Love you. Love you. Love you.
>> It is getting warm. Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Hello, doctor.
>> Please.
>> Okay. Um my question is do you have some
advice or and any exercises to transcend
worrying in general?
>> Transcend what?
>> W worrying like just worry.
>> Worrying is trying to control things, is
it not? You mean anticipation of the
future or regret over the past, right?
>> Yes.
>> It's not seeing in the present.
>> All right. So, you're either worrying
about the future, trying to control the
future, or you're clinging to the past.
So either one of them you can let go of
through willingness. If you turn your
life over to God, how the future goes is
up to God, not up to you. Yeah.
That which was in the past no longer has
any reality because the past had to do
with who you were then. You're not that
anymore. So you're not even talking
about yourself. There's no point to
regret the past because the person who
made that regretful action or decision
no longer exists. It's a fantasy memory.
So you see the unreality of both and let
them go.
>> I understand. Thank you.
>> I demand that you let them go.
>> Thank you.
19 years ago, I had a very vivid
spiritual experience
uh knowingly in the presence.
Uh how could I get back there?
>> Well, you you're assuming you've lost
it. You mean as a conscience as a as a
constant present state, you may not get
it back. you uh lead a spiritually pure
life as well as you can and the when the
karmic propensity
is right it recurs
you can't control it
mother whatcham call can't control it
neither can you
>> Mother Teresa yes
>> thank you
>> it can be there and then disappear and
the lives of all the saints
bemoan
that you can reach a high state and that
that high state uh doesn't remain. You
see, you've transcended your bad bad
karma and now you're in a good state and
then you're what's left of your karma
comes up and takes you back out of it.
It means you got more work to do. Just
keep going straight ahead.
Don't worry about recapturing those
great moments.
>> Thank you.
Don't worry about recapturing those
great moments.
>> Yes.
>> Hi. Hi. I'm so excited to sit in front
of you. Um,
first I want to say thank you and I'm
very grateful for your work. Yes.
>> Um, I'm a psychotherapist and I have a
counseling practice. And in regards to
an earlier question that you had
answered from that young girl who was in
school, I have clients that are very
integrous and wonderful and I believe
they're calibrating well over 200.
>> Sometimes they're going through great
grief, anxiety, attachment to desire.
Does that bring them down to a field?
>> No, that's just passing emotional state,
but it doesn't change who they are.
>> Okay. doesn't change who they are. Uh
like a person who was devoted to peace
and happiness and love can suddenly get
angry. Well, they haven't changed their
calibrated level. They just haven't
reached a perfection of that level. You
see?
>> Okay.
>> They haven't become a saint yet.
>> Thank you.
>> Oh god. That applies to everyone we
know, doesn't it?
>> Yet we're all saints and disregarded.
>> It's everyone the human humanness. You
see
>> hello Dr.
>> Hello. Yes. you and this.
>> Yes.
>> I like to know what my level of
calibration is
>> so that when we're at home
>> so that when we're at home when me and
my h my son are debating I can know that
I'm at least above 200 so that my answer
is at least integrous.
>> Oh,
>> you can ask if she's
>> Can you ask me if I'm above Can I be Can
I ask that?
>> Do Do you care?
>> Absolutely.
>> Then you're over 200. Under 200. You
don't give a damn.
>> Okay.
>> Under 200 you say move on or something
is normal, you know.
>> And these are the things I pray with. I
just like for you to
>> What is that though?
>> This is what prays with.
>> Things I pray with.
>> Pray.
>> Yes.
>> Oh. Oh.
>> And I just want your hand and your
bless.
>> You pay your bills with those. Oh, no.
>> Your blessing, please.
>> God bless you, please. Yes. Where do you
live? I'm in Michigan. I live in
>> Michigan.
>> Okay. Where in Michigan?
>> Uh Southville. Right outside of Detroit.
>> Oh, right outside of Detroit. Yes. Yes.
I was there in World War II. Detroit.
>> You think you're going to ever come to
the east? Maybe.
>> I don't know. I I find it very hard to
travel lately. Very hard to travel.
>> Thank you.
>> Very hard to travel.
>> They took off the super whatchamacallit
jets and that uh
>> They don't go to Michigan.
>> Oh, they don't go to Michigan.
>> Yes. I'd just like to ask for your
blessing.
>> Yes.
>> And where are you from? Michigan.
>> Uhhuh.
>> My son.
>> Huh?
>> He's my son. My 16-year-old son.
>> Oh,
okay. Fine.
>> What do you do there, love?
>> What do I do? I make cars for a living.
>> You make cars?
>> Yes.
>> Automobiles?
>> Oh, yes.
>> I used to work the Nash Auto Body Plant.
I work for Nash Auto Assembly line.
>> Nash.
>> That was about the same era as a terror
plane. They don't even make them
anymore.
It's so long ago.
>> Yeah. I was a factory worker in auto
body plant. Yeah. Beautiful eyes. Yes.
Yes.
My name is Eleanor and I'm from Mount
Chasta.
>> I know that.
>> I think you did it. And I'm wonder I'm
asking for the blessing of the teacher
through me or you both of us as one for
Mount Chasta.
>> For your sister,
>> Mount Chasta.
>> Mounta,
>> California.
>> You want me? We've been asked to go and
speak there several times and it just
>> Oh, it didn't work out our schedule. So,
what is she asking? Asking you to bless
Mount Shasta. Bless the mountain.
>> No, bless me and our community
>> and their community.
>> Oh, dear. Back.
>> Oh, this will be
>> that is uh doable. That is uh
permissible.
All right. I'm going to hold in mind
that which is blessed by um the reality
of the divine presence of God
who is universally present at all times
in all places.
only waiting to be acknowledged.
For which for thy presence do we give
thanks oh Lord. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> See God is everywhere present but
acknowledging it makes a difference.
>> Thank you.
>> Oh were we? Yes.
>> Well I'd love to go there if uh I was
younger. I guess I'd love to see it. go
there. We flew flew over it a number of
times.
>> I just want to thank you so much for
being here.
>> Yes.
>> And I want to seek seek your blessing.
>> Seek seek his blessing.
>> Seeking your blessing.
>> Oh yes indeed.
>> Yeah. It's my pleasure. It is my
pleasure. Uh oh Lord I give thanks.
Amen.
>> Thank God.
Yes,
we're just going to make it if we run
like a rabbit.
>> Okay,
>> there we go.
>> If we if we rush, we'll get through
them. If we rush
You can take pictures afterwards. Why
not?
>> Oh, we can.
>> If they can get it going. Yeah.
>> Yep.
>> Oh, you wrote your
frustration.
>> We'll try it afterwards. Yes.
>> We're just
We're already over and we're trying to
get everybody in the line.
>> Trying to move on out.
>> Okay. Quickity quickity quickity
quickity quick.
Thank you for
>> Yes.
Yeah. God bless you, sir.
>> Thanks a lot.
>> Fine looking young man.
I was once as tall as him. I just quit
eating right and you saw what happened.
>> Yeah,
>> I I'm from South Korea, but
>> Oh, yes. I've forgotten all questions.
>> Uh, could you bless me?
>> Yes, I can right now.
>> We're in South Korea.
>> Yeah. So,
>> yes. Yes.
>> Yes. We were in Soul twice.
>> Yes, I know. two times.
>> It was a great honor. Wonderful
experience. I really loved it too.
>> I love the people. I love the being
there.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> We have a special
>> special place with the Korean people.
Yes.
>> Yeah.
Oh boy. That one go flicker flicker.
Run rabbit. Run rabbit run
rabbit run
over.
>> Yes.
>> My question is about raising the
children. I read
>> about what?
>> Raising children.
>> Raising children. I read in one of your
books that at the the the moment of
birth, the moment of death is already
known.
>> Yeah.
uh according to my understanding if we
do the best at raising and educating our
children we cannot cause any wrong or
fatal.
>> You just do the best you can and uh they
have their own karmic destiny to be
dealt with you know.
>> Yes. And on the other hand you told uh
today that uh uh passivity is fatal. So
we really have to do all our best what
>> that we all really have to do our best.
>> Yes. Yes. Because you thought that
passivity is fatal.
>> Passivity is fatal.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Do our best. Yes.
>> Okay. I would like to ask uh for your
blessing for my nation Hungary.
>> For what?
>> Hungary.
>> Our book is in Hungarian.
>> Yes.
>> Oh, our book is in Hungarian. Yes. Oh,
you're from Hungary?
>> Yes.
>> Oh my goodness. I hardly ever meet
anybody from Hungary. God bless you from
Hungary. Hungarian.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Yes, they had great bakeries in in
Milwaukee. Hungarians.
>> All right, let's do the Let's do
first.
>> I can't get him to run fast enough. They
keep waiting. What are you waiting for?
The chair is empty. occupy
the chair. Yes.
>> Just thank you. Thank you from the
bottom of my heart.
>> Okay. God bless you. Amen.
>> Amen. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you, sweetheart, for giving me the
opportunity to share with you.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Next, next. Next.
>> You got to move faster, folks. Uh you
can't be sleeping there.
>> Yep. Yep.
>> Bless you.
>> God bless you, sir. A handsome man.
>> You, too.
>> He's a handsome man.
>> When your hair gets white, nobody calls
you handsome anymore. They call you old.
>> Great to meet both of you and get a
picture. Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> And thank you for your wonderful
morning.
>> God bless you both.
>> God bless you, sweetheart. God bless
you.
>> We're moving fast.
Okay. Rabbit, run, run, rabbit, run.
>> Hi. I just want to say thank you very
much. I've learned a lot today and I
appreciate it.
>> Thank you.
>> Picture.
>> Oh, picture. Okay.
Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Little rabbit.
>> We may not be able to answer all your
questions with the
>> We're gonna go. We're gonna have to
quit.
>> One more.
>> Okay.
>> Um I
came just quickly last at the end of
last session with the plant and so I'm
glad.
>> Thanks for letting me give that to you.
But
I'm read in one of your books that I'm a
guitar player, songwriter, and I read
how street musicians calibrate at 500 or
that activity does.
And uh so I came down to Sedona. I
thought I'd be a street musician, but
it's against the law. So
>> what's against the law?
>> To play play guitar on the street, open
your guitar case.
>> Yeah. Well, they just put you in jail.
That's all.
>> So yeah. So I've been just going to
meetings. And since then, it's fun. I
mean, just to do that, I met this guy
named Randy. He's going to help me out
with this thing called human design. And
uh but I want to ask a question about
the doctrine of inclusion. I heard an
Ira Glass show on NPR about
a guy who um
was a minister in a in a church in the
south and they he decided to start
believing that Christ died for not only
the sins of people who believed in him
that he could also give salvation to the
whole world. And that's what that
doctrine of inclusion is. And hearing
that made me really want to believe in
Christ a lot more rather than just,
>> you know, obey me or I'll fry your ass
in hell kind of. That's
>> Well, Jesus didn't say he'd throw you in
hell.
>> Well, I like that part.
>> He said on your own, you're very likely
going to land in hell, but with my help,
you won't.
>> Oh, okay.
So that doctrine of inclusion is it
integris?
>> I don't know. I'm not familiar with
>> never heard of that. Okay.
>> I I don't favor doctrines at all
generally.
>> Is the is it the spiritual practice
that's more important?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Doctrines are just belief
ecclesiastic belief systems, you know.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Even like the course of miracles has
them in it, you know.
Well, thank you so much.
>> There's people sneaking in that line. I
saw them.
>> You know where you're going when that
day comes.
>> Line sneakers.
>> If I submit this to the University of
Miami, can I get a PhD, too?
>> Oh, of course you can.
>> Awesome. Uh, my question is, I've been
um since a child a student of Christian
Science. And uh I was very curious how
um Mary Baker Eddie would um relate on
on the scale of consciousness. I didn't
see
>> we did Mary already and I forget what
she was now.
>> I think she's 490. We did her recently.
She's over 490. 495. She was 490. Yeah.
>> Got it. And how did we do as a group in
the room today?
>> Oh, I didn't calibrate us in the room
today. We're over 440. 450. 460. 455.
455 is pretty up there.
>> Did we gain a couple points?
>> Oh, I don't know. I didn't do it before
and after
>> started. So,
>> we haven't been doing that.
>> The optimal audience is, you know,
usually in the mid 400s.
>> Really? Well, they're intellectually
awake and alive and uh they're
interested in integrity, truth,
>> right?
>> And they move right along, you know,
they move right along.
>> Most of the time when we give a lecture,
they they increase anywhere from 35 to
45 points.
>> Depends. Depends.
>> Some people go five 10 points. Other
people suddenly jump Is there more
people waiting there?
>> They're sneaking in there.
>> There's one group. They want one
picture.
>> Okay, let's have
>> Okay, how about a blessing to take back
to Washington DC?
>> God bless it. Take it back with you to
Washington DC.
>> Cathedral.
>> Oh, it is, isn't it? It's lovely.
>> The National Cathedral. Yes.
>> Thank you, sir. Sir,
>> thank you so much.
We love the National Cathedral.
>> It's Gothic uh Gothic splendor.
It's almost identical to the great
Gothic museums of churches in Europe.
The great Gothics.
>> Look at all the lovely people I'm
surrounded with here.
>> I know.
>> And I can't even see them because I
can't see out the back of my head.
Oh, thank you all. You know
>> what is this?
>> Is this a heavenly choir?
Is this a signal to me, Lord?
>> I think God is trying to tell me
something. Don't you? When you find
yourself surrounded by a bivvie.
Whoa.
>> From New York.
>> You're all from New York.
>> Yes. We come all.
>> That's wonderful. Where in New York?
>> Long Island. Garden City.
>> Oh, Long Island. Yes.
>> Yes. I know very well.
All
right.
>> Are we done now? All I love.
>> Oh, can we bless everyone? Let's
>> Let's press bless just this group from
New York.
>> Yeah, just them.
Can't get blessed unless you're from New
York.
>> Well, we certainly give thanks for thy
divine presence, oh Lord, and you've
come this long way
for which I am highly uh joyful. And I
extend the same blessing to all people
present here. Um
oh my god. Uh
we all stand blessed by divinity by
virtue of our existence
by virtue of life itself
which is the energy of divinity running
through us.
We um
realize the divinity of our own
existence.
That which is the self within us is the
radiance of divinity shining forth as
the joy of our own existence. Therefore
we give joy and thanks and revere the
sacredness of our own existence. And out
of appreciation and respect for that we
lead an integrous life. We lead an
antigous life out of respect for the
divinity of the source of our existence.
Amen. Oh Lord. Amen.
>> Wow. I should have been a preacher.
Oh God.
I tell you, I I never would would have
been able to think up such a thing, you
know.
Thank you very much for your presence
this afternoon. It was truly joyful.
Truly joyful.
>> You all bring joy to my heart.
>> Oh my god, what a beautiful day.
Well,
>> those lights are strong.
So this is who we will all be with over
time.
This is who we'll be with when we leave
the body.
We'll just be with ourselves who we are.
Wow, that's great to look forward to.
Thank you so much for your love. Amen.
Hallelu
Hallelujah.
Hallelujah.AlleluAllelu.
Hallelu