Well, this is just um for
sophistication.
We talked about understanding how to get
along with others. You see, your
intention can be of of the highest
highest good, but you've got to be a
little more sophisticated than just
kumbaya.
You have to know who you're dealing
with. So, this is, you know, a sample of
one side of the world, the calibrated
levels of these various civilizations.
What is this here at 410?
Australia is that
>> I don't know what it is.
>> Anyway, I would approach these people
with reason and intelligence. Reason
reason, the intellect. See, and then
these people here, I would approach them
with, well, what's what's in it for me?
These people are only interested in
what's in it for me. So, I would show
them how peace and democracy makes you
richer. Oh, well, then they're going to
become democratic if it makes you
richer. Yeah. In other words, they have
to you have to find out what motivates.
All these people are motivated by
different levels.
The mistake of international diplomacy
is the presumption that because you're
in the 400s, the rest of the world is.
When you come from the 400s to somebody
at 90, you sound like a stupid idiot.
And you deserve to be shot
for being so stupid.
I'm not motivated by the same things.
I'm worrying about survival for God's
sake. And you're talking about a vote.
Oh, I care about a vote.
Keep your votes.
I've been so poor that frankly I that's
exactly where I was coming from. I
couldn't care less about all that
political BS. I frankly didn't have
enough to eat for God's sake and had to
steal to live. See, so you're talking
about all this fancy talk and I haven't
got enough damn food to eat for God's
sake. Yep. So you got to talk sense. You
do that by realizing what is the level
of the consciousness of the people that
you're talking about and what are their
needs? What is their view of reality?
And I'm sick of hearing what our view of
reality is. Uh I'm sick to death of it.
Everybody gets up there and pontificates
about our lofty uh democracy and all
that. You know, I'm tired of hearing
about democracy. I don't want to hear
any more about it. You know what I'm
saying?
Wonderful. Yes. So, what? All right.
Move on. Next.
Um
well, we correlated the level of
happiness. We did that on the other one,
didn't we?
uh the level of uh consciousness and the
percent of people who are happy. Uhhuh.
And we saw the great demarcation was at
200.
Uh the way to get people to move along
is to raise their level of
consciousness. All right. When you raise
their level of consciousness, you've
raised the level of the sea. When you
raise the level of the sea, all the
ships on on the ocean are lifted
effortlessly. Nor can they resist you.
You're trying to sell people, you know,
democracy is the holy grail. Yeah. Holy
grail. You know, and what they're
thinking is, "So, what's in it for me?
What's in it for me? What's in it for
me?" All right. So, the only way I say
you can cross this great divide is by
increasing the level of consciousness.
The first way you can do it is by
raising your own because that's the way
you raise all the ships on the sea.
All right. Accepting that other people
are motivated from this level here
allows you to understand how to deal
with them. These people are arrogant and
prideful. That's the biggest problem in
the world today. Arrogance and
pridefulness
about their position. It isn't their
position. It's their arrogance about
their position. They are now deaf to any
other approach.
All right. Here you can see angryness.
Angryness will always find a reason for
itself
because the west mistreated the east or
some bloody thing. You know, I don't see
any any place where the west mistreated
a certain culture whatsoever.
In fact, it was quite the other way
around.
We provided employment for the slaves
that they picked up and sold. All right.
So
what is the injustice?
As you can see, injustice collectors can
justify anything.
So therefore, the moral high ground.
Today's society is a fierce competition
for the moral high ground. That's all
it's about. Because from the moral high
ground, I can kill you. I can sentence
you. I can say that unless you convert
and pay 2.5% of your net worth, I can
kill you without feeling guilty.
The real gist of bin L's last comment
was not even really heard by the world.
The world didn't even notice it. I know
what it was. You study the Quran long
enough, etc. Meditate on it. He said, "I
invite America
to become Muslim."
That was the only important thing he
said. I invite America.
He is now fulfill the obligation via the
Quran. You cannot kill them unless
you've given them a chance to convert.
Once you give America the chance to
convert, and it does not convert,
you now have permission, in fact, the
obligation to kill kill them. that now
you get that you got any problem with it
talking about hearing about what he had
to say they think it's all political no
Islam is is political there is no
differentiation between political and
religion and Islam it's one and the same
thing there's the house of Islam and
then there's the house of war we live in
the house of war
All right. So before we can be killed,
you have to be given the chance to
convert.
Anybody here wants to convert to Islam,
you're free to do so.
You have to line up over there, pay me
2.5%.
And I will not kill you.
Those who don't convert, I don't have to
feel guilty about it because it's my
obligation to get rid of you. Yes. Now
you understand the international
politics better than other people. All
right. So we move on to the next.
We're not saying it's good or bad. We're
just saying that's how it works. And
that's why we don't seem to get it. So
long as there's infidels on Islamic
soil, we will be the enemy because you
defile them by being on their land. If I
say this is holy land and you're on my
holy land, I now have justification.
In fact, the obligation to get rid of
you. Why don't they don't kill more of
us more often? Is it beyond me to tell
you the truth?
I guess they're lazy, huh? Lazy.
They get busy and kill more Americans,
they'd be more holy. All right.
Characteristic of spiritual truth. Oh,
this is a good one. What's this one? Oh,
the Lou. How did the Louv get in there?
>> That's right. I like the Lou in there.
The Lou the Lou Calibrates at 700. You
know, it's it was the resident residents
of the great monarchs. Great monarchs.
And then they wanted to improve it. And
here you see one of the disasters of the
ages.
Future man will study this and wonder at
it.
Did it come from another universe?
It must have been tele teleported from
some other universe
because this gal calibra this abortion
of is a 180. It's a stunning piece of
architecture. Mr. Pie or whoever it was
that did it. It's a lovely piece of
architecture. It's just totally in the
wrong place. You know what I mean?
You wouldn't put this in the middle of
the Alhhamra or St. Patrick's Cathedral.
You know what I'm saying? is just so
totally out of place. And of course, so
that to me is what the impact of po mo
postmodernism. You see, modernism and
postmodernism
which dominates today's university
culture and this is what it looks like.
This is today's university culture.
Exactly. It's this is today's university
culture.
Completely ignorant of context.
If you look at the content, it's
wonderful.
If you look at the context, it's an
abortion, is it not? It's an
abomination. It's a It's an affront.
It's a
Can't think of enough negative words.
All right? So
you see that if you just look at content
there's nothing wrong with it but you
look at the president the context in
which it's presented. Say the same with
kambaya. Kambaya is wonderful
but as they're running at you with drawn
machetes it's not a good time to be
doing kambaya.
you in order to do kambaya you got to
survive long enough to have kambaya
picnics
in order to have a kambaya picnic you
got to be alive to have it with them
your first obligation is your own
survival first you know first your own
survival and take into account reality
instead of wishful thinking all right
I uh so this teaches a great lesson and
we were there we were there And it's
very functional. You get down below here
and you can go up the stairs and it's
wonderfully functional and they have
hamburger joints along there and down in
there and all.
And the louv is very very trusting.
uh you walk into a room in the Louv and
here's one of the world's most famous
paintings or a bunch of Reuben's I mean
these great famous world famous
paintings and there'll be uh one person
one attendant and she's sort of down the
hall several rooms and leaving you all
alone with these things worth millions
of dollars a piece. It always amazes me
the Lou that they don't have more theft
or damage or people cutting the painting
out of the frame or something. uh here
are these the most famous paintings in
the world and they're just sitting there
and and um and she's over chewing gum in
the corner and there a couple rooms
down. You have to go out in the hallway
to find an attendant.
It's just wondrous. It's just wondrous
at a calibration level of 700 and the
Lou. Yeah. All right. So, we'll move
back one. We'll move back one slide. Oh,
we did that one. No, move ahead. Okay.
>> Okay. Oh yes. Well, we were explaining
uh international diplomacy
uh of of great significance.
Calibrated levels of truth allow you to
know what anybody or anything is
planning or doing anywhere in the
universe any time.
The CIA may not know what's going on,
but I do.
The FBI may not know what's going on.
soon as you and I could find out in a
second.
Why is it that all the best brains are
the biggest most powerful country in the
world can't even know the most simple
dumb thing
mind-boggling
all right so in dealing with others then
uh I use this chart it's wonderful this
is the calibrated levels of of you see
side by side uh this is the the number
of where we're at where is the US 420 21
right now. 421. Let's see if US is 421.
It's still 421. It might have changed
since yesterday.
US is currently at 421. Thank you.
All right. So, here's us. Now, you can
do this with your company. You can do
this with your product. This is our new
Dodge agency. This is where we
calibrate. Okay. Over here is them. This
is us. This could be your customer of
Dodge vans or whatever. You see, this is
who we are. This is who our customers
are. So, what do we have to do to reach
these customers? Okay,
these are the other countries in the
world. So, you can put the calibrated
level of some country here. And now you
can see what your problem is. Here you
are at 421
and you're going to try and talk to this
country here. They're at 300. socialism.
China
socialism at least it's rational and
comprehensible. The UN itself calibrates
at 190. So forget them. They're they're
they've been going for a long time. The
Middle East right now is about 180.
Uhhuh. And then you have primitivism in
undeveloped countries at 40 to 50 bare
bareh substance. So here in dealing with
this country, what you're talking about
is enough food to eat, the elimination
of malaria and terrible diseases. You're
talking about the most basic things of
just ordinary physical survival. The
mental doesn't even come into it. Uh why
would they be interested in voting?
Voting for what? You haven't got enough
energy to live for another day or two.
So here you're talking about physical
animal survival. And now as you move up
the scale, you begin to see uh how to
approach these various people. Well,
this is one of the greatest economies in
the world right now, China. Yes. See, so
as you move up, you begin to see you've
got to change your whole style of
approach and presentation.
What's considered a reward here is
considered stupid here.
What's considered important here is
Yeah.
some warlike country says we'll stop
giving you war if you give us you know
and we say to them well we'll send you a
shipload of rice they say we can grow
our own rice
down here this would carry a lot of
weight we'll give you free grain and
rice in fact don't we have rice for
Ethiopia or something rice for Africa
yeah we do here it's very significant
here it's not significant here you talk
about political ideology they an
interest in political ideology. When I
was struggling through medical school,
the last thing I was interested in was
political ideology.
I was worried about where are you going
to get enough to eat? You know, enough
to eat literally. All right. So, here
you're wondering how you going to get
enough to eat. Uh these people up here
are starting to look for dominance.
Hegman or hegemony.
They're learning how to dominate others.
Dominating others. There's a make wrong
about that. There was a book written by
some idiot philosopher
some university.
Hegman or freedom something like that.
Anyway, hegman or hegemony meaning
meaning the desire for dominance
is intrinsic to all of human life
including that philosopher's writings by
which he intends to dominate the
intellectual academic world. Does he not
otherwise? Why is he writing it?
He's writing it because he's seeking
hegeman hegemony
dominance of the thinkingness of
academia and what he writes calibrates
160 to 180 around in there. Yeah.
Worthless crap. But anyway,
sell those books. Yeah. uh so uh
important for comprehension then is the
understanding of the dynamics the
interaction between countries and then
each country within it has its own
subcultures.
So this may appeal to the
the top of that particular culture but
it's not going to appeal to the masses.
So uh I have no idea what goes on in
Washington but uh if anything but anyway
this does not seem to be comprehended. I
don't get any I don't hear any ring of
what I mean we think democracy is just
tremendously wonderful and we get all
frothy and warm about it.
I don't know
why voting would be interesting in many
cultures I've been in. You get a chance
to vote on it. So So what? So what?
Okay. Can you walk the safely walks the
streets is what I'm really more
interested in. 10th Avenue in New York
City at midnight. I'm really not
interested in whether this is a
democracy or not.
There are big four big jumbos walking
towards me and I can tell they're little
little intoxicated.
And I figure out how I'm going to move
her maneuver off the block without
looking like a a running rabbit that's
going to attract the wolf.
Bye guys.
By the time at 4 in the morning,
elevator and some very fancy hotel and
the girls had coming out parties, you
know, and the elevator opens four
o'clock in the morning. I push the
button. It opens and here's four watusi
standing there looking it down at me
from 6'6 to 6'8 and they all began to
chuckle and I chuckle and they well okay
fellas
here's your recognition of the the
cultural conflict you know god
anyway we said okay and several times I
came close to it and what saved me each
time each time was a goodnaturedness.
I remember one guy that was about to m
just about to mug me and I he was what I
say about six foot something. He all he
had to do was go like this and he could
have broken my neck, you know. Anyway, I
heard his pace getting closer and closer
and then suddenly I jumped up and I went
and the guy went
I hit him on the shoulder. I said parall
luck next time.
I just blew his ass. He blew his chakra
system out. He just went pow.
I've done the same thing a number of
times with the batuses in the elevator.
It was laughter and I remember 10th
Avenue also about four guys walking down
and they are snuckered and looking for
trouble and I got away with the same
thing. I ran up to him and then bop bop
and ran the other side of the street.
So humor can save your life.
What's that?
Five minutes, four minutes, three
minutes,
>> two minutes,
no minutes.
Well, just tell me what the next slide
is. So, uh, okay. All right, that's
enough of that. Now, do we take a break
for lunch?
>> Yep.
>> Oh, I can't believe where what happened
to the morning.
I thank you for your attendance and uh
my my my wish is for you to incorporate
the benefit of what we've been talking
about for your own peace and peace of
the world today.
We'll meet again at what time?
>> Two o'clock.
>> Two o'clock. We'll meet again at two
o'clock.
How far do we get?
>> All right. Do we have to talk faster?
Move faster?
>> Well, I think you're doing fine.
>> Okay. We're galloping along. We have to
leave time for questions and discussion
later. So, how much time do we have? One
hour.
>> One hour.
>> Oh, we got we can explain the whole
universe one hour.
>> One hour. spiritual teachers at this
point.
>> Oh yes. Okay.
Well, I constantly get questions about
spiritual teachers and I tell him, look,
we listed a whole book of them and gave
their calibrations. Why do you have to
find Swami Nikananga in the middle of
Bhuaha?
I mean, you got over a hundred of them
to pick from. You all got to find Swami
something in the middle of nowhere.
You got to pledge everything to them.
Your underwear, shorts, everything.
And go to bed with them. So, I'll see.
Oh, Lord. Uh,
it's funny. This has never been uh
published by anybody before, you know.
It's very funny. Uh, not funny, sad. uh
because what brought my attention to it
was the number of fallen gurus. I mean,
it's just sort of startling. If you
start listening all the all of them that
were up in a really reasonably good
place, some I knew personally
and spent some time with and how they
crashed so severely. You say, "How can
people be so so naive?"
And it's because they themselves were
not prepared by their teacher.
Therefore, I always I do not want to
have that happen to any of our students.
As you evolve spiritually, certain
things are going to start happening in
your life. You don't have to be a big
baba or a big guru or a big teacher with
a big name or anything else. Just as an
ordinary citizen, as you grow and evolve
spiritually, certain phenomena are going
to begin to change around you as a
consequence of what you have become.
First of all, you're more you radiate an
energy of love from 500 and up. Don't
forget you're radiating love.
And this knocks a lot of people out. And
by the time you get to 540,
unconditional love, uh
when you by the time you get to 570,
you've got problems.
At 570, you get solicited all the time.
I remember that those phenomena,
complete strangers would walk up to you
and say, "I know this is going to sound
crazy to you, but I want to go to bed
with you.
And I don't mean ugly losers. I mean
knockouts would walk up to you and say
in a restaurant come over and sit next
to you and say, "Oh, hi." And uh I'm
Jane and I'm from uh I'm working for the
brokerage firm and I just thought you'd
like to chat
and uh if you got the whole hour noon
hour off.
So be aware of that as you get doesn't
matter if you're old and ugly.
How many ladies here would like to jump
in a sack with me?
Yeah, you see all the arms out there.
You see, because in illumined by love,
you don't look old and ugly to them. You
look young and gorgeous.
And you add the seduction of being a
little shy. Like
actually the last time I was hit on big
was I was 75 at the time.
All right. We make we make a joke of it.
But don't forget the sexually impulse is
very powerful. And when somebody very
attractive and you got the opportunity
uh hits on you, it's going to happen.
It's going to happen. You get
attractive. It don't matter who what you
look like or who you are, whatever your
status is. People are going to be
attracted to you. So the first thing you
don't want to fall for is seduction. And
many are the gurus that fall for
seduction. They're all over the
internet. In fact, you know, and there's
books out, gurus I have slept with. I
forget who the authors are. Yeah. There
are by there are women out there who've
written books on the various gurus they
slept with and how it all came about.
You know, let's have holy sex. All sex
is holy. Let's have holy sex. Yeah,
what a compliment. So, they feel
flattered. You see, if they can seduce
the teacher,
they feel flattered. And uh all right,
seduction is the first and number one.
And then how it happens with pedophilia
is beyond me because I never went
through the pedophilia stage.
Uh, pedophilia seems to be peculiarly
rampant. Also explained in great detail
uh on the internet the sad cases of
people that fell for pedophilia. I don't
know how they get to pedophilia but
anybody do.
So then there's being u famous being
famous and having many followers. So
let's say you start teaching now. You've
learned a lot of spiritual uh things and
you start a small class somewhere. Maybe
it's your discussion group at your local
church or whatever. Uh all right. So
then there's the glamour of being the
teacher. And uh so what arises then as
you evolve and become more spiritually
educated is the spiritual ego.
The spiritual ego. So you got rid of the
old ego of wanting money and fame and
all that stuff and you look down your
nose at that now and look at look down
your nose at it. But now you are the big
guru. Uhhuh. In fact, the word guru got
so decimated that when we used the arm
on it. We weren't allowed to use it in
any of the books from about the time of
the Beatles right after that. that big
guru there sort of kill the word guru
and we say is it appropriate to use that
term and we got no the word itself has
now become bismerched you might say
uhhuh
so there's the vanity of the ego there's
the agilation of the crowd
the agilation of the crowd don't forget
project their self with a capital S they
recognized it in you and they don't
realize realize it's their own self that
they're seeing in you, but they think
it's you. So,
uh,
the way they fall then is sexual
seduction, money and power, fame,
titles,
um, master so and so.
There's all kinds of masters around.
They're not masters of anything. If you
calibrate all the masters around, they
all
masters are in their head. Yeah. All
right. So, there's titles, there's
trappings,
special gowns, and beard styles and big
crosses hanging around your neck and
sandals and
that whole uh historical whoopdedoo.
The thing is as you evolve, become
extremely ordinary.
just be ordinary. Turn down the big
houses, the temples,
uh
soliciting people for funds
etc.
Of course, you can work them for money
and all the gurus do that don't they?
They became a lot of them became famous
and then of course what they do is they
build a hospital in their name or
something and say look how wonderful you
know Swami so and so is he built this
hospital for the crippled children. Oh
man, that grabs your heart. Crippled
children are a favorite. Give me a
crippled child enterprise anywhere and
I'll become rich and famous.
Send your $10 for the poor and crippled.
You could become a poor and crippled
guru overnight. All you need is the the
price of the taviad. Send your money for
the poor and crippled. One of the
biggest workers for the poor and
crippled kids was calibrating at 190 for
a long long time. One of the biggest
ones out there. Long expensive ads.
Yeah,
the poor and one. Let me just
hold that ad in mind. That or that that
orc uh is now over 190. It's over 200.
It's at 190. 195. No, it's still at 190.
All right.
The poor children routine. Uh
sends so much a month, etc. Then it
shows you this poor pathetic kid. You
know, it's a real tearjerker
and it's worth multi multi-millions,
isn't it? So, you got um
what does a a spiritually evolved person
uh to me is somebody who is more
ordinary than
uh the realization takes them out of
being special. So, specialness that's
yeah, that's the general label. I guess
we won't. Uh, specialness. As you
evolved, you will be perceived as being
special, especially if you got a title
of one kind or another. And God help you
if the miraculous happens around you
because then you're really in trouble.
And so, some claim to be miracle
workers. All right. the biggest miracle
worker on on in this hemisphere.
Uh the miracle worker I'm thinking about
now calibrates over 200 resist.
Yeah. Famous for the so and so miracle
worker. All right. So the exploitation
see the miraculous happens spontaneously
of its own. There's no way you can make
it happen because at the level at which
the miraculous begins to happen, the
condolini energy has risen to that
level, there is no personal you to will
it to happen. You are what you are. And
in your presence
because you're collapsing the wave
function to you know to the from the
waves to the particle
because of the energy of your
consciousness the potential becomes
actual and you witness the phenomena
handling h happening of their their own
there is no you causing a miracle there
as you can see that's obviously
dualistic
but as you begin to witness the
phenomena happening
uh happily it they happened
autonomously.
Uh and there wasn't any temptation to
think that there was a U causing of
that.
There isn't any you causing of that. The
apple falls from the tree when it's
sufficiently ripe. So if the apple is
hanging in ready to fall from the tree
and your energy comes forth and hits the
apple in the tree, the apple drops. It
drops because of the field. Because of
the field, not because of a personal
you. It's got nothing to do with a
personal you. A personal you could think
drop apple, drop apple, drop apple. It's
not going to happen.
Oh lordy. So
at 570 the condundalini energy keeps
rising and uh you see the transformation
uh in the way the brain processes
processes
there's a transformation and how you uh
witness phenomena from the impersonal
and you see that everything is happening
autonomously.
There isn't any personal you causing
anything to happen. So any teacher that
takes personal credit for anything out
there is already telling you they're not
really a teacher. There is no me teacher
causing you dumb student to finally get
wisdom or something.
No such thing happens.
Now the teacher is pleased to see the
phenomena occurring in the student. But
the phenomena occurring in the student
is happening impersonally.
You could take a dumb spiritual student
and shake him from morning to night and
he's not going to be more enlightened by
dinner, is he?
Now, what happens is one time the
student uh is sitting there and and
notices suddenly look out of the corner
of the eye. They got that the cat just
did that spontaneously with no personal
cause or effect, no valition. And that
that's the way everything is unfolding
including the the way you're sitting in
the chair at the moment. It is happening
autonomously.
Everything is happening beyond
causality. Causality is a Newtonian
concept in the mid 500 in the mid 400s.
Uh and of course a great boon to basic
science. Um this causes that in a linear
uh causality.
Uh in the higher dimensions nothing
happens by linear causality. Everything
happens
autonomously as potentiality
becomes actualized.
And of course the infinite
consciousness the infinite the
ultraheisenberg principle is the
consciousness of divinity itself. So all
that is possible to happen by virtue of
the presence of the power of divinity
which is omni omnition uh omnipresent
etc. is that all that is potential
actualizes when local conditions are
appropriate. It happens autonomously.
Therefore, creation and evolution are
one and the same thing. There is no
conflict possible between creation and
evolution.
Evolution is creation. Creation is
emergent like this. You see? So, it's
because it's emergent, an unfoldingness.
It's spontaneous.
God isn't causing it to happen. You know
the old roll of the dice, you know,
divinity by virtue of what it is is the
field in which but the potential
actualizes
and it's all happening autonomously.
So once you catch that in your own
consciousness, you realize there's no
you causing of that. The phenomena have
happened already.
the arm already went down and moved this
thing up and down. By the time you
notice it, it's history already. So, I
take credit. Well, I decided to move
this arm down.
You can see the egotism
and the uh naivity of that. By the time
you get the thought, I did that, it's
it's over already.
It's a retrospective falsification of
memory. There wasn't any eye that
decided that at all, you know.
And so then you become spontaneous. You
yourself
that you witness what uh this personhood
what the world calls a person is doing.
You become the witness of it. You know
you're not the author of it anymore. I
don't have anything to do with what the
doc talks about especially when he
lectures and stuff. I mean you can talk
about anything that thing.
Where are we on the slides?
Slittery slattering. Oh we were talking
about teacher. I knew something got him
talking.
Yeah. Well, it's uh you know, it's sad.
So, and therefore, they're all, you
know, guiltless. I I say nobody knew
what they were doing because their
teacher did not warn them. Did not warn
them. You're going to get sucked in by
the glamour, the glamour of it all. uh
the seeming power and the prestige and
all the theatrical business as well as
the justure attractiveness of that which
you have become.
All right. So
identification of integrous teachers
I've never read anything about it so I
put it together myself. Truth is true at
all times and places independent of the
culture, personality or circumstances.
So you can't claim credit for it. You
can't claim credit for Protestantism or
Calvinism or any one particular thing.
Not exclusive. Truth is all inclusive.
It's not secret and it's not sectarian.
Not sectarian. Any group that claims
they have the exclusive hold on the
truth is counting you.
these they do not have the exclusive
uh hold on the truth or they would
calibrate at a thousand
exclusive. All right.
It's it's not secret. So selling
spiritual truths and techniques for
money uh to me is smacks of uh
commercialism.
You know for so much money I'll tell you
the secret. Yeah. I'll tell you the
secret for another thing. You want to
hear the secret? Ask me. I'll tell you.
I won't charge anything. Like goes to
like what your old mind tends to
manifest. Da da da da. Let go attract
and aversion. I just give you about
$1,000 worth of trainings.
That's right.
Though up.
That's all they amount to. A very simple
spiritual obviousness.
and they can it. Then you have classes
in it and you sign up people for classes
and you get so many merits for signing
up people for classes. Then you present
the same thing only on there are
different rubric. How to make money, how
to have fun with your sex, how to make
find lovers
and you just reabel it. It's all the
same basic what what's holding mine
tends to manifest.
How much do you want to pay for that? I
just gave it to you for nothing.
What you hold in mind tends to manifest.
Is that a secret? hadn't been a secret
for a couple thousand years that I know
of.
That's what you call merchandising
packaging.
The magic power lectures. So we could
advertise these are the magic power
lectures. The magic power lectures
tells you how to become rich, famous,
and enlightened all at the same time.
All right. Truth is all inclusive.
Doesn't exclude anybody. We publish it
uh you know uh worldwide wide. Anybody
can read it. It's not secretive
and it's not sectarian. It's open to
all. Non-exclusive.
No. Oh, no secrets to be revealed,
hidden, sold, magical formulas or
mysteries. Huh.
ancient mysteries.
You know, the internet's full of them.
Ancient secret mysteries of the
you calibrate them 180. Yeah.
Don't go near the dragons. Yeah. Okay.
Integrity of purpose. There's nothing to
gain or lose. There's nothing anybody
can hear here can give me or buy. There
isn't anything I want. can't get me to
buy anything I want because I don't want
anything.
My wish and hope, yes, is that everybody
becomes evolved and spiritually
enlightened and unconditionally loving.
Uh, integrity of purpose. There's
nothing to gain or lose. There's also
the gain of signing up more followers. A
lot of times you take a training class
in something and now you got to sign up
followers for other classes. So you get
all right never mind. You got the idea.
Non sectarian.
Uh it's not an exposition of limitation
or exclusivity.
It's independent of opinion. Truth is
nonlinear and not subject to the
limitations of the intellect or form.
Has no opinions on outside issues.
devoid of positionality.
Truth is not anti- anything. Falsehood
and ignorance are not its enemies but
merely represent its absence. So
falsehood is not the opposite of truth.
It's the absence of truth. The absence
of truth. Uhhuh.
No requirements or demands. You don't
have to take any oaths, sign anything,
fill out any slips,
get, you know, put put up by somebody.
There's no regulations,
no oaths, no rules or conditions.
Yeah.
Boy, what a snap. Not controlling.
Spiritual purity has no interest in the
personal lives of followers. how they
dress, their style, their sex lives,
their money, their family patterns. We
don't tell you who to marry, who you
shouldn't marry. Marry your third
cousin, second cousin, marry your first
cousin, marry your sister. I mean,
where's the limit? As long as you're
going to get into incest, what's the
difference?
Marry your mother's third sister's
daughter. I mean, you know what I mean?
Free of force or intimidation. There are
no threats. No brainwashing.
Agilation of leaders. Yes.
No training rituals.
Indoctrinations
or intrusions into the private life. Now
you have to also watch indoctrinations.
Indoctrinations are sometimes in the
form of repetitive mantras etc. which do
not lead to spiritual advancement but
lead to altered states of consciousness.
So the other thing about a lot of these
trainings especially short ones
is um what they induce is an altered
state of consciousness but that is not a
spiritual dimension.
Uh you can go to the Monroe Institute
which I did spend 10 days laying on your
back with earphones on both ears and
learn how to leave the body at will and
meet people in various astral domains
etc.
But that is an altered state of
consciousness
is also feedback machines etc. So you
can go into alpha alpha mode training
and various things like that. Those are
altered states of consciousness that is
not a spiritual condition. It's an
altered state of consciousness which can
be learned and which is usually sold by
trainings
for which you pay money.
What I'm describing is a fact resist.
Okay. All right. Those are altered
states of consciousness and it's not the
same thing as spiritual awareness in
which these phenomena occur their own.
Sooner or later, you probably go out of
body anyway.
However, it's fun to learn how to do it
if you when you want. Yeah. Yeah.
All right. So, anyway, let's go to the
next uh thing.
Uh what's the next slide? Um
well, whatever it says.
Oh, non-binding. There are no
regulations, laws, edicts, contracts, or
pledges.
Make no pledges. Make no pledges.
There was the pledge
of a previous lifetime.
Three or four of us got together one
time at a lecture all held up by and
then we took a photograph of all the
thumbless ones. We all blamed this
belong to the same cult
same number of lifetimes ago
or may the so and so be my fate blood
pledge can never leave etc. And if
should I leave, may that be my fate.
Real did. Therefore, I say, make no
pledges, take no oaths because they're
binding down through lifetimes. It may
be three or four lifetimes ago that you
made the pledge, but that pledge is
binding through lifetimes. Let's just
make sure we're correct about that. The
pledge you make is binding through
lifetimes. Resist.
It is binding through lifetimes. So some
of the phenomena that may happen to you
are a consequence of having made a
pledge, a blood pledge at a certain
level of commitment and may the so and
so be my fate. Well, you will that you
said it. You put it out in the universe
and it's now part of your karmic
inheritance. Huh? So I say make no
pledges. Make no pledges. Swear no
oaths. Make no pledges and swear no
oaths.
It says that some place in the good book
too. Jesus or somebody said it. I forget
who said it. Somebody somebody said it.
Freedom not participants are free to
come and go without uh persuasion or
persecution or retaliation or
intimidation.
There's no hierarchy, no officers.
Everybody just does what they do
voluntarily. And you can see all the
staff that works with us. They just do
everything they do voluntarily.
Of course under secret threat but
few threats here and there carry a
little commonality
anyway all comes about as a consequence
of the advancement of this everybody's
own level of consciousness.
Uh truth avoids glamorization.
It it avoids seduction.
uh theatrics or power over others. Why
would anybody who's enlightened want
power over other people? Tell me that.
All what they're telling you if they
want power over other people is that
they're not enlightened. If they're not
enlightened, then why be bothered
treating them like a super guru?
Why would anybody want to control the
life of somebody else?
If you're enlightened, you're complete
and total and sufficient unto yourself.
There's no need to control others, the
glamour of control and all that. So
the teacher is has a defect where
they're vulnerable and the demons will
find that out the demons. And I've been
hit by demons throughout my periodically
in my spiritual illusion. The Buddha
complained about them. Jesus complained
about them. Anyway, so the demons will
attack you as you progress.
It's like temptations will come up in an
area where the evil spirits
figure you got to
place in your army they can get through.
Place in an armor to get through. They
like fill you out to see where it is.
Do I still have to fight demons? Yes.
negative attitude towards that which is
destructive, evil and sadistic. I have
to watch that my umbrage doesn't come up
about that like indignation.
The rape and murder of small children
and dogs and things. I have to watch
that the spiritual night
doesn't come up to me
and with a condemning attitude. See, so
wherever you are along the way, this is
a tough book I'm writing right now. This
is the toughest of all of them. I mean,
truth versus falsehood was tough. This
is even tougher.
Reality, spirituality, and modern man.
Well, if you're going to write about
modern man, you got to look at modern
man, which really primarily means the
media and politics and all this. And of
course, Jesus said, don't uh engage in
evil, avoid evil. So, I have to look at
evil. have to look at evil in order to
write about modern men.
Looking at evil brings up the energy of
evil. So Jesus Christ said, "Do not uh
fight evil. Avoid it. Avoid it." So even
to look at it has its consequences.
And uh I'm recovering from the
consequences of having looked at it for
number of months
and I'm happily looking forward to
finishing the end the end of the book uh
because I don't even like witnessing it
witnessing it. All right.
Detached. There is non-involvement in
the world's affairs. You see uh you're
as detached as you can be and still, you
know, be what you are. benign.
Uh
truth is benign. It has no enemies. You
know, there's nobody you have to
denounce. There's nobody you have to
denounce. So instead you can see that um
evolution is delayed and those people
who fall way below 200
uh it's because of karmic propensities
and therefore
uh everyone is actually innocent at a
certain level. They're innocent on the
other hand they're also responsible.
So on the other hand, karmically you owe
it, but as far as let's say guilt and
all, it's it's not a sin. On the other
hand, you still owe it. So you didn't
mean to kill somebody, but you still owe
a life. That's different than the karma
of murder where you purposely did kill
somebody. That has different
consequences. But if you took a life,
you owe a life. So
however, it's not a negative. It's just
a rebalance. Karmic rebalance. Okay.
Uhhuh. Non-intentional truth does not
intervene or have an agenda proposed to
inflict on others and to promulgate.
You know,
we're not concerned if if if nobody
hears of the work we're doing and if
nobody practices it, it's fine with me.
Okay.
I mean, they got along fine without me
and I got along fine without them. I
guess the world will survive.
Not as well. However, of course,
non-intentional truth truth is not it
has no positions and doesn't want to do
anything to anybody. Non-dualistic.
Yeah. As we just mentioned, the karma is
intrinsic to the intention. So, we'll go
to the next one. Has to do with
intention. Tranquility and peace. There
are no issues or participants.
uh laughter we say with there's a lot of
laughter and uh uh the everything is
happening independently autonomous as a
consequence of that which it is
equality is a reverence for all of life
and all of its expressions. Therefore,
you see the holiness. I always notice
the holiness
and the beauty of animal life. The
innocence of animal life is so stunning.
Uh because you don't get into human
positionalities about it. Now I have
sitting on my desk there's this doggy
and here these doggy
and sitting on
sitting on top of this doggy is a kitty.
Now here's the doggy sitting there like
that. There's the kitty sitting there on
top. If that doesn't knock you out, I
don't know what. It's hard to get to my
work. I take a glance at him and it just
sort of puts you in a bliss state. You
know what I'm saying? You see the
uh what's called animal grace, divine
animal grace, the grace of the animal.
And as you become more evolved, you pick
up the beauty of all of nature, the
grace of all all of animal life. And
eventually even the grace of a human
life even though you may not be agreeing
with it. I see the valor with which the
dedicated savage uh is savages and kills
others.
Uh and I see I see his intention. Yeah.
Yeah.
Equality, you know, reverence for all of
life and all of its expressions.
Life is realized to be eternal and
physicality is only temporary and life
is not subject to death. And the reason
that for that is that the energy of life
like the conservation of matter and the
conservation of energy
uh cannot be destroyed. Let's just
revalidate that because that is
incredible. There's the
life cannot be destroyed.
All right. There's the principle of
indestructibility of energy. It can only
change form of matter. It can only
change form. And life cannot be
destroyed. It can only change form. So
when you swat a moth, he goes right on
flying in his little ethereal astral
body and doesn't even notice that he
swatted him. He doesn't even notice that
you swatted him. You don't have to get
up.
The moth doesn't even notice it. You
just You don't even notice it. There you
are. Whoa. Poor poor moth. The moth
doesn't even notice it.
So there's irreverencing life does not
mean to become modelin. Sometimes you
see modellinism and sentimentality
and there sort of a wimpy uh business
about it all. No, he doesn't even
realize it.
Anytime I uh left the body, uh it just
happened spontaneously. Nobody asked me
if I wanted to.
Anyway, one second. You're in the body
and one second later you're not the
body. Do you agree the body? No.
Every time that happened to me, I looked
at the body. I had the slightest
interest. Looks sort of stupidly there
to tell you the truth. And you had to
sort of talk yourself into resuming it
because it's not at all interesting. He
say now here you spend all your life
valuing and calling it as me and now
that you're not in it, it's worthless.
Well, it's a very strange thing, but it
is. The second you leave the body, it's
totally uninteresting and totally
worthless. It's like a bag of dirty
laundry. I mean, you know, no appeal to
it. You say, "Well, it's not your turn.
Time to leave yet."
Not time to leave yet. You got to go
back in. You say, "Ah,
you watch. You'll see. You
you say, "Ah,
no. It's not your time to leave now.
You're just going back there."
Crying and whimpering won't do you any
good. You got 14 and a half more years
on your karmic clock.
So, all right, back to work. Back to
taking your lunch to the office.
Okay. Life is realized to be eternal. Uh
that which is provable is linear. You
cannot prove anything we do or say. Uh
you can realize it. Uh you can
demonstrate it. You can confirm it. But
it does not belong to the provable. The
provable belongs to the linear domain of
the 400s. You can prove things by logic
and math. Uh you cannot prove love. You
cannot prove consideration. You cannot
prove grace or beauty. None of those
things are provable. They're are
mystical.
Uh that which arises out of truth is an
eulgence, a radiance,
uh an illumination. So we say that
people who have advanced things are
illuminated. Why? Because the
understanding of it arises from within.
That's the value of meditation and
contemplation. With contemplation, then
you begin to see a recontextualization
of phenomena. The one phenomena that you
do notice is that everything is
happening spontaneously of its own
that which is spiritual is called
ineffable. It is not uh not provable. So
the difficulty between u science and
religion which is a recurrently popular
subject reappears in time magazine all
the time or some other magazine and the
scopes trial has never again been put to
rest and of course the book I'm writing
now has to do with how to resolve that
and you resolve it simply by uh a
greater inclusive scale of a reality.
Uhhuh. You see that it's a limitation of
par paradigm. The the lower mind uh can
only understand that which is linear and
provable. Uh you have to move to a
different dimension a higher mind which
is context. And you have to learn the
difference between appearance and
essence. And as you move into context
then you're not no you're no longer in
the world of the provable. So that which
is provable is not really uh possible
when you're dealing with uh spiritual
realities because they're all uh
contextual. Okay. So what do we got
next? Oh my gosh, there's more of them.
I can't believe it. Oh.
Oh, simplicity.
All right. Well, you already mentioned
this. You begin to as you spiritually
evolve, not only you're attractive to
others, etc. and you lose worldliness.
People tell you that, you know, you've
got to get sensible and make money, etc.
Uh
anyway, what happens is you begin to see
the beauty of everything. Now, the
beauty of everything begins to knock you
out after a while. You go through a
period where the beauty of everything is
just a preoccupation. It's a a
distillation of your experience and you
lose your ordinary motivation.
There is nothing you need to do about
anything because everything is
intrinsically beautiful just as it is.
The capacity to see the beauty of all
that exists uh arises as a radiance from
within that which exists. Uh the
intrinsic beauty of everything becomes
this most stunning quality.
Everything and everyone is beautiful
and everything that the world considers
horidl looking to you becomes uh unique.
It's really unique. And I always use the
battered up old garbage can. Oh, let's
get rid of that one. It's so ugly and
all bent up and all. Yeah, but it's my
favorite garbage can. Somebody's always
trying to get rid of my beat up old
garbage cans and stuff like that.
You have to guard your raggedy old
shirt.
>> You can't even Yeah. It's got it rips in
it. You can't even fix it. It's so thin
and worn out you can't repair it. But
it's your favorite.
Oh yeah. So
through simplicity then you begin to see
the intrinsic beauty of all that exists.
Uhhuh. You know and it it's
invitational.
It's non-predictive because reality is
nonlinear. You cannot uh predict. That's
why when we we say you cannot when you
use our calibration technique, you
cannot calibrate the future. You can cal
you can hint around it find various
things set up the hypothetical but you
cannot predict the future because the
future has no reality. Only the present
is real. Yeah. non-s sentimental
emotionality is based on perception.
Compassion is a different state of con
discernment of the truth. It's not
authoritarian. There are no rules or
dictates to be followed
except anybody who disagrees with me can
go out the back door now.
Non authoritarian. Why? Because the
truth speaks for itself. Those who can
hear will hear. Those who can see will
see. And those who cannot will not. So
there's no point in defending. You see,
and once in a while I get a wild and
crazy. I have a wild and crazy folder.
You get some really
all of you have a computer know what I
mean. Blog blog world.
What you call it? Well, www world. All
kinds of bizarre communications can come
your way.
And uh I call it the crazies and loons
folder. Anyway, you get all kinds of mad
things coming across. Um
yeah, what do we say? Non-authoritarian
and non-egoistic.
Teachers are respected but reject
personal agilation etc. It's educational
provides information. The what uplifts
the person is the owning of the
information and the it it's becoming
real experientially.
A real integrous spiritual organization
is neither mercenary nor materialistic
nor does it fake you know false poverty.
There's salt false poverty people
running all over too raggedy when they
could afford a pair of new pair of jeans
but it doesn't get the money in the
coffers.
Free standing complete without
dependence on external or historical
authorities.
Truth stands on its own. Doesn't matter
if anything that I say was once said by
master Wuha or not. What I'm saying now
is being said spontaneously and it
stands on its own not the authority of
some dead master. So what the teaching
of a dead master can give you a
direction can give you a direction can
give you a direction.
Uh but truth stands on its own.
Truth stands on its own. 2 plus two
depend on Sir Isaac Newton saying it or
anything else. Do you understand? Choose
stands on its own autonomously as a
consequence of that which it is not
based on the authority of where it was
quoted.
Natural devoid of induced or altered
states of consciousness. Well, we've
already mentioned that. So, the next
slide.
Uh, and these are spiritual teachers.
How much time have we got?
>> Huh?
>> 15.
>> 15. Oh my god.
Let's see how many slides I got. Where
am I?
>> Oh, we're on the putting green. Oh,
we're we're close to the putting green.
Okay. I just wanted to cover some of the
significant ones along the way. There's
actually about close to 140 uh slides.
Uh and we're putting together in due
time uh just a collection, you know, of
all the slides. And if I get time
there'll be a page of commentary. Uh but
just just all the slides because it puts
together you know a tremendous amount of
research and and work all in one place.
Its value is it represents just a lot of
information uh all together in one
place. So he did uh you know the
spiritual teachers of history and uh if
they're not on here don't send me a slip
about them and ask me what he
calibrates.
But here you see all the great names of
history. Yeah. Every once in a while
somebody will bring up a new one. And
once in a while we do find room to put
another one in. And see if if I'm going
to change this in the book, you don't
know what it's like. If you when you
reprint a book, you got to go back and
change everything around because you
want to add one name to the list. I
mean, you know, it isn't exactly
like you can ink it in or something.
Yeah.
Uh Wallace Black Elk Annie Bant you know
you recognize and orindo a very famous
name uh Wallace Black Elk wonderful
teacher Woody Dharma Jacob BM Richard
Buck you know Richard Buck what was the
name of the book he wrote he was a
physician I think became enlightened
yeah yeah and uh Buddhaandanda Swami
Buddha
Eric Bdderworth, John Calvin, of course,
uh, Confucious,
the current Daly Lama is at 570.
The last pope was at five, uh, the last
pope was at 570 also, and the current
pope is about the same, 565 or so.
Anyway, so the head of a a major church
such as the Dalai Lama or the uh Pope,
the ideal would be around 565 to size
70. From 570 and up, you wouldn't be
bothered with it all. You figure the
world can handle its own problems in
that area and they don't have to bother
you with it. So from 570 and up, you
wouldn't be interested in it anymore.
uh teal hard of course um all these are
very well known uh Dogen and 740
you can ask we'll ask questions about
all this later uh Meister Echart who was
a doctor of divinity a doctor of the
church and was suspected of heresy at
one time because he uh was a mystic uh
Arasmus the Filmores Myrtle and Charles
and uh we had the opportunity to visit
and give talks uh at in St. Louis at the
what's the name of the place where they
all are there?
Where were we?
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's right. So, we had a
chance to see the original longhand and
they had beautiful handwriting.
Beautiful handwriting. Charles Filmore
had beautiful handwriting. 515.
And we had a chance. They took us up in
the private library. We saw the original
manuscripts and they wanted us to
calibrate them and they were all
extremely high. The original manuscripts
were extremely high like 900 but
now is about in the 500s. Emmed Fox and
of course Mahatma Gandhi uh who stood
off the British Empire. There's a 90
pound you called them colored in those
days 90B colored. And he backed down the
entire British Empire.
The entire British Empire backed down by
the spiritual. So 760 or whatever that
says. And if I remember correctly, the
British Empire at the time calibrated
about 195 pridefulness. Pridefulness
sovereign probably
Joel Goldsmith uh
G. Manley Hall Ernest Holmes
uh all favorite names, aren't they?
Ernest Holmes, Aldo Suxley, uh John Paul
II,
um
Kasyampa, Karmapa,
and a number of those people I've got I
did actually meet over the years. Yes.
Uh Martin Luther,
Matilda, here's Maharaj and Mr. Gadana,
Ramana Maharshi. These are all people of
recent times that died in the 50s I
think or so. And so these are all very
famous names. Mutananda I got to know
also. So half a dozen of these I got to
know actually myself. Monroe. Robert
Monroe has the mo the most knockout
voice I've ever heard. Robert Monroe
wrote Journeys Out of the Body. And when
you put the earphones on, he he has the
most peaceful voice I've ever heard.
It's like infinite peace. It's a
mysterious quality to Monroe's voice.
And of course, Monroe had wild
adventures out of the body. Wild
adventures. All right. So, that's
enough. What What is the next slide?
Okay. Oh, we got more. Okay.
Anyway, as I say, I was pleased I had
the chance to meet a number of these and
they were still alive at the time. Uh,
Father Peio uh is well known 585. So, he
was more than just saintthood is 570.
from 570 and up is saintthood.
Uh father pe at 585 experienced a lot of
the so-called cities billocation and
spontaneous healings and things like
that. Wang po we've told told the story
about Wangpo
no attractions no aversions
and um how that can lead you to the void
at calibrated level 850.
uh and that comes from the error of
negating love as an attachment. You see,
love is a passion, a cravingness or an
attachment. You're going to negate it as
uh as a spiritual quality. And if you do
that, then you will go to 850 uh which
is the infinite void, the infinite void
of nothingness. It is indeed impressive
and indeed extremely splendid and it is
very akin to the ultimate state. The
only thing is there's no love there is
infinite peace, infinite tranquility.
It's a very impressive state and uh 850
is hard to get up beyond unless you've
had prior prior experience. But in the
snowbank where I experienced the
infinite presence of God, the self with
a capital S, timeless, eternal,
there was the radiance of divinity as
the most exquisite, indescribable,
timeless love.
And there there I experienced all
eternity, the foreverness of all wasness
and the extent of divinity of divine
love. So in that at the nothingness at
8:50
was the absence of that which had been
experienced in the snow bank. I
recognized the absence. I recognized the
absence and therefore negated it and but
it was with great difficulty I got out
of nothingness
uh into somethingness and had to rework
my way all the way back up again. This
time not negating love because love is
one of the qualities of of divinity.
Love is an attachment between me and my
toy, me and my kid, me and my wife. It
can be attachment me and my country,
whatever. Um,
love as an impersonal, not not a this
and a between a this and a that is a
quality of the you might say the
environment. It's the quality and one
feels the radiance of that love. Uh, and
that is the ultimate state. All right.
Uh there we did the popes, we did the
Batinus, Wang Poe, uh Robert Powell.
These are all very well-known names. So
when people asking me for a teacher, I
said, "Well, good God, here's a hundred
of them. What's your problem?"
These sonell I got to meet also. I met
at least I've done these people. It was
fun. Each one was different. Socrates,
unfortunately, was dead already.
I'm getting back together with him
though. Socrates and I have a an
appointment. We're going to both meet in
the same same place. All right. So, here
we have Mother Teresa who lately in the
into the news because of the the
documentation of her writings. As I
said, I disagree with the decision of
the Catholic Church about it. uh on the
other hand Jesus Christ said uh father
has thou uh deserted me
uh so doubt and faith the fact that you
you can maintain faith despite doubt all
right I'm going to see if I can correct
the Jesus Christ's words on the cross
all right I have permission to ask this
permission to ask about his words on the
cross
what he said Jesus Christ thou hast not
deserted me resist
therefore for King James version of the
testament is wrong. Resistu
he did not say my God why hast thou
deserted me.
He was Jesus the Christ divinity
incarnate. How could that which is
divinity incarnate say how hast thou
deserted me? No he said thou hast not
deserted me.
That's why the lamp survival calibrates
extremely high as compared to the King
James version. That's a very serious
mistake. If you are divinity incarnate,
even a person as evolved as I am would
know better than to say such a stupid
thing.
The fact that you've lost track with God
of God doesn't mean God has deserted
you. I mean, was Jesus Christ a dumb
cluck? You know,
Christ almighty is a
He siteth at the right hand of the
father and he speaks for for your soul
before the father and he's saying you
deserted me. I mean that's so stupid
when you read it. You say man this is
dumb.
Well the lumps of Bible has it correct.
It says Lord thou hast not deserted.
Despite all his travail when all the
chips were down the divinity shone forth
within him. You see? Oh my lord, thou
hast not deserted me. All right. What a
big difference that makes.
What a big difference that makes. All
right. Uh that's enough of all that.
Mother Terresol.
Uh so uh it's an interesting study. Uh
anyway, Evelyn Underh Hill, Vivicananda,
Alan Watts, The White Brotherhood is a
source of a lot of spiritual information
that we also use and sorry yet are we
done? Are we done?
>> Three minutes and then what happens
after that?
Well, then we have a break.
>> Then we have questions and answers.
>> Do I have any more slides to finish?
>> What?
>> You have quite a few.
>> She's lying. He
doesn't tell the truth unless threaten.
Tell the truth.
>> I got through almost all of them.
>> Well, I wasn't going to do all of them.
>> No, because relativism versus reality,
we did that recently in a recent
lecture.
>> Uh, so that's too recent to
>> Well, when the bell was time to ring the
recess bell, you ring the recess bell.
All right. These are the calibrated
levels of the great avatars
uh and the great uh John the Baptist,
Moses, Abraham, St. Paul, Muhammad at
age
at one age and then he fell down later.
St. Paul Saul of Tarsus. Yeah. Okay. One
more. We got one room for one more.
>> Huh?
>> What you want?
Oh, we did the human dilemma very
recently. Uhhuh.
>> Somebody's talking out there
>> 72.
>> Uh oh, we did them, I think, didn't we?
>> Yeah, we did uh the mantras. No, we
didn't do baptism, bathing in the
ganges,
>> but we said all devotional acts are
around 540. Genulection, the golden
rule,
uh, japa, the Jesus prayer. She doing
things behind my back and you're gonna
get get it later. Kneeling to pray is
540.
Lord's prayer we said was 650. Om
pronounced
um
uh turning the prayer wheels 540. People
see how ignorant spinning a wheel. I
mean, what good does that do? It's
because of the intention.
>> Oh, yeah. The wolf.
>> Yeah.
>> The wolf. Yeah. Wolf wolf.
>> Ah.
This is the This is the gist of
discerning truth from essence,
appearance, essence from appearance. And
now you see once you have that image,
the reason I like it is it's nonverbal.
Once you once you get it, you get it.
And you're not going to be as easily
conned the rest of your life. You can
say, "Yeah, that looks good. It sounds
good. Uh but what is the essence of it?"
You know, uh therefore, I just love that
picture. and uh Sonia found out it's a
great it's a great closet. All right, so
we will have a a break and then we're
going to resume. We'll have questions
and answers. We take on all comers and
answer any old questions that we can
>> after
we'll do uh we'll do book signing and
questions. If you only want your book
signed, we can line up on this side of
the room. We'll get you through real
quick.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you. If if I stop judging,
>> huh?
>> If I stop judging, can you
>> stop? If I stop judging,
>> stop taking a position,
stop editorializing,
stop resisting,
feel love and compassion for others,
surrender craving and aversion and fear
of my life to the love and will of God.
Will I after some time
hight tail it to enlightenment?
>> Yeah, sure enough. and
and stop being neurotic about things
below 200
>> and stop what?
>> Thinking about
>> be being neurotic about things that come
>> about things below 200.
>> Yeah. So, you'll find they're not
attractive. Neither do you have an
aversion.
>> Yeah.
>> They're just various expressions of
possibility
and you end up with neither attraction
nor aversion.
>> And I don't have to be afraid of them.
>> What? You don't have to be afraid of
them.
>> No. Why would you be afraid of them?
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
No, you're just not attracted. So, the
ideal is neither attraction nor
aversion.
>> Okay.
>> You just witness the phenomena of being
what it is and see that it's phenomenal.
It's a phenomena.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
Not to worry.
Don't worry. God's love.
Uh yes.
My question is about
transcending the 400s or the intellect.
>> Yes. I think I've understood correctly
um in your books or talks you've
mentioned that in order to transcend the
intellect one needs to
understand causality or positionality if
I've understood correctly.
Can you explain to me is there anything
else that one can do other than
surrendering the desire to transcend the
400s
that will help that? Well, the 400s what
I'm really saying there is uh is the
amount of uh energy and attention you
give to the linear especially causality.
Okay, the 400 travel of the 400s is you
get caught in in uh causality
and that's partly because of languaging
and so you stop languaging and trying to
define pe things in linear terms.
I see the
dog is chasing the rabbit. You see, it
says neither good nor bad, nor do I see
that the rabbit is causing the dog
causing the dog. I see that they're both
expressing their own innate nature
without any causality. So the main block
to the linear is uh it does not define
meaning. It gives you definition but not
meaning.
And it also almost always includes
causality. Now it does that by virtue of
the structure of language subject
predicate no pronoun.
So thinkingness always infers a subject
and an object and a transitive verb.
Whereas spirituality is more in the
intransitive verb verbs isness,
beingness.
So languaging then the way to get off
mentalizing
is stop stop trying to language it
mentally. Middle East. The way to get
off thinking this is let go of the habit
of constantly trying to structure
everything in language because you
realize that language is so constructed
that there's subject and object
transitive verb. Yeah. There's always a
me doing that. There's always like God
creating the universe somewhere in time.
It doesn't you know creation doesn't
come about that way.
>> So I understand this intellectually
having read the book and having heard
you speak. So therefore your advice
would be just simply to surrender from
there on in.
>> Therefore what
>> your advice would be to surrender from
there on in
because to understand it
>> well see it's different right? see it as
an attraction
and and look at the what is the payoff
of the attraction and let go of the
payoff of the attraction. The attraction
is if you think about it in a linear
style and language it in a linear style
now you know that. So that's the
pomposity of the ego that thinks it
knows things because it can put it into
languaging.
It's not necessary to language the
phenomena of the world. You witness it.
It's a relief to realize. A friend of
mine, which I quoted in the most recent
book, said, "It was a relief and I
realized I didn't have to have an
opinion on everything."
>> Dr. Hawkins, Susan, thank you so much
for the teachings. I'm really really
grateful. Um, I bought I bought this
cross from the Church of the Holy Cross
yesterday. If it's appropriate, could
you bless it, please, if you feel it's
appropriate?
>> You bought this as a present. to bless
this for him. He bought it at the chapel
of the holy cross.
>> Oh, you bought that at the chapel of the
holy cross. Okay. We have permission to
bless this. Resist. Okay. It's blessed.
I see its divine purpose and is the
divine origin.
Yeah.
>> Thank you. And and Dr. Hawkins, um, with
my mother, I find her very very
controlling because of my illness. I
live at home and I find her very
controlling and critical and I'd like to
love her but I don't see how to shift
from the feeling controlled and the
criticalness I get from her to
>> let's see how old is your mother
>> my mother is probably about 63 65
>> and how old are you
>> I'm 37 years old
>> huh
>> 37 years old
>> how does mother come to control you then
if you're 37 already
>> um because I'm I live at home with my
parents
All right. So, you're not really
controlled. You're just compliant for
whatever the payoff is.
>> Yes.
>> But now there's an emotional payoff of
the comfort of being with your family.
>> Yes.
>> So, the emotional payoff is you have the
comfort of being with your family and
living with familiar people. Yes.
>> The price of it is you have to cater to
to mom once in a while. Yes. Oh, that's
not too bad. Okay.
>> I just look at it, you know, you are her
son. She wants the very best for you and
she's trying to help you through a very
difficult time in your life.
>> Yes.
>> She may be a queer old duck, too.
>> Is she a queer old duck?
>> No. No. No.
>> So, it's no great strength. What is
this?
>> That's his photo.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank you. May I have a photo,
please, with you and Susan?
>> Thank you.
>> I didn't hear what he said.
>> It was a photo.
>> Oh, photo.
>> Photo. Photo.
Ah, photo. The great god of the camera.
Whoa. To photo.
Then there's bad cameras.
Why? So ugly they broke the camera.
That's the only thing was it
>> I I don't have a question but I am very
grateful for all your work and I just
wanted a moment to sit with
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Put that over there just for a minute.
>> Oh yes indeed.
Okay.
>> You want me to do something?
>> Can I get a photo?
>> Yes.
>> So, I'll get in position.
>> Hola.
>> Official photographer.
>> It takes a zillion.
Yes.
>> Well, I'd like to thank you for the work
that you've done and it makes so much
sense to me and it's really helped me.
So, I appreciate it. And the question
that I have is
if someone has been
unpleasant in this world and they have
passed
and you think unpleasant thoughts about
them because that's what you remember.
>> Is it helpful
that you can ask for mercy for them in
ask for mercy for them?
>> For them or for yourself.
>> Good one that needs the mercy. It sounds
like
But can it be helpful in the next realm
as well?
>> Does God need you to do that?
>> Yeah, I guess not. Huh?
>> No, he doesn't need you to remind him.
>> Thank you.
>> However, it's a positive altruistic
offering on your part, you know.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
I am moon along as fast as my widow wigs
can go.
>> Hi Dr. Hawkins. Yes. Um I wanted to tell
you thank you very much. Um your work
has meant a lot to me.
My question is um how do we reconcile
the differences between traditional
religion uh specifically Christianity
and a more opened inclusive type of
view?
>> You don't have to reconcile them.
>> Okay.
Um what what does what does
>> you ask me how can you reconcile the sea
and the mountains? You just don't bother
reconciling them.
>> How does um how do we understand like uh
Jesus when he says um
no man cometh unto the father but by me.
How do we understand that?
>> By by believing what he says. He is your
advocate before the father. Those who
honor me uh I will be their advocate
before the father. Those who negate me,
I will I am relieved from that
obligation. I will not represent them
before the father.
Therefore, I am somewhat perturbed by
ah relativism invading Christianity and
negating the divinity of Jesus Christ
and deciding this will change the the
year from anodominy
to BCE or some other idiotic
secularization
thereby negating
Jesus Christ as Lord and thereby
negating his obligation to be your
advocate before the father and that
ministers and people of spiritual
education would even fall for such a
ridiculous thing you know is somewhat
shocking to me
those who call upon me I will represent
before the father Krishna says the same
thing you know 91st psalm says the same
thing so to negate Christ as divinity to
me I wouldn't want to let you entertain
the karma of that,
>> right?
>> You get there and Christ says, "You're
on your own, baby."
You tell me to f if off, you know, f
off.
You wing it by yourself, baby. Good
luck.
>> Okay.
>> In the karmic soup.
>> Good luck in the karmic soup.
Have a good swim between the cabbages
and the potatoes.
Thank you very much. I appreciate it.
Thank you.
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> You betcha.
>> We already did calibrate that. Give me
your own second. None get to the father
except by me calibrates at a thousand or
over. Resist.
Therefore, those who negate the divinity
of Jesus Christ who do so at their own
risk.
You can make it on your own. Good luck.
>> Yes.
>> Hello. Um you talk about um the books
when you read them that it can raise
your consciousness level. Yes. And you
talk about um the audio word being at a
certain um frequency as well. And then
you talk about um the touch and being in
the presence of a teacher.
>> Yes.
>> Um
would it be a good idea obviously to be
in the presence of the teacher
if if you're in the presence of a
teacher for a long time and have plent
of physical contact would that raise a
consciousness of a student
>> or would it if you just read lots?
What's the question? You're making
convoluted. What is the question?
>> Um,
is it the amount of times that you'd be
in contact?
>> I never asked that.
>> No, I don't think it's the amount of
time. I think it happens in a split
second.
>> Right.
>> So, it's irrelevant on relevant if it's
audio, visual.
No, because and there's no no report of
that having been somebody's uh student
for many years that you become
enlightened just as a consequence of the
years.
>> Is it what he's asking is does it make a
difference being in the presence of the
teacher compared to say the audio and
video of the teacher?
>> It makes it's better to be in the
physical presence.
>> Yes.
>> So it' be a good idea to fly to the US
and come to lots of lectures. No, not
necessarily be the presence once
>> takes one second they get the energy. So
it's not
>> it's by your affirmation
>> right and obviously if you if you
>> it happens in one second
>> contemplate when you're away
>> it happens in one second just by virtue
of ascent just by agreement by your
agreement it happened already
>> beautiful
thank you
>> I mean he was understand
>> yeah I'm not very good at
>> placing questions
>> and it lasts many lifetimes and it lasts
many lifetimes How
many lifetimes?
>> The energy that I came into was I don't
know. I forget how many lifetimes
ago.
>> Thank you. Can I
It's the radiance of the aura
and it's it happens automatically
by your ascent, by your
Where did all these books come from?
>> Oh, this.
>> Well, you look familiar.
Hey, you're not
>> I'm not.
>> You're not new.
>> Tell me what's going on.
>> I'm not. Gee, I thought I was all brand
new. I got a new shirt on.
>> No, everyone is born a new every day.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, we'll go with that.
>> Okay. Marvelous.
Does that get rid of all the stuff I did
before, D?
>> It's forgiven.
>> Oh.
But in this moment, you're in trouble.
>> Well,
>> it's not the first time.
>> What?
Yeah. Tell me what's going on with you.
>> Uh,
as you know, uh, the last few months
I've I've had to be very involved with
the physicality,
which
>> Yeah.
uh has been difficult and recently made
a decision that I might get more
involved with the worldly thing.
>> Yeah.
>> My question is is it possible to
calibrate
if that is in my highest and best
interest at this time
>> to get involved in the construction for
instance?
>> Yes. To pursue that?
>> Well, I don't know. Let's see. We have
to ask this. Oh, getting involved in
construction would not uh be harmful to
his spiritual awareness or this. No, I
wouldn't think it would. Why would it?
>> Jesus was a carpenter, was he not?
>> Pardon?
>> Yes, he was.
>> Uh, well, I understand you were. I'm
looking for some good carpenters. If
you're looking for a little part-time
work.
>> Well, yes. I did carpentry for years and
years.
>> I uh
>> I did a big water wheel all by myself,
you know.
>> Oh, did you?
>> And I had a plate made dedicated to the
carpenter of Nazareth, you know.
>> Still on that water wheel. Yeah.
>> Is it? You had
>> It was a breast plate. I had to agree.
>> I'll have to come see that.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you very much.
piece
dedicated to the carpenter of Nazareth
in Galilee. It says that plate right on
the water.
>> It's very
>> Oh, it's probably
decades of water over it.
>> Yes. My question is, how should the
world deal with Bin Laden and those like
him?
>> What?
>> How should the world deal with Bin
Laden?
>> The world
Uh that's not an answerable question.
>> Okay.
>> Uh first of all, it doesn't deal. It
just is what it is with him.
>> And he represents, as I say,
civilization is like tectonic plates
moving across each other.
>> Okay.
>> And the book generations reviews that
the periodic uh
um
shifts in generation and their
viewpoints, you see.
>> Mhm. And the generation I grew up in uh
would consider the present one frankly
satanic.
>> My generation considers any any
afternoon I watch television all you
watch is satanic. Seduction image fraud,
lying for gain,
uh lying for money, seduction for money.
>> It's a litany of the satanic.
>> That's all it is.
And then comes the uh political which is
the luciferic rather than the satanic.
>> Okay.
>> So my generation considers it
the public life
to be satanic and luciferic both.
>> Mhm.
So what do we do then just to avoid it?
>> Well, you're a spiritual student.
>> Okay.
Thank you. So you don't become aligned
with that which you recognize as
falsehood. You know what I mean?
>> So the New York Times comes out with a
big thing. You calibrate it.
>> Mhm.
>> And that tells you in case you were
attracted to it that it may be the wrong
direction to go if you are in a
spiritual direction. Yep.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Uh civilization goes through phases,
right?
Mankind has been at war 93% of recorded
time. 93%.
The other 7% he was too poor or sick or
something. The plague was going on. He
couldn't get off the bed to fight.
>> Hi. Um I'm a psychology student and I'm
going into um counseling and I would
like to know how to help people who
calibrate below 200.
How to help what people?
>> It's very difficult.
>> You wouldn't wouldn't bother. But if you
want to
>> Yeah.
>> They're dedicated to evil and other than
hitting bottom and going through a
spiritual transformation. I frankly
wouldn't want to work with them.
>> Well, you kill a couple of people. You
get out and then what's the first thing
you do? You kill somebody.
What does a pedophiliac do his first day
out of jail? I tell you, within one hour
he's at the nearest park. I treat a lot
of them. What does the alcoholic who
hasn't hit bottom do? Within one hour,
he's at the nearest bar.
Homicidal maniac is already lining up
his next victim. She look and looks just
like you.
Don't you realize the next victim looks
like you?
>> Yeah.
>> Single young blonde lady. Everybody's
favorite murdery, isn't it? Just don't
go jogging in Central Park at midnight.
>> Am I dissuading you?
>> Um, yeah.
>> All right. So, the way to help those
people is to help them to hit bottom.
>> Okay.
In my spiritual experience,
unless they hit bottom, they're just
going to be receivist and they're going
to drain you of your energy. They're
going to drain your energy. Yeah. With
sympathy, empathetic, sad stories. And
then if you don't comply, they there'll
be a veiled threat.
>> Okay.
>> And you'll have to live with the fear.
And what are you going to get out of it?
somebody who used to calibrate a 70 and
now they calibrate a 75.
You're, you know, seeing as so many
people in the world who need and want
and are responsive to help. It always
seems to me like do gooderism to try the
impossible.
It's naivity.
>> Okay,
>> I practiced for 50 years and I don't
want to take on a case like that.
I tried and I fell. Unless spontaneously
they hit bottom,
forget it. If they hit bottom and want
help, that's different. And you got them
to a 12step group or something because
it takes a whole group energy to hold
together a person whose life has been
dedicated to evil. You know what I'm
saying?
Yeah. What's the recitism rate amongst
that population?
95%.
Yeah.
>> In in jail for rape after release,
what's the chance of returning to jail
for rape?
>> 90%. Uhhuh.
Unless Unless there's a some major
confrontation that causes them to stop
and hit bottom, right? You see all the
Hollywood hotties, you know, parade back
and forth across the the stage, right?
In and out of rehab.
hopeless situation.
>> Okay, thanks.
>> I don't know what I'm supposed to
>> um I guess I'm pretty new. This is my
first seminar and I only really read
sort of one of your book. But um during
your seminar there's something that kind
of stand out about that camel incident.
Um
>> the what
>> the
>> where you um you have to pay $10 to get
on the camel and then when you get off
you have to pay another $10. So, um,
well, to I don't know. Maybe I don't
know. Um, to me, $10 over here in the
US, it seems insignificant to the people
over.
>> It wasn't insignificant to me.
>> I was not a millionaire when I was
there.
>> I worked my way over there by teaching a
class.
>> Okay. Maybe
>> in return for teaching the class, I got
free uh transportation there at back. So
$10 was a
>> respectable piece of money.
>> Okay. I guess in my I don't know maybe I
don't know how to explain very well but
>> I felt like well 10 to me $10 is
insificant amount right now. So why
can't you just give them $10 and it's
means so much more to them over there?
>> Because I'm not a social welfare agency
and I have a contract.
>> Okay. I guess
>> I'm not a welfare agent. You know,
that's not my function.
>> Okay, I guess.
>> All right. And then one more question.
>> You sound just like him. Hey, rich
American, you can afford it so I can
extort it out of you using sympathy for
blackmail. You're not going to blackmail
me with sympathy, sweetheart. Because it
sounds ridiculous.
>> No, I'm
>> You make a contract with me. It's a
contract. Whether I have money and you
have money is irrelevant to the
contract.
>> No, I'm just saying like
>> I understand your point of view. Yeah.
I'm not saying like I just
>> rich America and you can afford it.
>> No, I feel like that's something that
>> the whole world says to us now. Rich
American, you can afford it.
>> I I just feel like see like I feel like
that when I go back too or something
like they're trying to rip me off, it's
not integrous, but at the same time that
amount of money seems insignificant and
might be helpful to others. That's what
I'm saying. But
>> from a relativistic viewpoint. Yeah.
>> So I don't know.
>> I don't know. But um then one question,
as long as you're happy, do you need to
>> happy with your life and everything
that's going on, do you need to search
for enlightenment?
>> No, nobody needs to.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Hello. I would just like to have a
picture.
>> I want $10 for that answer.
Oh lord.
>> Yes.
>> Wait. It's a little complicated. Uh
>> oh.
>> Uhoh.
>> Oh.
Thank you.
>> Hi there. It's good to meet you both.
Um,
the question that I had kind of changed
because, uh, each time you bring
something up, um,
whether I'm reading your books or
watching your DVDs,
uh, that's why we're in the course of
miracles. We're a student there. It's
been very helpful. And we go to the
Monroe Institute in a um, next month.
So, what am I going to gain from the
Monroe? Oh, you'll gain uh you know the
the capacities of human consciousness
for one thing.
Uh how to explore other domains.
Uh how to achieve various altered states
of consciousness which are useful such
as self-hypnosis.
Uh with self-hypnosis you can do a lot
of things other people can't do. It's
very pragmatically useful at times.
Yeah. So well worth it.
>> Oh, I thought it was educational. You
spent eight to 10 days laying on your
back when I was there.
>> Yeah. I I think it's six days now. So
>> that ought to be a feeling right there.
>> Yeah. So well anyway, that's you know
because each time you mention something
I guess if I'm going to, you know,
follow your teachings and I need to
follow your path,
>> you know, it's not a necessary thing,
>> right? But it does train you in uh
understanding altered all altered states
of consciousness, other levels of
consciousness also other domains. You
can visit other domains
and uh it's not necessary to do it u but
there's a lot of things you do just for
their educational
benefit, not because it's actually
necessary.
>> Okay? because I'm just trying to get
past the ego from the course of miracles
because I'm I'm really having a hard
time deciphering where my ego is running
me or if I'm being led somewhere. So
that's why I keep following the
>> Well, you just add it to your spiritual
education. You know, you investigate a
lot of different nooks and crannies and
u
it's an adventure.
>> Okay. Excellent. Did you do it?
>> Oh, okay. Why don't you come with me
next month?
>> I'll let Carol let you go.
>> All
their states of consciousness are are
whole field in and of themsself.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And some people spend their whole life,
you know, examining them, studying them,
fooling around with them. And at the end
of all that, what you know, you know,
all three states of consciousness.
>> Okay.
>> So, it's self-limiting also. Yeah.
>> Excellent. Excellent. May I get a
photograph?
>> But it is
interesting to leave the body.
>> Oh,
>> because the realization that you're not
the physical body becomes rather
stunningly obvious.
>> Well, that's the that's that's the thing
that becomes exciting is to take what
you're believing 99.9%
and then bring it into a known with a
capital K, you know, to where you can
go, okay?
>> So, it's uh it's interesting.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I think it diminishes the fear of death.
you realize the body's going to go boom
and you're not even going to be there.
So, you know,
>> well, it's been interesting because I've
never had a fear of death. I did my time
in the service and I've never had a fear
of death, but I've got a will to live. I
got a survival
ego that is just beyond.
>> Anyway, it's educational.
>> Okay.
>> And you'll hear you'll see what I mean
by his voice. He has the most uncanny
voice.
>> Is that the same voice? We got the
hemis.
>> I don't know if you're the same tapes,
but uh
>> really
>> his original voice is smooth. rather
unique.
>> This is a unique one. Exactly like it.
>> Okay. All right. Great. Can I get a Can
I get a photo?
>> Okay. Thanks.
Yallelu.
Hallelujah.
Hallelujah.AlleluAllelu.