Hello.
>> All right. So this is the we were trying
to define what is the pathway of the
mystic. If there is such a thing and
actually there is
you seek God now through the various
yogas
the
and the various yogas have to do with
the karma yoga.
The various yogas have to do with uh
disciplines and meditative styles and
the yogas are explicitly defined in
Hindu classic spiritual literature.
the great yoga raja yoga etc
in uh in our world the western world uh
these are extremely they're very
well-known classic uh mystics about
which much is written then this is the
aerial padite 755 and I can't pronounce
that and uh mutan matkananda
uh 655
uh St. Teresa of Aila 7:15 Wang Po 960
and we remember we said Wang Po
I think uh the f risen of wang po cal
850 but wang po himself went beyond and
that's the pathway of negation not this
not that uh netty netty not this not
that
to let go of all conceptual thought
let go of all concept Conceptual thought
is a Buddha pa p p p p p p p p p p p p p
p p p p p p p p p p p p p p p p p p p p
p p p p p p pathway.
No matter what you say about anything,
it only amounts to something that you're
saying about anything.
I was confronted with that at age three
is infinite reality, allness or
nothingness,
existence or or non-existence.
No matter what you say, existence or
non-existence,
those are both just mentalizations.
So why bother saying either one?
Don't bother with existence or
non-existence. Forget about it. Let God
worry about it.
Those are just statements. Statements
about how the mind sees things.
So what they're really saying through
that pathway of negation then is that
anything that your mind says is a
perception
otherwise it couldn't say anything
because it is stuck in perceptions you
cannot find divinity or the Buddha
nature uh through the mind. So
to transcend the mind is critical.
To transcend the mind with a small M
which opens the way for mind with a
capital M.
Neither existence nor non-existence.
So it took I forget 36 years to
transcend that dilemma. Is the reality
existence or is it non-existence?
You cannot say each one of them is a
definition. Uhhuh.
So Hangpo is one of my favorite
teachers.
Patangeli at 7:15. Plutinus at 7:30.
Rama Krishna at 6:20. Raman Maharshi and
Mr. Maharaj
uh are at 7:20. So the book we just
finished which is pretty much focused on
this level calibrates I don't know 720
to 740 because we're trying to focus on
the differentiation between perception
and essence
when mana says don't worry about the
world you see because the world you see
doesn't even exist it makes no sense to
the average person what do you mean the
world you see doesn't even exist
so 720 to 740 cal uh clarifies
you know the difference between
perception and essence and what the
world sees of course and thinks is truth
is perception. What it thinks is truth
is nothing but perception and therefore
is devoid of any inner reality.
One TV news program is just as facious
as the next.
St. John of the Cross. The some of these
are so well known and uh you know books
are available about them and I always
liked her this name Mild Deaf Machber
sounds so delightfully Germanic doesn't
it? Yeah.
St. Francis of Aisi of course we're all
familiar with. So I put in those that
were most famous. St. Dominic of the
Dominican order.
uh Meister Ehart of course who's
extremely well known and got into some
trouble with the Catholic Church over
his mysticism
and then there is a famous book uh it's
a really central to mysticism called the
cloud of unknowing
uh which calibrates at 700 the cloud of
unknowing has an unknown author
and I always wanted to write books
anonymously ly first book power versus
I wanted to I wanted it to be anonymous
because there's no person saying this
there's any person saying this
this happens after this it doesn't need
a person to say it and I thought putting
in a person as an author
uh detracts from the truth of what is
being written so the wisdom of the cloud
of unknowing is you I don't have an
author
uh that you can go online with and
criticize.
Oh, Puggy Whipwick. He doesn't know his
ass from Hot Rock and you know he's he
sounds like a leftist to me. Sound like
a conservative or something.
That propensity to politicize
everything. You know, I like a bagel.
Well,
so you want to you know what I mean?
Right away that's a political Oh, bagel.
Huh? Huh? What are you trying to say?
You're not trying to say anything. You
just want to have lunch. You know what
I'm saying? All right, we'll move to the
next one.
We have five on the mystic. Is that
correct? Yeah. All right. So, I know how
to time us. How much time we got left?
Huh? 20 minutes. Oh, good. We can go to
the moon and back in 20 minutes.
So the pathway of the mystic then is
very much aligned with consciousness
calibration and the kind of work we've
been doing here because what we try to
differentiate is perception from essence
not to be fueled by fooled by
perception.
what people consider to be myself I. You
have to transcend the personal eye and
this is why it is difficult to transcend
the personal eye is almost impossible
for the majority of people. Therefore,
enlightenment is chosen by
one out of 10 million people.
You ask what is your highest goal in
this life? Only one in 10 million will
say become enlightened.
First of all, it's extremely rare, is it
not? If only one in 10 million even
choose it.
Look how rare it must be. And out of
those who choose it, what percentage are
successful? Yes. Because eventually
great sacrifices are necessary that go
the whole way.
People identify themsel as their age,
their body, their sex.
the information from their senses and
how old they are and they also identify
themsel as an animal.
We have an animal side to our nature. We
have both the spiritual side and also
the animal side. So we have difficulty
because many most of the classic
religions tend to vilify the animal
side.
Carnal carnal
If it wasn't for carnality, there
wouldn't be anybody around here to
complain about carnality.
If it wasn't for sexual desire, nobody
would even exist in the physical plane.
All right? So, you're supposed to
repudiate. Well, what it really means is
to stop being run by it. Lust, not to be
run by lust. It doesn't mean you got to
be dead sexually,
although there's a cure for that. on
television. I notice
how to reawaken your animal nature.
So people identify automatically
as most importantly as the doer,
the decider, the chooser, the one who
feels, who who wants, who doesn't like,
who makes decisions.
And in all the previous lectures we try
to emphasize that there is no you making
any decisions about anything at all.
That is all 100% illusion. There is no
personal you that is deciding you know
what to say.
It's happening autonomously.
And you arrive at that observation as
you remove identifying as the personal
self and move into the witness observer.
The witness and the observer
notices that as soon as a decision is
made or something happens there's a
sense a personal eye jumps in there and
claims authorship.
So the hardest thing to get over as a
habit of mind is the claiming of
authorship of a personal eye.
There is no personal eye making any
decisions.
All that is happening autonomously
including the illusion that there is a
personal eye.
Therefore, you don't have to feel guilty
about considering yourself to be an
independent decider and initiator of
actions and thoughts and feelings
because even that is happening
autonomously
without asking your permission.
Here you have a presumption. There is a
personal you that is the initiator and
decider and the doer.
The jump ahead of this illusion
has to be done faster than 110,000th of
a second.
The leading edge of the ego, the
personal eye
instantly jumps in in one 10,000 of a
second and cla and claims to be the
author, the initiator and the
experiencer.
through the spiritual
styles we've been describing, it is
possible to transcend
transcend that. And the mind then
becomes silent. People say, "Well, I've
tried to silence my mind for years and I
can't do it." The harder I try to just
silence it, the more vigorous it
becomes.
And it's because they're looking for it
in a linear Newtonian dimension of
causality.
They're looking for a mind here that's
causing a thought or an action there and
then claiming authorship.
That's a Newtonian dimension.
The way you find the silent source of
all the inner phenomena
is underneath. I I always say there's a
blankness underneath thinkingness. Don't
try to stop thinking this because you'll
just end up as the person who's trying
to stop thinking this
or you'll end up as the person who
doesn't want to think of about himself
as I but he does or otherwise he
wouldn't be trying to transcend that I
think about myself as I
your foot gets stuck in the gum no
matter what you do you know get the gum
off this shoe and it's stuck on this
shoe
how do you get rid of the gum
The sequential thinkingness
and endless bo babble of nonsense having
to do with nothing but perception and
not with essence anyway is totally
worthless.
All your thoughts including your most
treasured wonderful thoughts that you
have embroidered surrounded with silver
and gold are worth nothing.
So you start with humility.
that all thoughts are worth nothing at
all. They're amusement. And where do you
look then for the source of the self?
You look, you don't look amongst
thoughts. You can't find it there. You
look underneath the field of thoughts.
Now, thoughts are like the waves on the
sea coming and going, coming and going.
The waves are always coming and going.
How can you silence the surface of the
ocean? You can't.
How can you find any stillness on the
The nature of the ocean is to have
little waves and big waves and that's
called oceanness.
So the stillness is below the surface of
the ocean, not on the surface of the
ocean. Trying to silence the mind on the
level of the waves on the surface of the
mind is feudal.
No, you dive below the mind underneath
thinkingness. Below thinkingness a
priori
prior to the thinkingness is an infinite
field an energy field of silence.
The silence is present now even as
you listen to the words
that which is speaking is nonsensical.
It's just a peripheral phenomena.
I don't need talking in the slightest
bit. Could dispense with him about the
slightest. Goodbye. Goodbye.
Get the hints.
Underneath that talkingness
is an infinite profound sense of
silence. This is the infinite field of
the self with a capital S, the Buddha
nature, the field of consciousness
itself.
You don't have to join an ash ram and do
all kinds of weird things and eat weird
food and go through weird exercises to
find that which is right obvious below
the surface and constantly present.
>> Sorry.
Guards
arrest this infidel.
Trying to penetrate the silence. Get you
some
infinite silence. Profundity of
consciousness which is not different
than God.
And he's playing his tune machine.
I hate to think of his karma.
The world is an amusement park, is it
not?
Actually, I slipped him five bucks
earlier to do that.
He says, "Okay, doc, if you want it."
Underneath the infinite babble, the
constant babble, talkingness, and
thinkingness, underneath all the air
addition,
you can read thousands and hundreds of
books on God and theology and Jesus and
the church and sin and guilt and all
that.
And
underneath it all is an infinite silence
in which all that becomes obvious. See
infinite silence. So you try to
transcend the identification of yourself
as the thinking mind or the sensations
of the body. The Buddhist said the first
bondage is to the senses.
So
what do you meditate on when you
meditate? What you do is you ask God to
remove your your condition from the
thinkingness the realm of thinkingness
to the infinite silence below it. Now
the infinite silence below it is present
as I talk.
What the hell else do you think is
talking? This voice does a voice
disembodied. Does this voice go around
talking? No. Does this brain go around
by itself talking?
Below the brain, below the thinkingness,
below the mentation,
you put an EEG, put all the wires
around, now you shut them off.
Oh boy, what a relief.
So, we know that e even the EEG shows a
change pattern, a slowing down, uh a
change of the wave pattern. So in
meditation and quietude and
contemplation
uh the frequency of the brain range
drops down to the slow theta range gets
rid of the fast alphas and betas and
stuff that is so entertaining.
It gets down to the very slow less
frequent uh pulse uh eg rate.
So what you look for then without
looking
you're not allowed to look for what
you're looking
first of all don't look for anything
when you're trying to look
you allow the awareness that below the
surface of this talkingness thinkingness
feelingness sensationness
is an infinite silent field which is all
knowing beyond all time beyond all
dimension
not different than divinity itself.
And you surrender to the infinite
presence
which is omnisient, omnipresent,
without beginning, without end. In the
snowbank at age 14 or whatever it was,
the infinite wisdom taught by every
great sage who has ever walked the earth
appeared spontaneously all by itself
without being asked. profound,
transformative
and that which had been uh never was
again you know the illusion that you are
the personal self.
So these uh
by spiritual practices and exercises you
open the door of the likelihood of such
phenomena to occur. It is only a like
likelihood.
It's not even a probability.
On a certain different level, you can
reassure yourself that if you do all
these things,
the presence will reveal itself.
Absolutely.
God cannot deny
cannot deny you.
Can he God deny? Refuse.
Divinity
cannot re deny your request. Resist.
Divinity cannot deny your request.
First of all, you cannot die.
There is no such thing as death.
And to be divinity because it is the
very essence of your own existence
cannot deny
the request for your existence to be
your existence can it?
Divinity does not deny you then.
So what does deny you? Nothing. No
nothing denies you. It's just that you
didn't notice.
You didn't notice that underneath the
listening mind sitting in these chairs.
All that's sitting in this chair, these
chairs are imbeciles.
Ignore them.
They're listening for truth.
Shut up.
Even underneath the talkingness, the
silence is present.
Right? As we talk, infinite space
doesn't disappear just because you put a
carton box here. You know,
to become aware that it's very close,
that the invitation to divinity is
irresistible to divinity. Divinity just
cannot resist an appeal to its own self
arising from itself which has lost its
identity with you like Krishna who
thought he was a cow and had to be
rescued.
Uh
the d the dance of Shiva you're all
familiar with the dance of Shiva. You
know that what you think is depends on
how you look at it and if you look at it
this way it appears to be something
else. This way it's wonderful truth.
This way it's horrible falsehood. The
only changed is your point of view. So
advance of Shiva is Krishna is has to do
with
the world of perception. So
enlightenment is really transcending the
belief in the
reality of perception. Now it doesn't
mean to be in denial that perception
does not exist. It merely means to stop
thinking that it is
uh capable of knowing truth. It cannot
it's not capable of knowing truth.
Uh the perception is then what rules
then the media the media the television
etc. uh the internet uh machine what do
you call those
blogger blogger blog sites you know
bloggerism anyway dominates perception
and people are now fascinated and in a
hypnotic state. People are in a hypnotic
state, a delusional state
of bloggerism.
Resist.
They are in an altered state of
consciousness. Resist.
They are in an alternate state of
consciousness. One that results in the
impairment of the capacity to discern
truth. Resist.
So what perturbs me about the research I
had to do in this last book was that the
constant repetition of falsehood has
injured the capacity to recognize truth
in the majority of mankind.
The capacity to recognize truth. So it's
not the falsehood but the capacity to
recognize truth.
So indoctrination then
which now goes on in all the school
systems the purpose of education is no
longer education but indoctrination.
In fact now they have movies
to indoctrinate kindergarteners to
become atheists. the kindergarteners are
already being indoctrinated by movies
and stories and all in which the this
program. So what happens then is by
constant repetition of that which is
false the things that I am only
concerned about is the capacity to
discern truth and falsehood has been
lost in 40% of of America. Yes.
Is that correct?
uh 40%.
45%.
All right. So, you let me know. Okay.
All right. So, the repetition of
falsehood through the media then
means that the mechanism by which people
can discern
truth from falsehood. The mechanism is
damaged.
the mechanism.
You won't be able to rescue yourself.
I'm glad I don't have children.
I don't know where I'd send them.
Don't know where it's in because the
indoctrination is so blatant, so overt,
starting so young, kindergarten, they're
already starting to brainwash people.
Uhhuh. under the name of freedom,
indoctrination in freedom, which is a
oxymoron.
Freedom means lack of indoctrination,
does it not?
Okay, now they're going to indoctrinate
you with all kinds of secular belief
systems.
So then we we have to uh say goodbye
to u
40% of the population in America
and God knows how much elsewhere that
the capacity to discern reality has been
lost in 40%.
And we pray for them oh Lord
not this lifetime maybe some other maybe
some other realm that that capacity will
be regained.
So the value then of consciousness
research we've done the calibrated
levels and and things is that you are
profoundly protected against this loss
of reality testing and people who
familiar with this work will say yeah
but what does it calibrate at in other
words they're checking perception
against essence checking perception
against essence yeah but what does it
calibrate at so they every time they
talk about a new movie uh that's
everybody's enthralled by some new movie
the first thing we do is calibrate it. I
mean my sense of the essence of it is
that it's frankly grossly evil. I think
well that could be my prejudice you know
so we calibrate it right away you know
uh so to know so that means that we are
aware few we're a very small minority on
the planet that are frankly aware of the
difference between truth and falsehood.
Do you realize that
hardly anybody knows the difference in
truth or and falsehood? Nor do they
really believe know that there is a
difference.
If everybody believes it, it's got to be
true is the way the average person
thinks. Yes.
Therefore, this is a very small
minority. Also very profound.
Very profound.
One last thing.
This uh group here is playing a very
important in counterbalancing the level
of consciousness of all of mankind
resist. This group right here right now
because of its enormous and rear power
is holding the world together to a great
degree. Yes. Do you realize that?
Well, we knew we were good all along,
didn't we?
I could have told him so all along.
We're the only ones that know that we're
imbecillic puppets.
People think they're real.
I don't like to disillusion them. I tell
Yes, you are real. That's right. You
are. You You are. Yes.
All right. Thank you so much. And we'll
get see you again after lunch. God bless
everyone here.
realize how rare it is to have the
company of such company as as we have
here today with each other. We take it
for granted. It's extremely rare. One of
the rarest things on the planet is all
of us here right now. Wow.
Boy. Oh boy. That should last us through
lunch. See you later.
I thought there was somebody in the
room.
I thought there was somebody out there.
Yep. Yep. Yep.
>> Oh, your
Oh, I don't need a soda. I don't need a
soda.
I sort of s sort of don't need a soda
anyway.
The nose is behaving better.
>> Oh, okay. So, I was trying to explain
the the whole way today.
uh the whole way uh things that that are
not known you can't read about etc.
The progressive levels of meditation
take you to new dimensions. So I forgot
to use the word dimension.
Through meditation, you will find
yourself actually in a different
dimension.
And the dimension gets deeper and
deeper. And it's as though you open into
universes. And each universe is more
great than the previous universe. And
you think this certainly must be the
ultimate condition.
And you surrender to the ultimate
condition. And then as you surrender to
the ultimate condition, a dimension far
greater opens up.
Unbelievable.
Beyond beyond then and beyond is beyond.
And then beyond greater yet is greater
yet.
And um the personal self begins to
dissolve and uh
becomes merely the witness, the
observer.
And eventually
uh by surrendering each state to God
one reaches
which I have explained before and but I
will explain it again because I'm
responsible for having said this. So,
I'm saying it and recording it, too. But
I said it.
When all has been surrendered, then
one enters a space beyond all previous
spaces.
Beyond whatever state you are in, there
is yet a state beyond it.
Therefore, constantly keep surrendering.
and ask God for guidance and be uh
willing to experience an even greater
dimension.
People worry about dying. I tell them
don't worry about dying. That's that's
nothing at all.
Eventually
uh you pretty much transcend any
interest in the body and where it is is
not of any particular interest.
And eventually the dimension you reach a
state which I have tried to explain
before
because I feel responsible for your
knowingness of this.
There there is a state beyond beyond all
the prior states.
um a state of pure austerity.
It is like the closest thing I can say
it's like a very high pass.
I've spoken of it before as the high
past because the members of this
audience will be going to those states.
That's why you're in this class. These
are all the Buddhas coming and that's
why you're here. Why else would anybody
be here? So
all the great teachers of the future are
here
are already here in this room.
That is so Lord resist.
All the great teachers of the future are
already here.
So you accept that responsibility
by being here. Yes.
that you will each and every one of you
become the great teachers of the future
if and some of you even in this
lifetime. So
when you surrendered everything to God
through meditation and completion and
letting go all attachments and aversions
one reaches a very high plane
where no one exists. No one there's
nobody there.
This high pass
Uh
you can see you can you can see who's
been there and I as I've said before I
saw those who had been there
and at that level comes the great
temptation which I've described as the
essence of the luciferic.
Now that you know you are beyond all
consequences. Now that you know you
karma no longer applies to you.
All power is yours. Use it. The
temptation then is to utilize
this infinite power which is now yours
for personal you might say
for
power over others
because now you you have the power to
actually take power over domains.
You actually have power over domains.
You've traversed all these domains where
the lower levels of consciousness and
mere mortals have gotten tripped up. And
now you are in a rarified rarified
place.
All power is yours. You're beyond the
consequences of karma.
And the temptation is power for its own
sake.
Power for its own sake. Not because of
some gain of the power. power for its
own sake. And this I call the luciferic
temptation.
The luciferic temptation is power for
its own sake. The satanic temptation is
wickedness. And people in this group
won't have any trouble with getting, you
know, refuting w uh letting go the
attractions of wickedness.
Uh but but the power overall because you
could fall for the illusion that well
you'll only use the power for good. You
mean good as you see it, right?
So it is the ultimate luciferic
temptation.
There is nothing there except the silent
knowingness.
All power is yours. Own it.
And I saw that the Lord Jesus Christ
went through it.
I saw those who went through that high
pass. Very few in number. But anyway,
what was I going to tell you about the
pass? Oh yes.
Uh
and then to to go through the next door
to go through the next door
you realize that you have surrendered
everything. everything,
including even the desire for power over
others.
And then it dawns on you that the one
thing you still have
or the illusion, the belief system you
have, you've let go all attachments and
and aversions, attachments and aversions
is your attachment to life.
Uh oh.
You've let go the attachment to the
details of life. Carninal and money and
power and prestige and excitement and
thrills and spills. Space diving. All of
it.
Canoeing.
All the great temptations. Pizza.
Pizza. Cheeseburgers. You all go.
There is nothing left in this high pass
except your own life.
And you will remember this in this high
pass. There is nothing left but your
identification that you are that which
life is. That you are life. That that
your life radiates forth from your
reality.
You've laid everything down at the feet
of God. everything. You've let
everything this world cherishes.
You've surrendered it all to God through
the pathway of negation. Not this, not
that. Not money, not riches, not looks,
not fame, not fortune.
You've got nothing left. You've given it
all away. Surrendered it all. No
attachments, no virgins.
And now, what have you got left to
surrender to God?
your life.
You have to surrender your life to God.
And this is the high pass beyond all
high passes. We have permission to
calibrate the high pass. It's over 900,
930, 925, 930 at about level 925.
uh
some of you will be reaching that
otherwise you wouldn't be in this class
or else would you be in a class on how
to transcend
and 25 to a thousand unless you were
destined for that you understand you're
listening to your own destiny so in that
life then you realize I have nothing
left oh god
Except my life itself. I surrender my
life to thee, oh Lord.
And with that there's a terrible fear of
dying.
There is an agony of dying.
When you experience the agony of dying,
you know you're in the right place.
This is the agony that you agreed to go
through to get to the other side.
that which you have believed throughout
all these lifetimes, all the way back to
eternity practically
down to the level of the bacteria. All
through the evolution of life, all
through the evolution of consciousness,
that which you have believed is the very
core and source of your existence, you
are now asked to surrender.
Then the fear of non-existence comes up
again now in a different level. Yeah.
Now comes the knowingness.
It's safe to lay down your life to God
because all fear is illusion.
That was the knowingness that came out
of I don't know how many lifetimes ago,
nine, 10 lifetimes ago. All fear is
illusion.
So out of nowhere because there's nobody
up there with you in this space. There's
no otherness.
There is only the infinite knowingness.
The infinite knowingness has to come
through with an absolute certainty of
those who have walked through the past.
Uhhuh.
All fear is illusion. And so you lay
down your life and surrender it and give
it to God.
And then
and then
the splendor of divinity
shines forth
as the as all that exists now or ever
more.
Yes.
We have permission to calibrate that. Oh
Lord, that opening beyond the door
calibrates at 1,00 is just that is the
doorway to 1,000 to the knowingness of
divinity.
Aha.
You thereby have owned
your own divinity.
You own your own divinity and you stop
denying it.
And now you the self with the smallest S
has become truly the self with a capital
S.
The surrender is beyond recall.
Once having surrendered your life,
you cannot recall it. Now you have no
control over your life from that point
on.
Oh dear.
Now, what'll I do?
Oh, dear.
What do you do then? Oh, well, you
teach. Oh, I didn't even know what it
was.
I guess if you're willing to do so, and
I think it was by karmic agreement that
I agreed to do so,
then you serve
God. You by serving your fellow man
by loving and serving your fellow man,
you serve God. They're not different.
They are not God or your fellow man.
They are God as your fellow man.
Oh god. What more could you want?
Finding out that all cheeseburgers are
God. Oh boy. I thought I had to give up
cheeseburgers to find God. And you find
that cheeseburgers are God.
Infinite
divinity expressing itself as a
cheeseburger.
The more you love God, the more you love
a cheeseburger.
the higher states take you through and
we've mentioned some of them
uh joy, bliss,
uh ecstasy.
Many of those states I went through here
at the chapel of the Holy Cross. When I
came back out here many decades ago, the
Chapel of the Holy Cross was open all
night. The visitors were all gone by
5:00.
Population of this town was only, I
don't know, 850 or something. Anyway, by
5:00, all the the visitors had gone
and you had the chapel of the Holy Cross
completely to yourself.
In those days they left the candles
burning all night and they left the
beautiful music playing all night. So
there you had the chapel of the Holy
Cross all to yourself all night long.
You could meditate
and uh read states of extreme ecstasy.
I found out that you have to let go the
ecstasy also
that beyond ecstasy. I thought this this
oh lord I can't lay down. The joy was so
phenomenal as a Rama Krishna ex
experience it the ecstatic joy
the presence of God is infinite joy
is ecstatic ecstasy beyond any ecstasy
that one experiences in the ordinary
human domain. This is ecstasy.
Ecstasy on the level of a universe like
a universe of ecstasy.
This too you have to surrender and
beyond the ecstasy
lay the infinite peace. So I remember
surrendering kneeling at the older
and then the ecstasy.
at the feet of the Lord. Yeah.
And then came the infinite peace beyond
which there is no understanding. Yes.
Right.
I wanted to make sure that that
knowingness is imprinted for the day
that it will be recalled
because I've known all along these are
the Buddhas of the future.
These are the great teachers here now
present.
Why else would you be here? This is not
a course on tennis.
If you're going to be great tennis
players, I would be a great tennis
coach.
It's not on tennis. Therefore, everyone
here is profoundly spiritually committed
u now and for the future. So, it must
have been something you said. Well, you
can always change your mind later and
say,
"I'll go back to booze and gambling and
women, you know,
except you won't be you you can't go
back. It's not possible to go back
because now you know better. Once you've
experienced higher celestial realms,
you won't settle for less anymore. You
won't settle for less. Uh only the most
ecstatic. All right. So we'll go to the
next uh next.
So that should handle union mystica. The
ecstasies uh joys and
difficulties of the great Christian
mystics are written uh in the literature
and their stories are indeed heartening.
And when that state of profound love
comes and disappears, you feel like God
has deserted you. Oh, where hast thou
gone, my love? Where hast thou gone?
And um
recent saint who died recently uh wrote
of that
um Mother Teresa. Yes. Uh went into high
states and then wondered where has where
has divinity gone? Yes.
expecting however divinity to take the
form of Jesus Christ which I thought was
what her difficulty was because it
doesn't necessarily take the form of a
figure much less a divine figure in the
high past there was no form there there
was no personage no entity
nothing with the name nothing came out
of the clouds and said I am God I'm
Jesus I am Buddha
The knowingness was nonlinear,
all prevailing, all pervasive, all
inclusive.
Yes. Because if you were waiting for the
personage of Jesus, that would leave out
all that is not Jesus, would it not? No.
The presence of divinity is allness, not
a personality as such. So that was uh
understandable.
So you've let go of identifying yourself
as
the physicality or its senses,
much less delineations, sex, age, that
you're part of the animal kingdom. You
let go of identifying yourself as your
history. I was born so and so and I had
these and that other experiences
and oh I remember that and I can recall
that. So now you think you are this
I am the physicality born such and such
a place and it went through all these
various
experiences which and and emotions and
feelings
and it ends up with desires and
aversions.
So the pathway, the direct pathway is to
let go of all attractions, all desires,
all wants and all negations. Neither
negation nor attraction.
You give up seeing yourself as the
decider, the chooser, the source of
valition. You give up the naivity that
you are the cause of anything.
You're not the cause of anything.
The infinite power of consciousness is
so profound to think that little puny
you could decide be the decider of
anything is a great pomposity.
The poopy little ego that doesn't have
as much power as my little finger can
hardly be the great decider of all your
life decisions.
Now something very very profound is
making the decisions and it's not your
personal self at all. So you begin to
see that when you let go of the
pomposity and grandiosity that there is
a personal you that is making choices
and decisions
that such an entity would be talking
right now and if he did I want anything
to do with them.
What do I want with anybody that talks
this way?
some kind of a nut job, wouldn't you
say?
So, you can't be the doer or you'd be an
idiot.
Neither can you be recipient.
So, in the high high places, there is no
other. There is not an other. There is
no archangel talking to you.
There is no spirit guide talking to you.
There's nothing floating around with
wings speaking to you.
There is no other. And as much as you
are all that is, how could there be an
other?
Great spiritual error.
One of very famous religion came out of
believing that some archangel was the
source of the the knowingness.
Yeah.
That which you are eventually becomes
the teacher, the knower is all in the
one. And there is no doingness involved.
If you uh if your reality of the self is
all that there is, all that there is,
how could there be an other o e? What
would the other be? It would have to be
not self with a capital S. Therefore, it
could hardly be divinity.
People who get their spiritual
instructions from otherness are prone to
fallacy. And very often before too many
years when you calibrate them early and
you calibrate them later you see they
fail drastically because how can there
be some other entity?
The other entity is hardly going to be
an angelic or divine one. Could they be?
Why would some other entity
want to interfere with your becoming a
Buddha unless its intention was to make
sure you don't become a Buddha because
the Buddha does not take instructions
from some other in Buddha land.
There is no other. By definition, the
Buddha nature is complete and total
allness. So how could there be some
other?
I'm the Buddha of allness and now some
other voice comes out of the
ethers
dictating things to me. You see the self
the negation the absurdity of such a
claim. Yes. So the teachers who get
their instructions from others are
somewhere along the line. I'm not saying
the bad but they are not the ultimate
state of of teacher.
All right? So you give up the illusion
that you are the the doer, you're the
winner, you're the loser, or that there
is anything to get. There is nothing to
get.
There is only the realization of the
truth of what you are. That's all.
There's nothing to get.
Even to get that truth is is to lose
because that would be a belief system.
You have to let go all belief systems.
Forget about the Buddha nature,
all that hulum,
Jesus nature, Buddha nature,
Mohab nature, whatever nature you want
to call it.
But the minute you give it a name, you
give it a limitation. The minute it's
eliminated, the minute you have a
limitation, then it is not the oldness,
is it? Now it becomes the Buddha. If you
meet the Buddha, kill him.
If you meet a Buddha on the road, kill
him.
Why? Because you know he's a devil. You
know, pretending to be a Buddha. If you
were a Buddha, you wouldn't be a Buddha.
Here on the Buddha road telling me
you're a Buddha.
Doom. Doom cuffs. Doomcuff.
You're not the doer. You don't not
receive anything.
You're not winning anything. You're not
losing anything. And there's nothing to
get. There's nothing to get. There's
only to to own the fullness of your
being. Now, most people through
the limitation of the ego
feel that to own the truth of that which
they are is being grandiose.
Yep. Grandio. They're afraid. Oh, I'll
be grandiose if I think I'm this or that
or something. Huh? I'm afraid I'll be
grandiose.
In the enlightened state, you are beyond
victim perpetrator.
Victim perpetrator.
All right. You can see our whole society
riddled by this illusion that out there
in the world there's always a victim and
a perpetrator.
By projecting victim perpetrator as a
dualistic belief system, you can see
victim and perpetrator everywhere.
Look at these poor victims here. They've
been cut loose from their roots.
Look at these poor things are going to
be used up and burnt. Burnt.
Look at the poor wife's going to get him
by.
Look at the poor tin can which is going
to litter the landscape and ruin the
entire environment.
Here's the great destroyer of our entire
environment. Oh, woe is us. Whoa. We
were going to we're going to give up
eating meat. You know why, don't you? I
don't want to say it.
But you know what the cattle do out
there? Emit methane.
That causes environmental warming. Ah.
Ah. Yes.
There's no end to Looneyville, right?
Yes.
You you give up intellection, education.
You only have left after you've left
everything go on sort of an intuitive
attraction.
You let go of time tracks, ideas of the
past, the present, the future.
And now you can see you're in a a
dimension with no points of reference.
Beyond time, there's no point of
reference. Beyond location, there's no
point of reference. You're in the middle
of nowhere and everywhere
simultaneously.
At that point, fear arises that you're
lost.
The best thing to do there is to rejoice
that you are lost.
Oh God, I am lost. I don't know where
I'm in time, space. I've forgotten my
name.
And I'm glad these things are attached
to my body or I would have left them.
So the way then to Yunio Mystica
is progressive levels of consciousness.
I think uh
there and the levels are are well
described in transcending levels. Uh the
book transcending levels just you know t
it takes you through the levels that
saves you that one book saves you three
or four lifetimes of monk being a monk
save you being a monk you don't have to
be monk
familiarity saves many lifetimes of
being a monk resist look at all the
monkism I saved you monks eat poorly you
get thin grrul and porridge
and you get to pray all morning work in
the garden all afternoon weeding
And they had to get a little fin
porridge again at four.
Anybody still want to be a monk? Monks.
So you have to be cured of monkism. The
romance of the monk. That's the romance
of the monk. You see? Happily I was
saved from it.
I was saved from it. It there was a
passing attraction of being a monk for a
while. Yeah. And uh anyway,
the monks are still meditating. They're
still there in the same place.
Still pulling up turn turnups and weeds
and having thin grill for breakfast.
After you have enough lifetimes of thin
grl
and mortification of the body. Oh god.
Mortification of the body.
Why keep it warm when it's cold out? No,
you can shiver.
Why stay cool when it's hot out? No. Why
feed it when it's hungry? Why?
So you can mortify the body. Will that
release you from the identification with
the body?
All vote votes who think it will say I.
You are not destined to be monks.
All right? So you see each one of the
things we mention is a pitfall along the
way. you you get off on mortification of
the body. You know, I can remember
learning how to go without eating or
sleeping or anything that you're you you
think that you have to have to survive.
And I thought I found you could
transcend them all. You can go almost
endlessly. You go into instead you go
into an altered state of consciousness.
And in that altered state, I told you I
used to try and walk through walls.
Well, I used to walk through walls.
It's because I wasn't in my physical
body, but I didn't realize that. And
after I came back in my physical body, I
didn't realize I had rejoined it. And I
can remember walking right smack into a
wall at full tilt. Bang, bang, bang.
That was the same monastic existence
where I would get surprised by seeing
somebody in the mirror. You know, see
somebody in the mirror and I would get
frightened. there's somebody in the
place with me and I didn't realize it
was uh this body. So, you do go through
phases of disbodiment. Well, you think
you're going crazy in all this unless
you hear a crazy story like this. You
hear crazy monks. Well, I was the crazy
monk. In other words, the phenomena that
you go through as you advance in levels
of consciousness
are not common place. uh so unless you
look uh to people who have knowledge of
the experience you will not find any
explanation
and they will the family will talk about
having you put away you see so it's good
to have spiritual friends who are aware
of what you're doing and it's good to
have uh uh somebody with whom you're
sympathetic sympatico
uh and all people in serious spiritual
work should have to have connections
with people who are aware that you are
into serious spiritual work and uh and
and prepared to deal with the
exingencies that arise. Another one that
arises and uh which I forgot to mention
is uh because you are exhilarating karma
intense spiritual inner work you're
really exhilarating your karma and you
rise above your karma and when you do
that pulls up the next stack. So the
thing about rapid spiritual evolution is
that you spend a lot of time being sick.
We're not full of good news this
morning, are we? No.
What happens is you're pulling up these
stacks. What you're doing is you're
exhilarating evolution. You're
exhilarating. So an intensely committed
spiritual student may be pulling up in
one lifetime. You know, the negative
karma of 10 or 15 lifetimes or even more
which may take the expression of phys
physical illness.
There is somewhere on some writing about
the mystic some one of them writes be
prepared to spend half your time in bed
which I thought was a little
pessimistic.
However, I just I'm going to put out a
book called self-healing in which I
include the things that I myself live
through and it is a little depressing
when you look at it all come to think of
it.
It's because you're pulling up stacks.
In other words, you're pulling up in one
lifetime uh the the negativities that
you have suppressed and expressed as
physicalities in many a lifetime. And so
I can remember I went through ulcers and
migraines and gout and all kinds of uh
disabilities. However, don't forget each
one of them also has a cure. Each one of
them uh had a cure. uh chiropractic
uh acupuncture diet, sugar-free diets,
various things, various meditative
styles, yoga things. So, each one of
them was transcended otherwise I
wouldn't be standing here talking to you
and standing here talking to you.
Migraine headaches were the worst and
they seemed to be uh intractable.
Intractable. I had one chiropractor that
knew how to fix it. I'd lay down on the
table, he'd get my head and he like that
boy, the migraine would be gone. Then
one day I went to his office, he'd moved
out of town.
Gee whiz. Didn't even tell me he was
going out of town. I mean, he without
him I was ready to die and he leaves
town and doesn't even tell me he's
leaving. He'll suffer for that, too. But
anyway,
I said, "Oh, God, now what? Oh, God, now
what? Oh, God, now what?" And somebody
I'd done a spiritual favor for
just dropped the note, dropped the
information to me that they had just
discovered a a medicine that cures
migraine called Imitrix. So, I got
Imitrix and so my chiropractor left, but
I got Imitrix.
So
life has its problems but it also has
its solutions. It has its migraine but
it also has chiropractors. It also has
limit.
So life has cures for these various
things and you get hypoglycemic uh
insulin shock and you learn to quit
eating sugar and sweets and go on a
sugar-free diet etc. So there's a cure
for all of these ailments.
Uh did we finish all of our charts? Oh
golly. How am I going to get off here?
Oh yes. All right. So as you let go
wanting to control uh aversions and
attractions, you eventually will
transcend the limitation of the
experiencer.
You will eventually suddenly come out on
the other side of the experiencer.
You become
that which is uh you might say
happening.
And I always compare it to
the recording uh the oldfashioned tape
recorder had a recording jack and it had
a monitoring jack. And you'll see that
one
one 10,000 of a second. The ego jumps in
and claims to be the author of
experience. to transcend that one
10,000 of a second
is is what happens when you finally
transcend the limitations and
identification with the personal ego.
Now you experience all that is as it is
as it is and it's nonsequential.
Nothing is happening in sequence. It's
only perceived to be in sequence. So you
stop identifying with the perceiver,
the perceiver and the experiencer and
then you are into the world of
enlightenment.
To get there you become the witness, the
observer. You're the watcher of
emergence.
You then become the knower of awareness.
Eventually you end up as consciousness
itself.
The easiest way to get there
is by allowing the idea of a personal
eye to
uh to be willing to relinquish that and
to own yourself as the witness and the
observer.
You are the witness and you are the
You are not the cause.
You're not the perpetrator. You're not
the victim. You're not any other of the
languaging,
none of the concepts, any concepts. You
drop all the concepts.
You are not any of those things.
It's easy to become
conscious that you are the witness of
phenomena. The witness.
What's happening today? I'm reporting
now from the viewpoint of the witness.
To the witness, the room seems to be
full of people. people and it seems like
there is some personage here called the
doc who's talking to them but I don't
know that that's true do I that's just
what the perceiver is telling me is
happening yes
all right so the
what happens then is instead of being
the decider
instead of being the main actor in the
middle of the drama of life you become
merely the witness of it. That is not a
difficult
that is not a difficult step to take. It
is not really hard to let go of the
egotism that there is some wondrous
entity called I
who is having these experiences.
The sheer egotism is rather obvious to
spot.
The best you can say that is closer to
the truth. How would you know what the
eye is experiencing that you claim
is because you're the witness of it. Ah,
now you can see closer to truth and
closer to reality is that you are the
witness. You are the witness and you are
the observer. Uhhuh. From the witness
and the observer, you can move off being
the experiencer.
You are the witness and the observer of
what thinks it is the experiencer.
All right. From these states then it is
easy to move into the realms of light,
love and what I call radiance.
The states are not states that can be
languaged.
All of you have done any kind of deep
meditation know that as you go past one
realm and allow yourself to go into an
even greater realm there there is like a
radiance and this radiance is
accompanied by a field of knowingness
which cannot really be described but it
changes the dimension in which you are
holding your own existence and the
existence of all all else and
it is autonomous and these are the
states of illumination.
So the mystic enters illuminated states
in which it the context is illuminated.
It's one thing to read about a truth to
memorize the truth and then there's it's
another thing to have a a total
realization of it. So as I say certain
music let's say certain music is the
music yes is beautiful the music of
Andre Bochelli
is beautiful
but it isn't just the sound of the music
what happens is the sound of the music
is enchanting
you listen to the music and you go oh oh
it's the oh you go into that is the
healed. So, but Chel is a mechanism.
Yes, his music is beautiful, but that
isn't all that it's about. No, it's the
awareness consciousness level that goes
with it. Because of the beauty of his
music, you go into an enchanted divine
state of Oh,
it's dangerous to play when you drive
because you could just drive off the
road and say
when you get into the ecstasy of such
beauty of such beauty, time stops. how
long it takes you to drive someplace
becomes irrelevant because the joy of
the presence of the beauty. So
aesthetics is another way to
spiritual awareness
the love of aesthetics. Uh and in the
highest states the state can only be
described as hyper aesthetic beyond
aesthetics.
When the final doorway opens up and the
beauty of
and the radiance of all existence shines
forth,
it is divinity that you are witnessing.
The divinity expresses itself as all
that exists
and be a and beyond the
apparent physical isness
is the more profound exquisite
stunning beauty of existence itself.
All that exists shines forth with the
radiance of divinity and one is struck
dumb and at that point the mind stops.
The mind falls back in awe
because one is aware that you are
witnessing divinity in its expression as
allness.
The death of the personal self of course
is gone now
gone now by virtue of revelation by the
radiance of divinity
and by the ensuing awe.
The awe
continues
and finally in order to be able to
function in the world again and that
would be the definition of a true mystic
has learned to transcend the awe
because the awe is
what can we say beyond all brilliance
beyond all breathtakingness beyond all
imagination
The revelation of divinity as allness
paralyzes you. And now
to continue on,
you have to transcend awe itself.
You cannot just get paralyzed out with
awe and fall over.
You can, but then you won't become a
teacher.
you'll become a dead would have been
So we don't want a room full of dead
would have been would have been
teachers.
So I prepare you now in advance because
at the moment of knowing this you will
remember what I'm saying because the
vibration in your aura now throughout
all time that when the awe shines forth
its stunningness is beyond all
imagination
and at that point you can
surrender and die or
you can transcend it. You can transcend
even the awe of the presence of divinity
because if the will of God is for you to
continue on, then that will be so.
Uh and if the will of God is for you to
succumb and fall over in a state of
catatonic ecstasy, then that will
happen.
Either way, it's all right.
You fall over dead with joy. Stop
breathing.
Great. Out of the body again. Thank God.
Or you transcend it and then you see
that you have more to do yet. Oh, thank
you God that I have more that I can do
or more that I can do. How can I be of
service to to thee, oh Lord, in your
expression as all of humanity? And so
many people devote their lives then
to the alleviation of suffering in all
of its forms,
including the suffering of all sensient
beings.
Being an animal doctor, being a
veterinarian
to me is a very holy practice.
The dog comes in in agony, the kitty,
and you relieve its suffering.
What more
can you do for God's creation?
So,
if you find to be reborn, I choose to be
a holy veterinarian.
veterinarian.
Well, we're all animals. So, every
doctor is a veterinarian only of people.
All the doctors here, you're just you're
nothing but veterinarians, but of
people. People animals instead of doggy
animals or kitty animals or horsey
animals.
All right. Now, we wanted to stop early
today for some reason.
And of course, you remember the reason
we I wanted to finish these five things.
We did. All right. Now, we wanted to
know if we had a couple minutes left for
private discussion of a thing or two.
>> Yes.
>> What?
>> Well, no. just that the purpose of life
is to serve God yourself because you're
part of the people of God and your
fellow man. So by spiritual effort,
you're accomplishing all three because
God wants you to become illuminated. So
by serving yourself, you serve God and
fulfill his
uh that sounds anthropomorphic his
desire for you anyway, his possibility
for you. You serve God, your fellow man,
and then uh serve yourself, God, and
your fellow man. Yes. And uh we were
going to discuss anything that might be
of interest that somebody mentioned. And
uh yes, I don't remember what it was
though.
Mike, there's Pete there. Maybe Jack.
Mike.
Oh. Oh.
As you can see on the mystic, we could
spend
the entire day on just one of these.
>> That's the screen going up.
I thought maybe I said something wrong.
You know,
>> you're next.
>> The words are you're next.
>> Oh my god.
>> Um my question is, you know, everybody
wants to have or be where you're at in
in your uh spiritual quest, although a
lot of us don't want to work that hard
for it.
Oh, I realize that,
>> you know. I mean,
>> yes.
>> I Well,
>> I make it sound arduous.
>> Well, it is because I've seen you go
through, you know, aches and pains and
um remember when we were in Korea and
you said that you had, you know, you had
you achd all over sometimes when you
were hit with something that was below
200 broken. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And um and so you know, I mean,
I've seen you go through some of that.
And um now it doesn't it doesn't really
ache anymore uh when it used to. Now
it's more or less that your your whole
energy is zapped and that you have to
lay down, you know, to in order to cope
with it. So it's not that you so there
is relief kind of at the end of the
tunnel but I mean I've seen you go
through those things and I just thought
people should know that that
>> is sheer exhaustion.
>> It's sheer exhaustion. Yeah. But I mean
I also you went through physical pain
too because you would lay down and you
felt like all your joints achd and
everything would hurt and and um
>> you would have to lay down for a short
time to recover. But it was usually when
you were hit with something that was
below 200 or something that it was um
>> had to clear from the collective.
>> You had to clear from the collective or
you know you had to clear from yourself
>> that would from past lifetimes or
something that's come up. So it it
really isn't all fun in games
to get to get where you're at. I mean,
is it?
>> Uh well, I didn't you know, it's travail
to witness it in another. On the other
hand, that that is the commitment that
you make when you get married to to be
the companion when another one goes
through whatever their anguishes are
that they are to
>> to go through. So, um,
uh, the only concern that I ever have
about it is that it will be distressing
to you. That's
>> the easiest thing to watch. I mean, you
know.
>> Well, I know. That's what I just got
through saying, the fact that it's
distressing.
>> But, but I mean, it is
>> But you see, I have the distress of
knowing that you're distressed. Well,
it's also part of who you are and what
um and what your commitments are, too.
>> But you get distressed and then I get
distressed that you're distressed.
>> Yeah.
>> Distress times distress. You go distress
squared. Right.
>> But it it is I mean it isn't all
>> Well, that's what relationship is about,
is it not?
>> Yes. But it's not all, you know, uh, oh,
God's going to bless you because there
are other things that come with that is
what I'm trying to say. You know, it
isn't like it's all blessings and you
have this wonderful outlook on life. No,
it's because
>> it's actually carrying the weight of a
lot of negative things on you too. Well,
you you then take on some effort for the
collective, you see, and it was moving
and pulling forth things from the
collective which I knew had the power to
clear that occasion those sink let's
have to that's correct if that is
correct. Okay. So, it's pulling forth
from the collection come from the
collective consciousness
or things that I know people cannot
clear for themsel or don't have the
power to clear it for themselves. So you
try to take advantage of
whatever capacity you have, you know,
still remaining in this life to clear
what you can for all of mankind.
>> Mhm.
>> When I see a child
in in a in a dark country
lying there half starving to death and I
realize in and out themselves, they
don't have the capacity and neither do
their parents to relieve their
suffering.
So that brings forth the desire
to clear in the collective that which is
unwilling to sacrifice itself for the
good of others.
>> Yeah.
Yes.
>> Well um you know last a couple of time a
couple of seminars ago we talked about
prayer. Um, I have to share with
everybody. We were um we have a cabin
that's up north and we were there and
there was a a mother with two fawns with
her and um one of them was limping and
was obviously hurt and um so I pointed
out to Dave that you know this little
fawn is limping around there and she
kept kind of close because we had food
and water out for him and um so they
kept kind of close to the cabin and I
kept eyeing it. Well, when we left the
cabin, you know, Dave says, "I'm going
to pray pray for this fawn." You know,
so all week long he prayed for this
little fawn at night. And the next
morning, we went back and the fawn was
walking.
>> So,
it just kind of confirmed that um
prayers are answered.
It affirms the oneness of all of life.
One of the most profound experiences
society had a few decades back.
There was these duck hunters. This this
hunter and the hunter there, the ducks
were flying over and the hunter shot a
duck and apparently it was a male duck.
>> Mhm. And it came down to earth with its
wings broken.
And then its mate
swept down,
opened her wings,
and sheltered him.
Anyway,
the hunter gave up.
He went the the hunter went through a
powerful transformation.
powerful
illuminating transformation because what
was revealed to him was the sacredness
of all life.
Tens of thousands of hunters when they
heard the story saw the picture
of the mother
sheltering him, the injured Drake.
>> Tens of thousands of hunters gave honey.
Let's see.
Tens of thousands,
40,000, 50,000,
45,000.
Close to 50,000 hunters were so struck
by the energy of the heart
that they gave up hunting as a sport.
Hunting because you're hungry is one
thing. Huntering, hunting for the fun of
killing is quite something else. You
see?
So when you see that all life loves its
own life.
So it changed uh it changed the whole
context of hunting for a whole
generation. That was a whole generation
that gave up hunting. You know target
practice. Yes. Trap shooting, ski
shooting, you know. I was an excellent
ski shooter. ski
and uh but killing for the sake of
killing was no longer a pleasure. See,
>> if you need meat, go to bashes.
Well,
>> you don't have to kill Bambi,
>> much less my my Bambi or anybody's
Bambi, you know,
>> to uh to let life live. Unless, you
know, if unless you have to sacrifice
lower life to higher life, which is
>> which is somewhat different, right?
Taking on a higher counter for the good
>> of life. But uh it was transformative. I
remember any everybody who saw and heard
and read of that story was profoundly
affected by it.
>> The picture of her with her arms out was
trying to shelter him.
>> Um, it's almost time for us to break. We
don't It's time for us to break. We
don't have a whole lot of time. It's
time for us to break.
>> And then what do we do, sweetheart? Then
we're going to do question and answer.
>> Oh. Oh,
we're going to take a break now.
>> Yes, it's 3:00.
>> She said we're going to take a break
now.
>> Um, if you have any questions, uh, line
up on this side of the auditorium. If
you have, uh, books that need to be
signed, lined up on this one. We will
sign and answer questions. Also, um, go
ahead and say what you were going to
say. I didn't mean to r
>> Oh, uh, no, you've already given them
instructions. Okay.
Is this mic on?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Mic on.
>> My name happens to be Mike as well. So,
yes,
>> Mike's on.
>> Great.
>> Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Okay. All right.
>> Go ahead.
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins, f first of all, thank
you very much for all of your teachings.
My grateful
In the past you've mentioned Dr. uh
sorry Robert Monroe and his work in the
Monroe Institute.
>> Yes.
>> Is it beneficial for a seeker to uh go
through any of his programs or
>> Well, a teacher has a a different uh you
know different just not just personal
enlightenment but also education. So
there was a period where I investigated
alternate spiritual pathways quite a
number of them visited a number of
teachers uh did their trainings uh
became acquainted with the whole field
of what's possible out there. the
Monurro Institute uh was very
interesting
uh for a person who's curious and uh and
also for people who are skeptical
because uh you've never been out of
body. There's nothing more fun than
going learning how to go out of body on
command
and uh visit various astral realms.
And as I've said before, Bob Monroe, he
had the most peaceful voice I've ever
heard.
>> Bob Monroe's voice.
He's like infinite peace. Incredible,
you know. And of course, his his
personal story itself is
>> Yes.
>> Journeys out of the body is a very
fascinating book.
>> Yes, it is.
>> Yeah.
>> So, is it beneficial for a student to go
through those or is it
>> as a learning experience? I found it
interesting. It doesn't add towards
enlightenment though. No,
>> it could be a serve distraction. Thank
you.
>> It can be a distraction because you can
get caught in, you know, various astral
realms and fool around there for for uh
centuries probably.
>> Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
You spent 10 days on your back with
earphones on.
>> Yes.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
I guess I'm nervous. Uh, even though we
don't speak English and understanding
English, but we are all away from come
from Korea. I just want to know why are
we here? Do we have any
You're here because we're here because
we're here because we're here.
I guess because I can't make the trip
anymore. I made it I think three times.
>> Whatever times it was, it was uh it was
all that I could do. And I I can't I
don't have the strength and the stamina
now.
spend 10 or 12 hours in a in
what do you call those airports and
various things, you know, and then we
missed the plane to we missed the plane
to Korea. We got to the airport. It was
pitch black.
The plane to Korea left yesterday.
There we are in San Francisco. Colder
than I'll get out. No plane
in the airport and a cab won't stop for
you in an airport.
You you go like this and they just drive
right by. No cab, no plane, no friend,
no no mama,
all fire lonesome. Yeah.
>> So it's not like, you know, we come here
all with the videotapes. So maybe we we
are here because we all meant to be here
in our
>> Oh yes. You're talking about intention
otherwise you wouldn't be here. You have
chosen as an option to be here. Yes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> I uh actually uh going to Korea.
>> Mhm.
>> I greatly enjoy the country and
everything about it and I love the
people. I love the whole style of that
society.
>> I love the reverence for each other.
Each person greets each other thusly.
Therefore, you don't get the gross
vulgarity that you do here. How can you
be grossly vulgar after meeting somebody
and uh
recognizing the god within you? You see,
so uh if they had supersonics, if they
would put the supersonics back on, I
would go to Korea.
>> I think they do have a
>> No, they don't have one.
No, I think they have a bad special bad.
Thank you, sir.
>> If they put the Super Sonics back on. I
never could understand why they took
them off. One got a flat tire because
there was something laying in the on the
tarmac. Well, what's that got to do with
it? Nothing. So, I thought there's other
reasons for it that they don't want to
share with the world, you know.
But I thought some country, Korea or
China, would pick up on the supersonics
because people don't want to spend all
day in the airport and then all day on a
plane and then all day at the other end.
They want to get on a supersonic jet and
be there in two or three hours. So I
think there's a huge industry waiting
and I think there's various politics and
shenanigans going on behind it because
the supersonics did not have a single
accident for what was it 26 years or
something and then one got a flat tire
and that brought down the whole
industry? I don't believe that. Do you?
You think the whole industry collapsed
because one supersonic got a flat tire
on the tarmac? I don't think so.
We haven't had time to check it out with
the arm. You know, there's so many
things we could check out.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> I'm glad you're here.
>> How do you say it in Korean? What do you
say?
>> Say it to me.
>> Ka.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Such a a gift today.
Thank you so much.
>> That's mine. Yeah. Um the question I
have that I would really like to know I
find I get confused by um you speak of
there is no doer and there is no
recipient. We're not making choices
and then
>> there is no personal self.
There is no personal self.
And
>> so how do we get um the wrong choices
like the false gurus or the could we not
just surrender and if you end up with
the wrong at the wrong place at the then
you can't end up at the wrong place at
the wrong time. Is that what I'm
hearing?
>> No, I'm talking about the idea
that the originator that all the
intention is coming from an independent
personal self. actually it's not coming
from that. So
the personal self says well I decided to
sign the book. I a separate personal
self is the initiator of this action now
taking place.
>> Not God.
>> The ego says there's a personal eye
doing this. In reality there isn't a
personal eye doing this.
>> As a consequence of the totality of this
whole situation now present. this arm
goes forward and signs it because that's
the expectation
that is in the air. You might say,
"Yeah,
there isn't any personal self making a
decision."
As soon as an action occurs,
the personal self jumps in in one
thousandth of a second and claims, "Oh,
I decided to sign these books.
I didn't decide to sign these books at
all.
>> I didn't know anything about it. She
hands them over and the arm goes like
this. And I say to myself, should I sign
these? I don't know. I didn't ask
myself, did I?
So all of life is is emergent rather
than causal.
The potentiality emerges for this to
happen. It's not caused by anything.
If it was caused, there would be no
freedom. Therefore, there'd be no karma.
There'd be no freedom because all
everything would be determined. So
to believe in a personal eye is to
believe in really materialistic
reductionism and naive causality
sort of primitive Newtonian cause
causality.
It's the totality of the universe.
Totality of the universe throughout all
of time
>> that that that
is responsible for this arm moving in
front of you this moment.
Without the last second, this second
couldn't occur, could it?
It took the evolution of all It took all
of evolution, of all of creation, all of
time to reach the point where this arm
reaches out and signs this book.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> The awareness does not arise out of
reason. It arise out of sort of
intuiting.
that everything that happens is is it's
a consequence of the of of the whole,
not of the part.
>> Hi, we don't have a question. We just
wanted to sit across from you and thank
you.
>> What?
>> We just wanted to sit across from you
and thank you.
>> Yes,
>> that's all.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Oh, I got a freebie, huh?
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> Oh, thank you. so much.
>> Yeah.
>> This won't hurt, will it?
>> Yeah, that's what the guy says. Does it
hurt? No, only when I laugh.
>> Yeah, I don't have a question either. I
just wanted to sit here and be with you
>> your presence and thank you.
>> Uh yes, please.
>> I'll tell you a story as long as you're
here.
>> Okay, sure.
>> This cowboy is out in the country by
himself and he hears this groaning
coming from behind a rock.
He goes around the rock and there's a
cowboy laying there with an arrow
through his chest. He says, "Oh my god,
man. Doesn't that hurt?" This is only
when I laugh.
>> That's funny.
>> Thank you for the story.
Thank you, S.
>> All right.
>> That's a funny punchline.
You can use it once in a while in life.
You know, say, "Well, how is something?"
You say, "Only when I laugh." Yeah.
Thank you.
>> Hallelujah.
Hallelujah.