Ah.
I was wondering where I was and I
discovered I'm right here.
Oh, what a relief.
It's always you're always right here and
it's always right now. That makes life
simple, doesn't it?
What else do you need to know? Nothing
else really. We were on slide one of
this uh
uh this a difficult subject reality
isn't it? Most people spend their whole
life puzzling it
and frankly never make much progress
with it.
It kept me in business for 50 years.
They send them from the view to my
office.
Paradigms of reality, huh? All right. Is
this lighting the way it's supposed to
be now? Yes.
>> Yep.
>> We can resume.
>> I presume we will resume.
All right. We were on this first one.
Okay. So we've talked about uh spiritual
evolution uh the reaching enlightenment
which the m next major lecture will be
really about uh uh the inner pathway to
to god uh when you say who is the eye it
makes a big difference that presumption
um so the unenlightened people uh I is
the feeler you know I is what's mad I is
what's Happy eyes is what's greedy eyes
is what's is so the eye is is actually
feeling in this and below 200 is all
feelings. You'll notice there's no
thinkingness there. Thinkingness doesn't
really start until the 400s.
So there are whole cultures where
thinkingness doesn't mean anything.
Isn't that astonishing?
Here we presume because we're in an
intellectually areaized society. Let's
see what percentage of the capa world is
capable of thinking
uh
of the world's population
cap cap capability for thinkingness is
in occurs in more than 10% of the people
15%.
20% 25%
20%. Only 29% of the people can even
think.
So if you ask what do you think of that?
They look at you blankly.
I know what I feel about that.
I know what I believe about that. Well,
you ask what do you think about it? They
don't think. I say to them, do you ever
read the newspaper? No.
read the Weekly Standard. No,
that's a standing joke. The Weekly
Standard. All right.
So, they think that I'm the one that is
the actor. So, the I is the actor and
here you have the I as the valitional,
the one who decides.
Now which of these I so people's idea of
who am I varies quite widely from the
feeler to some people consider the eye
is the body uh I is the brain
I is the witness uh I am the decider of
actions
uh the more sophisticated say well I'm
the that which experiences
I am that which chooses I am
the will well certainly karma would
imply that the will and choice and
valition are extremely important.
So your feelings don't really count that
much do they karmically and neither do
your thoughts because you can think
anything and you can feel anything
but it's choosing and the valition. So
then karmic
up and down the karmic ladder is
primarily you don't have to go is
primarily one of valition.
The will oh it's the will then
the will to choose
that which we consider to be aligned
with God's will for us. It doesn't mean
you you need to be right. You don't have
to be right. That's a break.
You don't have to be right. resist. Oh,
thank you,
folks. You don't have to be right.
Some people just dread being wrong. You
know, the atheist decides that face
facing divinity at the point of death is
just way too much. So, they just quit
believing in God altogether. That way,
you're you dismiss all responsibility
and accountability. If there's no God,
then you're not really responsible or
accountable.
So the person who dismisses God and is a
devout atheist,
you know, I was a devout atheist for
many years and also a devout agnostic.
So I speak from experience. But anyway,
you think you sort of got rid of divine
judgment and all that religious
superstition. You know what I'm saying?
So you can figure you picture this
atheist. He got rid of God. He got rid
of accountability.
He got rid of uh you know fa facing uh
doing a life review. He got rid of all
those worries.
So he dies and as he dies he he finds
himself in a large chamber and there he
sees a chain with a big scale
and in the distance he hears
he forgot Osiris.
You forgot you negated the god of the
overworld, but they forgot Osiris, the
god of the underworld.
And Osiris, of course, weighs your heart
in the scale of truth. And if you're in
line with truth, you go this way. And if
you're not aligned with truth, you go
this way. So those of you who are still
atheists, don't forget Osiris.
If you have any atheistic friends, you
say, "Well, you got rid of God.
Now let's see how you're going to get
rid of Osiris. Yes.
So accountability it is is inescapable.
Yes. Yes. Accountability. We have
permission to ask this is inescapable.
Accountability is inescapable.
So that should not strike fear into your
heart because
that also brings in the quality of mercy
that another quality of divinity is
infinite mercy.
And
even if you can't make it to heaven on
your own,
if you believe in Jesus, he will speak
for you. Right? God will become Jesus
will become your advocate before the
father. Right? And in Buddhism, there is
the the Buddha of the Buddhist land
resist. So you're not completely on your
own. So there's no point to despair
because your intention then speaks
loudly for you. That your intention was
to do that which you thought was your
your capacity.
We were talking during the break, those
of us that were in World War II, how
long after
the minute the war was over, it it
didn't take even more than 5 seconds,
uh, all of us forgave the people on the
other side.
It wasn't any problem.
The instant the war was over, the
kamicazi pilots and and and us were
buddies, you know. I saluted what I knew
he believed in and I I was I admired him
for it and uh the Germans the valor with
which they fought to the last man. So
because of the intention was to serve
their country, serve their nation, serve
their family, fulfill their patriotic
duty to the flag of their country. Each
one then was in a way serving God in
their understanding of it.
So when you see that it makes
forgiveness easy. You see each one of us
follows our own allegiance.
Now whether that allegiance is
objectively true or not apparently
doesn't make any difference.
God don't care
that you follow
your inner truth is what important is
this. All right. So, all these things
help heal the differences in our society
of differences and malevolences and
contention,
uh, hatred, the fact that people are
different than we are. They can't help
being different than people can't help
being different than what they are.
Is that so?
People can't help but be who they are.
Everyone is innocent. Wow. Does that
means everyone is innocent?
Innocent by virtue of the limitation of
the evolution of their own
consciousness.
We can't expect a person to get
a straight A in biology. Huh?
All right. So, each one then is
responsible only within the paradigm of
their own reality in a way. And um
so anyway because this is a world of the
greatest karmic opportunity.
So there's no point in deploring the
condition of the world because the world
spiritually speaking provides the
greatest of all possible karmic benefit.
That's true. Resist
the world. You see, there's no point in
condemning it
because it offers maximum karmic
opportunity.
From second to second, you're always
making a decision without even realizing
it. You're so used to uh constantly
making a decision because options and
choices are constant. I feel sorry for
human beings because they have no rest
from it.
No wonder it like going to sleep at
night or getting drunk. anything
relief from having to constantly choose.
Constantly choose every instant you're
choosing. You choose this, you choose
that, you choose the other way. And that
way, like a little magnetized iron
filing, you see with an infinite field
of consciousness. You're constantly mo
karmically moving up or down, closer to
heaven or closer to hell, depending on
which way you're moving. See?
So this is a world of maximum karmic
opportunity.
So the world that I see is that this is
a world of a great gift. And I agree.
The Buddha says uh
uh how wondrous it is to be how be
grateful we should be to be born a human
because in this world being a human you
have the option to move forward
karmically and in other realms you do
not have such an option. Here we have we
are the chooser
the the valition and the will.
Today we tend to identify people by
their social personhood. And of course
this is the virtual reality of the media
in which for a few moments of tase me
tas me bro
people will do anything strip naked in
public
hang from the edge of a building do
anything to get a few moments of
publicity.
So the narcissism of the ego
is uh is extreme. It will go to any
extreme
and you watch the weather channel or or
history channel the extremes to which
man will go so that he gets his name I
guess in the in in the book of
whatchamacallit
the first man to something or other the
first man to read something. the first
man to to get your name in the book of
of records, you know, uh it's so
important to the ego, you know, to be
somebody. So, the more you feel like you
are someone, the less you need uh the
society's approval and you finally reach
a state where you're not interested in
society's approval at all. You see,
you're indifferent to it. If they
approve you and like you that's very
nice you know but it's not necessary and
it's not a goal. So letting go so
uh the social personhood then is of
course superficial description but in
today's world people will do anything
for it. People will do anything when you
watch the Fox News or something I
sometimes we look at it when it just
boggles our mind. Why a person would go
to this extreme
to get that one second, that one second
on the screen, you know, uh I am my
feelings. I am then of course I am my
thoughts. So the lower level is only I
am what I feel. Then as you get more
evolved into the 300s and it's I am what
I think. Then you become very
sophisticated and you realize that what
I am is actually pretty much a blank
screen. and it'll believe anything on
Monday and believe something else on
Wednesday. That uh it depends on how
we're getting programmed by our society.
The self then is either the content or
it's the context. So as you become more
sophisticated,
you realize that that which I am is not
the content of what I think or believe
because it changes every year when you
know you're a year older if nothing
else. uh but I am the context in which
this scenario is going on.
Decart's famous uh and it's very
important to the consciousness research
we've done is u rest internal versus
rest external the world as it appear of
appearance the world as it appears
versus the reality of the world as it is
beyond observation.
Uh so discerning
rest internal the world as you think it
is from rest external uh reality as it
is
requires a great deal of sophistication.
And in our role, the current academia is
ignoring this alto together and just
saying, well, uh, the reality is, you
know, how I politically interpret it. It
has nothing to do because nowadays
people are indoctrinated. They no longer
think. They no longer reason. They no
longer learn. Now, the purpose of
education is indoctrination.
Do you believe that the purpose of
education
is no longer education
but indoctrination
out of that Antioch College collapsed
and now has gone bankrupt. First they
applied it to the curriculum that
brought it down from 450 to 190 or
something. Then they applied relativism
to the actual functioning of the faculty
and the running of the university and
went bankrupt.
That's not exactly a good vote for
Marxism.
Uh that's I'm aware because we are here
in a university here. We are in a
college that is stunningly unique.
Don't take this place where we're
sitting for granted. No way. Let's see
what academia currently
academia we have permission. Currently I
in the US calibrates over 190 200
195 academia
the great name universities Harvard
Dartmouth Yale
that was the backbone and strengthened
out of which the whole American economy
grew was it not the intellectual
structure
now calibrates at less than 200 yep
The purpose and it's formally stated
is not to educate but to indoctrinate.
Uhhuh. So we now have mind control and
thought control. So the reason we
appreciate this college here today, we
have permission to calibrate. This
community college calibrates over 400,
430,
435, 440.
It calibrates over 440. Is this 435?
It did calibrate 440 till we got in the
parking lot.
So the people who went to the bigname
eastern universities or the big 10 would
scoff. Oh, a community college.
The community colleges are the last
vestage of intellectual aridition and
integrity in the United States.
They have all gone down. All have sold
out. All have collapsed.
All right. So the fabric of the society
from the intellectual viewpoint
is now non-intiggorous.
The story of the fall of antiocologists
typical William and Mary you can name
one after another. Harvard Law School is
one of the most pathetic.
Where is Harvard Law School right now?
Harvard Law School calibrates currently
over 200. resist.
Harvard Law School currently calibrates
over 200 resist.
Harvard Law School.
The Law School of Harvard University.
Doesn't that shake the jello- in your
belly?
What is the future of an America where
Harvard Law School doesn't even
calibrate at 200?
No. Because the law school is now
dominated
by an ideology and unless you fulfill
this ideology, you can't get a license
as a lawyer anymore. So the political
power structure has reached out to
indoctrinate.
The reason this show up in my mind is
because we are standing right here in
Yavapai College that does calibrate at
440 where Yale and Harvard and Princeton
and
University of Wisconsin
and now they have delusional professors
talking about how we we did 911 and blew
oursel up and all and etc. In the old
days, you know, we put them in the
Milwaukee County Asylum for the insight.
That is called technically in psychiatry
a logic tight delusional disorder. Logic
tight. No matter what you say to the
person, it will have no impact.
I told you about the nutty professor.
He's writing these books about how uh
Einstein is wrong. I think he's on his
fourth or fifth book. You know how
Einstein doesn't know what he's talking
about. He's all a fake. He calibrates
all 190. Anyway, he doesn't sell any of
his books because they're so stupid. But
he keeps publishing more of them.
In psychiatry, we call them logic tight
delusional disorders. The prognosis was
zero. Nobody recovered from them.
Nothing you could say to them would make
the slightest difference. Yeah. Nothing
could nothing would shake their world
view. So, you know what is reality to a
person with a paranoid delusional
disorder?
uh it's their own irrational belief
systems.
Uh you can be very successful in today's
world having a paranoid delusional
disorder,
especially if you get a job at the
university in Colorado or something.
100,000 a year.
That's good money for being nuts.
100 grand a year. He's still getting it.
He hasn't. Plus all his legal fees is
are getting paid by the university. 100
grand a year. As a taxpayer,
I can feel my eye rising.
Rest the So the world as you see it is
one thing. Reality as it is, as it is
without your observation is something
else. See, so the difference between
parents and essence. So the self comes
to an achieving the that it knows.
However, the mind thinks the mind thinks
about it.
The mind thinks about a thing. The self
with a capital S
just knows.
The capital S self knows by virtue of
the fact that it is
By virtue of the fact that the reality
of my existence
is the whole context of life and
experience
is a knowingness but not a provability.
There's no way you can prove that. So
reality is radically subjective.
Radically subjective
that creates a paradox.
the experiencer. The experiencer. So
what what the person experiences
there's the disconnection between rest
externa and rest internal that takes
place in one one 10,000th of a second.
110,000th of a second. So we'll move to
the next slide.
We'll move to the next slide. We'll move
now to the next slide.
All right. So, I had to put this in
here. Folks, parents,
send your kids to Yavapai College at
4:40.
So, I've terminated my donations to
Harvard and Hill. Man,
I think Sanford is probably still up
relatively high, but I don't know. All
right. Good God, I can't see a thing
here. Reality as essence versus
appearance, but we just dis just cover
that. Now, we live in the world of free
speech. Let's clarify what is free
speech.
Yeah, you you dumb
Bush is a
in World War II. We all we all died for
this.
Free speech is
paranoid delusions.
The thing I don't like about the that
type of people is they they see with
hatred and malice. The intention is
malevolent. Therefore, what comes out is
annoying. It's because of the intention.
The intention is malevolent.
Well, what are you some kind of
conservative?
I heard some guy that wrote po power
versus force which has nothing in it
about politics at all and he says you're
really just a conservative.
I guess rationality makes you
conservative. Yeah, I guess I am a
conservative.
So, all right. It's beyond what you
feel.
So opinion then is limited. All right.
But we should be able to express our
opinion. So what is freedom of speech
that we all die for? And I'm sick and
tired of hearing about freedom of
speech. The next person who tells me
about freedom of speech, I'm going to
give him one right in the right in the
mouth.
What does freedom of speech mean? That
you can get out there and be super
vulgar. super pornographic
solicit
kids have sex with kids have sex with
your teacher
fornicate in the classroom I mean isn't
that freedom of speech
spir said speech no action is symbolic
speech
well man I'll tell you this is one free
for all
we have freedom of speech and action is
symbolic speech.
Look out. Here I come with my bulldozer.
I'm taking down your house because you
pissed me off. Isn't that my freedom?
What does freedom of speech mean
right now? It means, you know, you can
legally lie about somebody. Liable. You
can't slander anybody anymore. Liable.
You can tell an absolute falsehood.
And you can't sue anybody for slander
anymore because you got freedom of
speech.
Now, what is this freedom of speech
that people are willing to die for? I'm
not willing to die for Rocky's freedom
of speech. What do I care about their
freedom of speech? They can shut up. I
don't want to even hear what they're
talking about. What do I care about
their freedom of speech? Am I willing to
die for their freedom of speech? No.
What is freedom of speech?
Well, freedom of speech came out of the
constitution.
Came out of the idealism of
the founding fathers. Freedom of speech
means the legal right to express your
ideas.
You're free to express your ideas.
So freedom meant intellectual freedom
that you can express concepts.
You can say
the earth grows around the sun and not
vice versa
without going being put to death.
All right. So freedom of speech means
freedom of ideiation, concepts,
thinking. This
doesn't mean freedom to take off your
clothes, fornicate in public,
have sexual relationship with children,
inside with middle-aged men who are out
to seduce young boys
and tear the rectal sphincter. What do
you think those men are out the little
boys to do? UCLA
play checkers.
They're out to physically damage them.
See, so freedom of speech
then as we see the deterioration of the
western civilization and its
intellectual background
doesn't even know what freedom of speech
means is. You're supposed to be out
there and die for freedom of speech.
Not me. You can keep your freedom of
speech.
I don't care what they think. Do you?
They do a man on the street kind of
thing. And what do you think about the
world uh oil situation? What the hell?
This this guy just flunked out of sixth
grade. What do I care what he thinks
about the international oil situation?
What do you think about Bush's so- and
so policy?
Dumb is dumb. That's
You can disagree intellectually. E. I
think Bush is dumb on a lot of things.
That's my right as a human being, as an
American.
I don't have to be right. I don't have
to hate him. I don't have to molest him
on his way out to his branch.
I don't have to write vulgar oppressive
things. I don't have to throw red paint
on his secretary of state. See,
so freedom of speech means intellectual
freedom. The whole renaissance was the
freedom of the suppression by the
Catholic Church and various other
oppressors to be able to express your
mind freely. So freedom of speech means
by verbal means it says speech. It does
not say action.
Yeah, freedom of speech. You're free to
express your ideas.
I am free to tell you that I think free
speech as it exists in the United States
is a batch of horseshit.
I think it's nar it's it's regressed to
the point of infantile narcissistic
self-indulgence
to the point of vulgarity pornographic.
Am I willing to die for that? No sir, I
am not.
So they can't draft me anymore.
Can't draft me. Hell yeah.
Therefore,
there is no reality that no requirement
for reality. So, the world becomes Alice
and Wonderland.
A thing is what I say it is. Nothing
more and nothing less. That is today's
world of reality. A thing is what I say
it is. It's its perception.
A thing is what I say it is. nothing
more and nothing less.
So therefore, the intellectual world has
dropped to the level of Alice in
Wonderland.
It's what I indoctrinate you to think.
It's either that or nothing else.
And if you resist the indoctrination,
you will not pass and get a college
degree.
Where is somebody who knows the truth of
what I'm saying? Where is that guy? That
big tall guy.
Where is my student?
Student.
Step forward.
This is my hero of today's world.
This is my hero. Where are you going to
school?
>> Ever College.
>> Good God.
Well, I you know, he turned me on to so
much of what was going on in academia.
It never even dawned in my mind that you
know what's going on with going on and
he wised me up and uh so I'm very
grateful to you and uh anything you want
to add about what I said? Did I say it
right?
>> I agree.
>> Am I telling the truth?
>> As far as I know.
>> Yep. Well, he tipped me off and then of
course the weekly center came out with
the fall of antiology. I began to read
about it and what's that good book you l
meagerian
or Gusagarian or
>> uh Gary Gosharian.
>> Goshion. Yes, Gosserian. Thank you very
much, Gabe.
So, Gashgarian, I forget the name of his
book. It's great name. Goshion. can't
forget that name Dr. Anyway, he writes
in detail about, you know, the fall of
academia. And at first, I didn't believe
all this. I I said, "This is not even
possible." Not even possible that a
professor get wrote wrote the
professors, I forget what what his name
is. They booted him off the stage in
some So,
the leftwing says that conservatism has
no rights. Therefore, it's perfectly
okay to uh physically uh violently
oppose them.
In fact, Maru says it's your duty to
destroy them
as a person of the modern academic
world. You should not allow anybody who
doesn't agree with this position to
speak in a college auditorium.
So I am very happy that we still have
enough freedom left that there is a
college auditorium where I can have the
freedom to say what I think.
Thank you. You have a bal
yeah
yeah yeah. So Gabe uh tuned me into what
was happening and I began to read about
it and pay attention to it and I said I
can't believe uh and I know other
graduates of Eastern universities who
also couldn't believe it but they began
to uh so all right so that's why we have
this send your kids to my college
all right so the
there's reality in risk external and
rest internal
now the world as it is is unknown by the
mind.
Why? Because
information is instantly processed in
one 10,000th of a second. In one
10,000th of a second. That's why it's so
hard to become enlightened. all the
programs, all the feelings, all the
things you've learned, all your belief
systems,
uh your style of uh contextualizing,
your style of understanding and
intellectualizing, etc. All of this
happens in one 10,000th of a second.
How can you experience what is then? How
can you see? How can you ever experience
rest externa
when you're stuck in rest internal?
The distance between them is one
10,000th of a second.
H
how can you then escape being the slave
and the captive of the ego and it's all
all of its aversions and attractions
etc. How can you get past that one
10,000th of a second?
Well, people used to believe and they
still do that enlightenment is the space
between two thoughts. the Buddha taught.
I It's a mistransation of the Buddha
Buddha. I never did get to the original.
But the Buddha thought throughout the
centuries has been that um reality is
glimpsed between two thoughts, between
two thoughts.
Uh you can't glimpse it between two
thoughts because the mind works faster
than one 10,000 of a second. So by the
time you notice there's a gap there, you
no longer have a gap there. So it's like
a dog chasing its tail.
There's no way you can move your point
of observation faster than the rate of
mentation of the mind itself. You have
to move faster than 1 10,000 of a
second. That's why practically no one
ever gets enlightened. 1 and 10,000 of a
second because you cannot move faster.
It takes you one 10,000th of a second
then to look for the space between the
two thoughts and by that time the space
is gone. There's no way you can become
enlightened by looking for the infinite
silent formless space between two
thoughts. It's not possible.
The Buddha is alleged to have said that,
but he told me personally it's BS.
No, we've already talked about it in
these previous lectures. The infinite
silent space is not between two
thoughts.
It's below the thoughts. It's not on the
surface of the sea. It's not like one
wave chasing another and you're going to
find a place between the waves. No, the
silence and the stillness is below the
mind.
And we've spoken of this before. So as a
style of contemplation what you do is
you disconnect from the particularity
uh the linearity of the worldly
phenomena
and you become awareness. You become the
field of awareness. So you move from
participant experiencer
uh back to witness uh to observer.
Then you you get that the only reason
you're able to witness or observe is
because there is a infinite formless
field and you move back. The sense of
eye moves from out there or what people
think of you out there or what's said
out there or what you believe out there.
It moves and you realize the one thing
that doesn't change is the witness. It's
always the same witnesser. No matter
what you can be a Democrat one year and
10 years later be a Republican, but the
witnesser doesn't say. So you I am that
which I am the witnesser. I'm the
witnesser of the phenomena as they go
through the mind. Then you become even
more sophisticated. You realize that
you are prior to witnessing because
witnessing can happen of its own. But
how does one know that witnessing is
even happening?
There is therefore something more a
priority,
more fundamental
to the witness and that is consciousness
itself.
So the sense of self moves from the
individual ego, the narcissistic ego all
about me and I and my tube and YouTube
and all that.
It says the mind begins to say that's
boring BS. That's really a lot of BS out
there. And it withdraws its interest
from that. And then it says, "How do I
know anything?"
And then it says, "Well, who is the
eye?" I mean, who is the eye that
believes things?
The I believe this then and it believes
this now. Is it a different eye?
So, you begin to find something that is
always present. What is always present?
And you will finally end up as you in
deep meditation
uh you let go all of attachments and
aversions. If you let go of attachments
and aversions and all thinkingness yes
and all ideiation and all symbolism and
all the stuff that goes on in the in the
mind uh you end up with awareness
itself.
But that which I am is no different than
awareness. But that in itself then
becomes a belief system does it not?
Therefore when lets go even the thinking
or the belief of self as experiencer as
the consciousness out of which
experiencing arises
and the identity between the self and
that which
is the substrate of the self.
then suddenly disappears.
Suddenly disappears and as it disappears
you feel yourself die.
So people write me periodically they
feel they're dying. I say good wonderful
because that which you really are cannot
die. So what you're experiencing is the
death of the ego.
What happens then is the mind becomes
progressively silent. And then you're in
nonlinear realms, nonlinear realms, not
within mind itself. You're in realms of
much greater dimension. The these are
the realms of context, not of content.
So in the beginning, you think of self
in terms of content. I am me. I'm 62
years old, etc.
Then finally you you begin to experience
self as context. I'm the context out of
which arises awareness
believingness witnessing etc.
And you begin to move farther and
farther back and then you will come to
what I would call experientially it was
like a high pristine place. It was like
um being in the top of the highest
mountain. So the highest Andes
completely
altitude is the closest analogy.
Um infinite silence, nothingness.
There's nothing there, no nothing.
There is no one to experience anything
there. And you go through the void. Uh
the void is at calibration level 850.
That was the level confronting this
entity at age three.
Came out of oblivion into nothingness
and confronted with is the ultimate
reality allness or nothingness.
And that took uh decades.
Then when you feel like you're dying,
that's terrific.
When you feel like you're dying, when
your whole mind is silenced, it
disappeared.
When you feel yourself die, because you
feel yourself die, it's not a belief
system.
That which you are
dissolves and
you feel the self die. And I will tell
you it is for a few moments
uh in extreme agony. All that you ever
thought you were, believed you were,
experienced yourself were through all
the lifetimes, zillions of lifetimes,
you're letting it go.
Then you realize to reach enlightenment
this too, oh Lord, I must give up till
you leave. You give up everything, one
thing after another, desires and wishes
and aversions and thoughts and belief
systems,
politics, religion, etc. You give it all
up to find the ultimate reality.
The last thing you're holding back is
life. So then came the experience
and I realized that this too, oh Lord,
must I lay down to thee.
And
then there is a moment of agony in which
you feel yourself actually die and you
do die because that which you think is
you
is what's dying. And if it was the real
you, no nothing would be possible.
The real you dies. It's taking the big
jump that's leaping off the cliff.
And I said to thee, oh Lord, I surrender
my life. And then came the agony.
And then the agony stopped.
And then ecstasy beyond all description.
Um, the world was reborn and radiated
forth the divinity
and the incredible beauty of all that
exists
throughout all of time and the reality
of your own and you run that is what's
called yo mystical
the
god within god imminent etc.
Then life is totally transformed
experientially and in its meaning etc.
Yeah. So that is the ultimate reality
that there is no reality.
There is no reality to become, to
refuse, to ignore
that which is and that which you are one
and the same.
And
the the the thing that marks it as the
ultimate reality
is its stunning beauty,
but it's stunning love. The most
staggering thing about a after going
through this high pass of absolute
voidness
all of a sudden the earth shone forth
with an incredible beauty
that you the mind is silent in in the
witnessing of the incredible beauty and
you see the the essence of all things
shine forth. The presence of God as the
essence of all that exists shines forth.
So you all all you see is divinity
wherever you look. Huh? which pretty
much takes you out of operating in the
world
uh for quite a while actually.
Then if karmically
karmically uh predestined or not
predestined but destined as a capacity
one might return to the world and speak
of such matters but it's totally
unnecessary.
That which is hardly needs you to
validate that that which is is the
ultimate.
It's hardly needful of you to attest to
it.
However, in a group like this, we have
many strange people
who wish to reach enlightenment.
Oh boy,
what an exciting and wonderful journey
it is.
How exciting and wonderful it is. You
move one paradigm of reality onto a a
broader one. You move from content to
context. You end up with isness and
beingness itself.
Then if you've got a good teacher who
warns you about the void, you make it
through the void. And I've told you when
you get to the void, neg refuse it. The
void of nothingness is devoid of God's
love. And you reaffirm. All that exists,
the source of all that exists is
infinite love. And that which is void is
is facious. So you breach that gap at
consciousness level 850.
The ultimate is not nothingness. The
ultimate is allness.
And the allness of divinity
is powerfully love.
So whatever state you arrive in, if it
isn't overwhelmingly love, then refuse
it and go on no matter what it is.
Because the infinite love is the
unmistakable sign. There is first of all
motionless incredible beauty.
You you see everything unfolding as its
essence presents itself. You witness the
essence of everything.
And out of that essence, you become
aware of its divinity. And as an essence
of divinity is infinite love.
So I say dogs and cats are divine.
If I look at the kitty and I say, "Hi
kitty." The kid goes,
"I mean, isn't that the most miraculous
thing in the world?
She doesn't even speak English.
If I say Bowser, Bowser,
the radiation of love shines forth. The
divinity shines forth through the dog
and the cat. So maybe the first place
you can find it. It's hard to find in
your fellow man.
Unless you had a really good mom that
makes good cake cakes.
You got a good wife.
So the source of divinity then the
realization of divinity is within you.
It radiates in forth into the world as
lovingness.
And the quickest pathway to God is
to
choose the lovingness of your existence
and share that lovingness with others.
It makes the difference between life and
death. People
reach the end of their rope and you
smile at them and say hi. Suddenly they
decide to live. You realize.
So the good actions that you perform and
build up something that I never read
about or never hear about and that is
you build up a karmic uh bank a bank
account. You you have a positive balance
in your karmic bank account.
I can remember drawing on that positive
bank account.
You know, all the good deeds. You think,
well, I did all those good deeds and I
didn't get any reward. No, but boy, have
you ever got a lot, you know, and it's
scoring at 10% in a year.
One time I I'm driving my old truck,
which I still have, and it broke down
million miles from anywhere. Nobody knew
I was even there and I didn't have the
strength to take the big tire off. I
couldn't get the crank to work and I
didn't have the strength to jack it up
anyway. So I stood there for Lauren and
all of a sudden in this very remote
place out of nowhere drives up a car
pulls up to me and says, "Hi Dave,
you're stuck. I'll help you out."
Things like that have happened to me
over and over again in my life.
And people say, "Oh, yeah, that's just
accident." No, it's not accident. So,
it's like you had a positive
bank, karmic bank account, and when you
need it, wow, somebody pulls over. I had
the same thing happen in
a complicated one of those things going
into Sedona. I mean, going into Phoenix
to get to the airport. And the old truck
broke down on this, whatchamacallit.
And this old truck pulls over. He says,
"What? You broken down?" I said, "I
can't get this wheel off. It's flat." He
says, "I'll help you." He got out. He
took it off. He threw it in his truck.
He went down, got off the next, went to
his garage, got it fixed, came around
back up through the CL relief, came back
and pulled up next to me and says,
"Here, I'll put it on for you."
He took it off. He went and got it
fixed.
Put it back on for me.
All right. We'll just ask one last
question, then we'll break for lunch.
Uh, I have permission to ask this. That
man was an angel. Resist. So there are
angels in bodies.
I mean, what an angel would sacrifice
hours of their time, go out of their
way, loop around, loop back again.
And we bring angels into our experience
because of our own reservoir of positive
karma.
Isn't that a nice thing to know? If that
don't warm your heart up for lunchtime,
I don't know what will.
>> We'll see you again at what time?
>> Um, uh, two o'clock.
>> See you again at 2 o'clock.
Oh, it's hard to take it all seriously.
You know what I say?
Never take it seriously.
But look like you you do so people don't
get offended.
You're telling all about their
gallbladder operation. You say, "Oh my
god." Yes.
And then what?
Well,
where were we? Uhhuh.
>> Oh, right here. Right now. Huh?
Same place every time. So
certain things we emphasize that I've
said before I said there's two kinds of
learning leftrain linear sort of
memorization intellectual etc then
there's sort of a right brain holistic
uh knowingness you get the whole bundle
you know
certain things I emphasize because
they're rarely said and they're rarely
said from a certain energy level and so
I say them because you may not need them
in this lifetime
but in some lifetime. Those of you who
have chosen enlightenment as a direction
then uh have chosen your own
evolutionary path.
Once you choose enlightenment as an
evolutionary path,
the end is uh
certain. Let's see if that's true.
One who sticks to the evolutionary path
to enlightenment becomes enlightened.
Wow.
All right. So,
it therefore behooves me to tell you
things you I know you can't get
elsewhere
that you need to know. And uh so it's
your intellect has heard it before, but
I'm not speaking to your intellect now.
I'm speaking to the orica energy, the
energy of your aura.
All right. So the information is that
having abandoned everything
in the pathway of negation let's say not
this not that neither attractions nor
aversions uh you go into further and
further rarified
places in which there's nothing left
really to surrender
and as I said
the only thing you've got left to
surrender
is life itself.
You've let go all attractions and
aversions, money, fame,
the opposite sex, women, children,
architecture,
even let go of beauty, possessions,
uh the physical body. If it hangs in, it
hangs in. If it doesn't, it doesn't. You
know,
you know, it's still there. So,
but it doesn't mean anything one way or
the other. I really don't care if it's
there or not.
Now, most people care about it, but
there's a certain level where you don't
care whether it goes on or not. It's
it's a modest curiosity.
It's nice if it doesn't and and if it
doesn't, it doesn't. It's really
irrelevant. You actually arrive at a
situation like that and you end up in a
really um advanced state. As I said,
it's like rar rarified
uh stratosphere
and um there there's nothing to let go,
nothing left, nothing left.
Nothing left to let go of. You let go of
every attraction, every aversion, etc.
And then it at least in this experience,
it dawned on you that the one thing you
are clinging to is life.
What you're clinging to is life. Not the
experience of life, but life itself.
Not the acquisitions or the aversions of
life, but that core that gives you a
sense of reality is life itself.
Then it dawns on you. This too, oh Lord,
must be surrendered to you.
To thee, oh Lord, I surrender my life.
And then comes up a terror. All right.
At the moment of the terror,
there has to be already within your air,
your aura,
the absolute knowingness of somebody who
is abs absolutely transcended this level
that it's absolutely safe and to
surrender all fear.
There comes forth a knowingness
spontaneously, autonomously, not out of
thinkingness,
but out of a knowingness
that all fear is illusion.
The fear of the loss of life is just
another illusion but the last one.
So you proceed to let go of life. Now at
that point the terror comes up and at
that point you need a conviction from
the absolute. The absolute can only be
conveyed by somebody who has actually
lived through it. That's the value of
the spiritual teacher through the
transmission of the energy fuel through
the aura of which you've read about and
which happens here and now as well.
The absolute knowing the the the the
reliance on it must be absolute because
you're letting go of absolutely all that
you think you are and believe that you
are since the beginning of time.
That which has gone through that path
passage
with the absolute knowingness that you
can do so then the energy of that
knowingness is now in your aura having
you've heard it.
You may not remember it for 5,000 years
but out of nowhere in this instant it
came out of nowhere. It wasn't the
product of a stream of thinkingness or
reason or logic or memory. It came out
of nowhere.
Okay? Out of nowhere.
Out of nowhere came the knowingness
resist.
The knowingness came as a radiation from
the aura of the teacher resist.
And the teacher from which I picked it
up was over a thousand years ago. 2,000.
2500.
Over 2,000. Wait a minute. I'm sorry.
Over 2,000.
The teacher from whom I picked it up was
over 2,000 years ago. Resist.
Was over I can't I'm not thinking about
what I'm saying. It was over a thousand
years ago.
1500 years ago. 1,200 years ago. 1300
years ago. I for had to ask permission.
Okay. I have permission.
I have permission to ask this. Just Yes.
Because I'm just trying to convey a
knowingness
because the the the knowingness is now
theirs.
You have to know at a certain point that
it's safe to put your foot there because
if it's the wrong place,
uh you're going to drown. So,
it's safe to put your foot there. It's
safe to let go then
of that tether
to life itself.
All right, I've done my duty. I've said
it.
Okay.
I didn't give it to you to hoard. He
says, "Oh, okay. All right. is to share
oh
to share that experience you see so that
that knowledge the knowledge then is
experiential it's not academic it's not
intellectual
um
it's because you have been that and are
that etc all right so I just wanted to
emphasize why the repetition people say
well you said that before
all right where were
I can't read anything. I can't see.
Where are we? Where are we? Send your
good.
All right.
Well, I'm glad those are big letters.
You can see that.
Oh.
Oh, golly. Was
Yeah. the experience of uh without being
edited. We say that the ego jumps in and
edited edits everything within one t
10,000 of a second.
Uh and how do you get I call that the
experiencer. The experiencer
how how do you how do you get beyond
that? The what the mind does is like a
tape recorder. There's the uh let's say
the birds are singing outside. Then
there's the recording of the birds that
is singing outside. Then on the
oldfashioned tape monitor,
uh, now in the old fashioned tape
recorder, there's a tape out monitor.
Yeah. So the tape out monitor,
you hear what's just been recorded.
So you see there's a disparity. There's
what's happening. Then there's the the
quick recording of it. And then the tape
out is of what you just taped.
So you can see what you've just taped is
recorded.
So that's what the ordinary mind does.
What you're hearing hearing is the
recording.
Once you go past the experiencer
to the spontaneous
once you're past the experiencer
all you hear all birds as they the bird
sounds without having the bird recorded
and then you hear the recording of the
bird in your mind. So you hear the
source rather than the recording of the
source. That recording happens in one
10,000th of a second.
All right. So,
in letting go all of the things that you
let go of on the evolutionary path,
there comes the there comes the time
when you are
you are that that with with what what is
rather than that which has just been
recorded.
And that's what that's what is blinding
because that's what reveals divinity.
And it takes quite a while to get over
the shock of the shock.
I call reality shock. It takes uh years
frankly years before you can function
again.
All right. So you re live with reality
of of isness of existence of what is
without having any editing.
You don't say to yourself it's good or
it's bad
when you're just living with what is.
Your mind doesn't say isn't that
beautiful. That sounds stupid. You know,
isn't that beautiful?
Like saying seeing the Taj Mahal and
saying, "Wow, isn't that pretty?"
The Taj Mahal is beyond being pretty.
It's beyond being beautiful.
It's reality is stunning. It's reality
is stunning. Yes.
Or in one of the great pyramids or
something like that.
And there's various entities around the
great pyramids. That's how you you hang
out there. You visit them. Yep. Uh
lots gone in the period. The great
pyramids. So you it's a great place to
meditate all night.
Cost you a few bucks.
The guards become friendly.
Slip my 10 or 20 and you can meditate
all night in the great pyramid
and he'll make sure nobody else comes in
and invades your privacy.
I wish to be alone.
10 bucks. You got it all night.
Oh yes.
Okay. So uh that's tape out versus
recording.
Now you see the mind left to its own
device
uh has no check on reality.
So the human you can have compassion for
the human because the human is like the
old sailor trying to sail the seas
without a compass. No sextant, no
compass.
They sailed by dead reckoning.
And uh I think by dead reckoning, what?
At the bottom of the Great Lakes, there
are 6,000 ships at the bottom of the
Great Lakes. So the bottom the seafloor
is littered with tens of thousands of of
sailors who who did at that time did not
have a compass.
So that's the predicament of the human
mind. The predicament of the human mind
is it doesn't have any external point of
reference. It has no GPS positioning
system.
So you can be wacky and looney and
totally out of it and everybody can see
it but you can't see it because you
don't have a compass that says you know
you're 80 degrees off this way and 40
degrees this way.
So the human dilemma then compassion
arises for human ignorance etc because
the the mind has no point of reference
and anybody can understand from
scientific learning without a point of
reference there is no way of knowing
anything about anything
uh within the world that we call
reality.
That was the value I saw of the
calibrated levels of consciousness
was for the first time mankind had an
external source of reference of
verification of the truth or falsehood
of any concept, thing, idea, place,
position, personality, point of view,
whatever.
For the first time, man had a compass.
You realize man has never had a compass.
There's no way man has ever been able to
know the truth of anything he believes.
No way. He had faith in the Inca gods or
he had faith in the spirit of the
volcano or you know placed it in wild
animals etc.
But those were just belief systems.
Man has never had
any means of discerning truth from
falsehood. Staggering that man got this
far. Yeah,
mainly he didn't. However,
all you see is the megal tale of what
did make it. The majority didn't.
The majority of mankind did not survive
and it did not thrive.
So what we see is that little minority
that did learn how to maneuver in the
linear domain and science of course is
our biggest gift. I think science the
greatest gift of science is in medicine.
and the cure of all the diseases, all
the diseases I was trained to treat. And
when I and when and I started in
practice at a old hospital full of all
these diseases, none of which exist
anymore.
I guess I still pinch myself and I said,
"You can't believe it. No typhoid, no
dtheria,
no polio,
no menitis.
All the stuff that you spent all you're
up all night long treating and
diagnosing doesn't even exist anymore.
Science has cured it all. So I have
great reverence for science in the
linear domain can accomplish great
wonders. Great wonders.
So
the mind is without a compass. So once
you give it a compass within the linear
domain uh it was given to us by logic
and science then uh
great uh things can be accomplished.
the the difficulty with the current
teachings of our current society
uh of fallacy and programming
and indoctrination even though
indoctrination is not called
indoctrination
uh it's programming
in the United States 55% of the people
see my concern about it is is the damage
the damages the 55% of the people in the
United States are unable unable
to discern reality from illusion or
truthful falsehood. Even if you explain
it to them, 55% can't get it. Therefore,
the apparatus itself has been damaged.
You've been running your car with the
choke running a half tilt and now your
cylinders are carbonized.
half the people in the world, it's much
greater. But you see, we're constantly
programmed all day long by gum bloger
bloggerisms. Bloggerisms.
Blogerism. Bloggerism. Yes.
Whatever those nasty things they send
out to everybody.
We get them in the office. Everybody's
obsessed with sex.
you got a business office to sell
tractors or something and all all your
computer tells you is how to get a
bigger better one and how to be better
in bed and how to have better orgasms
and it's just constant you know 100
emails all of them having to do
with vulgarisms
it's it's it's very funny in a way it is
hysterical
so
55% % of the people in the United States
uh can't understand reality even when
you explain it to them. Even when you
explain it to them, the difference
between perception and essence, they
still can't can't get it. And I remember
a lection a lecture not too long ago,
you know, after a couple hours of
lecturing on the difference between
perception and essence, the person's
question indicated the slightest
conception of the difference between
perception and essence.
Lord, where have I failed? I don't know.
Spell it out even with pictures. That's
why I like that picture of the wolf in
the sheep because a picture is worth a
thousand words. Yes. So the people below
200 live in an alternate reality. One
problem is they have a a difficulty in
comprehending reality.
And one of the main reasons of course is
the politicalization of every belief
system. Now politics is like a big
paintbrush and everything in our society
has now been painted with a political
color.
Right? There is anything you can do or
say that to somebody doesn't have an in
a political inference.
It's very difficult to say anything
without stirring up the pot of
uh conversation about it.
It's a politicalization of everything.
So the people can't see the reality. All
they see is the label of it. A label of
it. So if something if person says I'm a
liberal and somebody paints this green,
this is this is conservative. They don't
look at what you're talking about. They
look at the green color and say that's
conservative. It just got rejected. Or
it's the other way around. You can say,
"Well, that's a far-left idea."
And and so you just reject it because of
its politicalization.
So, as you watch, you see practically
everything on TV, everything everywhere
in our society has been embellished now
uh with another layer of distortion
called the current current politics.
Uh the basic cause of all this warping
of course is the essence of narcissism
itself.
Narcissism itself is self-seeking.
And because of self-seekingness, it will
interpret everything in a way that is
self-s serving.
And indoctrination uh trumps reality. It
means no matter what the reality is,
indoctrination can overcome that.
uh for instance I was brought up uh
chivalry
calibrates I don't know 550 or something
but we ask let's see we'll just ask we
we can ask about children calibrates
over 500 540
530 All right let's calibrate honor
honor calibrates It's over 500, 530,
535,
540.
The area of 535
ran in there is honor.
People do things out of a sense of
honor.
How often do you hear that on
television?
That out of a sense of honor.
For how much?
Let's take uh chivalry.
Chivalry.
Chivalry. We said calibrate around 5:30.
Is chivalry is that which honors honors
uh you know in in the way I was brought
up was to honor women. Women were
honored. When a woman entered the room,
you stood up.
You never talk back to your mother.
Elderly women had precedence over
younger women.
Men curtailed their speech in the
presence of women.
They did not indulge in vulgarities.
Women didn't sit alone at a bar because
that invited male solicitation and might
suggest that they were out for business.
the women had uh the family entrance and
they sat at a table and and with chairs
and were served by the uh the bartender
or the waitress etc. didn't have to go
to the bar and get their own drinks. So
from the viewpoint of chivalry then
women were honored
because after all she is the mother of
the race
but there without women there ain't
nobody
out of that respect out of that respect
for the prime primary
uh role that she fulfills. You see uh
the mother is um
so out of that arises chivalry. See
chivalry is to honor and to respect.
Now you can turn that around by
politicalization and say it's
deprecatory.
I don't hold the door open for a woman
except to honor her presence
because I was brought up. I do it out of
respect for the woman. See, could she
open it herself? Sure she can. So what?
So you see sexism can immediately using
the marxian
dialogue of perpetrator victim picture
her now as a victim. Oh she woman is
being diminished by men you see etc. So
you see how politics then obscures the
inner reality.
The essence of standing up when a woman
enters the room is one of honor at 550
let's say and if it's an older woman for
her respect for her age as well. Yeah.
All right. So
to see it as demeaning to women let's
see we'll get into six of them.
To see it as demeaning to women
calibrates over 180 190 calibrates about
190. To see it
180 185.
All right. To see it as demeaning to
women
is a disorder of perception.
There's no demeaning women going out
there. It's all in your mind because
you've been indoctrinated
and brainwashed.
with what's called sexism.
Sexism. Ism. The minute you add ism to
anything, it come down comes down to
180. It's already down to 180.
So anything can be depicted by throwing
it into a Marx Marxist kind of a
dialectic to look as though there's an
oppressor and a victim. We can turn it
around with the same thing with men.
While the woman sits comfortably at
home, the man has to go out and fight
the wars and get shot up and have his
leg blown off and have his brain turned
to pulp.
M while she's sitting at home all cuddly
and cozy with the kids.
So he's doing it for home and hearth.
See? So you can see how you can mix
metaphors, mix
uh and editorialize and completely lose
the reality of it all.
What does a man feel in his heart when
he stands in respect to the woman? What
does he feel in his heart? Huh?
woman.
>> I don't know.
>> You know what's in the heart. Yes. So
anyway, I just wanted to use that as an
example how and of course this
indoctrination goes on subtly all day
round the clock in all various forms
including academia etc. in which
everything in society can be politicized
into perpetrator victim.
Even integrity and honesty itself, even
honesty, respect, morality can be
denigrated. Uh denigrated. All right.
So indoctrination trumps reality.
As Bush said, money and oil trumps
reality, doesn't he?
Did he say no? No. What he said is money
trumps peace or oil trumps peace. That
calibrates at 365.
Yeah. Bush said it. Money or oil, I
forget. Trump's peace.
Yeah. Functionally. Functionally.
All right. Narcissism therefore warps
and distorts.
Everything gets politicized.
narcissistically warped and distorted so
that it's self-s serving and it's always
self-s serving the perpetrator victim
role
and the reason people cling to it is
they love to picture themselves as
victim
victim.
It's funny, we don't have any mad
feminists getting up there and jumping
on the stage,
depriving them of feeling persecuted and
martyed and put down
when they've had the upper hand all
along. For God's sake,
Eve was no fool. I mean,
she's had her way ever since.
All right.
All information no matter how seemingly
uh correct is always presumptive. So
wisdom part of spiritual evolution
uh is the development progressive
development of wisdom.
One thing that is important to learn is
that all information and all knowledge
and everything you think and believe is
presumptive only
and that it may it's subject to change
later. Everything you know, think or
believe is provisional.
Everything is provisional. It's
presumptive and provisional. So with
wisdom, you learn to hold back a certain
degree
and
more will be added later. Expect that
more will be added. Look, all the years
since World War II and many of the
things that happened in World War II
that were extremely critical are only
coming to light now, 50 some odd years
later. Yes.
The fact the Japanese had almost
perfected an atomic bomb wasn't even
known until the papers of some
Japanese physicists were made public in
the mid70s.
American public didn't know it. Nobody
even knew it. They were just a couple of
months away from atomic bomb themsself
anyway. So that was on History Channel
or something like that. So even though
it seems like all has been known, there
is yet more to know. So we we then have
a certain modesty about anything we
think or believe because we know that
more may be added and the whole picture
may be changed. All you need is one more
piece of information and the whole chess
board changes. You move the bishop from
one square to this square, the whole
game just totally changed. moving one
little piece of information.
All information is presumptive.
We already covered Yev by college
and we covered Protagoras's dictim that
reality is purely subject subjective
presumption.
That is also a basic tenant of
relativism
that all information etc is only a point
of view. Yeah. And there is no such
thing as the absolute.
No such thing as the absolute. And uh
once in a while I get an indignant
letter. Somebody gets very indignant
when I I speak about the absolute
because to relativism there is no such
thing as an absolute.
And that's one reason there is no God.
And there is no calibrated level of a
thousand. There is no such thing as the
absolute. We have one more chart on
this. Uh yes. Mhm. All right. So,
absolutism is anathema
to relativist.
It just ruins their sleep and everything
else. They can't eat nothing.
Their life comes to an end
that there is an absolute truth.
Why does it make them so bad mad?
is because the narcissistic core of the
ego, that's the last thing it wants to
hear. That there is something of greater
sovereignty
than the ego itself.
So the narcissistic core of the ego
hates divinity and it hates the
absolute. It hates calibrated levels of
consciousness. Yeah. It hates that.
just hates that.
The fact that a dog calibrates higher
than people, you know.
Oh, well, I can't read what that says,
but it's uh whatever it says looks
interesting.
What does it say?
Reality is a product of paradigms. Oh,
yes.
Not only is reality difficult if not
impossible to ascertain,
every paradigm of reality has is a
different reality.
The different levels of consciousness
are really different different
paradigms.
The difficulty with atheism and
skepticism and all such things is that
the linear domain of causality uh the
400s
uh the linear is one domain and the
nonlinear is another domain and the
limited mind cannot grasp that there is
a domain and a context
of context that is greater than the
pedestrian mundane in world of logic.
See, so it cannot comprehend that
there's any reality greater than itself.
So you'll notice skepticism, which
calibrates very low, by the way, because
it's a form of nihilism.
Skepticism calibrates very low. And it
does so because it thinks the only
reality is content and linear causality.
and it doesn't realize that there's
anything that exists beyond
consciousness the level of the 400s.
It thinks that you know if you can't
prove it etc. So it poo poos religion
and faith and all these things. But as
we mentioned before the one thing that
skepticism has tremendous faith in is
its own self.
The skeptic re ridicules faith but it
has profound faith in its own
convictions and its own skepticism.
So that that is the paradox really
protagonist's paradox is the when the
the truth absolute truth is unknowable
and the skeptic is uh definitely
has faith in the truth of that statement
that the absolute truth is unknowable.
If it's unknowable, then what the
skeptic is saying has no basis in
reality whatsoever. Huh?
What?
What? What?
We down to the last page. I want to make
sure I do them all.
>> Huh? Are this the last page? We might
have some time where we can jabber for a
few minutes. Share it with the people.
>> Minutes left.
>> Well, I'll hurry up. I'll hurry up.
You notice women are not repressed. I
mean, all it's just do is raise her
voice and and I scurry. You know what
I'm saying?
Repressed women. Yeah. Right.
In their imagination.
They like to play victim.
So, the narcissistic ego loves to be
victim. Loves to be victim. Yeah. Well,
uh, tell you what, there's not better
that way either.
We said that all reality is presumptive
versus provable. Uh, you can't prove any
reality whatsoever.
Mark said religion is the opiate of the
people. Wonder people wonder why
relativism and far-left is atheistic is
because it's Marxism and Marx was an
atheist.
Didn't they ever hear the quote,
"Religion is the opiate of the people."
Therefore, all
Marxism and its various intellectual
disguises is atheistic. It's a basic
principle which denies the reality of
the absolute. It denies the reality of
the absolute.
So, Marxism denies the reality of the
absolute. And
religion is the opiate of the people.
All right. Relativistic antagonism
towards the absoluteism of religion.
See? All right.
Tolerance is a very fashionable world a
word
and it's really a downward slope to
non-reality
because tolerance is now applied to
everything.
uh that has been traditionally
unacceptable.
We should be tolerance to everything.
Tolerant to everything.
So I suggest you're welcome to be
tolerant to anything you like.
But don't include me in.
Why? Because a kimod dragon is still a
komodo dragon.
If we're nice to the komodo dragons,
they won't bite you.
No, they won't.
Kimodo dragons won't bite people.
The way they get to heaven is by killing
you.
That's our little secret.
Step into my cage and you're bare feet.
You're safe.
So tolerance then becomes a form of
ignorance. Is it not ignorance?
The world is afraid to call a spade a
spade anymore for fear fear of this
political splatter.
Nobody wants to call a spade a spade.
If somebody's out to kill you, let's not
pretend that it's due to a deprived
childhood when the speaker is a
multi-millionaire.
The warning given by bin Laden. See the
meaning of it was missed by the world.
You know if you read the Quran, the
Quran says
first you offer them to convert
and then if they refuse, you are
justified to kill them. Therefore, when
Bin Laden invited America to convert to
Islam,
you've been invited
And now if you don't we can kill you
with a free conscience.
The significance of that was missed by
everybody in the press etc.
The reason he invited America to be
convert to m Muslimism
is because that's the opening gambit.
And after all, they invented chess.
And I myself was once a pretty champion
chess player.
I've got his bishop trapped already six
moves ahead of him by moving this knight
here.
Did I move my knight here? I got his
bishop about five moves down and he
can't get out of it because I already
got this black with my knight.
If I say to you, you're all invited to
invert.
Now it's on your head. Your death is on
your head. You understand that chess
moves.
The people are way ahead of us in in
playing chess. Our
side is pretty dumb. Doesn't even
recognize an obvious move. Did you see
them move his bishop over like that? For
Christ's sake,
he just moved.
That's just women having their way.
Women have their way with men, if you
know what I mean.
So sexism works both ways.
So a lot of these uh politicalizations,
you know, lend themselves so really to
humor. So
I think humor is one of the most healing
modalities.
I think it's very uh supportive of
spiritual evolution because many things
you really can't get beyond because of
the ambiguity. Well, humor then brings
out the ambiguity. And because humor
brings out the ambiguity, you can see
the fallacy and laugh at it. So, if
you're very serious, you'd have
committed suicide by now.
You live to a respectable old age. So,
the first uh requirement to become a
member of the oct octagenarians of which
I am president
is a sense of humor.
A sense of humor about anything and
everything. See, a sense of humor is
necessary for longevity.
All the people who lack it are probably
six feet under already because they took
everything seriously. Yeah. I used to
take things seriously. Well, I told you
how I did. I had to go for treatment for
scupulosity.
My mother would call up to the bedroom.
She'd say, "Are you dressed, ready to go
yet?" And I'd say, "Yes, mom. I'll be
right down." I still had one sock and
one shoe to put on. I said, "Yes, mom.
I'll be right down." I quickly put them
on. I run down the stairs. Instantly,
I'm hit with guilt that I lied to my
mother.
>> She said, "Are you ready to go?" And I
said, "Yes, and I still had one shoe and
one sock." So, literally, it was a lie,
right?
Well, I'd have that guilt until I got to
confession.
10 Hail Marys and five our fathers.
And then the priest would say, you know,
you don't need to feel guilty about
every little trivial thing. So
yeah, the other side of no conscience is
too much conscience,
scrupulosity. So a sense of humor
prevents scrupulosity
because I want everybody to take
everything spiritually seriously, but
not to the point of scrupulosity and
still have a sense of humor about it.
Yes. Okay. What happens next?
>> We uh take a quick break.
>> Oh, yes.
>> And then we'll line up for question and
answers.
>> Oh, we take a quick break
and then we'll have questions and
answers and then after that I get to
shake everybody's hand. Oh, good. Okay,
that sounded like a jolly afternoon.
Hallelujah.