All right, so I thought this morning, if we had any time left over, if you can shut the
docket up for a chance, we could ask questions spontaneously, although we do them later.
It's usually more personal things later after we sign books and all.
I thought, because I want to make sure everyone gets it, if anybody has any questions or anything
you'd like amplified or clarified, we'll do that.
We've got a few remaining minutes.
So yes, oh, yeah, in a way that was going to come up next time when we talk about truth.
But I want you to also see that real is what you define as the qualifying, the qualification
of real.
Is real what is scientifically provable?
Is real what's experiential?
So real in a way is a way of approaching the subject, the defining the overall context
by which we call it.
Real.
Is there a reality that exists independent of human observation?
Quantum mechanics says no.
The whole universe is merely a consequence of observation.
Whether it's real really infers whether it exists.
It exists.
And then how you define what exists is where the error comes in.
To say that I have a foot is a subjective conclusion, actually.
You can't prove you have a foot.
But you experience it.
So there is an experiential reality independent of what somebody might say about it.
So somebody might say that's not really a foot.
That's a hoof.
In their language it's a hoof.
It's a hoof of a foot.
So anything that I . . . Is it really a . . .
At a certain level it's all an illusion, yes.
Well, because you're interpreting reality as what exists as form.
So you're talking about physical reality, physical existence.
The fact that you physically exist is a statement of truth because you can then verify that
experientially.
What that means, however, is something else.
That's more abstract.
How you define that reality?
The reality itself is independent of definition or how you look at it.
How you see the stare.
The stare is independent of how you perceive it.
But . . . . So then you call it . . . You think, well, eyes go through shape.
Yeah.
All right.
can make a statement about the stare and now you're talking about perception and now you're
talking about truth. So reality, what is real we're defining this morning as linear and confirmable
through the senses. That it is here and it is here now and it is here at a certain time. We can
confirm that. Then there are subjective realities that other people cannot confirm. That you had a
dream about your dog last night and he was running after a rabbit. Now that is a fact. But a fact is
something that is different than what is real. Somebody else could say well a dream is not real.
It may not be real to them. But it's still a fact that you had a dream last night and the content of
that dream. So you end up again with subjectivity, first person reporting. And of course the validity
of first person reporting is the whole
the
, the battleground of scientific argument. You know whether personal testimony has any scientific
value. Of course it does because they do the very thing with their own scientific proof that the
subjective is irrational. And they state that as a fact. That's a subjective conclusion. They upend
their own argument about pedestrian scientism.
Just one last piece.
Yes.
It's still a subjectivity.
Because what is it that says it's real? Consciousness actually.
It's all subjective and it's all within consciousness. That's why you know consciousness has no center. It has no beginning and no end.
That's why with consciousness calibration you can find out anything about anything anywhere in time or place.
You're not limited. It's beyond all limitation. So the truth and the truth the essence is beyond limitation. Facts and data.
And what's real are within the linear domain. Linear domain. So it's a less sophisticated domain.
Yes.
Eh?
Come on up a little closer so I can hear you.
Yeah. There's a thing above and below to level 200. Yes?
Yeah. About the contextual shift that happens to the value and the meaning of life.
Yes.
And I'm experiencing what used to be lives.
Things that I hear and see. And I'm wondering...
Well you would certainly agree with...
change its importance its meaning the fact may be the same but how you how you hold it what it
means to you is significant of course spiritually aligned people are almost always unconsciously
using how does this serve my spiritual intention that's why it's good to make a declaration if
you've never sat down formally made a declaration to the god i make a declaration of the purpose of
my life i and glory and excelsis adio is a declaration uh glory to god in the most high
that realigns everything that you experience in your life it either serves that end or it
doesn't serve that end so it's very powerful to make a declaration because it just does
change the whole context and significance and meaning and word there so i'm thinking about
in this world now the meaning of the setting that's what we have confirmed over and over
that this is uh really
you
and uh because here you get to suffer out bad karma and make a choice
a more positive option you get to transcend and evolve now in other realms you don't have any
choice hell is hell i tell you i've been in hell there was no option for anything positive
although well there was there was still the freedom of the will because i asked if there
was a god i asked him to help me and if i was if it was only total hell there i wouldn't have
been able to have that thought
i think there are people to whom that thought never never does occur in hell and they're
there permanently and the thought never does come to him oh god uh please forgive me i
i ask for our salvation in the name of the lord so from the very bottom suddenly to shoot
out all the way to the top like it was breathtaking you know if you would you know people i feel
sorry people don't understand that hell is an experience of reality and it's far worse
anybody could ever imagine. I don't want anybody here going there at all.
Yes, ma'am?
You made the comment that consciousness calibration had dropped
from 207 to, say, 209. The consciousness level of mankind
overall, overall, has dropped from 207 to 204.
And that was very recent. That was very recent, yes.
Why calibrating it, how do you think?
Huh? Well, you see
international war, you see the threat of nuclear.
You see primarily the same thing that the Pope pointed out,
and we've confirmed that in previous lectures. The Pope said
the decline of Western civilization, and what may
bring it to an end, is the decline of two things, you see?
Relativism and Islam. You put the two together and you've got destruction
in the world as you know it.
You have the opening the door for the wolf,
which is what do you call the road's
wooden pony, what do you call it?
The Trojan horse, yes.
The relativism is the Trojan horse.
And messianic Islam, then, is what's inside
the horse. The imam, it will kill all of the Western world
that will bring forth the 13th imam. It will save mankind, you see?
So, what did you say?
Yes, the Pope said the decline of Western civilization, in fact,
is even threatened by two things simultaneously.
Relativism, which decreases man's capacity to discern truth in the first place,
and that Islam, because of its fascist
totalitarian nature, you know, wants to kill you.
So,
the combination of the two is enough to bring down Western civilization.
Yes, that's, I think it's probably likely so, you know.
I mean, war is war. And when you get to nuclear war,
you see, the nuclear threat is due to falsehood.
You understand, Iran and the whole nuclear threat was due to
a couple of nuclear scientists who were compartmentalized personalities.
I won't even re-mention their names, but
Klaus Fuchs and
various people like that. America was an integrous nation and they had it.
These people then, out of their narcissistic egotism, gave it to Russia who then sold it
to everybody else. And the reason we all live in fear of nuclear annihilation now,
it was to the desecration of truth and integrity by a couple of compartmentalized personalities.
Whitaker Chambers was one, the whole answer about Whitaker Chambers, Klaus Fuchs, Robert Hanson,
and there's more and others, including some the world doesn't know about yet, because we can't
share everything we know with the world. But there are compartmentalized personalities out there.
Some are aware of the other personality and some are not. Generally they are not. Generally this
person is completely segmented from this person, generally. But Klaus Fuchs and Robert Hanson and
people like that, you know, now they've destroyed hundreds of CIA agents that were
away.
Working to try and working for the CIA and the FBI, etc. But they are the ones that are responsible
for Iran's having a nuclear threat. And he now says that he intends to destroy all of western
mankind. And when we check the arm, whether he means this, we always get yes, he means it.
Oh dear, he means it, yeah. I'll kill you if I can. So the point you could do that is make sure he can.
But it was the violation of truth and integrity that brought this world to its present state.
So though the Pope's talking about now, the severity of the negativity of now is due to
lack of integrity prior to that. It was World War II. It was the Manhattan Project and various
people, the four from Oxford Four, etc. So that small group that set themselves above
is why we all live in jeopardy now.
Yes. So the interesting truth and false, as you can see, is more than just a spiritual
sophistication. It has a very severe applications in mankind.
So anyway, we got the Pope is right. I've agreed with him. You know, I was young,
I was very anti-Catholic. I have great hopes for the Pope.
Well, I held a grudge against the Catholic Church for the Inquisition. That was it. Yeah.
Yes.
I don't know if I can hear her. Honey, you'll have to come up or speak louder.
With the EM transmissions from the sun and how the earth is responding to 0.12 and the
evolution of that, do you not think that that and what the physical
ramifications of the earth responding to that?
No. Yeah. No, the earth, see what man puts out is pollution.
What happens is they confuse pollution, which is one thing, with environmental warming, which is,
another thing. So environmental warning is not due to pollution. We've gotten that over and over
again. It's environmental warming, a cyclic phases of the sun. And if you do ice core drillings down
10,000 years, you can see the, and that's now in the daily, it's now in the news. You know, it was,
it got people upset when we first used to say that. So environmental pollution is a different source.
So you got two different problems. One is pollution,
the other is environmental warming. This is not due to that. See, this is, it's not causality.
The cause of environmental pollution is overpopulation. Everybody who lives now has
to have something to live by. They have to have heat, they have to have electricity,
they have to have a car, they have to have debris. The more people you have,
the more pollution you have. So the solution to pollution is less people. China realized that,
why you're only allowed to have one child, right?
How much pollution can you, you know, because lower Asia, there's a cloud five miles high of
pollution, lower Asia. We think we have pollution here and nothing compared to there. Yeah. So the
expanding population then. So pollution is one thing, global warming is another. Yes.
But see, the point I also, I was making is how much emotion people put into this.
I mean, you know, environmentalism, the emotion just becomes like shrill hysteria. You know what I mean?
Environmentalists are blowing up houses and buildings and want to destroy mankind
and give the planet back to the animals. Well, look what the animals did with it.
I got nothing against it. I'm not against Tyrannosaurus Rex
or Brontosaurus. No, no. I love Brontosaurus and Tyrannosaurus. Yes. Okay. We have one last quick and then we're done.
Are we done now? Were you going to say something? I can give you a one second answer.
No, I never used the word tolerate. Oh, forgive. That's different than tolerate, huh?
How to distinguish between what two opportunities? To forgive or?
Well, I said Jesus Christ. Don't quote me. Jesus Christ said to avoid evil. He didn't say,
make apologies for it. He, in fact, he said, I brought, I did not bring you the sword of peace. I brought you the sword of truth.
So therefore to avoid any kind of upset, you understand what I'm saying? You can't speak the truth
without people writing your nasty blogs at 2 am. Can't be done. So however, your dedication is to forgive
error. I mean, the Komodo dragon can't help but be a Komodo dragon, and people write nasty blogs
at 2 am because they're, you know, drunk and, you know, or high on something. Can't help it. So we need the opportunity.
That's just a今天的
We need the opportunity.
to.
to choose to forgive or to condemn so we don't have to hate them don't have to hate them but
you know jesus said don't get it get confrontational with them don't get
confrontational with them all right so now that brings us to the more important issue of lunchtime
well i might have made a mistake this morning somebody said i made a mistake about somebody's
name so we'll ask the arm i made a mistake about somebody's name resist that's true i don't know
what name it was but hey jd anything can be true you know
the principle was really compartmentalized personalities and uh yeah yeah that that was
a mistake yeah all right so i acknowledge that's a mistake the best thing to do about a mistake is
admit the mistake right away uh so anyway it has to do with compartmentalized personalities
uh
which very few people know about and very few people know about and uh which explains uh some
of the great mysteries of the political and the government and military and of course has to do
with nuclear uh security the party played in nuclear security is the compartmentalized
personalities is why we all live in fear of uh nuclear energy etc all right so that's uh all
we'll put the last slide back on now anybody still got questions they didn't get a chance to
ask guy well you should discuss some things further yes yes well don't forget i practiced
psychiatry for 50 years and uh so i have a lot of knowledge from other areas other than uh you know
just consciousness calibration uh compartmentalized personality which i know of one right now
is uh the the two personalities it's like two spirits came into one body you know there's
multiple personalities that have multiple personalities
multiple personalities is of course a little better known but that the interesting thing it
has to do with belief systems so when one personality let's say you have a multiple
personality and one of them is allergic allergic to dogs and cats and dust and all this kind of
crap so when that guy's when that entity is is in control the person has allergies
then when that personality leaves there's another personality that's very extroverted doesn't believe
it's all neurotic crap and doesn't have any of it yeah so there are multiple personalities so
you're subject to what you hold in mind that's a subject to what you hold in mind we have a book
coming out on lectures that i gave on self-healing and i think i cover that subject there
uh the same with hypnosis you can hypnotize a person and tell them they're allergic to roses
and then not tell them
some roses in the room and they will actually swell up with asthma in the presence of the roses
that was noticed by psychoanalysis years ago a psychoanalyst had a patient who was very allergic
to roses and so one time he had paper roses in his office and she came down with a terrible attack of
asthma so that shows the power of suggestion and also the therapeutic value of hypnotic states
compartmentalized personalities
one side may or may not know of the other i know of a local case right now he has an upside of 395
and the downside of 160 and the two don't know about each other
don't know about each other but one predominates as amnesia for the other and of course they you
know such problems have raised havoc in in our world now somehow these compartmentalized personalities seem to head for the wrong direction.
they seem to be attracted to that so any high security intelligence highly guarded area you would think would be devoid of negative personalities no that's right where they go i mean you know why does a robber go to the bank because that's where the money is
that means the money has gone
so if you're a surreptitious agent where are you going to go you're going
to be looking in admirers for managers and heroes where is it where is my personal start
where's now my personal status what's my bones where's some of you in the room we'll talk in a minute
go with a secret star so I could predict just from consciousness research the
Manhattan Project or anything to do with nuclear security etc is going to attract
every spy in the world and it did it attracted the best they were very good
and the Oxford four and various numbers of them you know were extremely good and
it's cost all of us our own security I mean it's why you know we're lined up at
airports because some guy had a shoe bomb tied to his shoe and you know yeah
well all of our lives have been impaired by the consequences of double
personalities the fact that they're one is secured and one secured is not
secured is extremely important yeah so very often if we run into a paradox
about a person always the nicest person in the world and then you find that
they're you're right
so
horrible blogs if I always got two personalities right that's that's so one
calibrates at one lumber and one calibrates at another it's like most two
personalities in the same body and one psyche takes over sometimes and another
psyche takes over other times yes yes it can be very dangerous it can be very
dangerous because the downside one may cause the upside one is life because of
the downside one you become executed
and the upside person gets executed because of what the downside person did
you know so it's an interesting thing I've only known a few well no I've known
quite a few in practice and practiced and in personal life I've run across
them each time with a devastating consequence frankly what did you
calibrate Bush Cheney and Bill Clinton I don't remember the sweetheart it's in the
book you know see you have
It depends on you asking what role, too.
As a person, what is this calibrated at?
As a functionary in this title, what does he function at?
Some people may be saintly and very bad at the helm.
Other people may be very good at the helm,
but you can't trust them with your wife, you know what I'm saying?
I wonder who that is.
So I don't think anybody agrees with how certain decisions
made by the government have turned out, of course.
But I think the person himself can be quite, you know, integrous.
But because you're integrous doesn't mean you can't be mistaken, you know.
Yeah, so...
Yeah.
You show the word what?
Doubt?
Yes, what about doubt?
Yes, doubt.
Well, it's sort of, to some degree, along with skepticism.
Well, doubt has to do with uncertainty,
and it is often a very logical and realistic to be doubtful.
It means I don't have enough information yet to make up a mind, in my mind.
A sophisticated person holds all information as being tentative.
All information is tentative.
And...
Yeah.
To be confirmed.
All information...
A mature person knows that there is yet more to be known.
No matter how much you know about a thing, there's still more to know.
Therefore, all information is held as tentative.
So I hold everything I say as tentative.
It's the truth to the best that we can discern it at this moment.
It doesn't mean that we won't be able to improve upon it,
because otherwise...
The evolution of mankind would be stationary, you know, it would be stationary.
More will be discovered later, is a great likelihood, you see.
There is yet more to be known, no matter how complete we think our knowledge is.
And you see this, you know, 25 years after a war,
you know, some Japanese scientists were working on nuclear energy,
and were very close to an atomic bomb, and we didn't even know it at the time we dropped the bomb on Hiroshima,
and Nagasaki, that Professor Nagasaki, and the professor, I forget his name now,
whose papers have just been revealed in recent years by his wife,
they were very, very extremely close to an actual atomic bomb,
and if we hadn't dropped it, they would have dropped it.
So there's more to know.
25, 50 years after a war, critical elements are still being discovered, you know, critical elements.
So all information...
All information and knowledge is subject to revision.
Subject to revision.
Partly because of the evolution of consciousness itself.
So certain things are not known, but then as the field rises, as the field lifts,
now that reveals access to things that would not have been thought about before.
Now if I was running the CIA etc., I would use consciousness calibration,
and frankly, I would take all the people in critical...
levels, just have a photo of them and
check them all with the arm and see if there's any double
personalities in there. There's somebody
that has another agenda.
Before I trust them with, you know,
the highest possible secrets in the United States.
I would run them through
a quick screen. Very simple.
Doesn't cost anything.
Yeah. Speak up.
I can't understand the question.
Oh.
Well, truth is one
you might say an attribute of divinity.
God is
omniscient, omnipresent.
Omniscient and omnipresent.
So, omniscience
is an attribute of divinity.
Omniscience has to do with
the knowingness of truth about all
things. So, only the
field of consciousness is
accessible to us
as humans.
In other realms, truth is
a prevailing reality. Here it is not a
prevailing reality. So,
the omniscience of God then is
a
one way to God is
by calibrating levels of truth
and following those things
which calibrate the highest.
In as much as we're born without that
capacity for discernment,
we have now
a methodology. We don't know altitude
by looking at a mountain either.
But we now have altimeters.
So, the advancement of human consciousness
has shown us
a different way.
A better way. One that's
impersonal. And I want to
emphasize again, it's impersonal.
I don't have any personal feeling about any of the calibrations
we do at all. I don't have any personal
calibration about it at all, correctly.
It's just whatever it is
is whatever it is. You know, like an altimeter,
you go up to the mountain and you read the dial.
So, with consciousness calibration
we just read the dial.
I don't personally have any investment in
what the answer is one way or the other.
In fact, if it comes out
different than what one expects,
that leads one to
important discoveries.
You know?
If there's a
differential between your expectation
and the result that you get, you know,
then that leads you to further
inquiry. And with further inquiry, then
you do discover the truth behind it.
Now, the question
was how do you differentiate between
divinity, reality, and truth?
Is that what it is?
We said that reality is that which
is confirmable.
Confirmable. So, then you have
truth which has to do with
essence.
And reality has to do with
content.
Reality is confirmable.
What is confirmable?
Therefore, it's linear.
It's here,
at this time, and it weighs this much,
and it measures this much, and it's
located right here.
So, that's all linear, confirmable.
And that's content
of consciousness.
Truth is of a different level. Truth has to
do with abstraction.
And truth is what escapes
people who are,
what do you say,
pedestrian, pedestrian, sorry.
They get the pedestrian
limited content,
but they don't get the meaning.
Therefore, what does it mean?
They don't know what it means, because
the mind at that point
has not reached the capacity
of abstraction.
So, abstract thought
is of a higher level than concrete
mundane thought.
Provability has nothing to do with meaning.
Meaning is an
abstract. So, meaning has to
do with the context, contextual
understanding of the significance of the
meaning. And much of
spiritual work is the revelation
constantly of significance and meaning.
You say, God, what does that mean?
What is the inference? And then suddenly
you stand
back and you suddenly get, oh wow,
you suddenly see the significance of
the whole thing.
And if you were going to explain this to somebody,
else you would find it difficult, because
how can you put the non-linear
into a linear content? That's been the
trouble with describing
spiritual truth throughout the ages.
How can you put the non-linear into
language when language is
primarily linear?
So, you speak of the ineffable,
you speak
of the mystical.
The mystic is
one whose consciousness
is dominated by a field,
not by
the content of the field, but by the field
itself, by which
everything is recontextualized,
yes? So,
truth is an abstraction.
So, you can take facts
and then from these facts you get meaning
and then you get
what is the truth of this, you see?
So, truth is a higher level of
abstraction. So, in the great books
of the Western world, you see,
the various levels
of comprehension are laid out pretty
much, you see? There's
the concrete, the literal, then there's
the inference, and then the higher
and higher levels of abstract
truth. The Kant, you know,
Kant, Manuel Kant's
levels of categories. And what you see
with relativism, for instance,
is there's no respect
for categories. They think
you can just, you know, mix one category
with another one because it suits your political
purpose. And
the laws of logic are you cannot
mix levels, you cannot mix levels.
What is true on one level is not true
on another level. What is true
on one level is not true on another level.
And so, one error
that people do make,
you know, especially critics of spiritual work,
is they don't respect
the Kantian categories,
levels of abstraction of
truth and logic.
Everything is only true at
its own level.
So, to make
it wrong, what is done politically is to
take it from this level, put it in this level,
and then do a make wrong on it.
Yeah.
Does that explain it well enough? Yes?
Probably the explanation is more
complicated than the
presentation to begin with.
Yes, ma'am?
Yes.
It sometimes is very critical to life.
As I just said, your very
existence is currently under threat.
Your existence is not guaranteed
whatsoever.
And it's because of a compartmentalized
split personality. So,
it is very critical.
And the only way
I know to diagnose it
is to begin to suspect it, that there seems
to be two sides to this person's personality.
There seems to be a puzzlement.
Sometimes the people
are aware of it, sometimes they're not.
Great disparities in behaviors
and the unexpected.
It comes about
really from clinical sophistication
to begin to suspect it, frankly.
First of all, you have to even know
that it exists and that it's a very
important thing to know at times.
To even know that it exists.
Compartmentalized personalities.
We know, pretty much everybody's
heard about multiple personalities.
But, you know,
a very discrete split personality
is very often
between one that calibrates very low
and the other one calibrates high.
It's like the angelic and the
demonic were both heading for this body
and they both got there at the same time
somehow.
Two spirits
in only one body.
So I'm sure there's peculiar karmic propensities
which I don't know and I've never
researched.
As I say, the split personalities I've known
in my personal life have been very unpleasant,
frankly, because they get into your life
with their benign, isn't he a wonderful person
and the next thing you know
they're putting a knife in your back
and you never suspected it.
They can have a very, very, very
devastating effect on your life.
Yeah, very devastating.
And
very often it's met with denial.
They'll say that, you know, so and so
and then they give you
some reading on their negative side
and you say, oh no, oh no,
because you're so sure the way your perception
is correct.
So you always hold in mind that there could be an alternate side
to a personality
and they're not always
the same person.
Yeah.
During the lecture you spoke of the experiencer.
Yes.
No, you just become the witness
of the experiencer.
The experiencer is
tries to milk everything
to ensure its own survivor.
You become the witness
of the ego doing that.
of the observer. So you're detached
then from subjectively
identifying yourself with the experiencer.
Ordinarily the mind
thinks, well I am that which is
experiencing.
Instead of I am the consciousness,
the observer, the witness
of the phenomena.
You're more detached when you see
yourself as the witness observer.
Then how do you know
that you're the witness observer?
The witness observer then is coming out
of the consciousness itself.
It's because of consciousness
itself that you're capable
of having a witness observer.
Much less an experiencer.
To have no thought
about what goes on.
It comes about
through a contemplative lifestyle.
So that you end up
thinking about a thing
only if you choose to think about it.
If you say, well I think
I'll think about this, then you think about it.
But you don't think about it
against
your own choice.
So that comes about
as a contemplative lifestyle
where the field
is aware of the content of the field
but it's aware
only out of its being a field.
Not out of its being
a particular you.
Just as what's being said now
is being witnessed. I have no idea what he's talking about.
I don't.
I hear it the same time you hear it.
The speakingness happens
of its own spontaneity
as the speakingness
because that's an attribute
that you relearn
after you
lose the ability to relate to the world.
Slowly over time
you relearn
and I call that
persona. There's an aspect
of consciousness which then learns
to interact with the world
and converse with it
and know which streetcar to get onto and all that.
But it has nothing to do with who you are.
You're the witness.
It could be just somebody else in another body.
It doesn't have any personal
meaning anymore.
Therefore whether you're
good or bad, you know,
it's the other person's problem
because it's their perception
and it's got nothing to do with your own reality
which is beyond good and bad, etc.
You don't know
who they're talking about.
So as I say,
when that state first emerged
I would see people
talking to this body
and I couldn't figure
who they're talking to.
Who the hell is he talking to?
And I realized they think it's me.
Oh.
I couldn't figure out who they're talking to.
Who are they talking to?
Because the body had nothing to do
with who I am
or even where I was, you might say.
The consciousness may be here
and here's Doc's body over here
and people are talking to this thing here.
What the hell are they talking to?
You know what I'm saying?
Like out of body, I'm here
and they're talking to this body here
and that's certainly a strange phenomenon.
It took a while
for people to realize
that they're talking to that
and that is what they assumed to be you.
So then you learn how to
via the persona
become that entity
to the degree that is necessary
in a social interaction.
If there's no necessity
for social interaction
there's no necessity
to own that persona.
It would just be excess baggage
like you don't need a raincoat
if it's not raining.
The phenomena sort of grew out of themselves.
Don't forget there isn't any book on such a matter.
And it was just discovered
through a personal
what the Rokoff's personal
subject of awareness
the learning of these things.
They may be somewhere
in some book
but I've never read it.
Yes?
I need somebody to translate
what he says.
With what?
Well this persona interacts with
everything.
It will say something
but it is
it will say something
but it's because
that's the conversational
interaction of the moment.
It has no intrinsic
great reality.
So
because of the alignment
and the lovingness between the two
everything becomes
recontextualized.
So no matter what the person says
it doesn't have any
effect on the alignment
whatsoever.
A person could be angry at you one second
and it doesn't really mean anything
because in two seconds later it's gone.
If something was going to
threaten the relationship
that would have a different impact.
Because your alignment is a commitment
you're both aligned
and committed to reach God
so that makes you parallels.
You know
a little static on the radio
is not exactly a major transmission
at all times.
You know what I'm saying?
You can say something
back and forth
out of your animalness.
Don't forget you're an animal.
So the cause for
disparity is really your animal.
It's really your animal.
And I'll say now
my animal will go in the refrigerator
and I say
where in the world is the pickled herring?
And her animal
will come up and say
right here in front of your eyes.
Alright, alright.
I don't want to mix it up.
Get a pickled herring
right in your eye.
No.
It's never physical.
It's just the nuisance
the annoyance.
It's the animal being annoyed.
The animal thinks there's a bone over there
and he goes over there
and the bone falls down the steps
and the animal is annoyed.
It's the animal that's coming up
and not the real you.
The real you hasn't changed any position.
So annoyance I think is between couples
is usually more the animal coming up.
Even the animal coming up.
Even wanting people to agree with you
is really your animal wanting
them they should agree with you all the time.
And
so if you say
well that's just my animal
it's not really who I am you see.
It's not really
So
you end up kidding each other a good deal
you know because
you really do because what would have been
annoying if you kid about it
it defuses it you know what I'm saying.
Somebody ate my last pickled herring well
I don't have to kill them.
I can let them live.
Gave it to the neighbor.
Gave my last pickled herring to the neighbor.
Oh
I don't have to let go of my attachment
to pickled herring.
Can't get to heaven because you're
attached to pickled herring.
God says you love me more
or pickled herring more.
Alright
What else needs clarification?
Yes indeed sir.
Oh yes.
Yes.
You see if you come from right and wrong
you'd say well gee that's terrible
they're lying all the time. But that's their job.
If I ask
about specifically let's see
I have specifically
have permission to ask about
the U.N. resist.
The politicians in the U.N.
lie routinely resist.
Routinely.
You know the U.N. calibrates at 190.
If they were telling the truth
all the time it would be like 420 wouldn't it?
So it's
means it's like you're jockeying
for a verbal rhetorical
position.
You're trading
white chips for black chips.
So it's a constant dealing back
and forth. I'll let go
this statement if you let go that
statement and if you give me this advantage
I'll let go this
disadvantage.
It's wheeling and dealing. So you might say
politics is wheeling and dealing
for power and
the gain. Whatever
gain they presume occurs.
Right now the primary gain
is number one oil
money and number two moral
high ground.
You hear all these
political arguments they're all about the moral
high ground.
Moral high ground and with it often
goes the money with the oil.
So that has to do with survival.
So the politician is interested
in survival and
primarily survival of his own position.
His own position.
You see people switch sides depending on which
is popular. If this gets more votes
suddenly they go in this way. When this gets more votes
they go this way.
So you might say that's not a defect
that's his job. That's what he's supposed
to do. If you find more people
like chocolate than vanilla somehow
you begin to favor chocolate don't you?
If you're going to run for president
you can't be for vanilla
when the 55%
prefer chocolate.
So the poll tells you how you got to move
and I think in truth versus false
we calibrated the
various political positions
and the political position of
the electorate. If I remember
the electorate was at about 375.
So for a spiritual platform
to work
they would have to devise it
to appeal to a consciousness level
about 375.
That's why hatred and spite don't really
win elections because that calibrates to 190.
At 375
very few people look favorably
at hatred.
I mean they'll tolerate it
and they'll quote it when they want it
but they don't respect it or vote for it.
So consciousness
level 370 I think was
where the last electorate was.
So if I was devising
a political platform
I would devise one that
appeals to about 375.
That's sort of
middle of the road, whatever is sane
and sensible, whatever sounds ethical
and logical
and sort of
reasonableness
and pretty much good naturedness.
Good natured reasonableness.
So to win an election
I would devise a political platform
and I would calibrate it at 375.
And move my positions around
until they're at 375.
So you can see
even as a politician I would have to
change what I consider to be
sufficiently truthful to present
to the public. Not in order to get elected.
You can't
malign the public
and still get elected.
You're going to have to say what sounds favorable.
I don't think any of them were aware of that.
They struck it by luck.
Clinton I think hit into that.
I think Clinton was in
his platform was around 370 or something.
And he was a big winner.
So avoid the
extremes and try and hit what's
reasonable. 375
and so that's also the appeal
of all the
spiritual books you see in the
truck stops and all. Who's the big
Warren? Rick Warren.
Yeah. You know his
375 that's enthusiasm.
It's 375 that built the
pyramids, that built the Empire State
Building. It's enthusiastic
good heartedness
and enthusiasm.
It's more than just saying yes.
It's being yes and then being enthusiastic
about the yes and enthusiastic.
So to be enthusiastic
about that which isn't
pretty much almost guarantees success.
Almost guarantees it.
Yeah. And because you're
in a safe level of truth
to begin with you don't have to change your positions
all the time. You don't have to constantly change
position. Yes.
Yes doc.
You were on the last...
Xeno.
Oh I don't want you to ask me that.
Xeno you know
the Xeno paradox
was if a
rabbit and a tortoise start out
at the same time
which will win the race you see.
And see the tortoise
goes slower but the thing is
at any point in time
you've only gone half the distance.
And then at the next point in time
you'll again have gone half the distance.
You will then have gone half the distance.
And according to Xeno's paradox
the rabbit never can catch up with the tortoise
because at any point in time
he's only half way
left.
Even if it's only
one millionth of an inch
he still can't get there.
He still can't get there.
Now I was telling you more
about likelihoods.
The more often you choose
the more likely you choose
a certain choice
with an infinite number of choices
the more likely you are
to choose that again.
Each time you have an infinite possibility.
The fact that you've
chosen this once
and especially if you repeat the choice
quickly, quickly, quickly
the likelihood of your choosing that again
gets higher and higher.
It's a spiritual choice
to forgive, to be
gracious, etc.
The likelihood goes up
that you will choose that again.
So this also reflects intention.
And we spoke of the work
of the doctor
whose name begins with an M
I forget now.
The work on intention.
Yeah?
That intention
then says
so your intention.
You're stating your intention.
That intention now greatly increases
the likelihood
of certain choices.
So this is partly an argument to free will.
Because there is the argument
that there is no such thing as free will.
But it ignores
what we just got through saying.
There is dominance of choice.
So when you make a dominant choice in this direction
then you influence
the whole field.
The likelihood
is much greater that you will choose
a positive option the next time also.
So the holier
you get, the holier you get.
And the worser you get, the worser
you get.
Therefore,
people who are into spiritual integrity
will, yes,
admit a mistake as soon as
they make it and say, I just made a mistake.
Because you
don't want its energy to be out there
and attract other mistakes.
So if you call it by its name
say, you know, that was a mistake
you made a name wrong.
Somebody from history
because
80 year memory is not as great as it was at 30
you know, you can forget a name.
Especially when there is so much
publicity about them, their name gets bandied
about so much that you begin to confuse it
with other people in the same
time era.
So the important thing was to remember
that a double personality can exist.
They do exist.
Their effect on our life
has been devastating.
It is a true clinical condition
and it is a strange
karma. I've never researched
the karma of why there's
two different personalities in one
body. And they trade off
time with each other. They trade off
you've had them for two weeks now
for God's sake.
I haven't even been able to kill anybody for weeks.
And that guy comes on
okay, let's go and have a good time
and stab some people to death.
Stab some children and a nice widow or two.
Pow, pow, pow.
Bang. That one goes out.
Well now this one has to go to jail because of this one.
And of course there's famous criminals.
Famous serial criminals
that are alternate
personalities. You remember the one
that killed Sam
or something like that. God was speaking to him
to kill people.
And the question then
is a judicial one.
You've got to imprison the innocent one
because the criminal
one
is a criminal.
You were going to ask me a question, huh?
Yes. At consciousness
levels below enlightenment
is there a personal me or does it just
Yeah, are you asking about the reality of it
or the illusion of it? There
below 200
Yeah, there is a
personal me. Yeah, there's a
me. It assumes that
I am the experiencer
primarily. And then
as you get higher you become more aware
that you're the
field which
is able to identify that.
So the below
200 people exist but they don't
really comprehend the
significance of existence. People say
how can that be? Well
if you comprehended the value of existence
you wouldn't be able to kill anybody.
It's only when they no longer are
real to you that you can kill them.
So below
200 people are dangerous because
they do not value your
life. They do not
value your life. They can blow up a whole
busload of children.
And they don't feel bad about it.
They themselves don't experience the
value of their own
life as a divine gift. Therefore
they don't value it in others.
So if you don't value your own money
you don't value other people's money either.
So
it sounds strange to say that people below
200 are not aware that they
exist. But I'm telling you about the word
awareness. They exist but they're not really
aware that they exist as such.
And above 200 but
still below enlightenment, is there a personal
me? Oh there very definitely is a
personal operation of a personal me.
Operation is very much
a very personal me. And we spend all
our time worrying about it actually.
The personal me
until you begin to transcend it
and see that it's autonomous.
You get to see the things that are happening
autonomously. However
the autonomous choices
are a consequence of that with
which you have aligned. So
as you choose a higher and higher
commitment even though
they're spontaneous as Medina's
research shows
the choices now begin
to show a preference for that
which is benign and harmless and aligned
with truth rather than
the other way.
Attention set. So Medina calls
it attention set.
Attention set.
So you have
intention and attention
set.
And these tend to dominate it.
These are dominant fields
of consciousness.
So you might picture fields
of progressive power.
And the smaller little
fields like the weather down here
is being dominated by
a more powerful weather field
which is dominated by an even higher
weather field. So
by commitment then
what you're doing is you're setting
the predominant overall field
and out of which
lesser and lesser choices are being made.
So there's still
freedom of the will but it is only
within certain fields.
So
consciousness really has
to do with energy fields.
Energy fields of increasing
power and dominance.
So your spiritual self eventually
becomes the most powerful aspect
as you go over 200.
The etheric
body forms, the etheric brain forms,
you develop
a personal karma
and kundalini
energy dominates
how your brain functions.
Your brain begins
releasing endorphins.
These endorphins
instead of adrenaline.
And the endorphins give you
a right brain
and the brain
dominated by endorphins sees
life as pretty much benign.
Sees life as relatively
benign.
With the proviso as I said
of not being the fool.
Simultaneously not playing the fool.
Oh aren't they nice?
Who just said that just left the world.
Aren't they nice? It's just a nice doggy.
No that is a tiger.
And he will eat you up.
Not because he hates you but because
he's hungry. Oh I see.
Tigers are not evil.
They just want you for dinner.
Should be a compliment.
He says
I want you for dinner baby.
So that gets you off good and evil
when you see that each thing is only being
what it's able to be
at any point in time.
If it could be different than it is
it would be. Therefore we can't
condemn anybody or anything for being
what they are. So
when I say beware of something
I mean
to beware of its upside and its downside.
It doesn't make it good
or better or bad.
It's just that you see it for what it is.
So I can't say
a Komodo dragon is bad.
There's nothing bad about him.
He just likes to bite people.
That's what it is to be a
Komodo dragon. Yes?
Yeah. Then at a certain level
of consciousness you don't have to come back
as a Komodo dragon.
That's how you evolve from being a Komodo dragon.
Yes. Who's next?
Yes. I forgot.
Yes. Yes.
I can't hear the question.
Dominant. Yes.
It becomes progressively
dominant as you
become aligned with the desire to reach
the truth. The capacity
to discern perception from
essence does not really
manifest until about
consciousness level 300.
Which is the opening
of the third eye of the Buddhic body.
The third eye of the etheric Buddhic body.
One of the higher bodies.
And when the
opening of the third eye
is called discernment.
So discernment is not really
dominant
until consciousness level
600.
Up to that time
one can be deceived quite easily.
At 600
you sense
the wolf in the sheep's clothing.
And like with
calibration I sense something out.
And then I calibrate
it and I say yes I got
what the second personality is now.
But you begin
to sense it.
So that's at
600. 600 is
the first level of true
enlightenment.
570 is saintliness.
580, 590 is joy.
Ecstasy.
And finally at 600
there is an incredible
calm. There is
experientially the
peace of God.
And one doesn't really have to remain here
any further.
At 600 you have permission to leave.
And it's a state of
infinite peace.
And infinite oneness beyond
all description.
The peace of God beyond all understanding.
Which is what you hear in
church and sermons. The peace of God
beyond all understanding.
It emerges at level 600.
As I say at that level
you can leave. And 50%
of people who reach that level do leave.
You're invited to leave.
As I say it's almost invitational
to
do so. And then for reasons
remembered
or not
the choice is made.
But again one is sort of
the witness to the choice. So when it
happens one doesn't
know whether they're going to walk on or not
walk on. And it's not really
your problem. There isn't any of you
left to worry about it. So no choice
has to be made. It seems
to be a karmic propensity.
And my own condition
I sort of intuited
had to do with an agreement.
With the fulfillment of an
agreement prior
to this incarnation. And I witnessed
the agreement
taking place. You know.
Like an agreement
that you agreed to fulfill.
Some people
may not be aware that
such a thing goes on in their life. But I think
all of us have made agreements
and promises and that these
are playing a part in our life
right now. Everybody
here has obviously made a
spiritual agreement, commitment or declaration
or they wouldn't be here.
Because this is not a class on bull fighting.
How to gore a bull.
So obviously
everyone here has made one.
Some don't consciously
remember it in this lifetime.
But to be attracted to such a group
and a group that calibrates as high as this
one has to have made such a commitment.
Yes.
Yes. No.
You don't identify a witness observer.
Well yes you do.
At first you realize that
there's
the witnessing and the observing.
And you observe them as phenomena
not as a personage.
There's no watcher and no witness
as an entity.
There's only these functions.
You'll notice that witnessing and watching
are going on all the time.
And these go on
independently of your
you don't have any say so
about it. In other words it's an aspect
of consciousness itself.
Unless you were witnessing and watching
you wouldn't know how to respond to the world.
So the witnessing and the watching
are automatic phenomena.
And therefore
the farther you get back
to the observer and then the witness
and then finally
what is it that's witnessing and observing
brings you back to conscious awareness.
You realize
that what's going on is awareness
of these phenomena.
What's closer to your reality
is the awareness itself.
That your inner reality
is the awareness
quality of consciousness.
No, because there's still
an illusion beyond that.
The illusion has to do with
let's see
that there is someone
that has
it has to do with the life itself
that one identifies
these phenomena
as life.
And
the last story I can remember
had to do with relinquishing
the desire
to be.
The desire to be
was somehow associated with life itself.
That if one gave up
life one would no longer be.
So the block was
to surrender the source
of life itself to divinity.
The only thing left
was the
thought that I exist
and I exist because of
life. And the source of life
so just as I had
laid down ecstasy
joy
and each thing as it arose
there was nothing left
with which I
identified except life itself.
And therefore
there was a knowingness
this too oh lord
do I surrender to thee.
And I surrendered life itself
and then
went through actual experience
of death and it was agony.
It was agony but the
agony was only
for moments.
One actually feels one's self
with a small s
actually die.
It actually dies.
And you experience the death agony.
And beyond that the door opens
and excels his deal.
Glory to God shines forth
is all the radiance of all existence.
Then you're beyond
all of that.
What did we do at 3 o'clock?
Oh
I thought I had some spiritual duty to perform
Take a quick break.
God bless you all.
We'd like to say thank you for everything.
Yes.
And we should say hi from Cornelia from Germany.
Oh yes.
She's doing the Cologne seminar.
She's very excited.
That's very nice. Thank you.
And maybe you can talk about
transcending the attachment to personal love.
Attachment to personal love.
Yeah.
It's a statuation
run by your endocrine system hormone.
Sorry.
There's a craving.
Cravingness.
Cravingness is coming out of your animal.
Try to replace the cravingness
with a lovingness.
Because cravingness is
I'm deficient and I need to get.
Lovingness is
you complete my
fulfill my
happiness.
So one is I have to have
it's coming from one's
animal instinctual nature.
Hippopotamuses do it.
Elephants do it.
So you've got to do it.
Being a young male is not an enviable
place in life frankly.
To transcend it requires
I'll tell you how to
transcend it. How to transcend any
desire of a physical nature
How to overcome a craving.
A craving
first starts in your mind
as an image.
If you watch this carefully
you'll see any craving
first appears as an image.
Whether it's a cheeseburger or a hamburger
the naked body of the opposite sex
or if you're an alcoholic a drinker.
First comes the image of the drink
and if you don't eliminate it instantly
it draws energy to it.
So when it first appears
it's only about five watts.
If you eliminate it within the first second
it's 150 watts and it's 600 watts
then it's a have to.
You can interrupt
the progression by interrupting
the image.
So even if you look at something
a cheeseburger or whatever
it isn't just the cheeseburger
it's instantly now you have an image of the cheeseburger
in your mind and that's what you crave.
Therefore you have to be very fast
and see
the object of the cravingness
appear in your consciousness
and make a choice to eliminate it now.
Yeah?
That's how you do it.
I was telling alcoholics
you've got about one or two seconds
to eliminate that image of a drink.
In the book Alcoholics Anonymous
it talks about some guy who was sober
14 years or something, 11 years
and he walked across
in the hall or something of a hotel
and the image of a martini
came into his mind
and mindlessly he walked to the bar
and after 13, 14 years
of sobriety
relapsed and got drunk.
So it was in that one second.
So you'll see that in the AA book
in which
the early members recount their experiences
that out of nowhere
suddenly appeared
the image of the martini.
That's when he had his chance.
When he didn't eliminate the martini
that instant he automatically
walked over to the bar
and lost 14 years of sobriety.
He didn't like consciously choose
he just didn't have the
consciousness technique
the spiritual technique.
Right? That's a secret.
Don't tell anybody.
A short question on the technique of surrender
as you described it
like in the final run
and like maybe more like
a confirmation maybe
when the sword is there
every sword has a hook
or a choose
and what I'm doing is
try to intuit the choose
so then the thought process
falls away?
I see you're trying to
eliminate thought before it reaches
the formation of the thought.
Eventually, yeah.
You can feel the image
of a dogginess coming up
out of the nothingness
arises a dogginess
big dogginess and then it becomes
a dog, then it becomes an old rover
then it becomes how an old rover got hit by the car
and then how we all cried
and it was my daughter's third birthday
and the whole family was sad
I mean it's a whole long tale
so you have to catch it as it emerges.
And the way
to give up the choose
would be the best way to do it?
To give up wanting to have it?
Give up the image
I can't really tell you
how to do that. You have to
experiment with it and reflect on it.
You don't
allow, you feel the energy
of thinkingness begin to arise
and now it's going to spill forth
figure.
So you let go the energy
of wanting to think
earlier and earlier
in the process.
It feels like a desire?
Yes it is, that's correct.
A desire to think.
You're going to feel like an attack
of thinkingness is coming on you.
When it's that much thinking
don't meditate, do something else
until it's gone.
That's very good.
It comes out of no form
it begins to gather form
and as it gathers form it gathers energy.
And by the time it gets to over over
and now you've got to run over by the truck
it's too late already.
You stay on the advancing edge
just prior to thinkingness.
And you see your thinkingness
as just amusement anyway.
Dr. Hawkins,
recently I've been shown to be aware
of my
self-centeredness.
Wait a minute.
Get closer to the mic and speak slowly.
Recently I've been made to be aware
of self-centeredness.
My self-centeredness?
Self-centeredness.
Oh yes.
And I want to ask you how to work on that.
Well it's like self-centeredness
is watching yourself in the movie.
So give up watching yourself in the movie.
See they're signing the book, right?
Then I could also be
aware of who's signing the book
and the fact that you're signing a book.
Look at all that, it's boring.
It's boring.
That's how self-centeredness can be.
Now I'm sitting in the chair
and I'm talking to Dr. Hawkins
and you see how boring all that is?
So that's a self,
I don't know,
sort of like you're doing a video
of yourself at the same time.
You see what I mean?
And it's a habit of thought.
It's a habit of thought.
And once you're aware that you're doing it
as a habit, it tends to diminish.
You just do what you're doing
without being aware that there's a you
see?
That happens of its own.
You don't say, well Dr. Hawkins,
I think while I'm talking to her
I'll wave my hands in the air
and go blah blah blah blah blah.
You know how boring that would be?
It would kill the spontaneity of it.
Intuitively you try to respond
in a nonverbal manner because
otherwise people mentalize
a mentalization.
Spontaneously just be that which you are
without any comment, without any witnessing of it.
They say when you scramble eggs
don't be saying, gee how good am I
scrambling these eggs.
That ruins the eggs for one thing.
It's like one's higher self
knows all these things
and you don't have to track it
with your lower self.
Just noticing it tends to diminish it.
Just noticing it.
See?
I don't say, now I am sitting in a chair
on a pillow and talking to you.
I don't say that, right?
I'm sort of saying, now I'm sitting in a chair
talking to you.
So what I want you to do is get bored with
self observation.
Mindfulness is something else.
We're talking about now self observation.
Mindfulness will tell you that
you're hooked in self observation.
That's what you're complaining about.
But that came out of mindfulness
which is something better.
Mindfulness is okay.
You have mindfulness
that's why you're complaining about it.
If you weren't mindful you wouldn't know
and you just think that's the way I am.
So that means good progress.
Where do these come from?
Hi. Hello.
I've simplified this question as much as I can
Dr. Hawkins.
I don't seem to have enough physical energy
to do what I want to do right now.
And I want to know
what the obstacle is blocking
my physical energy.
The intention may not be as strong as you
I mean
if you're into ought to, ought to
this and ought to that.
That's the hypothetical.
How do you know the ought to has any
reality to it?
I ought to be peeling more potatoes than I am.
I ought to be able to peel eight
and I only peel four.
That's projecting the hypothetical.
Why not just settle for the real?
You can only peel four potatoes at this time
in your life.
And don't invite a lot of company for dinner.
Can I do a follow up?
I mean
I think along the spiritual pathway there's
periods, sometimes long periods
where your capacity to function is really curtailed.
Really curtailed.
You say
I don't think I have the energy to
put my shoes and socks
on today.
Somehow the instinct of survival
takes over and you do what you need
to do.
So I wouldn't worry about it.
Between expectation and
actual capacity.
In spiritual endeavor a great deal of energy
goes into the spiritual work
and you don't realize it.
But
it siphons off a lot of energy
that would otherwise go into physicality
and movement, etc.
Thank you.
There are periods where you do nothing.
I spent several years just meditating
and doing nothing.
In the view of the world, doing nothing.
Sat cross-legged for years.
Thank you very much.
Black widow spiders were underneath the
seat in fact.
One time I looked down there and
I was just sitting there meditating
in this place for years
and there were black widow spiders
living under the chair.
Evil spirits, huh?
Yeah.