Yes, ma'am.
Speak.
Okay, I'll speak.
Okay.
Free speech.
Okay, here it goes.
My question is about having compassion for being human.
I notice that I have a lot of, like, self-judgment.
It's more like a feeling, not like thoughts happen, but it's just sort of a,
I notice there's some deep-seated self-hatred.
And a fear of making mistakes, just a lot of judgment.
And I feel, like, inside, I feel like that compassion is there towards myself.
Like, I can feel it in there.
Like, I can taste it.
But it's just not, like, there yet.
Like, it's not, you know, a part of my life.
And I just want to be okay with being human.
Be okay to do what?
Just be okay with being human and making mistakes.
No, hatred is excessive.
No, we all realize.
A decent regret.
A decent regret is what's appropriate.
You know, you ran over six people.
You burned down their house and caused them to go bankrupt.
And what's required is a decent regret.
Don't forget that other people are also at the effect of their karma as well.
Okay.
So you can't take on omnipotence to yourself.
I am the cause of that or something like that.
You may have had a participatory involvement.
Okay.
But you're only a participant.
You're not a determiner of outcomes, you see.
Okay.
So you forgive yourself for just being more limited than you might think you are.
You put in your two cents worth, but that's about it.
Okay.
Because the momentum of a person's life is what's running them 90% of the time.
Their life is in a spin to begin with.
And you got in their life, and then after you left, their life got worse.
And you say, oh, look what I did.
They were in a free fall to begin with.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
That helps a lot.
Thank you.
Yeah.
You know how to get involved with scrupulosity, see?
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
Have kindness and forgiveness towards yourself.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
There's a wrinkle cloth here, huh?
Yes, indeed.
Hello.
Ha ha.
Where are these all coming from?
My goodness.
Yes.
Well, first, I just want to say I love you, Dr. Hawkins.
Oh, thank you.
And thank you for all your help.
Thank you.
You speak about disidentification with the mind, ego.
And I saw you in August.
And since that time, I've had a better perception of disidentification with thoughts and mentalization.
Yeah.
Don't identify them as me.
Yes.
And that's-
The mind is an it.
Yes.
So once you understand the mind's an it, stop calling it me.
You know, you can say, it is screwed up today.
I, however, am pure and innocent.
Well, there's been an experience of that.
And if there's a trigger, so for instance, the other day on the phone, there was a conversation.
And I got triggered.
And it seemed as though I went from, like I was forced back into my body almost.
Like I felt it in my solar plexus.
You got a hit.
Yeah.
And so I went from that state of being able to witness to being the-
Oh, yeah.
So that's normal.
You know, spiritual progression is erratic.
You know what I'm saying?
It's erratic.
And well, you know, no, no, you wasn't in that bad a deal.
No, it wasn't that bad.
You got fractured out of a good space, you know.
My immediate response was to try to, well, not try.
My immediate response was forgiveness.
You put your thumb and middle finger together, both sides, and think the sound ah.
Out of divinity, I am forgiven.
You hold the thumb and the middle finger.
You sound the sound ah.
Think ah.
Ah.
Think, think, think ah.
Think ah.
Okay.
Let me have your arm.
He's now clear, is this.
You're now clear.
You just cleared that negativity.
You have to, like, clear the aura.
Yes, that's another way, yeah.
Is om even better than ah, silently?
No.
Okay.
You can do the thymic thump.
Yeah.
Ah, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
You can do them all at the same time.
It's really fun.
Think the sound ah, sound the sound om, om, hold these together, and then thump the thymus.
By that time, you've forgotten what the hell you were feeling guilty about.
Well, may I just have a blessing that I can maintain that as long as possible?
You can maintain that.
Thank you.
He was detached and became undetached.
Those are the blessings.
So, coming down.
Yes.
Um, could you help me, um, ah, with the, ah, some Luciferic temptations, like, um, love
is a constraint or limitation to freedom, or pride and power?
All right.
You'll have to translate what he says.
Say it again.
I'm sorry.
Um, like, how to protect oneself, or to deal with the Luciferic temptations?
How to protect yourself, or...
Deal with?
Protect yourself against Luciferic temptations.
Yes.
For example?
That love is a constraint.
Well, I already explained several methods, and, ah, traditionally, also, people burn incense,
and, ah, smudge the room, ah, mantras.
And if it comes...
Oh.
What negativity is going to dare come near you?
I was thinking more of temptations that come from inside.
You're thinking what?
Temptations that come from more inside.
Yes.
What about them?
Like, um, that love is a constraint to freedom?
Love is a constraint to freedom.
Where did you hear that?
Well, um...
From a demonic entity?
I guess so.
I think so.
The correct translation of that is, is attachment is a deterrent to enlightenment.
Love is the royal road.
The way of the heart is the royal road.
Divinity and love are not two distinct things.
Love is a quality of divinity.
Attachment, however, is what they're talking about.
Neither attachments nor aversions.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Okay?
Thank you very much.
It's the attachment.
No.
Hi.
Um, Doc, how do you know when you have an attachment to love?
Well, if you're not worried about it, you probably don't have an attachment.
Okay.
It's feeling that you'll die without the other person, that you don't want to go on,
that your life is over and ruined.
Mm-hmm.
You've made them the be-all and end-all of your life.
Uh-huh.
And lost sense of your own sense of self.
And how can you tell the difference between romantic love and unconditional love?
Unconditional love, you love the person no matter what they do or whether they stay with
you or they don't.
Conditional love, they only stay with you, I mean, you love them if they stay with you.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Okay.
And a lot of times, it's a combination of both.
There's some real love, also some attachment.
Yeah.
Okay.
Biologic forces are very powerful.
The survival of the race, you know, depends on biologic drives.
See, you can't just do a outro, because if it wasn't for biologic drives, you wouldn't
be here to complain about them.
Yes?
I have a picture?
Um?
Uh-huh. Yes, indeed. That's all right. It's okay. Uh-huh. Good to see you again.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Hello. Hello, Susan. As always, I'm compelled to give my heartfelt thanks and
gratitude to you for your dedication to your students. Your dedication to us profoundly moves
me, and I'm deeply grateful. And to you as well, Susan. Your devotion to Dr. Hawkins is
deeply admirable, and we love you for that, too. We love you, Dr. Hawkins. Thank you. You're
welcome. My question today is about you make reference to certain truths that humanity can't
handle, that are results of your research, that are not published.
Yes. And I was wondering if you would consider
making some of those, some of that information available when you feel-
What the public can't handle? You want me to make it public?
To those of us who might be able to handle it. I just feel that there's-
As you do your own investigation, you'll run across things that cannot really, I mean,
theoretically could be shared, but pragmatically speaking,
things that's written is not fit to print, see?
Right.
So it also requires discretion, who and where to share certain things, huh?
Mm-hm.
I mean, there's whole segments of society that are totally built on falsehood. Totally.
The whole thing is completely fallacious. The whole industry is based on a fallacy.
Scientific endeavors, multi-billion dollar research projects, which I can tell you the
outcome of the research project.
Mm-hm.
Yeah.
about 10 billion dollars ahead of where I know it's going to be.
So there's credibility, you know, all things are.
Logos, ethos, and pathos.
Logos is the wisdom of the speaker.
Ethos is the caliber of the communication.
And pathos is the receptivity of the audience.
So you can't ignore any one of them.
You have to have an authentic message.
It has to be authentically presented.
And then you have to have discernment about the audience.
There's certain things that you cannot tell people,
or you could only tell them under different circumstances,
under a different relationship, let's say,
because they're not ready to handle it yet.
So it's a subtlety.
Any situation requires.
Discernment.
And psychoanalysis.
Then the patient walks in the room,
and they've made an appointment.
I already know about 90% of what ails them.
But I'm not going to tell them now, you know.
Maybe six months from now, when they've developed trust,
and when many of the things have turned out to be helpful
that you've taught them.
And then would be the right time, so you see.
Well, I trust you're knowing this.
And the means is correct, but the timing is wrong.
So.
You know, there's lots of things we could put in the books
that would blow the scarf off people's ears, but.
I want to read that book.
But thank you.
It's a post-mortem book.
Post-mortem.
Well, I kind of assumed that, actually.
But I trust your judgment to always reveal to us what we know.
You always have to.
You see, because you're responsible
for the whole phenomena, all three phases,
what they can handle.
And.
Whether the truth is really truthful,
and if you can express it in a way that is, you know, correct.
We're deeply grateful for the truth that you do reveal to us.
Thank you.
And I ask for your blessings.
God bless you.
Thank you.
Namaste.
Well, I mentioned some things
that people don't know the answers to, you know.
The secrets of some of the most traditional mysteries.
Who was Jack the Ripper?
Whatever happened to Amelia Earhart?
Who stole the Lindbergh baby?
You know, stuff that goes on in the press decade after decade.
You can find out the answer to all those things
in about two minutes flat, you know.
Thank you.
Did you know who did it?
Yep.
Dr. Hawkins, Susan.
First off, I've just recently been introduced to your work,
and I am deeply honored to be in your presence
and to be up here today.
So, thank you.
Thank you.
Yes.
My question is, as an actor, if I assume the role of a,
a villain, is there any karmic consequence to that?
That's a good question.
I think it may depend on karmic propensities.
Okay.
We have permission to ask this.
There is some risk in assuming the role of a villain, resist.
As an actor, he is safe from any negative effects
of playing the role of a negative person.
I guess as an actor, you are protected.
Thank you.
It's probably the skill.
Yeah, it's because it's a craft skill.
You know, like in surgery, you cut somebody, but, you know,
you're not guilty of laceration because you're doing surgery.
I could see your consternation about it,
though I'd probably give it a thought myself, you know.
Very well.
Thank you so much, and I'm honored.
Yeah, it's a craft, but I could see his concern
because you don't know what kind of entities you're going
to pull into the field, you know.
Yeah. Yeah.
What's happening?
The symphony in red.
Hi.
So good to be back.
Yes.
I come to give you an update on my daughter's situation.
Since the six months that we've been introduced to your work,
we've followed everything that you have suggested in the past,
taking her off of sugar.
I found an integrous psychiatrist that finally believed me
that didn't want to lock us both up.
And she understands that the antipsychotic
that she gave my daughter, it started out at two milligrams,
but she could still hear the demons talking to her.
Yeah.
She hasn't tried to kill herself,
and she hasn't tried to kill me again, so that's good.
And so we're at five milligrams, and the voices stopped.
She stopped hearing the voices, but she's still having seizures.
In fact, the seizures have worsened.
So now what I do, when she goes into one, I can almost intuit that it's going
to happen, and I put my hand on her back, and I say the prayer to refuse and rebuke,
and yet it's still coming, and now I'm hearing music in my head.
You're hearing music?
Both of us.
So why am I hearing things?
Normally I can feel them touch me when it's at its worst, but what is this music?
Because if I go to the doctor and tell them I'm hearing music, they're going to want to lock me up.
They're going to want to lock us up.
Okay. We have permission to ask about this.
This one here has a brain disorder of a minimal degree, which one has a more maximal degree.
Okay. So it's congenital.
She's got a minimal degree.
It's an aberration of neurological functioning.
It's not necessarily pathologic.
It's just a variation, you know.
You can quell it if you wish.
Orthomolecular psychiatry suggested various nutritional means of altering the brain chemistry
by introducing larger doses of vitamin B3 and vitamin C,
which by mass action then tend to throw brain chemistry into a different area,
less likely to produce those kinds of neurologic effects.
Those are just a neurophysiology.
There's various ways you can change it experimentally, I suppose.
Acupuncture, there's a very, nutrition and acupuncture.
And with academic medicine, you're already doing what you can do, you know.
No seizure, how do I address the seizures?
Do I put her back on seizure meds?
Do I take her to a neurologist?
Because she's at 20.
Where did she get the seizure meds to begin with?
The quacks at Mayo.
The quacks at Mayo in Rochester, Minnesota.
I'm sorry, Mayo Clinic.
The Mayo Clinic is where she got the seizure meds.
Oh, yes.
Well, I would just, why don't you just continue it?
Put her back on some of it that test out.
What one is it?
Ethoxymide.
Huh?
Uh-huh.
You got a neurologist or psychiatrist now?
We have both.
Okay.
They should certainly be able to answer that question.
And anti-seizure medication should bring about improvement, you know, with no downside.
I know.
It hasn't worked yet, but I have faith that it will.
And on the antipsychotic, it's at such a high dose that it makes her sleepy and unable to go to school or function.
So what I had hoped to do is just maybe take her back down to the five milligrams of the antipsychotic and then not so much like, it's not doping.
Yeah.
It's not doping her all the time.
All clinical work is trial and error.
Okay.
Trial and error.
And you're dealing with likelihoods and balance, you know.
Too much, you get sleepy.
Too little, the symptoms come back.
And then there's a variety of medications now in that class, so there's probably half
a dozen things that would be helpful, you know.
Okay.
And so you try this, and then from that, the clinician guesses that this would probably
also be helpful.
And maybe not make you so sleepy or something, you know.
Yeah.
So it's a matter of expertise in clinical psychopharmacology, that's all.
My daughter is usually too scared to ask you a question, but she wrote one down, and she
wanted to hold Ms. Susan's hand while she asked it.
I'm not getting what she's saying.
She's going too close to the...
Yeah.
All right.
Yes.
I'm only 17.
However, I want to become enlightened.
But I'm scared my dreams and my goals of this world will keep me from it.
Being involved in this world will keep you from enlightenment?
Well, first you have to master this world before you can leave it.
So I wouldn't worry about that.
I'd work on making yourself as successful as possible as you can within the worldly
domain, and then worry about transcending it.
You can't transcend it until you've mastered it.
So first, with practice, et cetera, try to become as expertise as you can in handling
this world.
And then you use psychopharmacology to compensate for any neurologic genetic things you've got,
see?
Those are just genetic and biochemical.
Genetic and biochemical.
Thank you for all of your help, Dr. Hawkins.
I feel like you are truly the only one that can help us, or even believes us, when we
tell them that we see these things, and it touches, and that she hears them, and she
hears them.
You're truly the only one that's believed us.
Well, those are relatively common, you know?
When you see large numbers of patients, you know, a certain percentage have these symptoms
fall into certain categories, you know, hearing or visual or something.
And with a little experimentation, you can usually find what works.
Everybody's brain chemistry is different, you know.
But with experience, you can pretty much guess pretty often, you know, one milligram of prolific
does it, you know?
Maybe two, three at the most.
Yes, sir.
Yeah.
Thank you for everybody for waiting.
I know this took a little long.
Thank you.
Yes.
And you augment it with other things, too.
You augment it with nutrition, diet, acupuncture, everything you think might be helpful.
Boo.
You just hit it hammer and tongs, and it'll get better.
Yeah.
You know, be a doctor.
Too much.
Here's a case for experienced ..
Hi.
Yeah.
I just wanted to take a moment and look into your eyes and ask for the transmission
of no mind.
There's nothing to transmit because there's no mind.
How can I send you nothingness?
Inferning in the auric field.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
lifetimes ago that I was with myself, 24, 25, a long time ago, almost to the Buddha.
Yeah.
I have a six-year-old son who, from a very young age, I knew he was very open and received
messages.
Can you speak slower and closer to the mic?
Sure.
Yes.
I have a six-year-old son.
Six.
Mm-hmm.
And from a very young age, I knew that he was very open and very gifted in many senses.
And he's having a little bit of difficulty in school in the sense that he's a very active
child and very bright, and they're trying to peg him to be, you know, the normal public
school.
And I was wondering if you could tell me something that would be able to help him.
Help what?
Just for him to adapt or...
I don't get what you're saying.
He's bright and active.
And then what?
Yes.
And then what comes out?
What kind of a...
They're just...
They're trying to label him.
What do you mean, label him?
It's just ADD or...
Maybe he has ADD.
That's not a label.
Broken leg is not a label.
It's a broken leg.
He's lost all of his...
Huh?
He's lost all of his sense of wanting to perform.
He feels like there's a lot of negative attention instead of helping him in...
What kind of negative attention?
Like, he's losing recess because he's wiggling around in his seat, because he needs to run
around.
All right.
You're being evasive.
What's his clinical diagnosis?
ADHD?
I haven't had him tested with anything.
Is he on any kind of treatment?
No.
So what is the complaint?
The teacher says he's hyperactive?
Yeah, and so he wiggles around in his seat, so then she restricts him from recess, which
is what the run...
Yes.
Is he able to desist at that time?
Can he stop?
No, he has no...
He doesn't seem to have any control of his body.
He just wants to move all the time.
No, he just wants to move all the time.
It sounds like you need to have him tested.
Yeah, he probably has just ADD or ADHD, which is a very simple thing to cure, by the way.
How long does it take to cure it?
About three and a half minutes.
Give him a cup of coffee.
Yeah.
And see if he calms down.
Okay.
The caffeine.
It's due to...
The caffeine reacts differently to...
See, the human body is normally like this all the time, and the prefrontal cortex, right
in front of this corona, there's a section of the brain, its function is to suppress.
All right.
So if the prefrontal cortex is underactive, it allows the rest of the thing to constantly
go, like a chicken with its head cut off runs wildly around, because you've cut off the
suppressor strips.
My guess would be clinically, he's got a deficient function of the prefrontal cortex,
so that the suppressor strips are not suppressing hyperactivity.
Yeah?
Okay.
It's simple, and there's nothing to it.
It's sort of a neurologic variant, and it's quite common.
You know, 5%, 10% of kids all have it, and a lot of them grow out of it.
And there's also various nutritional approaches to it.
Untreated.
The side effects of untreating it are going to be worse than the illness itself.
By the time you've been bad enough and been put in the naughty seat, enough time your
self-esteem is going to be zilch.
So I would treat it early rather than go into denial and say there's nothing wrong.
Okay.
It's better to go in and treat it, you know, because if you don't, the child will have
to begin to fail and begin to see himself as failing or see himself as bad, and it's
a simple...
Neurologic disorder.
It has to do with balance of brain chemistry.
Thank you.
Okay.
Let's see if what I said is the truth.
The child has an insufficiency of prefrontal cortex suppression.
You know, that's all it is.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
So I would treat it, say, because the consequences of not treating it behaviorally, psychologically,
emotionally are worse than the illness, say, say.
By the time you wear the dunce cap every day, you begin to feel like an idiot.
See? It's just because you can't control yourself.
Okay. Thank you very much.
I once had to wear the naughty mittens in kindergarten.
The naughty mittens?
Naughty mittens.
You had to put like a dunce cap on, and they were naughty mittens.
And you had to sit in the front row in kindergarten with the naughty mittens on.
That was from talking in class.
Yeah.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
You'd mentioned at one of the lectures that when driving from Phoenix to Sedona,
that you disappeared time by surrendering to the experiencing of it.
Is that correct?
Yes.
Letting go of the resisting of it.
I'd just like to please ask if you could just expand on that a little bit.
No.
When I tried.
You'll notice that you're running constantly a sense of time.
All right.
So you can either.
There's two systems.
One is to not go resisting it.
And just swamp yourself with a sense of time until time becomes itself oppressive.
You see?
You can turn it around in the other direction.
Let go of resisting experiencing time, you know?
Anyway, if you let go of resisting time, eventually you'll disappear it.
You're experiencing time because you're trying to go faster than the time.
You're feeling the time is like a delay.
It's like boring to drive all the way home from Phoenix, you see?
Yeah.
It's a drag.
What's it a drag on?
It's a drag on your sense of time.
So if you let go in to change that, you can actually eventually eliminate the sense of time.
And you can leave Phoenix and two seconds later be impressed on experientially.
So there's a certain thought, way of thinking that you only experience that which you resist.
And when you totally stop resisting, no experiencing occurs because there's nothing to experience.
That's the general rule.
So if.
If I was trying to experience time, all right, so what I try to do is I try to just start experiencing.
I got confused.
It's like, how do you experience time?
It's like, you know, do you look at your watch and watch the clock, you know, tick or start thinking?
Time is a subjective clock, a subjective experience.
How long ago you and I have been sitting here talking?
A minute.
I don't know.
A minute or two minutes.
See, you were tracking it all along.
I said, I just got through telling you.
I was tracking it?
How would you know it's one or two minutes?
I was tracking it.
Well, you knew it wasn't five hours, three days, a month and a half.
Right.
So you were tracking it all the time.
Yes.
Yep.
Okay.
So how do I stop resisting that?
How do you know you're resisting it?
I don't.
I'm pretty confused about the whole thing.
You know, that's what I don't get, you know.
Maybe it's not the fastest track for you, you know.
Okay.
Okay, what would be?
Oh, that'd be two questions.
You let go experiencing time itself,
or you can let go resisting the experiencing of time.
Either way will undo it.
Okay.
Uh-huh.
But your mind is tracking time all the time.
Okay.
You know how long we've been sitting here.
Approximately, yes.
So you've been tracking it.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
The mind is such a trickster.
Hello?
Oh, it's not writing.
I can't read it in here.
Yes.
Hi, I'm interested in understanding more about spiritual energy.
Is the process of trying to accumulate it through receiving communion
or listening to high-calibrated music, or?
Well, you don't accumulate the energy.
You intensify it.
That's not going to write on here.
It's...
You can intensify it by devotion to beauty,
and music, and spirituality, and prayer.
Yes?
Is that a direct path to God, or a diversion?
Well, two things are going on.
One is you're increasing the spiritual energy itself.
The other is you're getting closer to...
It's because of this surface.
No, it was getting another...
Yeah.
You can increase the spiritual energy by devotion.
And all spiritual techniques and methods, et cetera,
tend to...
To increase the flow of the kundalini energy.
So what is your question?
I was wondering if that process was a direct path or a diversion,
like you talk about the astral circus,
the process of going to relics or listening to music
or receiving communion, stuff like that.
No, those are not diversions.
Those are direct.
Now, the astral circus is something else.
It's all that ooh-la-la voices from other out-of-body teachers and crap.
Do you know what I mean?
I mean, it's like in the library.
You're reading the tarot cards and getting readings and visiting psychics.
Okay, thank you.
Because even if the psychic is correct, so what?
There's one well-known one who is correct.
Calvary's at 440.
He's not lying.
What he said is true.
And then the question is, so what?
Okay.
Yeah, hi.
Hi.
Dr. Hawkins, how do you relate to...
and treat the ego when it becomes afraid for its own annihilation?
I'm not hearing her.
How do you treat the ego when it becomes afraid of its own annihilation?
You'd have to say, and then what?
And then you would have to surrender.
You do it by surrendering.
Each positionality has a quasi-reality to it,
and you have to be willing to surrender that.
If I so-and-so, then what?
So then you keep letting go until there's nothing left to let go of.
What you'll come to is the bottom of the stack,
and the bottom of the stack is always, and then I'll die.
If I stop eating, then I'll starve.
If I starve, I'll get thin, and I'll get a week,
and I'll fall over, and then I'll die.
No matter what you do, you always end up at the stack, and then I'll die.
People won't like me. Then what?
Then I'll be expelled by society.
Yeah, and then what?
So you'd use, and then what?
And each, and then what?
You'll come up.
The bottom of the stack is always death,
and then I'll die is what the ego's really afraid of
because it identifies with the body.
So if you say, all right, so let's die and get it over with.
I'll talk into action. Let's hear it, big mouth.
Call the ego's bluff.
Whatever his worst threat is, you surrender to it.
Then you'll be ugly, yes, and then the girls will go out with you, yes,
and then you'll die of loneliness, yes, right.
So die already.
You're still alive.
You're still alive and kicking.
Well, is its fear of enlightenment different from that?
There isn't such a thing as fear of enlightenment.
That's an imagination.
You seem like you're afraid of being in a state of infinite love and peace.
You can't really be afraid of that unless you're going to lose your job.
Can't be under view anymore.
Thank you, sweetheart.
It's always good to see you.
So how are you today?
Immensely grateful to be here.
I don't have a question.
No question.
I'm just going to say thank you so much.
Well, very good.
All is known or unknowable.
Either way, it's okay.
Thank you.
You come along pretty good yourself.
Hello, doctor.
Hello.
But I don't have any question.
Life itself is so precious because I want your blessing for my spiritual journey.
He wants a blessing?
Blessing for what?
For my spiritual journey.
He wants a blessing for his future journey.
Future journey?
Yes.
What do you mean a future journey?
Spiritual.
I'm sorry.
Spiritual journey.
I thought he said future journey.
I did too.
I'm sorry.
Well, yes, because you are here and you and I are together.
And obviously the reason.
The reason is because of your own spiritual integrity and desire to progress and reach
the level of enlightenment.
Yes?
Okay.
Thank you.
We said it was one in 90 million?
One in 80 million?
Eighty.
Eighty or 90 million.
You keep saying 90.
It's 80.
Well, whatever it is.
It doesn't really matter.
It's up there.
You have a right to be wrong.
Honey, it's either 80 or 90.
Yeah.
Start counting.
One, two, three, four, five.
One, two, three, four.
One in 80 or 90.
To merely desire to reach enlightenment is already an extreme rarity.
Well, I just don't want all the emails telling us that you said 90 is an 80 or 90.
We tell them he's getting old now.
They don't know 80 from 90.
How are you doing?
What is the difference?
Is there a difference between awareness and spirit?
Is there a difference between subjectivity?
A difference between awareness and subjectivity.
Is there a difference between the two?
Well, yeah, somewhat.
One is content and the other is field.
Awareness is more diffuse.
Subjectivity you're talking about the sense of me and I.
Awareness is an aspect of consciousness itself that does not necessarily even involve an
I or subjectivity.
It's a sense of personhood.
Awareness is aware without necessarily a person being aware.
So you can move beyond the witness to conscious awareness and the realization there is no
person, no one, no entity that is being aware or conscious.
It's consciousness becoming aware of its own consciousness.
So the next step is to depersonalize it.
Witnessing is witnessing.
Witnessing is happening as a phenomenon all of its own.
You don't have to interject the idea that there's an I that is doing the witnessing.
That's a narcissistic projection.
Witnessing is witnessing.
It doesn't need a person.
So the subjectivity is a presumption that there's an I that is doing this or to whom
this is happening.
Are there any I?
I don't know.
It's a habit of thought.
It's a habit of thought that there's an I that is conscious or aware.
There is no I that is conscious or aware.
When you say that the subjectivity is the essence of divinity.
Well, subjectivity is the arena.
It's not an out there-ness.
It's an in here-ness.
I think I'm still stuck in I, the I in your prologue.
You have a sentence that says, I'm in here.
I'm in here.
Subjectivity is the illumination of the self as the infinite I.
I guess my other question is, what is the infinite I as opposed to self?
I guess there's no opposition, but I don't understand the difference between self and
I.
Well, because I is subject or context, I-ness as a person, as a personhood, is a presumption.
Yes?
That's a presumption.
See?
You can let go of the presumption.
Awareness can be aware without there being a person who's doing the aware-ness-ing, who's
doing the being aware.
These are phenomena that occur of their own autonomously.
That's the point to get.
They're occurring autonomously, not as subject-verb, not as subject-verb-object.
Okay?
Witnessing is happening as a consequence of the fact that it is, that is its quality
to witness.
It's presumptive error to interject that there's an I to whom this is happening.
That's an illusion.
There is no personal I to whom this is happening.
Awareness is aware because that's the quality of awareness, period.
Is awareness manifest?
Is what?
Awareness manifest.
Is manifest.
Is awareness manifest?
No, manifest is the wrong word.
What is awareness then?
How would the question arise without awareness of the question.
What is the context of the question?
How could there be a cloud without a sky?
So in other words instead of focusing on the cloud, you would focus on the sky.
And then as things come by, that is the awareness.
Awareness of the content but what she's stuck in is...
Right.
There's the presumption that there's a you
that is doing the witnessing.
So you've interjected a subjectivity
of an imaginary pronoun called I.
What is the infinite I, then?
What is the infinite I?
The infinite I is one that is beyond all pronouns.
It's a quality of existence itself.
Okay, thank you.
You get those by meditation rather than logic or reason.
It's hard to nail it down, the question.
Yeah, it's more an awareness.
It's hard to put it in words.
Yeah, it is all really beyond words.
It's an awareness that is a spontaneous emergence.
I would look at it through meditation
rather than through the mind.
She's asking me the question through her mind.
Where did she disappear to?
That's right.
It's arrived at through meditation, I would say.
An understanding of it, yes.
Doc, I know some people here in Sedona
who have used a type of psychotherapy
to help them process non-integrity.
Can you hear me okay?
Yeah.
What is he saying?
In Sedona, they're what?
Some people in Sedona are using psychotherapy
to process...
Emotional negativity.
Psychotherapy to process emotional negativity.
That's probably a good idea.
I know some people who have done that.
You also speak of your own psychoanalysis.
Yes.
And I just wanted to ask you
to speak about the role of psychotherapy
or psychoanalysis in the life of a spiritual seeker.
When is it appropriate?
When is it useful?
In the life of a spiritual teacher?
Seeker.
Student.
Oh, oh.
Well, to know thyself, correct?
Isn't that the basic dictum?
Know thyself.
So first know thyself before you go beyond it
because you don't even know what yourself is
that you want to transcend.
So psychotherapy, you know, analytic type therapy,
I think is extremely helpful
to understand how the mind works.
It's mechanisms, how it originated
in your own particular case.
So know thyself, then.
Whose dictum is that?
I forget.
Know thyself.
Shakespeare.
Huh?
No.
Know thyself?
No. Know thyself is.
Descartes?
Huh?
Is it Descartes?
No. Before Descartes.
Anyway, know thyself is written in some great statue
or something, one of the first premises
of ancient Greek philosophy or something.
First of all, know thyself.
Know thyself, yeah.
Would you recommend using traditional psychoanalysis
or a more multidisciplinary spiritually oriented practitioner?
I don't know.
That's too general a question.
I have no idea what a multi or, you know, what I mean.
Well, like someone who is aware of your work, for example.
Yeah.
And has that, and is using that as part
of their understanding of you.
Yeah.
Versus someone who is Freudian, for example.
Oh.
Either.
Either way.
The fact that the analyst is an atheist doesn't affect you
because he's not concerned with that, nor is he even going
to bring it in, you know, except as anecdotally, you know.
But any analyst, Jungian, Freudian, et cetera,
to know thyself.
Thank you.
It's the first dictum of something or other that's famous
and I can't remember what it is.
I'm still trying to think about it.
You'll come to me in the middle of the night.
Oops.
Oh, yes, right.
Doc, I just wanted to ask you if you could touch on if one really wants
to devote, you know, intensely to their life, you know, to just giving up,
surrendering the self completely, if that should come
about on a spiritual aspirant's journey at some time,
what are the necessary requisites you would say as a teacher to a student?
And also any possible, like, pitfalls or things that one should watch out for,
perhaps, on such an endeavor?
What endeavor?
A spiritual endeavor.
What?
To?
Surrender everything.
To surrender everything.
What are the pitfalls?
Are there any pitfalls?
You know, just die or something.
Okay.
Yeah. I mean, I know you've touched on a lot of your books on the requisites, but, I mean,
what would be the requisite a student would, no, forget about it.
It's okay.
Well, the bottom line.
Yeah.
You could add the bottom line no matter what.
That would make any technique even more powerful.
Okay.
Let's say you want, you're picking surrendering, wanting this, and eventually you reach, oh,
I'm wanting to reach the state of not wanting this.
Could I let go of that wanting this?
You understand what I'm saying?
Mm-hmm.
You're, like, untethering the balloon and where it might go.
You have to go in the following direction.
You have to follow.
Thank you.
Let's see.
You want to let go of wanting this, yes?
Could you let go wanting to?
Let go of all wanting this.
Mm-hmm.
And, Susan, I'm first time here, and I've been four year and a half still studying you,
and it's been a great journey.
The question is not about me.
You got to speak slower.
The question is about studying.
Yeah.
It's a great question.
If you're someone who is suffering from ALS, and they deny, actually, that that's the
illness they got, would you?
They have ALS, and they're denying that they have ALS?
Yeah.
So, what's the problem?
Would you recommend some spiritual tool which could be maybe helpful?
Why do you want to convince them that they have it?
Not really to convince them, but I just stated that how they, I don't know, I don't know,
perceive it but is there any spiritual tool that they it could help them for
the illness itself except the diagnosis yeah yeah well not specifically about
knowing the details of the situation there may be reasons for it I wouldn't
try to change his mind why do you want change his mind I just thought that it
would be good to accept something what it is because you think that he should
accept it why should he accept it that's a good
question like a good idea to you that's because you don't have ALS you think
it's great he should accept it and his own psychology will take care of it in
due time and you know the denial can be a protective mechanism that's normal
if he accepts it are they going to cure it no so he's not holding off a cure yeah
and probably maybe part of the denial is an aspect of the ALS itself you see so it
could be a self-protective mechanism and I would frankly not mess with it
myself good question procedural question what is calibration level of Ten
Commandments what calibrated level of energy of Ten
Commandments
what is the calibration of the Ten Commandments think a thousand I wouldn't
mess with them I see people mess with them on television I'm put I'll tell you
it calibrates at ten blasphemy calibrates at ten and I watch people
encouraging doing black blasphemy and encouraging others to do it which
calibrates at ten and that is the one for which there is no forgiveness to
and that is the one for which there is no forgiveness to encourage others to do
that that you encourage to do it you self encourage others to do
that which for which there is no forgiveness to me is the height of
wickedness yeah the height of wickedness it's such a great privilege to be here I
just want to thank you for your exquisite communication both you're
teaching in what you communicate in silence thank you like you I'd just like
honor to be here with you and everyone here. My question is, how do you differentiate the
difference between spiritual joy and the payoff of the ego or the juice that it gets?
Between joy and what?
Payoff of the ego and the juice it gets.
The ego getting, oh, he's talking about legitimate joy. Well, they have a different quality.
You don't really confuse joy with ego satisfaction. You win the lottery, you know, you feel ego
satisfaction. Joy is something that happens without any particular occasion to bring it
on, necessarily.
Thank you.
Joy stems from within. Something out there precipitates it, but the joy comes from within.
You hear a piece of beautiful music and you begin to cry with joy.
That's...
The music precipitates it, but the joy is coming from within.
First off, Susan, I'd like to thank you for your love for your husband.
It is inspiring and very uplifting.
My question has been asked in the previous years several times, and I want to just give a little
preamble.
When I was in college and I had to take a math, complicated math course, and I was a beginner at
math, the professor really didn't have a clue.
He really didn't have a concept of not knowing what he knew.
Not knowing what?
What he knew.
What he knew. What the professor knew.
He assumed that his students knew what he was talking about. For example, in calculus.
Oh, yeah. The professor assumed that the student was getting what he was saying.
Correct.
Yeah.
So he didn't have a step-down transformer to make it simple and palatable.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
My question to you is, and so I'm hoping you can make it simple and palatable.
We'll see.
Calculus. Oh, okay.
No, no, no. I'm not going there.
My question is...
The differential calculus. I'll try that one.
Go ahead.
It seems to me that self-esteem is a very important stepping stone to the growth of consciousness.
If self-esteem is damaged and the person doesn't yet have an experience of self-esteem,
they don't have an experience of self-esteem.
They don't have an experience of self-esteem.
The essential knowledge of God, of what you are, is that.
How does one really go about repairing that wound?
Oh, you set up for yourself your own spiritual curriculum, and then you live up to it.
And out of that, you get a sense of self-esteem because you know that you are...
Aligned with your goals, yes?
What do you mean by curriculum?
Well, like you go to a Bible study group, or you would go to a religious...
I understand. So basically...
A regime that you live by.
So in other words, you kind of can one, say, a religious or gathering a week.
So what you're saying then is that...
You're saying that a person really who is atheist...
Who is what?
Who is atheist.
Yeah, thank you.
Atheist.
Yeah.
Has no hope while they're that?
Oh, no.
The atheist can feel quite secure because, first of all, he doesn't have God to contend with.
So...
Life is a snap.
So ignorance is a bliss sometimes, right?
But then he begins to wonder later on in life as he gets more mature.
Mm-hmm.
You know, if this is the...
Absolute truth.
Mm-hmm.
And he gets more sophisticated.
He moves from atheist to agnostic.
That's a great improvement.
Mm-hmm.
Atheist is...
I'm so smart I can prove that God doesn't exist, which means you're an idiot to begin with.
Nobody's ever disproven the existence of God.
So you become more sophisticated.
You become an agnostic.
Then as an agnostic, you can check out the validity of various pathways.
And I suggest for the agnostic...
Agnostic or the unbeliever, Buddhism.
The Buddha, you don't have to believe anything.
You don't have to believe in God.
You don't have to believe in divinity.
Nothing.
You go to, you know, Zen Institute and you learn meditation.
You just meditate, period.
And you just meditate the way they tell you to meditate.
And whatever comes up, comes up.
So then...
So that's very, very useful.
And very genuine because it's your own...
The emergence of...
Your own potentiality.
So all they do is teach you a meditative technique.
So I always tell atheists, first become an agnostic and then go for a Zen meditation.
So then to deal with one ego, with one's ego, a healthy self-esteem has to be in place.
I think so.
Thank you very much.
Can we have a picture?
Sure.
To make self-esteem easier to get, set your standards, you know, low so they're easy to reach.
Wow, look at the length on that baby.
That's huge.
Oh my God, look out.
Yeah.
What is that thing?
Bless our children.
Yes.
Where are these children?
One of them is home.
The other one is attending the seminar with me.
Oh, God bless your children, yes.
Mm-hmm.
I bet you didn't work.
Wait.
Oh.
Don't shake it.
Take a deep breath and exhale.
And then click.
Thank you.
It's like looking in the mirror and there's nobody there.
That's a little scary the first time it happens.
It's a huge lens on that thing.
You look in the mirror and you don't see anything looking back at you.
That's time to call the doctor.
Having a side effect.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Yeah.
My question is that there's a concern that the calibration of the world has fallen from 207 to 204.
Correct.
And I really feel personally responsible.
I'm sorry.
Oh, honey.
Shame on you for...
And I need help.
I wondered who did it.
Confession is good for the soul.
Thank you.
Yes, we are.
So the question is possibly is there a benefit for spiritual students such as us on the path that we,
as beacons of light that we've gotten from you,
go out into the world and live in certain communities and help counterbalance negativities in that communities?
I sort of doubt there's a physicality to it.
There is...
All right.
We have permission to ask this.
There is a regional effect, resist.
Oh, there is a regional effect.
Well, I think TM proved that many years ago.
Mm-hmm.
That if over 5% of the population are meditating,
the crime rate drops by 90% or something.
I know when I first moved to Sedona,
the number of spiritual people
was more than 5% of the population.
Remember the first class we had on A Course in Miracles?
There was over 100 there.
Well, at that time, there was only 3,000 in the town.
So they all began meditating.
So we were already over 5% of the town's population.
And according to TM's research,
if over 5% of the population meditates,
the crime rate drops and everything.
And in those years, crime was unknown.
Nobody ever locked their cars.
Nothing was ever stolen.
There was no such thing as a burglary.
So it could be, yes, that it does have a regional effect.
That's a surprise to me.
It does indeed have a regional effect.
Well, let's see.
Didn't you just say the 12 disciples,
the scatter to the winds?
Yes.
All right.
So.
This is an expression of Christ's instructions to the apostles.
Huh.
I didn't know that.
So if we were to start little spiritual communities
throughout the country or even the world.
It would have an effect, yes.
That would have an effect.
Yes.
So that would possibly keep the calibration from falling?
Or is that causality?
That would be causality.
But I think it isn't that it would raise it over the whole world,
it would raise it of that community, I would think, see?
Oh, yes.
In other words, a certain number of people calibrating high
is already affecting the collective.
So when we say, what's the consciousness level of mankind,
we're calibrating the collective.
Okay.
Uh-huh.
So, but there apparently is a regional effect.
Okay.
Because there's certain areas of the world.
When we did, calibrated the levels of consciousness
of various areas of the world in various countries,
there were some countries in which the calibrated level
of consciousness was below that of criminality.
Yeah.
Right in this hemisphere.
This is one very obvious one, calibrates at 70.
Yes, very low.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
That's an interesting question.
I never asked it before.
I'm going to have a picture.
Yeah.
So you would have like a contagion effect, too.
The more spiritual people are involved in spiritual.
Well, in other words, a certain contagion of spiritual interests.
Yeah.
You know?
A certain.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
So they have a contagious effect on people in the community when.
Yeah.
If a number of spiritual people move into town, it has like a contagious effect.
Like if somebody goes to church, they say, you want to go to church with me?
You know, it's like, next thing you know, they're going to church, you know.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Hi, Susan.
Thank you once again for your teachings.
And all that you give to us.
Driving down to Sedona from Toronto recently, I encountered some automobile trouble.
Some automobile's trouble?
Yeah.
In other words, she .
Oh, she had trouble.
Okay.
I, at one point, I heard a voice, just a soft voice through the thinking that said, check
the oil.
Check the oil.
Yeah.
And I pulled over into a gas station.
And immediately someone came to my aid who knew exactly what it was.
And helped me.
Gave me wonderful advice.
And then consequently, arriving in Sedona, another one filled the place and took over
with regards to the car.
What ...
What it sometimes seems to be is that there are more angels amongst us
than we might always recognize.
We don't call them that.
No.
But it dawns on us later.
Yeah.
The statistical likelihood of that happening was about zero.
There seems to be some type of, I don't know what it is,
a transference or something that occurs in the eyes, within the eyes.
Like, are the eyes the window of the soul?
There seems to be just a profound nonverbal communication that occurs.
Yeah, almost telepathic, right?
It's very, yes, very beautiful.
Yes, almost telepathic, yes.
That's true.
Telepathic, we have permission.
We have permission.
Telepathic calibrates over 250, 255.
Telepathic communication and all of those calibrated about 250.
Thank you, Dr. Hopkins.
You bet.
There are periods in your spiritual work where all these phenomena come and go.
There's a period where you're very telepathic.
In fact, it's almost a nuisance.
You know what people think in the instant they walk up towards you.
You already got what it's all about.
And you just pick up the thoughts.
And you went through that for a couple of years one time.
It was almost a nuisance, like, you know, what everybody was thinking all the time.
Yes.
Hi, Dr. Hopkins.
Mm-hmm.
I went through a time of great fear, despair, agony, and confusion.
And I felt very shaken up by it.
And I still feel paralyzed and still trying to recover.
Did something precipitate it?
What do you ascribe it to?
Karma.
I've read it.
I probably have lots of negative karma.
Oh.
That is what it is.
And, you know, I'm just dealing with it.
You use all the spiritual tools you have at your command and pray for God's help.
And you come out on the other side of it.
Okay.
That sounds simple enough.
Yep.
As my spiritual teacher, could you just tell me it's okay?
As a spiritual teacher telling you what?
That it's okay.
Yes, it is okay.
Oh, yes.
Life's okay.
It's good progress.
Mm-hmm.
If nothing's happening, you're probably not doing anything.
Nothing's happening.
Feeling content and happy all the time because it's a bad sign because you're not getting anywhere.
Thank you.
It's true.
Well, the reason people go through things like that is they're pulling up a stack.
It's a stack about something.
When you get to the bottom, work through all that stack, then that stack is quiet.
It may be quiet for a long time.
And then you maybe start on another.
It's a big stack.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Yes.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
I never met you before.
It's my first time.
And so I'm a little nervous to ask, but...
You're not nervous enough.
Be more nervous.
So it came up with calibration.
I just started some Sufi dancing and singing, and I'm really connecting with God that way.
And I saw Allah, infinity, calibrated.
And then you spoke...
You spoke about the Quran, which was hard to hear what it said.
And so I think my question is, how do I trust myself on a spiritual path to find the things which fit my karma on my right way to go when I still have a lot of ego?
Oh, well, that's normal.
No, you just pray for God's will for you and follow the simple things.
Maybe meditate half an hour in the morning.
Maybe meditate half an hour at night or 15 minutes in the morning at night.
Read some spiritual scripture periodically and meditate on that.
And do you have a feeling in your heart or something which can guide you?
No, you don't have to worry about all that.
You just do your intention.
You ask God for his direction for your life.
You pick a psalm that you think is very powerful for you.
I start the Christian miracles.
See?
And then...
It begins to move from there.
Yeah.
Then you're sort of lit.
Once you've asked God help, God's help to reach God, then, you know, you get special help at home.
Thank you.
God sends special help.
For your angels, angelic beings.
That would be wonderful.
Yeah.
Well, yeah.
It's an honor and a privilege.
Yeah.
My question is on your first physical incarnation.
Everyone's in general.
At birth, on your first physical incarnation, do you come in to the world at over 600?
Whose physical incarnation?
At any one.
Any human.
No.
No, I don't think so.
You don't come into the world over 600.
Like, I was wondering, like...
At 600, you wouldn't need to incarnate in this world.
You've already transcended to a heavenly realm.
Heavenly realms are 600 and up.
Well, then, how do you have negative personal karma?
On your first physical incarnation at birth?
That's...
I can't answer that.
Did you ever hear of the serpent of the Garden of Eden?
Yeah.
The fallen man?
That's about as good a legend as you can find to explain it.
I was just wondering if everyone went through that, the seduction of Adam and Eve, you know...
No, that's the origin of mankind.
Mankind.
Mm-hmm.
disobedience for which an angry God threw mankind into this realm I see it
the innocence of the child which is within everyone fell to the seduction of
the serpent of evil so it's like evil wanted to take over the realm of
goodness and sent a messenger the the weakness of the pert the weakness of Eve
was not her personal weakness but the seduction of the innocence of the child
within her for which she was not equipped like the guru falls I say the
fault is the teacher of that teacher who did not forewarn of what may arise so my
understanding of my acceptance of Genesis is limited I see it as the
innocence of the child within her.
of ignorance so even like Jesus Christ only had the one incarnation oh I don't
know and I couldn't tell you okay I'll ask him I know what you know traditional
religion says about it I don't actually know the answer what do you want me to do
you want me to shake hands with people
okay I'll do it.
I'll move along faster yes speak up well that works out that works out perfect I
don't have a question ah haha I just super duper there's just nowhere I'd rather be
so I just want to be here good to see you yeah yeah so then we shake the
hands of this many people already yes I'm a teacher high school teacher right
I am a high school teacher yes yes slowly and near the man Mike okay I'm a
I'm a high school teacher, yes, okay.
And I'm wondering what now the purpose of K-12 education is.
What now the purpose of what?
If the universities are calibrating below 200, what now is the purpose?
What's my purpose as a teacher?
Because that's not the end.
Those aren't the only people that are around.
I mean, we can live very well without Yale, Harvard, and Columbia
and all those that calibrate 190 or something.
We're sitting right here at 440.
My job is not now what I signed up for,
and I can see the seeds of what you talk about in my world.
So you look around to find that which is more integrous
and more in line with your own worldview and your own values.
It's the same as working for a company.
You can start with a company and then find that that company's values
and their mode of sovereignty are not within your realm.
So it doesn't mean you need to change your profession.
What you need to do is find the circumstance that is more in accordance
with your own alignment.
Are you religious at all?
Very.
Yes.
What kind of religion, if I may ask?
Well, I don't know what I would call it.
I've read all of your books, and I would consider you my teacher.
Oh, I see.
Yeah.
So what you're talking about is spirituality, yes.
Yes.
Yeah, so what you want is an institution that is sincerely dedicated,
to developing the student's mind,
and the integrity of the student's mind, yeah.
Yeah.
And that can happen in public school?
Well, it depends on the public school, yeah.
Okay.
I mean, there could be some school somewhere
that this is still maintained as the primary goal,
or you may have to go to the private school system
or the parochial, I don't know.
Yeah, okay.
Who's, you know, dedicated to the integrity
of the student and not to some political program?
That's the difficulty in today's world.
Well, No Child Left Behind has affected all public schools
because of, it's politicized it.
Is it?
Yeah.
It's real hard.
I don't know what No Child Left Behind means.
It means everybody gets promoted no matter what?
No, it's a little bit different from that.
It's everyone, everyone must have the same education.
Oh.
It, there, you don't really,
need a teacher because the curriculum is being standardized. I see. Everybody has
the matches standardized, yes. I don't know what to say about it. I'd have to
tell you a bit more about it. It's a challenge. I don't know. I went to State
Teachers College for two years and they were supposed to understand the
curriculum and you were supposed to bring forth their intellectual
capacities to the fullest. So what you accomplish with one student might be
sufficient, considering what their IQ is, but this student over here, they expect
that you're going to accomplish a good deal more with and give them extra work,
etc. Right, right. That's what we're doing. That's what we're told to do. That's very good. And to support those who cannot do the work. I think education is a great thing to get involved in. Thank you. Thank you very much.
Two best years of my college life. State Teachers College. Eighty bucks
a year tuition and free books. Boy, I'll tell you. I went to the same Teachers College my father went to for two years. Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Yes. I really appreciate you having a lecture on my birthday. It's been the greatest gift that I could ever have. I tried to accommodate you, you know. All I could ever ask for. I don't have a question this time. Oh, okay. I want to say thank you, but it seems.
The gratitude is. Very nice. How old are you today? I'm 47 today. Oh, very good. Very good. Which means I'm 11. I get to be 11 again because I add the numbers together. Oh, oh. So I'm 11 all over again. So I'm just very grateful to be here. Yes. To both of you very much. And I love you both very much. Thank you so much.
The age of ancient Greece. Few people lived to be 47 in ancient Rome. Let me go. What was the average age of death in ancient Rome? I think 28 or 30.
Not 28.
Not too high. Hi. Yes. My lesson for the day in Course in Miracles is there is a peace that Christ bestows on us. There is a peace that what? Christ bestows on us. Oh, yes. Yes. I thought maybe you could just say something about that. No, I think it's self-descriptive. Those who accept that Christ is one Savior, that Christ is a great avatar.
That Christ will be your advocate before the Father. Those who believe in my name, I will speak for them before the Father. That is a terrific comfort to have that, to know that. Is it not? Yes. Yes. And in itself, it's just a blessing, you know. Yes. I'd like to go down on bended knee. What did he say? You'll find out. Oh, I know what you say. God bless you.
Thank you. I love you. I love you and I love your love. Yes. I'm honored to be with you, be here with you. My question is, what to you is true intimacy in relationships? What is true intimacy? I think sharing, you know, the most intimate thing is the sharing of one's inner spiritual, inner thoughts and
sensitivities and ways of seeing things. The physicality you can experience with anybody, see? And if you know the right neighborhood for $20, that doesn't take long. It takes, it takes, I watch TV the same as you. But I think to really share your inner most, most sensitive sensitivities and concerns and
the things you're working through results in a profound intimacy in a spiritual manner, see? So I say relationships that are mature are parallel, side by side and parallel, because you're both aligned with the same destiny.
Relationships that are, that hold you back are in horizontal, solar plexus to solar plexus. What can I get out of it? What can she get out of it? Who's going to win? Who's going to win this argument? You know, to share your
really inner sensitivities, the things you don't really want to tell anybody about,
is the development of a spiritual trust, because you know what the people at work would think of
you if you reveal that such a thing. You know, I felt scared to death to go out and call down
this customer. But you could tell your wife that, you know, I'm scared to crapless about
talking to the president of this big corporation, you know? And she says, honey, I believe in you,
and you're doing it for me and the kids,
and somehow you feel better and you say,
my God, I'll do it, you know?
So that working back and forth with each other,
I think that's the most intimate thing,
is to share your passing inner doubts and thoughts
and what you're working through right now,
you know what I mean?
Because that implies a great deal of trust.
Because any one of those things that you confide
could then be used in a less integrous relationship
to attack you with, you know?
Well, you don't even have confidence in yourself,
you know, a clipper, you know?
So you can't trust people that are not trustable.
So you have to first define that they're trustable,
and then they're not going to use it
as some kind of an attack against you.
So some people are sort of congenitally malevolent,
and you've got to watch out for them.
Sort of vicious by nature.
They seem to get pleasure out of wickedness.
Appreciate it. Thank you.
Yeah, but it's a very good question.
Yeah. Oh, my God.
Thank you very much.
What do I need to hear regarding
the evolution of this consciousness?
What'd she say?
Oh, sorry. What do you need to what?
What do I need to hear?
What does she need to hear to elevate her consciousness?
What does she need to hear?
I don't know.
Okay, I have a better question.
When you were transcending,
when you were transcending the levels of consciousness,
you said that you would feel excruciating pain
until something was resolved.
You guys speak closer to the mic.
You said that as you were transcending
the levels of consciousness,
you would feel excruciating pain.
What needed to be resolved,
or what was resolved as you were transcending those levels
in order to resolve that pain in your body?
I don't get what she's saying.
She's talking about physical pain or what?
Yes.
Remember when you were transcending different levels?
In consciousness.
Yes.
You would have physical ailments.
Oh, yeah. All kinds of them.
Yeah.
But it was physical.
Yep.
And so what?
Well, it was psychic,
but also it could cause enough stress
to cause physical illnesses.
Right.
So what were the things that you resolved
in order to alleviate that pain
as you were transcending the levels?
It depends on the specifics.
You're being too general.
It's hard to put, you know,
because at different levels,
there's different things that come up.
And each one of us have different things
that will come up at different levels.
So that's a generalization.
Depends on what you're working on, you know.
Let's say you're working on jealousy.
That's going to be a different archetype
in the collective unconscious.
That's going to hit a different chakra
in the chakra system.
So depending on what kind of conflict
you're talking about.
Yeah?
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
Like possessiveness could be the solar plexus, you see.
And heart, pain in the heart,
it has to do with love, et cetera.
So it could be related.
It's related to the chakra system.
Yeah.
What's in that B?
B what?
That vitamin, you know, little B's
produce something that balances your acupuncture system.
I've mentioned it two or three times.
Little B's?
B's.
B3?
No.
B, a B's.
No, no.
I know what you're talking about.
No, no, no.
It's the...
It'll come to me.
Propolis.
B propolis balances the acupuncture
system and will help get you out of a negativity
quicker than anything.
So you go, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha,
and you chew on some B propolis.
Sounds like magic, but it actually works.
Hi.
I just came up here for the blessing in meeting...
Hello?
In meeting you.
What did she say?
She says it's a blessing in meeting us.
Oh.
Want me to sign that?
Yes, please.
Yes, B propolis.
B propolis.
B propolis tends to balance the acupuncture system
and put it back in balance after it's been blown out.
Do you have a question?
No.
If you're a real spiritual devotee,
it really keeps you busy, doesn't it?
You're busy sitting under a Bodhi tree, cross-legged,
chewing on propolis, going, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha,
going like this and going, ah, at the same time.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's enough to keep you busy.
Yes.
Dr. Honkins.
Can I see you?
Mm-hmm.
I was thinking about when you wrote about the harmonic convergence in,
I remember October 86, and I was thinking,
I went to the museum once and it said when Christ was born,
he was, you know, of course that's, or the Buddha was born,
it would raise the consciousness of the earth.
So is it possible during the harmonic convergence
that an avatar-type person could have been born
and changed the consciousness,
and raised it that one month?
I don't think so, because it stayed up there for years,
and only went, in fact, it continued up.
It went up from 190 to 204 in late 87.
It subsequently went up to 207,
and then it went back down to 205,
and now to 204.
So did you ever ask the arm,
Yes.
what did it?
The Pope is correct.
What did he say?
You don't keep track of what the Pope's telling people?
Not all the time.
Wrong religion, I guess.
No, the Pope is quite integrous.
Quite integrous.
He said that relativism plus Islam,
the combination of the two,
one is Luciferic and the other is Satanic.
Right, but what,
what kicked it up in October of 86?
Oh, I don't know.
That's what I was wondering.
Well, it's the natural evolution of consciousness.
It reaches, you know, it's like saying
what made the sea rise to a certain level.
Okay.
The total activity of the total sea over, you know, decades.
So I know that Jesus wasn't born or anything like that.
Well, we did the evolution of consciousness
during the, showing its evolution
over great decades, archaeological ages, you see.
And then as we get to the more, you know,
the more recent archaeological age,
we track its evolution through the animal kingdom.
So, yes, in the book, I forget which book,
it tracks it according to archaeological age.
During which archaeological age,
what was the consciousness level of life on the planet?
And you see that it,
so a quality of consciousness is that it tends to evolve.
Okay, thank you.
I get a picture?
It tends to evolve.
I'm going to put my arm right here.
Yes.
Bingo.
Yep.
I don't know, I can never tell when they work.
Okay.
Okay, thank you.
I'm sorry, we're not going to get to it.
Okay, we'll just run as fast as we can
and then I'm going to shake everybody's hand and we'll.
Yeah, but you have to get it.
Yes, indeed.
Yes, okay.
We'll just run like rabbits.
Hi, good to see you again.
Yes.
I do hands-on energy healing
and I wanted to ask you,
when I'm working with a client,
what are the beliefs or the prayers
that I should be focusing on
and what should they be focusing on
in order to heal themselves?
Well, you think of the highest thoughts
that you can think of.
Your gratitude for God's love,
your acceptance of God's love,
that the reality of the self
involves divine balance,
divine healing,
and you have the patient accept
divine balance, divine harmony,
that my, let's say, autonomic nervous system,
my sympathetic nervous system,
my acupuncture system, whatever it is,
manifests divine harmony and balance.
The self with a capital S,
obviously intrinsically,
has the quality of healingness
and divine balance.
Harmony and balance,
subject to karmic limitations.
So you ask for forgiveness
for all within yourself,
now or forgotten,
that could be impeding it.
You ask the Holy Spirit for a miracle
to become aware of anything within yourself
that could be impeding your healing,
you know, unconscious guilt or whatever.
It's spiritual work.
Self-healing is spiritual work.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
It involves many modalities.
I believe in exploring them all.
Chiropractic, acupuncture,
all the therapies can heal people.
What do you want?
Huh?
It's time to end.
Okay.
What do we do now?
Do we pull the plug and disappear?
Well, then weren't we going to shake everybody's hand
that we could?
After what?
I don't get any of the message.
We're supposed to be out of here by 5?
Well, we have to be cleared out by 5.30.
I mean, like, everyone's gone by 5.30.
All right.
So that gives us...
In other words, right now,
we should run, rabbit, run,
and shake everybody's hand?
Oh, good.
Run, rabbit, run.
We're going to try and shake everybody's hand.
I don't know how we can do that.
Well, uh...
Huh?
Yes.
Now, which way do they go?
Okay.
We say hello to everybody.
God bless.
Yeah.
God bless you all.
Yes.
Love you.
Oh, yes.
Thank you.
Yep.
Hi, New Zealanders.
I've never been to New Zealand.
What a wonderful place to be from.
Thank you very much.
But we do follow the Kiwi.
The Delphic Oracle.
Thank you, love.
Do we still have this thing on us?
Yes, yes.
The Delphic Oracle said,
Know thyself.
Mr. Delphic Oracle.
Delphi, for short.
Just call him D-O.
Is the microphone still on?
Yes.
Yeah.
The Delphic Oracle said,
The Delphic Oracle.
Now, where is it written?
I forget where it's written.
Yeah.
Yes, thank you.
Oh, yes.
Now I get it's within the cave.
The Delphic Oracle.
Many great public buildings it's written.
Around the top.
Know thyself.
Yes.
Say hello to everybody and then they have to move on.
I'll have to have more time to think about your question.
So I can answer it right.
God bless you.
Where's my peacock feather?
Oh, is it Macananda?
Macananda.
You'll have to get something similar.
A frond or something.
How about flypaper?
He walks away.
It's stuck on you.
I see you got bliss.
When he lectured, Macananda would have an orange knit hat on.
And then about every five minutes, he would take the hat off, throw it out in the crowd.
Everybody would grab for it because it had his energy in it.
So we need a whole bin full of orange hats.
God bless you.
Yes.
Sweethearts.
All my sweethearts here.
Yes.
The young men, too.
Hey.
This is great to get to see everybody.
It's easier than walking around.
I get to see them better than I do when I walk around.
Yes.
Hi.
Are you behaving yourself?
I am.
Oh, thank God.
She's behaving herself.
God bless you, sweetheart.
You too.
All right.
Good evening.
Hi.
Look at here.
Ruffle.
God bless you, sweetheart.
Oh, good.
All right.
Through time, the vibration radiates forth.
It's amazing to know that.
Beyond this lifetime.
25 lifetimes ago is when I picked up the frequency and the vibration.
It's the most amazing thing.
Good evening.
Wow.
What's that?
hello I feel like a tall person feels now I mean I see how Gabley this way he spews the world from
this altitude hi hi hi God bless you God bless you God bless you yes how many people I'm answerable
for that if you teach error you're responsible for each and every one of them I don't know what
scares me a little bit on divine guidance to speak nothing but the truth that's cute what is that
huh hi God bless you God bless you God bless you God bless you God bless you
God bless you now you promise to be good
that's okay God bless you okay this is good yes oh this is good you can stand against this thing
huh so you don't fall over hi hi my familiar faces yes God bless you God bless you God bless
you now and forever how is it healing okay he's healing okay
good God bless you my pleasure God bless you