We are
Oh,
>> you're in for it.
>> Uh, hi D.
>> Hi, D.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Um, I have a young friend that's an
associate at work who is Cambodian who
was raised in the Buddhist traditions.
Her mother died recently and she
immediately started getting
what she thinks are things from the
other side. She thinks her mother
>> was trying to contact her and now she's
hearing voices, her father and her
mother carrying on conversations
and it's driving her nuts. She she
doesn't relate to it, but it goes on in
her head.
>> Tell her she has the right to refuse it.
>> Yes.
>> And she has the right to demand entities
uh cease and desist.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Of course, she's a Buddhist, so you
know, but she could try asking in the
name of our Lord Jesus Christ.
I don't know that.
>> Yeah. Well, could you use the Buddha?
Uh, she um
>> Yeah, I told her that I didn't think
that they were her family that it was
most likely from the lower realm.
>> Well, it's entities taking advantage of
the situation. See, her emotional
vulnerability.
>> Yes. So, they're trying to get her
attention and get involved with her. Uh,
she should refuse them and say, "Get the
hints. Uh, I hereby uh order you to
leave my presence."
>> Yeah.
>> You don't have to say in the name of
Jesus Christ. You can just say, "I
hereby order you to leave me uh alone
and to leave my presence."
>> Oh, okay.
>> You can demand them to leave.
>> Right. Right.
Okay, thank you very much.
>> Astral do not calibrate the size of the
human so you can demand that they leave.
>> Human outranks them.
>> Ah,
>> I hereby order you to leave in the name
of the Lord.
>> They cannot refuse.
>> That's that's it. That's it.
>> She can order them to leave. She can
order them out because she actually has
more power.
>> Let's see.
>> Since she's a Buddhist, can she order
>> uh
my answer was correct. She has the
karmic right to order them to leave her
be. Uh she does not have to cite the
Buddha for authority. Resist. No, she
doesn't have to cite the Buddha as
authority.
>> Okay.
>> That it's a spiritual reality.
of spiritual reality. Just like the big
dog has the right to order the little
dog to stop nipping at his hind, you
know.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Right.
>> You don't need the Buddha to give him an
okay.
>> Picking order.
>> Yes. I understand.
>> She ranks in the picking order.
>> You know, it's quite evolved to become a
human as though as we see humanness gets
>> as far as what else goes on in the lower
astral realms. You know we are very
evolved.
>> Yeah.
>> Even to have a sense of right and wrong
you know is already
>> that's a gift to begin with.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> To be able to conceptualize and to have
a prefrontal cortex.
>> Yeah.
>> That's an incredible gift.
>> Mhm.
>> And and to understand that's even
more incredible.
>> Yeah. So I just tell her, you know, she
she has the right to demand them to
leave her in peace.
>> I will convey that to her.
>> Mhm.
>> I wanted to thank you also for
responding to my email.
>> Uhhuh.
Okay.
Thank you.
Good luck with that.
>> It'll be fine. Yes, indeed it will.
>> I want a picture with you and I have
just two quick questions
of um
what does Sedona
uh calibrate as? Thousand.
>> No,
the town of Sedona. Uhhuh. of this
beautiful surrounding.
>> I don't know if we've done Sedona. Have
we ever done Sedona? I don't remember.
>> And also, you skipped uh
>> Oh, sorry.
>> You skipped uh
dead dead white man. You didn't What's
dead white man?
>> 130 or something like that.
>> No, but what does that mean?
>> Oh, you're not a literati. I see.
dead white man.
The uh to to discredit the intellectual
integrity in history of mankind
by relativism, you would then have to
discredit that which of course, you
know, contradicts it completely. So you
can belittle it by calling it, you know,
the mad mouthings of dead white men or
something something insulting, you know.
Let's see if we got permission to do
Sedona. We got permission to do Sedona.
We have permission to do Sedona. Is this
>> Yes. Um my question is about the
difficulty and the courage required to
uh to be a human. Um after the last set
saying you went to the audience and you
spoke with a lady who uh looks like was
working through a big chunk of karma was
in a wheelchair and you said to her I
think uh all will be revealed at the
end.
>> Yes.
>> Is that how this trip goes? We get a
little explanation at the end.
>> I'll let you know.
We all take the answer to that one with
us, don't we?
>> Well, I always wondered um well, you
know, in the in the sense that your life
runs before you. Your whole life flashes
before you. You're confronted with with
everything, every thought, every
decision.
Your life is reflected back to you.
>> Is that kind of experience at the end
transformative? Maybe in a sense like a
near death is there is
>> near death is a dumb difference.
>> Why is there such a disparity? It
doesn't seem to be trans.
>> Well, one's a rerun in which you can
make choices.
The other you don't have any say about
it. You're leaving.
>> So, you're out of here.
>> Do we know when we come down here? Are
we given kind of like a preview what
we're signing up for or are we just
thrown in here? It seems like you'd need
to volunteer. That would seem in in all
justice and fairness. I don't know the
answer.
>> Okay.
>> Well, all right. I can answer it certain
level that you have to earn the karmic
opportunity to make the choice and then
you have to agree. All right. So,
everybody is here by their own
agreement. Resist. Everybody's here by
their own agreement. So, you can give up
all the resentments because the only
reason you're here is because you said
yes to it.
But we don't know that it could be a big
yes or the details.
>> Yes. Is a yes.
>> It means not to drag your feet
kicking and screaming into the world.
>> Choose to be here.
>> I don't really have a question today. I
just wanted to come up here to be while
you sign these things.
>> Okay. I have enough to work on already.
>> Oh, wow.
Here's a smart lady.
If you aren't dead, you've got a lot to
work on yet.
>> Oh, have I?
>> Yeah. It keeps us busy because each
layer opens up to the next layer. Mhm.
You finish with one layer and suddenly
Oops.
about 22 lifetimes. You forgot. Oh,
>> probably more than that.
Yo, thank you so much. My god, what is
this?
>> She's working.
>> Oh my god.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, Dr.
>> These two are for my new lady love,
Allah. Do you have a special signature
for that?
>> There we go.
>> Before my question, uh, may I present
you and Susan a gift?
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> Uh, in November in Long Beach, I asked
you about, uh, my running a a fast
marathon at a late age. Yeah.
>> And you, uh, said that the energy was
good. So I really thank you very much
for that. But I was a race director in
January 2000 and I created a new race
from scratch called the Melenathon
and all the runners in my race got a
free jacket and I wanted to present you
and Susan with one of the jackets.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> What does it say?
>> It says
>> millennia
>> Menathon.
>> You can open
>> Oh, I see. I see. Oh, yeah. Boy, isn't
that a fantastic one? They'll see you
coming down the road there then.
Nobody's got to run over you.
>> You see the the the uh slogan
>> slogan
>> is one race, one world.
>> Oh, that's beautiful.
>> What does it say?
>> One race, one world.
>> Okay. Human race. Yeah.
>> So, my my question pertains to Abraham
Maslo. I noticed that you have not
celebrated Abraham Maslo in any of your
books or your writings and also
>> oh you're talking about peak experience
psychologist Maslo
>> yeah right
>> oh my M Maslo described he's a
psychologist
>> right
>> he's he described the so-called peak
experience transitory yeah right
>> uh so my question is whether you can
calibrate Abraham Maslo and also I am
writing a book on Abraham Maslo and
whether you can give me some guidance on
that book
>> no Because I'm not a student of Maslo.
Maslo is over 460,
480, 475. Yeah, he's got to be in the
high 400s.
>> Yeah. He described what's called peak
experience, you know. And in a way, a
person gets a glimpse of their
potentiality, you know.
>> Right. Thank you very much.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> I never did give reference to him
because I hadn't read really read as low
at any depth. I know who he is and what
he taught. You know,
he was speaking of it as a psychological
experience, you know,
although a transcendental one.
>> Yes.
>> Um, I want to get a some clarification
on a couple of things that you said. Um,
I know you've calibrated most of the
countries of the West in the three and
400s. Uh and then earlier you gave the
calibration of western civilization had
fallen to uh 199 is were you holding in
mind the the culture?
>> When are you talking about
>> in this lecture today?
>> Today I didn't say it was 199.
>> You didn't. Okay.
>> You had a hallucination.
>> Is that on We don't Was it on the
>> in the consciousness of Western
civilization? Oh
>> yeah. I don't know what we said. We said
what western civilization was 205.
It is now 199 resist. Yes. It's now 199.
All right. Let's reaffirm. It's below
200 now. Resist.
No. So, Western civilization was around
205.
Now it's been going down as you would
assume by just watching the world
>> to 199.
>> Okay. I guess I was trying to uh
understand a distinction between
uh western civilization and and the
calibrations that you given for most of
the countries of the west being there's
all different countries then there's
America and uh and then today something
new we thought because what the pope had
said has to do with western civilization
and we never calibrated western
civilization as such so we calibrated
western civilization for the first
Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, we've never calibrated Western
civilization as such.
>> Hi.
>> Yes.
>> This is my first time here, so it's a
pleasure to meet you.
>> I'm hoping you can help me with some
clarity. I have a situation.
Um I know a person that has a history of
of perversion with an arrest involved.
>> You have you know a person who what
>> per a sexual perversion?
>> Yes.
>> Has a sexual perversion. Yes.
>> History.
>> Yes.
>> They are um acting as a counselor
>> and minister
>> and the person um is inappropriate the
way he touches women and young women.
Yes.
>> Although there's not been any out and
out molestation.
>> Yes.
>> And I am wanting to I'm trying to decide
if I should go to the state regulations
and licensing and file a complaint
even though
>> the person have a superior
>> are they superior?
>> This person you're talking about are
they like in an institution where they
have a superior or is this a freelance
individual?
>> Freelance. Oh, okay. So, you have no
authority to go to about it? No.
>> No. I was a client, so I have the
experience.
>> You was a client. You were a client of
the person.
>> Yes.
>> Who then took advantage of you?
>> All right. So, you file a complaint with
the licensing board of that person's
profession.
>> Okay.
>> Yes. And we may have a record. You may
pull up. They have a record.
>> Yeah. It was hard for me because I was
feeling a lot of anger and I was feeling
very distracted. So, I wasn't sure if I
should because it may put him out of
business.
You would have to decide how serious it
was and whether you think it's something
that's done to others as well.
>> It is.
>> If you feel that it's a pattern, this
person's getting away with it right and
left.
>> Yeah.
>> You could file a complaint with the
board.
>> Okay. Yes, they can look into the
matter. He may have a record already.
>> Yeah. Okay. Thank you.
>> Very much.
>> When I was in charge of institution,
every three years, we had to have an FBI
recheck. We had to go to the FBI, get
refing, and anything that was on your
record in the last three years came up.
And uh in order to keep your position
there and the girls girls school was
there uh
So, we had to get FBI clearance every
three years then.
>> Yeah. It'd be nice if they had something
like that.
>> That's probably required by the board of
whatever that profession is.
>> Yeah. He's not really licensed in a way,
>> I found out. So, so yeah. So, he doesn't
have
>> there's nobody you can complain to then
if there's no supervisoring licensing
board.
>> Well, he's licensed as a minister.
>> Well, licensed by whom?
I don't know. That's a good question. I
don't know. So, I guess I should file a
complaint so they can look into it.
>> Well, you don't know enough about it to
know he's a minister of what?
>> It's metaphysics.
>> Oh, a minister of metaphysics. Well,
that's not a minister. That's a
>> that that's a certain style of
presenting your spiritual position to
the world, you know.
>> Uh there's nobody you can complain to
that I know of.
But it's not out and out molestation.
It's not
>> It's not an illegal act. He be just
learing at you and being
>> No, he's it's touching. It's touching.
So,
>> I really don't know what to tell you.
>> Okay,
I'll find a way.
>> Okay.
Yeah, he needs to be stopped because
there's a lot of other women that
they're afraid to come forward.
>> Yes, maybe you can find some of them and
file a group complaint that would have
more power than just an isolated one.
>> Yeah, that's what I'm working on. So,
>> yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Very often nothing will happen, but
sometimes it does.
>> George might know who what ages.
>> I don't know. I can't tell you right
now. It's a legal question.
>> Hey, Susie.
>> I guess you go to the I guess I'd just
go with the local police department. For
God's sake, why make it complicated? You
know, go to
>> This is also my first time.
>> United States cabinet. You can just Why
don't you see the local police?
>> Okay.
>> They may already have a private They may
already have a private record on them.
They may already know about them. Not
everything's on the bladder, you know.
>> Cop on the beat knows lots of things
that are not on the official bladder.
>> Okay. So I wanted to thank you and thank
everybody here for this this wonderful
afternoon. And
>> there was something I was having
difficulty digesting with the use of
>> uh the isms that you brought up the 180
or 160
>> well the word the suffix ism brings
whatever it is down to 190 because it
now makes it a belief system.
>> Right.
>> It's not truth. It's not reality. It's
now a belief system. Mhm.
>> So you can have a belief system and that
which is false and you can have a belief
system make truth into a belief system.
>> That's one of the traps of the spiritual
student is he makes a belief system out
of spiritual truth instead of realizing
it's truth.
>> Mhm.
>> The reality check of that.
>> Yeah. So there was absolutism which is
something that I I'd heard used but also
I believe in a lot of Buddhist
techniques um teachings as well and
Buddhism is an ism as like Hinduism is
an ism and so I was curious does that
actually bring it down when you call it
an ism as well?
>> Well it depends on how you mean it. I'm
using its official title not as a
political position positional
positionality. Mhm.
So I wanted the clarity there because
there I know there's a number of isms
like racism it's a philosophy which I
don't prescribe to you and sex
>> as a political viewpoint when a thing
becomes an ism
>> it tends to drop down
>> okay
>> because now it's a positionality
>> rather than intrinsically
valid in its own right you know and you
can make an ism out of that which is
valid in fact and that brings it down so
peace is one thing. Peacemicism
>> is something different.
>> I don't even know what that is. But what
is that before I go? Just out of
curiosity.
>> Peace is calibrates to like 600.
>> Yeah.
>> Peace making parades uh getting a in the
face of the government etc.
>> Right.
>> Is an ism that drops it way down to 190
because now it's just a political
statement.
>> Right. If you believed in peace, you
wouldn't be
stirring up the mess that you're
stirring up in the world. You would be
peaceful.
>> It's like an anti-war rally.
>> That's right.
>> It's doesn't really Mother Teresa
wouldn't join in on something.
>> That's right.
>> Peace rallies are too dangerous. I don't
go to them. The dogs, the rocks, the
barricades, the police, the water hoses.
>> Well, thank you for your time. Thank
you, Susie, for listening.
>> Supposed to get a picture. That's all
right.
Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> I get to keep the camera.
>> Dr. Hawkins. Susan,
I attended your lecture in Austin in
September 2004.
Since then, I've been reading all of
your books and watching videos.
I got so much out of them. Um, one thing
that sticks out, I reflect on many, many
statements out of the books.
One thing that stands out u from one of
your videos you said one is responsible
to the universe at the level of the
absolute.
One is responsible to the universe at
the level of the absolute.
That's a statement that I remember and I
see that there's a lot of work to do.
Um,
I came here to thank you for all the
gifts and u my intention is to come here
whenever I can.
>> Thank you.
>> I'll continue to work.
>> It's a high compliment.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Where is your home now?
>> Plano, Texas.
>> Okay.
>> One of those.
>> Yes, they have a group there. You're
playing a Texas
>> group. Yeah.
>> I have put up emails to you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Uhhuh.
Okay,
>> thank you.
>> The question is about uh the power of
belief.
The belief is distracted. Destructive.
It's triggered by somebody and you start
leaving it.
>> You don't know what you're saying?
>> Yeah. Just a minute. Okay, go ahead.
>> Um, you experience losses, big losses,
>> right?
>> Stars accumulate negative emotions.
Uh, and our thoughts and emotions are
alive. And so when they accumulate, they
become energy configurations, holograms
stored in the body
>> and uh
they start running your life.
>> She's talking about the negativity.
negativity starts running your life.
>> Yes.
>> Um and then you start believing the
negativity.
>> Right.
>> And when you suffer, you you're looking
for solutions.
>> Yeah. And when you come across of
possibility to think about what you want
and not what you don't want
>> that energy which is running your life
um starts manifesting
um negative things like you see rubbish
on the floor hairs which were not there.
It's like control C of reality which
becomes control V.
Um and uh it's high technologies. It
defies gravity. For example, my hair is
glued with um spray because it stands
up.
>> So uh enamel is taken off my teeth and
uh optical part is taking off my
glasses.
>> Um my question is what is the
what being is it? because it seem to be
like a dominion of subconscious mind. Um
that entity if you call it can program
the thinking of other people and can
program my physiological functions. Um
>> yeah in other words the negativity she
feels is is running her life and
>> Yes.
>> and the way she's seen it is negative
and she can't see it any other way that
it's going to
>> Yeah. You you're saying that that which
is negative is negative. Is that what
you're saying?
>> No. No. I'm saying that this is negative
manifestations
which defies the law of this reality.
>> Negative manifestations defy the law of
reality.
>> No, they don't define the law of
>> Things appear from nowhere. My hair
stands up.
Lots of other things.
>> Paranormal phenomena. Yes, it's
paranormal. So what is the nature of
this being?
>> What the nature of it is that you are
noticing these things and putting them
together and then conceptualizing them
in that way.
>> Yes. I'm doing it myself. Yeah.
>> And I take full responsibility for
>> you. You put a label on these things
that instead of seeing them as natural
phenomena, you maybe suspect they're due
to some other entities entities or
energies. Is that correct?
>> But it's it's produced by myself.
>> It's what?
>> Created by myself.
>> So what is the problem?
>> It's a part of me. Well, my life is
trapped and I cannot be creative. Uh my
life is suppressed both physiologically
and and uh as far as work,
>> you can't work all day because your hair
is messy.
>> No. No. My computer doesn't work. My
printer doesn't print. It's all chaotic.
She's facing chaos.
>> Oh, chaotic. How old are you now?
>> 67,
>> huh?
>> 67.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You've had this before?
>> No, it has been going on basically all
together for a decade. But this negative
manifestations for for two years.
>> Two years.
>> Two years. Huh. So, have you seen a
doctor about it?
>> No, I have no psychological record of
psychological care. I'm perfectly
normal. And well then what are you
complaining about if you're normal?
>> I'm complaining about
>> you're complaining about the abnormal
>> right.
>> Is that right?
>> Yes. I'm saying that my negative
emotions produce are part of how they're
producing those phenomena. Yeah. Is that
what you think?
>> Yeah. Could be. They are.
>> How to deal with it? I
>> stop having negative feelings and
emotions by transforming how you see and
experience the world and your
relationship to it.
>> It's not easy because negativity is
going from morning to evening.
It's going nonstop.
>> This negativity is a projection of how
you see the world. Is that right?
>> No.
>> No. It's the way the world is.
>> No. I am unccapable of uh depression. I
I sing and dance and I open and I have
unconditional love. Then I don't know
what your complaint is. What is your
complaint?
>> Okay.
>> Um
>> Oh, something you read in a book. Now
the mystery gun unravels. Okay.
>> No, this is something unrelated or
>> um non your nonduality
has got nonduality has got confirmation
>> and development by enlightened Russian
physicist.
>> Yes. called Vasili Lenski.
>> He developed a science called
multipolarity.
>> Yeah.
>> And he developed the laws of each
dimension. Discovered the laws.
>> He discovered the laws of this
dimension.
>> Yes.
>> Is his name God or that's God?
>> No. No. Not this dimension.
Different dimensions.
Oh. Would you like maybe to calibrate if
if this is a science of the future
multipolarity? You
>> got permission.
>> Uh we have permission to calibrate this.
It's less than 200 because Yeah. It's
less than 200. That's why she's so
confused. I would give up the book.
>> You want to know my advice? Quit the
book.
>> Quit the book.
>> Yes. He's not helping you. You're
getting more confused. You don't even
know what you're talking about. It
calibrates less than 200. And if he's
the savior of the world,
>> he's less than 200.
>> He's what?
>> He's less than 200 is what she said.
>> Yes, that's right.
>> I'm very surprised.
>> Give up the book and all that nonsense.
It takes a Dutch uncle to get through
all that confusion.
>> Understand?
>> Ah, I can't help it. Yeah. You can't get
through all the confusion with
rationality.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Hi there.
>> Mhm.
>> Let's see. Um I have a question on
behalf of somebody else and that is um
what's the difference between praying to
say like um God or St. Francis or
um different different uh
>> I think the intention uh is what sets
the calibrated level of the prayer you
know.
>> Okay. So I could be praying to Baba
Gumpgump and um if my intention is good
>> your devotion
>> then that's what matters most.
Mhm.
>> But if I is it it's best that I pray to
somebody that I know is integrous being
that
>> conf confirmed level yes of higher
consciousness. Right.
>> Okay. Uh I had one other quick question
and that is would you calibrate uh the
level of a movie that's uh it's um
Shashank Redemption. Do you know that
film?
>> I don't know that one. Um, it's a pretty
popular film and I just wanted to know
what um
>> I know we probably calibrated it
somewhere. Uh, we have permission to do
this one.
>> What's the name of the movie? I forget.
>> Shashank Redemption.
>> Shashank.
>> The The Shashank Redemption.
>> It takes place in the Second World War.
>> Shashank Redemption.
>> Redemption.
>> Shashank
>> Redemption. I have permission.
>> It's over 200. 400 395
4. It's over 400. So it's not
intellectual. It's intentional. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Great. Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> I never watch movies. So that's why I'm
not too
good at it.
>> Good afternoon, Dr. Hawkins. Mrs.
Hawkins. Thank you for allowing me to be
in your presence today.
I have two books here that were um like
must readads when I started spiritual
work back in the late 70s. One is the
impersonal life and the other one is the
life and times um life and teachings of
the masters of the far east.
>> Oh yeah.
>> I I didn't I don't think you've u in
your books you haven't you know printed
the calibration of them if you have
calibrated them. If you haven't
calibrated them, I was wondering if you
could calibrate them today.
>> Which is the one, you know, on the top.
>> This is the impersonal life.
>> Who that?
>> Bremer.
>> Huh?
>> We have permission to do the impersonal
life. It's over 200 300
290 295.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. The other one, this is a volume
one of um the life and teachings of the
masters of the far east. It's a book of
five volumes.
>> Uh let's see. I have permission to do
this one. It's over 200. Thank god. Over
295 300.
>> Oh, okay. Thank you very much.
>> As long as it's over 200 is what the
critical point is.
>> There's two things. There's one is the
teacher himself and then there's that
which the person who's writing the book
says about the teacher.
>> This isn't written by the teacher
themselves.
>> This one,
>> right?
>> Uh it's written Yes.
>> It's written by the teacher themselves.
>> No, not the teachers. It's written by
Oh, I understand. Okay. All right. Thank
you.
>> By an author about the teacher,
>> right?
>> Okay.
>> All right. Thank you very much. What an
experience.
>> 200. Thank god.
>> Yeah. What an I just want to say thank
you. You're throwing your whole future
in karmic inheritance.
>> No, no. I I haven't read these since the
late '7s, but I I'm reading your books
now.
>> Yeah, but they're very well known. Yes.
>> Thank you very much. And it's a real
pleasure to be here in your presence.
Thank you.
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> You see, 295 doesn't mean it is not as
good as 400 because 295 is perfect when
you're at 295
and then that leads you further. But uh
yeah
>> um I've been preparing a number of
questions over the last few weeks and uh
found most of them have been answered
already and so I wanted to including in
the lineup this morning after 5:00
talking within the holy company there
and how special it is to have uh and
feeling such an enormous amount
gratitude for what you brought in your
teachings.
>> I'm honored by your presence.
>> Mhm.
>> Thank you very much.
My question is, could you give a little
clarification on the grace of the
teacher in respect to um
>> grace?
>> Yeah.
>> Grace of a teacher and the openness of
the student
>> of the what?
>> Grace of the teacher and the openness of
the a student.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Yeah. Little clarification on that. A
little explanation.
>> What what do you need clarification?
>> Well, um
>> it's it's self it's self-evident.
>> Yeah. I guess the question was because I
started psychotherapy like you mentioned
about a week ago and before coming here
she this is my first time here from
2,000 miles and she said what are you
going to expect by going and I said I
don't know I'm just drawn to go and
after reading your books for three years
and watching your DVDs I was just told
to get an airline ticket and be here.
>> Oh yes okay that's fulfilling uh an
important thing. Yes.
>> Mhm. Mhm.
>> You want to pick up the specific energy
itself on top of the words?
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. Well, thank you very much.
>> Where is your home?
>> Uh Cleveland, Ohio.
>> Oh. Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Bad weather back there.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. Last weekend. Three Three Ft.
>> Hope you get Okay.
>> Thank you. You've come a long way.
>> Bad weather, huh? Well,
>> good job.
>> Yes.
Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> I was going to um submit something to a
Sundance workshop.
So, I'd like to know if there's a
difference between the festival and the
organization.
>> Organization. Well, it's a workshop that
the Sundance organ there's no
difference.
>> I don't know. The the last workshop
calibrated u pretty low resist
the organization calibrates over 200
resist
205.
It's iffy ify.
It's if it could go either way.
>> So it might be right at 200.
>> It's right at 200.
So if they choose certain films this
year it goes down. They choose these
terms to go up.
>> See what happens.
>> What difference?
>> Well, it's a workshop. It's Well, um
yeah, maybe there's no difference. It's
a workshop where they help writers. It's
not
>> Oh, they help writers.
>> Yeah. So, I didn't know.
>> Uh
let's see. That's You're asking three
different questions now.
>> Uh we have permission to ask about the
workshop. The workshop exists. the
workshop which is you're referring to
calibrates over 200 resist.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. And I have one other question. I'd
like to know if you can um
I'd like to be better at sort of
surrendering it. It's something I've
been working on for a long time.
>> Be better at what?
>> Surrendering it. Surrendering it.
>> Can you
give me some advice?
You know, it's it's tempting to want to
control it, hold on to it, you know,
make something happen with it.
>> Well, don't try to let go controlling
it. Uh notice that what you that you
want control,
>> right?
>> First let go of wanting to control it
and then let go of controlling it.
>> Okay? It's because it's not the control.
It's your desire to control things, you
know?
>> And of course, you think there's a
secret benefit. So, are you willing to
give up the secret benefit? If I control
this, then I'll be happier and all that.
>> That's right. Yeah.
>> So it isn't the control, it's cuz you
think it's going to bring about
something.
>> Yeah.
>> I'll be successful, wealthy, happy, etc.
>> So let go of that.
>> Okay.
>> You can do it all your life and still be
bad looking, you know.
>> So be good at being bad looking.
>> So is there a way to
>> No. Ug and ugly don't bother you no
more.
See folks out in front get the brunt is
it?
>> Yeah.
>> Sorry.
>> How do you do that really though? I mean
you just have to surrender like that.
How do you
>> I just got through telling you.
>> I know. But
>> you have to listen to the answer.
>> You think there's going to be some
magical benefit. So you have to let go
wanting that benefit.
>> Turn it over.
that you know it's you're you're hooked
on some magical benefit.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> It doesn't you want to change it. You
don't want to change it. What you want
is some hidden benefit.
>> Right. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Turn the benefit over to God. If
you're supposed to be rich, you'll be
rich. And if you're supposed to be poor,
you'll be poor. So what's the
difference?
>> Okay.
>> I've been happy both ways.
>> Thank you.
>> That's true.
When you're poor, you eat better,
though.
>> When you're what?
>> Poor, you eat better.
>> When you're poor, you eat better.
>> When you're poor, you don't eat as well.
You know,
>> when you said when you're poor, you eat
better. You mean when you're rich, you
>> Well, no. When you're poor, you
appreciate hot dog. It's a feast.
>> Oh,
>> I'm just really happy to be here.
>> Yeah.
um and your work has just been a total
guiding force in my life for the past
year and a half. I just wanted to thank
you
>> and I've been following many of the
recommendations in the books and been
doing the course in miracles and
>> as part of my growth I I also did this
workshop that was in the lineage of EST
that the old est workshop
>> a rerun of the essence of est. Oh yeah.
Good old Warner's. Uh yeah.
>> And it proved to be the most devastating
experience of my life.
>> Devastating.
>> How was it devastating?
>> I it started off very much um
responsibility, integrity, right?
>> Um
>> and very non-judgmental,
accepting, freedom of choice. And as it
progressed uh with this other
facilitator
um it got very harsh.
It felt very um the facilitator was
extremely frustrated and felt very
angry. Um and I was in the place of
being really open and trusting.
>> Yeah. And and
I
I mean being surrounded by a room full
of people saying the most harshest
things they could say about me
personally. Yes.
>> And in an effort to like break me
through to the other side. Yeah.
>> And I just I
>> I drowned. And but part of my struggle
has been
um knowing whether
like I like I want to know what is true
and I want to be in integrity and if
that whole process was in integrity and
I had such a hard time with it am I
having difficulty confronting something
or was
the workshop just about
>> is it you were the trainer.
>> Yeah exactly.
>> Okay. We have permission to ask it.
Uh, it was you resist.
It was the trainer resist. Yeah, they
don't they're not all enlightened
Buddhas, you know.
Wner himself fell on his butt, you know.
>> Yeah. I just that was really important
for him and you don't know. Thank you.
>> There's a certain value to it, you know,
to let go of facades,
>> right?
>> Etc. And I can remember when he said
he's this little old lady in a
wheelchair. He says, "Uh, how about
getting off your crippled little old
lady in a wheelchair act?"
>> Now, that depends on how you hear that,
>> right?
>> That would sound uh sadistic,
>> On the other hand, it blew the lady
right out of her wheelchair and she quit
the little sick old lady in the
wheelchair act.
>> So, you don't know. See,
>> that's okay.
>> That was my question. Thank you.
>> Then she was a nasty little old lady on
crutches instead.
Anyway, you you had a good time. You get
there's a benefit out of it even though
you don't think so.
Doing the WER trip is part of uh the
initiation, you know.
Mhm.
Well,
>> Dr. David, I've got to really commend
you. I love your humor.
>> Oh.
>> Oh, that is just outstanding.
>> And uh one of the things I've uh been
chasing this path about as long as you
have. I've been stumbling, I think,
more. And I'm still out in the field. I
figure I've gotten onto Jacob's ladder,
but I don't know how many rungs I've
stepped. And I'd like I'd like to check
with you and see if I've passed 200.
>> Uh,
>> nobody you wouldn't be asking if you
were under 200.
>> Yeah, you're over 200.
>> Can you give me a number or is that
>> now? He wants to start. He's over 200.
He's over 300. He's over 400. 395. 400.
Yeah. 395 is a very good energy.
>> Willingness. willingness
and uh that kind of energy will take you
the the rest of the way.
>> Well, I
>> that's enthusiasm, commitment.
>> I think
>> stick tuitiveness.
>> I I because I I feel I'm running in that
field, but I don't know where to head to
where I could take this talent to help
serve the the supreme being. I feel I'm
still searching. Oh, you're serving the
supreme being by just struggling to
fulfill your own karmic possibilities. I
mean, that's serving God to the fullest
to become all that you can be. All
right. From 395, I would work on uh
lovingness. Then you got willingness,
you got enthusiasm, you got commitment,
you got your loyalty, you've got
everything you need to rebuild the
world. See? Uh so I would choose
something devotional then. And
jump the 400s, which is a lot of book
reading, and jump right into the 500s.
You can catapult from 395 to 500.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Thank you very much.
I have to have a picture.
>> Oh, a picture. Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
>> Old Navy buddies.
>> Try one more here. Were you the one that
was in on the same in the same area that
he was?
>> Yeah, I was on the tanker.
>> He was on a tanker and I was on a mine
sweep.
>> Wow.
>> Mhm.
>> We were playing the same war.
>> You didn't tear up the bars in
Singapore, did you?
>> Yeah,
>> he did.
>> No, it wasn't Singapore.
>> Oh, what was it? Uh,
>> Shanghai.
>> Well, I knew it was one of those.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
Singapore is very strict place. They
might come looking for me.
>> Yeah. Shanghai.
>> Hi. My question. I have watched your um
DVDs on health and I was really glued to
the one that said that you were only
able to eat lettuce at a certain time
and to these
>> practically down to eating lettuce,
>> right? And I've been that way myself. I
was diagnosed um with fibromyalgia and
I've been told all different kinds of
things to do. And finally when I was so
exasperated and down to lettuce and one
grain from India like you said in your
DVD, I watched your DVDs and then I
ordered a couple of more. And so I got
that um not labeling it mentally and
saying I am an infinite being and I am
not subject to this and I here
>> I hereby refuse it and don't accept it
and choose instead to love myself. And I
got that it's unconscious guilt
>> and I'm really
>> that's correct. try to do that and do it
and do it and I still feel the symptoms.
And so now I'm getting into I'm doing it
wrong.
>> Oh, don't forget it took me Don't forget
it took me years to overcome those
things. I mean, I just didn't get it on
Monday. I was healed by Friday.
>> Well, right.
>> Some of those things that I had them for
20 years,
>> right?
>> It maybe took me a couple of years to re
evolve out of them.
>> Right. Like you said, two years for
hypoglycemia. You said it took you two
years for hypoglycemia.
>> Yes. A number of them took some years.
Uhhuh. So I was just
>> some went instantly but I was in a very
unique sort of state of consciousness at
that time. Uh some of them went very
quickly others took years.
>> I was just wondering if you could give
me any more advice because I just get
I'm starting to kind of go down and feel
like oh I can't do this or I'll never
get out of you know I'm starting to get
out of all those positive things I've
been doing after watching.
>> Well that's because you're doing them to
try and control them.
>> Yeah I can see that.
>> Uh do them for their own sake. Okay,
>> I'm I'm an infinite being. I'm only
subject to what I hold in mind.
>> Now, what you hold in mind is either
personal or be could could be
collective.
>> Okay.
>> A couple of the major ailments I've had
in the last few years are not things
that I held in mind personally as a even
a possibility.
>> Okay?
>> But they are certainly out there in the
collective.
>> Okay?
>> So, you can buy them in. So, there
therefore maybe for karmic reasons you
buy something in from the collective and
it takes some time to undo it. Okay.
>> He asked for God's help in the matter.
Figure yourself for for having it
and uh
within a certain karmic period of time
it will leave.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Always feel like you've got a cash
register. You know they used to register
pain in terms of dos ls.
I figured this is 250 dos. How many dos
have I paid in migraine headaches? 149.
Maybe I only got 48 dos to go.
And all of a sudden out came immatrix.
One of my biggest
I battled migraine my entire life.
>> Wow. Thank you.
>> Nothing cured it. Well, yeah. A chi
there was a chiropractor in town that
could fix it, but then he left.
>> Thank you.
you picture it.
>> Who knows what the total uh
maybe you have a karmic debt of a
certain amount of suffering and if it
don't take this form it'll take another
form. So maybe something like that goes
on.
>> Here we go. Ready?
>> You know,
>> thank you.
>> Let's ask that. So maybe you have a
certain amount of suffering and if it
doesn't take this form, it can take
another form. Is this
>> Oh, so that makes sense.
Okay, you got a toothache, you got a
headache. If that don't happen, you got
an attack of the god. In other words, it
wanders around.
>> I guess the suff the amount of suffering
you've brought others. Okay. So, that
which is suffered out is equivalent to
the suffering you've brought into the
life of others. Is this Oh, okay. So,
that takes away the
>> resentment. My question I asked you I
asked you at noon.
>> Uhhuh.
>> You know, uh is you know uh
is Or do we have to pay that back?
>> Yeah, apparently.
>> Hi, Doc. I just want to sit with you a
moment.
>> Yes.
>> I haven't seen you in a while.
>> What's up?
>> Was your last month?
>> That's a while.
Every month is a while, isn't it?
Two months is a while. While
>> Thank you.
Would
you walk a walk a while in your
brother's shoes?
>> Hi.
>> Hey, Doc.
>> Yeah. Yep.
>> How's it going?
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Good.
I I was wondering um a couple questions.
One was I was wondering uh in AA they
have a group of people who get pretty
fussy about the big book. uh they refer
to them as kind of big book thumpers and
and they get a little grumpy about the
uh the treatment centers and things like
that and I wanted to know what your
thoughts were on that particular
>> Well, it's a naive attitude. You know,
you know, AA has no position on outside
matters. So, it's inappropriate to have
a viewpoint on other treatment
modalities, centers, hospitals or
whatever.
>> AA has no opinion on outside issues.
So I would recall them to mind to
respect that tradition.
>> And the other thing that comes up for me
um a couple of times in your lectures
I've had this uh very nice experience
where like the top of my head I feel
like it opens up a little bit and I just
I have some bliss uh very pleasurable
and there have been a variety of other
experiences like that. Uh
>> and yet lately I still find myself in a
state of doubt.
>> State of what?
>> Doubt. significant doubt about
>> uh sometimes just kinesiology, sometimes
the teachings, uh sometimes God in
general, uh just kind of this deep
nagging uh doubt.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And so I just wanted to know uh
get your thoughts on that too, I guess.
You know, is that
>> uh you'll transcend that also.
>> I'm not sure what the doubt is. Um
uh is the doubt that you trust your own
mind uh to the degree that it uh
interferes with your belief in something
higher?
>> Oh yeah, that's it. Yeah. Yeah. I tr I
have a lot of trust in my own mind I
think.
>> So you uh are genulecting to your own
mind.
>> Oh mighty mind. Oh great guru. Oh.
Oh.
The god of dubiosity.
>> Yeah. I think that
>> that's narcissis.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. That's narcissis.
>> Yeah. So, it's just narcissism, I think.
Huh.
>> Okay. Well,
>> thanks much.
>> Don't feel guilty about it. Yeah.
>> Don't feel guilty about being
narcissistic.
>> Okay.
>> Just punish yourself.
>> That's terrible.
>> Doubt is its own punishment, is it not?
>> Yeah.
>> You're agonizing yourself with it.
>> Yeah. I doubt a lot. I agonize.
>> Yeah. Doubt.
>> We'll see what that
>> a lot of anxiety, you know.
>> Yeah. And I think a lot of it is
>> just don't get run over by a car until
you make up your mind one way or the
other. Okay.
Well done. Well done.
>> Well, thanks, Dad.
>> Yeah.
>> I really I love you, Jess. I really
appreciate you guys being
>> Now you're you're going the you're going
the right direction. That's why you're
hitting resistance.
>> Ego doesn't want to let go of that, is
he?
>> Yeah.
>> So, surrender is sovereignty.
>> Yes.
I'm mostly here because I' I've been
afraid to come up
and I and I want to thank you both
for being here
>> and now you're here
>> and I thank God for the opportunity to
be here.
>> Yes.
>> And when I was standing in line, I've
been doing the course of miracles and
this is my second pass through. The
first time it was like I had on
rosecoled glasses
>> and it was wondrous. And the second time
through has been like the opposite.
Really, really hard.
>> Oh, difficult. Yes.
>> And um I I've been having trouble with
meditation. I'm at I'm at the point in
the lessons where you're asked to
meditate for five minutes.
>> Yeah.
>> And five minutes isn't very much,
>> but my mind will not be still.
And I get these little flashes of like
little pictures that have nothing to do
with anything.
How can I
>> Well, create an image of that which is
most aligned with what the lesson is. If
it says forgiveness, you know, picture
yourself uh forgiving. Picture one of
the great saints forgiving. Picture uh
who was it that crawled all the way to
the on his knees to beg the pardon of
what what was it? Pope or emperor or
something.
Just picture something and be that
picture.
>> All right.
>> Protect yourself. So you give yourself a
visualization to work with at the same
time. Otherwise, you just have a
mentalization.
>> Yes.
>> And I had a little like a little
revelation when I was standing in line.
Part of one of the lessons this past
week was that if
If I'm afraid of If I fear God, then I'm
afraid of joy. If
>> you're afraid of God, you're afraid of
joy.
>> Yes.
>> That's a lesson.
>> That's part of one of the lessons. Yes.
To fear God is to be afraid of joy. And
it occurred to me that being afraid to
come up here is is being afraid of joy.
>> Oh. Uhhuh.
>> So,
>> well, you've got the courage to do it
now.
>> Yes. Yes, you booked an
>> Lori as
good work.
>> Good work.
Takes a lot of courage to get in front
of an audience.
>> Picture.
>> Takes a lot. It takes a lot of courage
to get up in front of an audience.
>> Takes a lot of courage to get up in
front of an audience.
Okay, here we go.
>> First time I did it, I thought I was
gonna have cardiac arrest.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. I just have to say I
love you and I'm deeply grateful for
your teachings and for your devotion to
your students. It truly inspires me to
be the best that I can be. So thank you.
>> Thank you so much.
>> And um my question is about staying in
unconditional love in today's world.
>> Yeah.
>> And I tend to
>> I mean that's my heart's desire of
course. Um but I tend to run into people
that are not of the same level of
integrity.
>> Yes.
And I was wondering if you had any
specific advice in staying in my
integrity when I'm in and staying in
unconditional love.
>> It takes a great deal of spiritual
effort. See?
>> Mhm.
>> To try to stay with the essence of
things and not perception and not to
have an opinion or a viewpoint about it.
But that requires, you know, you're
really almost years of inner work. See,
you can ask God for a miracle. You say
you're doing the course.
>> No. Uh no not presently.
>> Yeah. You can ask to see the the miracle
of seeing the the situation in truth in
the eyes of truth
as to see the essence and not the
appearance. Uhhuh.
>> Okay.
>> All beings are intrinsically divine.
Just some are more divine than others.
No, what you you what you see is the
intrinsic innocence of the child within
each person. You see within each is the
innocence of the child
even the most horrific being is being so
out of the naivity of the child within
that it's okay I can get away with it
you know
profound stupidity is what's under it
you know profound blindness and
ignorance you know so you eventually
have compassion for they really do not
know what they do, you know,
>> and love them anyway.
>> You don't have to like them, but you can
quit hating them. You know, you can feel
sorry for them. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Compassion. So, the Buddha recommended
compassion towards all towards all
things at all times. See?
>> Yes.
>> That's why before the headsman chaps
your head off, you tell them, "Don't
feel bad about it. It's just your job.
Don't feel bad about it. You're doing
your duty to the crown, to the king,
to
>> Yeah.
>> And in business dealings, when you
discover someone is not of integrity, I
assume it's best to just disassociate
from those.
>> Well, look, 50% of the world that you're
going to meet in America is below the
level 200.
>> Yeah.
>> Go to some other places on the planet,
about 90% are going to be below 200.
>> You better get used to it. Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
>> Eventually you see their ducks quacking
at your ankles.
>> That's a good perspective. Thank you.
Love and blessings to you. All right.
>> Thank you.
>> And they always say don't duck quing at
their ankles.
>> I like that. Thank you.
>> Checking. Yeah. dex pecking at your
ankles.
>> Right.
Um, I've been having some spiritual
experiences. Um, and I can just describe
them as, um, blowouts. Um, where
>> where I feel, um, it first happened when
I met you and it, um, I
started experiencing cities and, um, all
the hairs on my body st stood up on end.
And then I went to a um I closed my eyes
and went to a state of peacefulness. Um
and this and but afterwards my body felt
floppy and
>> floppy and was just um
>> and then it happened uh the last time it
happened um I felt really sick
afterwards. Is that normal?
Those phenomena come and go when you
were on a spiritual pathway. They can be
very sudden and transitory
and nobody really knows what they mean.
They're just energy fields coming up, I
think.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yeah, it's cuz you're moving along.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah,
>> thanks a lot.
>> Steering the waters. Mhm.
>> Thank you.
Thanks. Oh, and lots of people are
waiting for you to come to England as
well. Got a big group waiting for when
you come over. again. Is that
>> Lots of people are waiting for you to
come to England.
>> Oh, England. Oh,
>> we've got a big group.
>> It's still there.
>> Just about just about. Thank you so
much.
>> That's my ancestors back there.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. Um, I had a question on
uh what you were saying earlier about
activism.
And um I was wondering is the best
position to take one of non-action?
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
All right.
>> Mahatma Gandhi recommended it didn't you
know and uh Martin Luther King because
um
to to push causes a counter push.
>> Okay. So to be to be that which you wish
for the world is more powerful because
there's no counter reaction. You see
force creates counterforce.
Um and power there is no counter to
power. Power radiates and there's no
defense against power.
>> So to be unconditionally loving towards
everyone even though you disagree with
them is more powerful than anything you
can actually do in the world. It's what
you are, what you have become that
influences and raises the level of the
water and that lifts all the ships out
at sea.
>> Okay. So focus on ourselves is the best
way to solve any problems.
>> Hey,
>> what did you say?
>> To focus on our ourselves as a way to
solve any
>> other to become all that you can be for
its own sake.
>> All right. See, because when you become
loving towards all of life, then you're
radiating an energy which is quite
powerful. Not many people even reach 540
4% of the population.
>> Sure.
>> You've already beyond 96% of the
population.
540 unconditional love is extremely
high.
>> Okay.
>> So to become unconditionally loving is
already doing what you can for the
world.
>> Okay. See, two people at 540 does more
for the world than 10,000 people on a
peace march to calibr,
you know, the riot police.
>> I can see that. Thank you.
>> That's what I mean. Yeah. Yeah.
>> See, for force creates counterforce,
>> power,
>> there's no nothing that can go against
power.
>> Absolutely. If you walk around radiating
love and geniality and good humor and
goodwill towards people, there nothing
they can do about it.
>> At your mercy,
>> they can't even call the police.
>> Oh no, she was kind to me.
>> Call the kindness police.
>> All right.
>> Okay. If you see the wisdom of that, you
see
>> absolutely
>> Mahatma Gandhi. That was what he
recommended. Be all that you can be.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> You will.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you very much for today's lecture
about standing up for the truth. And my
question was about I ask about Mahatma
Gandhi and you answered answered the
question. Um
what I wanted to say was whenever I come
up here I feel like my um my ego gets a
good beating and I want to thank you for
that.
It's it's uh
it's after I come here and I go back,
you know, there's so much happening and
uh
um I guess burning of karma, whatever
you call it. And I just uh really
appreciate it. Thank you.
>> My ego gets a beating.
>> It's funny. Yeah.
Yes.
>> I also loved what you said about
standing up for truth
and was wondering about um since being
with you coming into your field, yours
in wonderful Susan's field and the
attraction of that
>> attraction of what?
>> Okay. My question is being in the
attraction field with you and loving
that is that the same as knowing that
>> she's too close.
>> Being in the attraction field and
knowing that is that the same
is that this is
>> that
>> I don't know the question.
>> Okay, repeat the question but don't go
so close to the mic. Sit right there.
Okay, now
>> being attracted to you as my teacher.
>> Oh yes. And being in that field
>> and moving forward in that loving that.
Yes.
>> Is that the same as knowing that?
>> No. It takes you to knowingness.
>> Mhm. Some degree of knowingness is is
what makes you select the teacher.
>> Yeah. But then it takes you to your own
knowingness that within you is the
source of knowingness itself.
>> Nonverbal awareness.
>> Okay. So stand if I if I'm standing up
for what I know and standing up for the
truth.
>> Yes.
>> Is that the same as standing with you in
your field?
>> In a certain symbolic way. Yes. Yes.
Mhm.
>> Thank you. Yeah.
Thank you. Thank you.
Took me a minute. I didn't quite get the
gist of it.
>> Hi, Dr.
>> H. Yes. Hi.
>> Just wanted to come and express
gratitude and be in the presence.
>> Yes.
>> And say hi.
>> Thank you so much. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> He usually has some really good
questions.
>> Yeah. Here you
just
>> Yes.
>> I have nothing to say. I just wanted to
come up
>> for their benefit. I have nothing to
say. I just wanted to come up.
>> She had nothing to say. I want you to
say nothing into the microphone.
>> Thank you.
Everybody can say something. It's a lot
harder to say nothing.
>> Thank you so much. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
Yeah.
Hi.
>> Hello.
>> Uh, I I bring you some items from a lady
that was here with me at the July Satan
last year who gave you a Cocoa doll and
her uh she gave you some stuff about
Coco. Her her sister is Coco's trainer,
>> right?
>> Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
And Jennifer is um when when we left
here, she started going through some
pretty serious health challenges. And um
today she is, as far as I know, still
alive, but in hospice in North Carolina.
Um and she asked me to bring you some
items that she specifically wanted you
to have, uh the two of you. Um and I'll
I'll just give you the package. Uh, I
did want to just show you this is a
photo of uh Michael. Michael, who was
Koko's predecessor and Coco.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> And
how adorable. Yeah.
>> And this is a one of Michael's
paintings. He he learned how to paint.
And uh these are this one's called
pumpkin as you can see. So
>> now who is Michael? That's Coco's
>> Michael is was Koko's companion.
>> Companion. Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> So and there's a few other items in
here. A DVD and a
>> that's how very nice. What great
keepsakes
>> and a note from Jennifer. So
>> we'll put away with for posterity with
other things, you know.
>> Wonderful. Thank you.
>> Very nice.
>> I remember her. Yes. Lovely lady.
>> Yeah. Couldn't forget Coco.
>> Thank you.
>> Coco calibrated what? 400.
>> Well, yeah.
>> Yeah. Extremely high. Yes. Yes. Able to
think. Coco can think.
>> Better than a lot of humans.
>> Oh, yes. You're safer with Coco than
what is it about 80% of the people on
the planet?
>> Yeah.
You're safer in a cage with Coco than
you are with most of the people on the
planet.
>> She's more integrous.
It's sort of an
impressive thought.
>> Yes,
>> she doesn't suffer from malice.
That malice thing. So much of what goes
on in the media is nothing but malice.
Malice in different forms. You listen to
it night after night. It's one form of
malice by another form of malice by
another form.
>> Coco is beyond malice.
>> It's why I tend not to watch the
>> the talking heads and I watch the
Discovery Channel with
>> Thank you very much. Yes. Thank you
both.
>> Yeah. Coco is
>> um we now have a kitty who uh watches TV
and she loves the animal or he loves the
animal channel and he'll sit there and
just watch it
and then pause at it.
>> It's great. Okay.
>> Um, I've been really trying to cultivate
the inner observer, watching my emotions
and things like that. And I've been
analyzing myself psychologically, why
what makes up me and my personality and
my psyche. And I'm really getting to the
point of a high degree of
self-consciousness,
a high degree of uh fear just at the
core of my being. And I can watch that.
I just feel like I'm getting I don't
know what to do about
>> No, you're making good records. Yeah.
Sorry. Say that again.
>> Yeah,
>> you're making good progress. Good
progress. Yeah,
>> that's good.
>> The fear of non-existence coming up.
>> That's correct. Resist. Yes.
>> Do you have any recommended uh
meditations or practices?
>> No. What you're doing is fine. Just go
directly into it. Directly into it.
>> Invite the worst to happen.
Uh what is the worst that could happen
to you?
Uh,
I don't know. Uh,
>> that I'm actually worth loving.
>> Huh?
>> I'm just scared.
>> Well, you you look at the worst that
could happen to you and let go and
surrender to that.
Your imagination can certainly pick out
something awful happened to you. If you
run out of horrible things, I'll send
you my notebook on horrible things that
could happen to you.
>> I really wanted to sit here and be very
self-conscious in front of you.
>> Yes, it's fine.
>> Thanks.
>> Take care.
>> Conscious of self. I know.
>> Yeah, you're doing fine with it.
>> Yeah.
It's like trying to catch yourself in
the mirror. By the time you turn around
to catch yourself in the mirror, you're
gone. You see?
>> Oh, Dr. Hawkins.
>> This is not writing very good.
>> It's It's drying out. That's why
>> you have to put the cap on it. It's
sitting too long.
I know that you
have expressed um joy when people's
lives fall apart upon meeting you and my
life was already falling apart. So um I
can't say that you had a part of that.
However, I've had to rewrite this book
about four times and you've had a big
piece of that.
>> Oh, thank you. So yeah,
>> the dedication in there is
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you
>> to you and and have also endorsed it
>> and you have talked about playing magic
and being magic and I wanted to present
you with some magic wands.
>> Oh,
>> because every magician needs a magic
wand.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And these will transform water and
increase hydration.
>> Yes. and perhaps supposedly also
increase absorption of minerals. And
there's some information in there.
>> Okay.
>> And I do have available the studies, but
I my I don't have a printer. It's in
storage.
>> Yes. Okay.
>> So, I can email the files. Thank you
very much.
>> If you so desire.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you for your very generosity.
>> Hello. Hi. Uh, you talked today about um
the walls in chief's closing.
>> Wait a second.
>> Right. It's 5:00.
>> We have to hurry. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Uh, the walls in chips closing.
>> Yes.
>> And uh, you said it's like one of the
the worst things to betray and rape the
heart of the innocent child.
>> Yes.
>> And um, I wanted to know if u you could
tell me something maybe how to forgive
this or
>> how to what?
>> How to forgive
How to forgive.
>> Oh yeah. They forgive the rapist.
>> Yeah. Or or
>> Yeah. They forgive the rapist for being
an animal.
>> There's spiritual rapists that are worse
than physical rapists. There's one in
this newspaper, right?
Take away your money, take away your
integrity, take away your relationships.
Completely own the person.
And uh
>> so how can you forgive that is what
you're asking
>> right?
>> Yeah. The person themsself is the victim
of the narcissistic ego. The person
themsself is the victim of evil.
They have surrendered sold out to the
devil.
So now the they need compassion.
If you knew the future of somebody who
sold out for the devil, you would see
what I'm saying.
>> Yeah.
>> And how would you best undo that or
>> undo what
>> that negative karma?
>> Whose karma? Negative karma.
>> Well, in general, like from a spiritual
teacher, if at the at the moment he
become
>> that's their negative karma to forgive.
It's yours to learn to discern
appearance from essence.
One way to learn appearance from essence
and being glamorized etc is to go
through a painful experience of
disillusionment you know and then you
thank the person thank you for the
lesson.
>> Okay. Thank you very much. Thank you.
That's all right.
>> Yeah, we got to hustle. Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, Dr. Hawinson, Susan,
>> hi.
I just want to share that uh since the
14th of January,
you've had wonderful
benefits from your work by sharing it.
>> Yes.
>> I was at a kind of a Christmas dinner
with a friend and there were several
people there and I've been talking about
being involved in starting a group. So I
had to name the date and since then
we've had we've had about
six or seven meetings and I just want to
everybody that hears this all over the
world or the country that it's easy to
share the work by just getting your
September of last year's DVD
which you had for new people and so it
makes it very easy for somebody that
would like to share the work with people
that may not have the
um
knowledge or motivation to get to Sedona
that they can do it right in their
hometown with that DVD at the at the
right level at the level you chose to
give to new people.
>> Oh, okay. That was a good beginning
lesson.
>> I'm glad you liked it. I'm glad you
liked it.
>> Yeah, we're doing it here. I think this
may happen for Tucson too pretty soon.
>> Okay.
>> Really in Phoenix.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you. This is the general back to
unity in Phoenix.
>> Oh. Oh, yes. Oh, yes. Okay. Mhm.
>> Yes. I recognize
>> I don't know if you're going to sign on
top. Okay.
Yes.
>> Okay. So, I have an analytical mind. I
love to read. Consider myself a great
book learner.
>> But what I really want to know is what's
the cure for chronic grumpiness.
>> Enjoy being grumpy. Enjoy being grumpy.
>> Enjoy it.
>> Oh yeah. Don't fight it.
>> Be just be a grump.
>> Okay. Okay. The world needs grumps.
>> Is that all?
>> Well, I won't have to be so grumpy then.
You'll be volunteering to share the
burden.
>> Okay. Thanks.
>> Hey, we're going to start an
organization of Grumpers.
He's a great grumpy one to live with. I
can tell you that.
I am asking a question for a woman I met
today in the satellite room. And her
question is this. A course in miracles
teaches that the world is only an
illusion. And another spiritual teacher
says the world as we see it doesn't even
exist. So she wants to know if that is
true then what about Mozart and nature
and the cathedrals and god everything
and um so that's her question
you have to understand the sentence in
the sense in which it is presented.
It says the world of perception is not
the real world.
The essence is often disguised
because you project the glamorization
and perception onto it. Roman Mahari
says there's no point to try and save
the world you see because the world you
see doesn't even exist. Yeah.
All right. So
it has to be understood in the context
in which it is said.
So at 700 that is obvious. At 150 that
sounds like absurdity. See, so
you you stay with that which makes sense
to you and maybe stretches a little bit
but not too far out of where you
yourself are.
How you see the world is a projection of
perception.
That's what relativism is. Relativism
even denies that there is such thing as
a reality. That nothing is everything is
nothing but perception.
That is the sophistry of narcissism.
No, there is an essence to things and
there is an appearance and to
differentiate the two. Y
>> that's what Socrates taught. Yep.
>> Okay.
I I hope that answers her question for
her. Thank you so much.
>> It does tell her Socrates had the
answer.
>> Okay.
Ain't that so saki? Yeah. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Sometimes we call him secretes.
>> I just wanted to say thank you. Like so
many people here today, I reading and
listening and praying and trying to do
the best I can. So, thank you both.
>> That's all anybody can do.
>> Yeah.
Oh, picture.
>> We already have a picture. Yes. Okay.
Yes.
>> Yeah, that's all anybody can do.
>> Hi.
>> Um, I want to start by saying how much I
respect and appreciate and care about
both of you. Uh I was very puzzled and
confused today by um your talk on what
is absolute truth and uh especially when
you said that uh
>> talk on what
>> what was absolute truth
>> about saying that uh campuses have
replaced uh the great books by teaching
Herbert Marcusa that uh the military has
been banned from campuses that
patriotism is not okay that ethics and
morality
yes
>> but that's that's not true about campus
life. That's not absolutely the truth.
>> Campus life
>> about academia.
>> Oh, not academia.
>> Yes, that's a that's a gross distortion
that occurs in academia.
>> In other words, the Duke choir was not
attacked and thrown off the stage.
>> Incidents occur, of course, but there
are incidents millions of students. Uh
there are thousands of ROC programs
around campus. The great books are
taught on every major campus in America,
including Harvard. Oh, thank God.
>> Yeah, that's what's happening. So, what?
Well, great. Then that's not absolute
truth what you said about that. And
>> I said it calibrated. I said that
the level of uh academia calibrated at
certain things in 1955.
It calibrates as a different thing.
Right now, you're trying to defend
academia.
I'm not
criticizing it. And I'm seeing it. It it
it once calibrated to very high. It does
not calibrate high now. So
>> yeah, you just made statements about
what occurs on campus that uh it doesn't
corroborate.
>> Those are just perhaps examples of it.
You know,
>> we should let go of the examples. I
should just give you the calibration.
>> I don't really care myself personally
what the calibration is.
Uh
I know what the calibration level was of
universities when I went to Lemon
Wisconsin and I know what the
calibration of leading universities are
today.
>> I know what the calibration of the
presidents of some very leading
college colleges are now.
>> Yeah. Well, I um
>> and there's also
a list of 50 that calibrates still at
440.
50.
>> Yeah. Through ISI, you can get a list of
>> Are you aware that ISI is uh is a
publishing uh company that's owned by
the Unification Church? And
>> I think that's correct. Yes. Mhm.
>> Uh thank you very much for listening to
me.
>> Yes. Great respect.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
Yes.
>> I would like you to sign my book.
>> Yes.
>> I've just come for a blessing to say to
express my gratitude.
>> Yes.
>> And I think we're a little short on
time, so I'm just going to keep moving.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you very much.
My question is about how best to be of
service to God and most recently that's
taken the form of career choice. Does it
matter what we do for a living as long
as it's not like you know making
>> I think as long as it's integrous and uh
you feel it serves both yourself and the
world you know
>> is there a certain um I mean is is it of
equal service to the world to be a high
calibrating gas service attendant or to
be a psychotherapist who reaches more
people
>> that wouldn't make any difference.
>> Doesn't make a difference. Yeah.
>> Isn't a bad psychotherapist out there
and good gas station attendance.
>> Thank you.
>> Uh yes.
>> You just came to say thank you and ask
for a picture for sure.
>> You bet. Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> All right.
Okay. Ready. Fire.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. As far as the gentleman's criticism
of my criticism.
I myself experienced exactly what I
talked about.
I experienced it from the chairman of
the department of science
in a completely
inongruent manner
in the middle of a graduation suddenly
came through with a political meme
and I thought what the hell is he saying
that for in the middle of
a graduation exercise.
So there was a
a meme, a brainwash meme slipped in
between something else. So that told me
the reason the hair went up because
because I intuit its indoctrination.
This wasn't educational. This was to
brainstorm the p the people, you see.
And I I took that as an insult to the
integrity of the student body and to me
as a parent. I didn't send my child to
be indoctrinated. I sent her to be
educated.
You'll thank you for the indoctrination.
>> So if you had a resentment, so did I.
>> Very good. Uh I want to thank both of
you. I've been coming here for three and
a half years. Yes.
>> Uh the question I have is you've talked
in the past pretty highly about the
business world and the standard of
living it created.
>> Yes.
>> Allowing us to be here. And my question
is what wisdom or advice do you have as
I am I'm trying to figure out how to
communicate these concepts and your
knowledge to the business world. And
>> oh you just uh be that it's good
business. You see, we calibrated uh
don't forget we calibrated Walmart very
high long before it was popular to not
Walmart, you know,
>> right?
>> And uh Sam and I conversed. I was
attracted by his basic integrity.
>> And I think we calibrated about forget
380 or something.
>> Well, in the business world, which is
usually a little over 200, 204,
>> to come out at 380 was rather
astonishing. See, and uh so he and I
corresponded
back and forth. As far as the collapse
of Western civilization, the I have good
news. The good news is that Western
civilization can only collapse down to
like the mid to low 300s. And at that
point, it interfaces with the business
world, the banking world, the world of
integrity, the world of 20 bucks goods
for a $20 bill. And it can't crash any
lower than that. Oh, thank you, Lord.
So, the world's going to be held up by
Walmarts in the end.
As I said with um relativism,
they will forfeit truth, but they won't
accept a 10 for a 20. So, there is a
level of reality below which society is
not going to go. business, commerce,
banking, the law,
even the structure of local government,
police departments. So, it's not going
to go down below 200. I do not believe
the America could go below 200.
The mafia would have to take over the
entire country to do that. No, I think
the the the basic structure of reality
is going to hold up the Western world.
Let's see if if what am I saying is true
or is this what I'm saying is true? Yes.
They'll put up with all that BS unless
it interferes with the reality of
business. And when it begins to affect
the stock price, they're going to cut
out that BS.
So there is a floor underneath how far
the level of consciousness of our
society will go and they will not allow
it to go beyond a certain level. So
there is a certain safeguard. So that
which we is maligned by the uh
politically correct people in the end is
going to be their savior because if it
wasn't for the business world they'd all
be out of a job frankly they wouldn't be
paying nutty professors $60,000 a year
you know to be stupid
>> wouldn't get away with that business.
Can you imagine a guy like a nutty
professor saying you know 911 never
happened and the Holocaust never
happened in front of a business
conference and then expecting to get
paid $10,000 for it? I don't think so.
So there's a certain reality base that
the whole structure of our society
serves. So by participating in society
by all contributing paying our income
taxes etc. we serve we there we provided
a solid floor below which the western
world will not go.
Just one quick comment. In your book,
Power Versus Force, you'd mentioned it
took you a long time to figure out how
to articulate and communicate your
concepts.
And I'm just thinking along that line as
I've been here, this is my 15th time,
and I'm I guess a slow learner, but I'm
trying to articulate these concepts to
business people. And I I'm trying to be
who I am obviously and that's all I can
be. But
>> conceptually I'm trying to figure out
how do I con communicate these to the
business.
>> Research shows that integrity
uh wins in the marketplace.
>> Even if it's not, you don't have to
advertise the integrity. All you have to
do is be it.
>> Be it. Be the integrity.
And uh what's my favorite automobile
insurance company?
>> Geico. Geico. Yes,
>> a little lizard.
>> Anyway, I think they ought to calibrate
the consciousness level of their
advertising.
>> I do too.
>> A lot of companies sell themselves
short. Oh my god. I'll tell you.
Remember that fat guy that was a he had
a blue fairy costume on.
>> MSN.
>> Oh god. MSN. MSN.
>> I don't even know what MSN stood for.
>> Oh yeah. MSN.
>> Here's these three letters. And here's a
chubby butterfly guy. Is it supposed to
be a comedy? I mean, what was it? I
think and then they played it 30, 40
times a day, you know. So, there's what
I call negative advertising. The
irritation value. If I hear one, there's
a certain bank whose name I won't
mention. They will advertise it and as
the minute they get through advertising
it, they will rerun the ad again because
I guess they they get paid for so many
times a day. See?
>> Right. Right. So I I would like to see
the application of consciousness
research in business for the welfare and
the happiness of everybody including the
viewers of their television ads and
other TV ads are so clever. So clever
you know exactly and you can see the
heart in them and the humor in them.
>> Yes.
>> And immediately you feel you feel like a
friend of that company.
>> Right. Right.
>> So my object in advertising would be to
make every viewer become a friend of my
company and let them know that we're a
friend of you. So you get a warm uh you
know like J E L L O.
>> All right.
>> Okay. Thank you. By the way, I I left
the seven inches of snow in Wisconsin
behind.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yeah. You remember the dancing uh
cigarette package and J E L L. Uh we
incorporated into part of our family. J
E L L O.
I thank you so much. It was a wonderful
lovely day and uh
we tried to fulfill our oblig you know
to the best that we can we don't claim
perfection I don't claim perfection we
try with the best endeavor to fulfill
answer the questions and uh to be the
the most that we can be so all of us
here fulfill our obligation to God by
becoming
potential of that we could be to the
best of our ability
And you can't ask anything more of
anybody. Did you run as fast as you
could run? Yes, I did. I mean,
we're not all born with giant legs. You
know what I mean?
So, we thank thee, oh Lord, for the
wonderment, for the blessing. This is a
prayer. This congregation, the people
itself is a prayer. And um we thank you
for for revealing that uh this is the
tale that is actually wagging the dog
that this particular group has a impact
on the consciousness level of all of
mankind for which we give thanks to the
oh lord and uh amen.
>> Glory be to thee oh lord. Amen. Glory
and excius.
Hallelujah.
Thank you all.
>> Yes. Gloral.
Hallelujah.
Wow.