I think they're going to have jets that are faster than the supersonic.
They're going to bounce off the atmosphere.
I want to thank you and Susan,
and I want to just state before everybody that I claim you as my teacher.
The question I have has to do with constant prayer.
I know I want to heal something around Christianity,
Christ, and my relationship to God that comes from my childhood,
but my father conditioned us with beliefs from a Christian sect
that was based in revelations and apocalypse and an angry God.
I was attracted, after I became spiritual for the last 20 years,
I was more attracted to godless religions like Buddhism,
where there wasn't as strong a concept of God.
But through your teachings over the last three years,
I've realized,
I've seen Christianity and God from a new perspective,
and I'm grateful for that.
This summer, I've taken a three-month sabbatical to focus on constant prayer
and to spend time in the wilderness,
where I can focus on making it as much a part of my life as possible.
The questions I have have to do with the prayer I'm choosing.
I took your teachings that I had heard,
and I used the prayer,
Glory be to thee, O Lord.
Thy will be done.
And I repeated that over and over again.
As time went on,
a lot of my life came up before me,
and I started to see how much I needed salvation,
and what I felt as I wanted to switch to the Jesus prayer.
And the Jesus prayer has the statement of,
for Lord Jesus Christ,
have mercy,
have mercy on me,
a sinner.
And that didn't feel good to me,
so I used the terminology,
Lord Jesus Christ,
I ask your mercy,
and I repeat that over and over again.
So the question is,
is that an appropriate language to address Christ in a prayer?
Are you aware of what you call the Brother Lawrence,
the practice of the presence of God by Brother Lawrence?
No, I'm not.
It might be a good thing to look up,
because it's really sort of what you're looking for.
Okay.
Brother, it's a very small little booklet.
I don't even know where you can get any of it.
It's the prayer of Brother Lawrence, right?
Right.
Well, to be constantly conscious and aware of the presence of God,
you know.
It's boiled down to its probably most simple form,
Brother Lawrence.
You know, what should we call it?
What's the word I want?
What should we call it?
Brother Lawrence.
The practice of the presence of God.
Yeah.
The practice of the presence of God by Brother Lawrence is very famous,
time-honored, and has been used for great periods of time.
So, I mean, if you're looking for something that has been validated by widespread usage,
you know.
Okay.
The practice of the presence of God is the name of it.
Yes.
The last question I have about the prayer is that,
as I'm walking down the aisle,
you know,
walking in the wilderness,
it starts to take a singing quality,
kind of like a choir singing the prayer.
Yes.
And maybe because of my childhood and my scrupulosity around Christianity is,
I don't want that to be a disrespect of the prayer,
but it seems to happen naturally and it also feels good as I'm praying.
So, okay.
Yeah, that's the angelic response.
Yeah.
Okay.
So, it's primarily singing in my consciousness and very little just.
That's the angelic.
Good.
That's what I was doing, was worrying about it.
It'd be nice not to worry.
That's the angelic.
Great.
Thank you very much.
And I'd like to have a picture with my friend.
Okay.
Angelic, yes.
Hello.
My question's also about prayer.
In doing,
Glory be to Thee, O Lord, Thy will be done,
or the Jesus prayer,
would it enhance it by having some sort of gratitude towards God,
thanking Him or His divinity?
Being specific about gratitude?
Oh, I think we're too much interested in the words verbatim.
I think the overall intention of devotion can be expressed anyway, you know?
I think any kind of wording that's comfortable to you, you know?
It's the,
it's the energy with which it resonates.
That,
so how the wording I don't think makes that much difference.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yes.
Oh, okay.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
It's easier to write.
Okay.
Yeah, that's better.
Yeah.
Otherwise I get all my weight on my elbow.
Yes.
Hello.
I've been doing the Course in Miracles workbook this year.
Yes.
And I'm finding at certain lessons, like for example,
I want the peace of God.
That day, it's like all hell breaks loose.
And then I feel guilty and I don't know how to work through it.
Well, you should know what it could have been.
Flattened by a truck.
Well, don't forget, karmic propensities come up.
And, you know, we expect that it's going to be the way we want it to be
by praying and asking for a miracle,
that your phone bill is going to be paid now and not shut off.
And we think, well, if they shut off my phone, it didn't answer my prayer.
God wants you to know if you don't pay your phone bill,
they're going to shut it off.
You got the message.
It's called pay attention to reality.
So you don't know whether you're getting an answer to the prayer or not.
Yeah.
And to puzzle out the meaning of what you experience next until you understand it.
All right?
Thank you.
Tuesday night when I was meditating, suddenly the words came up,
ask Dr. Hawkins how you're doing.
So and instantly total and complete terror came up to the point where I was almost physically ill.
That's sensible.
So in order to work through the fear, I came up and I'm asking, how am I doing?
You're doing wonderfully.
Thank you.
To get out in front of the audience when you're suffering from anxiety and overcome it, face it, and break it out.
What more could you ask for?
True.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Hi, Doc.
Hi, Susan.
Hi.
For the longest time, I've had a problem in terms of a personal connection to divinity, to God.
And I even wrote a book, Struggling to Surrender.
I gave you a copy when I first met you.
And I just recently got it watching a 2002 video about surrendering
to thee, O Lord of God imminent.
Yes.
Could you explain a little bit more about the connection between, is that like the gateway to God transcendent?
Don't worry about God transcendent.
Okay.
You don't have to worry about the sky.
The sky's fine the way it is.
Okay.
You worry about, don't worry anyway.
Well, I'm not really worrying.
I'm just not really.
God imminent is identical to what the world considers to be transcendent.
But you see, a lot of people call God you, and it's an other, other.
It's an other.
They don't realize that, you know, as Christ said, heaven is within you.
Heaven is within you.
Discover the infinite presence within oneself.
God is simultaneously transcendent and imminent.
And those are merely artifacts of languaging.
Transcendent and imminent are not contradictory.
They're just different ways of stylizing it and vocabulary.
But traditional religion, you know, speaks of God transcendent.
But Jesus said God is, heaven is within you.
God is both transcendent and imminent.
It was such an incredible gift to be able to see that, well, I'm not surrendering to something out there, but this bigger piece within myself.
Yeah, it's not an out there-ness.
That's why I don't like the term you for God.
That's a pronoun, you know, and it's limited.
There isn't such a thing as you God.
The closest you can come is to thee, O Lord, to thee, O Lord.
Thee is respectful.
And thee implies the recognition of the divinity because that's the only thee that appears, you know, historically.
To thee, O Lord, is God transcendent, spoken of respectfully.
That's why I don't...
You say you, O God, you're making it like two persons, two personalities separated.
There's me and then there's you.
That's sort of a not too evolved kind of comprehension of divinity, you.
I think that's what 95% of the world gets transcended down to or, you know, what was my understanding of it.
So thank you so much.
The ineffable is very hard to put into words.
About seven years ago, I was involved in a group of a spiritual teacher.
I had...
Involved in what?
Oh, yeah.
And I've got...
Does she have to be closer or further?
And I've got real dramatic changes in my life.
But about five years ago, I moved away and I lost any contact with them.
I would like to continue my study with the group.
But right now, the group, for an outsider like me, looks much more like a sect than the group that it used to be.
Same group.
It's just you see it differently.
Yes.
I just see the teacher and the group itself differently.
It's more like a splinter group, yeah?
Yes.
Yeah, yeah.
No, their attitude to the teacher and her role in the world and their role of religion.
And in her teaching and so on.
It looks like they're creating a new religion with her being a messiah.
The leader of this group.
A new messiah?
Oh, yeah.
We'll have to redo the calendar.
Make this year one.
And I just wanted to ask you to calibrate the information coming from her back then and now.
All right.
I don't want any names.
You hold in mind the teacher.
The teacher is over 200, is this?
240?
500?
600?
505?
510?
That's pretty good.
A lovingness, right?
Yeah.
So basically, I can continue doing the studying.
So what's the question?
I can continue doing the studying.
Yes.
She can go through all that now.
No, I don't.
Her enemies.
Oh, that's.
Yeah.
But my energy is remaining high.
Okay.
And she's .
Oh, yeah.
They're cultizing around her.
The other people in the group are cultizing.
They're cultizing.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
But I can't go in the details of it.
How are you?
The teacher feels all right at 500.
Yeah.
Okay.
Somebody ask me another question if you don't mind.
Oh.
Mm.
I want to ask a question, and I also want to put it in a context, so that the question
So that the question becomes clearer. My question is if being
Being and feeling grateful
allows
For grace to flow down. Yes onto one gratitude gratitude
The context is I have a business to run a business to run
Well, yeah business, yeah
I
Noticed that whenever I think of promoting my business
Marketing anything of the sort nothing works
As soon as I start working on myself by addressing by working by reading a book like this by
Listening a tape that you have as long as I step away from business and concentrate on developing my conscious
Yeah consciousness and you attract then everything works. Yeah. Yeah
What I'm true, however, I still have a business to so I'm still attached
A little bit. So what I'm trying to do is I'm trying to ask people for testimonials
When they get help through my business
However, that doesn't happen
So I'm trying to see within myself
If there is something that I need to undo or get better with on my own so that it happens
Meaning am I not grateful enough myself that they don't feel grateful to me?
How do you ask them for this?
Yes, them for a testimonial. Yeah, if they have what's a relief of suffering
You have the result you feel better. Could you give us just the result of what?
I'm a refrigerator. What is it? I'm a doctor
Yes, and so they come to me because they have pain and so I help them with it. Are you looking for testimonials?
Yeah, I wouldn't know as illicit them would not even bother
because
what what furthers your
Practice is
Word of mouth. Yeah, that's that's personally where my
feeling is yes
No, I wouldn't ask them for testimonials because things would really happen on their own if I'm getting yeah
Yeah, that's what I'm thinking too
No, it happens spontaneously, right? Yeah
Thank you very much. I know from experience. Yeah, mm-hmm
No, you do all that you can to the best of your ability
And the energy of that radiates out.
And then other people hear of it, and they send somebody,
and they do the same thing.
And then your practice grows and grows.
And you have to run away to Arizona.
Out in the country.
Hiding in the country.
Oh, my gosh.
I'm afraid.
You have to look into the eye.
It's a real camera, so look into the eye.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
Strange things happen on this planet, Lord.
I'm reporting back that strangeness predominates.
That's great, yeah.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Yeah.
Hello, Susan.
First of all, I want to say thank you with all my heart and soul
for your teachings and for your devotion to your students.
Yes.
And I have a question about the student-teacher energy field.
There seems to be a field of consciousness,
a consciousness that I sense between you and all of us as your students.
And at times, it arises within me an awareness of your presence.
And sometimes it arises as the hearing of the Kyrie music spontaneously just arises within me.
And I sense that you in us, your presence is with me.
And I would just like you to.
Maybe comment on that phenomena and your sense of your accessibility to all of us in this plane and when you are around.
I pray every night to be a servant of everyone here, to be a servant of God, to be a servant of these people.
And I give gratitude, I thank God for the gift to be able to be what I am.
I am to the students, you know, that to me is a great gift.
And as I told you, my obligation is to God, my fellow man and myself.
And my fellow man is that as a teacher, just as I was the best physician I could be, to the fullest extent I could be that.
I was the best hermit I could be to the degree I could be a hermit for a while.
And now I am back in the world in this particular function.
But I do hold all of them in mind and pray for them.
And I pray for the spiritual evolution of everyone here present because they are indeed my blessing and their gift, God's gift to me to be able to serve them.
Thank you.
So you may be picking up the energy of the prayer itself.
I feel that I hear your voice in my head at times.
That would be the way the prayer is going to cross to you, yes.
And I feel that that will be with me for all my days and beyond.
Yes, it's so.
It is so.
God bless you.
And thank God for you.
Blessing me by that, you know.
Thank you so much.
You make a difference.
It's my honor to know you.
Picture.
Oh, there we go.
Very good, yes.
She picks up the energy of the prayer.
Something I heard you say in a recent interview that really stood out to me.
If I heard you correctly, you said that we have to master the world before we can transcend it.
And I just wondered what you meant by that, because I think maybe I've been trying to transcend it first.
Maybe you have mastered it.
You see its value, and its value.
To master the world really is to see its value.
As a teaching tool, having learned all you can from the world, there's no further need for it.
It's a big toy, a big whirling toy.
Okay.
It's a fun toy.
It serves its purpose for a period, you know.
And then we go on to other dimensions, you know.
This is not the ultimate dimension.
We go on to other dimensions.
Thank you.
I felt like I had started to understand the whole idea of karmic unity.
And the notion of the every hair on your head being counted, isn't that the same thing?
Same thing as what?
I don't know what karmic unity means.
What does karmic unity mean?
Well, the idea that everything leaves a karmic trace, and then, I don't know, you float in the ocean according to your karma?
Yes, everything leaves, yes.
Everything leaves a trail.
Forever.
Renewable forever, yeah.
So that's my understanding of karma.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Everything that exists.
So then the idea of the hair on the head is also...
Everything exists, everything that ever happens leaves a permanent track for all time, for eternity.
Therefore, you really don't want to make too bad of a mistake.
Because people are going to be reading it centuries from now.
They'll say, oh, that one there, man.
Look at what she did, right?
Oh, I know.
So then I pray for mercy, right?
It leaves a permanent track.
Okay.
But it's the same idea, just a different wording then.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Everything that exists emits an energy, including all events, personages, decisions, options.
And that leaves a karmic pattern, a track.
And that's what we call about our inherited karmic propensities.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Yeah, thank you.
I'm going as fast as I can.
My Widow Wicks can win.
I'm going as fast as my Widow Wicks can win.
I've been suffering from depression for like 15 years or so.
Yes.
And I'm trying to search for help.
And I don't think the cause is like, I don't believe it's like sugar, like you just say
before.
She's suffering from depression.
Yeah?
She has been for years.
Yeah.
So you've been treating with a doctor?
With what?
Have you been treating with a doctor?
Yeah.
I am an antidepressant right now.
What?
Antidepressants.
She's on antidepressants.
Yeah.
Is it helping?
Good.
But I would like to, like, get a deeper healing or something.
Oh.
All right.
Okay.
So the wisdom to accept that which you cannot change.
The wisdom to change the things you can.
The wisdom to know the difference.
So you do all you can do.
You're responsible for the effort but not the result.
And many of these depressive things come and go.
And you stopped eating sugar and sweets.
Did you try that?
Yes.
Okay.
All right.
So you've tried the antidepressants.
Yes.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
So you've tried the easy ones like functional hypoglycemia and all those kind of things.
Then you may have to just wait it out.
So these depressions tend to run their course.
You may run 10, 15 years and then disappear.
So you just maintain whatever level you need to keep the dopamine, to keep the serotonin
level up in the brain.
And it's genetic generally.
And you do what you can during the period of time.
When that's necessary.
In the meantime, you add to it all you can do.
Yeah.
I've been doing a course in miracles and all of these.
You do everything else you can do.
Yeah.
Using alternate health.
Everything from acupuncture to who knows what will help.
All those things are worth a trial run.
Okay.
You never know which one is going to be good.
Yeah.
I've been trying acupuncture and lots of things.
So you're doing what you can do.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
So you're doing what you can do.
It's better than being in denial.
It's better to face it.
Do what you can do.
Rather than be in denial.
And then some other solution will appear.
You know.
Take more vitamin B3.
Cut out sugar and sweets.
Try acupuncture.
Try jogging.
God knows what will help it.
Yes.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
I have suffered from headaches for about a year and a half.
Headaches?
Yes.
I have epilepsy.
Huh?
Epilepsy.
Yeah.
And I've been to a neurologist, and the second one has made the headaches a bit better.
Instead of every day, they're probably about five days a week.
Uh-huh.
And I've read that you suffered with migraine headaches.
Yes.
And I was curious on what you did to pass that.
I did everything under the sun, including acupuncture.
Acupuncture helped everything, but it didn't cure the migraine.
And I had pins and everything.
I did the whole thing, moxie combustion, et cetera.
It had cured my ulcer, you know, first treatment or second treatment.
It didn't do anything for my migraine.
See, but I think everyone is different.
Imitrex came along, and it was like magic.
I took a half an Imitrex, and like magic, it disappeared.
Yeah.
Right now, they have me on Zomeg.
It's a nose.
It's a nose spray that I take when I feel the headache coming on.
And then I also have what they call chronic headaches that are not considered migraines.
Cluster headaches, yeah.
All right, so you have to, everything's physical, mental, and spiritual.
So you handle it on all three levels, and then you wait it out,
and a lot of these things you'll grow out of.
Okay.
You know?
Like you just told me.
Most of the things I had when I was young were all gone, bye-bye, you know?
I didn't get them until I was older.
That's what's so bizarre.
Huh?
Yeah.
She didn't get any of this.
Yes.
Yeah.
Well, that's true.
You weren't old enough to get them yet.
And my own personal experience, middle age was the worst.
It wasn't one thing after another.
I mean, it was a wonder I survived at all.
Did you pass the migraines, or do you still get them?
The migraines still will recur periodically if the weather's right.
So weather can affect migraines.
If the weather comes on, yeah.
I live in Texas, so I've heard that.
So right now, I'm not eating.
I'm eating chocolate, because you can see it's sucking in.
I don't want to kind of put anything.
So you say, well, that's a belief system, and you can negate it.
So I've been negating it, but I don't want to push my luck.
And I've heard that.
When the barometric pressure is dropping, it's not a great time to indulge in chocolate.
And I've heard that acupuncture has healed some people of epilepsy.
Has what?
Healed people.
Yes.
Lots of wonderful things can be done.
And, of course, there's different acupuncturists with greater and lesser skills, you know,
like any other physician.
How do you know which one's good and which one's bad?
Well, you just work on it.
You try your best.
You go by reputation.
You use kinesiology if you can.
Okay.
You say, this doctor has capacity to help me.
Yes, no.
Okay.
God bless you.
It's so lovely to meet you.
You too.
Human beings are fragile.
It's a wonder how we stay alive.
I just marvel that we've survived it all, frankly.
When you think of all the afflictions that can hit you in one lifetime,
that you know about, and the ones that you didn't know about.
Yeah.
The other day, we're rounding a bend, and Susan's driving,
and we're out in the country, a sharp turn,
and coming right at us at a breakneck speed, right in our lane,
is a guy just dying to have a head-on, I guess.
I mean, you know, totally unexpected.
Minding your own business.
Went to church that morning.
We're on the bed, and here's a maniac coming right at you, dead on,
right in your lane.
Right in your lane.
God knows what.
Very scary.
I didn't have time to be scared.
It was over before I got a chance.
Happy 80th year.
Oh, yes, indeed.
My question, is the enlightenment level of consciousness
the level where there's no thinking, thoughtlessness, no mind,
and is it also the level at which you're released
from personal karma?
I don't want to answer about personal karma,
because there's karma at different levels,
and different consequences on different levels.
So you can go beyond the karma of this level,
but you're still stuck with the karmic propensities of humanness,
and et cetera, see?
What was the first question?
Is enlightenment the same as the level at which the thinking ceases?
Oh.
The mind becomes silent.
There is instead, in the high 500s,
an exquisite joyfulness, an ecstasy.
There then comes a bliss and an infinite state of peace.
The peace of God, it's unmistakable.
You realize when you go into it, you recognize the peace of God.
Timeless, infinite.
And without thought.
I don't remember any thought, no.
You also can, this is in Sikpat 600,
you can also leave the world at that point,
and you're aware that you could leave if you wish.
There's nobody to wish it.
So I suppose there's more karmic propensities than anything,
whether one will continue to survive.
But there is a strong desire to leave the world at that point.
I mean.
It's an option, with the door standing open, invitationally.
That's why, oh, I forget, probably the majority of people at 600 leave, do.
And that's why there's hardly anybody beyond 600.
Most people leave at 600 or more, a higher level.
Each level, you have an option to leave.
And sometimes you don't know what's going to happen.
You wait and see if you're going to leave or not leave.
Yep.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Good to see you, Susan.
Not to worry.
It's a state of infinite peace.
It's okay, whatever.
Yes.
My question is about wolves in sheep's clothing,
as you've been talking about today.
About what?
Oh, yes, yes.
If they're ever disguised as a spiritual aspirant,
and if it's ever okay to deal with people under 200,
when you feel like,
oh, there's a spiritual aspirant,
they could be wearing the sheep's clothing of a spiritual aspirant,
is that what you're saying?
Yeah.
But inside they're really demonic and evil?
Yeah, I'm sure of that.
Amen.
Is it, you always warn, stay away from under 200.
Stay away from under 200.
I think to avoid.
Avoid.
Jesus Christ said don't oppose evil, avoid it.
I've had a lot of interesting people come into my life lately,
and I have made exceptions because I didn't know how to say no.
Yes.
And I don't know how,
it feels unloving and unkind to say no when somebody is in desperation,
and yet it's such a drain.
That's a test.
You have to know how to be able to say no without feeling guilty about it.
That's a test along the way.
I said yes.
That was just negative.
That was very negative.
And what I said to the people who were in the room,
and I was 법lless in my own life,
I said to the people,
I said God, God, a question that I've been asked in my life,
a question that I've been asked in my life,
just to be able to think that God and I are close,
that we're not the same,
we don't have a common purpose,
help, help, help.
And I think the most important thing that I can say is,
I think people will try to cling to you and hang on you.
Just like the crabs in a pail,
the crabs in the pail,
when one tries to get out and starts to go over the tide of the pail,
the other crabs pull them down.
So you have to know when you have to walk on,
relationship with God, what do you want with me?
Yes, you're right.
You can intuitively detect that they really
mean to pull you down with them in a parasitic dependency,
which they juice you for your energies.
Let's see, they used to be called electric and magnetic.
There was a psychic lady in town that was pretty smart.
She would call them electric and magnetic.
The electric would give you energy,
and the magnetic would like pull your energy.
And she divided people into those that pull your energy
and those that give you energy.
People below your own consciousness
will be pulling energy from you, OK?
I'm in a pickle.
So you try to avoid them.
You can, yeah?
I agonized over it.
I knew I shouldn't, and I agonized, agonized over it.
Right, right, right.
I could not say no.
Yeah, I know what you mean, yep.
God knows.
I'm in an extra bedroom, and can't you just
let me board here for a while?
Then you discover they're doing evil incantations over your bed
while you're sleeping.
OK, it's all right.
Thank you.
Yeah, I understand what you're saying.
A lot of people run into that.
It's a tough one.
That's why people go to Al-Anon, you know, because, yeah, right.
That's why people go to Al-Anon.
I was wondering if you had any advice on how
to practice this identification.
How to practice this identification with the ego
and unconditional love toward the self simultaneously.
Yeah, it's the following all the things
that we're teaching combined.
It's following all the things combined, all of it at once.
And what was the first question?
How to practice this identifying with the ego.
Oh, yes.
To be aware that the functioning of the mind is not the real self.
The mind wants everything.
It wants amusement.
It wants to be bright.
It's self-glorifying, et cetera.
And you disown that as your own reality.
And you say that's the way the ego is.
And disown that you're identifying with it.
You can say, I am what I am despite that.
Despite that, not because of that, or not that I am that.
Thank you.
It's the animal nature.
You can call it animal nature.
Animal nature is greedy, desirous, narcissistic, vain,
wants to control, wants to take over the territory,
wants all the opposite sex.
Yep.
You can stay compassionate at the same time.
But you recognize it's the animal.
Those kind of instincts.
It always has to get.
It has to control.
It plays king of the hill.
Picture two wolf males, you know.
I'm my territory.
I'm my women.
My territory.
My women.
And that's the USA and America.
That's the international situation.
But there's a part of me which isn't that.
That's true.
It's bored with it.
Best to just be bored with all that,
other than to denounce it as evil or bad.
It's tedious.
It's chasing your own tail.
Because no matter how much you gain,
there's still more that can be gained.
When you're worth $100 million, you could be worth $100 million.
could be worth $150 million.
When you're worth $150 million, you could be worth a billion.
When you're worth a billion, you could be worth $100 billion.
You could be richer than the Queen of England, you see.
What good will it do you?
You can only eat one sandwich at a time,
sleep in one bed at a time, drive one car at a time,
make love with one person at a time.
So it doesn't do you.
All the excess doesn't do much good.
100 pounds of potatoes is better than one pound.
How many can you eat?
I'm a little nervous, so you have to excuse me.
But I have a question that's come to mind many times when I've come before.
And one of your wonderful teachings to include not being spiritually naive
is a big important lesson for me.
Too much?
She's either too close or too far.
OK.
A big question for me is about the spiritual naivete
and how important that was for me to learn.
That's a big one for me, all these years of spiritual work.
One of the analogies.
One of the analogies you gave about Chamberlain versus Hitler
and how Chamberlain went to Hitler and peace in our time.
And then that was a couple of times ago you gave us that analogy.
I had the white paper, yeah.
Exactly.
And so I wonder how one stays integrous in the world
in your life and your everyday comings and goings.
You have to work with folks that have calibrations that are not integrous.
So can you give some clues of how one
goes about the world and is able to make good choices
and not change your own level of integrity to deal in the world?
Well, you try to choose the most integrous pathway you can.
And if you find yourself in a non-integrous one,
you try to find the most diplomatic way
to remove yourself and to stop identifying with it.
And hold in mind what you do want.
Hold in mind what you do want.
Because what you hold in mind tends to manifest.
So you hold in mind that which you would be pleased and desirous of.
You hold in mind what you do want and just refuse that which you don't want or leave
it.
You can say, I've worn it out.
You know?
Yep.
You can say, I've worn it out.
Thank you.
Explored it.
You've worn it out.
Thank you.
May I have a picture?
Yes.
Thank you.
They keep him busy.
He's like the official photographer.
Thank you.
Yes.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins and Susan.
I have studied the Course in Miracles, and I'm working on it the second time.
And I work as a nurse practitioner.
Yes.
And how do I incorporate my new change of view of the world and people into this
medical world?
Well, you don't.
You see it the way you see it.
And some of it rubs off, and some of it does not.
Yeah.
Some people you can even recommend they try doing the course.
You know, you've seen a lot of people recover from a lot of illnesses.
You've got to be careful about that.
They don't consider you some kind of a proselyte or nut, you know.
Right.
So you just utilize it within yourself,
and the patients benefit from the fact that you yourself are coming from a higher place, you know.
I've been starting my day with the prayer from the course that I am here because of he who sent me.
And that's been helping me as a guidance system that what I say or what comes out of me isn't just my opinion.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
So that's been helping me.
No, you do the lesson for the day, and you go about your business,
and you choose to be as loving, you know, instead of forgiving,
if you choose to be as loving as possible, one way of being loving is to choose.
You can see forgivingness as an option, you know.
Okay.
Thank you so much.
If people could be better, they would be.
I know.
They can't.
That's true.
That's why they're stuck where they are.
That's what Jesus said.
Forgive them and they know not what they do.
Okay.
Good.
Thank you.
You can forgive them.
You don't have to give them the keys to your new car, though.
I'm moving as fast as I can move.
Hello.
Yes.
My sister and I are from Seattle, and we're not going to ask any questions.
You're the most quoted person in our life, I tell you.
I hope we quote you.
I hope we quote you correctly.
Oh, God.
I know.
We'll lose all of our friends after a while.
They'll get...
But I just want to thank you so much for everything.
Thank you for thanking me.
One thing that we've done is we have you on all the time through the night, too,
so that whenever we wake up, you know, we hear a little bit and can go back to sleep.
I see.
Yes.
Some people do for the music, too.
They like the music, yeah.
I know.
Well, I do hope that I'm not just brainwashing myself all the time.
No, I understand what you're trying to do.
And have some of my own thoughts, because we have you on all the time.
You just want...
You know, what you want is that energy is all.
Yeah.
What you want is the energy.
Right.
I understand that.
That's right.
So I just wanted to get your picture.
We all do that with certain kinds of music or incense or reminders, symbols, statues.
I could get up as easy.
I forgot the octopus.
Yes.
Hi, Susan.
Hello.
I'm here to ask you to om, please.
And a picture.
She said something.
Oh, yes.
Oh, my dear.
Yes.
Hi, there.
I have lots of questions for you.
And I was wondering if I could spend the next hour with you.
Okay.
You can.
Yes, indeed.
Sit right here.
All right.
Put your feet up here and put your bottom there.
Whisper in my ear.
Okay, doc.
What's up?
What's up, doc?
I just want maybe some validation over some doubt I'm having in exploring sort of the
inner realms of my psyche in a way.
I've been training in hypnosis, hypnotherapy.
And have been working with regression and going back to different seeming episodes.
But there's like part of me that's doubtful.
Like there's sort of the witness that's looking over the occurrence.
Well, what do you take yourself back to?
Something you specify in advance?
Yeah, it's with intention and like the cause of something occurring in my life.
Oh, what is that connected with, huh?
Right.
What is this connected with?
And.
It's sort of a sense of something coming about, but there's some doubt in.
It doesn't have to be literally factual.
Okay.
That's naive.
It has to be more that it recontextualizes for you.
Significance, meaning, and all that kind of thing.
Okay.
The specifics are not necessary, usually.
You see the symbolism of what was and what is now, and you see the connecting thread.
You know what I'm saying?
Mm-hmm.
In certain types of past life recall, you're not remembering an event like you're watching a movie.
What happens is the actual event begins to rerun all over again.
Mm-hmm.
You know, witnessing or watching something like out there from here, you're in the movie,
and the movie is happening again with the same sense of reality as it did originally.
Okay?
Yeah.
So you.
So the experience that.
So I was recalling was that I was sort of enslaved by this man, and that I had died,
but instead of returning to maybe the light or, you know, I decided to sort of invade him in a way,
like attach to him.
Uh-huh.
Does that seem like.
Is that a possibility, or.
Yeah, it's a possibility, yeah.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
All right.
Okay.
Thank you.
Appreciate it.
Where do all these come from?
Huh?
Yes.
Hi, Doc.
Susan.
Yes.
Um, we've come up to ask for a blessing.
Uh-oh.
Rob and I, um, have committed our relationship to be in service to each other on our path
to God.
Yes.
And we would love for you to bless that alignment.
So we can bless, what, your love, your unitedness, and your devotion.
That you do it for yourself, for the other, and for God, and for mankind.
Yeah.
Oh, that's right.
I said you'd do that for all of us.
Yes, we thank you.
Thank you.
Yes.
One thing I'd like to express gratitude for your work.
And bringing people closer to God, and so much specific explanations on how to get over
so many things.
But my question is, I have so many health issues, and I'm wondering, is there a mindset
to certain specific health issues, or a way to get over, to be healed from them?
Well, we're going to put out a book.
Uh-huh.
I did a bunch of lectures years ago.
Things I understood, things I treated, things that I myself experienced, and the answers
that I found, you know, for whatever good it might be, people have similar things.
It's really amazing the number of things you can go through in a lifetime and still survive.
I mean, as you're, you know, when you put them all end to end, and write them all up,
it's really quite awesome.
You know, really.
I know, between blood clots, and lupus, and migraines, and all this stuff.
Where do you get all that negative?
You say, where do you get all that?
Negative karma.
Mm-hmm.
Sometimes, because of the speed and the height of your own spiritual evolution, you bring
all these things up in one lifetime.
So how do you get over?
You go from here to there.
You pull in everything.
Mm-hmm.
Every karmic whirlwind along the way, and you can slow that down by just being dumb
and not trying to evolve spiritually.
Just zoning out.
Oh, boy.
Okay.
Well, thank you.
Yeah.
Thank you for your time.
Thank you for your work.
Thank you, Susan.
Yeah.
That's your doctor.
Uh-huh.
Go back to thievery, or something like that.
And you're stationary.
Lon, from the San Francisco Bay Area.
Yes.
One question.
As I promised.
First, you stated in your writings that one can reach the 500 levels in this lifetime,
in one lifetime.
Right.
Does one have to transcend from the low 400s all the way up to the 499s?
Well, it's not a linear progression.
You can jump from 350 right to 510.
No stopping off in the middle.
I'm making a very serious surrender and seeing things at some great depth.
Some spiritual passion comes up, and you can jump 150 points in a moment.
Thank you.
Yes.
Presently, I'm a teacher at an urban middle school, public school.
Mm-hmm.
And I wanted to identify the critical factor to be able to teach the best I can teach.
To teach what?
This.
Yes.
The critical factor?
Is your willingness to be of service.
You see, the student feels your love for them.
And if you love them, they'll do anything for you.
Kids will do anything if you express that love to them.
Not avert.
You can't say, kid, I love you.
They'll think you're a pedophile.
No.
I had a mentor.
He was a professor at the teacher's college who lived across the street from my grandfather.
And he became a great friend.
And I was into entomology, and I had some great specimens.
We swapped specimens.
But that camaraderie between me as a student.
I was about 10 or 11 at that time.
And he was a full professor in the Department of Science at the teacher's college.
But that lasted me a lifetime.
And in later years, his son.
Who then became an internist.
He and myself became friends.
And so we've been friends forever since.
And so the value of some teacher in your life who allows you to experience the value of who you are.
I'd say the gift of being myself to the fullest extent I can to this child.
And let him know I appreciate his ambition and his interest.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Returning interest.
I can do that.
Professor Atwood would say, boy, that's some specimen you got there.
Well, my pride would just swell up, you know.
Luna moth about this big, you know.
Took me all night in the swamp to get it.
All night long in the swamp.
Yeah.
I want to know if it's for the highest good to move to Sedona.
I can't just say that like that.
It has to be a decision you make.
Yeah.
I don't know how to answer that for her.
I don't think I can answer that for her.
What do you want to come to Sedona for?
To be around the energy field.
To be around what?
The energy field.
For your own spiritual advancement.
Yeah, like holy.
You mean for your own spiritual advancement?
Like holy company?
So therefore, what is your question?
Is that a ?
No.
Yes.
To choose move for because of holy company.
Yeah.
What could be higher than that?
Okay.
Thank you.
That's a great motivation.
That's why many people came to Sedona.
They knew there was a certain spiritual energy.
Not the ooh, la, la, new agey.
But the actual.
Because even those who are misled are trapped in the glamour of all that.
There is a core of reality.
There's a core of reality that they really do want spiritual advancement.
And I always try to tell them, try and avoid the amusements along the way.
Just to save time, you know?
Yeah.
Thank you.
A great many people came to Sedona for that very reason.
Because of some spiritual pathways, some spiritual teacher, because of spiritual friends.
Yeah.
Hi.
How does one best surrender or transcend joy?
Joy?
Surrender or transcend joy?
Well.
In the back of the mind, there is, depending on your own spiritual trajectory.
In this mind, as exquisite as it was, was the knowingness that this too has to be laid down to the old Lord.
That came as a knowingness.
This too must be laid down to the old Lord.
And the state, it was the state that Ramakrishna also experienced.
It was exactly the same.
It was the same state.
And I saw that one could get attached to that state.
Attached to the being in a state of high joy.
And in fact, it was more than high joy.
It was ecstasy.
Ecstasy.
Timeless ecstasy.
And in this particular case, there was the knowingness that this too must be laid down,
given, surrendered to the old Lord.
And sometimes, like, the more I push it away, the stronger it gets.
Oh, don't push it away.
But.
I didn't say to push it away.
No.
I said become.
Become that joy.
Become that ecstasy.
And know that sooner or later, one will need to go beyond even that.
Okay.
No, don't push it away.
Don't resist it.
Become it to the fullest extent.
When I dance for you, I dance out of ecstasy and joy.
I don't repel it.
I don't refuse it.
It's exquisite.
It's beautiful.
It's.
It does itself.
It doesn't require any person to do it.
It's automatically doing it itself.
Facing the patterns in the air.
And becoming out of joy and ecstasy, the essence of that pattern.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Yes.
This question comes from Kansas, from my daughter and son-in-law.
Hi.
Hi!
I can't answer this, resist. No, I can't answer it. If it were me, I'd go for it, but I mean, you know, what more do you want?
Well, that's enough of an answer for them to go for it. They'll go for it.
Alaska is so incredibly beautiful, but you have to value the rural and the remote.
And they do.
Yes.
Oh, yes.
Right. They are aware of those limitations.
Yeah. It's a great place to be.
Thank you very much.
You learn how to fly.
I think bush planes all over the place.
That's right. There's no roads.
Yeah.
Yes.
I'm doing this spontaneously for the first time without writing this out.
I've had a lot of deeply held beliefs that I was unaware of from the unconscious that have been profoundly affecting my life.
And those are surfacing.
And a lot of those are from my experience with my biological father.
With your biological father?
With my biological father projected onto God.
Oh, uh-huh.
How do I surrender those?
Well, do you know which ones they are specifically?
Unforgiving.
Unforgiving, uh-huh. Judgmental, yeah.
Abandoning.
Uh-huh.
Rejecting.
But don't see God as a hero.
Yeah, God is not androgenic, so don't identify divinity as masculinity, because that which
is beyond gender, that which is the source of the universe is also beyond all gender
or is not going to be this way or that way, so in a way you're talking about anthropomorphic
depictions of God, cast in a paternalistic view, and that's my criticism of old time
religion and the Bible and all, is seeing God as some kind of an anthropomorphic projection,
so a temper, subject to jealousy and fits and punishing and all this kind of stuff.
I didn't even realize this, Dr. Williams.
No, I don't think that's too advanced in understanding of God, that's a very primitive
idea.
Yes.
That was a tribal culture on the other side of the world, thousands of years B.C., and
the concepts were appropriate for the time.
I like the concept of divinity of the American Indian native culture, much more benign, much
more also feminine, to be the source of the spirit of all of life and its expression as
nature and divinity and the animal forms.
You know, the spirit guides, the spirit guides to the various animal forms are a reality.
You know, there are spirit guides for each one, yeah, there are spirit guides for each
one.
Yeah, there's a condensation of spiritual energy of that animal's nature, and we wrote
about it in Power Versus Force, I think, energy fields, so what this animal knows is a radiation
of the knowingness of that field.
Yeah.
See?
So when it leaves the physical body, its spirit goes to the one spirit, because the animals
all have one spirit, and that's the god of the leopard, or the god of the monkeys, or
the gods, so these various gods, which is typical in Hinduism, those are energy power
fields, attractor fields.
The word I'm on is attractor field.
Okay.
That is the collective attractor field of that animal species, and it makes sense to,
again, the pantheon of gods of Hinduism makes sense, because there are energy constellations,
you see, which represent that animal knowingness, that animal way of beingness, and that type
of animal grace, you see?
Each animal has its own grace, even though it may look terrible to you, that is its grace.
Yes.
Better to eat you, my dear.
Okay.
Yeah.
So Native American and Hindu pantheons, you know, get the energy field of the, the attractor
energy field of those life forms, and they are valid.
They are valid.
Thank you.
That's why you don't want to get them mad.
Okay.
I'll work harder.
Thank you.
Yes.
Welcome.
Thank you so much, good to see you.
I wanted to ask.
If you had any thing to say, or any particular advice for me as a young gay man on the spiritual
pathway.
Uh-huh.
It seems very complicated.
Yes, it does.
And the politicalization of today's world, and the legalities, I grew up to consider
platonic love a valid.
Intense, sometimes far more intense than heterosexual love.
And some degree of it is innate to being in the service, where the bonding, and the loyalty,
and the love of the men for each other can be very, very powerful and very strong.
And I consider that legitimate.
Whether one gets into sexualization brings up a whole new thing.
The seven deadly sins, one of them is lust.
Therefore.
To surrender the lust aspect, you know, to supplement the lust aspect, try to make it
more of a Hellenic classic, the love between men was celebrated in those days.
Celebrated.
Right.
Platonic love.
So, platonic love is an ideal.
Ideal.
Uh-huh.
And if it were my own condition, I would strive for that.
Okay.
And I would also use this as maybe an opportunity to transcend something that other men are really
stuck in, and that is lust itself, or its own sake.
So, you could look at it as an opportunity to let go.
Now, the way you transcend lust, or any desire, you'll find that every desire, whether this
is for alcohol, for drugs, for sexuality, comes up first as an image in the mind.
Uh-huh.
If you don't first get the thing, you first have an image, and if you're quick enough,
you'll see it.
You say, no, I don't get an image of it.
I thought of a drink, it just was in my mind.
Yes, it was the thought of a drink.
What happens is the thought of a desire comes up first.
Now, you can eliminate that thought the instant it's there.
If you allow it to linger, it will draw more and more energy, and finally, it will reach
a point where you cannot say no to it.
That's the secret of how to overcome any addiction.
Uh-huh.
What I see happen with some people, gay people, is they get addicted to sexuality and carnality
for its own sake.
The downside, then, is to get sucked into sensory pleasure and carnality.
The upside is the opportunity to transcend that and deny that, and that's the Hellenic
tradition, where the sports figures were the great figures of the time, and where the love
of one man for another was traditional.
That's the way I'd hold it, in my own understanding and my own development of it.
Read some Plato.
What is it?
Thank you.
Platonic love means non-sensual, non-you call indulgent of the senses, non-whatever.
Whatever you call it.
You can eat for survival, or you can eat out of gluttony.
So I see sometimes gay couples fall into what I would call sensual gluttony in the experiential
framing of it.
And some I've known for many years, and they're, you know, the same as an ordinary married
couple of any kind.
Helpful, helpful teammates, loyal, and forever.
Thank you.
No.
Yeah.
No questions.
Right.
Now that I'm here, I know a lot less than I used to.
I know a lot less than I did before I moved here.
I seem to be reacting to everything in my life.
I have my little mental commentaries going on.
I react emotionally to everything, and I can't tell.
I look at things, I can't tell what's real, and what's just the way I'm interpreting it.
And I just need a little help getting it in context, because I'm just nothing but reactions
lately.
Emotionally reacting to everything?
Yeah.
So how do you become detached?
Why do you emotionalize everything?
Why do I?
Hmm.
Yeah.
So that's just a habit.
You can't just look at a dead mouse on the floor and say, oh, it's a dead mouse.
Surrender the theatrics and the drama.
Stop being a drama queen.
Yeah.
I don't have to dramatize everything.
Everything.
No.
In order to experience a thing and see what it is, you don't have to dramatize it.
Sometimes people get to thinking that, oh, it's a dead mouse.
Yeah.
You don't have to be thinking that that's their duty as a woman.
You're supposed to dramatize.
No, you don't.
You can be detached and cool and cold and say, that's a mouse, so what?
So what?
So I'll pick them up.
What's the big deal?
You don't have to scream and faint and fall on the floor.
It's not all about me, probably.
Right?
Everything that happens is probably not all about me.
Yeah.
All right.
So what you're really complaining about is sort of excessive emotionalizing.
Yeah.
So I pray to God to help you transcend emotionalizing.
Pray to become more detached.
Intellectualize it and mentalize it.
See?
Emotionalizing it is coming up through the solar plexus.
Mentalizing it is bringing it up to the head.
So try to bypass the solar plexus and put it in the form of thought.
Thought.
What do you think about it, not what do you feel about it.
Okay.
The world doesn't care what you feel about it.
Do you know that?
I've noticed.
They really don't.
You like this?
Everybody says, yeah, that's well.
You say, I don't like that.
Oh, that's okay.
Now try doing, force the energy up, you know, from the solar plexus up into the mind.
The thinkingness chakra.
The mind thing.
The thinking.
To mentalize about it.
Okay.
Write a little mental thing about it.
Yeah.
It's just a practice.
It's just habit.
Thank you.
And it follows family traditions, cultural traditions, and you know.
Cultural styles.
Men don't have that problem.
The plan is, don't you have any feelings?
Well, that's what I was thinking about, Henrietta.
Yeah.
Ten days ago when I came here, I got direction from you that I haven't been able to get in four years for the treatment of the lower astral attacks on my daughter.
Okay.
And I wanted you to tell me about that.
And I wanted to thank you, Andrea, Dr. Kallenbach, and Susan, for the support.
I found a psychiatrist.
We're going this next week in Texas to see him.
The astral attacks have been very hard.
It's a biochemistry, it's a problem in brain chemistry and biochemical.
It's very easy to fix.
I watched her go into an attack on Friday, and for the very first time, she started to say, no, I rebuke you, and I refute you.
And all she could get out was no, and she got stuck into the state.
What would have lasted five minutes only lasted a minute.
Yes?
Yes.
And all she kept saying was no, no, no.
But in her mind, she was thinking, I rebuke you, and I refuse you in the name of Jesus Christ.
So she wanted to come meet this man that finally believed her that she's not crazy.
Okay.
You refute it, and you also biochemically block it.
Yes, sir.
Because anything wrong in the nervous system, the entity will use that.
Like unconsciousness, brain injury, drunkenness, those, that's the, you know.
So it's like the human becomes vulnerable then.
So you offset it.
So pharmacology, you're doing all the right things.
Yes, sir.
Yes.
She wanted to say thank you.
You're doing all the right things.
Thank you.
May we get a photo?
She'll be better.
She'll be all right.
These things can be awful when they happen.
But also, very often, you can find the solution, and the solution is often very simple.
You know, you can turn on a lot of these things.
A half a milligram a day of prolixin can turn it on and turn it off.
Thank you.
Something simple like that.
Sure enough.
All on the scissor, that way.
Okay.
Grab a photo, dear.
Yeah.
You can perforate an ulcer and take one tablet of something rather than the ulcer cures.
I mean.
So everything.
Everything is physical, mental, and spiritual.
So you take care of all three at the same time.
You hit it on all three levels.
She'll be all right.
I don't get any negative feeling around here.
She's going to be better.
Dr. Harkins.
Yeah.
Will you hold my hands while I ask this question?
Yes.
Thank you.
Often when I meditate, I'm beginning to become deeply relaxed.
My neck will go backwards like this as I relax, or it'll go to the side and contort like this.
I'm wondering if it's safe for me to let it do that, because that happens at the same time that,
you know, the meditative state is deepening.
Is it safe for me to do that?
Well, you can refuse it.
Right.
But what happens is when I change my body back to being upright, I lose the progress
that I had made the previous, like, four or five weeks.
Well, try breathing it up to a higher chakra.
Keep breathing it up to the crown chakra, the energy.
Keep breathing the energy up to the crown chakra.
I don't understand how to do that.
You breathe.
You picture the energy.
Where is the energy stuck when you're having this problem?
I don't understand how to do that.
You're afraid to stop what?
My body from going, like, so my neck will go backwards like this, because I've heard
that people go into psychotic states sometimes when their neck goes back like that.
I'm wondering whether it's okay.
Is that not so?
Okay.
Yes.
It's sometimes, and it's often, like, yeah.
Right.
Okay.
So what you want to do is when you feel that in there, picture it going up.
Picture it going up.
Yeah.
To your brain.
To the crown chakra.
Okay.
So don't concentrate on fixing the physical.
Concentrate on the breathing.
Well, it'll fix itself.
It'll fix itself, yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Yes.
Dr. Hawkins?
May I touch your feet in gratitude?
Yes.
And would you please touch my head again?
And what?
Touch your head.
Whatever you wish.
Whatever.
Good.
It serves.
It's fine.
Pleasure.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Oh.
So this is for you to be a servant, My встречe Servante, O Lord.
I give thanks for your divine devotion, your love for God, you know?
Thank you.
That is a tradition from India.
It's okay?
Yes.
You forgot to touch my head.
God bless you!
God blesses you now!
This is the Indian culture, you know?
Yeah.
I came all the way just to do this.
It was so important for me to do it.
Yes, I understand.
And last time I requested that you transmit no mind to me,
and you said it's been automatically done.
You said it already.
Oh, yes, yes.
Stay a little farther away from that.
Not so close to the mic.
Okay.
Yeah, that's better.
Yeah, you already have that energy field.
Yes.
Let's see.
Let's verify for her sake.
The energy field that you seek is already within your aura.
Resist.
Yeah, you got it last time.
Yes, you did that last time.
I just want to know if there's any real progress that I've made.
Oh, yes.
There are a lot of experiences I have where I just don't have any personal self,
you know, since the last year.
And I just feel like, who am I?
What am I kind of?
No, you're looking for answers.
You see?
You have precipitated by your decision and by your will a certain process.
Now, it's not up to you to question the process.
Okay.
All right.
Yeah.
If you get stupid and fall flat on the ground, that's the way the process is going.
Okay.
And if you go into a state of ecstasy, you have to put up with it.
That's the way it's going.
Okay.
And so sometimes, you know, I find it silly to use the personal word, personal I,
and because I know it's not real anymore.
Yes.
She knows this kind of word.
After a while, you become, what happens is speaking more and more in the third person.
Some people complain that I write that way, you know what I'm saying?
This happened, you know, and that happened.
It's like a third person report.
The desire came up to ride the bicycle and then the skill arose.
I don't say the desire came up immediately.
To ride the bicycle, the desire came up to learn how to ride a bicycle
and out of that, the bicycling skill arose.
It's like happening of its own spontaneously.
You don't need to constantly put the pronoun in.
Yes.
As you eliminate narcissism, the pronoun disappears.
You see that phenomena are happening.
Yes.
Yeah.
So sometimes, you know, it doesn't quite work when you're sitting in a dinner party or something.
When you're in what?
It doesn't work when you're in a dinner party.
Oh.
So what to do?
Well, you see the body starts to eat and enjoy the food.
Yes.
That's the body doing that.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Not your nose, not your ears.
Okay.
The senses are seeking gratification.
So you witness the senses seeking gratification.
And you know that's part of your animal nature.
See?
And without that, you would die.
If you don't get hungry and eat, you die.
Okay.
So the price of life is putting up with one's animal nature.
And you don't have to call it I.
Yeah.
So I can use, I can refrain from using the word I.
It's all right.
Yes.
Yeah.
Even in a social gathering.
That's a certain skill.
Yeah.
I know.
It's coming though, you know.
Yeah.
On its own.
To be polite, you use certain pronouns.
Oh, okay.
You see?
So.
But.
It won't bring my level of consciousness down, will it?
No.
No, you won't get dumber and dumber.
They have said I can only ask one question.
Yes.
But may I ask one more?
Oh.
If all the actions of the past, if all the actions of the past.
Yes.
Leave an impression forever.
What role.
What role does atonement or the earning of good karma or the undoing of bad karma play?
That's how you evolve.
So if you have a karmic debt, when you repay it, then your energy.
I always liken it to a magnetic field, see?
And you're like little iron filings.
And all, every decision you make affects the polarity.
One end is negative, the other end is positive, see?
So every time you say yes, oh, I'll forgive them, he didn't know any better.
The iron filing moves a little more in the positive direction.
And you say, well, I hate him.
I just think he's terrible.
Now you move a little bit more in this direction.
So your little iron filing is like constantly moving in the field of gravitational field
of the infinite field of consciousness, which is infinitely powerful.
So you don't need an arbitrary God who rewards.
You or gets mad at you.
That's the automatic consequence of that which you are.
Therefore, the justice of God is absolute.
You can only be in an infinitely powerful magnetic field exactly where you should be.
So every time you forgive somebody, your magnetic polarity moves a little more this way.
You move a little more towards God.
So moving towards God is of your own inner consent.
So God doesn't force anybody to do anything.
So may I give you the example?
I wasn't very kind to my son when he was little.
Yeah.
And but I understand that now.
And I'm being as loving as I possibly can be to him.
And I've explained it to him that, look, I didn't know what I was doing then.
Yeah.
And I'm sorry.
So does that original action still have an effect forever?
That's all you can do.
Okay.
So be it.
Thank you.
Yeah, I've addressed it.
So you had a limitation at one time.
You realize this.
You had a limitation.
I'm sorry.
I'm taking so long.
You don't know why you had that limitation either.
Good God.
Have you got a bus parked out in front there?
A bus?
Good God.
Okay, sweetheart.
I brought something for you.
Oh, thank you so much.
Someone who looks just like you.
Oh.
I'm going to save this, honey.
You put this right here, sweetheart.
All right.
That's for you.
Oh, my God.
Yeah, very pretty.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
I love you.
And you also.
Thank you so much.
Yeah.
All love is God's love.
Yep.
Oh, good.
No squeeze on the merchandise.
That's where they have that beautiful island they're building there, huh?
Yes.
And they're cute.
Yeah.
People from places like Dubai, they go, oh, yeah.
A billion, billion dollar extension of the building of the country.
They go, uh-huh.
And you're going to have the Queen Mary.
What do you mean, uh-huh?
Queen Mary, for God's sake.
Dubai is an interesting country.
Thank you once again on behalf of everyone.
Your presence is truly a blessing to us all here.
My question for you is my experience thus far is that there's a depth and a breadth to consciousness,
which you normally don't go into in the books.
But, for example, we have a relationship consciousness.
We have a space spiritual consciousness.
We have a.
We have a professional consciousness, and that all these things play a part.
Is that something that you'd care to comment on or write about?
They're not different consciousnesses.
It's just a consciousness of a certain level will express itself this way in this situation
and this way in this situation.
A person with a different level of consciousness would express themselves differently in the
same situations.
So they're not different.
They're how that one person responds to all those things.
He sees them as opportunity or resents them.
His obligations depends on how he sees it, or he sees it as a chance for camaraderie and good naturedness.
Yeah.
Thank you.
What's good for General Motors is good for the country.
Good.
That's what we used to say when I grew up.
What's good for General Motors is good for the country.
That was what we grew up with.
We're going to quickly.
Thank you.
Yeah.
When we pray to the Lord, does the Lord have to be a specific and an exclusive avatar?
I don't think so, because you know what you mean by it, and the Lord knows what you mean by it.
God's smart enough to know that he's Lord, and that you're trying to reach him.
I think that your intention already sets the level.
Your intention is already known.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yes.
Your intention is unmistakable.
Hello.
Good to be with you again.
Yes.
Lately, I'm crying.
And all the way up here, I've been reading the rest of this book, and part of the Yoga
Vesastha, and Chorus of Miracles, and it seems like the thing for me to do next is to stop
thinking.
Yes.
It's illegal in certain parts of the world.
But the first fear that comes up is that, Neil, you're not ready to do that yet.
To give up thinking?
Yeah.
And I don't want to, you know, get impatient and then come to a place where I've failed.
If you get a chance to give up thinking, by all means, take it.
Okay.
So I can't get ahead of myself then.
If you get a chance to give up thinking, do so.
Okay.
Everything from that point on is autonomous.
I don't have to think about what to say to you, do I?
No.
It comes right up.
I don't have to think about being here.
I don't have to think about that thing.
Right.
Okay.
Join me.
Give up thinking.
Okay.
I will.
Thank you.
A bad habit.
Yes.
I've been on the path for a lot of years, and I've had a lot of growth.
And in the past year, I think it's really been coming apart at the seams.
And I've really found that a lot of it has been, like, self-serving.
And I've been, like, throwing myself into the path to avoid dealing with issues and,
you know, with spiritual courage and integrity.
Yeah.
Okay.
And now they've really come up to be dealt with, and they're not going anywhere.
And, like, as I've been facing this, it's like, wow, I'm just, like, a really broken person.
Oh, you are.
You're a mess.
Yeah.
I just feel like...
You're a mess.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
And I feel like I failed you as a student.
Oh, God.
And I feel like...
I mean, seriously, though, like...
You come and made a mess out of yourself.
Yeah.
And I feel like, even though I see it, it's like,
there's just a weakness in my own will to, like, get through it.
I think you're expecting some kind of linear discipline progression of things.
It doesn't happen that way.
You go from chaos to collapse to failure to jubilation and then discouragement and then...
So, there's no way you can rate whether you're making progress or not.
Yeah.
When you finally make real progress,
the question doesn't even...
The question doesn't even arise whether you're making progress.
So, don't worry about it.
See, it's your intention and your alignment,
and the rest is not up to you.
Well, I think that's part that really worries me,
is, like, what are my intentions?
Some of it seems so self-serving a lot of the time.
Self-serving like what?
Worshiping worldly success, material success,
position in the world, special...
Well, those are all things you acknowledge is going on within yourself.
And you say that's normal for a certain age.
And each of those things, maybe you'll have to live it through a bit to decide.
There's nothing wrong with it.
Nothing wrong with it.
I think in the Bible it says,
don't want worldly success.
Yeah.
Just that a rich man can't get through the eye of the needle, that's all.
You have a shortage of poverty.
Yeah.
He's suffering from a poverty shortage.
Well, thank you.
Don't worry about it.
See, if you weren't okay, you would.
You wouldn't be worrying about it.
I know.
Yeah.
I know, Dr. Hawkins.
Susan Hurd.
Uh-huh.
I've come from Dublin to see you, so I'm very pleased to be here.
Dublin, Ireland.
Yes, yes.
You thought it was in Iowa, not in Iowa.
She thought Dublin was in Iowa.
In Iowa.
Yeah, go ahead.
My question is, it has changed.
It has changed as I was standing up there.
You calibrated homeopathy in truth versus falsehood as 200 and over the years, I'm a medical physician
as well, and over the years I've had a lot of contact with homeopaths who have had miraculous
results with homeopathy where I know that ordinary medicine wouldn't have been able
to affect.
So I'm just...
What about it?
I'm wondering, how come it calibrates at 200?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I didn't calibrate it.
Oh, I didn't calibrate it.
Homeopathy?
I didn't make it be that way.
It's probably talking about the scientific theory of it.
Is that what you calibrated?
This week's newspapers are full of deaths by homeopaths doing liposuction, five or six
of them losing their licenses from not knowing what they can do and what they can't do.
So if you talk about public image in this week's Arizona Republic, it's not so great.
What aspect of homeopathy did you calibrate?
I just talked about homeopathy.
Homeopathy as a theory, you see, as a...
Any practice in certain practitioner's hands is excellent.
Okay.
The same practice in an idiot's hands is, you know, terrible, so homeopathy as a field
of science.
Homeopathy as a field of science doesn't measure up rationally.
The effects of it, though, are...
You're talking about two different things.
Okay.
We have permission to do homeopathy.
It's okay.
It's over 200.
205.
It's at 200.
Homeopathy is 200, so that means the result is more likely intention.
Intention.
The intention of the patient, the intention of the doctor is probably going to bring about.
That has to do with the law of similars, does it not?
Yes.
All right.
So let's do the law of similars.
The law of similars calibrates over 200, is this?
205.
210.
Yeah, the law of similars is about 205.
Okay.
Don't ask me why.
Yeah, I understand that.
I don't have any money in the market, do I?
Yeah, yeah, I understand that.
I don't have any position about homeopathy.
All right, I understand that.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
If I'm suffering from an incurable disease, I want to see everybody, including every
homeopath in town.
All right.
Yeah.
Well, Western medicine, like, calibrates at 450, 460.
Western medicine.
460, whatever it is.
Oh.
440.
Academic medicine.
Yeah.
440.
Academic medicine.
All right.
Clinical medicine.
445.
Yeah.
All right.
Okay.
That's enough.
Thank you very much.
Yes.
No, just because .
No.
No, I'm not.
I understand that.
That's not what I mean.
It's not negative.
I'm talking about it's effective.
It seems to be more effective than a lot of orthodox medicine, especially for
chronic disease.
Depends on how vast your experience is.
Right.
We could say you were .
Yeah.
Yes.
I think your dedication to the patient carries more weight than the mechanics of what you
give them.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
There are a lot of very dedicated homeopaths, that's for sure.
Yeah.
Some doctors can get more cures with distilled water than others can with the world's best
medicines.
Yes.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
We both .
I believe you.
Thank you very much.
We've both seen homeopathic physicians .
Okay.
Thank you.
When something ails me, I'm going to see everybody from top to bottom.
Chiropractor, homeopath, physician, surgeon.
Well, what do you want me to do?
Anybody got anything crucial that you can make short?
We're going to hurry up.
You can't spend forever coming up here.
Let's go.
Now.
Real quick.
Up.
Um.
Yep.
What?
Keep it short and sweet.
Okay.
What?
My father, just last month, I bring my father to a house for Alzheimer and my
spouse also bring her mother to Alzheimer's place.
You know what he's saying.
Alzheimer.
Alzheimer's.
Yeah.
Alzheimer's got its Alzheimer.
Alzheimer.
Yeah.
So.
. . Yeah.
and bring your father and your mother there.
Yes.
My question is, is it a nightmare for them?
No.
No?
Only for you.
Only for me?
Yeah.
The suffering is on the part of the witness,
not on the part of the Alzheimer patient.
So we don't have to worry about them?
No.
They are taken care of?
No, I've checked that out extensively.
Okay.
I was the only doctor who was willing to go to the nursing homes
in the whole Yavapai County.
So I get through with seeing patients in Periscope,
and I then hit every nursing home in the county all the way home.
Over and over again, it was always the same.
The family was upset by the Alzheimer patient.
And I would interview the Alzheimer patient.
I'd say, how are you today?
Oh, hello, dearie, I'm fine.
You got any complaints today?
No.
Is the food all right?
Oh, they're very nice to me.
Consistently, I got that from, I would say, 100% of the patients.
Okay.
But are their soul out of their body?
Are they gone?
That's true.
They're not there.
They are not there?
No.
The spirit has already gone over to the other side.
The body stays here.
The family gets upset.
If you ask the patient, you know, if I ask the patient, how are you today?
Oh, I'm fine.
How do they treat you here?
They're very nice to me.
I have never heard a complaint.
All the sobbing and maudling and carrying on and drama is the family.
It's the family drama.
Oh, poor old daddy.
He's lost his mind.
And I say to dad, how are you, dad?
Fine, fine.
Why are you asking me?
I'm just wondering since you've been here a little while.
Oh, I have, eh?
Oh, oh, oh.
So, only the envelope stay there.
Don't worry about it.
Okay.
God takes care of them.
Yep.
Alzheimer's is painless.
Thank you.
I'll just bring you something.
A sweet maple syrup from Montreal.
Oh.
To enjoy with you.
Montreal.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, that's the real stuff.
Thank you.
That's the real stuff.
Oh, oh, oh.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Yeah, the suffering with Alzheimer's is in the witness, not the subject.
Thank you very much.
I've never heard anyone complain.
Yeah.
And if they do complain, it's not due to the Alzheimer's, it's due to something else.
I was just wondering if you would calibrate that book for me.
No, I don't want to.
No.
I figured it would be fast.
No, I'll tell you.
There's too much feedback.
I'm sorry.
Everybody has to keep their mouth shut or what they know to themself.
If I calibrate this, what's going to happen is it's going to be on the internet within
24 hours and 82 people will object to what's being said, and I've learned the hard way
not to do it.
Okay.
Thank you anyway, Doctor.
Nobody can keep their own counsel anymore.
Yeah.
Is it relevant to no one's own calibration, and if so, why?
Is it what?
Relevant to no one.
Oh, it's not really very helpful, no.
You know, if you look at the levels of consciousness, you'll intuit approximately where you are.
Okay.
You're either angry all the time, or you're flat or disinterested, or you feel depressed.
Look where I am.
Where am I on the thing?
You see?
And there's ways, you know, you can test kinesiology yourself.
You know, you can say, you know, there's a closed ring finger, you know.
The other way is to just hold a bunch of heavy dictionaries and say, my consciousness level
is over 200.
And if it is, you'll see the weight, the books weigh something.
My consciousness level is over 300.
Yeah?
My consciousness level is over 800.
The simplest way is you'll notice that your strength, your strength fluctuates.
So with a little practice, you can do it all by yourself, just lifting books.
Right.
Yeah.
So it's just so you'll know that, because your level of...
Okay.
Yeah.
Enthusiasm.
400 is more hard.
400 is reading a book.
The 300 is being a volunteer fireman.
Okay.
So you just sort of sense where you are.
Right.
Yeah.
You just sort of sense it, you know.
You just keep going straight ahead no matter what.
Right.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Yes.
Have you found in a love relationship between a man and a woman that there needs to be
some range of...
Consciousness level for it to be enduring?
I haven't noticed that.
No.
People who are quite the spirit can get along with each other.
Look at Socrates and his wife, Zantippe.
Hmm.
So it could be a wide range, huh?
Yeah.
Well, they...
Most couples will accommodate to each other and balance it out.
If it's too far out of line, that relationship won't last, you know.
Won't last.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Because you learn from each other either way, you know.
She's back.
That's going to cost you a dollar now.
Flippo.
Okay.
Thank you, George.
We're all done.
No.
You got to run faster.
You're too slow.
Why are you guys so slow over there?
Thank you.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
I just wanted to sit in front of you and tell you thank you and I love you and God bless
you for everything you've done for me.
Good.
Thank you very much.
You've transformed my life.
Thank you.
Thank you for your love.
That's it.
Thank you.
That's my pleasure.
Yes.
Exactly the same.
Thank you very much.
That's my pleasure.
God bless.
Thank you very much.
We're saving dessert for the end here, huh?
Oh, yeah.
Hello.
Yeah.
Thank you very much for your lecture.
Yes.
What I got was when you dealt with your demons, that moment of despair, what you got was
the way out was to verify the sanctity of your own life.
Did I get that right?
And how do you ...
Well, no, that came as a greater understanding later on.
I don't know what you're referring to now.
Well, how do you recommend verifying the sanctity of your own life?
What's a good way to get that?
Verify it?
Yeah.
You don't have to verify it.
Just take my word for it.
Nothing exists without except by divine ordinance.
Nothing exists without divine ordinance.
Consequently, you exist only as a consequence of divine ordinance.
Okay.
Unless you're capable of spontaneous combustion or something.
Thank you.
All that exists does so by virtue of divine grace.
Divine grace, which is called divine ordinance.
Yes?
I hug everyone in this room.
And I give thanks to almighty God for the gift of all of you.
And don't forget that we are all one.
That we come into this world together, you know, over a couple decades.
In my time dimension, that's the same time.
Over 50 years or so, it's the same time.
We all come in together.
And we all leave together.
And we all do this as a unison.
We all do this as a unison.
You see?
And the fear of death is the fear of death.
And the fear of death is really not, is the fear of separation.
I told you about this during World War II.
And this mine was going to go off.
And he said, what if it goes off?
We'll die.
And I said, well, no.
He said, what will happen if it explodes?
And I said, well, we'll die.
And he looked at me and said, yeah.
Because he got.
We wouldn't die alone.
We will die together.
So look at the, I want you to get rid of the fear of death.
It's not a fear of dying.
It's a fear of being alone.
Well, being committed to a group like this is not possible to be alone.
You know what I mean?
It is impossible.
So none of us are ever going to be separated.
It's not a fear of death.
It's a fear of separation.
That's what it is.
You see?
So anyway, God bless you all.
And I give thanks.
You are God's gift to me.
Thank you, God.
And the world's lucky that we're here, too.
When we give them the bill.
Saving the bill, the world.
100 trillion trillion dollars.
OK.
I'm submitting a bill.
All right.