Okay. One of your famous sayings is that love is beyond duality.
What? Yes.
I wanted to ask, what is the fastest way to get there?
There's no place to get.
You just realize that is innate to your own reality
and just acknowledge that it is innate to that which you are.
Don't you love like beetles?
Sorry? Oh, yes, I do.
At first, love is only discovered where it's most intense and obvious,
very often interpersonal.
And then after a while, you realize that you love life, you love nature,
you love all the kitties, you love all the doggies,
and that you love life, you know, the experience of life itself,
that you love life, yes?
So lovingness, you identify with more and more
when you realize that it is already a reality and a capacity
and all you have to do is own it.
It's not something new.
You love yourself?
Sometimes.
You love yourself right now?
It's hard not to.
Huh?
Right.
You love yourself enough to come up in front of an audience
and ask a question, don't you?
So that's your answer.
It's just what you are.
Just own that.
It's your nature.
All right?
Yeah, thank you.
That's something you have to get or develop or acquire.
Thank you so much.
It already exists.
If you didn't love,
life should expire already.
There you go.
Yes?
I had to write this one down.
Oh.
Uh-oh.
I didn't flub it up.
I asked this question for all of us
who are dealing with or trying to understand
the guilt and shame associated with masturbation.
Yes.
It's come up a lot lately in conversations
and I said, you know what?
I'm going to talk to you about it.
Well, let's see.
That has a long history, see?
It has a long history and a biblical history
and one of the seven deadly sins is, you know, lust.
Lust, lust.
I myself consider it, you know, relatively irrelevant.
Well, I mean, it's not bringing harm to anyone.
Okay.
So why is it decried in the first place?
I mean...
I'm sorry?
I mean, why did mankind get into such a make-wrong
about it in the first place?
That's my question.
Because they didn't know any better.
Well, lust.
Because lust then becomes an attachment.
An attachment.
It's a normal physiologic phenomenon.
And, of course, nowadays people don't...
When I grew up, you know,
your father would leave you a book quietly
in your dresser drawer about...
My dad didn't meet your dad.
Well, you missed a great book, you know.
The evil, the evils.
Of self-abuse.
And then if you continue it,
then they would describe somebody in a mental hospital
who was a feeble-minded idiot.
Oh, that kind of book.
And associated with syphilis.
So somehow if you did that,
you would end up feeble-minded.
And you can't stop doing it,
and they had to put him in a cell.
You know what I'm saying?
So in those days, it was thought it led to insanity.
I remember when I started at...
I started at a state hospital.
Oh, yes, Manhattan.
I was not an inmate.
I was a psychiatrist on the staff
at Manhattan State Hospital.
It was right under the Triborough Bridge.
And off the Triborough Bridge,
you can take an exit called Ward's Island,
and you circle down,
and here's an island underneath the bridge,
right in the middle of New York City,
completely removed from the rest of the world.
It's its own world.
Manhattan State Hospital.
And in the state hospital,
I saw a lot of cases, of course,
and their case history was there.
Well, some people have been there
since, like, the 1920s, you see.
And then on the front of the chart,
it always gave you the probable cause of the disorder.
And it would say self-abuse.
Yes.
This guy's advanced schizophrenia
with massive personality deterioration.
And the contributing or causative factor
was called the masturbation.
So it led to insanity, yeah?
Yeah.
Thanks for helping me through that one, Doc.
No, it's being trapped in sensuality.
Don't forget the Buddha said,
the first thing you've got to let go of
is your attachment to sensual pleasure.
So it's an attachment to sensuality,
short-circuiting one's growth and development.
Yeah.
But it was greatly overplayed, of course.
And don't forget, all that came out of the Victorian age,
when it was indecent to have
the naked leg of a table.
You'd have to have a drape over the leg of a table,
don't forget.
So it's very Victorian.
Well, I'm trying to behave myself.
Very Victorian.
Thank you, sir.
Yes.
It's very Victorian.
Well, all forms of sex were foreboding
in the Victorian era, except marital.
Hi, Susan.
Hi, Doc.
Yes.
Could you speak about transcending dualities?
And rather,
can we talk about the generality of it,
rather than specifics?
I mean, I've gotten through the one about
who's doing the healing work
between the small self and the big self.
And there's stuff coming up about
thinking this.
Oh, it's identification with the initiator.
It's seeing yourself as the source
and the initiator of volition.
See?
And you don't realize that these phenomena
are happening of their own.
There's the assumption
that there is a personal pronoun,
me, a self,
as the doer and the originator and the decider.
And you'll realize,
if you keep looking at it and meditating on it,
that that's a narcissistic presumption
and that no such entity exists.
Well, you also talked about
that every thought that you come through your mind
is counted.
And also, at another time,
you've spoken about how the thoughts are not ours.
And so we're not responsible for that.
At another time, wait a minute, don't jump around.
At another time, what?
You said that the thoughts are not ours,
that the thoughts are happening on their own.
Oh, that's true.
That's thinkingness.
When you're enlightened, they don't count anymore.
But when you're not enlightened, they count plenty.
So, can you...
That's how you develop karma, right?
Okay.
To be enlightened is to be beyond karma.
See, because you realize
that you are not the source of the author.
These phenomena are happening of their own.
Thinkingness is happening of its own.
Okay.
There is no you, personal self,
that is doing this thinkingness.
Thinkingness is happening autonomously
and spontaneously of its own.
And then you presume that you're the author
because it's on your TV set.
Okay.
So, then we're letting go of the...
Authorship.
The authorship.
That's it.
The phenomena are happening of their own.
They don't care a whit about you, actually.
Okay.
So, then to what end?
To what level are we responsible
for those thoughts that do come through?
Oh, until you transcend them.
Until we let go of the authorship of them.
There you got it.
Ah, okay.
So, the purpose of enlightenment
is to transcend karmic consequences.
Great.
Thank you.
All those phenomena are happening of their own,
including the presumption
that they are originating from you.
That's also happening of its own.
So, once you see through that hooker,
you get off it.
Gotcha.
The presumption that you are,
there's a personal you causing all this,
is already an autonomous phenomena happening of its own.
Thank you.
Due to mental insanity.
Hi.
Yes.
Yeah, my question is about...
I've been noticing that I get really stuck in my head
and I analyze things to death.
Like, I'm very analytical.
And there's lots of questions
and they just kind of keep going around.
And I notice that it's always...
The basis, you know,
they're kind of masked by the question of why.
And my question is how to bypass it
and just be like, okay, you know, it just is.
Well, the mind gets enamored of its own thinkingness.
Yeah.
It gets hypnotized by it.
And so, it takes some subtlety of meditation
to let go the attraction of the pleasure of thinkingness
as amusement,
as the feeling that you...
that you are doing something by...
or that you're getting some place.
Thinkingness can be let go as like a bad habit.
It's not necessary to think at all, yeah?
Because everything is happening autonomously.
So, there's the presumption that it's a requirement for life, you see?
As I'm talking to you, I'm not giving this last thought
to what I'm saying.
I don't even know what I'm talking about.
Is that okay?
I trust that...
The knowingness gets what the question is
and that the knowingness will respond, you see,
within the appropriate context, huh?
So, it's an addiction, let go of the thinkingness.
You'll see that all the purpose of thinkingness, amusement,
the idea that you're achieving goals,
that you're getting some place, that you're learning something, yeah?
Mm-hmm.
So, it's a lot to let go of to transcend thinkingness,
but it is possible.
And it long lasts, the mind becomes silent.
Then you realize it always was silent.
That which is you doesn't think.
It witnesses thinking.
Then identifies it as me.
It's not you, you know?
It belongs to you, but it isn't what you are, who you are.
So, meditate with that.
There was one time I had this experience where that seemed to happen
where like there was less identification with the body and,
and like thoughts were just happening of their own and I was just watching.
They're all happening spontaneously.
Yeah, and everything was really beautiful.
I mean, there was just a change of everything.
Yeah, you get the sense of it.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
So, you walk through the woods, the birds are singing,
you're not making them sing.
The sun is shining, you're not making it shine.
The leaves are crunching on the grass,
you're not making them crunch on the grass.
You're not making anything happen.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Including being aware that you're walking through the woods.
That's happening of its own.
You don't say to yourself, gee, I wonder what I'm doing now.
Oh dear, I guess I must be walking through the woods.
That's not necessary.
You automatically know it.
So, the, the trick then is, is not to eliminate thoughts, but
stop verbalizing them.
You don't have to turn it into language.
Oh, what a nice day it is out here in the woods to see the squirrels playing with
the acorns in the trees.
Okay, okay.
So, stop boring yourself with verbalization.
Okay.
Yeah.
You don't have to verbalize about it.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
I mean, you get it.
You got it.
Incredibly perfect day.
You don't have to say, oh my, what a beautiful day.
Okay, so trust in the autonomous.
Okay.
Quality that the mind has the, the capacity to get it in one instant.
It gets it, what it's all about.
Yeah. Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Yep.
Yes.
Yes, sir.
I came back with an update on my
daughter since we were here last.
Yes.
The demonic possessions have changed.
They went away for ten days, and when they came back, it's no longer her being told
to kill herself.
She has not attempted that again.
But now, more so, the demons are telling her to kill me.
So, and it's pretty much constant every night in her sleeps.
This is the third psychiatrist that we went to see.
All were appropriate and integrous.
The first one, over 200?
This first one, what?
The first one tried to institute, well, wanted to institutionalize.
Oh, yeah, put her in a hospital?
No, both of us, actually.
And then the second one ended up not being appropriate.
He wanted to treat her epilepsy and said her psychosis was basically in my head.
So this third psychiatrist has given us a new drug, but the possessions are still happening
in that they're all, they're all directed at her killing me.
So, what I ask of you now is, what do you do?
What do you do?
I believe this doctor is appropriate, Dr. Hawkins.
I believe she is integrous to treat my daughter, and that this new medication is an antipsychotic,
as you suggested.
Right.
And it's still not working, and it seemed to have heightened in that they don't want
her to hurt anyone else but me.
To the point of, I did put bolts on my doors, but I went ahead and let her sleep with me
so that I could show her that I'm not afraid, that even if she does kill me, that's okay.
It's okay if you're going to kill her.
Okay.
It's my karmic inheritance, right?
What do I tell her?
I do not know.
I don't know.
Anyway, what kind of medication is she on?
Abilify.
Uh-huh.
And it was Risperdil.
Up until seven days ago, it was Risperdil, and now it's Abilify.
Oh, okay.
That's fine.
All right.
So it's a matter of adjusting doses, and some of these things take, and some of these take
several months.
Yes, sir.
Several months.
And sugar-free diet helps.
Yes, sir.
Okay.
And big doses of vitamin B, B3 especially, and then the rest is a matter of time, a matter
of time.
She is terrified that she's going to get sent to the depths of hell like you.
She was at your last lecture, so she understands when you told that story, and she's juicing
the fact that that's where she's going to end up if she kills herself or me.
So I need to reassure her that she has the choice to ask God for mercy.
Yes.
All right.
So you're treating a mental illness.
It takes patience.
Some of them are slow to respond.
You've got to get the dose right.
Keep raising the dose a little at a time until the symptoms should diminish.
Yes, sir.
That's what I would do.
Just keep raising the dose until you get out of the response you want.
Last time I was...
There's a certain threshold.
Once you get beyond that therapeutic threshold, you should see an improvement.
Yes?
I saw an improvement for 10 days.
So I've seen a change.
Yes, sir.
improvement but when it plummeted it went right when it when it when it turned
back around in the position started it was magnified a new wave 10 intensified
oh I can tell you is you try a one or two different medications but within the
same class of anti-psychotics then you adjust the dose if you don't get a
recovery on half a milligram a day of prolixin you go to one milligram if you
don't get it on that you go to two milligrams I mean you know it's just a
matter of professional skill doctors don't like to be told what to do what
when I've suggested prolixin or something like it I've been met with
contempt except for the last doctor they've all told me well it's an old drug
there's newer better ones so I guess there's no better ones but I just gave
that as an example yes sir all right so then it's a matter of adjusting the dose
to find the therapeutic range
the last time I was here I think Andrea and you both and dr. Kallenbach but what
I felt to express was my gratitude to the hundreds of people that have been in
your lecture so what I get right now is that because your mother Mia hold your
hand and I wanted to tell you thank you for helping me yeah and believing in me
all right now here's what you do is try to talk them into going to a higher dose
If it's a man or a lady, I don't know.
It's a lady.
Yeah.
Look, I'm willing to take the risk of a higher dose
because there's a certain therapeutic range,
and you may get nothing,
and then once you break through a therapeutic range,
suddenly the whole thing will disappear.
So I would let her know you're willing to experiment
with maybe stronger doses, you know,
to at least eliminate that as a possibility.
But very often, the psychosis will prevail
on half a milligram a day or something
when you get up to three-quarter or one milligram disappears.
So you can be just below the therapeutic threshold.
It's hard to work with psychiatrists.
I don't know.
Some of them are really so stupid.
I don't know how they stay in practice.
They really are.
Yes, there are.
I mean, yeah, you know,
every patient is a research project, everyone,
because everyone is different.
You don't know what combination of meds
and what dosages they're going to respond to.
You can hang out at one milligram
and they stay completely psychotic,
and at two milligrams,
the whole thing disappears.
So why not experiment and go up to two milligrams
and see what the heck happens?
When the dosage is right, I get my daughter back.
When the dose is right,
we have great hopes that the phenomenon will disappear.
Yeah.
So trying to get a doctor who's willing to go along with you
and say, you know, I'm not going to be able to rest
until we've tried maybe a stronger dose.
Yeah, I'm relentless.
They're clear on that.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
And everybody here.
Any patient doesn't get better on one dose.
You go a little higher and they go random remissions.
Yes.
Hi.
I have a question about a sentence in this one.
Yeah.
It is best to speak to the inner conscience
and commit it to becoming a useful ally and teacher
rather than a sadistic self-perpetrator.
Yes.
And I made such an intention,
and I don't think it listened very well.
And currently...
Your ego is sadistic, right?
It gets pleasure out of punishing you
and causing you pain and suffering.
Yeah.
Is that correct?
You'll have to deprive it of that pleasure
and teach it that it's being wicked by doing that.
Can you clarify, teach it that it's being wicked?
What?
Can you clarify that a little more?
How do I teach it?
How do I teach it that it's being wrong?
Oh, well, I'm talking to it right now.
Right now, you talk to it.
I mean, you know, the conscience is supposed to be your guide,
not your tormentor.
Thank you.
Not supposed to be your prosecutor.
Or persecutor.
It's supposed to be a helpful guide between right and wrong.
And you can't give it full reign or that much credence
because it isn't all that smart to begin with.
Thank you.
I have one more quick question.
Is hypnotherapy...
Yes.
I'm Tegress.
Mm-hmm.
You can give your superego a name.
Harold.
Okay.
Okay, Harold.
I hear you.
And I didn't ask you to become a sadist or a weirdo.
Thank you.
You have to talk to it like a Dutch uncle.
Thank you again.
You see, the superego is one's incorporated parental voice.
Are you listening to me?
Harold is listening.
The superego is one's internalized parent.
So that gives you a different way to deal with this overzealous parent
who's overdoing his job.
You talk to it like an overzealous parent, like you're a counselor.
You're supposed to be a guide, not a crucifier or a punisher.
Okay?
You've got to talk it into being more rational.
Thank you again.
Yeah.
You have to get rough with them once in a while.
Dutch uncle.
You're not going to put up with abuse from them.
We value your guidance, but not your abuse.
Yeah.
Dr. Hawkins, when I came across your teaching a couple of years ago,
I was reasonably reclusive, and I thought would become more so,
but actually becoming more and more active and extrovert and out in the world.
And it's been more enjoyable.
And my prayer for the last many months has been, you know,
I'm not going to be able to do it again.
And my prayer for the last many months has been to be more committed
to the path of devotion and truth in that process so that that would be there in activity.
And I wanted to state that prayer in your presence out loud.
Oh, good.
Thank you.
Yes?
My question has to do with what you were saying about marketing this morning.
And previously, marketing is usually on the level of 100 and 125.
And my question is how to do marketing
in an integral way?
Yeah.
How do you do marketing in an integral way?
Marketing?
Marketing.
You were talking about advertising.
Oh, advertising.
Yes. Advertising, a few of them know what they're doing.
And the rest of them seem to be totally blind to what they're doing.
Some ads are attractive and enhance the project, their product, you know.
Let's take Geico, right?
They're nothing cuter than the Geico guy walking around and all the Geico ads.
You know, Geico, Geico, yeah.
Well, no, it's Geico.
It sure is kind of, yeah.
But it's a Geico.
Oh, it's a Geico for Geico.
Now, there are some products that by sheer repetition
and the dumbness of the advertisement create an aversion.
They don't realize that they're creating an aversion to their product.
Well, I didn't know.
I never liked the A-flag duck.
But, you know, there's a bank and a banking firm that comes on.
And I'm glad to see that.
I'm glad to see they've taken big losses in this last dump.
They deserve it.
I mean, this idiot comes on with his rap.
And then the advertisement immediately turns out and immediately replays itself, you know.
Is there a way to do advertising in an integrous ways?
Well, integrous means a little bit different in advertising than, you know.
First of all, the person says they've recovered something.
I mean, they're not using such and such a product.
If they're lying or not convincing, they get an actor or an actress to say,
oh, how so-and-so cured my acne.
She never had acne, for God's sake.
She's lying.
So there isn't the ring of truth.
The energy field of truth is not there.
I want somebody who actually recovered from an actual disease
that was making your life miserable with this product.
Now when he tells me, you know, that solved my acne, I believe the guy.
You know, I used to be a pimply mess, and now the girl's all smiling at me.
So it should be truthful to be convincing,
because the energy field of a lie is below 200 is not very convincing.
And then some of them just suffer from sheer lack of IQ on the part of the designers.
But I also thought it would be great fun to show people how to get more for your money,
because they spend big money.
And to me, they get a poor return on their money, frankly.
I'm in the process of creating advertising and marketing right now.
Yes.
So I was wondering what some of you are doing.
What are some of your suggestions might be?
Yeah.
No, it's a real fun thing.
And also, various parts of an ad may create a version.
This part of the ad is attractive, but this part of the ad creates an aversion.
So you have people look at the various parts of the ad.
How do you feel about that?
And calibrate the energy of it, yes?
I think marketing would be great fun.
I'd like to see people get more miles for their dollar, because they put big money there.
And the company that puts on the ad, I mean, they don't care what's,
the content of the ad, because they're getting paid so much per minute, you know?
Yeah.
Thank you.
Yeah, that's a fun thing.
Hi.
I've been through some serious trauma recently, mostly.
But in my life as a total, it's getting to a peak right now.
And I feel like if I don't do something to semi-heal myself to an extent,
then I'm going to fall too far to come back.
And I'm wondering if you have any advice.
What kind of trauma are you talking about?
Well, I've had a lot of family issues.
I've been homeless on and off for years.
I've been abused for a long time.
Uh-huh.
Do you have any working relationships right now?
Yes.
You got friends?
Oh, okay.
I have things working to the best they've been in about six years.
I'm just trying to figure out what was my next step.
What do you think is the best bet for me to...
As regards what?
To come to some kind of realization of what terms I need to keep to keep myself from slipping back or...
Slipping back to what? Robbing banks?
Something, no, something that I can't, no, like...
Suicide, what?
Yeah, like feelings of suicide or feelings that I just am too deep in despair to do anything with myself.
It's like depression, is that what you're talking about?
Or drugs or whatever it may be.
You're talking about depression?
Yes.
I have a serious problem with depression.
So are you taking any antidepressants?
No, they won't put me on antidepressants.
Well, first of all, I'm very sensitive to the medications.
And when I take the antidepressants, the stimulant in them kind of makes me...
Agitated?
Too up to date.
Yeah, like...
Yeah, yeah, uh-huh.
Angry, so...
Well, then it's a matter of working on yourself psychologically, being in every kind of therapy you can be, individual and group.
Any 12-step groups you belong to?
I've done that for years.
Yeah.
I don't belong to any right now because I just moved, but...
Oh.
I'd like to get back into it.
Yes, that's all you can do is a total push.
You know, whatever medications work the best, whatever 12-step groups, recovery groups, associating with friends.
What do you do for an occupation?
You work?
No, not lately, but I've worked many, many, many jobs.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Why aren't you working?
What are you on, welfare or what?
No, I have money in the bank.
Yes.
And I was left in inheritance.
I was left in inheritance, actually, and...
Oh.
Well, maybe you and I could...
No.
I've got great therapeutic plans for you.
Yeah.
No, it's...
Yes.
What brings you joy in life?
You got anything that brings you joy besides feeling sorry for yourself and giving me a sad story?
I like music.
Yes.
I like videos.
I like movies.
Yes.
I like...
You like dancing?
You like to dance?
Yes.
Stuff like that.
Take up dancing.
Yes.
Here's how he does dancing.
All right.
You like dancing and movies, and usually you work.
Yeah.
And you got friends.
You're way ahead of the game.
I'm just at that...
I'm at that point where I need to do something.
Yeah?
Because it's either this time I decide to really get it done and make it...
Do you volunteer?
It's either do I take the step or do I not take the step.
Do you volunteer for anything?
Not in a long time, but I used to do something.
I don't remember what it was.
I'm just trying to remember, but I didn't...
Try volunteering.
Nothing in your life is meaningful?
Do I feel my life is meaningful?
Yeah.
I don't feel my life is meaningful, but I know my life is meaningful.
It doesn't feel like it is, but I know it is.
Yeah.
So in what situation do you feel best?
Like she asked you about working with animals.
I do.
I have two puppies right now, but they're at my ex-roommate's house, who is just a
horrible person as far as anything's concerned, and I'd love to work at Community Society,
but I need to take care of my puppies.
I don't know what to do, and it's just, I'll figure something out that gives me direction
to head, thinking to volunteer at the Community Society.
All right.
So you're working your way through this swamp slowly.
Mm-hmm.
You're not as bad as you used to be.
Yeah.
The depression's not quite as bad.
Almost overwhelmed, but...
You're able to...
Yeah.
I'm working on it.
All right.
Then the only thing you can do is pharmacologically, I think we could do better with you.
I believe so, too.
I mean, I'm not satisfied with the pharmacologic results.
Not at all.
I think the whole business...
The whole business has not really been worked on yet.
Yeah.
As far as what I'm...
So you need a good psychopharmacologist.
I'm not satisfied with what the medications are doing for you.
Yeah.
You shouldn't be just dilapidated.
Mm-hmm.
Discombobulated.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
You got a doctor you're working with?
No.
I have a therapist.
I have a psychiatrist, yeah, but I see him like once a month.
He gave me Risperdal.
I was on Risperdal constantly.
Then I got off Risperdal constantly.
Then he gave me Risperdal pills, 0.5 twice a day, and I haven't taken...
I've taken them for three days, two days ago, and now I'm coming off of them again.
Coming off of what again?
Risperdal.
Makes me sick.
Oh, Risperdal.
That's not an antidepressant.
No, it's an antipsychotic.
So what do you take for an antidepressant?
I've taken Welbutrin, which gave me the 2% to 3% that people have anxiety.
I got extreme anxiety from it.
Yeah.
No, I wouldn't prescribe Welbutrin.
Zoloft.
Zoloft made me too hyper.
Oh, I see.
Okay.
Huh?
I have ADD and ADHD, so.
Okay.
Uh-huh.
All right, so you're a project.
Yeah.
A multifaceted project.
All right.
You work on all of them with patience, and at the other end, there's a light at the end
of the tunnel.
Mm-hmm.
All right?
All right.
It's a matter of patience, and work your way through it.
Okay.
Do all the things that you know will be helpful.
All right.
Having friends is a very important part of it.
Yeah.
I agree.
All right.
So you've made good progress.
You've made good progress.
All right.
You're halfway through.
Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Things were worse before.
Isaac.
Yes.
In the death and dying video, you mentioned a horrible mistake that you had made that
condemned you to a thousand years of guilt and inability to enjoy dancing and things
like that.
There's something wrong with the microphone.
Either too close or too far.
Do you want to say it again?
Should I say it again?
Yeah.
Say it again.
In the death and dying video.
That's the microphone there.
Can you hear me?
Yeah.
There it is.
In the death and dying video, office series.
Yeah.
You mentioned that you had made a horrible mistake that self-condemned you to many,
many lifetimes of guilt and therefore an inability to enjoy joy, like dancing, things like that.
Yeah.
What was that mistake?
What was what?
What was this mistake that you mentioned?
What was the mistake you made?
Oh, I don't know.
You don't remember it?
It's irrelevant.
Where did it hurt 10 years ago?
I don't remember where it hurt 10 years ago.
All I know is it doesn't hurt now.
Okay.
I don't remember what it was.
I guess I was thinking so that others could potentially avoid it if you remembered it,
but you don't remember it.
Oh, no, I don't remember it.
Okay.
What is...
You know, it could be something like killing the wrong person, you know?
That isn't the guy my wife was having an affair with after all.
Sorry, Jake.
Oops, wrong guy.
What is...
What is hypno...
Well, since you don't know that one, can I just ask another one?
Different one?
What is...
Do you know hypnagogia or hypnagogia?
Are you familiar with that?
Hypnagogic.
Yeah.
What is that?
Where does that come from?
Those experiences?
Hypnagogic is an altered state of consciousness.
A hypnotic-like state.
Hypnagogic.
Hypnagogic hallucinations, for instance.
Right.
People have them right before they fall asleep.
They'll suddenly have like a dream.
Or they'll wake up in a hypnagogic state.
They're not...
They're like half asleep.
Right.
What's the significance of those?
No significance.
Okay.
Just a physiologic reaction.
Like some people sleepwalk, a lot of people don't, you know?
What did you say?
Bad pizza.
Hmm.
Thank you.
Yes.
For three years, we've been studying all of your books at my university in classes.
And just watching what happens at the University of Redlands in California.
And I've known enough to assign your books, turn on some classical music, and get the
hell out of the way.
Until now, I realize the semester's starting again.
And what's coming up is really wanting to, in your presence, and yours, Susan, and the
group.
Too close to the microphone.
Too far away.
I don't know.
Okay.
What's coming up as the new semester is starting is to wanting in the presence of you two and
these people that I love so much, even though I don't know hardly any of their names, is
to dedicate all the studies that happen there, everything that is part of my work, to you,
to my love for you, and to the truth, and...
And to the group.
I feel like what happens there is...
Is part of what happens here, too.
And it's a real blessing.
And it's because of you.
I'm glad you're going well.
It's going great.
Couldn't be better.
Thank you so much.
You already are there.
Yeah.
Sounds good.
Yes.
Hi.
You said this morning that the best thing we can do is to dedicate our lives to our
fellow man and to God as we understand him.
Yes.
And I...
I guess I would like you to elaborate on as we understand him.
What does that mean?
Because of your comprehension, understanding God varies at various stages of your evolution.
So to serve yourself, serve your fellow man, and serve God simultaneously fulfills all
the possibilities.
All the possibilities, you see?
And serving God as you understand him means, however you might conceive of it, being, you
know, the most loving way you can be.
Yeah.
So I don't have to try and understand him at a higher level and...
You're not going to understand God.
No, you're not going to understand God.
That's not understandable.
Okay.
So just where I...
Where I'm at with my relationship with divinity is just fine.
That's fine.
To serve that.
Yes.
Wherever you're at with it is fine.
Okay.
Yes.
Thank you.
God will give you a beefer effort, you know.
First, I just want to express my gratitude.
I just want to express my gratitude to both of you for your devotion to being devoted
to us and to mankind.
So thank you.
It seems like we all have our own little personal subjective bubble that sort of seems personal.
And whatever comes into that, we're prone to identifying with it.
Does that sound about right?
Yeah.
All right.
I'm done.
You graduate.
You got another question.
Oh, oh, thank you.
I just wanted to see if I had it figured out.
You got it.
Thank you, sir.
Whatever comes into the bubble.
Hello, Doc.
Yes.
For enlightened beings who remain in this world, are they accountable for their body,
what their body does?
Accountable?
Is who accountable?
Oh, it wouldn't even be a question to them.
Then how did enlightened beings fall back into a small self?
How can enlightened beings fall back into a small self?
Then how did an enlightened being fall into what?
Then how did an enlightened being fall back into what?
Into a small self?
Into a separate small self?
How did enlightened beings calibrate above 600,
fall back down into a state of duality?
Oh, yes, because not every person who reaches a high level
is sufficiently evolved to stay there.
There's still defects, still defects, vulnerabilities.
See?
My fault.
in my opinion, it's the fault of their teachers
that didn't warn of what could happen at these various levels
and what to watch out for.
For one thing, when you hit a high level,
the spiritual ego wants to take over right away
and say, oh, look how marvelous I am,
and I'll be the great teacher
and be on all the television programs and write books and all.
So the vanity of the ego then wants to take over.
Now, the problem there is
there's still the illusion of a personal self.
Once the illusion of a personal self disappears,
then the great vulnerability tends to disappear, yeah?
Oh, that means enlightened teacher,
they're not there permanently yet,
and they still have vulnerability,
residual tendency to identify with a small self.
Is that right?
There still may be a defect, yes.
So a person may go into a very high state
and then succumb to a weakness.
Don't forget the evil spirits the Buddha described.
He was attacked by demons.
Start looking around to see where you're vulnerable.
How about money?
How about fame?
How about a little roll in the hay, baby?
They just keep feeling you out
until they see, my gosh, I think you're a wonderful teacher.
Oh, I'm a wonderful teacher.
So influencing others, having many followers,
mega church,
but you've got 50,000 followers.
Does that make you more knowledgeable?
No, it makes you a charismatic character.
So each of these things has its own vulnerability, yeah?
And some people through good fortune
and because of good karma
don't have any open gates like that
for anything to come in.
Other people have been taught in advance
and forewarned about it.
I've had very close relationships with teachers
and watched them crash.
Saw it coming, yep.
So there's,
there's a vulnerability all the way up to 1,000.
Is that true?
I don't know if it's up to 1,000.
There's a,
there's a chance for error,
but it's not a vulnerability to something from out there.
As I said, you know,
the trap of the void at 850, see?
Unless you realize that there's something beyond that,
you're going to think that's the end.
So you have to have a very advanced teacher
that tells you of the traps along the way
and outlines the stages.
The upside and the downside of each of those levels, yeah?
So for the last doorway,
when the illusion of one is the source of one's life died
and transcend,
is there more gates to go through after that?
No, no.
You don't have to worry about it
because you'll be dead.
That sounds good.
Thank you.
Yeah, the you that's worried about it won't even exist.
There's no you left to worry about it, you know?
It's God's worry.
I'm trying to figure out how to make this microphone
work a little better, you know?
All right, yes.
Hi.
I just simply came to ask for your hand
and your eyes.
Yes.
You see what you see?
What is that you see?
Something's looking back.
You see your own self shining forth back.
That's all you're seeing.
Thank you, sir.
The beauty and perfection of the reality
of that which you are, see?
Hello.
Yes.
My question is,
why did humanity fall from non-duality to duality?
Oh, you have to ask God that one.
Anyway, in the beginning,
in the Garden of Eden,
and the serpent came along and tempted Eve, you see?
And my feeling is that it was her innocence.
Her vulnerability was her innocence.
The trustiness of the inner child.
Now, the serpent knows that the weakness of the child
is curiosity.
Come here, little girl, and I'll show you how this works.
So the serpent seduced her where he knew she was not conscious
and not defended.
Now, the only defense she had was if she had bided it
by God's edict to obey the Lord.
So it's said that it was due to disobedience.
Huh?
Well?
The obedience was a way of protecting her
from the ignorance and the vulnerability of her innocence.
Like you tell a child,
don't walk across the street without holding my hand.
Because the child in innocence thinks
if he walks across the street, the cars will put the brake on.
So the only thing that protects the child
is the authoritative statement of the parent
until the child's own sense of reality grows up
and sees that you can't walk across the street
without looking both ways.
In the meantime, there's only the authority of the parent.
So Eve's innocence was her vulnerability,
and her current defect was a disobedience to God,
which would have protected her against the vulnerability
of her narcissistic ego.
Thank you.
What I just said was absolute fact.
I don't really like to resist.
What I just said is factually so.
Anyway, that's my understanding of it.
He didn't throw her out of the garden.
She fell out of it.
You've talked about the difference between salvation
and enlightenment and how the Lord Christ taught for salvation
and Buddha taught about enlightenment.
And the Course in Miracles, I understand,
calibrates at about 600, is that correct?
The workbook.
The workbook, right.
And isn't 600 the first level of enlightenment?
Yes.
So then the Course in Miracles is really teaching both salvation and enlightenment.
Is that correct?
I don't know.
I haven't read it in many a year.
Oh.
Well, that's the impression...
It doesn't make any difference, does it?
Well...
Can you turn down salvation for enlightenment, or turn down enlightenment for salvation?
Well, I think of salvation as one of the stages before...
Enlightenment is already salvation, and salvation is already enlightenment.
They're just two different pathways.
They're terminologies.
Oh.
I thought they were...
Like, salvation was prior to enlightenment.
Well, enlightenment is in itself salvation, but not of a design such as salvation.
You see, with salvation, one has a savior who speaks for you before God as your what?
What is that word?
I always forget that word.
As your...
Advocate.
Right.
Before the Father.
See?
Yes.
That would not come to the mind of the Buddha to need an advocate, having become enlightened.
See?
Uh-huh.
All right.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
If you get stuck there, give me a phone.
Give me a call.
There's a lens cap.
Advocate.
I always forget that word.
I can't seem to remember.
I remember it in German, but not in English.
I hope no one left their car windows open.
There's a fine time to tell them.
Hi.
whole way is that all that's needed for the whole way as far as i've gone as far as i've gone which
i've related to you that that far is now open to you just as a consequence of the frequency
of the vibration and the aura yes and is that like permanent you want to go beyond there you
probably got to go to a different dimension okay and how how would you it's potential to be it's
it's the potential knowingness then how would how would you actualize that if it's potential
well through spiritual effort and work all spiritual work devotions selfless service
at the yoga all the you just follow the spiritual pathway yeah okay all right let's do my best
the only way you get to the end is to to put one foot in front of the other
okay you're worrying about the end of the trip
you've rarely taken off already don't worry about that thank you
uh he's a naive charm you have a naive charm
infectious charm yeah yes oh we're getting married oh god bless you yes now what
we didn't think about that
uh you feel happy with it
you feel happy with it well that's that's uh all there is to it isn't it is there anything more
nothing else i can think of okay i have a general question also yeah um how do you know when um you
understand something intellectually or when you like an intellectual understanding or is it like a
subjective um understanding yeah it's experiential it's experiential and uh
you can understand it intellectually but not experientially or vice versa
or you can understand them uh both both ways simultaneously
okay so how do i know when i'm having a subjective um experience like where i have an
a real subjective understanding of your teachings or is it uh intellectualized understanding well
the both both go together you know st thomas aquinas says you know that reason reinforces
faith and that faith illuminates what reason uh illuminates reason so you can intellectually
understand the thing but its true meaning is only a revelation which comes out of accompanying it by
faith though faith and reason go hand in hand see okay yeah faith the reason go hand in hand
so you can understand the thing and then ask god for a miracle to really fully
realize, what does that really fully mean
in its totality?
And if you don't get an answer, complain.
God, I'm shaking the gates of heaven.
I need to know.
Yeah, the answer comes forth.
Reason plus faith is the great
combination.
St. Thomas Aquinas was a
doctor of divinity. He was a doctor of the
church, and about as good as you can get.
Well, congratulations to the two of you.
Yes.
They owe us a dollar.
We'll pay you later.
Now, God bless you both.
God bless you.
I mean, there's
so many couples that met in that class
and got married.
If you get to stack up the couples that met
and got married in the class.
Yes.
Hi, Dr. Aquinas. Hi, Susan.
I have a question
about experiencing
when I was
15. I was really
excited because I told a friend,
I know what all my problems are.
I know how to solve all my problems. If I can give up
experiencing, I won't
have any problems anymore.
And she
thought I was crazy, and so
I just dropped it. I forgot about it
until 25 years later when I found your work.
And then I remembered that experience
or that I had that
memory of that experience
or knowledge.
So,
as I've been working on
practicing
surrendering experience
to divinity,
then I came to a place
that I realized
was peace.
And then I started
becoming like
not having any emotion, like very
flat.
And I remember you telling somebody
during one of the lectures that that's very normal
part of the process.
So I let that go.
Then I have a fear
arising of not existing
at all. So if I'm not
attached to experience
and I have this fear of not
existing, then
I move backwards
it seems like when I have that fear.
So you are
experiencing. You're experiencing
fear. Yeah, yeah, yeah. That's what I'm saying.
So I move backwards when I
when the fear arises.
Well, let go. Wind the track.
Let go. Wind the controller.
And look more
to the presence of God as
love, as love.
The presence of love. See?
Because love is an
awareness. It's not really experience.
It's a way of being.
So you can transcend the sort of
void that you're going through
by focusing on the infinite reality
of divinity itself to the core
of divinity is love.
And affirm love as
a basic quality of divinity.
That was my confusion
was because I have
had an experience of
the celestial realm and the
overwhelming, unspeakable
love that, can you
speak? Yes, yes. So I was
confused about experiencing
because that was an experience.
Well, you're saying it's an experience.
Right. You're saying it's
an experience. That it was just a being.
It's a state. You know, experiencing was something
that you're tacking on to it.
Okay. So. It is.
It is.
It is of its own. See?
It doesn't need to experience it to confirm
it's a reality or existence.
That's a tag on.
It's a rainy thunderous day.
It doesn't need I experience
it as such for it to be that.
You know? Understand?
It's a tag. It's an add-on.
You can let go of the add-on.
Okay. And
what you're going through is not that
hard to go through. It's not hard
to go through. Okay.
It just seems puzzling at
the time. But it's actually
not that hard. It's much
harder to get beyond the lower levels.
Okay. Higher levels are
maybe dumbfounding, but
they're relatively easy.
They suddenly resolve.
Okay. So the confusion
is normal then? Yes. Yes.
That's all. The confusion is coming from trying to
understand it. You can't understand it.
Okay. Not understandable.
Thank you very much.
You're trying to understand it.
Don't try to understand it. Okay.
It is what it is. Okay.
Let God get you through it. Okay.
Help God. Help God.
Thank you, Susan.
I'm on this side of the garden gate.
Get me through the garden gate, Lord.
Yes? I started a study
group in Madison, Wisconsin.
And for
six months, nobody showed up.
But then
she showed up, and
we got married last month.
Oh.
We're going to end up as Mary and Sam
and
somebody else.
Susan.
With that cartoon, Mary and Sam.
Yeah.
My question is, what are some
things we could do to protect ourselves from
the media barrage
of the programming?
Sophistication,
for one thing, what we
talked about this morning, already
guards you against it.
And
hold all information
as provisional. There is
no final information out there. Everything
is provisional. You know, all the records of World
War II, now some of them are turning out to be false,
you know, 25, 50 years later.
So all information is provisional at the time.
So wisdom means to hold all, everything that you learn,
as provisional. That's the way it seems now.
Yep. We only recently learned from Professor,
I forget his name now, that Japan was very close to
their own nuclear bomb. And if we hadn't dropped it, they would have dropped it.
They would have dropped it on us. They were very close.
And that was only revealed in 1992 or 94, isn't it?
That's many years after the event. And even now, we just, we suddenly get the information.
He was on television and we got to interview him and talk about it.
They were, if we hadn't dropped it, they were going to drop it.
And they're going to drop it very shortly, you see.
What I've been kind of doing is avoiding watching television just because, you know,
Oh, yes. I find myself getting sucked into the
dramas and the things. Oh, yes, yes.
And it's just like, oh, here I go again. And so I've, I've kind of been...
Well, there's a detached amusement. When you watch a cartoon, you don't have to believe
the cartoon. Mickey Mouse is real and he's going to come in your backyard. To me, it's
like Mickey Mouse. What's Mickey Mouse saying here tonight, you know?
Thank you. It's a game, a conversational game.
Do you still have... Yes, yes.
Give your, close it up on the thing and then everyone will know it was caused by a nuclear
bomb. Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, give it to Scott right down there in the front.
Thank you.
He'll put it up and then you'll have more.
Yeah, my father was very well known at the University of Madison. Red Hawkins Band
was a university band for many years. And so Madison is the old Rathskeller and it was
really in Lake Mendota and all the frat houses and sorority houses.
Can we get a blessing, a marital blessing?
Yes, you got a blessing. Yes, indeed. God bless you both.
Thank you.
Through the family, love and blessing.
Yes, indeed. God bless you both. God's happiness be yours. Amen.
Thank you.
What a charming couple.
Madison, Wisconsin, can you believe that, huh? I can tell you some wild stories about
Madison.
That's where the
bird went poop.
The vial.
The beard.
The beer.
Ten cents.
Yes.
I make up the last third of the Madison, Wisconsin contingent.
What do you say?
Amazing.
except the last third of the Madison list.
Oh, oh, oh, okay.
Oh, okay, yes, I get you.
And I just wanted to come to receive your grace.
Yeah, all right.
God bless you, man.
God bless your way in this world,
in and beyond.
Thank you.
May I also have your picture?
Sure.
Madison, I had a 34 Chevy coupe,
and I ran out of oil,
and I threw a rod through the block.
It cost me 10 bucks to get it towed into Madison,
where I sold it for junk for $5.
Yes, uh-huh.
Hello.
Well, I finally got the guts to ask you a question,
being the third time that I came to see you.
Well, first of all,
I'd like to thank you for your work.
Yes.
But most of all, I'd like to ask Susan
for having facilitated you coming out in the world
and teaching devotional non-duality.
Oh, yes.
I don't think she gets enough credit for that.
But anyways, my question is...
Get up, you lazy look, she said.
That's what got me going.
You're weighing, what, 90 pounds or something back then?
Yeah.
My question is regarding a few meditation courses
that I've taken in the last year.
I don't know if you're familiar with Vipassana meditation.
Vipassana technically is the path to enlightenment
that took me to the world.
That took the Buddha?
Okay.
You haven't heard that.
I'd like to know if Vipassana meditation
is aligned with my own spiritual journey,
meaning devotional non-duality.
What is the name of the meditation?
Vipassana or Vipassana?
Yeah.
There's several...
Oh, it begins with a V.
V, yeah.
Oh, Vipassana.
Yes, yes.
Yeah, it's...
All right, okay.
Let's ask if we have permission.
We have permission to ask.
As taught by S.N. Goenka.
Vipassana.
Vipassana is aligned with your spiritual destiny, resist.
It is aligned and helpful.
It's aligned and helpful with your spiritual pathway, yes.
Thank you very much.
That's all I needed to know.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I'd like to have a picture taken.
Thanks a lot.
Vipassana is a historical, you know.
Yes.
Yeah, Vipassana, yes.
Mm-hmm.
I thought he said bypassa.
Bypassa the Buddha.
No, no, bypassa.
I said Pali words.
I know.
Bypassa the Buddha.
That's funny.
Could I just be with you for a moment?
Mm-hmm.
Indeed.
God bless you.
Yes.
There's a boy who doesn't talk too much.
Don't have to tell him to shut up and cut it short.
Yes, he did.
To facilitate awakening, I would like to know how to spend my time in the mornings.
I wake up between four and five, and I have until about seven.
And I do centering prayer, Father Keating centering prayer.
I don't know.
You're following the centering prayer?
Uh-huh.
Yes.
Father Keating?
What's the question?
Yes.
The question is doing that and doing Bible study, and then also Gurdjieff's The Fourth Way.
Oh, yeah.
Reading the work, and I just wondered, because the work seems so intellectual to me.
It is.
I think a little bit too much for what you're looking for, perhaps.
Awakening.
Yeah, Gurdjieff.
Yeah.
OK.
So maybe not that, then.
Gurdjieff may not be, let's see, I forget what Gurdjieff calibrates that anymore.
I don't know what I thought of it.
Yeah, you don't need Gurdjieff on top of it all.
OK.
Thank you.
Why?
Because you get programmed to start looking in this direction, and then looking in that
direction.
Yes.
I've been working with just getting to the experience of, like, not labeling my
experience, the energy, like Gurdjieff . . .
Don't call it anything.
Just let it be whatever it is, yeah.
And surrendering it, allowing it, and it's getting to . . . this has been going on for
years now, and it's getting to the point where I'm extremely uncomfortable.
Uncomfortable?
Yeah.
With what?
I feel like my whole being is caught up in a taffy machine, churning, and tension, and
. . .
I'm at this point of questioning the energy that I'm experiencing, whether it's something
I need to release, or just to open up to, but at this . . .
If you let go resisting it, you'll disappear it.
OK.
My concern has been that when you talked about the ego . . . I mean, the . . .
Yeah.
. . . the id today . . .
. . . and the . . . all the dark aspects of humanity, that has been coming up at the
same time with this, and I've been concerned about being run by that, and all the stuff
you've said about lower astral energies, too, and . . .
You're going to give reality to them, huh?
The only reality that I have is whatever you give them.
OK.
I don't think I'd give them any kind of . . . I wouldn't give them much.
Yeah.
I don't think I'd give them much credence, I thought.
The flashing by, I wouldn't identify.
Consider them as an aspect of who you are.
OK.
I guess I'm just starting to . . . I feel like coming out of denial about a lot of the
darker aspects . . .
Oh, the darker aspects.
Yeah.
Those are within the animal.
The animal.
The cingulate gyrus.
You see?
The cingulate gyrus calibrates about 170.
Yeah.
You give it enough flexibility.
The prefrontal cortex calibrates at 200, which is neutral, because that's the same as the
human body, which is the same as the planet.
The planet, the human body, the prefrontal cortex, are neutral.
That's 200.
They're good or bad, they just are, like a stone sitting there.
A stone is neither good nor bad.
Those terms are not applicable to it, see?
It just is.
It's neither good or bad.
The cingulate gyrus is the gyrus in the brain
which is the seat of animal instincts.
So I wouldn't call them evil.
I would just call them animal.
So then you have to ask yourself,
am I an animal or am I something beyond the animal
and deny the reality.
So I can just let it rip.
Well, you say, okay, animal, I hear you.
But I'm not identical with you.
You, I have gone beyond.
And you're where I was a couple of million years ago.
The dinosaur is in our id.
It loves to kill for the fun of killing.
But that's where we were millions of years ago.
I've been doing the Course in Miracles,
I guess the daily course lessons.
And also I just feel a tremendous attraction
towards Zen type, Taoist Zen type teachings, etc.
And sometimes I'll intensely go with that.
And recently in talking with a friend,
I mean, who I respect very much said,
you know, I'd be very careful
with the Zen type style teachings.
As he believes, like many teachers have fallen
and who have followed that rote, etc.
I just want to get from you that, you know,
Zen always doesn't include pathway of the heart
and that type of thing.
And if I want to go on intensely,
is there any pitfalls or downfalls
one should watch out for
if they totally just go for the,
you know, the path of the heart?
What am I? Zen tip, so to speak.
Zen style meditation?
Yeah.
Is that what your main energy is put into?
Yeah, if I totally just go with it.
I think this question is coming up
just from a conversation with a friend.
I feel a strong attraction towards Zen type teachings
and Taoism, Advaita, etc.
Yeah, go with it.
Okay.
Yeah, Zen, Buddhism will not lead you into any evil.
You may transcend the void,
but beyond that,
the level of Huang Po,
you've already heard to affirm the presence of God as love
and then you'll transcend the void.
Yeah, Zen is a very rapid and I like it.
It's a strict discipline.
Okay?
All right, thank you.
If you're not okay, I'll beat you with a stick.
Please, anytime.
Thank you.
Well, I did Zen meditation for many years.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
First of all, thank you for your presence in my life.
I'm deeply grateful.
My question today is about being too hard on myself.
Yes.
I try to make good choices all the time
in alignment with my heart,
but hindsight is always 20-20.
Oh, yes.
And I tend to review past choices,
and be myself up for it.
So, could you help me with self-forgiveness?
Don't identify with that which you were in the past.
That which you were at that time
made that choice because of that which you were.
Now, you are not that anymore,
and therefore, you negate that choice
as being inappropriate for who you are now.
It was probably okay for that that you were then,
but it's not okay for what you are now.
So, don't identify what was in the past
with yourself,
with the reality of who you are now,
because who you were then no longer exists.
It's only a memory of a past state.
Thank you.
That's very helpful.
Blessings.
What you did in the past has to be looked at
in the context of who you were at the past.
Who you are now says it's wrong,
but that's not who you were then.
Who you were then decided,
yeah, he needed a good punch in the eye,
so you gave him a punch in the eye.
You wouldn't do that now
because you don't need to prove
that you can protect yourself
and that you're as strong as a man
or whatever the event was.
So, it was okay for that,
whoever that person was then,
but that person no longer exists.
You can't step into the same river twice.
So, just let it go.
It's a different river now.
Different river now.
Okay.
You wouldn't choose it now
because that's not who you are now.
Right.
Okay.
Thank you.
My love to you.
And to you.
Thank you.
Give him a good biff in the nose, Frankie.
When you're 14,
you've got to learn to give him a good biff in the nose.
At 80, it looks ridiculous, you know.
Dr. Hawkins,
I've been following your work
for about five or six years now,
and I feel very privileged to be here.
Yes, thank you.
My question is that many spiritual teachers
teach you to use a pendulum
and that it taps into your brain.
It taps into the universal mind.
Could you clarify between the kinesiologic test
and the pendulum?
What is the question?
To use the pendulum to try to ascertain truth?
What's your question?
Yes.
Is it useful?
I'm sure it's useful.
The pendulum.
It's useful, yes.
In your CDs, discovery CDs,
you say not to use it.
I don't know what you're hearing.
Well, in some of your CDs, you use it.
Oh, because unless you're well taught,
people start, they have to start
fishing around with negative energies.
The next thing you do is you pick up a negative entity.
Next thing you know, you're being run by the negative entity,
and you're getting the exact opposite of truth.
So don't go poking around trying to find out
what is Hitler calibrated, Bin Laden,
you know what I'm saying?
No.
So just use it for, to know truth.
To make decisions, let's say.
Yes, for truth.
Yeah, make decisions.
Help you make decisions.
Thank you.
It's only one of many, you know, ways of getting answers, you see.
It may corroborate or not corroborate something that you wish to know.
Dr. Hawkins, may I have your blessing?
So anyway, many people have found it useful, yes.
Yes.
Dr. Hawkins, may I have your blessing?
God bless you, and stay out of trouble.
Yes, okay, I'm moving as fast as my widow Wicks can carry me.
Yes.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
In the preface to Power Vs. Force,
you mentioned upon reaching a certain level of awareness
that few follow the steps because they're so simple.
My question is, why would few follow simple steps?
I don't get the question.
He wants to know, you say that the steps are very simple.
That what?
The steps are very simple.
What steps?
Upon reaching a certain level of awareness that you described.
Steps to enlightenment are very simple.
Yeah, very simple.
Yes, it's just a matter of willingness to do them.
But he says, why don't more people follow it?
Oh, how do I know?
It's their karmic destiny.
Some people are smarter than others.
Some people curse Walmarts and other people shop there.
You want to save money?
It depends on your motivation, you know what I'm saying?
The steps in and of themselves are simple.
You don't have to be a college graduate or an intellectual genius
to understand the willingness to forgive people.
That's just it, a willingness, a willingness to be loving towards all of life.
So you don't have to be a PhD or a genius to be willing to be gentle and loving
and supportive of all of life and all of its expressions, you know?
So that's why I say it's simple.
There's nothing to memorize, you know?
It's a willingness, a willingness.
May I have a picture too?
Yes. It's a willingness, you think?
Yeah. Thank you.
Thank you very much for all that you do.
My question relates to surrender
and the difference between true surrender
and stuffing emotions, denying emotions.
The difference between surrender and what?
True surrender.
Oh, stuffing, yeah.
Stuffing is refusing to look at it.
Yeah, because I had a recent experience.
Surrender, yeah.
You experience it out.
You're angry.
You just let the angriness be there.
Angry, angry, angry, angry.
After about midnight, the angriness gets very tiresome
and you say, the hell with it, go to sleep.
Okay.
So then it can be more healthy to experience through that
rather than constantly saying, well, I surrender or not.
And as I've said before, those of us who remember,
you know, there's a number one stack, number two stack, number three stack.
So if it's a mild stack, you can,
you can get over it in a few minutes.
If it's a heavy stack, it'll take a repeated application of it.
But eventually, it runs out of energy.
It's limited.
Okay.
Eventually.
And is it better to not discuss it among friends and family
and that sort of a thing?
It's none of their business.
Okay. So it's better because that lends to juicing it?
You can tell them you're working through something.
You don't have to share it with them.
It depends on how understanding they are, you know.
Some families are sort of.
They're sort of idiotic when it comes to anything spiritual.
Yeah.
So I would look to them for forbearance.
Okay.
And other people are more, you know, understanding.
It depends on how spiritually evolved the family itself is, you know.
Whether it's appropriate or not appropriate.
Thank you very much.
Yeah. You can also explain it to people.
It's just you're working through a lot of angriness.
See, if you're in therapy, you can always blame it on your therapy.
Hi, Doc.
Hi, Susan.
Hi.
My wife sends her love and couldn't be here today.
And I have a friend.
Yeah.
She's a nurse.
And I have a friend who is a Brian.
You've met him.
He's a monk in the Ramakrishna order.
He also.
I don't know.
I'm not hearing anything.
All right.
They're either too close or too far.
I don't know which it is.
So my wife sends her love.
She couldn't be here.
Oh, your wife.
Yes.
And a friend named Brian, who is a monk in the Ramakrishna order, asked.
Oh, yes.
He asked me to tell you thank you for all the work you've done.
Yes.
I really came up here just to be in your presence.
And I'm working on reading Nisargadatta's work on focusing meditation on I am.
Oh, okay.
And I was wondering if you could say a little bit about that, I am, as a meditation, and
about awareness tapping into it.
I can't say much about it.
It was a technique that he advised.
I myself don't.
In, oh.
Because it gets to be verbalized.
A repetition is verbalization.
Yeah.
Awareness I seek is a nonverbal.
It's of a nonverbal knowingness.
The only thing that you know about yourself is that you are.
But that is also true in philosophy.
I am.
I think, therefore, I am.
Ergo, I assume, right?
But I don't know that it's a really good phrase to repeat.
I'm afraid with you it's going to become a phrase, and you're repeating this phrase over and over.
Okay.
I would say instead of who am I, look at what am I.
Who am I is going to make you search around for another pronoun, more universal-sounding
pronoun, but still a pronoun.
I think instead of who am I, I prefer what am I.
Okay.
Because you're a what, not a who.
Right.
See, a who already makes you a separate individual pronoun identity.
A what is a far more generalized identity.
All right.
Okay.
Good.
Bye.
Explanation of the self with a capital S. Yeah. Mm-hmm. Yeah, okay. Thanks
Thank you. What am I you reflect on that without using the words?
Ramana Maharshi suggested
Yes, hi who I just had a question
lately, I feel like I have been I used to come in to the lectures and
Like it felt like my head was going to come off the top of my head was going to come off. It felt great
I felt really in tune with everything and lately. I've just felt really flat
And like I'm spinning my wheels and not going anyplace
Or doing anything so what now yeah, so what now?
What is it?
So are you trying to program it or what am I trying to program it? Mm-hmm?
I don't know. I'm trying to figure out what to do spiritually because I feel like I'm
Just hanging around lots of resentment coming up always. I you know you mean as far as the process how to process
Spirit thing about spiritual processing yeah, yes, just what is I did the course of miracles a couple years
Oh, and I used to do every day, and now I don't worry about where do you go with meditation?
I just look at the breath. Huh I watched the breath. Oh, you watch the breath yes. Yeah
That's it
take care of you for the next 20, 30 years.
Okay.
You're like a young man, you want to go
from Chicago to New Orleans.
It doesn't work that way, man.
You stay right in Chicago
and realize more
and more about who Chicago, what
Chicago is and who you are
and the awareness
of your presence.
Now stay right where you are.
Stay right where I am.
A tent of an inch from exactly where
you are and just
stay fixed there and refuse
to budge. Refuse to
budge. Yes.
Insist on being just
right where you are.
Don't move it.
No evolving, no progressing.
The next time I see you, just stay and do not move
one iota.
Okay? Okay.
That's not asking much, right?
No, it's...
Yeah.
This is the answer he wanted.
I know.
Don't move one iota
from where you are.
No progress, please.
I don't want any accomplishments,
any great awarenesses.
I don't want any great leaps of awareness.
Okay?
Promise to not move an inch
from where you are.
Good for you, sir.
I'll try and help him out with that.
That makes me nervous to ask a question.
Yeah.
So,
we've been married
three months tomorrow.
Oh, yes.
Yeah.
And I'm wondering if you can speak at all
to alignment versus involvement.
I don't really know how to do it.
Question.
Alignment versus involvement.
Oh.
Or maybe you could even...
Oh, you mean as a couple?
Yeah.
Oh, yes.
All right, so...
Alignment is like this.
You're both headed in the same direction.
See?
Now,
there's no interference
because you're both headed the same way.
You're both trying to be as loving as you can
and fulfill your obligation to yourself
and society, et cetera.
You're both heading in the same direction.
Really?
Yeah.
All right.
So, the way most people get involved
is there's a power struggle
that goes from one solar plexus to the other.
You're going to do it my way?
No, I'm going to do it your way.
No, I'm going to do it my way.
Thank you.
I see a lot of ads a lot of times
that try to sell something.
And then it focuses on the guy,
and you hear what he says,
and it focuses on the woman,
and she winks and says,
he's going to do it my way.
So, it's a struggle for who's going to win,
to see things in terms of a struggle
between one and the other,
winning and losing, et cetera.
See that you're both aligned,
and then all you can discuss is how the two of you
can best get there together, see?
It's hard to do that.
No, it's not hard to do that.
I mean, I think he's cool.
I think he's brilliant.
I imagine you feel the same way.
I'm just not really sure how to do it, or myself.
Well, let's see.
What is it?
You know, do you get into arguments?
Is that what you're saying?
Have you read the book?
I know we're different.
OK.
He's read.
I've read some of it.
No, you've got to read the book.
I think it's very good.
The other thing is to realize if you both have the same goal,
then you're not interfering.
If you have different goals, different goals,
then you're going to cross.
You both want to have a job and buy a house.
OK, so you're aligned.
Aren't you?
One says, no, I don't want to buy a house.
I want to get a horse.
I want to buy a racehorse.
I mean, now you're going to have a conflict.
Right on.
Thank you very much.
Well, it may be more general.
What you want is a satisfying home,
and then you discuss which would be the most satisfying home.
It's not an RV versus a brick cottage, you know?
That's being too literal.
I think we just slip in and out of it.
Yeah?
It just gets discouraged.
Well, it takes some years to.
More than three months.
It takes.
Yes, it takes days.
Yeah.
It gets better all the time.
The first year of marriage is tough.
It gets better all the time, though.
You get used to how to discuss things, how to discuss,
how to discuss.
OK?
The marital discourse.
Thank you.
I got to keep moving.
I'll keep moving.
Okey-doke.
Come along, love.
Yes?
Hello.
I don't really have a question.
I just wanted to come up.
It's my first time being here, and I'm from Seattle,
Washington.
Do you guys have any groups in there?
Yes, we do.
We have several groups in Seattle.
OK.
That's great.
If you go to consciousnessproject.org,
he has a list of all the groups and their locations.
All right.
Great.
Well, it's nice to meet you.
You've come at a very pivotal time in my life.
And I'm just honored to be here.
You know what the most difficult period in anybody's life is called?
What?
Now.
Thank you.
Thank you, Susan.
Oh, thank you.
Sorry.
I was thinking about you, but .
Yes.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
It's an honor and a privilege to be here with
you.
You mentioned the angel when we cross over, when we drop the body.
And I was, because of past experience, it seemed
that there was angelic guidance going on.
Is that a trueism?
Yes.
Thank you so much.
Yes, you have your own spiritual guide,
your own personal angels.
We have permission to ask this.
You have your own personal angel guides.
That's wonderful.
Nice thought, isn't it?
It is.
It's great.
Couldn't be better.
Thank you so much.
Who could ask for anything more?
You're not as cooperative, though.
Thank you both for leading the way for us.
I've had some really dark nights about four months ago,
and they turned into dark weeks,
which I can't recommend.
I attended a seminar in a state of fear,
and I feel really guilty about being here in that state.
And on the other side,
also I'm grateful for the refuge,
for being able to come.
I was wondering if you can help me reconcile my feelings.
Reconcile what?
It's torn up.
He feels afraid, right?
It was an extreme state of fear during that dark night of soul.
Fear, dark night of soul.
Yeah?
I was experiencing it.
I have to have a better description of the fear.
Fear of what?
Oblivion?
Punishment?
Sin?
Death?
It was like an energy came in that shut down my third eye.
And, you know,
you kind of, I experienced,
I was aware of what was happening.
There was all these thoughts,
attack thoughts flying around,
and I couldn't really disassociate myself from it.
You're talking about being attacked by demons.
That's what it appears.
Oh, okay.
You're talking about being attacked by demons.
Oh, yeah.
And I...
So you rebuked them and refused them.
Yes.
And denied them reality.
And demand that they leave you and get the hints.
Yes.
Thank you.
And I came here in a state,
in the state,
and I feel really,
I feel guilty about having been here in that state,
you know,
like in the sanctuary.
Yeah, I don't know why.
I'm Catholic,
so I'm born Catholic.
Oh, poor lad.
Thank you.
But I just...
Sharon Begora, the good Lord,
will forgive you for your good will.
Thank you.
And you can do six Hail Marys and the Rosary back then.
And a little donation to the church building fund
would be helpful.
Now do you feel better?
Actually, I do.
Yes.
Thank you.
God bless you.
Yeah.
Hello.
Uh-huh.
I wanted to come up and express my gratitude,
my thanks,
my admiration.
Thank you.
The love of the group that we work with in the Delaware Valley
could be an inspiration to me,
my children,
and, uh,
I also feel the part that is also me here.
And I was listening to a tape on the way up last night.
And you were saying that sometimes you feel like
I'm looking at myself through someone else's eyes.
Yes.
Uh-huh.
And after that, I just can't speak.
It's magnificent.
It's a lot of the phenomena to develop on their own.
It gets better all the time.
It does.
Yeah.
God bless you.
Sometimes you got to pull off the rope.
Good idea.
Thanks.
I can't remember having to pull off the rope.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
Very nice to meet you.
This is my first seminar.
Yeah.
And I've been a great student of your work,
so thank you so much.
And, um,
I'd written down questions in reading your work from before,
and I couldn't think of any for now.
So I'll just say thank you so much.
Thank you for thanking me.
Yeah.
Bless you.
Thank you, Susan.
Mm-hmm.
Ah, these new-fangled gadgets.
There.
Oh, yeah.
Yes.
I wanted to come and talk to you about music.
About what?
Music.
Yes.
Music is very important to me.
I've been a music teacher for about six years in all my life.
Um, it's been a part of my life.
Yes.
And I know that different things calibrate at different amounts.
And, um.
Oh, yes.
Yes.
And I just wanted to ask you, um,
Mm-hmm.
I wanted to ask you where some things calibrate.
Where does jazz music calibrate?
I tell you, uh, uh, there's a book called, uh, Truth Versus Falsehood.
It has a section in Chapter 9, I think, on music.
Okay.
All the various forms of music are calibrated there.
Also the great musicians, uh, yeah.
Okay.
And as far as instruments go, like an electric guitar with distortion,
does that calibrate high?
Oh, I never calibrated individual instruments, no.
Okay.
No, it's what you put into them.
It's not the instrument itself.
You can put all your heart and soul in it, and wow, you know?
Okay.
Yeah, so it's what you put into music.
I think all music is great, you know?
All music is great, except for rap music and that kind of stuff.
You have to listen.
Calvary's Less Than 200 is demonic, you know?
Oh, okay.
Yeah, raping and killing and shooting and stuff, you know?
Thank you.
Yes.
And a picture.
Who's the black singer that sings,
It's a wonderful world?
Oh, yeah.
Louis Armstrong.
Calvary's the highest of all of them.
Five centimeters.
It's a wonderful world.
Yeah, Calvary's, I think, is the highest of all the pop singers.
Dr. Hawkins, I just have one question.
If we as a group are here to serve God and mankind,
how do we accept the downfall or the,
what consciousness, level of consciousness is happening now?
In our society and in our culture?
Yup.
Those are the normal fluctuations of evolution.
Evolution's not a straight line.
You know, it goes like this, and it goes like this, and then, you know, it goes like this.
And then it has big advances, and then it slides back, and then it goes forward.
You know, the dark ages were very dark.
The dark ages were very dark.
So, you have the high of the ancient Greek intellectual Plato, and Sophocles, and Socrates.
You go from the greatest, and then it declines, you know.
And then you have the Renaissance, the renewal, the Protestant Revolution, you know, the Renaissance in Europe.
The rebirth of what was already known in ancient Greece but had been forgotten, you see.
So, these are normal fluctuations, you know, in the growth curve.
And sometimes what happens is you don't have the impetus to bounce further until you hit bottom,
and then you say, that's enough of that, and then you turn around.
Now we're trying to see how, you know, what gains are there in falsehood.
We're plumbing the depths.
How far will falsehood get you?
And we're going to find out that it doesn't get us too far.
To be an apologist for evil, you join in the karmic consequences of that evil.
So, the apologists for evil will hit their own skids, and then there'll be a turnaround again.
So, it goes like this.
It goes like so, like waves.
If you trace it over history, you see the energy field of mankind goes up and down and down.
Divine providence.
Sometimes we only learn by mistakes, you see.
So, we check this out, and we see where it leads us, and then we say, oh, I see where that leads us, so we'll come back.
Libertinism, well, brings you to a bottom.
When you hit that bottom, you come back up again.
You reminded me of Wayne Dyer.
I think you said Wayne Dyer.
Thank you for your work, Doctor.
Yes.
I like your books.
I wish there were more pictures.
You wish that?
I wish there was more pictures.
You don't see the pictures there?
That plant used to belong to friends of yours, Bill and Lois Wilson.
Oh.
Thirty-six years ago when Bill died, Lois passed along some of her plants
to friends of theirs they sponsored in the AA, and she said to pass them on.
I thought it would be nice to see one come full circle since you were there when he died.
Yes.
Looks just like Bill.
Well, thanks, that was a great gift.
Bill was a great being.
Changed the face of the world.
Changed the world.
Calibrate the impact of the various religions.
On American society today, you'll find that the one that calibrates the highest is the 12-step movement.
It has the greatest positive impact on our society.
I know we can't answer all the questions because they're going to throw us out.
Run faster.
Their little legs are moving too slow.
What?
We closed the questions?
Yes.
Oh.
I didn't know that.
The reason nobody's there is because there's nobody there.
Is that it?
Right.
What do they think?
Oh, who cut it off?
Who cut it off?
I guess we got cut off.
Right.
So, anyway, all right.
Dear God, we give thanks for this magnificent day and the joy of thy presence as these people here.
We give thanks for thy divine presence and inspiration, and I ask for thy blessing on this group.
We come in together, and we go out together.
We shift from this domain to the next domain, and then we flock back again in this domain,
and then we flock out again in that domain, and gradually we circle up and up and up and
up, up and up.
Then anyone's left here are the laggards.
So we thank thee, O Lord, for the blessing of thy divine love, thy presence, for you
all are God's gift to me.
You are God's gift to me.
I thank God for all of you.
And God bless you.
Amen.
Yeah.
Thank you, God.
I'm spoiled rotten.
Thank you for your presence.
Yes.
Yeah.
Such a great and wonderful people.
Amen.
Thank you all so much.
What a blessed moment.
Yeah.
What an incredible group of people.
What an incredible group.
Man.
I am truly blessed.
Truly blessed beyond belief.
Amen.
Me too.
Yes.
Amen.
God bless you.
God bless you all.
Thank you.
I kill myself in a way that I don't know why I am so roasted.
And.
They're going to chase us out.
Sacrilege.
Don't eat the flowers.
Thank you again until next time.
God bless.