an excelsis Deo. Glory to God in the highest. By that alignment, we're united as one. You're
God's gift to me. I'm responsible for the truth of everything I say, and I take responsibility
for it on your behalf. I pray to God to speak through me every lecture that we give. Today
will be a somewhat difficult lecture, difficult to prepare at least, to explain insanity to
people where rational is difficult. We're going to be speaking about relativism today.
The Pope, you know, said that two things tearing down Western society, one of them
is relativism. And so we decided to address the issue in some detail today. And I'm going
to do that today. We have some slides, some new ones, very interesting. And so we'll do
the best we can to try and...
We're having a little bit of technical difficulties. Just bear with me a minute.
Right. Okay.
We live in a technologic world.
In the world that I grew up, good and evil were compartmentalized. I didn't know anybody
that was evil. We didn't know anything about evil except...
God was out there someplace, Nazis or something. Life was simple. Everything was clearly demarcated.
In today's computerized internet, WWW intercom download, whatchamacallit world, they're mixed
together. And we confuse reality with the image. So I'll start out with a declaration
for the day. Everything is what it is.
What it is is what it means. And what you think about it and how you label it is irrelevant.
That's up to you. Everything is the reality of its own existence. And that's what it means
is what it is. What this hand means is what it is. You can call it anything you want.
You can call it victim. You can call it perpetrator.
Right. All right. How many people are new today? Okay. We have a lot of new slides,
so we're going to spend most of the lecture on the new slides. But we will just do a fast
review of some of the basics for those that are new. Also, these are videotaped, and therefore
people out there who haven't been to prior lectures want to see it. So I'll just present
some of the background.
So the pheno-kinesiologic method itself was a fortuitous discovery. I mean, its application
to consciousness research was a fortuitous discovery, and I felt it was so important
that I had to stop everything and do research on it. And it was a very important piece of
work. So my dedication was pretty much like Sir Alexander Fleming. When Fleming discovered
what penicillin was, it was a very important piece of work. But I believe it's a very important
could do he couldn't rest until he had gotten it across to the world because he
saw the implication of it comes out of all the pharmacology the cure of all the
diseases when you know I had a huge practice for many years I practiced for
50 years when I started out the diseases that were prevalent you don't even see
anymore I can hardly believe but all the people all the people in the hospital
where I went none of those diseases even exist how can that be that's due to all
the wonders of science and the progression of our civilization all
right so we'll start off with just a review we could do number one which we
always do to give us an orientation now this skill of consciousness has become
relatively well known you realize it's an absolute scale
you
it defines the absolute not which is relative if it's 38 degrees out is 38
degrees out according to this thermometer and that's an absolute fact
it doesn't change how you think about it or whether you see yourself as a victim
of the temperature map of consciousness then it gives us a
common out of a common point of reference and it works pretty much like
a common out of a common point of reference and it works pretty much like
an altimeter or barometer or a thermometer it just gives you the
temperature gauge of an energy field this energy field then has a
physiologic response the physiologic response is shown most easily by the
kinesiologic response but it's also showing many other ways yeah there's
in brain function, neurophysiology,
and as Carol has shown,
I just got a recent paper,
the update on the pupillometry.
The pupil of the eye reacts
depending on the truth or falsehood of stimulus,
irrespective of the person's personal opinion.
The critics of it say, you know, it doesn't work.
Kinesiology does not work in a lot of people.
Those who calibrate below 200 doesn't work at all.
And above 200, there's also a limitation.
So about a third of people in the United States
are capable of doing ordinary kinesiology.
The criticism is people can't understand
what it means to be objective.
Objective means they'll say,
well, you said so-and-so calibrated so-and-so.
I don't say it at all.
I don't care what they calibrated it at.
I haven't the slightest interest on a personal level.
Because when you're doing
diagnosis, you just want to know the truth
for its own sake, for its own sake.
That seems to be beyond some people's comprehension.
That you're interested in truth
for its own sake.
So I say if you have a biased opinion,
first ask what the truth is,
and then decide on an opinion about that,
instead of in reverse.
And the letters we get, we can't make it work
because they go the other way around.
First they have an opinion.
And then it doesn't corroborate
their opinion.
It requires actually some sophistication
to be consistently accurate.
What you're trying to discern is essence
from appearance.
Essence from appearance.
In this world, it's very difficult
because in our current society,
the perception of everything
is politicized.
The perception, the image
has become
everything is politicized.
And therefore,
there's another layer on top
besides your own personal.
There's your own personal politicized thing.
So everything is regimented
left and right, etc., etc.
Incorrect and not correct
and all the rest.
Anyway, the map of consciousness then
came about
as a consequence of doing thousands
of calibrations
and seeing that energies were stratified.
Stratified.
And those that are aligned
with truth
and the
integrity
calibrate from 200 up
and those that are aligned
with falsehood
are 200 and down.
In psychiatry,
these are called the negative
destructive emotions,
the emergency emotions.
And these are the welfare emotions.
Welfare emotions.
So the level 200 then
is above 200 is truth,
below 200 is falsehood.
And as we'll see today,
it really delineates
two completely different
populations.
They are really two different cultures,
very different cultures.
And they even have different
brain physiology.
Even brain physiology.
Okay, so, all right, next one.
We're just going to go fast
through the beginning slides.
This just shows the level
of consciousness
and the energy level.
And you see as you get over
200,
it begins to rise very rapidly.
And then it goes all the way
up to the top.
Okay, next one.
So the higher levels
have to do with power.
The lower levels have to do
with force.
Force goes from here to there
and it does something.
It falls within the Newtonian paradigm.
Power doesn't go from
anywhere to anywhere.
It stands still
and influences everything around it
by virtue of the field
of that which it is.
Like gravity.
It just stands there.
But then influences everything
within its domain.
The distribution in the world
of the world's population,
I think we've got spots up there
that are blotting out the screen.
Approximately,
the world's population,
around 80%
calibrate below 200.
In America, that's about 50%.
And there are some areas
of the world
where there's a lot of
energy.
And there are some areas
where there's nobody above 200.
There are whole countries
where practically nobody
calibrates over 200.
The entire culture is below 200.
Okay, so we'll move
on to the next.
And this is how they're distributed.
For those who have never seen it
before, it's self-explanatory.
Why doesn't the world just
self-destruct?
Well, because those
who calibrate above 200,
although they compose a small
percentage, their power is
so much greater, as you saw
from the level of power.
Even a few individuals
who calibrate extremely high
will practically counterbalance
most of the rest of mankind.
Their consciousness is so powerful.
And it's because the numbers
as they go up are logarithmic,
exponential in a logarithmic
to the base 10.
So in each population,
you only really need a few individuals.
There have been times,
there have been centuries,
where nobody was on the planet
to calibrate over 600.
Many times, there's only a few.
Right now, I think there's only,
I forgot to count them,
but there's probably a dozen.
So, but these are so powerful
that it counterbalances.
Otherwise, human life would
really actually come to an end.
So we'll move to the next.
This is just a different way
of depicting the same balance.
That these few here
counterbalance the rest of mankind.
Yes?
Okay.
Percent of elapsed time
of life on this planet.
And we were calibrating the level of consciousness,
the evolution of consciousness
over great periods of time.
And you see that it just began
to go up very, very recently.
Now we'll go to the next slide.
This chart, which we have shown many times,
is interesting.
It shows the level of consciousness
of life on this planet
over great eons of time
and you see that over great eons of time,
the level of consciousness
has risen progressively.
In this is interesting
because you see the origin
and evolution of the ego itself.
It's not necessary to condemn the ego
and call it wicked, call it evil,
beat yourself with sack cloth and ashes.
You can see, it exists.
evolved as a consequence of the nature of
life itself. In the beginning there was only
when organic matter was hit by
the energy field of divinity, life
evolved. So life evolved from life, not from
non-life. Let's see if that's correct.
Life evolved only from life itself.
Did not arrive from inorganic
non-life, so much from the bottom-up
theory of evolution. Anybody still
think life evolved from non-life? They've been weeded
out, I see. Put to death,
which was kindly. Put them out of
their misery. Well, anyway, lots of best-selling books
hold that life evolved from non-life.
Now, that's a defect of abstract thinking, because
anybody who has any education realizes that those are different
levels of abstraction. Life is a totally different level
of abstraction from mechanicalness and non-life.
So in the beginning, then, the evolution of
life, the radiance of divinity, the light of
God, it says in Genesis, the light of God, when the radiance
from the Godhead,
arose the God of creation.
But the God of creation was a manifestation
of the Godhead, which just is.
It's expression, then,
as the creator. When this energy then hit organic matter, life evolved.
In its most primitive form, life is not self-sustaining.
Life has to get energy, so the whole problem of the ego was,
the earliest forms of life had no form of intrinsic source of energy,
such as chlorophyll. It had to seek and search and sample, and that's how the
human ego began. It had to discern that which is poisonous, that which is food,
that which is nutritionist. And so this is a capacity of the ego to this day in
the human mind.
searches out there symbolically or actually physically
to ascertain the qualities of that which is out there
so that it can begin to decide that which is agreeable
and that which is disagreeable.
Okay.
All right.
And then we saw that the animal kingdom reflected that.
I have a new kitty.
To keep you up on my wildlife at home.
I have a new kitty who calibrates.
We'll calibrate kitty.
Calibrates over Bootsy.
He's over 210, 220, 225, 226.
Bootsy's at 225.
You're going to meet lots of people in this world
that don't calibrate over 225.
Cost me 50 bucks, though.
I'm going to get my money's worth out of that cat.
So the evolution of the consciousness level
of the animal kingdom
is very, very informative.
You see?
And we start out very low
and then you see this incredible evolution.
What's it called?
Blue planet?
Blue planet.
Have you seen Blue Planet?
It's on TV.
It's an incredible special, you know,
like Channel 8 or whatever.
Anyway, it's subterranean.
It goes to the bottom of the sea
and you see all these creatures living down there.
And their ingenuity,
it's just absolutely incredible.
You know?
To not be able to see intelligent design
within their intelligence
is to really be blind
because these are very clever creatures.
You know, they pretend that they're a little fish
and they hang out there
and then their lights go on
and then they quickly become the same as that
which is attacking them.
And then there's this marvelous intelligence
and marvelous ingenuity.
The absolute genius of creation.
The genius of creation.
So, we go all the way from vipers,
Komodo dragons,
reptiles, snakes.
Don't get into the pen with a Komodo dragon.
And we come up through the whole animal kingdom here.
And we see at about level, consciousness level 200,
you shift from the predators to the herbivores.
These are exclusively reptilian
and dinosaurs.
Live solely by killing others.
And then around 200,
you see you shift to the elk,
the zebra, the giraffe, deer.
Here's our family cat.
Dogs, family dogs.
And you move on up
and you see then how amazing.
And then we see
the most amazing thing
is the cat and the dog.
The cat's purr
calibrates at 500.
And the dog's wagging tail
And the cat's purr calibrates at 500.
You see the emergence of love
in the animal kingdom.
Love.
And of course the kitties I got at home,
all you have to do is say,
how are you today?
And they start going purr, purr, purr, purr.
The capacity to recognize
and reciprocate to love
is a very, very unique thing.
And I've always just been amazed at that.
The dog's wagging tail.
All you have to do is say,
how are you, Bow-wow?
How are you?
Bow-wow.
Man's best friend.
Yeah.
Okay, so.
The next slide.
Oh, it's up there already.
Good God.
The great books of the western world
serve as a point of reference.
Roughly they calibrate around 450.
I forget what, 455 or whatever.
Anyway, they calibrate in the mid 400s.
It's gonna be important to today's lecture
because this is the point of reference.
See, the great books of the western world
really evolved out of an extension of ancient Greece,
the golden age of Greece.
So the basis of our civilization
is really the golden age of Greece.
And frankly, nothing has improved since then.
I hate to tell you,
but nothing has really improved
since the golden age of Greece.
And an intellectual, you know,
in the world of the mind.
Then we had the,
I was gonna say the period of the enlightenment.
We came out of the dark ages,
out of the dark ages,
black superstition and all.
And you have this golden age,
you might say, primarily in Europe.
The great thinkers of all time,
the great books of the western world collectively,
as I say, calibrate around 450, 460, around in there.
And I hate to tell you,
but these are all dead,
white men.
These are the oppressors of the proletariat.
I wanted you to understand
who the oppressors of mankind are,
because we're gonna talk about relativism today.
Logic and reason are oppressive.
Totalitarian, capitalistic, white men control.
Yeah.
So we will refute them then.
So we have St. Thomas Aquinas,
you know, the great saints of all time.
Aristotle, Socrates, Socrates is over here.
Socrates, someplace.
Anyway, no, they're not,
he's not in the great books of the western world.
So anyway, these are the great minds of history,
great minds of history.
And we notice that the only thing that's peculiar,
and it's gonna be very important in understanding
today's lecture,
is that they all calibrate in the like high 400s,
mid 400s, intellectual integrity,
the world of the intellect,
on our scale of consciousness.
The 400s are quite high indeed.
And you'll notice that in the middle of it suddenly,
what's that guy's name?
Suddenly you got Marx at 130.
And there you got the one apple that ruined the barrel.
All it takes is one apple.
One rotten apple to ruin the barrel.
And here he is.
And then of course he sided up with Engels.
Engels was at 200.
Now Marx never worked.
He lived off Engels' family,
Engels was left a business by his family.
And Marx hung out, didn't have to work
because he hung out with a rich guy.
So here he talks about, you know,
the fate of the worker, and he never was one.
He never was a worker.
I did more work than Marx ever did.
Let's see if that's a fact.
I did 10 times as much as Marx ever did.
I did 10 times as much work as Marx ever did.
He doesn't know anything about being a worker,
for Christ's sake.
He should have worked at the automobile factories
where I worked.
Yeah.
You can see what he thinks of his theory.
You can see what he thinks of his theories then, wise guy.
Anyway, these are the great minds,
the great minds, Sophocles, Shakespeare,
Plutarch, Plotinus, all the great names.
Freud, Galen, Harvey, and this is the whole world of science,
the whole world of science,
Hippocrates and all of science, the great philosophers.
These are the great names throughout history.
Francis Bacon, Dostoevsky, Euclid, the geometry.
Hardly to be sniffed at, right?
Well, we're gonna sniff at them today.
These oppressors, they're gonna get their due.
Okay, let's go to the next one.
We're all familiar with them for these lectures.
Now, intrinsic to today's lecture,
or not intrinsic, but interestingly, we see that below 200
is the level that the brain has a different physiology
from those above 200.
Therefore, they warrant mercy and forgiveness,
as the Lord Jesus Christ said,
forgive them for they know not what they do.
These people do not know what they do.
Let's ask.
That's a statement of fact, for instance.
They do not know or realize that which they do.
He said, forgive them, Lord,
for they know not what they do.
Wow.
That's another reason they need a savior,
because they're incapable of realizing spiritual truth,
and therefore, they need someone who will speak for them
before the Father.
So this is the animal instinct.
200 down is the narcissistic ego behind the animal,
which is only interested in gain and survival.
Gain and survival.
It's territorial, it's hegemonous.
You like that word, or hegemonous?
Dictionary says either way.
Chickened out.
This is hegemony, dominant, dominant, dominant.
It's vilified politically,
and there are current fashionable philosophers
that will tell you America deserves 9-11,
because America deserves the 9-11.
because of its hegemony, because of its success.
The fact that it's successful, it deserves to be attacked.
Oh, there's an interesting concept.
Evolution wouldn't have gotten too far with that one.
Now, we've evolved because that which is successful survives,
and that which is not does not.
All right, so this is left brain physiology,
and you're dealing with the alarm reaction.
You're dealing with the animal world.
And if you look at the world today, you'll see
the difference between the alpha male and a wolf pack.
The world is like a bunch of wolf packs.
You've got an alpha male killing off rivals to be president or king or head monarch.
And you see turf wars.
Every country is like in a turf war with that around it.
So this is the world of the wolf pack.
The wolf pack, the alpha male.
The wolf pack, the alpha male, et cetera.
The dictator.
The dictator who calibrates 90 or 100 to 190 operates completely off this.
Completely.
You don't see any compassionate.
They do not purr.
They do not wag their tail.
If you are nice to people like that,
they will become paranoid and suspicious and have you executed
because they know you're up to something.
Because in their culture, people aren't nice unless they're looking for something.
They don't understand being nice for nice sake.
That's why we have difficulty dialoguing with that part of the world.
We think, if we're really nice, they'll be nice to us.
Give me a break.
All right.
So below 200, the world is linear, pedestrian, causality, Newtonian.
And this is the world.
This is the alarm reaction, and people live off stress hormones.
Now, from 200 up, what happens?
The kundalini energy arises, the spiritual energy arises,
within the etheric body, and it goes up through the chakra system.
And it completely changes your etheric brain and how it operates.
The etheric brain now becomes dominant,
and it goes through, instead of the alarm reaction,
it goes into your memory as a positive, positive feeling.
Because the right brain puts out endorphins,
which are healing and support your thymic gland and stress reactions.
Also, it increases healing and recovery, balancing the acupuncture system.
And you get a positive kinesiologic response.
So in the presence of this energy field,
the alarm reaction sets in, the acupuncture system,
the energy system, your energy field goes down.
When you hold this in mind, your energy field goes up,
and the kinesiologic response is positive.
And we know now from Carol that the pupil response also is similar.
From stress, the pupil dilates,
and in peace, peace and harmony and love, it constricts.
So people who are critical of the kinesiologic response
try to make it like you're just finding out what you want to find out.
No, the pupillary response is not under voluntary control.
So that sort of dispels the critics of kinesiology.
Because when done with a slit lamp,
even though you don't see what the stimulus,
you can cloak the stimulus,
and of course we've done that on stage.
We've taken a fake painting, turning it around,
and a good painting is turning it around,
so you can't see what it is.
And when she looks at the back of a fake painting,
her arm goes weak.
When she looks at the back of a true painting,
the arm goes strong.
So it's the energy of it then.
The energy of it then radiates out in a quantum world.
Now the other thing that's odd about the kinesiologic response
and this whole phenomena is the physics of it.
What you're picking up is the energy field of consciousness itself.
Which is non-linear, non-local.
It has no beginning, it has no end.
It's outside of time.
It's outside of time-space and it's outside of causality.
So you can't cause it to do anything.
It is what it is as a consequence of it being its own nature.
Because it's outside of time,
the kinesiologic response,
you can ask anything about anywhere in time.
Because it's out of locality,
it has nothing to do with locality.
It's non-linear, it has no local.
There's no center to the universe.
So that which is infinite
is beyond time-space location or causality.
So not only can you ask anything about anything where in time,
you can also ask about anything anywhere in space.
So you're asking for the energy of an essence
which is beyond time and space
and it has to do with essence.
Essence is a different domain altogether.
They're also discovering,
also having to do with the critics of kinesiology,
that biologic phenomena cannot be accurately studied
via Newtonian physics.
For people who are scientifically educated,
Newtonian physics is not applicable to biologic phenomena.
Why?
Because biologic phenomena are regulated by a life energy
Life energy is non-linear.
You cannot delineate it.
The most recent discovery then
is that what they're forgetting to define is
the energy of life itself
is intrinsic, of course, to all biologic phenomena
and therefore the Newtonian paradigm of reality is too restricted.
And of course we now have the Heisenberg principle
that at least gives us some crossover
from the linear to the non-linear.
And we know that intention already changes
the output.
So, you know, in talking with other physicians,
you know, we commonly had the experience
that somebody who'd been treated by all the
Newtonian strict medicine techniques
were incurable.
And a person who was non-traditional,
you know, just got them better by loving them.
I had a couple of old patients that couldn't quit practice
so they left the planet
because frankly their positive transference
was keeping them going.
And I said to Susan, I said,
I've only got two left.
And finally one went
and then finally the last one went.
The last one who went was the guy
that used to get me to light his cigarette
so he had an oxygen tank.
In the Newtonian paradigm of reality
that would be foolish indeed, wouldn't it?
I said, are you sure it's safe?
He says, yeah, I do it all the time.
I said, okay.
He passed on, of other things.
Then a nurse later told me
that one time she'd done that
and it blew the oxygen tank
right through the floor of the trailer.
So I didn't do that anymore.
But I didn't have to
because the last little guy left.
So then I closed my practice.
Okay, now we'll go to the next.
Level of consciousness and social problems.
Relativism would like to say
all social problems are based on
the perpetrator-victim model.
So relativism is basically Marxism
but with the name Marx removed.
It's always perpetrator and victim.
So the people that are at the bottom of society
according to that politicalization
are always the victims of those
that are at the top of society.
You can't be poor anymore without being,
you're poor because you're a victim of somebody.
That's the first 35 or 40 years of my life
being a victim then
because the reason I didn't have
more money is because
those bad guys had it all.
They had billions.
And I'm writing this paper out
to make $40 a month.
So I was a victim.
No money at all.
Of course, the one reason there was no money
was that the Depression wasn't really over yet.
All right, so the level of consciousness
is related to the rate of employment.
Not to external bad guy predators at all.
It's because of who you are.
So you can look at people in society
that they are a cork.
Society is the ocean.
And each cork floats to the height of its own buoyancy.
You can take a certain person
and put him anywhere
and he will come out a success.
And you can take other people
and put them in the most advantageous circumstances
and they will blow it.
They'll blow it with a flash of hostility,
a flash of inappropriate jealousy,
paranoia,
inappropriateness somehow.
They had it made and they just blew it.
It's because that side shows up.
Okay.
So all the phenomena we see socially
are really evidence of the level of consciousness.
The level of consciousness.
You see, even criminality is related to it.
Happiness, race,
weight is related to it.
Poverty, unemployment.
All related to level of consciousness.
So that we could say within a certain field,
certain phenomena are common to that field.
Common to that field.
So these fields then
are accompanied by these phenomena.
Okay.
We'll go to the next one.
I'm bringing this up today
because we're talking about postmodernism
and relativism.
Here you have the Louvre
which calibrates at 500.
So this image pictorially, artistically would represent
let's say the great books of the Western world
which is traditional, beauty, aesthetics, etc.
Then comes postmodernism.
And I was here and I couldn't believe it until I saw it.
I said nobody would build something that looked like that
in the middle of the Louvre.
Nobody.
Ah, they did.
Leave it to the French.
Yes, anyway.
This was back in the 80s.
You know, back in the 80s.
Anyway, this is the impact of what we're going to be talking about today
in visual form.
In visual form.
This thing here certainly looks nice all by itself.
But in the middle of the Louvre,
it's an insult.
Is it not?
It's really insulting to the beauty of the Louvre.
Insulting to the beauty.
And inappropriate.
And from a certain viewpoint, grotesque.
Certain point of...
It's really an ugliness.
Because of the extreme disparity.
We could take an alternate view
and say that it's stark, cold glass,
lack of historic,
traditional beauty, etc.
Brings out the beauty of the Louvre.
Now we'd be really postmodern.
We could think it sounds very smart and modern.
We didn't think anybody would notice the beauty
and historic authenticity of the Louvre.
So we put this abortion right in the middle of it.
So that you could go,
Oh, Jesus.
We take a picture of the Madonna
and we put a tattoo on her shoulder, on her cheek.
I thought of doing that myself.
Take the Mona Lisa and put a tattoo right here, an anchor.
So that the viewer will notice her beauty.
Oh, thank you, perverse artist.
I didn't realize she was beautiful
if you put that anchor on her cheek.
Thank you so much.
Take this abominable slide off of here.
Oh, God.
Let's see.
Is this our slide list that we're doing?
Okay, fashionable philosophies.
We're going to get into them today.
The academic left 180.
Everybody sort of knows that.
Anarchism is about 100.
Atheism is about 165.
And I discovered why some people that I thought
shouldn't be having such problems do kinesiology.
One's a well-known professor.
And I thought,
Why is this guy only calibrating?
He couldn't do it.
And he writes against it and all.
He's at 190.
And I thought,
Why is this guy at 190?
He's out there for holistic medicine
and professor and all that crap.
And then I discovered,
I didn't even think of asking it,
he's an atheist.
Huh.
He doesn't lecture on atheism.
He lectures on good stuff.
But the reason he can't get kinesiology to work
is because he's below 200.
A lot below 200.
So,
we'll tell you right off the bat,
it doesn't work for atheists.
Those who deny the truth of God
are denied the gift of truth.
So, karmically it makes sense, does it not?
If you refute the very source and authority
and dignity of truth itself,
then you're not allowed to benefit.
So, they're like disenfranchised.
Okay.
We're going to get into Marcuse's critical theory today,
because that's going to be a good part of it.
Deconstructionism,
dialectical materialism
is the essence of Marx.
Now, what happened,
what happened a few decades ago,
1950s,
I forget when,
around in the 60s, 70s,
over there.
To try and preserve,
what happened is the Frankfurt School evolved,
in which various philosophers
tried to preserve the essence of Marx,
dialectical materialism,
by removing the name Marx
and calling itself instead
a school of social theory,
school of social theory.
But what you're going to see,
the modern world,
is nothing but that,
dialectical materialism in new clothes.
These are just phenomena that we see,
fascism and feminist politics,
somebody says,
you should vote for me because I'm a woman.
What's that got to do with being president?
Or I'm black,
or I'm Jewish.
What's that got to do with being president?
Being president has to do with understanding international politics,
the works of the United States government,
et cetera.
So they still play the sexism and color cards.
No, they're just cards.
Politics.
Free speech in the United States
is now down to 180,
and at the time of,
1955 or so,
it was 255.
We'll get into those a little bit later.
And hate is a very popular product,
calibrates around 70.
So news commentators and publicity people
get out there on panels and spew hate
because there's a big market.
Being hateful is profitable.
Wow.
Quick way to wealth, huh?
Irresponsibility.
We notice that a thing,
when it becomes an ism,
drops to 180.
That's going to be interesting
because when we go to,
you know,
the new earth-warming theories and all,
what happens is it becomes like a crusade.
A crusade.
So science is really damaged by these crusades
in which they give research grants
to people who agree with the political position.
Yeah.
And,
question of authority,
these are names that we'll get into later.
We won't waste any time on them right now.
Anyway,
the essence of what's going on in the world then
is actually the core of Marxism
with the name Marx removed.
But it's the same dialectic materialism
that makes everybody into victim and perpetrator.
Okay, next one.
Nutty professors are at 160.
Now, nutty professors will tell you
the truth is false and the false is truth.
That America bombed 9-11
and God knows what all.
And they're very relativistic
until it comes to their paycheck.
Suddenly,
$10,000 is not a relativistic,
$8,000, $6,000 is $10,000.
You say, well, things are only,
if truth is only what they appear to be,
then your lecture is only worth $10,000.
And I'll give you $10,
you should be satisfied with it.
No, they're not relativistic
when it comes to money.
Money.
So the way you get them out of being totally crazy
is to speak money to them.
Narcissism, 140.
All right.
But free speech, you see,
in 2007 is 180.
Free speech in 1955,
was 255.
So the modern electronic media
then are the royal road to hell.
Are they not?
Is it not?
Yes.
When I grew up, the bad guys were here
and the good guys were here.
We didn't have any problem.
We didn't worry whether America secretly pulled off,
what was it, the beginning of World War II?
Pearl Harbor.
We didn't wonder if, you know,
President Roosevelt had done it.
Let me see.
Oh, this is the beginning of relativism versus reality.
So we can get into it.
Okay.
When we're talking about a scale of consciousness,
we're really dealing from absolute.
Absolute is an amount of centigrade thermometer.
Water boils at 100 and it freezes at zero.
And that's an absolute phenomena.
It does not depend on what you think about it
or what its appearance is.
In relativism, perception is reality.
Not essence, perception.
So what it's saying is,
the sheep's clothing is what's real.
And don't mind the wolf underneath.
The sheep's clothing is what's real.
Huh?
Yeah.
So discerning essence from appearance.
We know that that's one of the most difficult things.
It doesn't happen within the individual
until about consciousness level 600.
At 600, you pick up the essence of a thing
and you glimpse the appearance,
but you know that's not what it really is.
But that's the opening of the third eye
of the Buddhic body, one of the etheric bodies,
which is above the crown chakra.
So discerning essence from appearance, then,
is at 600.
It's, of course, what we do with consciousness calibration.
The science of consciousness calibration itself
calibrates at 605.
It's God's gift to those of us
who would like to be able to see truth from a falsehood,
but are unable to do so for one reason or another.
Yeah.
So it, to me, is a gift.
We now have a means in which we can see
the truth which formerly was only apparent
to enlightened beings.
600 is very rare.
There's probably nobody on the planet at 600.
And those who get to 600 leave.
Half of them leave.
You're in such an infinite state,
I don't even want to think about the infinite state,
that you want to evaporate.
You just want to dissolve.
So there is no inclination to come back to the world
or to deal with the world.
And the world, you know, as you see it,
doesn't even matter.
You know, as you see it, it doesn't even exist.
So anyway, it's very rare then.
So here we've been given an awareness,
a means to an awareness
that previously was only possible
for a couple of people in any generation,
and historically very few in number.
So I considered it, you know, an amazing gift,
an amazing gift.
Just like discovering penicillin,
I could see the enormous benefit.
It could come to mankind.
Therefore, I had to write about it,
and that's why I'm still here.
I could have been gone a long time ago.
Well, I intuited a contractual obligation.
I intuited that there had been an agreement,
and that I had not fulfilled that agreement yet.
To discover a thing and then to explain it.
Yeah?
So the agreement was...
So because of that, okay.
To discern...
So this is absolutism.
I get a kick out of these rambling critiques of our work, you know.
And one of my members says,
Be forewarned, he's an absolutist.
Be forewarned, he's an absolutist?
Good God.
Mean truth is true and false is false?
Yup.
Sounds pretty oppressive to me.
What about my opinion?
So the alternate to absolutism,
is narcissism.
Which says perception is reality.
And you'll see that's a dictum flashing on the TV screen very frequently now.
Perception is reality.
Forget about essence.
It's what it looks like.
Look how we package it.
If we make it pretty and frilly,
and smell nice.
This guy buys this car.
He sees this beautiful thing.
So seductive, she lays on this car.
He can't wait to get to the...
To buy one.
Give me a new Fousey.
Where's the Brog?
I thought you got one of them in the car.
Seduction.
So what they do is they program you with this image,
with this product.
So that you're...
Pavlovian reflex.
So that what you've been programmed to comes up.
And you say, I want it. I want it. I want it. I want it. I want it.
Big juicy cupcake or big beautiful blonde.
Forget whether it's real.
Because perception is reality.
What you bought was the box.
I invented a new breakfast cereal called Gimmies.
Gimmies. Gimmies. Yum, yum, yum.
And then it's even got a clever advertising thing.
It's a little hand that comes out.
So when you put...
When the clerk puts it in the grocery store,
they move this, this little hand comes out.
It says, grab...
Or grab me. Grab me. Grab me.
Gimmie. Grab me. Gimmie. Grab me.
We could sell them.
Would you guarantee we could sell them?
Oh yeah, we could sell them.
Gimmies. Gimmie.
Now what's in the box is irrelevant.
And it can't have an old flake or something in it.
Because they've already bought the Gimmie. Grab me.
And they've already got the yum, yum, yum, happy.
They just bought it.
They don't care what's in the box.
The mother doesn't know what's in the box.
She opens it, hopes it's nutritious.
What's important is whether it likes it.
So absolutism is 650.
Relativism is 125 to 190.
It's even lower than 125 sometimes.
Shockingly low.
So I want to do this one first.
A wolf in sheep's clothing calibrates at 120.
That's the lowest energy of all the ones we're going to be talking about.
The wolf in sheep's clothing calibrates at 120.
There's the trap.
120.
I was shocked when I rechecked it over and over again.
Let's do it.
I can still believe it.
The wolf in sheep's clothing calibrates at 120.
There is the warrant to the conscious, to the wary person,
to the enlightened person.
Because your destruction is masked as a sheep.
Your destruction is masked as a sheep.
And the media are very clever at providing sheep's clothing.
Why is it important to know?
Well, in the long run, it probably isn't.
It has to do with survival.
I don't know if survival is important or not.
The world's interest in things being right is more important than survival, generally.
Being right.
All right.
So perception, then, is reality, is the basis of postmodernism.
And you see, Marx has the whole victim-perpetrator model.
And that's at 130.
130.
And so these have some intellectual input to them.
So relativism, the philosophies of it, are generally higher than 130
because you've added some intellectual fluff into it.
Mm-hmm.
The original, the originator, historically in ancient Greece,
is represented by Protagoras.
Protagoras at 190.
Protagoras' argument is this.
I live in my own reality.
What seems to me, you know, real is real to me.
You, on the other hand, live in your reality.
And what seems real to you is real to you.
Therefore, reality is merely perception.
When Judas said, therefore, perception is only perception,
not reality is perception.
What I think is reality, yes, it's true.
To some degree, that's solipsism.
Each person, you might say, lives in their own personal universe.
But most people of integrity realize that that doesn't mean
that that's necessarily the way it is.
Most people are aware of the fact that that's the way they see it.
So the beginning of the downfall was represented,
represented by Protagoras,
to whom his own statement was real.
It was then countered.
Therefore, your statement is not real either.
Therefore, your statement that what you think is real is real to you
is also false.
So Protagoras couldn't prove his own theorem.
If you can't contradict a theorem, then it has no validity,
because a true theorem is opposite and negates it.
Protagoras' relativism really died around 400 and something B.C.
Now, the most modern world hasn't gotten the word yet.
It was a dead argument in 450 B.C.
This argument was presented and shown to be fallacious even then.
So you can see what not reading the great books brings you to.
You don't even realize
that all the things you're discussing were settled thousands of years ago.
Thousands of years ago.
All right.
Plato calibrated 485,
and it's in his discussions that this argument comes up with Protagoras.
And you see that Plato calibrates at 485.
So the modern world throws out Plato at 485
and goes along with Protagoras at 190.
The fallen decline of Western civilization, you know,
is in free fall right now.
It rejects Jesus, Buddha, and Krishna.
Relativism, postmodernism, hates all these creatures here.
They've calibrated at a thousand.
It would rather be an atheist at 165.
Rather be an atheist at 165.
That's why relativists can't do kinesiology.
To begin with.
They set out to disprove it.
I'm going to prove the fallacy of that.
So they start out at 130.
It is what, you know, at 130,
in addition to which they're an atheist.
Therefore, of course it doesn't work for them.
I don't want it to work for them.
I don't want them to be able to do it.
All right.
So that pretty much answers what that problem is.
You see the apostles at 990.
And here you balance that with skepticism at 130.
Now, should we believe Socrates at 570?
Or should we believe Noam Chomsky at 135 to 185?
Well, Chomsky has replaced Socrates.
The great books of the Western world have been removed
by Harvard University.
Removed.
President of Columbia University currently is at 190.
President William and Mary at 190.
The idea of you don't want to appear old fashioned.
You want to be, you know, be with it.
Therefore, you throw out Socrates at 570.
And you adopt this politician, philosophical politician.
So are we going to have a break?
Four more minutes.
Oh, four minutes.
We can do Chomsky in four minutes.
Now, we'll get to the philosophers later.
All right.
Science, you see, calibrates.
It wouldn't seem like you've got to prove the value of science at 440 to 499.
Sir Isaac Newton, Einstein, Freud, 499.
From the viewpoint of relativism, science is oppressive at 160.
So the relativist is very anti-science.
Anti-science.
You'll notice that they're anti-science.
Because it has to do with logic and reason.
Logic and reason trumps perception.
And therefore, it has to be discarded.
So the anti-science bent then is sort of interesting.
Because we live in a world in which science pervades everything.
And they will tell you that science is oppressive.
I really have to read you a few things to prepare you for the shocks.
They'll have a break in which they can recover.
The basic postmodern dictums of relativism.
You're an uneducated lot.
And therefore, my job is to educate you.
I don't know how you got along without these amazing concepts.
Now, we'll have a whole list of philosophers.
What we showed you.
All the famous philosophers behind all this.
You're not going to believe this.
This is, I took it right out of the books.
And I've got the references right here.
The basic philosopher behind current modern postmodernism.
And the decline of the university.
Is Herbert Marcuse.
Marcuse.
Born in 1898.
Died in 1979.
Of unmentionable diseases and problems.
Marcuse is the main one.
The professors.
Who preach this.
Never read Marcuse.
They're like Marxists that never read Karl Marx.
Or Freudians that never read Freud.
They have never bothered to read it.
I will then make you more educated than a college professor.
Postmodern dictums of relativism.
Fiction is truth and truth is fiction.
How's that for a starter?
Herbert Marcuse.
Lying is legitimate.
Indoctrination is the purpose of education.
You thought you were sending your kids to college for education.
Forget it.
They're being indoctrinated.
I heard it with my own ears.
I wouldn't have believed it but I heard it with my own ears.
In one flash this professor came out with an indoctrinating dictum.
Yep.
Tolerance is really intolerance.
We should not be tolerant to conservatism.
It deserves to be destroyed.
So, all words mean their opposite.
Tolerance really means intolerance.
Ethics and morality are repressive and totalitarian.
Conservation should be attacked.
No, conservatism should be attacked and destroyed.
Of course, at Duke University, things like that happened.
The choir went there.
So, if a conservative tries to speak in any public university,
they're stoned, the crowds are there, pulled off the stage and attacked.
Marcuse recommends that.
That all conservatives be physically attacked and silenced.
All minorities are victims.
Here's the grandest of all.
The purpose of human life is sexualization, including that of children.
You should teach your kids all the various crafty perversions you can think of.
I've said it down backwards with children, rabbits, etc.
Any weird perversion you can think of.
And these philosophers, they're the basis of it.
Personally led those kind of lives and very frequently died of the consequences of them.
The purpose of life is sexualization, including that of children.
What is it he said? Drop something, tune in, drop out, right?
Sex and drugs and rock and roll, maybe.
The enemies of freedom are family.
You see, the family is to be removed.
The state will come in and give your kids a sexual education on the various perversions
by the time they're in their 30s.
By the time they're in third grade.
The enemies of freedom are family.
Of course, because they stand for traditional values.
Religion, patriotism, work.
Work is for the fools.
Science, reason, logic.
Morality, capitalism, tradition, and God.
These are the enemies of freedom according to postmodernism specifically.
A couple of very good books on the subject.
For those parents that are in a matter of shock here.
I'm not done yet.
You're going to be in worse shock.
There is a book called All American Colleges.
This is 50 colleges that all calibrate at 440 or over.
I'll give you the reference if you want.
We'll probably put it on our website.
It's by the Intercollegiate Studies Institute out of Wilmington, Delaware.
More about which I've just mentioned.
It's in a book called The Professors.
The Professors by Horowitz.
The one I like the best, although its title sounds somewhat insulting, is Intellectual Morons.
Why would you call anybody morons who said the truth is falsehood and falsehood is truth?
I don't know.
It's just being arbitrarily pejorative, I guess.
Well, I have to give the audience a break.
Because what we're taking about is the fabric of current society.
The book I'm working on is called Spiritual Reality in Modern Man.
The Spiritual Reality in Modern Man.
Because modern man is up against things that traditional man never had to put up with.
He wasn't being programmed constantly, both liminally and subliminally, and consciously and unconsciously all the time.
He wasn't being programmed.
Now it requires even greater than discernment than before.
Some of the slogans that flash in front of you constantly, don't forget they're repetitious.
Some commercials, I think I've probably seen them over a thousand times.
So just by sheer repetition, you become programmed.
So how can you ever reach spiritual reality in a world that is programming you with falsehood constantly, both consciously and unconsciously?
So we need to defend ourself.
And the way you defend yourself is you learn how to discern truth from essence, etc.
And they have such prevailing qualities that after a while you automatically begin to pick up when you're being programmed and when you're being had.
So it's out of defense of everybody that I want us to stand up for truth.
Stand up for truth, you know.
That's really where we're at, you know.
Okay, so we'll take a break. How long?
Fifteen minute break, yes.
So, we're ready to restart?
Okay, go, she says.
Now we gave you the fruit of these philosophers.
Now don't forget these professors who teach these concepts.
Never read the philosophic basis on which these came.
It's like being a rabid communist and you never read Karl Marx.
You don't even know if you agree with it.
But you know it's fashionable and it's a big parade and it's exciting.
Let's get involved, you know.
So I gave you a list because I want to be academically integrous myself.
The names of the philosophic, the basis of the philosophic theories.
We'll make these available in the book I'm writing right now, actually.
One just died, Jean Baudrillard.
Calibrates at 175.
He said America deserved 9-11 because it's successful and imperialistic, etc.
John Caputo, these are names known in academia.
Noam Chomsky, of course they all calibrate at 130, 140, 150.
Gilles Daluz.
190.
Jacques Derrida, 170.
Michael Foucault, very well known, 190.
Edmund Husserl, 195.
Lucy Irrigary, 155.
Julia Kristeva, 150.
Fritz Kuhn, 195.
Jacques Lacan, 180.
Jean-Francois Lyotard, another well known name.
How many people have heard of that?
Oh, you make good professors, yes?
Mark Kuh is at 150.
Of course, Mark's at 130.
Karl Popper at 185.
Jean-Paul Sartre, 200.
And now three well known names in academia.
Peter Singer, Gore Vidal, and Howard Zinn.
All below 200, yeah?
Those of you who are parents and struggle to get your kids through college,
I'm starting a new organization in which we are going to ask the universities for a refund.
The Ethical Refund Committee.
You mean this is what you were teaching my kid for my hard-earned money or the taxpayer's money, yeah?
Gee, thanks a lot.
I just learned something during the break that I didn't know what a hookup is.
I thought they were talking about hiccup, hiccup.
You go on this thing and you arrange a hiccup, a hookup.
It means a quick sex.
Everybody goes on the internet, hookup, hookup with me.
They don't mean, I thought it meant go with them, you know, introduce them and become friends and all.
It means a quickie on the fly.
I just learned this.
Oh, God.
That's what it means, you know that?
I think it's shocking.
Well, anyway.
That's because I'm a repressive white male.
Conservative, probably.
You see, the enemies of freedom are family, morality, ethics, religion, patriotism, work, science, reason, logic, ethics, morality, capitalism, tradition, and God.
So, I guess that takes care of that.
Back to being an old fogey, I guess.
All right.
So now, I'm going to try and give you the intellectual underpinnings of it because a lot of people get, as I say, videos of this.
A lot of people study a lot of stuff off these lectures and they then look it up.
So, I want them to have the references of where to look it up so they don't think I'm just ranting.
So, in this side, I put that which is aligned with truth and integrity.
Let's see.
Chivalry, Calvary, it's at 465.
I grew up in a world of chivalry.
Everybody defended women.
Not to belittle them.
Because they honored them.
We honored women.
We stood up when a woman entered the room because we honored her.
They don't understand honor, that we were honoring her.
We're not belittling her.
We're honoring her.
I still find it difficult to watch a woman filling her own car at a gas tank at a filling station.
The world I grew up, nobody would allow a woman to get all greasy and dirty and crappy like that.
Then they came out and did it for you.
So, we did it not to belittle women, which is post-modernistic intellectual distortion,
but because we loved them and honored them.
Yes?
You get that difference, you see?
We weren't belittling them, saying you're too weak to do that.
Here, let me do that at all.
Yeah.
So, chivalry calibrates at 465.
Its downside is sexism at 180.
Its real downside is honor killing at 90.
There are cultures in which if the woman gets raped, she goes to prison.
Pakistan, the prisons are full of women who were raped.
It's her fault that she got raped.
So, there you're seeing the diametrically opposite of chivalry.
The chivalry, the man would be indignant about who raped the woman.
And here's the culture that stones her.
That stones her to death.
And then it doesn't honor killing, kills her family to preserve the family honor.
All right.
So, Orwell, in Orwell's 1984, predicted today's society extremely accurately.
And he predicted newspeak.
And that's what is now called politically correct.
It's called newspeak.
Exactly.
And what did he calibrate?
425.
And newspeak, you see, 180 is today's politicized social discord at 180.
180.
So, he predicted and now it's called newspeak.
What is it called politically correct?
It's called newspeak.
And he pointed out that newspeak was extremely oppressive.
So, the paradox of this is that the new freedom is more oppressive than the totalitarianism
that it alleges to displace.
You misspeak once, you just lost your job, right?
All it takes is one.
So, here we have Orwell at four and a quarter.
Newspeak is now the language.
And on college campuses, newspeak is imperative.
In fact, they have laws on the campus that you are not allowed to speak anything except
newspeak.
You know that you're only allowed on the campus to speak newspeak?
You are not allowed to talk about ethics, morality, all right.
Patriotism is not allowed on the college campus.
When I was in college, they had recruiters from various industries, companies, including
the military.
Because the military was one option, which is, you know, a suitable option.
You can join the military, you can get an education, and if you come from a poor family,
if it wasn't for the GI Bill, I never would have gotten through college, you know?
So, but now, do you realize that the military is not allowed on the campus?
So, this is the new freedom.
The new freedom is all kinds of languages cannot be spoken.
No conservative clubs can meet on the campus.
The military recruiters are not allowed to recruit.
That's the new freedom.
And in newspeak, that's freedom.
In newspeak, that's the new freedom.
So, if I couldn't have signed up for the Navy, I don't know how I would have gotten through medical school.
I signed up early when I was 17.
And when I got to the recruiting station, he says, you don't weigh enough.
He says, go home and eat bananas.
And he'll come back in two weeks.
So, I did.
I stuffed myself in bananas.
I can't stand a banana to this day.
I stuffed myself with bananas.
And I went back two weeks later, the same recruiting officer.
He says, get on the scale.
So, he put his thumb like this, and he said, you just make it 100 pounds.
He fudged about 4,500 pounds, I guess.
But his thumb was congenitally.
He did it so expertly.
He said, you just make 100 pounds.
Oh, boy.
There's 1980.
All right, here we have Sigmund Freud, calibrated 499.
And, of course, I will say that I might have some prejudice because I had a Freudian signal analysis.
And my analyst was Abraham Karner, whose analyst was Sigmund Freud.
So, he's my great-grandfather.
So, I might as well tell you that.
I might have a bias.
However, I'm not biased about the calibration.
The calibration is at 499, the same as Einstein.
The modern explanation of intra-psychic conflict is that it's caused that you're the victim,
and somebody is to blame that you're screwed up.
It's somebody's fault.
It's somebody's fault that you're.
Oh, I want to ask a question about this list of.
What I would call incorrectly crazy professors.
Taking them all off weird sex drugs and putting them on a mild anti-psychotic would have helped all of them resist.
If you read their personal lives, you'll see what I'm saying.
You know, their personal lives were so dissolute.
And they died of various venereal diseases and various things.
And sort of borderline schizophrenia.
The difference you see in schizophrenia.
You can't differentiate levels of abstraction.
So, they cannot differentiate a label from the thing itself.
To them, the label is the thing.
And that's why they have such difficulty in the world.
They cannot isolate levels of abstraction.
And, of course, Descartes.
I mean, who was it?
Not Descartes.
The levels of abstraction are part of the teachings of the great books of the world.
The Western world.
Don't mix levels of truth.
You see, what's true at this level is not true at this level.
What's true in this situation is not true in that situation.
Because truth depends not only on content but also context.
So, what is legitimate or okay in one situation is not in another.
And these philosophers mixed up labels with reality.
And I remember the disaster that happened to psychiatrists.
There was a guy who wrote a book, Thomas Szasz, postmodern kind of thinking.
And the whole concept of labeling.
There are no mentally ill.
Those are just labels.
Okay.
Here's God telling him to kill people.
Well, you can cure that usually with some kind of a medication.
So, the thing about mental illness is you can turn it on with a medication and turn it off with a medication.
The only thing you change is the medication.
And therefore, it's not, you know, just a, they're not victims of society.
Free speech in 1955 calibrated at 255.
Free speech in today's world calibrates at 180.
Therefore, I agree with Socrates that the downfall of democracy and Western civilization will be via free speech.
Yes?
If you give everybody a chance to vote for what is and half the people calibrate below 200, what are you going to get out of it?
What are you going to get out of it?
If people cannot tell truth from falsehood, then where will it lead?
Let's do the calibration level of the Western world.
Western world.
The Pope said it's the Western civilization that's at risk.
Western civilization in 1955 calibrated over 205, 206.
Calibrated 205.
In 1955, Western civilization calibrated at 205.
Can anybody hold that in their mind?
Okay.
Okay, currently, Western civilization calibrates over 199, 200.
Calibrates over 200.
It went down from 204, 205 to 199.
So, therefore, what the Pope said is true.
Resist.
What the Pope said is true.
We are witnessing the decline of Western civilization, of course.
It's already happened in Europe.
Europe's already had it.
It's already wimped out, I think it's called.
There's a new book that sounds startling.
It says something like,
Psycho's on the left of me, wimp's on the right.
All right.
So, we see without personal responsibility at 475,
what happens is that free speech at 255
drops down to the level of narcissism.
Because of narcissism then,
so narcissism and free speech then,
what you're doing is giving a loaded gun to children.
Free speech is a very powerful weapon.
And you put it in the hands of people who are not,
don't take personal responsibility.
Therefore, out of free speech then becomes the tool of narcissism
in which cultures that kill women for having been raped
are supposed to be welcomed into our society
where they can establish shiara.
Shiara calibrates at 190.
You see, honest dissent and disagree is 495.
The sophistry that goes with treason and sedition, et cetera,
is free speech.
They say, well, that's just free speech.
No.
Free speech is honest dissent.
I can disagree with many things in the government,
and I do.
I wouldn't give you a nickel for most of it,
but the way it runs, I mean,
if you ran your own household that way,
you'd be bankrupt in no time.
And,
all right, so you don't have to go to sedition at 140
or treason at 105.
During the break, we were remembering Tokyo Rose.
I think it was the only one ever executed for treason
in the last century, huh?
Tokyo Rose during World War II.
And then there was Lord Ha Ha.
These were anti-American treasonous and sedition.
So they could have, you could, so,
your option is if you don't agree with the United States
or its politics or with the Republicans
or the Democrats or whoever,
you can be honest dissent and disagree,
and that's still integrous.
Therefore, the option is to become a conscientious objector.
Now, conscientious objector calibrates over 300, 400, 375,
375.
Conscientious objector is 375.
It's integrous.
You say, I don't believe in killing people.
I'll serve in the military,
and I can do many things.
I can do warehousing.
I can do secretarial work, radio work.
I just, it's against my inner self.
I just can't kill another human being.
So you can be integrous,
and the option is not to become a deserter or a turncoat,
but to be a conscientious objector.
I wasn't a conscientious objector,
but I'm very happy that I never had to pull the trigger
on anybody in World War II.
You see, I never, I'm very happy I didn't have to be the gunner.
So I was the assistant bosun's mate at the time,
and all I had to do was keep the ship
from getting blown up by mines,
but I didn't have to shoot anybody.
So that would be within myself.
I did not, you know, wish to be the agent
by which others are killed,
but I didn't make others wrong for doing it,
because, you know, I could see how they saw their duty,
and I saw if I'd been ordered to do it,
I suppose I would have,
because I was respectful of authority,
and after all, you are in the war.
The U.S. National Anthem,
Pledge of Allegiance of the Flag,
calibrates at 510.
Treason calibrates at 80.
So a Pledge of Allegiance then, see?
What it has, what it's really,
your love of mankind,
this is your love of country.
The National Anthem, et cetera,
it brings tears to many people's eyes.
You put your hand over what?
The National Anthem, you don't go like this,
that's military.
You put your hand over your heart,
that it's your love for your country,
your esteem for your fellow man,
your extended family,
even if you disagree with them.
You can disagree with them.
So you don't have to resort
instead of, the opposite of patriotism
and love of country and honor
is not hate America.
So many now, and they're on television,
you know, television big names,
specialize in hate America.
And the excuse is,
because I disagree with its decisions.
That's not the only opposite.
You can honestly dissent and disagree
and be 495,
and you don't have to be certain people
who instead hate.
All right, hate gets you good ratings, they say.
Playing the victim card, playing the race card,
the colored card, all this, you see?
Hate America pays well.
Now Bush said one thing that we calibrated.
It was money trumps peace.
It's over 375, 380.
Yeah, we calibrated 375.
Money trumps peace calibrates at 375.
Hmm.
Where does that put all the peace people?
They need more money.
They better start quick parades
and start gathering money.
Okay, so I thought that's interesting.
But I just want you to see honest dissent.
You don't have to become a traitor.
You don't have to go into sedition.
You don't have to vilify your country.
You don't have to vilify servicemen.
You don't have to vilify the president
or the United States of America.
You have an option to merely disagree.
Disagree.
Mm-hmm.
Is that interesting?
Anybody got any questions to clarify that?
Because it's really important to see that,
that your option, you can still remain integrous
and disagree.
As I say, I disagree with a lot of things
that go on with the government.
Both parties included, you know.
Don't agree means I would do it differently.
But I just know that I would do it differently
is only my personal opinion.
I don't feel that the world has to,
that I've made some pronouncement about reality.
Perception is reality.
All right.
So that's, any questions about that?
Anybody, is it clear enough?
If it's clear, I'm very, very happy.
Oh, boy, am I happy.
I thought it might be difficult to get across.
Okay, we'll go to the next thing then.