Okay, this is where we sit.
What happens next?
Exciting.
Who knows?
The shadow knows.
>> Only the shadows.
>> Yes. What evil lies in the hearts of
men?
>> Who are you?
>> The shadow knows. Um, I'm Randy
Langston. I used to take your journal,
the u orthomoleiccular psychiatry. I
practice ENT and allergy years ago. Um
my question is um about you know if I
have if I have strong opinions about
something and then trying to calibrate
it for example say political parties if
um if Franklin Pierce were running and
uh I had strong opinions about Franklin
Pierce would that affect the ability to
calibrate
>> it would unless you're it would unless
you're pretty sophisticated
>> u a few people are really capable of
being sufficiently detached that they
really want to know the truth.
>> Mhm.
>> So what you can do like in let's say
politics you're bringing up
>> uh is you calibrate the people they hang
out with. Birds of a feather flock
together
>> and so you you calibrate who do they
hang out with. Uh and that will give you
the group because groups usually
calibrate around the same. you know,
>> they're either above 200 or below 200
for one thing.
>> Uh, so if somebody hangs out, if they're
closest associates over the years have
all been members of the mafia, you don't
have to really calibrate them. You
could, you just know the general area in
which, you know, this person is aligned,
you know.
>> Mhm. Uh but becoming detached, there's a
way we do it with this sometimes
is we'll write a thing down and put it
in an envelope and I'll say the name I
have in the envelope stands for somebody
who calibrates so and so. Okay.
>> So I'm not influencing her at all.
>> Uh so you can do it blind like that.
>> Right.
>> Yep.
>> Okay.
>> It's hard to be detached. It really
takes a scientific education. The
scientist is only interested in the
answer to the problem. He's not
interested. He doesn't have any invested
interest in what the answer is. You know
what I'm saying?
>> True.
>> Yeah. So that that that's one way around
it.
>> All right.
>> Especially when it comes to politics,
it's very hard for people to be
detached, you know.
>> Yeah. It's connected to so many things.
Your childhood, your culture, the world
you grew up in.
>> You know, I grew up, you know, in World
War II. So, uh, the world I I grew up
in, the the depression was already on
and, uh, uh, the end of prohibition came
and, uh, people made money running a
little booze out to the university.
That was not considered to be, uh, you
know, anything bad at all, you know,
>> make a little bathtub gin, you know.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. But there are probably a lot of
people that would consider that
horrible, you know. So,
>> okay,
>> that answers it. Thank you very much.
Thank you.
>> Making Beth Beth have gin. My
grandfather was good at that. Juniper
berries.
It's still alcohol and put in juniper
berries. And you got
that was a different era. Era.
Yeah.
>> Am I signing in the right place? I can't
tell.
>> I had a darker pen to bring and I don't
know what happened to it.
What is that book? It looks familiar.
>> Oh, that's what I thought. Okay.
What version is this? Is the lamps of
Bible or the
>> Eastern text?
>> That's the lamps of Bible.
>> Yeah. That calibrates higher than the
King James version. King James version
is from the Greek. The Lumps of Bible
is from the Eastern manuscripts.
>> Yes.
>> Hi doctor. I have never calibrated
anyone or anything and I have great
curiosity about learning how to do that.
>> Yes.
>> I have read your descriptions of how to
do that. But my question really centers
around finding someone with whom I can
Oh yeah. practice.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's sometimes a problem
to find somebody that can practice with
you. In a group like this, there's lots
of people. Usually there's groups that
that are curious about it and interested
in practice it. Uh
I suggest you do it blind. You say uh
what I'm holding in mind calibrates over
you. The first thing you want to know is
it over or under 200? Because if it's
over then you're you know levels of
truth. What level of truth? If it's
under 200 then you know it's not truth.
You see, so the the main thing you want
to know is it over or under 200. That's
the main thing you want to know. And it
should not be too difficult to find
somebody who will go weak when they
picture the devil and go strong when
they picture an angel.
>> Part of my concern is that I may not
calibrate over 200.
>> Oh, you don't have to calibrate over 200
>> to be able to.
>> Well, you're interested in truth. People
under 200 are not interested in truth.
They're interested in propagating what
they believe in.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Let's ask with the arm something. He's
capable of learning the technique.
Resist. Yeah. You wouldn't be interested
otherwise.
>> Thank you.
>> People are not interested in the truth.
Do want to find out how do you find out
the truth?
>> Thank you very much.
Am I signing these right? I don't know.
I don't have the right pen. I don't know
what I did with the right pen.
>> I'm sure I had it ready for today.
>> Hi.
>> Yes.
>> Um, my only question is um I wanted to
ask you for a blessing today.
>> For what?
>> A blessing.
>> A blessing. Yes.
>> You want a blessing because you're
spiritually aligned.
Correct.
>> Trying to be
>> that trying to be means that you are
you're on the road.
>> I am. So I certainly feel no uh I
certainly bless the
your your spirituality
and cooperate it and pledge it to the
highest good.
>> Thank you.
So
>> dedicate your spiritual awareness to the
highest good that it serves not only
yourself but your fellow man. thing cuz
every time you raise because when your
level of consciousness goes up it
benefits all of mankind.
I say when your the level of the sea
goes up it lifts all the ships at sea.
>> Thank you.
>> Be all that you can be out of your love
love for mankind
>> and love for God and that gives it even
more power.
>> Okay.
>> Dedicate your spiritual awareness for
the good goodness of all. and the relief
of suffering of mankind.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Is that microphone working? Okay. Is
everybody hearing everything? All right.
Yeah.
Yes.
>> Earlier I used visualization for a long
time to try to achieve my goals in the
everyday life.
>> I'm not hearing
>> um he's used v visual visualization in
his trying to um achieve his goals in
everyday life.
>> Yeah. Visualize what what you wish for
yourself.
>> Yes. Then I learned your uh teachings
and I gave it almost completely uh up.
Surprisingly enough uh my life did not
collapse.
>> I'm not hearing I'm not hearing
>> in the opposite.
>> I'm not hearing something wrong with the
microphone.
>> So echo back.
>> I see. So I gave it up
>> here. Come closer. See what happens. And
the question raised how to find balance
between the willingness uh to achieve
the goals in everyday life and between
the willingness to accept the ev the
evolution of life.
>> How to achieve balance between what?
Spiritual evolution and
>> yes
>> practical
>> and the practical goals.
>> Practical world
>> goals.
>> Goals or why do you see them as
different?
Um,
I'm not certain.
>> They're not different.
You know, if I'm a surgeon, I ask God to
help me to be the best surgeon I can
possibly be for the good of the patient
and everyone.
Now, if I end up being a better surgeon,
then it benefits me indirectly because
everybody says, you know, I hear he's a
very good surgeon. See, but you you
don't do it so that everybody thinks
you're a great surgeon. You do it
because of the excellence of your
dedication to what you're doing.
>> I see.
>> Yeah. So, if I'm selling vacuum cleaners
from house to house, I I pray to be able
to sell, you know, as many vacuum
cleaners as possible.
Yep.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Wanting to be the best you can be at
whatever you do. Whatever you do. Yeah.
Whatever you do, you ask it to be the
best you can be at that, you know.
Okay. Thank you very much. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
>> Best you can be at whatever you do.
Yeah.
Boom.
Yes, indeed.
>> Hello.
>> Uh, my question for you today is one
that's been bothering me or I've had for
a long time is when Jesus said that no
one comes to the father but by me.
>> Yes.
>> How do you go somewhere by someone? What
exactly did he mean?
>> Yeah. Jesus, if you uh
if if Jesus Christ is your teacher, your
ultimate teacher, then he is your ad he
he says in return I will become your
advocate before the father. He I will
speak for you as an advocate before the
father. Jesus Christ calibrated at a
thousand. So that would be a very
powerful friend in Congress.
>> Yeah.
So he vouches for you.
I vouch to the degree that any error I
have taught I will I will speak before
the father that I taught you incorrectly
that I stand by the truth of what I I
teach to the best of my knowledge and
that I will attest to the Lord that I
have spoken incorrectly to them and I
will speak in your behalf so that I make
that pledge to you as a teacher
that I will take responsibility that I
incorrectly informed you.
Yes.
>> Thank you.
There is an aspect of the Buddha that uh
is the same. will speak for you in on
the celestial realm
of vatabara or something
the Buddha of uh
the something land of Buddha of
>> Yes. Yes. who functions the same as
Jesus Christ but in the Buddh Buddha
realm you might say. Yes.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Uh, is it is there
any downside to not looking at the ID?
In therapy sometimes, you know, you ask
questions and then you really look at
the dark side of the ID. Is there any
downside to not looking at it?
>> What is it? What
>> is there any downside to not looking at
the ID?
>> To not looking at the
>> in therapy sometimes, uh, you know, you
ask how well, how does that make you
feel? How does that make you feel? And
the it sort of comes out. Does that make
sense?
>> Is there any harm in looking at the id?
>> What's your question?
>> Is is there any harm in Is there any
downside to not looking at the id?
>> Yeah. Unconsciousness.
In politics, people specialize in not
looking at the end.
And in politics, malice, fraud,
anything's okay just as long as you win.
Yeah. Now, the more sophisticated person
wants to know, you know, what what does
ask yourself, what does mankind
generally
want to admit about itself and then
project it onto others. So, the value of
understanding the id is you see what
people do not want to admit about
themsel and they therefore project it
onto others.
So all the evil that they see everywhere
is generally a projection of their own
hatred, hostilities, fears, jealousies
etc.
So in psychoanalysis you become familiar
with the id. The id is all that is
forbidden and repressed.
One of the deepest things hidden is the
death instinct.
Death instinct.
The desire to kill.
Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Freud said there's aeros and thantos.
Aeros is the basic instinct of life and
love. Thanoos is the basic attraction of
death.
And certainly at the guillanti
guillotine 15,000 died in the guillotine
and throngs by the hundreds of thousands
witnessed the event
their death instinct. Yeah. Yes.
>> Hello. Um, I listen to you discussing
prayer and I pray morning and evening
and sometimes in between and I always
ask the Lord, may I be a servant of the
Lord as part of that? And when I do that
every morning,
>> put yourself close to the mic. See if I
can hear you better.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> I've I've asked to be a servant of the
Lord.
>> Yes. So anything that shows up in my
world that day is mine for some reason
>> because I I have asked for it.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> So if I've got um a tremendous amount of
pain like physical pain and it's not
gone away with say treatment or I've
tried to disappear it according to your
tapes. So would I be right in assuming
that this is karmic and possibly I've
caused pain to others and this is I
>> I have pain and I just pray to forgive
myself to have forgiveness for having
caused pain to others and just suffer it
like just I have to live like the pain
just has to be felt. Is is that right?
>> Not necessarily but it is an option at
one time.
uh later on you can let go experiencing
the pain itself.
Uh if you quit resisting it eventually
it will run out.
Pain will only last so long. So
if you quit resisting it and eventually
it runs out. When you've run out that
you know Es used to call it a stack when
when that stack has run out it's run
out. Yes.
>> Okay. So uh but a certain what I was
wondering is like what I said to myself
and as part of my prayer since it hasn't
gone in other ways that for some reason
I do have to experience it.
>> Well then you weren't praying if you're
willing to resist it.
You're questioning it, right?
>> Yes.
>> First you ask for it, then you question
it and don't want it when you get it,
right?
>> Yes. Yeah. I
I think I think I've got the answer.
>> You got it. Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> It'll go away.
>> Yeah.
>> It'll either go away or your awareness
of it will disappear.
It'll still be there if you think about
it, but you never think about it. So,
>> hi. Um,
in working with young children like age
six or seven, what would you say are the
top one or two spiritual practices that
are important for supporting them?
>> I can't understand.
>> She's working with children that are
like six and seven age group six and
seven. Yeah.
>> What would you say is their top uh
practices that you would advise to them
to use
>> the children to use? Because you said
the link to happiness.
>> Yeah. The
>> remember the first slides he did on the
link between happiness
>> between happiness
>> and joy and
>> joy
>> to get them up to those states.
>> To get them up to those states.
>> Six-year-olds you don't have to worry
about. They're already in that all the
time.
>> I guess I guess supporting them to stay
in that. I guess trying to do some some
things to help. If you develop the
capacity to be loving and concerned
about others, loving concerned about
others, also loving towards yourself and
loving towards your parents, loving
towards your classmates.
That's probably the most advanced thing
you can learn, you know,
>> kindness.
>> Kindness. Yes.
>> Yeah. Children can be nasty.
>> They could be really the worst,
>> especially to each other.
>> Yep.
>> So, I would teach him kindness out of
anything else and compassion. Well, you
can start with animals, kindness to
doggies and kitties and that which is,
you know, going to protect itself,
>> compassion for all living things. Yeah.
>> And the willingness to help each other.
>> Friendliness. Yeah.
>> Friendliness and willing to, you know,
if someone if a child falls down, go
over and see if they need help or, you
know, help them up. So, you know,
six-year-olds, if you teach that at that
age, I think that that makes them better
human beings in the long run. That's
kindergarten, first grade, right?
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Better you than me.
Yeah.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Hello, Susan.
>> Um, okay. So, my question has to do with
the moment of death. with the mode of
death.
>> The moment
>> moment of death. Yes.
>> And um I guess it's a fear of that I'll
go to sleep and I and
wanting to stay awake, you know, when I
die. If that makes
>> No, you won't want to stay awake.
>> I won't.
>> What would you want to hang on to that
for?
>> I had a Okay. I had a Buddhist teacher
before who said that if you don't stay
awake
when you're dying that you'll end up
back on the karmic wheel. Um, does that
that doesn't make any sense?
>> Oh, I know what you're saying. Yes. If
you're not aware that you're dying and
and you go on living not knowing that
you're dead,
>> that is a problem. Yeah.
>> So, can you call out for help from
somebody like you at a time like that?
Um
>> you can choose to remain conscious
through the transition
first of all by knowing that death is
not a possibility.
The only thing can happen is you leave
the body. But you're right a lot of
people believe in death is such an
extreme you know amount that they'll
sometimes go unconscious for a couple
hundred years.
>> So you can choose to stay conscious.
>> You can choose to stay conscious.
You ask God to be with you. And don't
forget you have helper angels. You ask
your gu your guiding angels to help you
stay conscious and to learn from this
experience through this transition. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> And when you die, you're not going to
really care about it at all because the
body is laying there, but you're not the
body. So, it's rather irrelevant what
what's happening to the body. In fact,
the body is extremely boring.
>> It's a dumbl looking thing. The idea
that you ever cherished it to such a
degree seems like an absurdity.
>> Okay.
>> It's really a dumb looking thing laying
there.
There any desire to get back in at day
truth. If you're karmically decent that
you have to go back, you do. But it
isn't,
you know, you think, well, you would
have an aversion to leaving the body and
physical death. On the contrary,
>> okay,
>> on the contrary.
Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Hi.
>> Um I have a I guess a psychoanalyst
question. um if when going through the
process of um you know working with a
therapist, they ask you to uh drag up
your childhood memories and and try to
um unear things that are causing pain
and I just want to ask your uh advice is
what's the best way to deal with that?
Is it
>> does a therapist actually ask you to do
that? Uh it's actually a family member
of mine and they have Yes.
>> Usually well in psychoanalysis you you
report anything and everything that
comes to your mind as it arises. You
don't try to categorize it. This is
childhood. This is adolescence.
This is more like a scholarly
>> okay
>> examination of yourself. But that could
be a place to start a scholarly
examination of what your childhood was
like etc. Mhm.
>> And that of course will bring up
associated memories and feelings
and it's the associated
interpretation and feelings that you
know you work with in therapy.
>> Okay.
>> The fact that you were born and
graduated from kindergarten at age five
is just immaterial you know.
>> Okay.
>> But the events that happened there and
the emotions that were left with that
you try to see a connection between
those things and the past.
>> Okay.
And is it if you have like a like let's
say you had an abusive parent, right?
Is it enough to just experience it or is
there a tool like um and the family
member I'm that I'm talking to or I'm
asking about is having a lot of trouble
forgiving that they had an abusive
mother. Um is there a tool that is is it
just to you know the the therapist has
asked them just to bring it up right and
just to experience it and experience it
like a victim like as a child. Is that
enough or is this should we seek help
elsewhere? I guess is a
>> well you you you bring it up and see the
conclusions that you drew about yourself
and about life etc. And you you try and
compare that to a more sophisticated
adult view.
>> Okay.
>> And to like so it's more like
re-education more like re-education
but it may take some some working
through to re-educate yourself.
>> Okay. that to make make a mistake
doesn't mean that you're worthless and
have to go hide in the closet and kill
yourself.
>> Okay.
>> That it's okay. So a more permissive
super ego. Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> It's not necessary to take such an
extreme
self-punitive view of mistakes and
errors.
So you become more congenial toward
yourself.
Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you so much. Could you explain um
the difference between compassion
towards someone and enabling so that I
can make sure that I'm not getting in
the way of someone's karmic
undoing?
>> Compassion means accepting that that's
part of the human potential.
And um
and compared to what was the compared to
what?
>> Enabling.
>> Enabling. Oh, enabling. Well, enabling
means to assist the other person in that
behavior, to assist, to contribute to
it. If they're problem is they're
feeling sorry for themsel, an enabler
would say, "Oh, poor so- and so. Oh, you
did have a terrible time and you know,
potentiated
instead of trying to get the person to
see that that's that was happened at
that time for what could be learned from
it at that time, but now is a different
time." And therefore we have to grow
beyond these things. Enabling means you
assist the person with excuses for to
continue pathologic behavior.
You know the classic example is the
alcoholic whose spouse you know makes
excuses for him etc. So the take
responsibilities.
So it' be a matter of taking
responsibility. So you're not enabling
if you insist that the other person take
responsibility for that.
Thank you.
>> Yeah. So, they're not playing victim.
>> Thank you.
>> All right.
I always feel like I could answer it
better than I do, but I guess
may or may not be. So,
who
Yes,
>> Susan.
>> In all of the Hawkins
materials I've been exposed to and the
lectures I've attended, I've only heard
you talk about past lives as a man.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Have you ever been a woman?
>> I don't recall any lifetime as a woman.
>> Is that a karmic propensity?
>> I don't know.
I don't recall
uh a feminine lifetime
for whatever reason. I haven't
researched it.
And I would have to ask uh
uh let me just see. I have permission to
ask about this. I have had feminine
lifetimes resist. Well, what do you
know?
He just can't recall right now.
>> Well,
>> well, I mean, if I was interested in
researching it, I would.
>> It just hasn't come up.
>> Okay.
>> If I was pregnant, I'd look into it.
>> So would I.
>> Might be a problem.
>> No, I don't recall any spontaneously.
That's an interesting question. I've
never been asked before and I've never
looked at it.
>> The only ones I consciously recall were
all male lifetimes.
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> That's funny. I never looked at that
before.
>> Hi Is Barack Obama a Marxist socialist?
>> You knew this was gonna come up.
>> What is a Barack Obama a Marxist
socialist?
>> Is he a monster socialist?
>> He's a socialist.
>> He is.
>> Yeah. Admittedly, he says he's a
socialist,
>> but like a mar a Marxist.
Like a seriously Marxist socialist.
Not consciously Marxist per se.
>> No,
>> but the Marxian dialectic, you have to
understand the Marxian dialectic,
even if you depoliticize it, is
picturing life as perpetrator and
victim.
>> You can then project that on everything
and anything.
All minorities thereby become
victims. All all including people who
believe in God who lure in the minority
in large parts of the world. So a
picture you know what you picture is
what you define then is what you find
and what you look for. Mark the Marxon
dialectic is one of perpetrator victim.
It sees it because it projects it the
way it projects it. There's two trees
trees in the forest. Here's the little
for little tree. Here's the big tree.
All right. The sun comes this way. So
the big tree throws the small tree into
shadow.
So a Marxene would say, "Well, the big
tree is robbing the small tree of
sunshine and energy."
>> See,
>> he's not robbing it. It just is what it
is. There's no
evil intention behind it. You see,
>> I just have concerns about
>> Yes. I have concerns about him becoming
president of the United States of
America and the global implications that
>> and what
>> and the global implications of that.
>> Yeah. Well, so is everybody.
>> Yeah. Good. Well, the polls don't show
that everybody's concerned. The polls
don't show
>> the polls do. Don't you watch Fox News?
>> Well,
all
>> what what do you watch? NBC or what? I
watch Fox News, but the polls still show
Obama leading by eight points. And so,
>> yeah,
>> you know, it keeps
>> Have they called you for a poll?
>> No,
>> they haven't called me either.
>> They haven't called me.
>> Well, so there's hope still.
>> So, that tells you right there. I don't
think the polls are balanced.
>> Okay, good. I don't believe polls too
much but uh besides it won't be make any
difference because
>> if this person wins we move this way and
if this person wins we move that way see
because the we go back and forth like
this in my lifetime you know I can
remember my father used to get livid
about FDR
>> FDR was a goddamn socialist and union
organizer and he's going to hell and
if it wasn't for FDR we probably
wouldn't have made it through World War
II, you know, Len Lee and all that
rebuilt the American economy. So, it
depends on how you look at FDR, you
know, is he's the evil evil evil demon
>> or did he save American society? You
know what I'm saying?
>> But didn't FDR had a had a had didn't
have the resume of a Barack Obama.
>> He didn't have what
>> he didn't have Barack Obama's resume
>> regimen
>> resume
>> experience, you know. And I I don't
know. I feel a little bit nervous about
Barack, but that might just be me.
>> Well, how do you get experience? By
doing the job, I guess.
>> On the job training.
>> Of course, all of us are statewise on
the job.
>> That's what I'm saying.
>> We're all We're all into on the job
training. And
>> okay,
>> we try to stick together. Whoever's
president, we're all going to try to put
our shoulder to the wheel and help that
president, whoever it might be, you
know.
>> Okay. because we all our survival
depends on his doing the best job. So,
whoever gets to be elected, I'm going to
do the my best I can to support that
person and what I consider integrity and
all.
>> So, do so prayer would help.
>> Yeah, prayer would help, of course,
because you're you're stating your
intention and adding your intention of
integrity and uh worthwhile and reality.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you. I stay too long.
>> No, this one.
>> Okay.
>> See, both sides are influenced by the
collective intention.
>> You know, both sides, not just one side.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello, I'm from Australia. Just like to
wish uh a blessing to your country. Yes.
The home of the best and the worst. And
I hope that
>> the best flourishes. Yes, indeed.
>> So, my uh a little bit nervous uh
presently probably because the nature of
my inquiry. Uh I've been spent my life
uh inquiring into the nature of being
and I've I know less now than when I
began. But uh along the way I I just
feel that uh I've been very unembodied.
Uh so I've practiced things to embody my
existence. Uh yet I've been very
fortunate. I've been free from uh injury
and sickness.
But uh I found uh uh a partner who loved
me like a mother but was unable to bear
a child. And I wanted to have a child
much like you said before in having a
pet to love or another to walk with. I
wanted a child to love and to feel more
embodied. So I I left that partner and I
joined another and had a child but uh
lived with her for three years. But
there was a constant tension and
fighting and uh it was difficult to be
with a child uh to have that sort of
environment for a child to grow up in.
So I left left them and uh she returned
to her home country of Austria where the
child had an accident and he suffered a
axial diffuse axial brain trauma. Uh
fortunately um
if there's been anyone older, he might
be still in a coma, but he's now uh full
100% recovery.
I uh didn't want to force her to come
back to Australia. Uh so and and she
said she didn't want that imposition
made on her. So I granted that she could
be wherever she wanted to and I would
travel to uh support the child there.
And as a result, she wants to come to
Australia now, which is great because I
want to be around him. However, it now
means that the mother of my son and my
partner will be living in the same town.
And
>> I don't think I can track this. I mean,
>> you need a social worker.
I don't think I can help you with this
long involved narrative.
>> Essentially, there is a case where there
two women that I I feel um caring of
living
living in proximity to each other and in
tension with each other. And um my my
challenge is to live in a way that
doesn't uh propagate this tension
with
>> Well, you could stop breathing. That
would help.
You seem to be the cause of it all.
Stop messing around with women's lives
is what I advise you. Yeah, it's it's
kind of cute and it's kind of cheeky,
but I I do feel that it is a travesty
and it is a uh it is an offense against
against women.
>> It's uncomfortable for you.
>> It's certainly uncomfortable for me and
I I just see that women and the earth as
a feminine being. You know, the the
feminine has been abused and uh it's not
something outside of my own life that I
see. But
>> I don't what I don't get what the
question is. What is the question? He he
he's he's being put into a position
where he has two women that he cares
about in the same town and he doesn't
know how he's going to handle it.
>> Well,
>> that's it.
>> Well, maybe you won't.
>> I don't think you're going to handle it.
>> Yeah.
>> I think you're going to do a lousy job
of it.
>> You've done a lousy job so far. Why
would you change?
>> You couldn't get any stupider than you.
situation you guide yourself in.
>> I would get out like a gentleman telling
you you you you've loved them both and
bid them fun farewell and leave women
alone.
>> Thank you. Anyway, it's it's great to
sit amongst you. Could I have a photo
taken between you, buddy?
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Don't get friendly with my wife either.
Don't be telling her she's a beautiful
woman, you son of a
He's up to it all the time.
Oh yeah.
Need another hobby than seduction.
Keep them laughing. Yeah. Hi Doc. Hi
Susan.
>> Hi.
>> I was going to ask a question, but now
I'm afraid because of what you said
before.
>> Anyway, um
>> yeah. Firstly, uh Rob and I are from
Australia and I just want to thank the
both of you for everything that you've
given us.
>> Oh, you're from down under Elsa.
>> Yeah, we are.
>> How come you don't fall off the planet
when you're coming to
>> done because of you, Doc?
>> But I just want to thank you both from
the bottom of our hearts.
>> Yes.
>> And if it's appropriate, uh next week
we're getting married here in
>> Oh, goody. Good. with and we're having
um your students present or a group of
your students
>> and if it would be appropriate to ask
for a blessing.
>> Oh yeah. Coach said I should bless your
wedding
>> as a spiritual bless
>> couple. Bless them as
>> as a spiritual couple. Well, God bless
you both as a spiritual couple.
>> Yes indeed.
Uhhuh.
>> Australian.
>> Yes.
>> I'm not from Australia. I've been in
Sedona for three years and it's been
wonderful three years. And um I think
I've just realized that I don't do
anything without looking for gain. I
don't think or do anything without
looking for gain. And it's taken three
years for that to really hit home, but
it has. And I'd like to change that.
>> Well, why don't you let a thing
uh become what God wills it to be
instead of uh what you will it to be?
You mean to get over your personal
willfulness?
>> Yeah. surrendering outcomes to God, you
know, and uh
pray pray for God's guidance and and
surrender it to to God instead of what
you think you want.
First of all, you don't know what you
want. You just know what you think you
want, you know. So, you might clarify
what it is you really want. Trying to
find happiness in one way or another. If
you find a source of happiness,
you don't need anything from out there.
So you can stop wanting anything to
happen or anything to be different
because the source of happiness is
within you.
Nothing is going to make it happen
otherwise. Huh?
Good enough.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
asking only for knowledge of his will
for us and the power to carry it out.
That's what we pray to God for.
Knowledge of his will for us
and the power to carry it out. Yeah.
>> I I don't have a question. I just want a
moment of silence with you.
>> Yes. Okay.
>> Thank you. Thank you, Susan.
Hi Doc. Hi Susan. It's great to be here.
Um I have a fun animal story and there's
a question in it. I practice a
meditation that you had in Eye of the
Eye where we radiate love through our
body. And I have a little cat that comes
and sits on my lap when I do that and
she stays perfectly still. And then
she'll move and I'll I'll realize that
I'm thinking of something negative and
she'll jump down. And even if I go back
to that love state, she's usually gone,
right? Like
>> so as long as I'm karma cat.
>> Yeah. Karma kitty.
>> And she came from a monastery, too.
>> Cute karma kitty from a monastery.
>> Adorable. That's adorable.
>> So as long as I'm holding a loving
>> Yes.
>> She's right there with me.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> And um I've gotten better at meditation
so I can keep her on my lap for longer
periods.
But in my life, if I'm taking a shower,
if I'm in the kitchen, a lot of times
I'll have very negative uh things come
up um that right right now they're often
workrelated like this person did this
and I feel this, you know, and I might
feel victimized or whatever. I just have
these
>> Yeah.
>> And how can I so I'm able to do that in
that one state.
>> So you want to get over resentments.
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> So, um I think you've talked about it
today, but if you have any guidance,
>> letting go resentments. Yeah. And um the
willingness to let go resentments. You
know, there's a teaching there is no
such thing as a justified resentment.
>> It's just the way you're holding it. It
makes it look that way.
>> And when you let go holding it anyway,
you see that it's just life.
that car pulled in front of you in the
lane not to get even with you but
because he's a a bum driver or because a
rabbit was crossing the road. You see?
So you stop taking it personally. So the
the core of the problem is egoentricity.
>> You know that things are happening
either for or against or with your will.
>> So you stop exerting your will and uh
you know whoever wins the election is
whoever wins the election. I mean, I
don't give a damn cuz one side's going
to be as bad as the other. You know
that?
>> Oh, we pray not. Yeah. Okay.
>> Yeah,
>> that's helpful.
>> You're going to get crooked one way or
the other. Isn't that so? Yeah.
>> So, I'm internal. I'm putting it on me
as if it's me. And if I give up that
>> Yeah. The egoentricity of it, you know,
>> things just happen of their own accord
>> and there's nothing personal. You just
happen to be the witness.
So remove yourself as the participant
and and be merely the witness of the
phenomena of life.
>> Yeah.
>> See
>> whichever side wins is not going to do
anything to me personally. I'm only the
witness.
>> Yeah.
>> It's a little harder when it's it it
seems personal but but I see what you're
saying.
>> It seems personal but actually you're
just witnessing the phenomena.
>> Yeah. Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> That's beautiful. Thanks, Susan. Okay.
>> The first time I came up here, I was uh
with the question of doubt and uh um I'm
since then it's been I've been much less
agitated about that. In fact, one time I
was expressing my gratitude to you and I
experienced a level of love that uh has
remained with me ever since it um it's
been very powerful. Um but what I'm
asking is uh some guidance around
listening to that still small voice
>> guidance of listening to the
>> small voice the intuitive the guardian
angels. Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> If you could um give some advice about
what how one would set about doing that.
>> Oh, well, you ask God, you got ask God
for his knowledge of his will for you.
And you pray for your guardian angels.
Everybody has guardian angels. And you
ask your angels to make you more
conscious and aware of God's will for
you. That's all. So, it's just a matter
of meditative alignment
to become more conscious of God's will
for you.
I haven't gotten idiot. Oh, I didn't
mean that.
>> Thank you.
>> You know that old joke. You know, I
mean, I know there's something about
your horse that just pisses me off. You
know that.
>> Thank you.
>> That's a funny joke.
Uhhuh.
Yes.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Hello, Susan. I want
to thank you for the way that you the
many ways that you bless us. So, thank
you for all that you are. My question
today is about making good decisions for
ourselves. And personally, I'm being
faced with a life-changing decision
around my health. I happen to be someone
healing from cancer and my chemotherapy
has cleared it 80 to 85%
and I have a trusted doctor saying you
need surgery and radiation and then I
have very trusted holistic doctors
saying you don't.
>> And I'm very torn about of course
>> how to make the right choice. I've
prayed about it and I just don't seem to
get any clarity. I keep going back and
forth. So, do you have any insight on
how to make the best possible decisions
when we're faced with something?
>> You're getting two kinds of advice. One
is holistic.
What are you supposed to do?
>> Yes. Holistically,
>> nuts and wheat germ or something or
what?
>> Uh vitamin C, IV treatments, mistletoe,
uh ozone.
>> Oh, yeah. and rife machine uh different
measures.
>> We have permission to ask about it. The
regime that you just explained
calibrates over 400
4 The regime that she just described
calibrates at 420. All right. Uh versus
what?
>> Surgery and radiation.
>> All right. All right. And you heard
surgeon radiation calibrates over 400,
420, 430.
>> Wait, go down further.
>> Okay. 420, 440, 450.
In her case, radiation and surgery would
offer the best prognosis. Resist.
>> Thank.
>> What are you crying about?
>> I'm I'm so happy.
>> Huh?
Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> I I always say the combination of the
two. Go the traditional medical route
and add
everything else that you can add. You
know, wheat germ therapy and gunless
will.
>> Okay.
Thank you for your assistance.
I love you.
>> All right.
You love You only love me because I got
you off the hook. That's all.
The thing about holistic is it's sort of
iffy, you know, in a way.
>> Yeah.
>> First of all, thank you very much. Um, I
want to thank you for sharing too,
Susan. It's
Anyway, all my questions are generally
answered long before I get here. But,
uh, I do have one concern that's been
coming up in my daily uh, meditations,
contemplations, and even though I'll get
a breakthrough and things are really
good almost immediately, I feel much
better. and and there's a knowingness
that that you uh
move moved on. Uh then almost
immediately as you talk about the stack
that comes up, it's g it's been getting
darker and darker.
Kind of kind of hairy, doc, but uh
>> darker and darker.
>> Yeah.
>> So we call you killer or what?
>> Well,
>> homicidal maniac.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, okay. So
>> pretty ugly. You have this contrast of
something very beautiful happening on
one side, but then the next stack is so
ugly. It's it's
>> well Freud said there's Santos and
Aeros.
Aeros is the love and life instinct.
Thanoos is the death instinct.
And if Aeros wins, you live. And if
Thanos wins, you die.
No problem. Right.
>> Okay.
No problem.
>> So just continue with the surrender,
praying and contemplating no matter.
>> Yes. You're doing all the right things.
Yes.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. You become acquainted with the it.
But don't forget the it is not you. It's
a psychological basement.
>> That's helpful. Actually,
>> if the id rained, there wouldn't be
anybody alive. We would have all killed
each other a long time ago.
It rains in certain parts of the world.
People will adopt a political ideology
uh by which 10 million people die of
starvation. 10 million.
Another country adopted the same thing
and 100 million died of starvation.
So there is a difference.
Can you imagine a political ideology by
which 10 or 100 million people die of
starvation
and it still has its champions out
there.
Its champions
radical socialism right brings about
death of the millions.
So,
>> so as the next level just comes up just
to stay
here and uh and surrender it no matter
what.
>> Yeah. But you you you see how you see
how the it is constructed. You see why
things are repressed because you people
and then you can see the value of that
is because when you see what's
repressed, you then become aware how you
project it onto the world. So the value
of unc unearthing the characteristics of
the id
is that you see how that gets projected
onto the world
is not me that's evil it's them
are the evil ones but of course evil is
harbored within the unconscious and the
id and everyone you know we just call it
evil
>> I just was the it calls it Good.
>> It was frightening me that I could be
that.
>> Is it evil or is it good to kill your
enemies?
>> Well, when you're in that state.
>> Yeah. That's
>> Should we forgive them or kill them?
Yeah. Yeah.
>> Kill them comes up first. Then the
forgiveness.
>> Yeah. Self-investigation is uh very
interesting.
>> Yeah.
>> Can I
>> And don't forget it can take years, you
know. take a long time to get used to a
certain thought and then begin to see
that it's universal. Then to stop taking
it personally and then stop
uh rejecting it about yourself or
castigating yourself and see that it's
impersonal.
>> Can I hug your hand?
>> Yes.
>> Thank you very much. Thank you. Within
us is the historical anticedant of the
herbivor herbivore and also the
carnivore.
When you look at a fellow human being,
you're seeing a herbivore but also a
carnivore.
He gets hungry enough he'll eat you.
>> Thank you, Doc.
Well, I want to investigate the it for
him. I know he don't want to go there.
I'll go there for him.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I brought a pen.
>> Yes.
>> Cuz I have some photos I was hoping you
could sign. So,
it only takes like four seconds to dry.
So, it's
>> one.
>> And you wanted a new one anyway, so you
can keep it.
>> Four.
>> Boom. Boom.
Oh my goodness. All different sizes,
too.
>> Yeah. Okay.
Oh dear.
>> Oh, that's a great one.
>> Wanted you to sign that one too if you
can.
>> Very nice. Oh dear. Oh dear.
>> Yeah. I'm glad you had a good pen
because I
>> Yeah, you can keep it. Go ahead.
>> I didn't bring that my good pen with me.
I did have a a question about um
I think I forgot it. Oh no, glamour.
Um I was reading Alice Bailey's book on
glamour and she talks about how
um glamorization of uh you know primal
instinctual drives has occurred and
talks about how to transcend them but
kind of uh speaks to it from a
visualization perspective to use
visualize light going towards the
glamour.
>> Yeah. And uh I was just wondering um I'm
getting a little confused that I
understand glamour you you said was its
own energy field.
>> Yes.
>> And uh
>> it's like desiraability exaggeration.
You see it every day on television.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
So letting go of of the glamour is is
>> seeing it for what it is. It's an energy
that creature dancing around uh doesn't
have any intrinsic attraction. You say
it's attractive.
>> Mhm. Okay. So, it's just glamour is
almost like this at the same level as
desire. So, you let go of traction.
>> You're projecting it onto the uh thing,
right? You're projecting it.
>> Okay. So, surrender and asking the Holy
Spirit to see the essence
>> to see the essence of it as is in truth.
Yeah.
>> Okay. Right. Mhm.
>> All right. I think that's it.
>> I mean, what's what she points out is
that it's a specific energy.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Desiraability
is projected onto things. This car, that
dress, this person, that university,
this
label in your clothes, those are all,
you know,
>> is that the same as a level of desire on
the scale of consciousness?
>> No.
>> No. It's it's different.
>> No. Desiringness is what 190 or
something. It is a certain level. Yes.
Of desiring and wantingness.
>> You can project it onto anything.
>> So it can be projected on. Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> Thank you.
>> You can project it on to anything.
wanted to be president of the United
States, for instance,
you got to be mentally ill. You want
that?
For one thing, the minute you're
elected, 50% of the people hate you. So,
I mean,
>> because they didn't vote for you.
>> Yeah. 50% of the people are going to be
you. What do you want to know?
>> You said that um we could hang out with
you for $20 and there's my contribution.
Am I supposed to sign this thing here?
>> Yes. I thought I'd pay for it.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> I just want to thank you for everything
you do.
>> She's such a funny lady.
>> You're a funny lady.
>> Um, is America still at 421 today? What
>> is America
>> still at 421?
>> I don't know. We haven't done that.
>> I haven't done it in a while. Would you
be willing to today?
>> Yeah, because you got to take this back
though.
>> No, you can have it. You can have it.
>> Let's see. We have permission to
calibrate.
What about uh America
uh overall? Resist. We have permission
to do America overall. America overall.
Is it 421?
422. 421.
>> So even with all the stuff that's going
on, it's staying.
>> Yeah. Because a lot of good stuff goes
on equally. Don't forget
>> we're just
>> you you will you take that seriously.
No, you don't want to.
>> No, no, because you don't, you know,
you're seeing the bad stuff because
you're focusing on that. But at the same
time, all kinds of good good works are
going on by all kinds of people, you
know,
>> like your groups, huh? Like your groups.
>> I mean, if we look at some something
like the glamorization of publicity and
glamour of millions of dollars of
promotional money, that looks pretty
thin, doesn't it? You know what I mean?
spend $120,000 a week on TV ads.
>> I don't know anybody's worth that kind
of money, frankly.
>> It's probably more more than that that
they spend.
>> May I shake your hand?
>> Anyway, that's just part of the game,
you know.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Game they have to play.
>> Yeah, it's just part of the game.
Doesn't mean anything really.
>> We're all trying to win.
>> Thank you.
>> Everybody wants to win.
America
has an obsession with winning. Winning.
Win at any cost.
>> Hi.
Look at this.
>> Oh my goodness sakes. Isn't that
something? Oh my goodness. Clever. Very
clever.
>> Isn't that cute?
>> Thank you.
>> Very clever. Thank you so much.
>> You know, I want to um thank my friends,
too. It's a bus with pictures of us in
the bus
>> with all these with all those people
here in the bus.
>> I I'm just so grateful to both of you
and also to all of my friends for
helping keep me on track.
>> So, thank you.
>> That was so clever. Thank you so much.
>> Wow, that's great.
Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Several had written you a question a
while back and you gave us an answer and
a miracle happened and I thank you for
that.
>> Mhm.
>> I was going to ask you a question about
animals, but the answer came to me while
I was in line. However, I wanted to show
you our babies.
>> They're kitties.
>> What is that?
>> They're two kitties. Oh,
I love kitties.
Adorable kitties.
>> Adorable.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Yes.
>> You have pink nose.
>> This goes here.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Buffy and Skitter.
>> Skitter.
>> That's Skitter.
>> Looks like a skitter.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Put it right with us here. I think Thank
you.
Yes.
>> Um,
recently I have begun to lose um
function of my muscles.
>> What?
>> Function of my muscles.
>> Her muscles.
>> Her muscles. She's
>> What about them?
>> She's losing function of her muscles.
>> How come? Uh they don't they can't
figure out why.
>> Oh.
>> And so my question is uh should I cons
continue to try to see different doctors
to find out why or is it just a
spiritual issue?
>> What is the question?
>> Is it physical or spiritual?
>> Okay.
We have permission to ask about this.
She she's not losing control of her
muscles. resist. You're not losing
control of your muscles.
Okay. What you're suffering from is
hysteria. Resist. You're suffering from
hysteria. An emotional condition. You're
not losing control of your muscles or
you wouldn't be sitting up here laying
on the floor.
>> Well, I'm losing control of my eye
muscles.
>> What do they do? turn backwards in your
skull.
>> No, they have to close. They get weak
and I can't use them.
>> What? Your lid muscles?
>> Yeah.
>> You mean your eyelids? You can't hold
your eyelids up anymore. Is that right?
>> Right.
>> Okay.
The eyelid business is emotional
doing it. The eyelid business is
emotional resist. The eyelid
problem is mythenia gravis resist.
So, you're seeing a doctor who's doing
diagnostic testing.
>> What do they say about myia gravis?
>> Uh, he said the blood work came back
negative.
>> He said what?
>> The blood work came back negative.
>> What came back negative?
>> The blood work on it.
>> Oh, the blood work. All right. The blood
the blood work just hasn't shown it up
yet. Is this She has early myia.
>> Thank you.
There's there's antidotes for it.
>> Minioras there's antidotes. It's a neuro
muscular hormone but imbalance
but there's a antidotes to it.
It's a neurological problem. neurologist
for
>> Hello Doc. Hello Susan. Nice to see you
again. Um well I had a number of
questions but they've dissolved on the
way and I really was it's a very basic
question but when you two were talking
together you talked about the recession
and I know here the consciousness is
very high and you were saying that we'd
have to give up caviar sandwiches and
have peanut butter sandwiches but um one
of my daughter's friends uh he's lost
his job he's now redundant and we have
other friends who uh are losing their
home and I'm just wondering how we can
give them spiritual help or advice or
how do we relate to them and show them
compassion and not get caught in their
drama.
Um
I think that's
>> well you have to stay detached from
them. They've got their own karmic
they have their own karmic uh
uh pattern to to live through.
>> Yes.
>> Right. So
what you do is
allow them to
live their life without trying to change
it.
>> I mean I lived through the uh depression
far worse one than this one.
>> Yes. So would it have been better if I
had not lived through the depression? I
mean who's to say? I don't know.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> I can live without money and I can live
with money. Adds more conveniences, you
know.
>> Yes.
>> But you can still hitchhike every day. I
did. Didn't have to have a car.
>> No.
>> Hitchhiked every single day for years.
>> Yes.
>> Ice, rain, snow, summer, winter. every
morning, every night
>> for years, you know.
>> So, what do you learn from that? I don't
know. Self independence, stamina,
who knows what uh the purpose of it was.
Very likely there was no purpose. It was
just the way life was in those days. You
know what I mean?
>> So, if the stock market crashes and
people
uh lose houses they can't afford, etc.,
It's neither good nor bad. It's just the
current circumstances, is it not?
>> I mean, it's really impersonal.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Yeah. It's really impersonal.
>> All right. Thank you, Doc.
>> I I think, you know, the government
should look into public housing instead
of everybody, you know, owning their own
home. I mean, that's a little
ridiculous.
>> When I was in medical school, we lived
in public housing. You know, it was a
big apartment building and for $ 15 or
$20 a month, you had your apartment and
you also had to help maintain the place
and do your duty on the the list of
cleaning the stairs, etc.
>> And it cost far less than putting
everybody in that apartment building in
their own home, I'll tell you.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. You look at a high-rise in New
York City, imagine 40 floors of people.
You're going to have to provide an
individual home for everybody in every
apartment all the way down the corridor
and all 40 stories. I mean it's
ridiculous.
>> All right.
>> So you try to implement a ridiculous
idea and what you get is failure and
that's how we found out.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> I had a patient one time. She lived I
forget what floor it was
32nd floor or something. She got mugged
six times coming off the same elevator
on the same floor.
>> Oh.
It's incredible.
>> Six times. And I said to her over and
over, "Are you going to keep living
there?"
>> Yes.
>> Six times. The same elevator, the same
floor.
>> And did she finally move?
>> I don't know. I forget now.
Too painful of memory. I think I've
repressed it.
>> She would get mugged every time. come
off the elevator and some idiot would
mug her.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Because the apartment building was
crawling with druggies, you know, and
the various
uh
uh what do you call them? Group groups
fought over who was going to control
each building, you know, the various
gangs gangs
>> fought over control of the buildings,
you know, and various
>> levels of the various buildings, you
know. But there's many solutions to
mankind's housing problem other than
having everybody in their own house, you
know, like Levittown, USA.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> Thank you, Doc.
>> Yeah.
>> That's wonderful. All right. And I am
part of that um lousy triangle as well,
the Australian one. But we're working
through it. There's a lot of deep
friendship there.
>> All right. All right.
>> Thank you, doctor. Thank you, Susan.
>> Thank you
>> indeed.
>> Yes. Well, I'm going to move as fast as
I can move.
>> Hi, Doc.
>> They give me such tough questions for
God's sake. That guy with all them
women. He's got He had me hung up for 10
minutes.
>> I promise. No women questions.
>> Oh, good. Give up women. And that was
the advice I was going to give. But
>> yeah,
>> um first of all, I just really want to
thank you guys. Uh I listen to your
lectures uh as I have a job as a janitor
and I listen to your lectures and I've
noticed now that uh cleaning is sort of
sometimes like a trigger for a spiritual
experience. And so I'm really thankful
for that because uh when I was a kid,
you know, it was really heck for my mom
to get me to clean things. So I really
want to thank you for that. And I have a
question uh regarding an experience that
I had. And um
the uh experience involved a person I
was in a relationship with uh
saying that she uh she
intuited or um saw in a vision or
psychically. uh me being sexually abused
and when she uh
when she said that it triggered like a
like a like a flashback or a memory for
me.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Um which was like very uh very full body
and I felt for for some days like I was
being uh like I was being stalked or
sort of uh hunted I guess to extent. But
I I investigated it like within my
family network and um I've done some
past life
>> work and a few other things. I've seen
uh um various various therapists and
>> I I don't have a I guess I'm the thing
I'm looking for is is the is whether
that that experience was actually a a
reality or it was something that um was
put forward on me or it was a trigger
from a a past life or um or if
>> you're talking about a memory.
Um I guess I guess my question is if it
was something from this lifetime as
>> I think it's a fantasy.
>> Yep. What he's saying about is a fantasy
never happened.
Okay.
>> Thank you.
In psychoanalysis, such things come up.
You you have a a memory of a event.
Actually, it didn't happen. Oh, God
bless us all.
We'll have to tighten it a little bit so
it's a little tighter. Yeah.
>> There you go.
Oh, yes. Thank you.
>> Idiot boy reporting.
>> Thank you. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Um, I just wanted to thank you. You've
done so much for me. You've whacked me
when I've asked to be whacked.
And um, right now I'm going through the
fourth step and I need some help.
>> Yeah.
How do you do need help being honest
with yourself?
>> Is that just a moral inventory?
>> Yes.
>> Well, just to agree that everything's
going to be horrible and get it over
with
>> selfish, greedy, intolerant,
abusive,
negligent,
dishonest, thievery, liar.
Check them all off.
You're a human being, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, you got all of them.
>> I got
>> Go for it.
>> Go for
>> It's really the human condition. Of
course, you personalize how it came up
in your life, but it applies, you know,
fourth step applies almost equally to
everybody. Everybody's lied. Everybody's
been taken advantage of others. Other
everybody's been selfish. everybody, you
know,
it's been a two-time some. So, you just
accept that's the human condition. So,
your karma, your karmic inheritance as a
human being is going to involve most of
those things to one degree or another.
Otherwise, we would be in an angelic
realm.
Because you're a human being, I assume
you're not an angel in disguise
sent here to spy on us.
You're a no good Nick to begin with. So
is one no good Nick to another. Welcome
to the fraternity.
called crossing the swamp.
Spiritual
legends it's called crossing the swamp.
Crossing the swamp. So you just go
through the swamp till you get through
the swamp.
And don't be a crybaby that it's a
swamp.
It's just a swamp. You drag your butt
across the swamp. the spiritual swamp.
All the icky bad stuff you don't want to
look at and being held back by all kinds
of things.
It's called the swamp.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> That way you get to be an ex swamper.
And some people haven't been through the
swamp yet.
They have no idea what's waiting for
them.
You can tell them
we're galashes.
Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> The courage to look at yourself in all
the repressed crevices, all the hidden
closets.
Yes.
>> Today you were talking about um how hard
it is to have a consistent meditation
practice. How daily life
>> Wait, start over.
>> How the difficulty in uh having a
meditation practice that the pressure of
daily life starts to squeeze it.
>> Okay, I understand what you said.
>> Okay, sit back just a hair and say
>> the difficulties of what? Having a
meditation practice.
>> Having a meditation practice.
>> Yes.
>> What are the difficulties?
>> Well, you said it today that the
pressure of daily life starts to
squeeze. But you had a very demanding
career. I presume you had a family and
you did it consistently for over 20
years. Oh yeah. How
>> how did you do it?
>> Five o'clock in
>> Yeah. You get up at 5:00 while it's
still dark and your priority is to do an
hour meditation before you take off for
the day's activities. So that's just
intensity of dedication. That's all.
I assume people become vegetarians. I
was a vegetarian for 20 years.
And so I mean your dedication is your
alignment with that and then your
commitment you commit to it no matter
what. Commit to it no matter what. See,
>> you did it in the evening, too. That's
much harder.
>> Hour in the morning, an hour at night.
Yeah.
>> How did you carve out an hour at night?
And with your career and family?
>> Well, you don't sleep a lot.
>> Just if you can't get it in the evening,
do two hours in the morning. Just get up
earlier.
Yeah, I find that you can arrange your
life so you got an hour in the morning,
an hour in the afternoon.
See, first of all, you don't need as
much sleep as you think you do. You
don't need to watch TV. There's lots of
stuff where you while away all kinds of
time, you know.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
Hi.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. We don't have a question. We just
wanted to thank you
>> for everything you've both done and you
look so adorable in
>> Thank you.
>> Yes. Thank you. I can get a picture.
Thank you.
>> And I do have a request. Um, Doc said
for $20 we could spend the day. I
thought for 40 we could spend the day
with both of you.
>> Thank you.
>> Now we're going to have emails on that.
>> Oh,
>> people are going to watch this and we're
going to get emails. Here's my 20.
>> Well, we have a sense of humor about
such things, you know.
>> Yeah.
Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah, it's cute kitties, huh?
>> Okay, we're moving as fast as we can go.
>> Be okay. 15 minutes left.
>> All right,
>> my books.
Oh, these are from
>> German.
>> What?
>> These are German editions of our work.
>> Oh, okay.
Alf.
>> Yeah. Alto.
Yeah.
I wanted to ask a question about
understanding the future
and um I thought
about future as you explained it
and um
I thought maybe it's the unfolding of
the universe
with speed of time with the speed of
light is is it a different phase during
this unfolding or it's just a sequential
perception.
>> I don't understand the question.
>> Okay. He said um it's about the future
the unfoldment of
u the universe.
>> Yes.
>> Is it and it's at the speed of light.
>> He says is it
>> what was it?
>> Is this is the future another phase
during this unfolding
>> of the universe unfolding? Is the future
a phase of the universe unfolding?
>> There there is no such thing as the
future. That's all in your head.
>> There is no such thing as the future.
That's all a fantasy.
There is no future. There's only now.
Yep.
>> That's clear.
>> What happens to the future? When you get
to the future, you find out it's just
now.
Last week, Monday, it was now. This week
Monday, it's now. Next week Monday, it's
going to be now. It's never anything
other than just now.
You see? So
to look at it otherwise is just to write
a narrative about it. But a narrative is
not a reality. A narrative is just a
story.
So what people think is the elapse of
time is just a narrative.
Yep. So it's just our perception
sequentially
>> there there isn't any sequencing. The
sequencing is is in in the narrator. In
reality there is no sequencing
because you experience the thing
sequentially. You think it's happening
sequentially.
To be strictly honest all you can say is
you're experiencing it that way. You
can't say that that's the way it is
because you cannot see beyond your own
capacity to experience
to be honest. All you can say is I
experience things thusly. That is
truthful and verifiable. To say that it
is that way is making a leap uh which
you cannot support that the world is how
you think it is or time is what you
think it is is you know grandiosity.
You're no such thing.
Things are what they are. They're not
what you think they are. Think think
them to be
or how you intellectualize it.
>> Oh yeah,
>> that's the problem.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> Past, present, and future applied to the
narrative, not to the reality.
Yeah.
You bet.
>> Yes,
>> I had a question about event that had
that occurred in my life that I
perceived that occurred in my life. Um,
let's see. I was out on a bike ride a
few years ago and was hit by a car.
>> And what?
>> Was hit by a car.
>> Hit by a car. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And it just so happened um you
were in Colorado where I live that same
evening giving a talk and um I just
wanted to talk about coincidence and um
let's see and accidents.
And you say there are no accidents.
And um
I'm not sure that I would have met you
if I wasn't involved in that accident.
>> What do I have to do with it?
>> I don't know.
>> He said he was he was he was
>> Oh, I said Oh,
>> you were speaking in Colorado.
>> Oh, at that time.
>> Oh, yes. That same evening.
>> Oh, I see.
>> I No. Oh, you missed the lecture.
>> I missed the lecture.
>> Oh,
>> so that's not punishment for not being
there.
>> Was that was that when um
>> it was in at the Mile High Church?
>> Oh, yes, that's right. That's right.
That's right.
>> Yeah.
>> We spoke a couple times in Colorado.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes. That's a sophisticated question
having to do with nonlinear dynamics and
things that are impersonal. the
likelihood of a thing, you know,
reaching the 26 decimal point, etc.
Iteration means that often you repeat a
thing, all of a sudden something
completely unexpected will occur.
Out of 10,000
generations of orange fruit flies, all
of a sudden you'll get black ones.
10,000 times orange. 10,0001 a black
fruitly
who has no black ancestors. How can that
be?
So you might say part of creation is
randomness
non and the mechanism is described as
nonlinear dynamics.
Out of a thousand fruit flies of one
color, you'll suddenly get a black one
who has no ancestry of black fruit
flies.
How can you explain that logically? You
can't.
>> Perfect.
>> That's the fun of it.
>> Yeah.
>> No, you can't explain it.
>> No sense in looking for explanation.
>> No.
>> Great.
>> There are still mysteries of life.
Mysteries of life.
>> Where does the 1 millionth black fruit
fly come from?
The infinite field of possibility.
Because possibility is unlimited. It's
infinite.
Yes.
>> Mhm.
>> Yes.
>> I'm one of those people at the edge of
the swamp. And um I know you spoke
before once about intention and decision
and effort and I was hanging on the edge
of going forward and um checking
calibration and I had of all the
intention in the world but the decision
and the effort is I'm sure there's a lot
of other things behind it but do I have
to have a better understanding of the
personal will just like one would have a
better understanding of the ego to
transcend it. Do you have to understand?
Well, it's more a decision rather than
will. It isn't a matter of willpower.
It's a matter of decision
to choose this, choose this. Yeah. So,
it's a matter of choice and options. You
know, karmically you're presented with
options continuously.
The human
psyche is is doesn't have any choice
except to make choices.
All it can do really is make choices.
That's really all the mind can do when
you think about it. Is it this or is it
that? It has to make a choice. Every
intersection you have to choose left or
right or straight ahead, slow down or
speed up.
You don't think you have any option, any
freedom about that.
So all this business about freedom, you
know, is sort of a fantasy. You don't
have any freedom at all.
Hey, you don't have to be moan any loss
because you never had in the first
place.
>> You're forced. You're forced. The human
will is forced
to constantly make a choice.
What should the next word be? What
should my inflection be?
>> You know what I'm saying?
>> Yeah, I do.
>> I think I've been making the posture to
make a choice.
>> What should the posture be? What you
know?
>> Yeah.
>> You don't have any option other than to
constantly make choices. So all the
human will, the will is constantly
making choices. This and that and this
and that. And it's driven by nonlinear
gears, you know. It's
it's really um
it's really fields of dominance.
Karmically there's a powerful field of
dominance. Within within that there are
lesser fields of lesser dominance.
Within that there's lesser fields. And
what we fantasize as freedom is at the
end of the line after about 150
decisions have already been made. And we
call that freedom of the will. Oh, that
makes us happy to think we have freedom
of the will.
But you don't have freedom of the will.
>> Don't have to grieve losing it because
you never had it in the first place.
>> I think that's what I had the problem
with because you would say that
everything is what it is. People are who
they are. Yes.
>> But then at the same time, you're like,
of course, we are here karmically to
That's right.
>> And to you constantly have to where
where is that?
>> You constantly have to choose.
>> Okay. It's like the rudder of the canoe.
>> Yeah.
>> The rudder, you know, the paddle has to
be somewhere.
>> Yeah.
>> You don't have any choice. So, you got
to have that paddle somewhere.
>> Yeah.
>> If you put it this way, you go this way.
If you put it this way, you go this way.
But you don't have any choice.
>> Thank you very much. Take care.
>> Be nice if God would just paddle our
canoe for us.
Yep.
>> What do you call that system that tells
you where you are and when you're going?
>> Garmin.
>> Garmin. You need a psychic garment.
>> I never heard anything so crazy as a
Garmin until I heard a Garmin. It was
unbelievable.
I said, "This is spooky."
>> Yeah. So from the standpoint of the
absolute,
there was nothing that was said today,
nor is there anything being said now. Is
that the truth?
>> Nothing happened either.
>> Just the infinite silence.
>> Isn't that easy?
>> So this is just taking place right now
in consciousness.
>> There's nothing actually happening. No.
Sounds good to me. How to how to Never
mind. That's good.
>> No, go ahead.
>> To make that experiential, the practice
that's most attractive to myself is to
do what you've said like living in the
silence and just witness it all from the
silence. Is that
>> That's true. Because while you and I are
talking,
the major part of this consciousness is
silent and nothing is happening. It's
not deciding anything. It's not saying
anything or hearing anything
like the ocean. The ocean goes down
maybe a couple thousand feet and you see
the waves on the surface,
but there are thousands of feet below
that surface which are utterly still.
But the mind is looking for
justification for its existence. So it
focuses on the waves and says, "Boy,
isn't this some mountain, some ocean
tonight?" Well, it's the top couple feet
of the ocean. That's all. The next 5,000
ft down is completely still to the
bottom of the whatcham call it crevice
or whatever it is across the sea.
though thousands of feet down it's still
and silent and dark and the action is
only on the surface. So you can view
your own consciousness that way.
It's only what's going on the surface is
entertaining.
But its reality is far beyond what's
happening, you know, in today's TV
drama.
>> Good thing too.
>> Thank you. You can't be drowned with
every little wave that comes along. Then
we'd all be dead in the mackerel.
>> So hang.
>> All right, we got to move it.
>> Hang out on the bottom of the ocean.
>> Thank you, Doc.
>> Below the surface of the sea, everything
is still and silent and peaceful.
All the action is on the only on the
surface. Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
What advice would you give those that
have committed the eternal sin or
blasphemy? Blasphemy. I can't even say
the word.
>> I can't understand what you're saying.
>> What advice would you give someone that
committed the eternal sin? Blasphemy.
>> Pray.
>> Okay. May I
>> Thank you.
>> Pray.
Just like a picture.
>> That is scary, isn't it? A question like
that.
See, there's other ways to recover other
than forgiveness. There's the karmic uh
paying it up, paying it off.
Well, let's say you curse God. Okay,
that's blasphemy. And I hear it done on
there certain internet websites that
even specialize in blasphemy. They scare
the wits out of me when I read them. The
for, you know, that's the one sin for
which there is no forgiveness.
Uh if there's no forgiveness, then what
are you going to have to do? you're
going to have to live out your prison
term,
right? So, whatever Stephanie goes with
that, you'll have to go through it.
You're not going to be relieved of this
suffering by forgiveness. Forgiveness
really means that you will not suffer
for a certain thing, you know, and
otherwise it's just whatever the crime
is. If it's 20 years in prison for that,
so you serve the 20 years in prison. If
there was forgiveness, they would
forgive the 20 years that you're out of
your mind at the time, mentally ill, not
responsible or something. But if you
were fully conscious and made a a
decision with your will in agreement and
you're committed blasphemy,
which by the way calibrates at 10,
then you just suffer some time in hell.
So big deal.
>> Okay.
Yes.
>> Okay. Firstly, we would like to thank
you and Susan for all of your works. We
very much appreciate it. And secondly,
and simply, we just like to ask for your
blessings.
>> Okay.
>> All right.
>> Thank you.
>> We have permission.
>> Yeah. We have permission to give them
our blessing. Yeah. We give you our
blessing. God bless you.
>> God bless you.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
We got to move it.
>> We only have one more.
>> One more.
>> Yep.
>> Last one.
>> We're on time.
>> Let's go.
>> Yes.
>> Hi. Hi.
>> Um, I've been coming for about a year
now and have taken you as my teacher and
um,
>> yes,
>> I've noticed the schedule for your
visits opening to all of us here. Like
you're not going to be there's only four
sessions
next year. Yeah.
>> I'm not even here in Sedona. And um
>> Oh, you mean next year? Yeah. Yeah.
>> Oh, next year we're going to do
Prescott, I guess, for a while.
>> Yeah.
>> The problem of the problem is
>> more seating.
>> We only have four seminars and we have
so many people that we have to turn away
when we have seminars here in
>> Yeah. This only seats 350 or something.
>> They are building a new auditorium at
the high school. It should be done 2010.
So hopefully when that's completed, we
will return to Sedona and have events
there.
>> Yeah. Uhhuh. You have to have bigger
seating. Yeah,
>> we have more people than what can come
in here and every day we get emails, you
know, complaining about we have to do a
satellite room when we're in this event.
So, and this is about the only place
that we know that would sit close to the
amount of people here. So,
>> um we're looking at we had to go to a
larger venue.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Because I feel like I haven't
learned everything.
>> Yes.
>> I need to warn you
>> and I don't want to lose you yet. Oh,
you won't lose me. I'll be around the
neighborhood.
>> You will?
>> Well, we hang out Prescott Prescott
Valley. Uh
the worst would be uh Phoenix all the
way to Phoenix.
We hang out in the neighborhood.
>> I'll take that for now.
>> Yep.
>> We do have sat too that
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Question answer.
>> All right.
God bless
God bless us everyone.
How fortunate we are to be together.
Uh how fortunate we are to be with such
holy company, you know, and that we're
all in one place and all of one one uh
intention
and we strengthen each other by our
collective intention.
Each one of us is more than what we
would have been had we been alone. Uh
because we have a
effect each one multip multiplies the
intentional power of the other. It's not
arithmatic. It's uh uh it's not
arithmetic. It's uh you know what I'm
thinking. God resist
whatever the word is.
So two of us doesn't have twice the
power of one. It probably has three or
four times
and three of us has probably 20 times.
So it it we empower each other. The
collective empowerment
of a group like this is probably not
even measurable. Yes. And it transcends
time and location.
It doesn't just go down the road 8 and a
half miles.
It's an empowerment within the field of
human consciousness itself.
So a group like this influences
the collective.
The group like this is influencing
favorably the collective the collective
consciousness of all of mankind
from now on through the future. Wow.
Zippity dooah.
Well, it's good thing to know.
It's nice to know that uh
the consequence of one life
is to fulfill the spiritual potentiality
of mankind. So we serve not just oursel
and not just our fellow member of this
group but we serve all of life by our
intention and by our collective power. A
group like this
serves all of life.
Resist serves all of life including
animal life. Resist
vegetative life. Yes. Well, it serves
all of life because you can see places
in the planet where life is just
floored. Life is just floored and
flowing out from every nook and cranny.
Collects a little dust and out of that
grows a vine. And out of that vine grows
some bugs. And out of the bugs grow some
birds. And out of the birds grows a cat.
Out of the cat grows a kid who wants a
kitty.
So life propagates life.
uh just to know that by our intention
then we are aligned in a very powerful
way and that we are our decision to
serve God as best we can
is there is no higher intention uh there
is no higher intention
that is the highest intention of which
man is capable resist wow that is the
highest intention of which man is
capable so therefore
It is our desire to serve God. And
because of our desire to do so, we
actually are doing so. Whoa.
that we are given the opportunity to
serve God and that by our intention we
have aligned oursel
and we are serving God and by doing that
we are also benefiting all of life
including mankind including animal kind
including all of life so we uh uplift
life by our intention
therefore we become like an arm uh of
God right so we become
in in in effectively an arm of God.
Wow.
Yeah. It took me a while to get over
that one.
We serve part and parcel because all
that is and all that exists is divinity.
So what we are is divinity expressed as
mankind. Oh my god.
We are divinity expressed as mankind.
Resist.
Well, that'll take me a while.
Yeah, it'll take me a while to digest
that. Digest that. Uh,
okay. So, I thank thee, oh Lord, for
divine providence
that we may serve thee individually and
collectively
now and forever.
This group is forever
within the celestial realms. We are
forever. We are forever. Okay. So, this
is a group
that transcends time, earthly, worldly
time
and transcends just personal human
interest
serves something greater than its own,
greater than itself.
That which we are is greater than that
which we are.
which we are. That is certainly the
fulfillment of divine providence
to become all that you can be
in the name of God.
And therefore I give thanks. Thank thee
oh Lord for this group now and forever.
Amen.
>> God bless you all.
Yeah. All right.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
Hallelu.
Okay.
We give thanks to the oh Lord for our
existence
and for our group and for being with
each other.
What a tremendous blessing
to experience God through each other.
What a wonderful blessing.
Amen.
So we love each other now and forever.
>> Each one of us is created by God. So we
share the the divinity of our source and
our origin and our destiny which are all
one in the same thing. Our origin, our
source and our destiny are all of God.
Amen. Wow.
That's good to feel good about, ain't
it?
What is it kids? Kids say at the end of
their their thing, "Yay, God."
>> Thank you all. I love you so much.
>> Yeah. I love you all so much.
>> And look at these beautiful flowers
here.
My god, they are so gorgeous.