And
And with
And with that,
And with that, I'd
And with that, I'd like
And with that, I'd like to
And with that, I'd like to introduce
Dr.
Dr. David
And with that, I'd like to introduce
Dr. David Hawkins.
We
We always
We always start
We always start with
We always start with Gloria
We always start with Gloria and
Excelsius
Excelsius Theo.
We always start with Gloria and
Excelsius Theo. Glory
Excelsius Theo. Glory to
We always start with Gloria and
Excelsius Theo. Glory to thee,
Excelsius Theo. Glory to thee, oh
We always start with Gloria and
Excelsius Theo. Glory to thee, oh Lord
most
most high.
All
All right.
most high.
All right. If
All right. If I
most high.
All right. If I can
All right. If I can recover
most high.
All right. If I can recover from
All right. If I can recover from that,
we
we will
we will have
we will have a
we will have a lecture.
I
I forgot
we will have a lecture.
I forgot what
I forgot what the
we will have a lecture.
I forgot what the lecture
I forgot what the lecture was
we will have a lecture.
I forgot what the lecture was about
today.
So,
So, I
today.
So, I brought
So, I brought this
today.
So, I brought this thing
So, I brought this thing here
to
to tell
to tell me
to tell me what
to tell me what it's
to tell me what it's about.
What's
What's the
to tell me what it's about.
What's the name
What's the name of
to tell me what it's about.
What's the name of the
What's the name of the lecture?
Ah,
Ah, so
Ah, so it
Ah, so it isn't
Ah, so it isn't just
Ah, so it isn't just me.
>> It's
>> It's It's
Ah, so it isn't just me.
>> It's It's true.
>> It's It's true. faith,
Ah, so it isn't just me.
>> It's It's true. faith, uh,
>> It's It's true. faith, uh, truth
Ah, so it isn't just me.
>> It's It's true. faith, uh, truth and
>> faith,
>> faith, reason.
>> Well,
>> Well, I
>> faith, reason.
>> Well, I don't
>> Well, I don't know
>> faith, reason.
>> Well, I don't know what
>> Well, I don't know what we'll
>> faith, reason.
>> Well, I don't know what we'll find
>> Well, I don't know what we'll find out
what
what the
what the what
what the what the
what the what the name
what the what the name of
what the what the name of this
what the what the name of this speech
what the what the name of this speech is
later.
And
And we've
And we've got
And we've got the
And we've got the How
And we've got the How many
And we've got the How many people
And we've got the How many people here
are
are new?
How
How many
How many people
How many people here
How many people here are
How many people here are new?
How many people here are new? Yes.
Okay.
Okay. Not
How many people here are new? Yes.
Okay. Not a
Okay. Not a lot.
How many people here are new? Yes.
Okay. Not a lot. Just
Okay. Not a lot. Just a
How many people here are new? Yes.
Okay. Not a lot. Just a few.
Okay. Not a lot. Just a few. So
How many people here are new? Yes.
Okay. Not a lot. Just a few. So for
Okay. Not a lot. Just a few. So for the
few
few we'll
few we'll just
few we'll just recapitulate
few we'll just recapitulate some
few we'll just recapitulate some of
few we'll just recapitulate some of the
most
most basic
few we'll just recapitulate some of the
most basic slides
most basic slides to
few we'll just recapitulate some of the
most basic slides to give
most basic slides to give you
few we'll just recapitulate some of the
most basic slides to give you an
orientation
orientation or
orientation or a
orientation or a reorientation
uh
uh to
orientation or a reorientation
uh to the
uh to the entire
orientation or a reorientation
uh to the entire subject.
uh to the entire subject. And
orientation or a reorientation
uh to the entire subject. And um
uh to the entire subject. And um so
let's
let's start
let's start with
let's start with uh
uh
uh this
let's start with uh
uh this is
uh this is the
let's start with uh
uh this is the the
uh this is the the basic
let's start with uh
uh this is the the basic slide
uh this is the the basic slide to
let's start with uh
uh this is the the basic slide to which
we
we refer
we refer you
we refer you know
we refer you know the
we refer you know the calibrated
we refer you know the calibrated levels
of
of consciousness
and
and um
and um h
and um h how
and um h how they
and um h how they arose
and um h how they arose in
and um h how they arose in the
and um h how they arose in the first
place
uh
uh was
uh was interesting
because
because um
uh was interesting
because um we
because um we were
uh was interesting
because um we were studying
because um we were studying I
uh was interesting
because um we were studying I had
because um we were studying I had a
uh was interesting
because um we were studying I had a big
clinic
clinic back
clinic back east
clinic back east and
clinic back east and we
clinic back east and we were
clinic back east and we were studying
um
um all
clinic back east and we were studying
um all the
um all the things
clinic back east and we were studying
um all the things that
um all the things that could
clinic back east and we were studying
um all the things that could help
patients
patients who
patients who were
patients who were very
patients who were very desperate.
patients who were very desperate. They'd
been
been everywhere
patients who were very desperate. They'd
been everywhere in
been everywhere in the
patients who were very desperate. They'd
been everywhere in the world,
been everywhere in the world, nothing
had
had helped.
had helped. So,
had helped. So, we
had helped. So, we were
had helped. So, we were looking
had helped. So, we were looking at
had helped. So, we were looking at every
diagnostic
diagnostic and
had helped. So, we were looking at every
diagnostic and healing
diagnostic and healing modality,
many
many of
many of which
many of which uh
many of which uh traditional
many of which uh traditional science
many of which uh traditional science poo
pooed,
pooed, you
many of which uh traditional science poo
pooed, you know,
pooed, you know, cerebral
many of which uh traditional science poo
pooed, you know, cerebral allergy,
functional
functional hypoglycemia,
things
things that
functional hypoglycemia,
things that were
things that were of
functional hypoglycemia,
things that were of critical
things that were of critical importance
to
to the
to the patients
to the patients we
to the patients we saw
to the patients we saw and
to the patients we saw and were
to the patients we saw and were not
to the patients we saw and were not part
of
of traditional
to the patients we saw and were not part
of traditional medicine.
And
And one
And one of
And one of the
And one of the things
And one of the things we
And one of the things we looked
And one of the things we looked at
And one of the things we looked at was
kinesiology
kinesiology and
And one of the things we looked at was
kinesiology and muscle
kinesiology and muscle testing
And one of the things we looked at was
kinesiology and muscle testing and
various
various things
various things like
various things like that.
And
And and
various things like that.
And and the
And and the first
various things like that.
And and the first thing
And and the first thing that
various things like that.
And and the first thing that was
impressive
impressive about
impressive about it
impressive about it was
impressive about it was if
impressive about it was if you
impressive about it was if you take
impressive about it was if you take a
naive
naive person,
impressive about it was if you take a
naive person, let's
naive person, let's say
impressive about it was if you take a
naive person, let's say you
naive person, let's say you take
impressive about it was if you take a
naive person, let's say you take a
naive person, let's say you take a naive
person
person and
person and you
person and you tell
person and you tell them
person and you tell them to
person and you tell them to look
person and you tell them to look at
person and you tell them to look at the
fluorescent
fluorescent light
person and you tell them to look at the
fluorescent light and
fluorescent light and to
person and you tell them to look at the
fluorescent light and to hold
fluorescent light and to hold tell
person and you tell them to look at the
fluorescent light and to hold tell them
hold
hold your
hold your arm
hold your arm out
hold your arm out and
hold your arm out and resist
and
and then
hold your arm out and resist
and then you
and then you push
hold your arm out and resist
and then you push down.
and then you push down. If
hold your arm out and resist
and then you push down. If they
and then you push down. If they look
hold your arm out and resist
and then you push down. If they look at
the
the fluorescent
the fluorescent light,
the fluorescent light, their
the fluorescent light, their arm
the fluorescent light, their arm goes
weak.
That's
That's standard.
That's standard. Or
That's standard. Or if
That's standard. Or if you
That's standard. Or if you put
That's standard. Or if you put a
pesticide
pesticide next
That's standard. Or if you put a
pesticide next to
pesticide next to the
That's standard. Or if you put a
pesticide next to the solar
pesticide next to the solar plexus,
their
their arm
their arm goes
their arm goes weak.
So
So I
their arm goes weak.
So I was
So I was going
their arm goes weak.
So I was going to
So I was going to give
their arm goes weak.
So I was going to give a
So I was going to give a lecture
their arm goes weak.
So I was going to give a lecture on
So I was going to give a lecture on it
to
to the
to the staff
to the staff at
to the staff at the
to the staff at the clinic.
to the staff at the clinic. We
to the staff at the clinic. We had
to the staff at the clinic. We had a
pretty
pretty big
to the staff at the clinic. We had a
pretty big staff,
pretty big staff, about
to the staff at the clinic. We had a
pretty big staff, about 50
pretty big staff, about 50 people
to the staff at the clinic. We had a
pretty big staff, about 50 people or
100,
100, I
100, I guess.
100, I guess. Anyway,
100, I guess. Anyway, a
100, I guess. Anyway, a lot.
100, I guess. Anyway, a lot. And
100, I guess. Anyway, a lot. And uh
100, I guess. Anyway, a lot. And uh so
100, I guess. Anyway, a lot. And uh so I
needed
needed some
100, I guess. Anyway, a lot. And uh so I
needed some volunteers.
So
So I
So I said,
So I said, "Who
So I said, "Who wants
So I said, "Who wants to
So I said, "Who wants to volunteer?"
So I said, "Who wants to volunteer?" And
there
there were
So I said, "Who wants to volunteer?" And
there were some
there were some people
So I said, "Who wants to volunteer?" And
there were some people standing
there were some people standing around
and
and we
and we had
and we had a
and we had a attitudinal
and we had a attitudinal healing
and we had a attitudinal healing center
there
there for
and we had a attitudinal healing center
there for hopeless
there for hopeless diseases
and we had a attitudinal healing center
there for hopeless diseases based
there for hopeless diseases based on
and we had a attitudinal healing center
there for hopeless diseases based on a
course
course of
course of miracles.
course of miracles. And
course of miracles. And uh
course of miracles. And uh so
course of miracles. And uh so a
course of miracles. And uh so a couple
of
of them
course of miracles. And uh so a couple
of them were
of them were standing
course of miracles. And uh so a couple
of them were standing around
of them were standing around and
course of miracles. And uh so a couple
of them were standing around and I
of them were standing around and I said,
"Come
"Come on
"Come on over
"Come on over here.
"Come on over here. I
"Come on over here. I want
"Come on over here. I want to
demonstrate
demonstrate something."
"Come on over here. I want to
demonstrate something." So
demonstrate something." So I
"Come on over here. I want to
demonstrate something." So I said,
demonstrate something." So I said, "All
right,
right, look
right, look at
right, look at the
right, look at the fluorescent
right, look at the fluorescent lights."
And
And I
right, look at the fluorescent lights."
And I pressed
And I pressed down
right, look at the fluorescent lights."
And I pressed down and
And I pressed down and their
right, look at the fluorescent lights."
And I pressed down and their arm
And I pressed down and their arm did
right, look at the fluorescent lights."
And I pressed down and their arm did not
go
go weak.
go weak. What
makes
makes everybody's
go weak. What
makes everybody's arm
makes everybody's arm go
go weak. What
makes everybody's arm go weak?
makes everybody's arm go weak? So
go weak. What
makes everybody's arm go weak? So I
makes everybody's arm go weak? So I held
pesticides
pesticides over
pesticides over their
pesticides over their solar
pesticides over their solar plexus
pesticides over their solar plexus and
pesticides over their solar plexus and I
pressed
pressed down
pesticides over their solar plexus and I
pressed down and
pressed down and they
pesticides over their solar plexus and I
pressed down and they did
pressed down and they did not
pesticides over their solar plexus and I
pressed down and they did not go
pressed down and they did not go weak.
So
So something
So something about
So something about these
So something about these people
So something about these people had
transformed
transformed their
So something about these people had
transformed their whole
transformed their whole energy
So something about these people had
transformed their whole energy balance.
And
And with
And with further
And with further investigation,
And with further investigation, we
And with further investigation, we found
out
out that
And with further investigation, we found
out that by
out that by the
And with further investigation, we found
out that by the time
out that by the time you
And with further investigation, we found
out that by the time you get
out that by the time you get up
And with further investigation, we found
out that by the time you get up to
out that by the time you get up to about
lesson
lesson 75
lesson 75 in
lesson 75 in a
lesson 75 in a course
lesson 75 in a course of
lesson 75 in a course of miracles,
uh
uh you
lesson 75 in a course of miracles,
uh you become
uh you become immune
lesson 75 in a course of miracles,
uh you become immune to
uh you become immune to negative
stimuli.
stimuli. They
stimuli. They no
stimuli. They no longer
stimuli. They no longer blow
stimuli. They no longer blow out
stimuli. They no longer blow out your
acupuncture
acupuncture meridians.
That
That was
That was a
That was a very
That was a very important
That was a very important discovery.
Then
Then then
That was a very important discovery.
Then then uh
Then then uh it
That was a very important discovery.
Then then uh it came
Then then uh it came to
That was a very important discovery.
Then then uh it came to me
Then then uh it came to me from
That was a very important discovery.
Then then uh it came to me from uh
Then then uh it came to me from uh other
places
that
that you
places
that you could
that you could calibrate
places
that you could calibrate it
that you could calibrate it an
places
that you could calibrate it an actual
scale
scale of
scale of relativity.
And
And by
scale of relativity.
And by using
And by using the
scale of relativity.
And by using the same
And by using the same technique
scale of relativity.
And by using the same technique uh
And by using the same technique uh we
went
went up
went up the
went up the traditional
went up the traditional chain
went up the traditional chain of
went up the traditional chain of being
starting
starting out
went up the traditional chain of being
starting out at
starting out at the
went up the traditional chain of being
starting out at the bottom
starting out at the bottom is
went up the traditional chain of being
starting out at the bottom is hatred
starting out at the bottom is hatred and
despair
despair and
despair and and
despair and and all
despair and and all the
so
so we
despair and and all the
so we started
so we started out
despair and and all the
so we started out with
so we started out with the
despair and and all the
so we started out with the chain
so we started out with the chain of
being
being and
being and we
being and we found
being and we found uh
being and we found uh that
being and we found uh that all
being and we found uh that all things
like
like shame
being and we found uh that all things
like shame and
like shame and hate
being and we found uh that all things
like shame and hate and
like shame and hate and all
being and we found uh that all things
like shame and hate and all calibrated
way
way down
way down at
way down at the
way down at the bottom
way down at the bottom and
way down at the bottom and the
way down at the bottom and the emotion
going
going with
way down at the bottom and the emotion
going with that
going with that is
way down at the bottom and the emotion
going with that is humiliation.
And
And so
And so we
And so we constructed
And so we constructed this
And so we constructed this is
And so we constructed this is the
classic
classic chain
And so we constructed this is the
classic chain of
classic chain of being
And so we constructed this is the
classic chain of being uh
classic chain of being uh it's
And so we constructed this is the
classic chain of being uh it's in
classic chain of being uh it's in many
uh
uh psychological
studies
studies and
uh psychological
studies and traditional
studies and traditional spiritual
traditions
and
and we
traditions
and we found
and we found a
traditions
and we found a correlation
and we found a correlation between
traditions
and we found a correlation between your
view
view the
view the view
view the view of
view the view of yourself
view the view of yourself a
view the view of yourself a view
view the view of yourself a view of
view the view of yourself a view of God
the
the level
view the view of yourself a view of God
the level emotional
the level emotional level
view the view of yourself a view of God
the level emotional level and
the level emotional level and a
calibrated
calibrated scale
and
and the
calibrated scale
and the process
and the process going
calibrated scale
and the process going on
and the process going on within
consciousness.
So
to
to move
to move from
to move from the
to move from the lower
to move from the lower to
to move from the lower to the
to move from the lower to the upper
means
means to
to move from the lower to the upper
means to go
means to go through
uh
uh this
uh this process.
So
So you
uh this process.
So you can
So you can see
uh this process.
So you can see that
So you can see that despair,
humiliation,
humiliation, blame,
humiliation, blame, all
humiliation, blame, all these
humiliation, blame, all these things,
craving
craving and
humiliation, blame, all these things,
craving and hate
etc.
etc. are
etc. are amanable
etc. are amanable to
etc. are amanable to let's
etc. are amanable to let's say
forgiveness
forgiveness is
etc. are amanable to let's say
forgiveness is a
forgiveness is a very
etc. are amanable to let's say
forgiveness is a very powerful
forgiveness is a very powerful one.
etc. are amanable to let's say
forgiveness is a very powerful one. You
can
can always
can always if
can always if you're
can always if you're willing
can always if you're willing forgive
anything
anything of
can always if you're willing forgive
anything of anyone
anything of anyone and
can always if you're willing forgive
anything of anyone and see
anything of anyone and see and
can always if you're willing forgive
anything of anyone and see and you
that's
that's what
that's what Jesus
that's what Jesus Christ
that's what Jesus Christ taught
that's what Jesus Christ taught the
sermon
sermon on
that's what Jesus Christ taught the
sermon on the
sermon on the mount
that's what Jesus Christ taught the
sermon on the mount through
sermon on the mount through forgiveness
uh
to
to move
uh
to move from
to move from the
uh
to move from the bottom
to move from the bottom of
uh
to move from the bottom of the
to move from the bottom of the ladder
from
from the
from the move
from the move from
from the move from the
from the move from the bottom
from the move from the bottom from
from the move from the bottom from all
these
these negative
from the move from the bottom from all
these negative emotions.
these negative emotions. In
from the move from the bottom from all
these negative emotions. In psychiatry,
these
these are
these are called
these are called the
these are called the emergency
these are called the emergency emotions.
Everything
Everything from
these are called the emergency emotions.
Everything from 200
Everything from 200 down.
these are called the emergency emotions.
Everything from 200 down. And
Everything from 200 down. And these
these are called the emergency emotions.
Everything from 200 down. And these are
called
called the
called the welfare
called the welfare emotions.
We
We know
called the welfare emotions.
We know that
We know that healing
called the welfare emotions.
We know that healing takes
We know that healing takes place
called the welfare emotions.
We know that healing takes place through
all
all these
all these positive
all these positive emotions.
all these positive emotions. Lovingness,
uh
uh willingness,
all these positive emotions. Lovingness,
uh willingness, acceptance,
reason,
reason, love,
reason, love, joy,
reason, love, joy, and
reason, love, joy, and eventually
reason, love, joy, and eventually peace.
And
And if
reason, love, joy, and eventually peace.
And if you
And if you keep
reason, love, joy, and eventually peace.
And if you keep doing
And if you keep doing this,
reason, love, joy, and eventually peace.
And if you keep doing this, you
And if you keep doing this, you end
reason, love, joy, and eventually peace.
And if you keep doing this, you end up
with
with a
with a state
with a state of
with a state of enlightenment.
with a state of enlightenment. So
with a state of enlightenment. So that's
just
just a
with a state of enlightenment. So that's
just a quick
just a quick review
with a state of enlightenment. So that's
just a quick review for
just a quick review for those
with a state of enlightenment. So that's
just a quick review for those who
just a quick review for those who are
not
not familiar
not familiar with
not familiar with it.
not familiar with it. Everybody
not familiar with it. Everybody here
not familiar with it. Everybody here is
generally
generally familiar
not familiar with it. Everybody here is
generally familiar with
generally familiar with it.
not familiar with it. Everybody here is
generally familiar with it. All
generally familiar with it. All right.
So
So now
So now we
So now we have
So now we have just
So now we have just a
So now we have just a few
So now we have just a few review
So now we have just a few review slides.
We'll
We'll do
So now we have just a few review slides.
We'll do them
We'll do them successfively
So now we have just a few review slides.
We'll do them successfively this
morning.
morning. What's
morning. What's the
morning. What's the next
morning. What's the next one?
Oh,
I
I don't
I don't know.
I don't know. Oh,
I don't know. Oh, yes.
I don't know. Oh, yes. Those
I don't know. Oh, yes. Those are
I don't know. Oh, yes. Those are the
higher
higher states.
I don't know. Oh, yes. Those are the
higher states. The
higher states. The other
I don't know. Oh, yes. Those are the
higher states. The other u
higher states. The other u the
I don't know. Oh, yes. Those are the
higher states. The other u the other
scale
scale only
scale only goes
scale only goes up
scale only goes up to
scale only goes up to 600.
scale only goes up to 600. Uh
scale only goes up to 600. Uh but
scale only goes up to 600. Uh but these
are
are the
scale only goes up to 600. Uh but these
are the higher
are the higher states
scale only goes up to 600. Uh but these
are the higher states from
are the higher states from 600
scale only goes up to 600. Uh but these
are the higher states from 600 on
are the higher states from 600 on up
scale only goes up to 600. Uh but these
are the higher states from 600 on up to
a
a thousand
a thousand from
a thousand from eight
a thousand from eight from
a thousand from eight from 600
a thousand from eight from 600 up
a thousand from eight from 600 up to
a thousand from eight from 600 up to a
thousand.
thousand. Usually
a thousand from eight from 600 up to a
thousand. Usually at
thousand. Usually at any
a thousand from eight from 600 up to a
thousand. Usually at any one
thousand. Usually at any one time
a thousand from eight from 600 up to a
thousand. Usually at any one time there
may
may be
may be only
may be only a
may be only a two
may be only a two one
may be only a two one or
may be only a two one or two
may be only a two one or two or
may be only a two one or two or maybe
sometimes
sometimes even
may be only a two one or two or maybe
sometimes even no
sometimes even no uh
may be only a two one or two or maybe
sometimes even no uh people
sometimes even no uh people on
may be only a two one or two or maybe
sometimes even no uh people on the
planet
planet that
planet that calibrate
planet that calibrate 600
planet that calibrate 600 over
planet that calibrate 600 over 600
planet that calibrate 600 over 600 is
the
the opening
planet that calibrate 600 over 600 is
the opening of
the opening of the
planet that calibrate 600 over 600 is
the opening of the third
the opening of the third eye
planet that calibrate 600 over 600 is
the opening of the third eye of
the opening of the third eye of the
Buddha
Buddha body
Buddha body in
Buddha body in which
Buddha body in which you
Buddha body in which you instantly
perceive
perceive the
Buddha body in which you instantly
perceive the difference
perceive the difference between
appearance
appearance and
appearance and essence.
appearance and essence. behind
appearance and essence. behind the
appearance
appearance you
appearance and essence. behind the
appearance you see
appearance you see the
appearance and essence. behind the
appearance you see the essence
appearance you see the essence of
appearance and essence. behind the
appearance you see the essence of a
thing.
thing. So
thing. So and
thing. So and that's
thing. So and that's called
thing. So and that's called the
thing. So and that's called the opening
of
of the
thing. So and that's called the opening
of the third
of the third eye
thing. So and that's called the opening
of the third eye of
of the third eye of the
thing. So and that's called the opening
of the third eye of the Buddha
of the third eye of the Buddha body.
thing. So and that's called the opening
of the third eye of the Buddha body. So
we'll
we'll move
we'll move on
we'll move on to
we'll move on to the
we'll move on to the next.
This
This is
we'll move on to the next.
This is the
This is the scale
we'll move on to the next.
This is the scale of
This is the scale of energy
uh
uh energy
uh energy as
uh energy as consciousness
uh energy as consciousness goes
uh energy as consciousness goes up
uh energy as consciousness goes up uh
the
the energy
uh energy as consciousness goes up uh
the energy goes
the energy goes up
uh energy as consciousness goes up uh
the energy goes up becomes
the energy goes up becomes more
uh energy as consciousness goes up uh
the energy goes up becomes more and
the energy goes up becomes more and more
powerful.
So
So one
powerful.
So one person
one
one person
one person at
one person at a
one person at a very
one person at a very high
one person at a very high level
one person at a very high level of
consciousness
consciousness can
one person at a very high level of
consciousness can actually
counterbalance
counterbalance all
counterbalance all of
counterbalance all of humanity
counterbalance all of humanity by
counterbalance all of humanity by the
fact
fact that
counterbalance all of humanity by the
fact that it
fact that it it
counterbalance all of humanity by the
fact that it it the
fact that it it the power
counterbalance all of humanity by the
fact that it it the power goes
fact that it it the power goes up
counterbalance all of humanity by the
fact that it it the power goes up so
rapidly.
rapidly. Next,
rapidly. Next, next
rapidly. Next, next one.
The
The uh
rapidly. Next, next one.
The uh 85%
The uh 85% of
rapidly. Next, next one.
The uh 85% of the
The uh 85% of the world's
population
population 85%
population 85% This
population 85% This is
population 85% This is the
population 85% This is the world's
population.
population. The
population 85% This is the world's
population. The majority
population. The majority of
population 85% This is the world's
population. The majority of the
population. The majority of the world's
population
population calibrates
population calibrates below
population calibrates below 200.
population calibrates below 200. The
majority
majority of
population calibrates below 200. The
majority of the
majority of the world's
population calibrates below 200. The
majority of the world's population,
in
in fact,
in fact, the
in fact, the number
in fact, the number above
in fact, the number above 200
in fact, the number above 200 is
minuscule
minuscule compared
in fact, the number above 200 is
minuscule compared to
minuscule compared to the
in fact, the number above 200 is
minuscule compared to the masses
minuscule compared to the masses below.
So
So why
So why doesn't
So why doesn't society
So why doesn't society self-destruct?
Because
Because the
So why doesn't society self-destruct?
Because the power
Because the power of
So why doesn't society self-destruct?
Because the power of these
Because the power of these individuals
here
here is
here is so
here is so enormous
here is so enormous that
here is so enormous that they
counterbalance.
counterbalance. Next
here is so enormous that they
counterbalance. Next slide.
That
That they
That they counterbalance.
That they counterbalance. And
That they counterbalance. And this
That they counterbalance. And this is
That they counterbalance. And this is a
classic
diagram
diagram showing
diagram showing the
diagram showing the 15%
diagram showing the 15% of
diagram showing the 15% of the
diagram showing the 15% of the world's
population
population that
diagram showing the 15% of the world's
population that calibrates
population that calibrates over
diagram showing the 15% of the world's
population that calibrates over 200
counterbalances
counterbalances the
counterbalances the 85%
that
that is
counterbalances the 85%
that is below
that is below 200.
But
But it
But it explains
But it explains human
But it explains human history.
But it explains human history. Human
history.
history. You
But it explains human history. Human
history. You know,
history. You know, we've
But it explains human history. Human
history. You know, we've had
history. You know, we've had war
something
something like
something like 97%
something like 97% of
something like 97% of recorded
something like 97% of recorded time.
something like 97% of recorded time. And
right
right now
something like 97% of recorded time. And
right now there's
right now there's probably
something like 97% of recorded time. And
right now there's probably half
right now there's probably half a
something like 97% of recorded time. And
right now there's probably half a dozen
wars.
wars. Since
wars. Since I've
wars. Since I've been
wars. Since I've been on
wars. Since I've been on the
wars. Since I've been on the planet,
there's
there's been
wars. Since I've been on the planet,
there's been a
there's been a couple
wars. Since I've been on the planet,
there's been a couple of
there's been a couple of wars
wars. Since I've been on the planet,
there's been a couple of wars all
there's been a couple of wars all the
time.
I
I consider
time.
I consider war
I consider war to
time.
I consider war to be
I consider war to be a
time.
I consider war to be a normal
I consider war to be a normal state.
If
If you're
If you're not
If you're not at
If you're not at war,
If you're not at war, what's
If you're not at war, what's the
If you're not at war, what's the matter
with
with you?
You
You should
You should be
You should be aware
You should be aware about
You should be aware about something.
You should be aware about something. I
mean,
mean, you
You should be aware about something. I
mean, you know.
mean, you know. Okay.
You should be aware about something. I
mean, you know. Okay. What's
mean, you know. Okay. What's next?
You should be aware about something. I
mean, you know. Okay. What's next? And
this
this is
this is just
this is just a
this is just a a
this is just a a re
this is just a a re repetition
this is just a a re repetition of
this is just a a re repetition of the
same
same concept.
this is just a a re repetition of the
same concept. But
same concept. But this
this is just a a re repetition of the
same concept. But this this
visualization
visualization just
visualization just makes
visualization just makes it
visualization just makes it cement
visualization just makes it cement in
memory
memory so
visualization just makes it cement in
memory so you
memory so you can
visualization just makes it cement in
memory so you can comprehend
and
and account
and account for
and account for the
and account for the state
and account for the state of
and account for the state of the
and account for the state of the world.
Okay.
Okay. Next
uh
uh the
uh the evolution
uh the evolution of
uh the evolution of consciousness
uh the evolution of consciousness over
time
um
um as
um as we
um as we see
um as we see the
um as we see the consciousness
um as we see the consciousness was
um as we see the consciousness was very
low
low at
um as we see the consciousness was very
low at the
low at the time
um as we see the consciousness was very
low at the time of
low at the time of uh
um as we see the consciousness was very
low at the time of uh the
low at the time of uh the Buddha.
um as we see the consciousness was very
low at the time of uh the Buddha. The
consciousness
consciousness level
consciousness level of
consciousness level of mankind
consciousness level of mankind was
consciousness level of mankind was about
70.
70. Uh
consciousness level of mankind was about
70. Uh by
70. Uh by the
consciousness level of mankind was about
70. Uh by the time
70. Uh by the time of
consciousness level of mankind was about
70. Uh by the time of Jesus
70. Uh by the time of Jesus Christ
consciousness level of mankind was about
70. Uh by the time of Jesus Christ it
was
was about
was about 90.
was about 90. Anyway
was about 90. Anyway the
was about 90. Anyway the consciousness
level
uh
uh very
uh very very
uh very very slowly
uh very very slowly and
uh very very slowly and then
uh very very slowly and then suddenly
uh very very slowly and then suddenly in
the
the late
uh very very slowly and then suddenly in
the late 1980s
it
it suddenly
it suddenly shot
it suddenly shot up
it suddenly shot up for
it suddenly shot up for no
it suddenly shot up for no apparent
reason.
reason. the
it suddenly shot up for no apparent
reason. the late
reason. the late 1980s,
it suddenly shot up for no apparent
reason. the late 1980s, the
consciousness
consciousness level
consciousness level of
consciousness level of mankind,
mankind
mankind was
consciousness level of mankind,
mankind was at
mankind was at 190
consciousness level of mankind,
mankind was at 190 for
mankind was at 190 for many
consciousness level of mankind,
mankind was at 190 for many centuries.
All
All throughout
All throughout the
All throughout the Middle
All throughout the Middle Ages,
it
it was
All throughout the Middle Ages,
it was at
it was at 190.
All throughout the Middle Ages,
it was at 190. And
it was at 190. And suddenly
in
in the
in the late
in the late 80s,
in the late 80s, for
in the late 80s, for no
in the late 80s, for no apparent
in the late 80s, for no apparent reason,
never
never actually
in the late 80s, for no apparent reason,
never actually explained.
never actually explained. It
in the late 80s, for no apparent reason,
never actually explained. It jumped
never actually explained. It jumped from
190 to
190 to 204
190 to 204 and
190 to 204 and then
190 to 204 and then went
190 to 204 and then went up
190 to 204 and then went up to
190 to 204 and then went up to 207
190 to 204 and then went up to 207 and
now
now it's
190 to 204 and then went up to 207 and
now it's back
now it's back down
190 to 204 and then went up to 207 and
now it's back down to
now it's back down to 204
190 to 204 and then went up to 207 and
now it's back down to 204 again.
now it's back down to 204 again. All
right,
right, we'll
right, we'll move
right, we'll move to
right, we'll move to the
right, we'll move to the next
right, we'll move to the next one.
right, we'll move to the next one. So
right, we'll move to the next one. So we
calibrated
calibrated all
right, we'll move to the next one. So we
calibrated all the
calibrated all the animals
right, we'll move to the next one. So we
calibrated all the animals on
calibrated all the animals on the
right, we'll move to the next one. So we
calibrated all the animals on the planet
and
and uh
this
this has
and uh
this has lots
this has lots of
and uh
this has lots of interesting
implications.
Uh
Uh you
implications.
Uh you see
Uh you see the
implications.
Uh you see the predatory
Uh you see the predatory animals
calibrate
calibrate all
calibrate all below
calibrate all below 200.
calibrate all below 200. Below
calibrate all below 200. Below 200
calibrate all below 200. Below 200 you
have
have the
calibrate all below 200. Below 200 you
have the predatory
have the predatory the
calibrate all below 200. Below 200 you
have the predatory the uh
have the predatory the uh the
calibrate all below 200. Below 200 you
have the predatory the uh the predatory
animals
animals the
animals the wolf
animals the wolf the
animals the wolf the these
animals the wolf the these people
animals the wolf the these people all
live
live majority
animals the wolf the these people all
live majority majority
live majority majority not
animals the wolf the these people all
live majority majority not all
live majority majority not all live
animals the wolf the these people all
live majority majority not all live by
the
the sacrificing
the sacrificing the
the sacrificing the life
the sacrificing the life of
the sacrificing the life of others
the sacrificing the life of others from
200 and
200 and up
the sacrificing the life of others from
200 and up uh
200 and up uh and
the sacrificing the life of others from
200 and up uh and the
200 and up uh and the animal
the sacrificing the life of others from
200 and up uh and the animal world
becomes
becomes more
becomes more benign.
You
You get
becomes more benign.
You get up
You get up to
becomes more benign.
You get up to the
You get up to the kitty
becomes more benign.
You get up to the kitty cats,
You get up to the kitty cats, the
becomes more benign.
You get up to the kitty cats, the family
cat,
cat, the
cat, the family
cat, the family dog,
cat, the family dog, monkeys,
cat, the family dog, monkeys, gorillas,
chimpanzees.
Oscar
Oscar the
Oscar the cat
Oscar the cat is
Oscar the cat is at
Oscar the cat is at 250.
Alex
Alex the
Oscar the cat is at 250.
Alex the trained
Alex the trained African
Oscar the cat is at 250.
Alex the trained African gray
Alex the trained African gray parrot
Oscar the cat is at 250.
Alex the trained African gray parrot is
at
at 400.
at 400. Very
at 400. Very famous
at 400. Very famous parrot.
And
And Koko
at 400. Very famous parrot.
And Koko the
And Koko the trained
at 400. Very famous parrot.
And Koko the trained gorilla
And Koko the trained gorilla at
at 400. Very famous parrot.
And Koko the trained gorilla at 405.
Koko
Koko the
Koko the train
Koko the train gorilla
Koko the train gorilla is
Koko the train gorilla is more
Koko the train gorilla is more conscious
and
and safer
Koko the train gorilla is more conscious
and safer to
and safer to be
Koko the train gorilla is more conscious
and safer to be with
and safer to be with than
Koko the train gorilla is more conscious
and safer to be with than 90%
and safer to be with than 90% of
mankind.
Coco
Coco is
mankind.
Coco is very
Coco is very gentle.
mankind.
Coco is very gentle. We
Coco is very gentle. We got
mankind.
Coco is very gentle. We got a
Coco is very gentle. We got a picture
mankind.
Coco is very gentle. We got a picture of
Coco
Coco at
Coco at home
Coco at home holding
Coco at home holding a
Coco at home holding a kitty.
Coco at home holding a kitty. Says,
"Soft,
"Soft, nice,
Coco at home holding a kitty. Says,
"Soft, nice, nice
"Soft, nice, nice kitty."
Coco at home holding a kitty. Says,
"Soft, nice, nice kitty." Soft,
"Soft, nice, nice kitty." Soft, nice,
nice
nice kitty.
I
I thought
nice kitty.
I thought that's
I thought that's so
nice kitty.
I thought that's so cute.
I thought that's so cute. The
nice kitty.
I thought that's so cute. The cats
I thought that's so cute. The cats purr
and
and the
and the dogs
and the dogs wagging
and the dogs wagging tail
and the dogs wagging tail are
and the dogs wagging tail are now
famous.
famous. So,
and the dogs wagging tail are now
famous. So, if
famous. So, if you're
and the dogs wagging tail are now
famous. So, if you're surrounded
famous. So, if you're surrounded by
purring
purring cats
purring cats and
purring cats and dogs
purring cats and dogs with
purring cats and dogs with wagging
tails,
tails, you're
purring cats and dogs with wagging
tails, you're you're
tails, you're you're in
purring cats and dogs with wagging
tails, you're you're in a
tails, you're you're in a good
purring cats and dogs with wagging
tails, you're you're in a good place
already.
Stay
Stay off
already.
Stay off the
Stay off the telephone
already.
Stay off the telephone and
Stay off the telephone and you're
already.
Stay off the telephone and you're going
to
to have
to have a
to have a good
to have a good day.
Stay
Stay off
to have a good day.
Stay off the
Stay off the blogger
to have a good day.
Stay off the blogger the
Stay off the blogger the blogger
machine.
All right.
All right. Now,
machine.
All right. Now, what's
All right. Now, what's the
machine.
All right. Now, what's the next
All right. Now, what's the next one?
Oh,
Oh, yes.
Oh, yes. The
Oh, yes. The great
Oh, yes. The great books
Oh, yes. The great books of
Oh, yes. The great books of the
Oh, yes. The great books of the western
world.
world. Uh
Oh, yes. The great books of the western
world. Uh this
world. Uh this may
Oh, yes. The great books of the western
world. Uh this may sound
world. Uh this may sound academic,
Oh, yes. The great books of the western
world. Uh this may sound academic, but
it
it is
it is of
it is of enormous
it is of enormous uh
it is of enormous uh importance
it is of enormous uh importance in
today's
today's world.
it is of enormous uh importance in
today's world. uh
the
the greatness
the greatness of
the greatness of western
the greatness of western civilization
was
was was
the greatness of western civilization
was was built.
was was built. This
the greatness of western civilization
was was built. This is
was was built. This is the
the greatness of western civilization
was was built. This is the intellectual
structure
structure of
structure of the
structure of the basis
structure of the basis of
structure of the basis of western
civilization.
And
And you
And you see
And you see it
And you see it calibrates
And you see it calibrates in
And you see it calibrates in the
primarily
primarily in
And you see it calibrates in the
primarily in the
primarily in the in
And you see it calibrates in the
primarily in the in the
primarily in the in the high
And you see it calibrates in the
primarily in the in the high 400s.
And
And this
And this is
And this is the
And this is the reason,
And this is the reason, logic,
And this is the reason, logic, scient
science,
science, scientific
And this is the reason, logic, scient
science, scientific proof,
uh
uh all
uh all the
uh all the great
uh all the great philosophers
uh all the great philosophers from
uh all the great philosophers from Plato
uh
uh on
uh all the great philosophers from Plato
uh on down
uh on down to
uh all the great philosophers from Plato
uh on down to current
uh on down to current times.
This
This is
This is the
This is the great
This is the great books
This is the great books of
This is the great books of the
This is the great books of the western
world.
world. It
This is the great books of the western
world. It was
world. It was compiled
This is the great books of the western
world. It was compiled at
world. It was compiled at the
This is the great books of the western
world. It was compiled at the University
of
of Chicago
of Chicago by
of Chicago by somebody
of Chicago by somebody whose
of Chicago by somebody whose name
of Chicago by somebody whose name I
always
always forget.
of Chicago by somebody whose name I
always forget. And
always forget. And uh
of Chicago by somebody whose name I
always forget. And uh the
always forget. And uh the thing
of Chicago by somebody whose name I
always forget. And uh the thing that's
important
important about
important about it
important about it is
important about it is you
important about it is you get
important about it is you get that
important about it is you get that the
400s
400s are
important about it is you get that the
400s are the
400s are the intellect
important about it is you get that the
400s are the intellect and
400s are the intellect and integrity.
See
See there's
See there's there's
See there's there's faith
See there's there's faith and
See there's there's faith and then
there's
there's reason.
See there's there's faith and then
there's reason. And
there's reason. And faith
See there's there's faith and then
there's reason. And faith needs
there's reason. And faith needs to
See there's there's faith and then
there's reason. And faith needs to be
enforced
enforced by
enforced by reason
enforced by reason and
enforced by reason and the
enforced by reason and the two
enforced by reason and the two should
enforced by reason and the two should be
mutually
mutually reinforcing.
enforced by reason and the two should be
mutually reinforcing. Yeah.
All
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, the
All right. So, the thing
All right. So, the thing the
All right. So, the thing the implication
for
for today's
All right. So, the thing the implication
for today's society
for today's society because
All right. So, the thing the implication
for today's society because we're
for today's society because we're going
to
to be
to be looking
to be looking at
to be looking at the
to be looking at the world
to be looking at the world today
to be looking at the world today is
to be looking at the world today is you
see
see they
to be looking at the world today is you
see they are
see they are all
to be looking at the world today is you
see they are all in
see they are all in the
to be looking at the world today is you
see they are all in the 400s.
see they are all in the 400s. They're
all
all very
all very very
all very very high.
all very very high. Uh
all very very high. Uh Dante
all very very high. Uh Dante however
all very very high. Uh Dante however is
at
at 505.
all very very high. Uh Dante however is
at 505. A
at 505. A few
all very very high. Uh Dante however is
at 505. A few others
at 505. A few others are
all very very high. Uh Dante however is
at 505. A few others are Augustine
at 505. A few others are Augustine five
over
over 500.
Darwin
Darwin at
over 500.
Darwin at 450.
And
And then
And then you
And then you see
And then you see angles
And then you see angles at
And then you see angles at 200
and
and uh
And then you see angles at 200
and uh Markx
and uh Markx I
And then you see angles at 200
and uh Markx I don't
and uh Markx I don't know
And then you see angles at 200
and uh Markx I don't know where
and uh Markx I don't know where he
And then you see angles at 200
and uh Markx I don't know where he is.
Here's
Here's Markx
doesn't
doesn't belong
Here's Markx
doesn't belong on
doesn't belong on the
Here's Markx
doesn't belong on the list.
doesn't belong on the list. Got
Here's Markx
doesn't belong on the list. Got put
doesn't belong on the list. Got put in
there
there because
there because of
there because of the
there because of the importance
there because of the importance of
there because of the importance of his
work,
work, social
there because of the importance of his
work, social importance.
But
But right
But right now
But right now the
But right now the problem
But right now the problem in
But right now the problem in society
But right now the problem in society is
um
um what
But right now the problem in society is
um what I
um what I would
But right now the problem in society is
um what I would call
um what I would call cultural
But right now the problem in society is
um what I would call cultural Marxism
perpetrator
perpetrator victim
projected
projected onto
perpetrator victim
projected onto everything
projected onto everything that
perpetrator victim
projected onto everything that you
projected onto everything that you see
in
in the
in the world.
in the world. So
in the world. So that
in the world. So that you
in the world. So that you can
in the world. So that you can take
anybody
anybody and
superimpose
an
an interpretation
of
of victim
of victim and
of victim and perpetrator.
And
And we'll
of victim and perpetrator.
And we'll see
And we'll see that
of victim and perpetrator.
And we'll see that later
And we'll see that later when
of victim and perpetrator.
And we'll see that later when we
And we'll see that later when we get
of victim and perpetrator.
And we'll see that later when we get to
things
things that
things that are
things that are more
things that are more current.
things that are more current. Okay.
things that are more current. Okay. The
next
next thing
uh
how
how a
uh
how a thing
how a thing comes
uh
how a thing comes about
in
in the
in the lectures
in the lectures we
in the lectures we we we
in the lectures we we we point
in the lectures we we we point out
reemphasize
that
that there
that there is
that there is nothing
that there is nothing causing
that there is nothing causing anything
else.
else. There's
that there is nothing causing anything
else. There's no
else. There's no cause
that there is nothing causing anything
else. There's no cause for
else. There's no cause for anything.
There
There is
There is the
There is the origin
There is the origin of
There is the origin of it
but
but there
There is the origin of it
but there is
but there is no
There is the origin of it
but there is no cause.
but there is no cause. In
There is the origin of it
but there is no cause. In other
but there is no cause. In other words,
the
the phenomena
the phenomena that
the phenomena that you
the phenomena that you see,
the phenomena that you see, the
the phenomena that you see, the mind
tends
tends to
the phenomena that you see, the mind
tends to put
tends to put it
the phenomena that you see, the mind
tends to put it in
tends to put it in a
the phenomena that you see, the mind
tends to put it in a linear
uh
uh scientific
uh scientific causality,
uh scientific causality, Newtonian
causality.
Actually,
Actually, everything
Actually, everything is
Actually, everything is occurring
spontaneously.
Everything
Everything is
Everything is autonomous
Everything is autonomous and
Everything is autonomous and occurring
of
of itself.
Everything is autonomous and occurring
of itself. Nothing
of itself. Nothing is
Everything is autonomous and occurring
of itself. Nothing is being
of itself. Nothing is being caused
Everything is autonomous and occurring
of itself. Nothing is being caused by
anything
anything else.
Let's
Let's see.
What
What I
What I just
What I just spoke
What I just spoke was
What I just spoke was the
What I just spoke was the truth
What I just spoke was the truth resist.
Nothing
Nothing is
What I just spoke was the truth resist.
Nothing is causing
Nothing is causing anything
What I just spoke was the truth resist.
Nothing is causing anything else.
Nor
Nor is
Nor is anything
Nor is anything happening
Nor is anything happening in
Nor is anything happening in time.
Time
Time and
Nor is anything happening in time.
Time and causality
Time and causality are
Nor is anything happening in time.
Time and causality are things
Time and causality are things that
Nor is anything happening in time.
Time and causality are things that we
mentally
mentally construct
mentally construct and
mentally construct and then
mentally construct and then projected
out
out into
mentally construct and then projected
out into the
out into the world.
mentally construct and then projected
out into the world. Projected
out into the world. Projected into
mentally construct and then projected
out into the world. Projected into the
world.
Consciousness
Consciousness is
world.
Consciousness is an
Consciousness is an infinite
world.
Consciousness is an infinite field
Consciousness is an infinite field of
infinite
infinite field
infinite field everywhere
infinite field everywhere present
infinite field everywhere present beyond
time
time and
infinite field everywhere present beyond
time and place.
Consequently,
Consequently, because
Consequently, because it's
Consequently, because it's beyond
Consequently, because it's beyond time
and
and place,
Consequently, because it's beyond time
and place, it
and place, it has
Consequently, because it's beyond time
and place, it has no
and place, it has no center.
Consequently, because it's beyond time
and place, it has no center. Also,
and place, it has no center. Also, in
the
the infinite
the infinite field
the infinite field of
the infinite field of consciousness,
there
there is
the infinite field of consciousness,
there is no
there is no then
the infinite field of consciousness,
there is no then and
there is no then and there
the infinite field of consciousness,
there is no then and there is
there is no then and there is no
the infinite field of consciousness,
there is no then and there is no no
there is no then and there is no no now
or
or future.
or future. There
or future. There is
or future. There is no
or future. There is no time
or future. There is no time itself
or future. There is no time itself is
or future. There is no time itself is a
mental
mental construction
or future. There is no time itself is a
mental construction projected
mental construction projected by
or future. There is no time itself is a
mental construction projected by the
human
human mind.
human mind. That's
human mind. That's hard
human mind. That's hard to
human mind. That's hard to believe.
Isn't
Isn't that
human mind. That's hard to believe.
Isn't that hard
Isn't that hard to
human mind. That's hard to believe.
Isn't that hard to believe?
Isn't
Isn't that
Isn't that hard
Isn't that hard to
Isn't that hard to believe?
I
I can
Isn't that hard to believe?
I can hardly
I can hardly believe
Isn't that hard to believe?
I can hardly believe it.
Time
Time and
Time and location
are
are mentalizations
Time and location
are mentalizations that
are mentalizations that we
Time and location
are mentalizations that we project
are mentalizations that we project onto
an
an infinite
an infinite field
an infinite field of
an infinite field of power
in
in which
an infinite field of power
in which no
in which no such
an infinite field of power
in which no such thing
in which no such thing actually
an infinite field of power
in which no such thing actually exists.
So
So it's
So it's a
So it's a mentalization.
So it's a mentalization. Henry
So it's a mentalization. Henry Stap
So it's a mentalization. Henry Stap the
professor
professor of
So it's a mentalization. Henry Stap the
professor of physics
professor of physics at
So it's a mentalization. Henry Stap the
professor of physics at Berkeley
professor of physics at Berkeley has
written
written a
written a book
written a book called
written a book called Mindful
written a book called Mindful Universe
and
and and
written a book called Mindful Universe
and and from
and and from it
written a book called Mindful Universe
and and from it we
and and from it we can
written a book called Mindful Universe
and and from it we can just
and and from it we can just take
written a book called Mindful Universe
and and from it we can just take this
this
this interesting
this interesting series
this interesting series of
this interesting series of Henry
this interesting series of Henry staff
the
the universe
this interesting series of Henry staff
the universe is
the universe is the
this interesting series of Henry staff
the universe is the repository
the universe is the repository of
information
information a
information a quantum
information a quantum state
information a quantum state a
information a quantum state a wave
function
intention
intention collapses
intention collapses the
intention collapses the wave
intention collapses the wave function
intention collapses the wave function so
how
how does
intention collapses the wave function so
how does how
how does how does
intention collapses the wave function so
how does how does anything
how does how does anything come
intention collapses the wave function so
how does how does anything come about
how does how does anything come about if
it's
it's not
it's not caused
it
it comes
it's not caused
it comes comes
it comes comes about
it's not caused
it comes comes about as
it comes comes about as a
it's not caused
it comes comes about as a as
it comes comes about as a as the
fulfillment
fulfillment of
fulfillment of a
fulfillment of a potentiality
fulfillment of a potentiality of
fulfillment of a potentiality of the
universe
universe and
fulfillment of a potentiality of the
universe and what
universe and what makes
fulfillment of a potentiality of the
universe and what makes it
universe and what makes it appear
fulfillment of a potentiality of the
universe and what makes it appear yeah
phenomenally
phenomenally is
phenomenally is intention.
So
So intention
phenomenally is intention.
So intention then
So intention then is
phenomenally is intention.
So intention then is what
So intention then is what we
phenomenally is intention.
So intention then is what we call
So intention then is what we call it
phenomenally is intention.
So intention then is what we call it the
Heisenberg
Heisenberg process
Heisenberg process choice
Heisenberg process choice intention.
The
The universe
Heisenberg process choice intention.
The universe goes
The universe goes from
Heisenberg process choice intention.
The universe goes from potential
The universe goes from potential to
actual.
actual. It's
actual. It's a
actual. It's a it's
actual. It's a it's potentially
actual. It's a it's potentially this
actual. It's a it's potentially this and
then
then it
actual. It's a it's potentially this and
then it becomes
then it becomes an
actual. It's a it's potentially this and
then it becomes an actual.
So
So what
So what you're
So what you're seeing
So what you're seeing then
So what you're seeing then is
So what you're seeing then is not
causation.
causation. What
So what you're seeing then is not
causation. What you're
causation. What you're seeing
So what you're seeing then is not
causation. What you're seeing is
causation. What you're seeing is the
collapse
collapse of
collapse of the
collapse of the wave
collapse of the wave function
collapse of the wave function in
collapse of the wave function in the
collapse of the wave function in the in
a
a quantum
collapse of the wave function in the in
a quantum universe
a quantum universe in
collapse of the wave function in the in
a quantum universe in which
a quantum universe in which the
potential
potential becomes
potential becomes the
potential becomes the actual
potential becomes the actual by
potential becomes the actual by virtue
of
of intention.
potential becomes the actual by virtue
of intention. So
of intention. So this
potential becomes the actual by virtue
of intention. So this demonstrates
of intention. So this demonstrates then
the
the power
the power of
the power of the
the power of the human
the power of the human will.
the power of the human will. Without
the power of the human will. Without the
human
human will,
the power of the human will. Without the
human will, without
human will, without the
the power of the human will. Without the
human will, without the observer,
without
without intention,
without intention, the
without intention, the world's
without intention, the world's the
universe
universe stays
without intention, the world's the
universe stays suspended.
If
If you
If you laugh,
If you laugh, you
If you laugh, you get
If you laugh, you get another
If you laugh, you get another smile.
Who's
Who's doing
If you laugh, you get another smile.
Who's doing that?
Nobody
Nobody is
Nobody is doing
Nobody is doing that.
Nobody is doing that. The
Nobody is doing that. The universe
Nobody is doing that. The universe is
doing
doing that.
So
So your
So your laughter
So your laughter then
So your laughter then collapses
So your laughter then collapses the
So your laughter then collapses the wave
function
function from
So your laughter then collapses the wave
function from potential
function from potential to
So your laughter then collapses the wave
function from potential to actual.
Potential
Potential to
Potential to actual
Potential to actual you
Potential to actual you see
Potential to actual you see our
Potential to actual you see our infinite
power
power by
Potential to actual you see our infinite
power by our
power by our own
Potential to actual you see our infinite
power by our own intention.
power by our own intention. Then
Potential to actual you see our infinite
power by our own intention. Then we
power by our own intention. Then we tell
the
the universe
the universe what
the universe what to
the universe what to do
the universe what to do and
the universe what to do and the
the universe what to do and the universe
instantly
instantly obeys.
the universe what to do and the universe
instantly obeys. Wow.
Okay.
Okay. We'll
Okay. We'll move
Okay. We'll move on
Okay. We'll move on to
Okay. We'll move on to the
Okay. We'll move on to the next
Okay. We'll move on to the next exciting
thing.
The
The next
The next exciting
The next exciting thing
The next exciting thing yes
The next exciting thing yes we
The next exciting thing yes we which
The next exciting thing yes we which we
have
have to
The next exciting thing yes we which we
have to reemphasize
have to reemphasize is
The next exciting thing yes we which we
have to reemphasize is that
have to reemphasize is that there
The next exciting thing yes we which we
have to reemphasize is that there are
two
two sides
two sides to
two sides to the
two sides to the brain
two sides to the brain and
two sides to the brain and that
spiritual
spiritual intention
begins
begins to
begins to pull
begins to pull up
begins to pull up an
begins to pull up an energy
begins to pull up an energy not
begins to pull up an energy not present
in
in the
begins to pull up an energy not present
in the non-spiritual
in the non-spiritual person.
begins to pull up an energy not present
in the non-spiritual person. All
in the non-spiritual person. All right.
The
The brain
The brain you
The brain you might
The brain you might say
The brain you might say the
The brain you might say the left
The brain you might say the left side
The brain you might say the left side is
animal
animal and
The brain you might say the left side is
animal and the
animal and the animal
The brain you might say the left side is
animal and the animal is
uh
uh run
uh run run
uh run run by
uh run run by uh
uh run run by uh animal
uh run run by uh animal instincts
uh run run by uh animal instincts and
emotion
emotion plays
uh run run by uh animal instincts and
emotion plays a
emotion plays a very
uh run run by uh animal instincts and
emotion plays a very big
emotion plays a very big part
uh run run by uh animal instincts and
emotion plays a very big part in
emotion plays a very big part in the
deepseated
deepseated and
deepseated and the
deepseated and the emotional
deepseated and the emotional center
deepseated and the emotional center of
the
the brain
deepseated and the emotional center of
the brain is
the brain is the
deepseated and the emotional center of
the brain is the so-called
the brain is the so-called amygdala
which
which calibrates
which calibrates extremely
which calibrates extremely low.
which calibrates extremely low. I
which calibrates extremely low. I forget
what
what it
which calibrates extremely low. I forget
what it calibrates
what it calibrates at
135 or
135 or something.
135 or something. Anyway,
135 or something. Anyway, it's
135 or something. Anyway, it's the
vicious
vicious animal
135 or something. Anyway, it's the
vicious animal and
vicious animal and the
135 or something. Anyway, it's the
vicious animal and the So,
vicious animal and the So, the
135 or something. Anyway, it's the
vicious animal and the So, the amygdala
knows
knows how
knows how to
knows how to handle
knows how to handle enemies.
knows how to handle enemies. It
knows how to handle enemies. It snarls
at
at them
knows how to handle enemies. It snarls
at them and
at them and then
knows how to handle enemies. It snarls
at them and then kills
at them and then kills them.
No
No problem.
What's
What's the
No problem.
What's the problem?
What's the problem? Kill
No problem.
What's the problem? Kill them.
Infidels,
Infidels, no
Infidels, no problem.
Infidels, no problem. Kill
Infidels, no problem. Kill them.
Infidels, no problem. Kill them. Oh,
the
the right
Infidels, no problem. Kill them. Oh,
the right side
the right side of
Infidels, no problem. Kill them. Oh,
the right side of the
the right side of the brain.
Infidels, no problem. Kill them. Oh,
the right side of the brain. And
the right side of the brain. And once
you
you become
you become conscious
you become conscious above
you become conscious above level
you become conscious above level 200
you become conscious above level 200 and
you
you become
you become conscious above level 200 and
you become more
you become more and
you become conscious above level 200 and
you become more and more
you become more and more conscious,
what
what happens
what happens then
what happens then is
what happens then is you
what happens then is you begin
what happens then is you begin putting
out
out the
what happens then is you begin putting
out the condundolini
out the condundolini energy
what happens then is you begin putting
out the condundolini energy field
out the condundolini energy field and
the
the condundolini
the condundolini energy
the condundolini energy field
the condundolini energy field then
activates
activates the
the condundolini energy field then
activates the right
activates the right brain.
the condundolini energy field then
activates the right brain. The
activates the right brain. The right
brain
brain releases
brain releases endorphins,
oxytocin
oxytocin and
brain releases endorphins,
oxytocin and other
oxytocin and other wonderful
neurotransmitters
which
which account
neurotransmitters
which account for
which account for friendliness,
helpfulness,
helpfulness, forgiveness
helpfulness, forgiveness and
helpfulness, forgiveness and all
helpfulness, forgiveness and all the
positive
positive emotions.
helpfulness, forgiveness and all the
positive emotions. So
positive emotions. So in
helpfulness, forgiveness and all the
positive emotions. So in spiritual
positive emotions. So in spiritual work
what
what we're
what we're doing
what we're doing is
what we're doing is by
what we're doing is by spiritual
our
our spiritual
what we're doing is by spiritual
our spiritual will
our spiritual will we
what we're doing is by spiritual
our spiritual will we move
our spiritual will we move from
what we're doing is by spiritual
our spiritual will we move from leftrain
animal
animal fight
animal fight or
animal fight or flight
animal fight or flight animal
animal fight or flight animal dominance
and
decreased
decreased resistance
decreased resistance to
decreased resistance to disease
decreased resistance to disease and
decreased resistance to disease and we
begin
begin to
decreased resistance to disease and we
begin to release
begin to release positive
decreased resistance to disease and we
begin to release positive hormones
within
within the
within the brain.
within the brain. Right
within the brain. Right brain
within the brain. Right brain dominance
brings
brings peaceful
within the brain. Right brain dominance
brings peaceful endorphins,
brings peaceful endorphins, positive
emotions,
emotions, supports
emotions, supports the
emotions, supports the thymus
emotions, supports the thymus gland,
increased
increased immunity,
emotions, supports the thymus gland,
increased immunity, healing.
increased immunity, healing. So
emotions, supports the thymus gland,
increased immunity, healing. So all
healings
healings in
healings in spiritual
healings in spiritual dimension
healings in spiritual dimension consists
of
of forgiveness,
healings in spiritual dimension consists
of forgiveness, love,
of forgiveness, love, devotion
healings in spiritual dimension consists
of forgiveness, love, devotion and
reinforcing
uh
uh the
reinforcing
uh the flow
uh the flow of
reinforcing
uh the flow of the
uh the flow of the spiritual
reinforcing
uh the flow of the spiritual energy.
Now
Now the
Now the the
Now the the end
Now the the end result
Now the the end result will
Now the the end result will depend
Now the the end result will depend on
many
many things.
Now the the end result will depend on
many things. One's
many things. One's personal
Now the the end result will depend on
many things. One's personal one's
collective
collective karma
collective karma for
collective karma for one
collective karma for one thing,
collective karma for one thing, one's
personal
personal karma
collective karma for one thing, one's
personal karma and
personal karma and the
collective karma for one thing, one's
personal karma and the overall
personal karma and the overall life
collective karma for one thing, one's
personal karma and the overall life plan
to
to which
to which we
to which we agreed
to which we agreed when
to which we agreed when we
to which we agreed when we came
to which we agreed when we came into
this
this lifetime.
So
So things
So things may
So things may or
So things may or may
So things may or may not
So things may or may not improve.
Well,
Well, I
So things may or may not improve.
Well, I I
Well, I I had
So things may or may not improve.
Well, I I had a
Well, I I had a very
So things may or may not improve.
Well, I I had a very difficult
Well, I I had a very difficult time
So things may or may not improve.
Well, I I had a very difficult time with
my
my right
my right ankle
my right ankle for
my right ankle for a
my right ankle for a couple
my right ankle for a couple of
my right ankle for a couple of weeks
my right ankle for a couple of weeks and
my
my right
my right ankle for a couple of weeks and
my right foot
and
and I
and I thought,
and I thought, how
and I thought, how am
and I thought, how am I
and I thought, how am I going
and I thought, how am I going to
and I thought, how am I going to walk
around
around the
and I thought, how am I going to walk
around the room
around the room at
and I thought, how am I going to walk
around the room at the
around the room at the lecture?
So,
So, I
So, I prayed
So, I prayed up
So, I prayed up a
So, I prayed up a storm
to
to heal
So, I prayed up a storm
to heal the
to heal the right
So, I prayed up a storm
to heal the right foot
to heal the right foot and
So, I prayed up a storm
to heal the right foot and ankle.
to heal the right foot and ankle. So,
least
least I
least I can
least I can walk
least I can walk around
least I can walk around and
least I can walk around and shake
everybody's
everybody's hand.
least I can walk around and shake
everybody's hand. I
everybody's hand. I don't
least I can walk around and shake
everybody's hand. I don't play
everybody's hand. I don't play tennis
anyway,
anyway, so
anyway, so that
anyway, so that wasn't
anyway, so that wasn't a
anyway, so that wasn't a problem.
anyway, so that wasn't a problem. And
sure
sure enough,
anyway, so that wasn't a problem. And
sure enough, by
sure enough, by this
anyway, so that wasn't a problem. And
sure enough, by this morning,
sure enough, by this morning, I
anyway, so that wasn't a problem. And
sure enough, by this morning, I walked
around
around every
around every place
around every place and
around every place and in
around every place and in the
around every place and in the last
around every place and in the last week,
I've
I've had
around every place and in the last week,
I've had my
I've had my foot
around every place and in the last week,
I've had my foot up
I've had my foot up and
around every place and in the last week,
I've had my foot up and elevated
I've had my foot up and elevated and
taking
taking penicellin
taking penicellin or
taking penicellin or something.
taking penicellin or something. Anyway,
by
by Saturday
taking penicellin or something. Anyway,
by Saturday morning,
by Saturday morning, we
taking penicellin or something. Anyway,
by Saturday morning, we walked
by Saturday morning, we walked around.
So,
So, that
So, that was
So, that was an
So, that was an accord
So, that was an accord with
So, that was an accord with karmic
propensities
propensities and
So, that was an accord with karmic
propensities and permissions
and
and God's
and God's will.
and God's will. Now,
and God's will. Now, if
and God's will. Now, if it
and God's will. Now, if it didn't
and God's will. Now, if it didn't get
better,
better, I
and God's will. Now, if it didn't get
better, I would
better, I would say
and God's will. Now, if it didn't get
better, I would say you're
better, I would say you're not
and God's will. Now, if it didn't get
better, I would say you're not supposed
to
to walk
to walk around
to walk around the
to walk around the room
to walk around the room today.
Obviously,
you're
you're not
you're not supposed
you're not supposed to
you're not supposed to walk
you're not supposed to walk around
you're not supposed to walk around the
room.
All
All right,
All right, next
All right, next one.
Um,
Um, this
All right, next one.
Um, this is
Um, this is very
All right, next one.
Um, this is very important
Um, this is very important to
All right, next one.
Um, this is very important to understand
because
because today
because today we're
because today we're going
because today we're going to
because today we're going to be
because today we're going to be talking
about
about today's
because today we're going to be talking
about today's world.
about today's world. Oh,
because today we're going to be talking
about today's world. Oh, Lord.
about today's world. Oh, Lord. Lord,
somebody's
somebody's got
somebody's got to
somebody's got to do
somebody's got to do it.
I
I can't
somebody's got to do it.
I can't leave
I can't leave it
somebody's got to do it.
I can't leave it all
I can't leave it all up
somebody's got to do it.
I can't leave it all up to
I can't leave it all up to Bill
O'Reilly,
O'Reilly, you
O'Reilly, you know?
He's
He's such
O'Reilly, you know?
He's such a
He's such a moralist.
O'Reilly, you know?
He's such a moralist. I
He's such a moralist. I got
O'Reilly, you know?
He's such a moralist. I got a
He's such a moralist. I got a kick
O'Reilly, you know?
He's such a moralist. I got a kick at
him.
him. Anyway,
what's
what's important
him. Anyway,
what's important for
what's important for us
him. Anyway,
what's important for us to
what's important for us to know
him. Anyway,
what's important for us to know because
it's
it's a
it's a counter
it's a counter to
it's a counter to cultural
it's a counter to cultural Marxism.
See
See relativity
it's a counter to cultural Marxism.
See relativity and
See relativity and c
it's a counter to cultural Marxism.
See relativity and c cultural
See relativity and c cultural Marxism
it's a counter to cultural Marxism.
See relativity and c cultural Marxism is
what
what uh
what uh is
what uh is causing
what uh is causing the
what uh is causing the pressure
what uh is causing the pressure in
today's
today's society.
what uh is causing the pressure in
today's society. So
today's society. So we
what uh is causing the pressure in
today's society. So we look
today's society. So we look at
what uh is causing the pressure in
today's society. So we look at the
today's society. So we look at the level
of
of consciousness
and
and what
of consciousness
and what I'm
and what I'm interesting
of consciousness
and what I'm interesting is
and what I'm interesting is what
of consciousness
and what I'm interesting is what is
and what I'm interesting is what is the
rate
rate of
rate of unemployment?
What's
What's the
rate of unemployment?
What's the rate
What's the rate of
rate of unemployment?
What's the rate of poverty?
What's the rate of poverty? These
rate of unemployment?
What's the rate of poverty? These are
the
the big
the big social
the big social ills
the big social ills about
the big social ills about which
the big social ills about which we'll
get
get to
the big social ills about which we'll
get to when
get to when we
the big social ills about which we'll
get to when we get
get to when we get to
the big social ills about which we'll
get to when we get to the
get to when we get to the isms.
the big social ills about which we'll
get to when we get to the isms. The
what's
what's happy
what's happy and
what's happy and the
what's happy and the rate
what's happy and the rate of
criminality.
Now,
Now, cultural
Now, cultural Marxism
Now, cultural Marxism will
Now, cultural Marxism will try
Now, cultural Marxism will try and
Now, cultural Marxism will try and blame
this
this on
Now, cultural Marxism will try and blame
this on social
this on social conditions
Now, cultural Marxism will try and blame
this on social conditions and
this on social conditions and historic
conditions.
conditions. It's
conditions. It's what
conditions. It's what your
conditions. It's what your grandmother
did
did with
conditions. It's what your grandmother
did with your
did with your grandfather.
And
And you'll
And you'll see
And you'll see that
And you'll see that none
And you'll see that none of
And you'll see that none of these
And you'll see that none of these main
indicators
of
of health
of health and
of health and success
of health and success and
of health and success and survival
of health and success and survival have
anything
anything to
of health and success and survival have
anything to do
anything to do with
of health and success and survival have
anything to do with situations
that
that they're
that they're all
that they're all correlated
that they're all correlated with
that they're all correlated with the
rate
rate level
that they're all correlated with the
rate level of
rate level of consciousness.
that they're all correlated with the
rate level of consciousness. The
rate level of consciousness. The rate
that they're all correlated with the
rate level of consciousness. The rate of
unemployment
unemployment at
unemployment at the
unemployment at the top
unemployment at the top is
unemployment at the top is zero.
unemployment at the top is zero. The
rate
rate of
unemployment at the top is zero. The
rate of poverty
rate of poverty is
unemployment at the top is zero. The
rate of poverty is zero.
rate of poverty is zero. Life
unemployment at the top is zero. The
rate of poverty is zero. Life is
rate of poverty is zero. Life is okay.
98%
98% say
98% say so.
98% say so. And
98% say so. And one
98% say so. And one 2%
98% say so. And one 2% are
98% say so. And one 2% are not
satisfied.
satisfied. They
98% say so. And one 2% are not
satisfied. They haven't
satisfied. They haven't reached
enlightenment
enlightenment yet.
The
The rate
enlightenment yet.
The rate of
The rate of criminality
enlightenment yet.
The rate of criminality in
The rate of criminality in higher
enlightenment yet.
The rate of criminality in higher levels
of
of consciousness
of consciousness is
of consciousness is practically
of consciousness is practically zero.
Practically
Practically zero.
of consciousness is practically zero.
Practically zero. In
Practically zero. In fact,
of consciousness is practically zero.
Practically zero. In fact, the
Practically zero. In fact, the main
of consciousness is practically zero.
Practically zero. In fact, the main ones
really
really are
really are fallen
really are fallen gurus
really are fallen gurus who
really are fallen gurus who fall
really are fallen gurus who fall in
seduct
seduct seduction
really are fallen gurus who fall in
seduct seduction of
seduct seduction of one
really are fallen gurus who fall in
seduct seduction of one kind
seduct seduction of one kind or
really are fallen gurus who fall in
seduct seduction of one kind or another.
All right.
All right. So
All right. So the
All right. So the level
All right. So the level of
All right. So the level of consciousness
then
then is
All right. So the level of consciousness
then is you
then is you see
All right. So the level of consciousness
then is you see the
then is you see the rate
All right. So the level of consciousness
then is you see the rate of
then is you see the rate of unemployment
as
as it
as it the
as it the consciousness
as it the consciousness level
as it the consciousness level goes
as it the consciousness level goes down
not
not world
not world conditions
not world conditions not
not world conditions not economic
conditions
conditions not
not world conditions not economic
conditions not politics
the
the level
the level of
the level of consciousness
the level of consciousness as
the level of consciousness as it
the level of consciousness as it goes
down
down the
the level of consciousness as it goes
down the rate
down the rate of
the level of consciousness as it goes
down the rate of unemployment
down the rate of unemployment eventually
reaches
reaches almost
reaches almost 100%.
reaches almost 100%. The
reaches almost 100%. The rate
reaches almost 100%. The rate of
reaches almost 100%. The rate of poverty
reaches
very
very high.
very high. Happiness,
very high. Happiness, the
very high. Happiness, the rate
very high. Happiness, the rate of
happiness
happiness is
very high. Happiness, the rate of
happiness is zero
happiness is zero to
very high. Happiness, the rate of
happiness is zero to 1%.
happiness is zero to 1%. And
very high. Happiness, the rate of
happiness is zero to 1%. And the
happiness is zero to 1%. And the rate
very high. Happiness, the rate of
happiness is zero to 1%. And the rate of
criminality
criminality is
criminality is an
criminality is an amazing
criminality is an amazing 98%.
Every
Every day,
criminality is an amazing 98%.
Every day, that's
Every day, that's everyday's
criminality is an amazing 98%.
Every day, that's everyday's news,
Every day, that's everyday's news, isn't
it?
it? Couple
it? Couple of
it? Couple of college
it? Couple of college kids
it? Couple of college kids walking
it? Couple of college kids walking down
the
the street
it? Couple of college kids walking down
the street in
the street in their
it? Couple of college kids walking down
the street in their car
the street in their car drives
it? Couple of college kids walking down
the street in their car drives up,
shoots
shoots them
shoots them all
shoots them all dead.
shoots them all dead. No
shoots them all dead. No reason.
That's
That's these
shoots them all dead. No reason.
That's these jokers
That's these jokers here.
Let's
Let's go
Let's go kill
Let's go kill a
Let's go kill a couple
Let's go kill a couple of
Let's go kill a couple of college
students.
students. Okay.
Let's go kill a couple of college
students. Okay. Hey.
students. Okay. Hey. Wow.
What
What must
What must they
What must they talk
What must they talk about?
What must they talk about? Let's
What must they talk about? Let's do
What must they talk about? Let's do a
little
little more
What must they talk about? Let's do a
little more something,
little more something, whatever
What must they talk about? Let's do a
little more something, whatever they're
doing.
doing. Hey,
doing. Hey, let's
doing. Hey, let's go
doing. Hey, let's go and
doing. Hey, let's go and kill
doing. Hey, let's go and kill a
doing. Hey, let's go and kill a couple
of
of women
doing. Hey, let's go and kill a couple
of women walking
of women walking down
doing. Hey, let's go and kill a couple
of women walking down the
of women walking down the sidewalk.
And
And they
And they find
And they find that
And they find that exciting
And they find that exciting and
And they find that exciting and pleasing
and
and attractive.
And they find that exciting and pleasing
and attractive. The
and attractive. The car
And they find that exciting and pleasing
and attractive. The car stops,
bodies
bodies fall
bodies fall over,
bodies fall over, and
bodies fall over, and they
bodies fall over, and they drive
bodies fall over, and they drive off.
So
So in
bodies fall over, and they drive off.
So in the
So in the old
bodies fall over, and they drive off.
So in the old days
So in the old days we
bodies fall over, and they drive off.
So in the old days we used
So in the old days we used to
bodies fall over, and they drive off.
So in the old days we used to keep
So in the old days we used to keep them
in
in mental
in mental hospitals.
I
I was
in mental hospitals.
I was in
I was in psychiatry
in mental hospitals.
I was in psychiatry many
I was in psychiatry many years
in mental hospitals.
I was in psychiatry many years saw
thousands
thousands of
thousands of patients
thousands of patients in
thousands of patients in state
thousands of patients in state hospitals
and
and all
thousands of patients in state hospitals
and all the
and all the thousands
thousands of patients in state hospitals
and all the thousands I
and all the thousands I saw
thousands of patients in state hospitals
and all the thousands I saw over
and all the thousands I saw over the
decades
decades I
decades I never
decades I never saw
decades I never saw one
decades I never saw one patient
decades I never saw one patient in
decades I never saw one patient in a
state
state hospital
decades I never saw one patient in a
state hospital who
state hospital who didn't
decades I never saw one patient in a
state hospital who didn't belong
state hospital who didn't belong there.
Not
Not one.
Not one. And
Not one. And I
Not one. And I saw
Not one. And I saw thousands.
Not
Not one.
Not one. And I saw thousands.
Not one. one
Not one. one flew
Not one. And I saw thousands.
Not one. one flew over
Not one. one flew over the
Not one. And I saw thousands.
Not one. one flew over the cuckoo's
Not one. one flew over the cuckoo's list
and
and all
and all that
and all that stuff
and all that stuff is
and all that stuff is all
and all that stuff is all fiction
fiction.
fiction. But
and all that stuff is all fiction
fiction. But the
fiction. But the world
and all that stuff is all fiction
fiction. But the world took
fiction. But the world took it
and all that stuff is all fiction
fiction. But the world took it as
fiction. But the world took it as truth.
So
So they
So they went
So they went in
So they went in and
So they went in and they're
So they went in and they're going
So they went in and they're going to
save
save these
So they went in and they're going to
save these poor
save these poor middle
So they went in and they're going to
save these poor middle patients
save these poor middle patients who
So they went in and they're going to
save these poor middle patients who are
getting
getting where
getting where they
getting where they are.
getting where they are. Extra
getting where they are. Extra medical
care,
care, social
getting where they are. Extra medical
care, social work
care, social work care,
getting where they are. Extra medical
care, social work care, food,
employment,
doctors
doctors of
employment,
doctors of all
doctors of all ilks.
employment,
doctors of all ilks. And
doctors of all ilks. And we'll
employment,
doctors of all ilks. And we'll close
doctors of all ilks. And we'll close the
hospital
hospital and
hospital and turn
hospital and turn them
hospital and turn them loose
hospital and turn them loose on
hospital and turn them loose on the
streets
streets where
hospital and turn them loose on the
streets where they
streets where they got
hospital and turn them loose on the
streets where they got to
streets where they got to step
hospital and turn them loose on the
streets where they got to step over
them.
them. They're
them. They're drunk
drunk
drunk and
them. They're drunk
drunk and busy
drunk and busy committing
them. They're drunk
drunk and busy committing crimes.
So
So all right,
So all right, we
So all right, we were
So all right, we were interested
So all right, we were interested in
their
their safety.
So all right, we were interested in
their safety. The
their safety. The criteria
So all right, we were interested in
their safety. The criteria was
their safety. The criteria was that
So all right, we were interested in
their safety. The criteria was that you
were
were um
were um able
were um able to
were um able to take
were um able to take care
were um able to take care of
were um able to take care of yourself
self
self and
were um able to take care of yourself
self and not
self and not of
were um able to take care of yourself
self and not of no
self and not of no harm
were um able to take care of yourself
self and not of no harm to
self and not of no harm to the
were um able to take care of yourself
self and not of no harm to the community
and
and that's
and that's what
and that's what kept
and that's what kept the
and that's what kept the people
and that's what kept the people in
and that's what kept the people in the
state
state hospital
and that's what kept the people in the
state hospital was
state hospital was they
and that's what kept the people in the
state hospital was they were
state hospital was they were un unable
to
to care
to care for
to care for themsel
to care for themsel unable
to care for themsel unable to
to care for themsel unable to look
to care for themsel unable to look after
their
their own
to care for themsel unable to look after
their own needs
their own needs and
to care for themsel unable to look after
their own needs and dangerous
their own needs and dangerous to
to care for themsel unable to look after
their own needs and dangerous to others.
Okay,
Okay, so
Okay, so we'll
Okay, so we'll move
Okay, so we'll move on.
Um,
correlations
correlations of
correlations of level
correlations of level of
correlations of level of consciousness
and
and rate
correlations of level of consciousness
and rate of
and rate of happiness.
correlations of level of consciousness
and rate of happiness. I
and rate of happiness. I thought
correlations of level of consciousness
and rate of happiness. I thought we
and rate of happiness. I thought we just
did
did that
did that one.
Well,
Well, anyway,
did that one.
Well, anyway, it's
Well, anyway, it's a
did that one.
Well, anyway, it's a redoing
Well, anyway, it's a redoing of
did that one.
Well, anyway, it's a redoing of it.
Well, anyway, it's a redoing of it. It
just
just shows
just shows that
just shows that that
just shows that that near
just shows that that near the
just shows that that near the the
just shows that that near the the cause
of
of unhappiness
just shows that that near the the cause
of unhappiness and
of unhappiness and all
just shows that that near the the cause
of unhappiness and all the
of unhappiness and all the social
problems
problems that
problems that go
problems that go with
problems that go with it
problems that go with it are
problems that go with it are in
intrinsic
intrinsic not
problems that go with it are in
intrinsic not extr
intrinsic not extr exttrinsic.
So
So the
So the downside
So the downside of
So the downside of politics
So the downside of politics is
So the downside of politics is it
presumes
presumes that
So the downside of politics is it
presumes that the
presumes that the co
So the downside of politics is it
presumes that the co causality
due
due to
due to various
due to various social
uh
uh theories
due to various social
uh theories is
uh theories is external
due to various social
uh theories is external whereas
uh theories is external whereas as
due to various social
uh theories is external whereas as you
can
can see
can see the
can see the reality
can see the reality is
can see the reality is internal
internal.
Mhm.
All
All right.
Mhm.
All right. So
All right. So we'll
Mhm.
All right. So we'll move
All right. So we'll move up.
Oh,
Oh, who's
Oh, who's that?
Oh, who's that? Oh,
Oh, who's that? Oh, that's
Oh, who's that? Oh, that's my
Oh, who's that? Oh, that's my old
friend.
Boo.
So
So what
So what sound
So what sound like
So what sound like very
So what sound like very nice
So what sound like very nice social
theories
very
very nice
very nice peaceful
very nice peaceful wonderful
let's
let's dance
very nice peaceful wonderful
let's dance around
let's dance around the
very nice peaceful wonderful
let's dance around the mapole
let's dance around the mapole and
very nice peaceful wonderful
let's dance around the mapole and heal
them
them all
them all and
them all and buy
them all and buy them
them all and buy them no
them all and buy them no and
them all and buy them no and buy
them all and buy them no and buy them
toilets.
toilets. Buying
them all and buy them no and buy them
toilets. Buying toilets
toilets. Buying toilets for
them all and buy them no and buy them
toilets. Buying toilets for India
toilets. Buying toilets for India is
them all and buy them no and buy them
toilets. Buying toilets for India is the
latest
latest kick.
latest kick. You
latest kick. You know
they
they don't
latest kick. You know
they don't want
they don't want toilets
latest kick. You know
they don't want toilets in
they don't want toilets in India.
Everybody
Everybody goes
Everybody goes behind
Everybody goes behind a
Everybody goes behind a bush
Everybody goes behind a bush or
Everybody goes behind a bush or in
Everybody goes behind a bush or in a
shrub
shrub or
Everybody goes behind a bush or in a
shrub or down
shrub or down the
Everybody goes behind a bush or in a
shrub or down the street.
shrub or down the street. So
Everybody goes behind a bush or in a
shrub or down the street. So anyway,
we're
we're going
we're going to
we're going to buy
we're going to buy toilets.
we're going to buy toilets. All right.
So,
So, but
we're going to buy toilets. All right.
So, but all
So, but all those
we're going to buy toilets. All right.
So, but all those things
So, but all those things that
we're going to buy toilets. All right.
So, but all those things that sound
So, but all those things that sound so
wonderful.
wonderful. Buy
wonderful. Buy toilets
wonderful. Buy toilets for
wonderful. Buy toilets for India.
wonderful. Buy toilets for India. Save
the
the Himalayas.
wonderful. Buy toilets for India. Save
the Himalayas. Uh,
the Himalayas. Uh, they
wonderful. Buy toilets for India. Save
the Himalayas. Uh, they all
the Himalayas. Uh, they all sound
wonderful. Buy toilets for India. Save
the Himalayas. Uh, they all sound so
idealistic
idealistic and
idealistic and woo
idealistic and woo woo
idealistic and woo woo woo.
idealistic and woo woo woo. Oh,
idealistic and woo woo woo. Oh, let's
save
save the
idealistic and woo woo woo. Oh, let's
save the wo
save the wo wo
idealistic and woo woo woo. Oh, let's
save the wo wo wo.
save the wo wo wo. Let's
idealistic and woo woo woo. Oh, let's
save the wo wo wo. Let's save
save the wo wo wo. Let's save all
idealistic and woo woo woo. Oh, let's
save the wo wo wo. Let's save all the
woo
woo woo
woo woo woo
woo woo woo woo.
woo woo woo woo. Let's
woo woo woo woo. Let's save
woo woo woo woo. Let's save the
woo woo woo woo. Let's save the woo.
Send
Send your
woo woo woo woo. Let's save the woo.
Send your money
Send your money to
woo woo woo woo. Let's save the woo.
Send your money to the
Send your money to the following
address.
We
We find
address.
We find that
We find that they
address.
We find that they all
We find that they all make
address.
We find that they all make your
We find that they all make your arm
address.
We find that they all make your arm go
weak.
Every
Every one
weak.
Every one of
Every one of these
weak.
Every one of these wonderful
Every one of these wonderful save
weak.
Every one of these wonderful save the
hippopotamuses
hippopotamuses or
hippopotamuses or whatever.
All
All those
hippopotamuses or whatever.
All those ads
All those ads make
hippopotamuses or whatever.
All those ads make you
All those ads make you go
hippopotamuses or whatever.
All those ads make you go weak,
All those ads make you go weak, which
means
means you're
means you're being
means you're being fleeced.
The
The monies
means you're being fleeced.
The monies that
The monies that you
means you're being fleeced.
The monies that you send
The monies that you send in
means you're being fleeced.
The monies that you send in go
The monies that you send in go to
means you're being fleeced.
The monies that you send in go to p
The monies that you send in go to p go
in
in the
in the pocket
in the pocket of
in the pocket of the
in the pocket of the organizers
in the pocket of the organizers of
in the pocket of the organizers of all
that.
that. Okay,
in the pocket of the organizers of all
that. Okay, we'll
that. Okay, we'll move
in the pocket of the organizers of all
that. Okay, we'll move on.
Uh
I
I don't
Uh
I don't know
I don't know what
Uh
I don't know what this
I don't know what this is.
The
The virtues.
I
I didn't
The virtues.
I didn't know
I didn't know the
The virtues.
I didn't know the virtues
I didn't know the virtues were
The virtues.
I didn't know the virtues were in
I didn't know the virtues were in this.
>> What?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> What?
>> Oh, okay. All right.
>> Oh, okay. All right. Now,
>> What?
>> Oh, okay. All right. Now, we'll
>> Oh, okay. All right. Now, we'll get
>> What?
>> Oh, okay. All right. Now, we'll get to
today's
today's lecture.
>> The
>> The reason
today's lecture.
>> The reason we
>> The reason we have
today's lecture.
>> The reason we have it
>> The reason we have it up
today's lecture.
>> The reason we have it up there
>> The reason we have it up there is
today's lecture.
>> The reason we have it up there is I
forgot
forgot what
forgot what it
forgot what it was.
forgot what it was. When
forgot what it was. When I
forgot what it was. When I look
forgot what it was. When I look up
there,
there, I
forgot what it was. When I look up
there, I remember
there, I remember what
forgot what it was. When I look up
there, I remember what it
there, I remember what it was.
forgot what it was. When I look up
there, I remember what it was. Now,
the
the guy
the guy said,
the guy said, "I've
the guy said, "I've got
the guy said, "I've got trouble
the guy said, "I've got trouble with
the guy said, "I've got trouble with my
memory."
memory." He
the guy said, "I've got trouble with my
memory." He says,
memory." He says, "How
the guy said, "I've got trouble with my
memory." He says, "How long
memory." He says, "How long has
the guy said, "I've got trouble with my
memory." He says, "How long has that
been?"
been?" And
been?" And he
been?" And he says,
been?" And he says, "How
been?" And he says, "How long
been?" And he says, "How long has
been?" And he says, "How long has what
been?
I
I don't
I don't know.
I don't know. I
I don't know. I forget
I don't know. I forget what
I don't know. I forget what it
I don't know. I forget what it was.
I don't know. I forget what it was. I'm
supposed
supposed to
I don't know. I forget what it was. I'm
supposed to remember."
supposed to remember." That's
I don't know. I forget what it was. I'm
supposed to remember." That's the
problem.
problem. The
problem. The only
problem. The only problem
problem. The only problem I
problem. The only problem I got.
So
today's
today's lecture
today's lecture is
today's lecture is faith,
today's lecture is faith, trust,
today's lecture is faith, trust, and
credibility.
credibility. Is
today's lecture is faith, trust, and
credibility. Is that
credibility. Is that the
today's lecture is faith, trust, and
credibility. Is that the name
credibility. Is that the name of
today's lecture is faith, trust, and
credibility. Is that the name of it?
Yes.
All
All right.
Yes.
All right. So,
All right. So, we're
Yes.
All right. So, we're looking
All right. So, we're looking at
credibility
credibility and
credibility and of
credibility and of course
we
we get
credibility and of course
we get a
we get a constant
credibility and of course
we get a constant bombardment
we get a constant bombardment from
credibility and of course
we get a constant bombardment from the
media,
media, the
media, the television,
media, the television, the
media, the television, the blogger
blogger
blogger uh
media, the television, the blogger
blogger uh channels
and
and all
and all that
and all that goes
and all that goes with
and all that goes with that.
and all that goes with that. type
and all that goes with that. type press
type
type typing
and all that goes with that. type press
type typing press
type typing press typing
and all that goes with that. type press
type typing press typing on
type typing press typing on your
telephone
telephone and
telephone and you
telephone and you can
telephone and you can communicate
anywhere
anywhere in
telephone and you can communicate
anywhere in the
anywhere in the world
telephone and you can communicate
anywhere in the world and
anywhere in the world and put
telephone and you can communicate
anywhere in the world and put anything
you
you want
you want on
you want on there
you want on there which
you want on there which then
you want on there which then goes
worldwide.
Now
Now that
Now that you
Now that you see
Now that you see what
Now that you see what percentage
Now that you see what percentage of
humanity
humanity calibrates
Now that you see what percentage of
humanity calibrates below
humanity calibrates below 200
Now that you see what percentage of
humanity calibrates below 200 and
humanity calibrates below 200 and they
all
all have
all have one
all have one of
all have one of these
all have one of these internet
all have one of these internet typer
message
message machines,
all have one of these internet typer
message machines, you
message machines, you can
all have one of these internet typer
message machines, you can see
message machines, you can see what's
likely
likely going
likely going to
likely going to occur.
It's
It's like
likely going to occur.
It's like giving
It's like giving all
likely going to occur.
It's like giving all the
It's like giving all the dogs
likely going to occur.
It's like giving all the dogs in
It's like giving all the dogs in the
neighborhood
neighborhood an
neighborhood an automobile.
I
I love
neighborhood an automobile.
I love them
I love them and
neighborhood an automobile.
I love them and I
I love them and I forget
neighborhood an automobile.
I love them and I forget them.
I love them and I forget them. Forgive
them.
them. But
them. But the
them. But the streets
them. But the streets are
them. But the streets are dangerous.
them. But the streets are dangerous. So
you'll
you'll see
them. But the streets are dangerous. So
you'll see the
you'll see the streets
them. But the streets are dangerous. So
you'll see the streets of
you'll see the streets of public
information
uh
uh are
information
uh are dangerous
uh are dangerous and
information
uh are dangerous and it's
uh are dangerous and it's really
information
uh are dangerous and it's really a
carnival.
carnival. As
carnival. As you
carnival. As you watch
carnival. As you watch television
carnival. As you watch television and
you
you listen
carnival. As you watch television and
you listen to
you listen to all
carnival. As you watch television and
you listen to all the
you listen to all the what
carnival. As you watch television and
you listen to all the what goes
you listen to all the what goes on,
especially
especially in
especially in a
especially in a year
especially in a year where
especially in a year where there's
especially in a year where there's an
election,
election, those
especially in a year where there's an
election, those years
election, those years are
especially in a year where there's an
election, those years are always
election, those years are always very
wonderful.
We
We have
wonderful.
We have an
We have an election
wonderful.
We have an election this
We have an election this year,
wonderful.
We have an election this year, don't
We have an election this year, don't we?
2008.
2008. Yeah.
2008. Yeah. Two
2008. Yeah. Two of
2008. Yeah. Two of 2004.
The
The hysteria,
2008. Yeah. Two of 2004.
The hysteria, the
The hysteria, the pitch
2008. Yeah. Two of 2004.
The hysteria, the pitch of
The hysteria, the pitch of the
2008. Yeah. Two of 2004.
The hysteria, the pitch of the hysteria
got
got higher
got higher and
got higher and higher
got higher and higher and
got higher and higher and higher
got higher and higher and higher and
got higher and higher and higher and I
was
was afraid
got higher and higher and higher and I
was afraid to
was afraid to say
got higher and higher and higher and I
was afraid to say anything,
was afraid to say anything, you
got higher and higher and higher and I
was afraid to say anything, you don't
think.
think. So
think. So anyway,
think. So anyway, now
think. So anyway, now we
think. So anyway, now we what
think. So anyway, now we what we
think. So anyway, now we what we see
think. So anyway, now we what we see is
uh
uh the
think. So anyway, now we what we see is
uh the war
uh the war of
think. So anyway, now we what we see is
uh the war of the
uh the war of the isms.
think. So anyway, now we what we see is
uh the war of the isms. And
uh the war of the isms. And so
think. So anyway, now we what we see is
uh the war of the isms. And so here
here's
here's today's
here's today's uh
here's today's uh total
here's today's uh total madness
uh
today's
today's madness.
today's madness. So
today's madness. So the
today's madness. So the war
today's madness. So the war now
today's madness. So the war now in
today's madness. So the war now in this
we're
we're having
today's madness. So the war now in this
we're having peace
we're having peace but
today's madness. So the war now in this
we're having peace but but
we're having peace but but the
today's madness. So the war now in this
we're having peace but but the media
we're having peace but but the media is
concerned
concerned with
concerned with uh
concerned with uh intense
concerned with uh intense uh
concerned with uh intense uh uh
concentration
concentration on
concerned with uh intense uh uh
concentration on class
and
and uh
and uh race
and uh race and
and uh race and gender
and uh race and gender and
and uh race and gender and age.
You
You know
and uh race and gender and age.
You know you
You know you can't
and uh race and gender and age.
You know you can't uh
You know you can't uh beat
and uh race and gender and age.
You know you can't uh beat up
You know you can't uh beat up people
because
because of
because of their
because of their class
because of their class anymore.
But
But you
because of their class anymore.
But you can
But you can play
because of their class anymore.
But you can play the
But you can play the race
because of their class anymore.
But you can play the race card
But you can play the race card uh
because of their class anymore.
But you can play the race card uh gender
card
and
and uh
card
and uh age.
and uh age. Now,
card
and uh age. Now, the
and uh age. Now, the age
card
and uh age. Now, the age cards
and uh age. Now, the age cards are
right.
right. If
right. If somebody's
right. If somebody's 72,
right. If somebody's 72, you
right. If somebody's 72, you can
right. If somebody's 72, you can beat
him
him up
right. If somebody's 72, you can beat
him up because
him up because he's
right. If somebody's 72, you can beat
him up because he's too
him up because he's too old
right. If somebody's 72, you can beat
him up because he's too old to
him up because he's too old to be
president.
What
What you
president.
What you need
What you need is
president.
What you need is a
What you need is a black
president.
What you need is a black woman
What you need is a black woman who's
elderly.
An
An elderly
elderly.
An elderly black
An elderly black woman.
Nobody
Nobody will
Nobody will dare
Nobody will dare say
Nobody will dare say anything.
And
And so
Nobody will dare say anything.
And so now
And so now it
Nobody will dare say anything.
And so now it used
And so now it used to
Nobody will dare say anything.
And so now it used to be
And so now it used to be you
Nobody will dare say anything.
And so now it used to be you had
And so now it used to be you had to
Nobody will dare say anything.
And so now it used to be you had to be
high
high class,
high class, now
high class, now you
high class, now you got
high class, now you got to
high class, now you got to be
high class, now you got to be low
high class, now you got to be low class
because
because low
high class, now you got to be low class
because low class
because low class is
high class, now you got to be low class
because low class is more
because low class is more class
high class, now you got to be low class
because low class is more class than
high
high class.
And
And if
high class.
And if you're
And if you're in
high class.
And if you're in the
And if you're in the minority,
high class.
And if you're in the minority, you
And if you're in the minority, you then
have
have the
have the majority
have the majority vote.
Oh,
Oh, so
have the majority vote.
Oh, so we
Oh, so we have
have the majority vote.
Oh, so we have this
Oh, so we have this circus,
have the majority vote.
Oh, so we have this circus, the
Oh, so we have this circus, the politics
party
party circus,
which
which is
party circus,
which is u
which is u if
party circus,
which is u if you
which is u if you look
party circus,
which is u if you look at
which is u if you look at it
party circus,
which is u if you look at it from
which is u if you look at it from a
somewhat
somewhat detached
somewhat detached viewpoint
somewhat detached viewpoint is
entertaining.
entertaining. And
somewhat detached viewpoint is
entertaining. And you
entertaining. And you hear
somewhat detached viewpoint is
entertaining. And you hear the
entertaining. And you hear the quasi
arguments
arguments and
arguments and the
arguments and the liberties
arguments and the liberties they
arguments and the liberties they take
with
with logic
arguments and the liberties they take
with logic and
with logic and truth
arguments and the liberties they take
with logic and truth and
with logic and truth and facts
arguments and the liberties they take
with logic and truth and facts uh
with logic and truth and facts uh to
arguments and the liberties they take
with logic and truth and facts uh to to
serve
serve them
serve them around.
serve them around. You
serve them around. You see
serve them around. You see the
serve them around. You see the impact
the
the big
serve them around. You see the impact
the big sales
the big sales salesmanship
of
of collectivism
of collectivism and
of collectivism and socialism
and
and the
of collectivism and socialism
and the the
and the the pre
of collectivism and socialism
and the the pre the
and the the pre the pressure
of collectivism and socialism
and the the pre the pressure is
and the the pre the pressure is to
uh
uh bring
uh bring about
uh bring about a
uh bring about a change
uh bring about a change of
uh bring about a change of our
uh bring about a change of our society
to
to be
uh bring about a change of our society
to be more
to be more and
uh bring about a change of our society
to be more and more
to be more and more like
uh bring about a change of our society
to be more and more like Europe
socialist
socialist and
socialist and atheist.
socialist and atheist. socialist
socialist and atheist. socialist and
atheist
atheist and
socialist and atheist. socialist and
atheist and 50%
atheist and 50% of
socialist and atheist. socialist and
atheist and 50% of your
atheist and 50% of your income
socialist and atheist. socialist and
atheist and 50% of your income goes
atheist and 50% of your income goes to
taxes.
taxes. You
taxes. You get
taxes. You get about
taxes. You get about 50%
taxes. You get about 50% of
taxes. You get about 50% of your
taxes. You get about 50% of your check.
But
But in
taxes. You get about 50% of your check.
But in return,
But in return, so
taxes. You get about 50% of your check.
But in return, so the
But in return, so the the
taxes. You get about 50% of your check.
But in return, so the the from
But in return, so the the from a
taxes. You get about 50% of your check.
But in return, so the the from a you
might
might say
might say paternalistic
um
meritocracy,
meritocracy, which
meritocracy, which America
meritocracy, which America was,
meritocracy, which America was, the
meritocracy, which America was, the idea
is
is to
meritocracy, which America was, the idea
is to move
is to move to
meritocracy, which America was, the idea
is to move to a
is to move to a more
meritocracy, which America was, the idea
is to move to a more maternalistic
socialism.
You
You see
socialism.
You see the
You see the the
socialism.
You see the the the
You see the the the male,
socialism.
You see the the the male, the
traditional
traditional male,
traditional male, you
traditional male, you get
traditional male, you get what
traditional male, you get what you
traditional male, you get what you get
in
in the
traditional male, you get what you get
in the world
in the world by
traditional male, you get what you get
in the world by your
in the world by your own
traditional male, you get what you get
in the world by your own effort.
in the world by your own effort. Period.
Period.
Period. What
Period. What you
Period. What you get
Period. What you get is
Period. What you get is what
Period. What you get is what you
Period. What you get is what you worked
for
for and
Period. What you get is what you worked
for and earned
for and earned through
Period. What you get is what you worked
for and earned through your
for and earned through your own
Period. What you get is what you worked
for and earned through your own sweat
and
and blood.
and blood. That's
and blood. That's the
and blood. That's the paternalistic.
and blood. That's the paternalistic. The
maternal
maternal maternalistic
is
is more
is more politically
is more politically expressed.
is more politically expressed. The
mother
mother does
is more politically expressed. The
mother does not
mother does not differentiate.
is more politically expressed. The
mother does not differentiate. All
mother does not differentiate. All of
her
her children
her children she
her children she treats
her children she treats equally.
her children she treats equally. All
her children she treats equally. All of
them.
them. All
her children she treats equally. All of
them. All of
them. All of them
her children she treats equally. All of
them. All of them are
them. All of them are deserving
her children she treats equally. All of
them. All of them are deserving because
they
they are.
they are. So
they are. So that
they are. So that is
where
where the
they are. So that is
where the wealth
where the wealth of
they are. So that is
where the wealth of the
where the wealth of the nation
they are. So that is
where the wealth of the nation is
distributed
uh
uh more
distributed
uh more equally
uh more equally not
distributed
uh more equally not just
uh more equally not just by
distributed
uh more equally not just by those
uh more equally not just by those who
have
have earned
have earned it
have earned it but
have earned it but because
have earned it but because of
have earned it but because of the
have earned it but because of the nature
of
of our
have earned it but because of the nature
of our society.
of our society. So
have earned it but because of the nature
of our society. So actually
of our society. So actually our
have earned it but because of the nature
of our society. So actually our country
is
is very
is very well
is very well balanced
is very well balanced between
is very well balanced between the
is very well balanced between the two.
The
The paternalistic
is very well balanced between the two.
The paternalistic you
The paternalistic you get
is very well balanced between the two.
The paternalistic you get where
The paternalistic you get where you
is very well balanced between the two.
The paternalistic you get where you get
ahead
ahead in
ahead in the
ahead in the world
ahead in the world by
ahead in the world by hard
ahead in the world by hard work
ahead in the world by hard work and
self-sacrifice.
self-sacrifice. No,
ahead in the world by hard work and
self-sacrifice. No, and
self-sacrifice. No, and socialistic
because
because there
because there is
because there is also
because there is also a
because there is also a safety
because there is also a safety blanket
and
and you
because there is also a safety blanket
and you can
and you can only
because there is also a safety blanket
and you can only go
and you can only go down
because there is also a safety blanket
and you can only go down so
and you can only go down so far.
because there is also a safety blanket
and you can only go down so far. And
then
then the
then the matriarchal
then the matriarchal principle.
then the matriarchal principle. So
then the matriarchal principle. So these
are
are the
then the matriarchal principle. So these
are the great
are the great archetypes,
then the matriarchal principle. So these
are the great archetypes, Young's
archetypes,
archetypes, the
archetypes, the masculine
archetypes, the masculine and
archetypes, the masculine and the
feminine
feminine which
archetypes, the masculine and the
feminine which are
feminine which are expressed
archetypes, the masculine and the
feminine which are expressed socially
feminine which are expressed socially in
our
our political
our political system.
our political system. So
our political system. So this
our political system. So this is
our political system. So this is totally
maternalistic.
You
You don't
You don't have
You don't have to
You don't have to do
You don't have to do anything
You don't have to do anything uh
You don't have to do anything uh to
You don't have to do anything uh to get
everything.
uh
uh and
uh and our
uh and our society
uh and our society I
uh and our society I think
uh and our society I think is
uh and our society I think is very
wellbalanced
wellbalanced where
uh and our society I think is very
wellbalanced where through
wellbalanced where through your
uh and our society I think is very
wellbalanced where through your own
effort
effort and
effort and self-sacrifice
you
you move
effort and self-sacrifice
you move ahead
you move ahead and
effort and self-sacrifice
you move ahead and also
there's
there's a
there's a sufficient
there's a sufficient output
there's a sufficient output from
there's a sufficient output from that
kind
kind of
there's a sufficient output from that
kind of a
kind of a structure
there's a sufficient output from that
kind of a structure that
kind of a structure that there's
there's a sufficient output from that
kind of a structure that there's enough
capital
capital uh
capital uh provided
capital uh provided to
capital uh provided to the
capital uh provided to the economy
capital uh provided to the economy and
to
to our
capital uh provided to the economy and
to our country
to our country to
capital uh provided to the economy and
to our country to take
to our country to take care
capital uh provided to the economy and
to our country to take care of
everybody.
everybody. So
everybody. So it's
everybody. So it's sort
everybody. So it's sort of
everybody. So it's sort of hard
everybody. So it's sort of hard to
everybody. So it's sort of hard to hard
to
to hard
everybody. So it's sort of hard to hard
to hard to
to hard to starve
everybody. So it's sort of hard to hard
to hard to starve to
to hard to starve to death
everybody. So it's sort of hard to hard
to hard to starve to death in
to hard to starve to death in our
everybody. So it's sort of hard to hard
to hard to starve to death in our world.
You
You have
You have to
You have to really
You have to really work
You have to really work at
You have to really work at it
You have to really work at it because
somebody
somebody will
You have to really work at it because
somebody will pick
somebody will pick up
You have to really work at it because
somebody will pick up pick
somebody will pick up pick up
You have to really work at it because
somebody will pick up pick up for
somebody will pick up pick up for you
and
and lead
and lead you
and lead you to
and lead you to the
and lead you to the nearest
and lead you to the nearest welfare
assistance.
assistance. So
and lead you to the nearest welfare
assistance. So in
assistance. So in my
and lead you to the nearest welfare
assistance. So in my opinion,
I
I don't
I don't express
I don't express opinions
I don't express opinions much,
I don't express opinions much, but
I don't express opinions much, but when
I
I do,
I don't express opinions much, but when
I do, I
I do, I say
I don't express opinions much, but when
I do, I say in
I do, I say in my
I don't express opinions much, but when
I do, I say in my opinion,
I do, I say in my opinion, my
I don't express opinions much, but when
I do, I say in my opinion, my opinion,
our
our country
our country is
our country is a
our country is a is
our country is a is a
our country is a is a wonderful
our country is a is a wonderful balance
of
of the
our country is a is a wonderful balance
of the maternal
of the maternal and
our country is a is a wonderful balance
of the maternal and the
of the maternal and the paternal,
our country is a is a wonderful balance
of the maternal and the paternal, the
masculine
masculine and
masculine and the
masculine and the feminine
masculine and the feminine of
masculine and the feminine of blended
together
together and
masculine and the feminine of blended
together and working
together and working together
masculine and the feminine of blended
together and working together because
each
each one
each one serves
each one serves the
each one serves the other.
each one serves the other. All
each one serves the other. All right.
each one serves the other. All right. We
see
see the
each one serves the other. All right. We
see the carnival
see the carnival in
each one serves the other. All right. We
see the carnival in our
see the carnival in our world
each one serves the other. All right. We
see the carnival in our world of
see the carnival in our world of of
causes,
causes, you
causes, you know,
uh
all
all kinds
all kinds of
all kinds of elitism
and
and there's
all kinds of elitism
and there's a
and there's a there's
all kinds of elitism
and there's a there's always
and there's a there's always a
all kinds of elitism
and there's a there's always a passing
fed
fed like
fed like I
fed like I say,
fed like I say, save
fed like I say, save the
fed like I say, save the hippopotamus
fed like I say, save the hippopotamus or
save
save the
fed like I say, save the hippopotamus or
save the reindeer
save the reindeer or
fed like I say, save the hippopotamus or
save the reindeer or save
save the reindeer or save somebody.
Environmentalism
Environmentalism gets
Environmentalism gets a
Environmentalism gets a very
Environmentalism gets a very big
Environmentalism gets a very big push.
And
And of
Environmentalism gets a very big push.
And of course,
And of course, you
Environmentalism gets a very big push.
And of course, you can
And of course, you can justify
Environmentalism gets a very big push.
And of course, you can justify anything
with
with historical
with historical revisionism.
with historical revisionism. What
with historical revisionism. What you
with historical revisionism. What you do
is
is you
with historical revisionism. What you do
is you reinterpret
is you reinterpret history
with historical revisionism. What you do
is you reinterpret history in
is you reinterpret history in such
with historical revisionism. What you do
is you reinterpret history in such a
is you reinterpret history in such a way
and
and what
and what gets
and what gets juiced
and what gets juiced the
and what gets juiced the most
and what gets juiced the most is
and what gets juiced the most is being
the
the victim.
and what gets juiced the most is being
the victim. People
the victim. People love
and what gets juiced the most is being
the victim. People love to
the victim. People love to be
and what gets juiced the most is being
the victim. People love to be the
victim.
victim. It's
victim. It's enormous
victim. It's enormous competition
victim. It's enormous competition to
victim. It's enormous competition to be
the
the victim.
victim. It's enormous competition to be
the victim. And
the victim. And if
victim. It's enormous competition to be
the victim. And if you
the victim. And if you can't
victim. It's enormous competition to be
the victim. And if you can't find
the victim. And if you can't find any
reason
reason to
reason to be
reason to be a
reason to be a victim,
reason to be a victim, that's
reason to be a victim, that's because
you
you haven't
reason to be a victim, that's because
you haven't gone
you haven't gone back
reason to be a victim, that's because
you haven't gone back far
you haven't gone back far enough
reason to be a victim, that's because
you haven't gone back far enough in
history.
In
In history,
history.
In history, everyone
In history, everyone here,
history.
In history, everyone here, everyone
In history, everyone here, everyone here
was
was enslaved.
You
You know
was enslaved.
You know the
You know the antecedence
was enslaved.
You know the antecedence of
You know the antecedence of every
was enslaved.
You know the antecedence of every single
person
person sitting
person sitting here.
What
What I
person sitting here.
What I just
What I just said
person sitting here.
What I just said is
What I just said is true.
person sitting here.
What I just said is true. Resist.
What I just said is true. Resist. Why?
Because
Because slavery
Because slavery was
Because slavery was an
Because slavery was an evolutionary
stage
stage of
Because slavery was an evolutionary
stage of mankind.
In
In the
In the old
In the old days,
In the old days, the
In the old days, the Vikings
In the old days, the Vikings captured
everybody
everybody and
In the old days, the Vikings captured
everybody and killed
everybody and killed everybody.
In the old days, the Vikings captured
everybody and killed everybody. The
everybody and killed everybody. The gods
killed
killed everybody.
killed everybody. The
killed everybody. The Vikings,
killed everybody. The Vikings, the
killed everybody. The Vikings, the Huns,
everybody
everybody killed
killed everybody. The Vikings, the Huns,
everybody killed everybody.
Then
Then some
Then some enterprising
Then some enterprising smarty
Then some enterprising smarty got
Then some enterprising smarty got you
could
could sell
Then some enterprising smarty got you
could sell these
could sell these people.
Oh,
Oh, when
Oh, when you
Oh, when you So
Oh, when you So they
Oh, when you So they stopped
Oh, when you So they stopped killing
them
them because
Oh, when you So they stopped killing
them because now
them because now they
Oh, when you So they stopped killing
them because now they could
them because now they could be
Oh, when you So they stopped killing
them because now they could be sold
them because now they could be sold off.
So
So slavery
So slavery was
So slavery was worldwide.
So slavery was worldwide. Worldwide
So slavery was worldwide. Worldwide in
ancient
ancient Rome
So slavery was worldwide. Worldwide in
ancient Rome almost
ancient Rome almost everybody
So slavery was worldwide. Worldwide in
ancient Rome almost everybody was
ancient Rome almost everybody was a
slave.
slave. Nine
slave. Nine out
slave. Nine out of
slave. Nine out of 10
slave. Nine out of 10 people
slave. Nine out of 10 people ancient
Egypt,
Egypt, ancient
slave. Nine out of 10 people ancient
Egypt, ancient Greece,
Egypt, ancient Greece, etc.
slave. Nine out of 10 people ancient
Egypt, ancient Greece, etc. So
Egypt, ancient Greece, etc. So therefore
it
it was
it was normal.
it was normal. It
it was normal. It was
it was normal. It was not
it was normal. It was not immoral
it was normal. It was not immoral in
that
that world.
it was normal. It was not immoral in
that world. Historically,
that world. Historically, it
it was normal. It was not immoral in
that world. Historically, it was
that world. Historically, it was normal.
Frankly,
Frankly, it
Frankly, it was
Frankly, it was a
Frankly, it was a lot
Frankly, it was a lot better
Frankly, it was a lot better to
Frankly, it was a lot better to be
enslaved
enslaved than
Frankly, it was a lot better to be
enslaved than slaughtered
enslaved than slaughtered because
Frankly, it was a lot better to be
enslaved than slaughtered because in
those
those days,
those days, the
those days, the Vikings
those days, the Vikings chopped
those days, the Vikings chopped your
head
head head
those days, the Vikings chopped your
head head off.
Uh,
Uh, as
Uh, as parts
Uh, as parts of
Uh, as parts of the
Uh, as parts of the world
Uh, as parts of the world would
Uh, as parts of the world would like
Uh, as parts of the world would like to
do
do still.
Uh, as parts of the world would like to
do still. Anyway,
do still. Anyway, if
Uh, as parts of the world would like to
do still. Anyway, if you
do still. Anyway, if you lost,
Uh, as parts of the world would like to
do still. Anyway, if you lost, they
chopped
chopped off
chopped off your
chopped off your head.
chopped off your head. Chopped
chopped off your head. Chopped off
chopped off your head. Chopped off your
head.
head. So,
chopped off your head. Chopped off your
head. So, it
head. So, it was
chopped off your head. Chopped off your
head. So, it was better
head. So, it was better that
chopped off your head. Chopped off your
head. So, it was better that you
head. So, it was better that you got
sold
sold off.
sold off. At least
sold off. At least you
sold off. At least you got
sold off. At least you got to
sold off. At least you got to live.
sold off. At least you got to live. And
if
if you
sold off. At least you got to live. And
if you live,
if you live, sooner
sold off. At least you got to live. And
if you live, sooner or
if you live, sooner or later
sold off. At least you got to live. And
if you live, sooner or later you
if you live, sooner or later you would
find
find some
find some level
find some level of
find some level of happiness
find some level of happiness and
find some level of happiness and you
might
might escape,
find some level of happiness and you
might escape, etc.
might escape, etc. But
find some level of happiness and you
might escape, etc. But it's
might escape, etc. But it's better
find some level of happiness and you
might escape, etc. But it's better to
might escape, etc. But it's better to be
captured
captured and
captured and enslaved
captured and enslaved and
captured and enslaved and allowed
captured and enslaved and allowed to
live
live than
captured and enslaved and allowed to
live than having
live than having your
captured and enslaved and allowed to
live than having your head
live than having your head cut
captured and enslaved and allowed to
live than having your head cut off.
live than having your head cut off. When
your
your head's
your head's cut
your head's cut off,
your head's cut off, that
your head's cut off, that cuts
your head's cut off, that cuts your
options
options short.
So
So we
So we see
So we see all
So we see all these
So we see all these uh
So we see all these uh isms,
exhibitionism.
Um
Um the
Um the desire
Um the desire to
Um the desire to be
Um the desire to be famous,
Um the desire to be famous, you
Um the desire to be famous, you know,
Um the desire to be famous, you know, is
so
so predominant.
Who
Who was
Who was the
Who was the famous
Who was the famous B
Who was the famous B beetle
Who was the famous B beetle that
Who was the famous B beetle that was
just
just shot
Who was the famous B beetle that was
just shot in
just shot in west
Who was the famous B beetle that was
just shot in west side
just shot in west side of
Who was the famous B beetle that was
just shot in west side of New
just shot in west side of New York
Who was the famous B beetle that was
just shot in west side of New York City
in
in the
in the whatchamacallit
in the whatchamacallit apartments?
>> Lennon.
>> Lennon. Yes.
in the whatchamacallit apartments?
>> Lennon. Yes. Well,
>> Lennon. Yes. Well, the
in the whatchamacallit apartments?
>> Lennon. Yes. Well, the guy
>> Lennon. Yes. Well, the guy who
in the whatchamacallit apartments?
>> Lennon. Yes. Well, the guy who just
>> Lennon. Yes. Well, the guy who just who
shot
shot Lennon,
his
his only
shot Lennon,
his only motivation
his only motivation is
shot Lennon,
his only motivation is he
his only motivation is he wanted
shot Lennon,
his only motivation is he wanted to
his only motivation is he wanted to be
famous.
That's
That's all.
famous.
That's all. He
That's all. He wanted
famous.
That's all. He wanted to
That's all. He wanted to be
famous.
That's all. He wanted to be famous.
That's all. He wanted to be famous. And
we
we see
we see these
we see these killers
we see these killers who
we see these killers who kill
we see these killers who kill all
we see these killers who kill all their
fellow
fellow classmates
we see these killers who kill all their
fellow classmates in
fellow classmates in school
we see these killers who kill all their
fellow classmates in school and
fellow classmates in school and then
we see these killers who kill all their
fellow classmates in school and then get
on
on and
on and do
on and do this
on and do this mad
on and do this mad lecture.
on and do this mad lecture. And
on and do this mad lecture. And I
on and do this mad lecture. And I think
he
he calibrated
on and do this mad lecture. And I think
he calibrated him
he calibrated him at
on and do this mad lecture. And I think
he calibrated him at 10
he calibrated him at 10 that
on and do this mad lecture. And I think
he calibrated him at 10 that boom
he calibrated him at 10 that boom or
whatever
whatever his
whatever his name
whatever his name is.
whatever his name is. Uh
whatever his name is. Uh he
whatever his name is. Uh he just
whatever his name is. Uh he just wants
to
to be
whatever his name is. Uh he just wants
to be famous.
to be famous. So
whatever his name is. Uh he just wants
to be famous. So for
to be famous. So for fame
whatever his name is. Uh he just wants
to be famous. So for fame and
to be famous. So for fame and money
whatever his name is. Uh he just wants
to be famous. So for fame and money uh
to be famous. So for fame and money uh a
large
large part
large part of
large part of our
large part of our society
large part of our society will
large part of our society will do
anything
anything and
large part of our society will do
anything and selling
anything and selling their
large part of our society will do
anything and selling their soul
anything and selling their soul is
traditional.
What
What you
traditional.
What you do
What you do is
traditional.
What you do is you
What you do is you get
traditional.
What you do is you get fame
What you do is you get fame and
traditional.
What you do is you get fame and fortune
and
and you
and you sell
and you sell your
and you sell your soul
and you sell your soul to
and you sell your soul to get
and you sell your soul to get it.
and you sell your soul to get it. So
and you sell your soul to get it. So a
good
good part
and you sell your soul to get it. So a
good part of
good part of society
and you sell your soul to get it. So a
good part of society is
good part of society is willing
and you sell your soul to get it. So a
good part of society is willing to
good part of society is willing to sell
their
their soul
their soul for
their soul for fame
their soul for fame and
their soul for fame and fame
their soul for fame and fame and
fortune.
fortune. I
their soul for fame and fame and
fortune. I never
fortune. I never asked
their soul for fame and fame and
fortune. I never asked what
fortune. I never asked what percent.
their soul for fame and fame and
fortune. I never asked what percent. We
have
have permission
have permission to
have permission to ask.
have permission to ask. You
have permission to ask. You have
permission
permission to
have permission to ask. You have
permission to ask
permission to ask in
have permission to ask. You have
permission to ask in our
permission to ask in our society
have permission to ask. You have
permission to ask in our society over
5%.
10%.
15%
20%
15%.
15%. Good
15%. Good God,
15%. Good God, it's
15%. Good God, it's higher
15%. Good God, it's higher than
15%. Good God, it's higher than I
thought.
thought. 15%
15%. Good God, it's higher than I
thought. 15% of
thought. 15% of the
15%. Good God, it's higher than I
thought. 15% of the world's
thought. 15% of the world's of
15%. Good God, it's higher than I
thought. 15% of the world's of our
population
population is
population is willing
population is willing to
population is willing to sell
population is willing to sell their
soul,
their
their soul
their soul for
their soul for fame
their soul for fame and
their soul for fame and fortune.
That's
That's sort
their soul for fame and fortune.
That's sort of
That's sort of scary
their soul for fame and fortune.
That's sort of scary when
That's sort of scary when you
their soul for fame and fortune.
That's sort of scary when you think
That's sort of scary when you think of
it.
it. Yeah,
it. Yeah, you're
it. Yeah, you're lying,
it. Yeah, you're lying, you
it. Yeah, you're lying, you know,
for
for fame
it. Yeah, you're lying, you know,
for fame and
for fame and fortune,
it. Yeah, you're lying, you know,
for fame and fortune, but
for fame and fortune, but you
it. Yeah, you're lying, you know,
for fame and fortune, but you see
for fame and fortune, but you see it
every
every day
every day on
every day on television,
every day on television, you
every day on television, you know,
every day on television, you know, uh
the
the things
every day on television, you know, uh
the things that
the things that people
every day on television, you know, uh
the things that people do
the things that people do in
every day on television, you know, uh
the things that people do in order
the things that people do in order to
every day on television, you know, uh
the things that people do in order to be
in
in the
in the limelight.
All
All right.
in the limelight.
All right. So,
All right. So, we
in the limelight.
All right. So, we we
All right. So, we we pretty
in the limelight.
All right. So, we we pretty much
All right. So, we we pretty much checked
out
out these
out these are
out these are all
out these are all very
out these are all very powerful
out these are all very powerful trends
in
in today's
out these are all very powerful trends
in today's world.
in today's world. Exhibitionism,
uh,
uh, now
uh, now that
uh, now that you
uh, now that you can,
uh,
uh, get
uh, now that you can,
uh, get yourself
uh, get yourself on
uh, now that you can,
uh, get yourself on international
television
television at
television at the
television at the flip
television at the flip of
television at the flip of a
television at the flip of a button
television at the flip of a button while
you're
you're driving
television at the flip of a button while
you're driving with
you're driving with one
television at the flip of a button while
you're driving with one hand.
We've
We've looked
We've looked at
We've looked at relativism
We've looked at relativism versus
absolutism
absolutism before.
uh
uh relativis
uh relativis relativism
uh relativis relativism is
uh relativis relativism is actually
uh relativis relativism is actually a
variety
variety of
uh relativis relativism is actually a
variety of the
variety of the Marxist
uh relativis relativism is actually a
variety of the Marxist doctrine
variety of the Marxist doctrine Marxism
of
of victim
of victim and
of victim and perpetrator
victor
victor and
of victim and perpetrator
victor and perpetrator.
It
It comes
It comes uh
It comes uh actually
It comes uh actually from
It comes uh actually from intellectual
error
error relativism.
A
A thing
A thing is
A thing is only
A thing is only true
A thing is only true if
A thing is only true if I
A thing is only true if I believe
A thing is only true if I believe it
A thing is only true if I believe it to
be
be true.
A thing is only true if I believe it to
be true. So
be true. So in
A thing is only true if I believe it to
be true. So in relativism
be true. So in relativism is
A thing is only true if I believe it to
be true. So in relativism is the
opposite
opposite of
opposite of absolutism.
And
And I
opposite of absolutism.
And I notice
And I notice some
opposite of absolutism.
And I notice some people
warn
warn readers
warn readers of
warn readers of of
warn readers of of anything
warn readers of of anything I've
written.
written. Warning,
warn readers of of anything I've
written. Warning, he's
written. Warning, he's an
warn readers of of anything I've
written. Warning, he's an absolutist.
Warning,
Warning, he's
Warning, he's an
Warning, he's an absolutist.
Warning, he's an absolutist. Watch
Warning, he's an absolutist. Watch out.
You're
You're not
Warning, he's an absolutist. Watch out.
You're not a
You're not a relativist
Warning, he's an absolutist. Watch out.
You're not a relativist because
You're not a relativist because truth
Warning, he's an absolutist. Watch out.
You're not a relativist because truth is
not
not what
not what subject
not what subject to
not what subject to your
not what subject to your opinion.
not what subject to your opinion. Uh
truth
truth is
not what subject to your opinion. Uh
truth is so
truth is so no
not what subject to your opinion. Uh
truth is so no matter
truth is so no matter what
not what subject to your opinion. Uh
truth is so no matter what your
truth is so no matter what your opinion
is.
is. So
is. So the
is. So the value
is. So the value of
is. So the value of counter
is. So the value of counter burning
levels
levels of
is. So the value of counter burning
levels of consciousness
levels of consciousness was
is. So the value of counter burning
levels of consciousness was we
levels of consciousness was we could
discern
discern essence.
discern essence. The
discern essence. The first
discern essence. The first time
discern essence. The first time in
history
history man
discern essence. The first time in
history man can
history man can discern
discern essence. The first time in
history man can discern the
history man can discern the essence
discern essence. The first time in
history man can discern the essence and
the
the truth
the truth of
the truth of a
the truth of a thing
the truth of a thing uh
the truth of a thing uh without
the truth of a thing uh without having
it
it impaired.
the truth of a thing uh without having
it impaired. There
it impaired. There is
the truth of a thing uh without having
it impaired. There is rest
it impaired. There is rest internal
the truth of a thing uh without having
it impaired. There is rest internal and
rest
rest externa.
rest externa. Rest
rest externa. Rest interna
rest externa. Rest interna is
rest externa. Rest interna is as
rest externa. Rest interna is as Renee
Deart
Deart said
rest externa. Rest interna is as Renee
Deart said the
Deart said the world
rest externa. Rest interna is as Renee
Deart said the world as
Deart said the world as it
rest externa. Rest interna is as Renee
Deart said the world as it looks
Deart said the world as it looks to
rest externa. Rest interna is as Renee
Deart said the world as it looks to you.
Rest
Rest externa
Rest externa is
Rest externa is the
Rest externa is the world
Rest externa is the world the
Rest externa is the world the way
Rest externa is the world the way it
Rest externa is the world the way it is.
And
And Socrates
Rest externa is the world the way it is.
And Socrates of
And Socrates of course
Rest externa is the world the way it is.
And Socrates of course uh
And Socrates of course uh pointed
Rest externa is the world the way it is.
And Socrates of course uh pointed out
that
that man
that man man
uh
uh doesn't
that man man
uh doesn't see
uh doesn't see truth.
that man man
uh doesn't see truth. He
uh doesn't see truth. He sees
that man man
uh doesn't see truth. He sees his
uh doesn't see truth. He sees his own
projections
projections projected
projections projected onto
projections projected onto the
projections projected onto the world.
What
What he
projections projected onto the world.
What he considers
What he considers to
projections projected onto the world.
What he considers to be
What he considers to be the
projections projected onto the world.
What he considers to be the good
What he considers to be the good is
projections projected onto the world.
What he considers to be the good is what
he
he projects
he projects onto
he projects onto the
he projects onto the world
he projects onto the world as
he projects onto the world as good.
he projects onto the world as good. And
in
in more
he projects onto the world as good. And
in more recent
in more recent times
he projects onto the world as good. And
in more recent times uh
in more recent times uh the
he projects onto the world as good. And
in more recent times uh the book
in more recent times uh the book glamour
explains
explains it.
explains it. Uh
explains it. Uh glamour
explains it. Uh glamour means
explains it. Uh glamour means that
explains it. Uh glamour means that the
attractiveness
attractiveness of
explains it. Uh glamour means that the
attractiveness of what
attractiveness of what you
explains it. Uh glamour means that the
attractiveness of what you desire
attractiveness of what you desire in
explains it. Uh glamour means that the
attractiveness of what you desire in the
world
world you
world you think
world you think is
world you think is intrinsic
world you think is intrinsic to
world you think is intrinsic to what
what
what it
world you think is intrinsic to what
what it is
what it is you
world you think is intrinsic to what
what it is you desire
new
new elephant
new elephant or
new elephant or whatever.
But
But the
new elephant or whatever.
But the glamour
But the glamour and
new elephant or whatever.
But the glamour and attractiveness
But the glamour and attractiveness of
that
that elephant
that elephant is
that elephant is that
that elephant is that you've
that elephant is that you've projected
great
great worth
that elephant is that you've projected
great worth and
great worth and value
that elephant is that you've projected
great worth and value and
great worth and value and desiraability
on
on the
on the elephant.
on the elephant. Although
on the elephant. Although a
on the elephant. Although a trained
elephant
elephant will
on the elephant. Although a trained
elephant will cost
elephant will cost you
on the elephant. Although a trained
elephant will cost you a
elephant will cost you a couple
on the elephant. Although a trained
elephant will cost you a couple million.
Of
Of course,
Of course, where
Of course, where would
Of course, where would you
Of course, where would you keep
Of course, where would you keep it?
Of course, where would you keep it? I
don't
don't know.
All
All right.
All right. So
we
we have
All right. So
we have discussed
we have discussed you
All right. So
we have discussed you know
we have discussed you know considerably
relativism
relativism versus
relativism versus absolutism.
The
The truth
relativism versus absolutism.
The truth is
The truth is what
relativism versus absolutism.
The truth is what it
The truth is what it is
relativism versus absolutism.
The truth is what it is irrespective
The truth is what it is irrespective of
what
what you
what you think
what you think about
what you think about it.
what you think about it. Uh
what you think about it. Uh all
what you think about it. Uh all right.
So
So that
what you think about it. Uh all right.
So that is
So that is a
what you think about it. Uh all right.
So that is a different
So that is a different viewpoint
what you think about it. Uh all right.
So that is a different viewpoint that
So that is a different viewpoint that is
this
this particular
this particular absolutism
this particular absolutism will
eventually
eventually take
this particular absolutism will
eventually take you
eventually take you to
this particular absolutism will
eventually take you to God.
eventually take you to God. If
this particular absolutism will
eventually take you to God. If you
follow
the
the absolute
follow
the absolute truth,
the absolute truth, if
follow
the absolute truth, if if
the absolute truth, if if every
follow
the absolute truth, if if every decision
tree,
tree, every
tree, every decision
tree, every decision tree
tree, every decision tree you
tree, every decision tree you come
tree, every decision tree you come to,
you
you choose
tree, every decision tree you come to,
you choose that
you choose that which
tree, every decision tree you come to,
you choose that which calibrates
you choose that which calibrates the
highest,
highest, eventually
highest, eventually you
highest, eventually you will
highest, eventually you will arrive
highest, eventually you will arrive at
divinity.
divinity. Eventually
highest, eventually you will arrive at
divinity. Eventually all
divinity. Eventually all roads
highest, eventually you will arrive at
divinity. Eventually all roads will
divinity. Eventually all roads will lead
to
to God.
to God. And
to God. And that's
to God. And that's why
to God. And that's why the
to God. And that's why the atheist
cannot
cannot do
to God. And that's why the atheist
cannot do consciousness
cannot do consciousness calibration.
Some
Some well-known
Some well-known professors
Some well-known professors and
Some well-known professors and all
Some well-known professors and all who
poo
poo pooed
Some well-known professors and all who
poo pooed it.
poo pooed it. And
Some well-known professors and all who
poo pooed it. And I
poo pooed it. And I couldn't
Some well-known professors and all who
poo pooed it. And I couldn't understand
how
how could
how could how
how could how they
how could how they couldn't
how could how they couldn't get
how could how they couldn't get it
how could how they couldn't get it to
work
because
because they're
because they're into
because they're into alternative
medicine
medicine and
because they're into alternative
medicine and all
medicine and all that
because they're into alternative
medicine and all that kind
medicine and all that kind of
because they're into alternative
medicine and all that kind of stuff.
medicine and all that kind of stuff. And
then
then I
then I found
then I found out
then I found out it's
then I found out it's because
then I found out it's because they're
atheists.
atheists. So
then I found out it's because they're
atheists. So if
atheists. So if you
then I found out it's because they're
atheists. So if you negate
atheists. So if you negate the
then I found out it's because they're
atheists. So if you negate the very
source
source and
source and reality
source and reality of
source and reality of truth
source and reality of truth itself
source and reality of truth itself which
is
is a
source and reality of truth itself which
is a divine
quality
quality of
quality of divinity
then
then you
quality of divinity
then you disenfranchise
then you disenfranchise yourself
quality of divinity
then you disenfranchise yourself from
the
the fruits
the fruits and
the fruits and the
the fruits and the rewards
of
of adhering
the fruits and the rewards
of adhering to
of adhering to truth
the fruits and the rewards
of adhering to truth and
of adhering to truth and the
the fruits and the rewards
of adhering to truth and the source
of adhering to truth and the source of
truth
truth as
truth as divinity.
All
All right.
truth as divinity.
All right. So
All right. So we'll
truth as divinity.
All right. So we'll go
All right. So we'll go to
truth as divinity.
All right. So we'll go to the
All right. So we'll go to the next.
truth as divinity.
All right. So we'll go to the next. Yes.
The
The carnival
The carnival of
The carnival of the
The carnival of the isms.
Uh
Uh communism
The carnival of the isms.
Uh communism and
Uh communism and Marxism.
The carnival of the isms.
Uh communism and Marxism. Of
Uh communism and Marxism. Of course
The carnival of the isms.
Uh communism and Marxism. Of course we
are
are very
are very familiar.
are very familiar. We've
are very familiar. We've already
are very familiar. We've already pointed
out
out paternalism.
You
You get
You get what
You get what you
You get what you deserve
You get what you deserve through
You get what you deserve through you
your
your own
You get what you deserve through you
your own self
your own self uh
You get what you deserve through you
your own self uh uh
your own self uh uh discipline
You get what you deserve through you
your own self uh uh discipline and
maternalism
maternalism that
maternalism that everybody
maternalism that everybody deserves
maternalism that everybody deserves to
live
live because
maternalism that everybody deserves to
live because they
live because they are
maternalism that everybody deserves to
live because they are born
live because they are born a
maternalism that everybody deserves to
live because they are born a human
live because they are born a human in
our
our society.
our society. Then
our society. Then you
our society. Then you have
our society. Then you have the
our society. Then you have the various
levels
levels of
our society. Then you have the various
levels of in
levels of in infantilism
which
which are
which are really
which are really um
narcissism.
Infantilism
Infantilism is
Infantilism is really
Infantilism is really narcissism
and
and narcissism
Infantilism is really narcissism
and narcissism is
and narcissism is really
Infantilism is really narcissism
and narcissism is really a
and narcissism is really a form
Infantilism is really narcissism
and narcissism is really a form of
infantilism
in
in which
infantilism
in which you
in which you just
infantilism
in which you just think
in which you just think about
infantilism
in which you just think about me
in which you just think about me and
everybody
everybody is
everybody is supposed
everybody is supposed to
everybody is supposed to teach
everybody is supposed to teach to
everybody is supposed to teach to to
treat
treat your
everybody is supposed to teach to to
treat your inner
treat your inner feelings
everybody is supposed to teach to to
treat your inner feelings as
treat your inner feelings as though
everybody is supposed to teach to to
treat your inner feelings as though they
are
are precious.
Nobody's
Nobody's supposed
are precious.
Nobody's supposed to
Nobody's supposed to hurt
are precious.
Nobody's supposed to hurt your
Nobody's supposed to hurt your feelings.
So,
So, as
So, as long
So, as long as
So, as long as we
So, as long as we don't
So, as long as we don't hurt
So, as long as we don't hurt anybody's
feelings,
feelings, we're
So, as long as we don't hurt anybody's
feelings, we're okay.
feelings, we're okay. Except
So, as long as we don't hurt anybody's
feelings, we're okay. Except that's
infantilism
because
because the
infantilism
because the world
because the world the
infantilism
because the world the world
because the world the world wasn't
created,
created, you
created, you know,
created, you know, uh
created, you know, uh to
created, you know, uh to handle
created, you know, uh to handle your
infantile
infantile feelings
created, you know, uh to handle your
infantile feelings of
infantile feelings of what
created, you know, uh to handle your
infantile feelings of what you
infantile feelings of what you like
created, you know, uh to handle your
infantile feelings of what you like and
what
what you
what you don't
what you don't like.
what you don't like. And
what you don't like. And people
what you don't like. And people might
what you don't like. And people might be
offended.
offended. People
what you don't like. And people might be
offended. People are
offended. People are offended
what you don't like. And people might be
offended. People are offended by
everything.
you
you you
everything.
you you wouldn't
you you wouldn't be
everything.
you you wouldn't be able
you you wouldn't be able to
everything.
you you wouldn't be able to speak
you you wouldn't be able to speak or
talk
talk or
talk or leave
talk or leave the
talk or leave the house
talk or leave the house because
talk or leave the house because you're
going
going to
talk or leave the house because you're
going to offend
going to offend somebody.
So,
So, this
So, this preoccupation
So, this preoccupation that
So, this preoccupation that somebody
might
might be
So, this preoccupation that somebody
might be offended,
might be offended, every
So, this preoccupation that somebody
might be offended, every day
might be offended, every day you
So, this preoccupation that somebody
might be offended, every day you see
some
some group
some group that's
some group that's offended
some group that's offended offended.
some group that's offended offended. I'm
offended
offended by
some group that's offended offended. I'm
offended by their
offended by their being
some group that's offended offended. I'm
offended by their being offended.
I'm
I'm I I
I'm I I belong
I'm I I belong to
I'm I I belong to an
I'm I I belong to an offender
I'm I I belong to an offender protest
group
in
in which
in which I
in which I don't
in which I don't give
in which I don't give a
in which I don't give a P
in which I don't give a P whether
in which I don't give a P whether you're
offended
offended or
in which I don't give a P whether you're
offended or not
offended or not about
in which I don't give a P whether you're
offended or not about anything.
Being
Being offended
Being offended is
Being offended is your
Being offended is your problem.
No,
No, I
Being offended is your problem.
No, I am
No, I am offended
Being offended is your problem.
No, I am offended by
No, I am offended by they're
Being offended is your problem.
No, I am offended by they're being
offended
offended by
offended by everything.
offended by everything. You
offended by everything. You can't
offended by everything. You can't speak
of
of anything
offended by everything. You can't speak
of anything that
of anything that some
offended by everything. You can't speak
of anything that some group
of anything that some group doesn't
offended by everything. You can't speak
of anything that some group doesn't put
up
up a
up a protest
up a protest sign
that
that somebody's
up a protest sign
that somebody's first
that somebody's first in
up a protest sign
that somebody's first in line
and
and somebody's
and somebody's last
and somebody's last in
and somebody's last in line.
and somebody's last in line. Some
and somebody's last in line. Some people
are
are offended
and somebody's last in line. Some people
are offended by
are offended by that.
and somebody's last in line. Some people
are offended by that. I
are offended by that. I get
and somebody's last in line. Some people
are offended by that. I get a
are offended by that. I get a kick
and somebody's last in line. Some people
are offended by that. I get a kick out
of
of truthers.
of truthers. uh
of truthers. uh truthers
of truthers. uh truthers uh
of truthers. uh truthers uh is
of truthers. uh truthers uh is the
latest
latest headline
of truthers. uh truthers uh is the
latest headline and
latest headline and they're
of truthers. uh truthers uh is the
latest headline and they're always
coming
coming up
coming up with
coming up with the
coming up with the latest
coming up with the latest conspiracy
theory
theory and
coming up with the latest conspiracy
theory and uh
theory and uh the
coming up with the latest conspiracy
theory and uh the one
theory and uh the one the
coming up with the latest conspiracy
theory and uh the one the conspiracy
theory
theory I
theory I like
theory I like they
theory I like they always
theory I like they always tell
theory I like they always tell you
theory I like they always tell you how
the
the the
theory I like they always tell you how
the the United
the the United States
theory I like they always tell you how
the the United States government
engineered
engineered 9/11
engineered 9/11 and
engineered 9/11 and put
engineered 9/11 and put secret
engineered 9/11 and put secret bombs
engineered 9/11 and put secret bombs in
the
the buildings
engineered 9/11 and put secret bombs in
the buildings and
the buildings and stuff
engineered 9/11 and put secret bombs in
the buildings and stuff like
the buildings and stuff like this
engineered 9/11 and put secret bombs in
the buildings and stuff like this and
what
what and
what and what
what and what they're
what and what they're getting
what and what they're getting out
what and what they're getting out of
what and what they're getting out of it
you
you get
what and what they're getting out of it
you get at
you get at the
what and what they're getting out of it
you get at the end
you get at the end of
what and what they're getting out of it
you get at the end of the
you get at the end of the story
what and what they're getting out of it
you get at the end of the story because
they
they then
they then they
they then they give
they then they give you
they then they give you a
they then they give you a smirk
everybody
everybody knows
they then they give you a smirk
everybody knows that
everybody knows that steel
they then they give you a smirk
everybody knows that steel doesn't
everybody knows that steel doesn't melt.
Everybody
Everybody knows
Everybody knows that
Everybody knows that steel
Everybody knows that steel doesn't
Everybody knows that steel doesn't melt.
That's
That's the
Everybody knows that steel doesn't melt.
That's the punchline,
That's the punchline, the
Everybody knows that steel doesn't melt.
That's the punchline, the final
That's the punchline, the final uh
convincer
convincer of
convincer of the
convincer of the truthers.
Everybody
Everybody knows
convincer of the truthers.
Everybody knows that
Everybody knows that steel
convincer of the truthers.
Everybody knows that steel doesn't
Everybody knows that steel doesn't melt.
How
How do
How do they
How do they think
How do they think railroad
How do they think railroad trucks
How do they think railroad trucks came
about?
about? I
How do they think railroad trucks came
about? I don't
about? I don't know.
where
where they
where they went
where they went to
where they went to school.
where they went to school. Anyway,
where they went to school. Anyway, I
where they went to school. Anyway, I was
like
like that
where they went to school. Anyway, I was
like that steel
like that steel doesn't
where they went to school. Anyway, I was
like that steel doesn't melt.
like that steel doesn't melt. Calibrates
at
at 150.
at 150. Calibrates
at 150. Calibrates at
at 150. Calibrates at 150.
at 150. Calibrates at 150. All
at 150. Calibrates at 150. All right.
So,
in
in this
in this is
in this is the
in this is the infantilism.
in this is the infantilism. The
in this is the infantilism. The truthers
are
are then
working
working conspiracy
working conspiracy theories
working conspiracy theories because
they're
they're getting
working conspiracy theories because
they're getting narcissistic
gratification
out
out of
gratification
out of the
out of the their
gratification
out of the their idea
out of the their idea of
gratification
out of the their idea of moral
superiority.
superiority. So
superiority. So the
superiority. So the world
superiority. So the world is
superiority. So the world is in
superiority. So the world is in a
superiority. So the world is in a race
for
for moral
superiority. So the world is in a race
for moral superiority.
The
The intense
The intense competition
The intense competition for
The intense competition for the
The intense competition for the moral
high
high ground.
The intense competition for the moral
high ground. You
high ground. You see
The intense competition for the moral
high ground. You see it
high ground. You see it with
The intense competition for the moral
high ground. You see it with Iran,
high ground. You see it with Iran, the
president
president of
president of Iran.
president of Iran. You
president of Iran. You see
president of Iran. You see it
president of Iran. You see it everywhere
in
in the
president of Iran. You see it everywhere
in the public
in the public arena
president of Iran. You see it everywhere
in the public arena everywhere
in the public arena everywhere in
president of Iran. You see it everywhere
in the public arena everywhere in the
world.
world. You
world. You see
world. You see pe
world. You see pe people
world. You see pe people struggling
uh
uh for
world. You see pe people struggling
uh for the
uh for the moral
world. You see pe people struggling
uh for the moral high
uh for the moral high ground,
world. You see pe people struggling
uh for the moral high ground, the
uh for the moral high ground, the moral
high
high ground
high ground to
high ground to justify
high ground to justify something.
high ground to justify something. And
high ground to justify something. And if
I
I can't
high ground to justify something. And if
I can't find
I can't find it
high ground to justify something. And if
I can't find it in
I can't find it in today's
high ground to justify something. And if
I can't find it in today's world,
I can't find it in today's world, I
high ground to justify something. And if
I can't find it in today's world, I can
dream
dream it
dream it up.
dream it up. my
dream it up. my ancestors
dream it up. my ancestors and
dream it up. my ancestors and your
ancestors.
ancestors. And
dream it up. my ancestors and your
ancestors. And now
ancestors. And now I'm
dream it up. my ancestors and your
ancestors. And now I'm getting
ancestors. And now I'm getting even.
dream it up. my ancestors and your
ancestors. And now I'm getting even. And
I
I have
I have a
I have a right
I have a right to
I have a right to what
I have a right to what the
I have a right to what the Irish
I have a right to what the Irish did
I have a right to what the Irish did to
the
the Protestants,
I have a right to what the Irish did to
the Protestants, what
the Protestants, what the
I have a right to what the Irish did to
the Protestants, what the Protestants
did
did to
did to the
did to the Irish.
did to the Irish. I
did to the Irish. I we
did to the Irish. I we can
did to the Irish. I we can go
did to the Irish. I we can go all
did to the Irish. I we can go all over
the
the world
did to the Irish. I we can go all over
the world and
the world and sooner
did to the Irish. I we can go all over
the world and sooner or
the world and sooner or later
did to the Irish. I we can go all over
the world and sooner or later we'll
the world and sooner or later we'll find
something
something that
something that we
something that we can
something that we can juice.
So
So these
something that we can juice.
So these are
So these are all
something that we can juice.
So these are all ways
So these are all ways of
something that we can juice.
So these are all ways of ju
So these are all ways of ju the
something that we can juice.
So these are all ways of ju the truthers
are
are juicers.
Everybody
Everybody heading
are juicers.
Everybody heading for
Everybody heading for the
are juicers.
Everybody heading for the moral
Everybody heading for the moral high
ground.
ground. And
ground. And the
ground. And the clincher,
ground. And the clincher, every
ground. And the clincher, every time
ground. And the clincher, every time you
hear
hear one,
ground. And the clincher, every time you
hear one, next
hear one, next time
ground. And the clincher, every time you
hear one, next time you
hear one, next time you say,
ground. And the clincher, every time you
hear one, next time you say, "Right,
hear one, next time you say, "Right, and
still
still doesn't
still doesn't melt."
still doesn't melt." Right?
Still
Still doesn't
still doesn't melt." Right?
Still doesn't melt.
Still doesn't melt. They
still doesn't melt." Right?
Still doesn't melt. They ran
Still doesn't melt. They ran all
still doesn't melt." Right?
Still doesn't melt. They ran all over
and
and put
and put bombs
and put bombs all
and put bombs all over
and put bombs all over these
and put bombs all over these buildings
and
and blew
and put bombs all over these buildings
and blew it
and blew it up.
and put bombs all over these buildings
and blew it up. And
and blew it up. And we
and put bombs all over these buildings
and blew it up. And we know
and blew it up. And we know they
and put bombs all over these buildings
and blew it up. And we know they did
that
that because
that because we
that because we know
that because we know that
that because we know that steel
that because we know that steel doesn't
melt.
melt. So
in
in my
in my view
in my view of
in my view of it,
in my view of it, you
in my view of it, you can't
in my view of it, you can't have
in my view of it, you can't have too
high
high an
in my view of it, you can't have too
high an IQ.
high an IQ. and
in my view of it, you can't have too
high an IQ. and also
high an IQ. and also go
in my view of it, you can't have too
high an IQ. and also go along
high an IQ. and also go along with
in my view of it, you can't have too
high an IQ. and also go along with these
kind
kind of
kind of this
kind of this kind
kind of this kind of
kind of this kind of thing.
When
When I
kind of this kind of thing.
When I grew
When I grew up,
kind of this kind of thing.
When I grew up, I
When I grew up, I always
kind of this kind of thing.
When I grew up, I always thought
When I grew up, I always thought of
kind of this kind of thing.
When I grew up, I always thought of it
as
as people
as people have
as people have a
as people have a a
as people have a a low
as people have a a low IQ
as people have a a low IQ and
as people have a a low IQ and either
they
they can't
as people have a a low IQ and either
they can't help
they can't help it
as people have a a low IQ and either
they can't help it because
they can't help it because they
as people have a a low IQ and either
they can't help it because they just
don't
don't have
don't have the
don't have the intellectual
don't have the intellectual capacity.
But
But there's
don't have the intellectual capacity.
But there's more
But there's more than
don't have the intellectual capacity.
But there's more than intellectual
capacity.
capacity. There's
capacity. There's the
capacity. There's the capacity
capacity. There's the capacity for
honesty.
honesty. And
capacity. There's the capacity for
honesty. And to
honesty. And to be
capacity. There's the capacity for
honesty. And to be honest,
honesty. And to be honest, you
capacity. There's the capacity for
honesty. And to be honest, you have
honesty. And to be honest, you have to
give
give up
give up infantile
give up infantile gratification
give up infantile gratification of
give up infantile gratification of being
right
right and
give up infantile gratification of being
right and being
right and being superior
give up infantile gratification of being
right and being superior and
right and being superior and searching
for
for the
for the moral
for the moral high
for the moral high ground.
If
If you've
for the moral high ground.
If you've discovered
If you've discovered what
for the moral high ground.
If you've discovered what you
If you've discovered what you consider
to
to be
to be the
to be the truth,
to be the truth, that's
to be the truth, that's fine.
to be the truth, that's fine. And
doesn't
doesn't mean
to be the truth, that's fine. And
doesn't mean other
doesn't mean other people
to be the truth, that's fine. And
doesn't mean other people have
doesn't mean other people have to
to be the truth, that's fine. And
doesn't mean other people have to agree
with
with it.
with it. Uh
with it. Uh lots
with it. Uh lots of
with it. Uh lots of people
with it. Uh lots of people don't
with it. Uh lots of people don't agree
with
with me
with it. Uh lots of people don't agree
with me and
with me and and
with it. Uh lots of people don't agree
with me and and it's
with me and and it's it's
with it. Uh lots of people don't agree
with me and and it's it's their
with me and and it's it's their loss,
you
you know.
All right,
All right, we'll
you know.
All right, we'll move
All right, we'll move on.
you know.
All right, we'll move on. Next,
the
the war
the war of
the war of the
the war of the isms.
the war of the isms. There's
the war of the isms. There's eventually
a
a loss
the war of the isms. There's eventually
a loss of
a loss of credibility.
There's
There's also
There's also a
There's also a loss
There's also a loss of
There's also a loss of boundaries.
There's also a loss of boundaries. Uh
they
they invade
There's also a loss of boundaries. Uh
they invade other
they invade other people's
There's also a loss of boundaries. Uh
they invade other people's boundaries
all
all the
all the time.
all the time. A
all the time. A decline
all the time. A decline of
all the time. A decline of efficacy.
You
You end
all the time. A decline of efficacy.
You end up
You end up in
all the time. A decline of efficacy.
You end up in this
You end up in this carnival
all the time. A decline of efficacy.
You end up in this carnival of
You end up in this carnival of islams.
You
You end
You end up
You end up with
You end up with dysfunction.
Dysfunction.
This
This is
This is a
This is a country,
This is a country, the
This is a country, the most
This is a country, the most powerful
nation
nation in
This is a country, the most powerful
nation in the
nation in the world.
This is a country, the most powerful
nation in the world. We
nation in the world. We can't
This is a country, the most powerful
nation in the world. We can't even
nation in the world. We can't even put
This is a country, the most powerful
nation in the world. We can't even put a
fence
fence across
fence across the
fence across the border,
right?
right? Whether
fence across the border,
right? Whether you
right? Whether you politically
fence across the border,
right? Whether you politically agree
with
with it
with it or
with it or don't
with it or don't politically
with it or don't politically agree
with it or don't politically agree with
it,
it, you
with it or don't politically agree with
it, you think
it, you think that
with it or don't politically agree with
it, you think that a
it, you think that a huge
with it or don't politically agree with
it, you think that a huge country
it, you think that a huge country like
this
this would
this would be
this would be able
this would be able to
this would be able to solve
this would be able to solve a
this would be able to solve a few
this would be able to solve a few little
simple
simple mechanical
this would be able to solve a few little
simple mechanical problems,
simple mechanical problems, mechanical
problems.
Anyway,
Anyway, you
problems.
Anyway, you get
Anyway, you get a
problems.
Anyway, you get a decline
Anyway, you get a decline of
problems.
Anyway, you get a decline of efficacy.
Uh
Uh you
Uh you become
Uh you become dysfunctional
uh
uh because
Uh you become dysfunctional
uh because you're
uh because you're going
Uh you become dysfunctional
uh because you're going in
uh because you're going in four
different
different directions.
uh
uh at
different directions.
uh at once.
uh at once. Uh
different directions.
uh at once. Uh also
uh at once. Uh also in
different directions.
uh at once. Uh also in this
uh at once. Uh also in this war
different directions.
uh at once. Uh also in this war of
uh at once. Uh also in this war of isms
there's
there's a
there's a loss
there's a loss of
there's a loss of privacy.
there's a loss of privacy. You
there's a loss of privacy. You see
public
public attacks
there's a loss of privacy. You see
public attacks on
public attacks on people
there's a loss of privacy. You see
public attacks on people all
public attacks on people all over
there's a loss of privacy. You see
public attacks on people all over the
place.
place. People
place. People who
place. People who are
place. People who are the
place. People who are the private
advisors
advisors to
place. People who are the private
advisors to the
advisors to the White
place. People who are the private
advisors to the White House,
advisors to the White House, as
place. People who are the private
advisors to the White House, as soon
advisors to the White House, as soon as
they
they get
they get out
they get out of
they get out of the
they get out of the White
they get out of the White House,
they get out of the White House, they
write
write an
they get out of the White House, they
write an expose.
What
What would
What would I
What would I do
What would I do with
What would I do with them?
I
I would
What would I do with them?
I would shoot
I would shoot them
What would I do with them?
I would shoot them at
I would shoot them at dawn.
I'm
I
I was
I'm
I was in
I was in the
I'm
I was in the military.
Commit
Commit treason,
Commit treason, you're
Commit treason, you're dead
Commit treason, you're dead at
Commit treason, you're dead at 6:00
Commit treason, you're dead at 6:00 in
the
the morning.
Commit treason, you're dead at 6:00 in
the morning. Firing
the morning. Firing squad.
I
I would
I would have
I would have everybody
I would have everybody sign
I would have everybody sign an
I would have everybody sign an agreement
of
of confidentiality
I would have everybody sign an agreement
of confidentiality and
of confidentiality and violation.
I would have everybody sign an agreement
of confidentiality and violation. You
know
know you
know you will
know you will be
know you will be executed.
That's
That's why
know you will be executed.
That's why Singapore
That's why Singapore has
know you will be executed.
That's why Singapore has practically
That's why Singapore has practically a
zero
zero crime
zero crime rate.
zero crime rate. You
zero crime rate. You try
zero crime rate. You try that
zero crime rate. You try that in
Singapore,
Singapore, they
zero crime rate. You try that in
Singapore, they execute
Singapore, they execute you
zero crime rate. You try that in
Singapore, they execute you the
Singapore, they execute you the next
morning.
Why
Why are
morning.
Why are there
Why are there no
morning.
Why are there no drug
Why are there no drug dealers
morning.
Why are there no drug dealers in
Singapore?
Singapore? Because
Singapore? Because they're
Singapore? Because they're all
Singapore? Because they're all executed
the
the next
Singapore? Because they're all executed
the next morning.
Get
Get arrested
Get arrested at
Get arrested at 10:00,
Get arrested at 10:00, you
Get arrested at 10:00, you die
Get arrested at 10:00, you die at
Get arrested at 10:00, you die at 6:00
a.m.
No
No problem.
Chewing
Chewing gum,
No problem.
Chewing gum, they
Chewing gum, they don't
No problem.
Chewing gum, they don't kill
Chewing gum, they don't kill you,
No problem.
Chewing gum, they don't kill you, but
they
they put
they put you
they put you away
they put you away for
they put you away for a
they put you away for a while.
So
So the
they put you away for a while.
So the loss
So the loss of
they put you away for a while.
So the loss of privacy,
So the loss of privacy, the
they put you away for a while.
So the loss of privacy, the loss
So the loss of privacy, the loss of
confidentiality,
the
the loss
confidentiality,
the loss of
the loss of trustability,
the
the loss
the loss of
the loss of trustability.
the loss of trustability. And
the loss of trustability. And we'll
the loss of trustability. And we'll see
that
that in
the loss of trustability. And we'll see
that in some
that in some later
the loss of trustability. And we'll see
that in some later things.
I'll
I'll tell
I'll tell you
I'll tell you with
I'll tell you with all
I'll tell you with all these
I'll tell you with all these isms,
I'll tell you with all these isms, the
rights
rights of
I'll tell you with all these isms, the
rights of the
rights of the media,
I'll tell you with all these isms, the
rights of the media, where
rights of the media, where did
I'll tell you with all these isms, the
rights of the media, where did these
rights
rights come
rights come from?
I
I don't
rights come from?
I don't remember
I don't remember any
rights come from?
I don't remember any great
I don't remember any great document
rights come from?
I don't remember any great document by
our
our founding
our founding fathers
our founding fathers that
our founding fathers that everybody
our founding fathers that everybody has
the
the right
our founding fathers that everybody has
the right to
the right to know
our founding fathers that everybody has
the right to know everything.
the right to know everything. Does
anybody
anybody know
anybody know what
anybody know what that
anybody know what that document
anybody know what that document is?
The
The public
anybody know what that document is?
The public has
The public has the
anybody know what that document is?
The public has the right
The public has the right to
anybody know what that document is?
The public has the right to know
everything.
everything. What
everything. What goes
everything. What goes on
everything. What goes on in
everything. What goes on in your
bathroom
in
in the
in the in
in the in your
in the in your the
in the in your the executive
in the in your the executive branch
in the in your the executive branch of
your
your company.
in the in your the executive branch of
your company. Oh
your company. Oh yeah,
in the in your the executive branch of
your company. Oh yeah, we
your company. Oh yeah, we did
in the in your the executive branch of
your company. Oh yeah, we did greed
your company. Oh yeah, we did greed for
fame
fame and
fame and money.
fame and money. Populism.
fame and money. Populism. Sedition.
Sedition
Sedition is
fame and money. Populism. Sedition.
Sedition is now
Sedition is now very
fame and money. Populism. Sedition.
Sedition is now very trendy.
If
If you
If you want
If you want to
If you want to be
If you want to be somebody,
If you want to be somebody, you
If you want to be somebody, you get
If you want to be somebody, you get up
there
there and
If you want to be somebody, you get up
there and denounce
there and denounce the
If you want to be somebody, you get up
there and denounce the United
there and denounce the United States
government.
government. And
government. And it
government. And it used
government. And it used to
government. And it used to be
government. And it used to be you
government. And it used to be you got
government. And it used to be you got a
few
few points
government. And it used to be you got a
few points for
few points for denouncing
government. And it used to be you got a
few points for denouncing Bush,
few points for denouncing Bush, but
that's
that's now
that's now you
that's now you you
that's now you you don't
that's now you you don't get
that's now you you don't get any
that's now you you don't get any you
don't
don't you
that's now you you don't get any you
don't you don't
don't you don't get
that's now you you don't get any you
don't you don't get any
don't you don't get any credit
that's now you you don't get any you
don't you don't get any credit at
don't you don't get any credit at all
for
for denouncing
for denouncing Bush.
for denouncing Bush. He's
for denouncing Bush. He's so
for denouncing Bush. He's so beat
for denouncing Bush. He's so beat up
that
that he
for denouncing Bush. He's so beat up
that he isn't
that he isn't worth
for denouncing Bush. He's so beat up
that he isn't worth even
that he isn't worth even a
for denouncing Bush. He's so beat up
that he isn't worth even a couple
points.
He's
He's like
points.
He's like a
He's like a little
points.
He's like a little rag
He's like a little rag ragd
points.
He's like a little rag ragd doll.
He's like a little rag ragd doll. You
can't
can't get
can't get any
points
points for
can't get any
points for beating
points for beating a
can't get any
points for beating a bush.
He
He didn't
He didn't realize
He didn't realize when
He didn't realize when he
He didn't realize when he took
He didn't realize when he took the
He didn't realize when he took the oath
of
of office
He didn't realize when he took the oath
of office his
of office his duty
He didn't realize when he took the oath
of office his duty was
of office his duty was to
He didn't realize when he took the oath
of office his duty was to to
of office his duty was to to be
He didn't realize when he took the oath
of office his duty was to to be beat
of office his duty was to to be beat up.
Yes,
Yes, I
Yes, I was
Yes, I was here.
Yes, I was here. All
Yes, I was here. All right.
Yes, I was here. All right. So,
Yes, I was here. All right. So, we
Yes, I was here. All right. So, we have
all
all these
Yes, I was here. All right. So, we have
all these uh
all these uh hysteria,
all
all these
all these things
all these things you
all these things you see
all these things you see become
uh
uh like
all these things you see become
uh like mad
uh like mad delusions
all these things you see become
uh like mad delusions and
uh like mad delusions and we've
all these things you see become
uh like mad delusions and we've talked
about
about mass
about mass delusion,
about mass delusion, the
about mass delusion, the madness
about mass delusion, the madness of
crowds.
crowds. Mass
about mass delusion, the madness of
crowds. Mass delusions
crowds. Mass delusions and
about mass delusion, the madness of
crowds. Mass delusions and the
crowds. Mass delusions and the madness
of
of crowds
of crowds is
of crowds is today's
of crowds is today's world.
of crowds is today's world. They
of crowds is today's world. They will
tell
tell you
of crowds is today's world. They will
tell you our
tell you our big
of crowds is today's world. They will
tell you our big problem
tell you our big problem is
of crowds is today's world. They will
tell you our big problem is go
tell you our big problem is go global
warming
warming and
warming and environmentalism
warming and environmentalism and
warming and environmentalism and so
warming and environmentalism and so on.
Lionus
Lionus falling
warming and environmentalism and so on.
Lionus falling figured
Lionus falling figured out
warming and environmentalism and so on.
Lionus falling figured out around
Lionus falling figured out around n
warming and environmentalism and so on.
Lionus falling figured out around n that
the
the maximum
the maximum the
the maximum the most
the maximum the most beneficial
population
uh
uh was
uh was in
uh was in about
uh was in about 1910.
The
The ideal
uh was in about 1910.
The ideal world
The ideal world population
uh was in about 1910.
The ideal world population is
The ideal world population is really
about
about 2.5
about 2.5 billion
about 2.5 billion which
about 2.5 billion which is
about 2.5 billion which is where
about 2.5 billion which is where we
about 2.5 billion which is where we were
at
at around
about 2.5 billion which is where we were
at around 19
at around 19 I
about 2.5 billion which is where we were
at around 19 I forget
at around 19 I forget what
about 2.5 billion which is where we were
at around 19 I forget what year
at around 19 I forget what year it
about 2.5 billion which is where we were
at around 19 I forget what year it was.
So
So what
So what all
So what all these
So what all these isms
So what all these isms and
So what all these isms and all
So what all these isms and all these
problems
problems all
So what all these isms and all these
problems all boil
problems all boil boil
So what all these isms and all these
problems all boil boil down
problems all boil boil down to
So what all these isms and all these
problems all boil boil down to one
problems all boil boil down to one cause
overpopulation.
Why
Why is
overpopulation.
Why is so
Why is so much
overpopulation.
Why is so much stuff
Why is so much stuff in
overpopulation.
Why is so much stuff in the
Why is so much stuff in the air?
overpopulation.
Why is so much stuff in the air? Because
you
you got
you got a
you got a zillion
you got a zillion people
you got a zillion people in
you got a zillion people in South
you got a zillion people in South Asia
over
over China.
you got a zillion people in South Asia
over China. There
over China. There is
you got a zillion people in South Asia
over China. There is a
over China. There is a haze
you got a zillion people in South Asia
over China. There is a haze about
over China. There is a haze about a
you got a zillion people in South Asia
over China. There is a haze about a half
or
or two
or two to
or two to three
or two to three miles
or two to three miles three
or two to three miles three no
or two to three miles three no three
it's
it's three
or two to three miles three no three
it's three miles
it's three miles thick.
or two to three miles three no three
it's three miles thick. A
it's three miles thick. A haze
or two to three miles three no three
it's three miles thick. A haze of
pollution
pollution coming
pollution coming from
pollution coming from the
pollution coming from the cities.
pollution coming from the cities. Why
pollution coming from the cities. Why is
it
it coming
pollution coming from the cities. Why is
it coming from
it coming from the
pollution coming from the cities. Why is
it coming from the cities?
it coming from the cities? Because
pollution coming from the cities. Why is
it coming from the cities? Because of
millions
millions and
millions and millions
millions and millions and
millions and millions and millions
millions and millions and millions and
millions
millions and
millions and millions and millions and
millions and millions
millions and millions of
millions and millions and millions and
millions and millions of people.
millions and millions of people. If
millions and millions and millions and
millions and millions of people. If they
just
just do
just do nothing,
just do nothing, they
just do nothing, they create
just do nothing, they create a
just do nothing, they create a problem.
If
If you
just do nothing, they create a problem.
If you couple
If you couple get
just do nothing, they create a problem.
If you couple get a
If you couple get a couple
just do nothing, they create a problem.
If you couple get a couple billion
people,
people, tell
people, tell them
people, tell them to
people, tell them to sit
people, tell them to sit down
people, tell them to sit down in
people, tell them to sit down in your
chair
chair and
people, tell them to sit down in your
chair and don't
chair and don't do
people, tell them to sit down in your
chair and don't do anything.
They're
They're already
They're already creating
They're already creating a
They're already creating a problem
putting
putting all
They're already creating a problem
putting all that
putting all that carbon
They're already creating a problem
putting all that carbon dioxide
putting all that carbon dioxide out
there.
So
So pro
there.
So pro overpopulation
So pro overpopulation is
there.
So pro overpopulation is the
So pro overpopulation is the primary
problem
of
of all
problem
of all of
of all of the
problem
of all of the problems
of all of the problems of
problem
of all of the problems of society.
of all of the problems of society. The
ideal
ideal world
ideal world population
ideal world population right
ideal world population right now
ideal world population right now would
be
be let's
ideal world population right now would
be let's ask
be let's ask it.
ideal world population right now would
be let's ask it. We
be let's ask it. We have
ideal world population right now would
be let's ask it. We have permission
be let's ask it. We have permission to
ask
ask what
ask what is
ask what is the
ask what is the ideal
ask what is the ideal world
ask what is the ideal world population
right
right now?
ask what is the ideal world population
right now? It's
right now? It's over
ask what is the ideal world population
right now? It's over two
right now? It's over two billion
ask what is the ideal world population
right now? It's over two billion three
billion
2.5
2.5 billion
billion
2.5 billion 2.6
2.5 billion 2.6 billion
billion
2.5 billion 2.6 billion exactly
2.5 billion 2.6 billion exactly at
billion
2.5 billion 2.6 billion exactly at 2.5
billion.
billion. And
billion. And Lannis
billion. And Lannis polling
billion. And Lannis polling was
billion. And Lannis polling was correct.
He
He said
billion. And Lannis polling was correct.
He said the
He said the ideal
billion. And Lannis polling was correct.
He said the ideal world
He said the ideal world population
billion. And Lannis polling was correct.
He said the ideal world population was
He said the ideal world population was 2
and
and a
and a half
and a half billion.
and a half billion. That
and a half billion. That would
and a half billion. That would leave
huge
huge areas
and a half billion. That would leave
huge areas to
huge areas to reforestrate
and a half billion. That would leave
huge areas to reforestrate for
huge areas to reforestrate for nature
etc.
etc. and
etc. and would
etc. and would not
etc. and would not pollute
etc. and would not pollute the
planet
planet planet
etc. and would not pollute the
planet planet the
planet planet the ideal
etc. and would not pollute the
planet planet the ideal population
planet planet the ideal population then
is
is 2.5
is 2.5 billion
is 2.5 billion and
is 2.5 billion and currently
is 2.5 billion and currently we
is 2.5 billion and currently we are
is 2.5 billion and currently we are at
six
six billion.
is 2.5 billion and currently we are at
six billion. So
six billion. So if
is 2.5 billion and currently we are at
six billion. So if 2.5
six billion. So if 2.5 is
is 2.5 billion and currently we are at
six billion. So if 2.5 is ideal
six billion. So if 2.5 is ideal and
we're
we're at
we're at six,
we're at six, then
we're at six, then the
we're at six, then the most
we're at six, then the most of
we're at six, then the most of the
world's
world's problems
we're at six, then the most of the
world's problems are
world's problems are emanating
we're at six, then the most of the
world's problems are emanating from
over
populating.
And
And we
And we know
And we know what
And we know what the
And we know what the cause
And we know what the cause of
overpopulating
overpopulating is.
So,
So, if
So, if you're
So, if you're so
So, if you're so worried
So, if you're so worried about
So, if you're so worried about the
world,
world, I'm
So, if you're so worried about the
world, I'm sure
world, I'm sure you
So, if you're so worried about the
world, I'm sure you won't
world, I'm sure you won't mind
sacrificing
sacrificing the
sacrificing the cause
sacrificing the cause of
sacrificing the cause of the
sacrificing the cause of the world's
overpopulation.
We'll
We'll all
We'll all take
We'll all take a
We'll all take a pledge.
We'll all take a pledge. No
We'll all take a pledge. No more.
We'll all take a pledge. No more. You
know
know what?
For
For the
For the sake
For the sake of
For the sake of environmentalism,
what
what do
For the sake of environmentalism,
what do they
what do they call
For the sake of environmentalism,
what do they call all
what do they call all that
For the sake of environmentalism,
what do they call all that stuff
what do they call all that stuff in
For the sake of environmentalism,
what do they call all that stuff in the
air
air everybody's
air everybody's so
air everybody's so excited
air everybody's so excited about?
air everybody's so excited about? uh
warming,
warming, global
air everybody's so excited about? uh
warming, global warming.
For
For the
For the sake
For the sake of
For the sake of global
For the sake of global warming,
For the sake of global warming, I'm
For the sake of global warming, I'm sure
we're
we're all
For the sake of global warming, I'm sure
we're all each
we're all each willing
For the sake of global warming, I'm sure
we're all each willing to
we're all each willing to make
For the sake of global warming, I'm sure
we're all each willing to make a
we're all each willing to make a certain
sacrifice.
We
We see
sacrifice.
We see because
We see because of
sacrifice.
We see because of these
We see because of these isms,
sacrifice.
We see because of these isms, a
We see because of these isms, a loss
sacrifice.
We see because of these isms, a loss of
credibility.
credibility. You
credibility. You can't
credibility. You can't believe
credibility. You can't believe anybody
anymore.
anymore. Loss
credibility. You can't believe anybody
anymore. Loss of
anymore. Loss of boundaries,
credibility. You can't believe anybody
anymore. Loss of boundaries, anybody
anymore. Loss of boundaries, anybody can
just
just cross
just cross over.
just cross over. You
just cross over. You can
just cross over. You can go
just cross over. You can go on
just cross over. You can go on the
just cross over. You can go on the uh
just cross over. You can go on the uh on
the
the internet
just cross over. You can go on the uh on
the internet or
the internet or whatever
just cross over. You can go on the uh on
the internet or whatever the
the internet or whatever the computer
machine
machine and
machine and you
machine and you can
machine and you can punch
machine and you can punch in
machine and you can punch in anybody's
address
address and
machine and you can punch in anybody's
address and go
address and go there.
machine and you can punch in anybody's
address and go there. They'll
address and go there. They'll show
machine and you can punch in anybody's
address and go there. They'll show you
address and go there. They'll show you a
picture
picture of
picture of how
picture of how to
picture of how to get
picture of how to get there
picture of how to get there and
picture of how to get there and probably
where
where you
picture of how to get there and probably
where you keep
where you keep your
picture of how to get there and probably
where you keep your valuables
where you keep your valuables in
picture of how to get there and probably
where you keep your valuables in the
house.
Go
Go in
house.
Go in through
Go in through this
house.
Go in through this back
Go in through this back window.
house.
Go in through this back window. It's
never
never locked.
never locked. And
never locked. And go
never locked. And go right.
They
They give
never locked. And go right.
They give you
They give you the
never locked. And go right.
They give you the credit
They give you the credit rating
never locked. And go right.
They give you the credit rating who
lives
lives there.
lives there. And
lives there. And so,
lives there. And so, uh,
lives there. And so, uh, forget
lives there. And so, uh, forget about
privacy.
privacy. you
lives there. And so, uh, forget about
privacy. you haven't
privacy. you haven't got
lives there. And so, uh, forget about
privacy. you haven't got any
privacy. you haven't got any and
lives there. And so, uh, forget about
privacy. you haven't got any and the
public
public right
public right to
public right to know
public right to know and
public right to know and the
public right to know and the rights
public right to know and the rights of
the
the media.
public right to know and the rights of
the media. Therefore,
the media. Therefore, you
public right to know and the rights of
the media. Therefore, you have
the media. Therefore, you have no
public right to know and the rights of
the media. Therefore, you have no more
uh
uh legal
uh legal rights
uh legal rights to
uh legal rights to privacy
uh legal rights to privacy anymore.
uh legal rights to privacy anymore. And
the
the people
uh legal rights to privacy anymore. And
the people who
the people who contested
uh legal rights to privacy anymore. And
the people who contested whether
the people who contested whether or
uh legal rights to privacy anymore. And
the people who contested whether or not
their
their house
their house and
their house and where
their house and where they
their house and where they lived
their house and where they lived and
their house and where they lived and how
to
to get
their house and where they lived and how
to get there
to get there down
their house and where they lived and how
to get there down the
to get there down the driveway,
their house and where they lived and how
to get there down the driveway, etc.,
lost
lost the
lost the suit
because
because of
lost the suit
because of the
because of the public's
lost the suit
because of the public's right
because of the public's right to
lost the suit
because of the public's right to know.
Anyway,
Anyway, we
Anyway, we see
Anyway, we see through
Anyway, we see through a
Anyway, we see through a loss
Anyway, we see through a loss of
boundaries,
boundaries, a
Anyway, we see through a loss of
boundaries, a decline
boundaries, a decline of
Anyway, we see through a loss of
boundaries, a decline of efficacy.
boundaries, a decline of efficacy. You
see
see dysfunction,
loss
loss of
see dysfunction,
loss of confidentiality,
loss of confidentiality, loss
see dysfunction,
loss of confidentiality, loss of
privacy.
All right?
All right? You
privacy.
All right? You see
All right? You see through
privacy.
All right? You see through populism,
All right? You see through populism, you
see
see that
see that sedition
see that sedition is
see that sedition is now
see that sedition is now popular.
Sedition,
Sedition, if
see that sedition is now popular.
Sedition, if you
Sedition, if you can
see that sedition is now popular.
Sedition, if you can get
Sedition, if you can get up
see that sedition is now popular.
Sedition, if you can get up there
Sedition, if you can get up there and
hate
hate your
hate your country,
hate your country, the
hate your country, the more
hate your country, the more you
hate your country, the more you hate
hate your country, the more you hate it,
the
the more
hate your country, the more you hate it,
the more superior
the more superior you
hate your country, the more you hate it,
the more superior you are.
You
You can't
You can't just
You can't just say
You can't just say you
You can't just say you hate
You can't just say you hate America.
You can't just say you hate America. You
got
got to
You can't just say you hate America. You
got to really
got to really hate
You can't just say you hate America. You
got to really hate America.
Denounce
Denounce it
Denounce it as
Denounce it as an
Denounce it as an evil
Denounce it as an evil country.
All
All Americans
Denounce it as an evil country.
All Americans are
All Americans are evil.
They
They deserve
They deserve to
They deserve to die.
All
All Americans
They deserve to die.
All Americans deserve
All Americans deserve to
They deserve to die.
All Americans deserve to die.
All Americans deserve to die. Certain
part
part of
part of the
part of the world
part of the world teaches
part of the world teaches that
part of the world teaches that teaches
that
that in
part of the world teaches that teaches
that in their
that in their schools
part of the world teaches that teaches
that in their schools in
that in their schools in the
part of the world teaches that teaches
that in their schools in the United
States
States that
States that all
States that all of
States that all of you
States that all of you deserve
States that all of you deserve to
States that all of you deserve to die.
Teaching
Teaching it
States that all of you deserve to die.
Teaching it in
Teaching it in the
States that all of you deserve to die.
Teaching it in the United
Teaching it in the United States
States that all of you deserve to die.
Teaching it in the United States in
Teaching it in the United States in a
school
school district.
Rates
Rates of
school district.
Rates of the
Rates of the media.
school district.
Rates of the media. Greed
Rates of the media. Greed for
school district.
Rates of the media. Greed for fame
Rates of the media. Greed for fame and
money.
money. Populism.
money. Populism. seditionism.
All right.
All right. So,
money. Populism. seditionism.
All right. So, we've
All right. So, we've handled
money. Populism. seditionism.
All right. So, we've handled rather
important
important things.
important things. We'll
important things. We'll move
important things. We'll move to
important things. We'll move to the
next.
next. Huh.
Uh,
Uh, the
Uh, the New
Uh, the New York
Uh, the New York Times,
Uh, the New York Times, I
Uh, the New York Times, I like
Uh, the New York Times, I like to
Uh, the New York Times, I like to just
document
document some
Uh, the New York Times, I like to just
document some of
document some of these
Uh, the New York Times, I like to just
document some of these things
document some of these things so
Uh, the New York Times, I like to just
document some of these things so they
don't
don't think
don't think that
don't think that I'm
don't think that I'm a
don't think that I'm a raving
don't think that I'm a raving maniac.
The
The New
don't think that I'm a raving maniac.
The New York
The New York Times,
don't think that I'm a raving maniac.
The New York Times, in
The New York Times, in the
don't think that I'm a raving maniac.
The New York Times, in the world
The New York Times, in the world I
don't think that I'm a raving maniac.
The New York Times, in the world I grew
up,
up, you
up, you could
up, you could believe
up, you could believe the
up, you could believe the New
up, you could believe the New York
Times.
Times. And
up, you could believe the New York
Times. And it
Times. And it was
up, you could believe the New York
Times. And it was 403,
right?
right? In
right? In the
right? In the current
right? In the current current
right? In the current current world,
right? In the current current world, the
New
New York
right? In the current current world, the
New York Times
New York Times calibrates
right? In the current current world, the
New York Times calibrates at
New York Times calibrates at 190.
It
It was
It was actually
It was actually a
It was actually a little
It was actually a little lower
It was actually a little lower than
It was actually a little lower than that
before,
before, but
It was actually a little lower than that
before, but it
before, but it came
It was actually a little lower than that
before, but it came up.
before, but it came up. It
It was actually a little lower than that
before, but it came up. It doesn't
before, but it came up. It doesn't feel
guilty
guilty about
guilty about what
guilty about what it
guilty about what it does.
People
People climb
guilty about what it does.
People climb climb
People climb climb over
guilty about what it does.
People climb climb over it.
People climb climb over it. I
guilty about what it does.
People climb climb over it. I always
People climb climb over it. I always get
a
a kick
a kick out
a kick out of
a kick out of those.
a kick out of those. They're
a kick out of those. They're always
Frenchmen,
Frenchmen, skinny
a kick out of those. They're always
Frenchmen, skinny guys,
Frenchmen, skinny guys, and
a kick out of those. They're always
Frenchmen, skinny guys, and they
Frenchmen, skinny guys, and they climb
51 stories
51 stories up
51 stories up the
51 stories up the New
51 stories up the New York
51 stories up the New York Times.
New
New York
51 stories up the New York Times.
New York Times
New York Times now
51 stories up the New York Times.
New York Times now was
New York Times now was 403,
now
now 190.
now 190. Just
now 190. Just the
now 190. Just the implication
now 190. Just the implication of
now 190. Just the implication of that,
the
the most
now 190. Just the implication of that,
the most respectable
uh
uh newspaper
uh newspaper in
uh newspaper in the
uh newspaper in the United
uh newspaper in the United States,
actually
actually the
uh newspaper in the United States,
actually the Wall
actually the Wall Street
uh newspaper in the United States,
actually the Wall Street Journal
actually the Wall Street Journal is
uh newspaper in the United States,
actually the Wall Street Journal is is
calorie
calorie is
calorie is still
calorie is still high.
calorie is still high. Anyway,
calorie is still high. Anyway, the
calorie is still high. Anyway, the New
York
York Times,
calorie is still high. Anyway, the New
York Times, I
York Times, I I
calorie is still high. Anyway, the New
York Times, I I wouldn't
York Times, I I wouldn't think
calorie is still high. Anyway, the New
York Times, I I wouldn't think I'd
York Times, I I wouldn't think I'd live
long
long enough
long enough that
long enough that you
long enough that you can't
long enough that you can't believe
long enough that you can't believe what
you
you read
long enough that you can't believe what
you read in
you read in the
long enough that you can't believe what
you read in the New
you read in the New York
long enough that you can't believe what
you read in the New York Times.
you read in the New York Times. It
doesn't
doesn't seem
doesn't seem even
doesn't seem even believable.
doesn't seem even believable. Everybody
got
got up
doesn't seem even believable. Everybody
got up and
got up and read
doesn't seem even believable. Everybody
got up and read the
got up and read the New
doesn't seem even believable. Everybody
got up and read the New York
got up and read the New York Times,
especially
especially on
especially on Sunday.
especially on Sunday. New
especially on Sunday. New York
especially on Sunday. New York Times
weighed
weighed about
especially on Sunday. New York Times
weighed about five
weighed about five pounds
especially on Sunday. New York Times
weighed about five pounds and
weighed about five pounds and that
especially on Sunday. New York Times
weighed about five pounds and that took
care
care of
care of your
care of your whole
care of your whole Sunday
care of your whole Sunday morning.
The
The internet
care of your whole Sunday morning.
The internet right
The internet right now
care of your whole Sunday morning.
The internet right now is
The internet right now is doing
care of your whole Sunday morning.
The internet right now is doing better
than
than it
than it was.
than it was. The
than it was. The internet
than it was. The internet is
than it was. The internet is now
than it was. The internet is now up
than it was. The internet is now up to
200.
200. The
than it was. The internet is now up to
200. The internet
200. The internet was
than it was. The internet is now up to
200. The internet was down
200. The internet was down below
than it was. The internet is now up to
200. The internet was down below 200
200. The internet was down below 200 has
now
now come
now come back
now come back up.
now come back up. My
now come back up. My face
now come back up. My face NBC
now come back up. My face NBC I
now come back up. My face NBC I say
now come back up. My face NBC I say what
are
are these
now come back up. My face NBC I say what
are these thing?
are these thing? NBC
now come back up. My face NBC I say what
are these thing? NBC news
are these thing? NBC news is
now come back up. My face NBC I say what
are these thing? NBC news is 190.
are these thing? NBC news is 190. Fox
News
News is
News is 300.
News is 300. I
News is 300. I don't
News is 300. I don't know
News is 300. I don't know how
News is 300. I don't know how they
News is 300. I don't know how they why
they're
they're so
News is 300. I don't know how they why
they're so different.
they're so different. Hollywood
News is 300. I don't know how they why
they're so different. Hollywood in
they're so different. Hollywood in back
in
in the
in the 50s
in the 50s was
in the 50s was 375.
Uh,
Uh, who
in the 50s was 375.
Uh, who can
Uh, who can you
in the 50s was 375.
Uh, who can you believe?
Uh, who can you believe? Well,
in the 50s was 375.
Uh, who can you believe? Well, Bill
O'Reilly,
O'Reilly, who's
O'Reilly, who's a
O'Reilly, who's a I
O'Reilly, who's a I put
O'Reilly, who's a I put him
O'Reilly, who's a I put him up
O'Reilly, who's a I put him up because
he's
he's such
O'Reilly, who's a I put him up because
he's such a
he's such a moralist.
O'Reilly, who's a I put him up because
he's such a moralist. He's
he's such a moralist. He's 355.
And
And a
And a fellow
And a fellow moralist
And a fellow moralist is
And a fellow moralist is Glenn
And a fellow moralist is Glenn Beck.
And a fellow moralist is Glenn Beck. So,
here
here we
And a fellow moralist is Glenn Beck. So,
here we see
a
a lamenting
a lamenting that
a lamenting that the
a lamenting that the moral
a lamenting that the moral backbone
a lamenting that the moral backbone of
society
uh
uh is
uh is disintegrating.
uh is disintegrating. And
uh is disintegrating. And this
uh is disintegrating. And this is
uh is disintegrating. And this is the
main
main theme
uh is disintegrating. And this is the
main theme that
main theme that they
uh is disintegrating. And this is the
main theme that they so
main theme that they so that
uh is disintegrating. And this is the
main theme that they so that that
main theme that they so that that this
decline
decline Hollywood
decline Hollywood was
decline Hollywood was 375.
It's
It's now
decline Hollywood was 375.
It's now 185.
Uh,
Uh, who
Uh, who brings
Uh, who brings it
Uh, who brings it to
Uh, who brings it to our
Uh, who brings it to our attention?
Uh, who brings it to our attention? Uh,
these
these are
Uh, who brings it to our attention? Uh,
these are the
these are the social
Uh, who brings it to our attention? Uh,
these are the social commentators
these are the social commentators that
are
are probably
are probably the
are probably the best
are probably the best known,
are probably the best known, Fox
are probably the best known, Fox News
and
and and
are probably the best known, Fox News
and and all
and and all these.
are probably the best known, Fox News
and and all these. You
and and all these. You see,
are probably the best known, Fox News
and and all these. You see, NBC
and and all these. You see, NBC News
are probably the best known, Fox News
and and all these. You see, NBC News is
off
off the
off the rail
off the rail uh
off the rail uh and
off the rail uh and has
off the rail uh and has been
off the rail uh and has been for
off the rail uh and has been for some
time.
time. So,
off the rail uh and has been for some
time. So, things
time. So, things that
off the rail uh and has been for some
time. So, things that we
time. So, things that we traditionally
place
place faith
place faith in,
place faith in, if
place faith in, if you
place faith in, if you don't
place faith in, if you don't calibrate
them,
them, you
place faith in, if you don't calibrate
them, you don't
them, you don't know
place faith in, if you don't calibrate
them, you don't know that
them, you don't know that you're
place faith in, if you don't calibrate
them, you don't know that you're being
uh
uh hoodwinkedked.
uh hoodwinkedked. So,
uh hoodwinkedked. So, I
uh hoodwinkedked. So, I check
uh hoodwinkedked. So, I check on
uh hoodwinkedked. So, I check on these
jokers.
jokers. A
uh hoodwinkedked. So, I check on these
jokers. A rally
jokers. A rally gets
uh hoodwinkedked. So, I check on these
jokers. A rally gets too
jokers. A rally gets too moralistic.
uh hoodwinkedked. So, I check on these
jokers. A rally gets too moralistic. He
gets
gets carried
gets carried away,
gets carried away, you
gets carried away, you know,
gets carried away, you know, carried
away
away with
gets carried away, you know, carried
away with the
away with the indignity
gets carried away, you know, carried
away with the indignity about
away with the indignity about it
gets carried away, you know, carried
away with the indignity about it all,
but
but at least
but at least somebody
but at least somebody does.
So
So that's
but at least somebody does.
So that's his
So that's his job.
but at least somebody does.
So that's his job. I
So that's his job. I send
but at least somebody does.
So that's his job. I send him,
So that's his job. I send him, you're
getting
getting indignant,
getting indignant, but
getting indignant, but not
getting indignant, but not indignant
enough.
And
And Glenn
And Glenn Beck
And Glenn Beck joins
And Glenn Beck joins the
And Glenn Beck joins the parade,
And Glenn Beck joins the parade, too.
So
So you
And Glenn Beck joins the parade, too.
So you have
So you have social
And Glenn Beck joins the parade, too.
So you have social commentators
So you have social commentators with
And Glenn Beck joins the parade, too.
So you have social commentators with the
conscience.
conscience. And
conscience. And in
conscience. And in the
conscience. And in the old
conscience. And in the old days,
conscience. And in the old days, that
was
was true.
conscience. And in the old days, that
was true. True.
was true. True. In
conscience. And in the old days, that
was true. True. In the
was true. True. In the world
conscience. And in the old days, that
was true. True. In the world I
was true. True. In the world I grew
conscience. And in the old days, that
was true. True. In the world I grew up,
there
there was
there was the
there was the Hollywood
there was the Hollywood columnists
there was the Hollywood columnists and
they
they would
there was the Hollywood columnists and
they would get
they would get on
there was the Hollywood columnists and
they would get on the
Mr.
Mr. and
Mr. and Miss
Mr. and Miss America
Mr. and Miss America and
Mr. and Miss America and all
Mr. and Miss America and all the
Mr. and Miss America and all the ships
at
at sea.
Mr. and Miss America and all the ships
at sea. Who
at sea. Who was
Mr. and Miss America and all the ships
at sea. Who was that?
at sea. Who was that? There
Mr. and Miss America and all the ships
at sea. Who was that? There was
at sea. Who was that? There was give
Mr. and Miss America and all the ships
at sea. Who was that? There was give you
the
the latest
the latest Walder
the latest Walder Winchell
the latest Walder Winchell give
the latest Walder Winchell give you
the latest Walder Winchell give you the
latest
latest gossip
the latest Walder Winchell give you the
latest gossip from
latest gossip from Hollywood,
the latest Walder Winchell give you the
latest gossip from Hollywood, etc.
latest gossip from Hollywood, etc. So,
Walder
Walder Winchell
Walder Winchell is
Walder Winchell is not
Walder Winchell is not around
Walder Winchell is not around anymore.
So,
So, yeah,
Walder Winchell is not around anymore.
So, yeah, this
So, yeah, this is
Walder Winchell is not around anymore.
So, yeah, this is all
So, yeah, this is all we
Walder Winchell is not around anymore.
So, yeah, this is all we got
So, yeah, this is all we got to
Walder Winchell is not around anymore.
So, yeah, this is all we got to try
So, yeah, this is all we got to try and
find
find out.
find out. Keep
find out. Keep an
find out. Keep an eye
find out. Keep an eye on
find out. Keep an eye on what's
happening.
happening. Okay,
find out. Keep an eye on what's
happening. Okay, let's
happening. Okay, let's go
find out. Keep an eye on what's
happening. Okay, let's go on
happening. Okay, let's go on next.
find out. Keep an eye on what's
happening. Okay, let's go on next. Keep
an
an eye
an eye on
an eye on what's
an eye on what's Oh,
an eye on what's Oh, yeah.
an eye on what's Oh, yeah. So
an eye on what's Oh, yeah. So I'm
looking
looking who
an eye on what's Oh, yeah. So I'm
looking who who
looking who who who
an eye on what's Oh, yeah. So I'm
looking who who who can
looking who who who can you
an eye on what's Oh, yeah. So I'm
looking who who who can you give
looking who who who can you give some
kind
kind of
kind of degree
kind of degree of
kind of degree of credibility
kind of degree of credibility and
kind of degree of credibility and how
much
much credibility?
kind of degree of credibility and how
much credibility? Well,
much credibility? Well, it
kind of degree of credibility and how
much credibility? Well, it seems
much credibility? Well, it seems about
the
the highest
the highest degree
the highest degree of
the highest degree of credibility
the highest degree of credibility you
can
can get
the highest degree of credibility you
can get in
can get in today's
the highest degree of credibility you
can get in today's world.
can get in today's world. Uh
the highest degree of credibility you
can get in today's world. Uh Neil
Kavuto,
Kavuto, uh
Kavuto, uh Charles
Kavuto, uh Charles Crowhammer,
Kavuto, uh Charles Crowhammer, they're
all
all in
Kavuto, uh Charles Crowhammer, they're
all in the
all in the high
Kavuto, uh Charles Crowhammer, they're
all in the high 300s.
all in the high 300s. Nuke
Kavuto, uh Charles Crowhammer, they're
all in the high 300s. Nuke Gingrich,
all in the high 300s. Nuke Gingrich, his
viewpoint,
viewpoint, I'm
viewpoint, I'm not
viewpoint, I'm not talking
viewpoint, I'm not talking about
viewpoint, I'm not talking about N
himself,
himself, but
viewpoint, I'm not talking about N
himself, but his
himself, but his viewpoint
viewpoint, I'm not talking about N
himself, but his viewpoint just
himself, but his viewpoint just as
viewpoint, I'm not talking about N
himself, but his viewpoint just as these
people
people is
people is their
people is their viewpoint
people is their viewpoint I'm
people is their viewpoint I'm talking
about
about is
people is their viewpoint I'm talking
about is around
about is around 400.
people is their viewpoint I'm talking
about is around 400. So
about is around 400. So I
people is their viewpoint I'm talking
about is around 400. So I pay
about is around 400. So I pay attention
to
to N's
to N's analysis
to N's analysis of
to N's analysis of the
to N's analysis of the news
to N's analysis of the news because
to N's analysis of the news because it
seems
seems to
to N's analysis of the news because it
seems to be
seems to be relatively
to N's analysis of the news because it
seems to be relatively intelligent.
A
A demagogue
A demagogue calibrates
A demagogue calibrates 180.
A demagogue calibrates 180. And
A demagogue calibrates 180. And our
world
world now
A demagogue calibrates 180. And our
world now is
world now is full
A demagogue calibrates 180. And our
world now is full of
world now is full of demagogues.
A demagogue calibrates 180. And our
world now is full of demagogues. They've
got
got all
got all kinds
got all kinds of
got all kinds of flashy
got all kinds of flashy presentations
and
and they
got all kinds of flashy presentations
and they like
and they like to
got all kinds of flashy presentations
and they like to play
and they like to play one
got all kinds of flashy presentations
and they like to play one race
and they like to play one race against
another,
another, one
another, one sex
another, one sex against
another, one sex against another
another, one sex against another and
squeeze
squeeze everything
another, one sex against another and
squeeze everything they
squeeze everything they can
another, one sex against another and
squeeze everything they can out
squeeze everything they can out of
another, one sex against another and
squeeze everything they can out of it.
Those
Those are
Those are demagogues.
The
The US
Those are demagogues.
The US Senate
The US Senate currently
Those are demagogues.
The US Senate currently calibrates
The US Senate currently calibrates at
190.
The
The US
190.
The US Congress
The US Congress 200.
Let's
Let's see
Let's see if
Let's see if that's
Let's see if that's so
we
we have
Let's see if that's so
we have permission
we have permission to
Let's see if that's so
we have permission to do
we have permission to do with
Let's see if that's so
we have permission to do with the
we have permission to do with the US
Senate.
Senate. It
Senate. It calibrates
Senate. It calibrates at
Senate. It calibrates at 190.
Calibrates
Calibrates over
Senate. It calibrates at 190.
Calibrates over 190.
Calibrates over 190. Is
Senate. It calibrates at 190.
Calibrates over 190. Is it
the
the US
the US Congress
calibrates
calibrates at
the US Congress
calibrates at 200
over
over 200
you
you see?
over 200
you see? Therefore,
you see? Therefore, you
over 200
you see? Therefore, you remember
you see? Therefore, you remember the
fall
fall and
fall and decline
fall and decline of
fall and decline of the
fall and decline of the Roman
fall and decline of the Roman Empire,
the
the fallen
fall and decline of the Roman Empire,
the fallen decline
the fallen decline of
fall and decline of the Roman Empire,
the fallen decline of the
the fallen decline of the Roman
fall and decline of the Roman Empire,
the fallen decline of the Roman Empire,
uh
uh from
uh from the,
uh from the, you
uh from the, you know,
uh from the, you know, the
uh from the, you know, the Senate.
You
You see
uh from the, you know, the Senate.
You see the
You see the Senate
uh from the, you know, the Senate.
You see the Senate de
You see the Senate de climb
uh from the, you know, the Senate.
You see the Senate de climb between
You see the Senate de climb between 200.
We're
We're recapitulating
We're recapitulating the
We're recapitulating the history
We're recapitulating the history of
Rome,
Rome, are
We're recapitulating the history of
Rome, are we
Rome, are we not?
You
You think
You think you
You think you can
prevent
prevent the
You think you can
prevent the freef
prevent the freef fall
You think you can
prevent the freef fall by
prevent the freef fall by going
You think you can
prevent the freef fall by going out
prevent the freef fall by going out the
con
con the
con the limits
con the limits of
con the limits of the
con the limits of the continental
con the limits of the continental United
States
States that
con the limits of the continental United
States that say
States that say well
con the limits of the continental United
States that say well that
States that say well that may
con the limits of the continental United
States that say well that may be
States that say well that may be the
con the limits of the continental United
States that say well that may be the US.
I'll
I'll tell
I'll tell you
I'll tell you I
I'll tell you I I
I'll tell you I I would
I'll tell you I I would I'd
I'll tell you I I would I'd be
I'll tell you I I would I'd be ashamed
to
to put
I'll tell you I I would I'd be ashamed
to put up
to put up the
I'll tell you I I would I'd be ashamed
to put up the equivalent
to put up the equivalent in
I'll tell you I I would I'd be ashamed
to put up the equivalent in other
countries
countries they're
countries they're so
countries they're so low
countries they're so low that
countries they're so low that we
countries they're so low that we I'm
sure
sure get
countries they're so low that we I'm
sure get attacked
sure get attacked for
countries they're so low that we I'm
sure get attacked for saying
sure get attacked for saying it.
countries they're so low that we I'm
sure get attacked for saying it. The
United
United Nations
United Nations itself
United Nations itself calibrates
United Nations itself calibrates at
United Nations itself calibrates at 180.
So
in
in order
in order to
in order to know
in order to know the
in order to know the truth
in order to know the truth about
in order to know the truth about things,
you
you got
in order to know the truth about things,
you got to
you got to know
in order to know the truth about things,
you got to know what
you got to know what is
in order to know the truth about things,
you got to know what is the
you got to know what is the society
in order to know the truth about things,
you got to know what is the society that
we
we live
we live in.
we live in. That's
we live in. That's why
we live in. That's why I
we live in. That's why I show
we live in. That's why I show the
we live in. That's why I show the sheep
with
with a
we live in. That's why I show the sheep
with a wolf
with a wolf inside.
Oh,
Oh, the
Oh, the UN's
Oh, the UN's going
Oh, the UN's going to
Oh, the UN's going to solve
Oh, the UN's going to solve it.
Oh, the UN's going to solve it. The
Oh, the UN's going to solve it. The UN
can't
can't even
Oh, the UN's going to solve it. The UN
can't even pay
can't even pay their
Oh, the UN's going to solve it. The UN
can't even pay their own
can't even pay their own rent.
They
They can't
They can't pay
They can't pay their
They can't pay their own
They can't pay their own rent.
They
They can't
They can't pay their own rent.
They can't maintain
They can't maintain their
They can't pay their own rent.
They can't maintain their own
They can't maintain their own building.
They're
They're going
They're going to
They're going to tear
They're going to tear it
They're going to tear it down
They're going to tear it down and
They're going to tear it down and for
a
a zillion
They're going to tear it down and for
a zillion trillion
a zillion trillion dollars
They're going to tear it down and for
a zillion trillion dollars going
a zillion trillion dollars going to
build
build a
build a whole
build a whole UN
build a whole UN which
build a whole UN which will
build a whole UN which will also
calibrate
calibrate at
build a whole UN which will also
calibrate at 180
calibrate at 180 and
build a whole UN which will also
calibrate at 180 and which
calibrate at 180 and which will
build a whole UN which will also
calibrate at 180 and which will also
calibrate at 180 and which will also do
nothing.
Do
Do I
nothing.
Do I sound
Do I sound pessimistic?
No.
No. I'm
No. I'm realistic
because
because what
No. I'm realistic
because what has
because what has that
No. I'm realistic
because what has that got
because what has that got to
No. I'm realistic
because what has that got to do
because what has that got to do with
No. I'm realistic
because what has that got to do with us?
Nothing.
What
What do
Nothing.
What do I
What do I care
Nothing.
What do I care about
What do I care about all
Nothing.
What do I care about all that?
What do I care about all that? nothing,
right?
right? What's
right? What's it
right? What's it got
right? What's it got to
right? What's it got to do
right? What's it got to do with
right? What's it got to do with your
your
your inner
right? What's it got to do with your
your inner integrity
your inner integrity and
right? What's it got to do with your
your inner integrity and your
relationship
relationship with
relationship with God?
relationship with God? Yeah.
relationship with God? Yeah. As
relationship with God? Yeah. As a
spiritual
spiritual teacher,
relationship with God? Yeah. As a
spiritual teacher, then
spiritual teacher, then I
relationship with God? Yeah. As a
spiritual teacher, then I feel
spiritual teacher, then I feel that
relationship with God? Yeah. As a
spiritual teacher, then I feel that I
should
should try
should try to
should try to reveal
should try to reveal the
should try to reveal the effect
should try to reveal the effect of
should try to reveal the effect of the
world
world that
should try to reveal the effect of the
world that we
world that we live
should try to reveal the effect of the
world that we live in
world that we live in by
should try to reveal the effect of the
world that we live in by using
world that we live in by using something
objective
objective to
objective to just
objective to just calibrate
objective to just calibrate it.
objective to just calibrate it. So,
objective to just calibrate it. So, I'm
not
not telling
objective to just calibrate it. So, I'm
not telling you
not telling you you
objective to just calibrate it. So, I'm
not telling you you should
not telling you you should curl
objective to just calibrate it. So, I'm
not telling you you should curl up
not telling you you should curl up in
objective to just calibrate it. So, I'm
not telling you you should curl up in a
paranoid
paranoid box.
Well,
Well, there's
paranoid box.
Well, there's religious
Well, there's religious traditions
paranoid box.
Well, there's religious traditions that
the
the only
the only way
the only way you
the only way you can
the only way you can reach
the only way you can reach the
the only way you can reach the state
the only way you can reach the state of
enlightenment
enlightenment or
the only way you can reach the state of
enlightenment or reach
enlightenment or reach God
the only way you can reach the state of
enlightenment or reach God is
enlightenment or reach God is to
withdraw
withdraw from
withdraw from that
withdraw from that evil
withdraw from that evil society,
withdraw from that evil society, join
withdraw from that evil society, join a
monastery,
monastery, close
withdraw from that evil society, join a
monastery, close the
monastery, close the gates,
become
become celibate,
join
join the
become celibate,
join the other
join the other monks
become celibate,
join the other monks and
join the other monks and weed
become celibate,
join the other monks and weed turnipss
all
all day.
that
that appeal
all day.
that appeal to
that appeal to anyone?
No.
No. Most
No. Most of
No. Most of us
don't
don't have
No. Most of us
don't have any
don't have any choice.
No. Most of us
don't have any choice. We
don't have any choice. We live
No. Most of us
don't have any choice. We live in
don't have any choice. We live in the
world
world in
world in which
world in which we
uh
uh apply
world in which we
uh apply spiritual
uh apply spiritual teachings
world in which we
uh apply spiritual teachings and
principles
principles to
principles to our
principles to our own
principles to our own life.
principles to our own life. So
principles to our own life. So how
principles to our own life. So how do
principles to our own life. So how do we
live
live in
principles to our own life. So how do we
live in the
live in the world
principles to our own life. So how do we
live in the world we've
live in the world we've just
principles to our own life. So how do we
live in the world we've just depicted?
Jesus
Jesus Christ
Jesus Christ said,
Jesus Christ said, "You
Jesus Christ said, "You wear
Jesus Christ said, "You wear the
Jesus Christ said, "You wear the world
like
like a
Jesus Christ said, "You wear the world
like a light
like a light garment."
So
So when
So when you
So when you feel
So when you feel discouraged
So when you feel discouraged or
So when you feel discouraged or forloren
about
about and
So when you feel discouraged or forloren
about and and
about and and woeful
So when you feel discouraged or forloren
about and and woeful about
about and and woeful about the
So when you feel discouraged or forloren
about and and woeful about the condition
of
of the
of the world,
of the world, Jesus
of the world, Jesus Christ
of the world, Jesus Christ said
of the world, Jesus Christ said the
of the world, Jesus Christ said the same
thing.
thing. He
of the world, Jesus Christ said the same
thing. He just
thing. He just said,
of the world, Jesus Christ said the same
thing. He just said, "Wear
thing. He just said, "Wear the
of the world, Jesus Christ said the same
thing. He just said, "Wear the world
like
like a
like a light
like a light garment.
like a light garment. Know
like a light garment. Know what
like a light garment. Know what it
like a light garment. Know what it is,
see
see what
like a light garment. Know what it is,
see what it
see what it is,
like a light garment. Know what it is,
see what it is, and
see what it is, and wear
like a light garment. Know what it is,
see what it is, and wear it
see what it is, and wear it lightly,
like a light garment. Know what it is,
see what it is, and wear it lightly, and
don't
don't let
don't let it
don't let it get
don't let it get to
don't let it get to you
don't let it get to you and
don't let it get to you and ruin
don't let it get to you and ruin your
dinner."
Shall
Shall we
Shall we take
Shall we take a
Shall we take a break?
>> What?
>> About
>> About three
>> About three more
>> About three more minutes.
>> About three more minutes. Three
>> About three more minutes. Three more
minutes.
Uh,
Uh, let's
Uh, let's be
Uh, let's be good
Uh, let's be good to
Uh, let's be good to oursel.
Uh, let's be good to oursel. Let's
Uh, let's be good to oursel. Let's give
oursel
oursel another
Uh, let's be good to oursel. Let's give
oursel another three
oursel another three minutes.
Do
Do you
Do you deserve
Do you deserve three
Do you deserve three minutes?
>> Do
>> Do you
Do you deserve three minutes?
>> Do you deserve
>> Do you deserve three
Do you deserve three minutes?
>> Do you deserve three minutes?
>> Do you deserve three minutes? Oh,
Do you deserve three minutes?
>> Do you deserve three minutes? Oh, we
love
love oursel.
We
We all
love oursel.
We all deserve
We all deserve three
love oursel.
We all deserve three minutes.
We all deserve three minutes. God
love oursel.
We all deserve three minutes. God bless
us.
us. Three
us. Three more
us. Three more minutes.
us. Three more minutes. Amen.