gung-ho spiritual elixir all right we will resume glad to see you all back
and those of you who tried to sneak out we took you down your names
i want to do one the guy i'm holding in mind calibrates over 440 450 450 even calibrates
about 450. okay joe the plumber that beats 170. all right what honey no i'm sent okay
all right today we're talking about practical spirituality so we're going to go
to the charts for today uh which will appear right here i had one more chart to do on the last run
okay let's see the last one i'm sorry spiritual practices
oh yeah
yeah spiritual practices uh well those were somewhat familiar with we've talked about
them all in all these all of these things calibrate very high in other words what really
gives them all the power they have is your intention the intention so it isn't just the sound
it isn't just the sound but the intention behind it the same with all the functions
of
churches baptism and various things is that there are all devotional acts and by their intention
they're by their intention then so gregorian chants of course are beautiful in and of
themselves and to be in one of the giant cathedrals in europe and here uh acquire in
the background practicing the gregorian chance i mean it's just incredible experience you almost
fall over uh so all the kneeling to pray the lord's prayer so if you do nothing at all then
just do the lord's prayer you see that calibrates at 650 reaffirms spiritual reality
and the lord's prayer will do if you can't think of anything else
and if you really uh can't think of anything at all you can go oh let's see
you want
again yeah that calibrates over 740 750 740. let's all do an om for fun
so the donor just lifted off the earth a little bit right so let's see spiritual practices and
yeah we pointed out that there's a book by a well-known spiritual teacher which
suggests you go aum and we see that only calibrates at 210. that was by sachin ananda i
think
uh an error in one of his books in which he said he recommended aom
two syllables om is one syllable so one syllable om ok surrender the world to god so we'll be
talking about these things now today really surrendering the world to god in other words
the election is going to go the way it's uh going and we'll all survive
walking the labyrinth which you can now do in sedona you know the labyrinth is
Outside of St. Andrew's Episcopal Church.
In the parking lot of St. Andrew's Church is a reproduction of the labyrinth.
And walking the labyrinth is itself over 503.
So walking the labyrinth itself has a mystical energy.
Don't ask me why.
I couldn't tell you.
I don't care why.
It just does.
I think the basic intention.
But those of you who, the effect is the same.
If you trace the labyrinth with a pencil, you have a picture of the labyrinth and you trace it.
It has the same effect as though you walk it.
Let's see if that's true.
To trace it has the same effect as walking it.
Resist.
Wow.
So you don't have to get out there in bad weather.
How did we get that made?
We had the labyrinth made into a.
Okay.
Anyway, we had it made and I don't know how we did that.
Oh, Grace Cathedral in San Francisco has the labyrinth printed.
Because we were going to get it printed onto a medallion and we found the cost was so prohibitive.
And then we found out that you can actually get them.
Grace Cathedral in San Francisco.
I think that's Episcopal Cathedral, the one with the huge organ.
I've been there a number of times when I used to go to San Francisco.
Whenever I traveled, I was.
I always went from cathedral to cathedral.
So to me, San Francisco means to go to that cathedral.
To go to London means.
So to me, the great cities of the world, which I've traveled a couple of times.
I always just went from cathedral to the cathedral, you know, from Sharts to whatever the cathedral was.
And we stayed near the German border.
What was that cathedral?
They had all the little shops, right?
Here was the shops.
And here was the cathedral.
Strasbourg.
Strasbourg, yeah.
Each of those great, great cathedrals.
So it isn't just walking the labyrinth and visiting the cathedral, but the intention behind it.
The intention to become closer to God, to be more conscious and aware of the divine energy.
All right.
So we've spoken of these before, and therefore we won't go through them again.
But for a practical value.
To many people in the audience, is the 12 steps of Alcoholics Anonymous.
So many people are attracted to spiritual work via the 12 step movement.
And the 12 step movement itself calibrates 540.
And Bill Wilson's experience when the room lit up, calibrates extremely high.
I forget what it calibrated at now.
And where the room lit up.
Tell me what the experience was like.
What was the experience like?
Can you describe it?
Because Susan had the same experience.
Oh, here.
You've got this here.
Give me a minute.
Oh, give me a minute.
What next?
Start with a minute.
Then they want a half hour or an hour.
Then they want your life all the time.
What he's referring to is I had a very high experience right after Dave and I got together.
And it happened to me.
And it happened to me as right in the dawn, right about 5 o'clock in the morning,
just as you're awakening.
And a lot of spiritual experiences since I had mine, I've checked with other people
and they said that it happens just as you're going off to sleep or just as you're coming awake.
And that's when it usually you're awake enough to think, is this a dream or is this really happening?
And that was my experience.
And this light changing, life changing force of energy came through the corner of the wall.
Just came in the corner.
There wasn't a window there.
There was a corner.
And this light force came in through the corner and it lit up the whole room.
And it was a brilliant light as though brighter than looking at the sun.
And it had an energy behind the light.
Yes.
And the light energy force then went through me, just came through me.
And that's when Dave and I started to do the work.
So, you know, everybody asks us, you know, what propelled you to do the work?
And that's when I knew we had to go out and share this with everyone.
Because that was, it was almost like the light, like this light changed
everything that we had my whole life.
And people that are in AA,
they've experienced the same thing where all of a sudden this brilliant,
life changing event happens and they know that God is within you.
That's the way Bill Wilson explained it too.
I knew Bill and he explained it exactly the same way.
Ebby or somebody tried to bring the message to him.
Bill was an atheist.
And now his problem was he would never recover unless you could accept God.
And he was an atheist.
So anyway, Bill was presented with this dilemma and he was a hopeless, hopeless
case and and he contemplated the message and the message had really come because
Carl Jung, the great psychoanalyst was so honest that he told Roland,
I cannot help you, but from time to time throughout history,
it has occurred that a spiritual transformation,
people have recovered from this grave and incurable progressive disease.
And so Bill was looking at this dilemma.
Here he is, a profound atheist.
These are going to die a death of agony and a wet brain and convulsions.
Somebody put away is that unless you believe in God and he was an atheist,
it was a dilemma and then the same identical experience.
I remember Bill talking about it.
He says suddenly the room lit up.
Every corner of the room was illuminated by this brilliant, profound light,
a light that's even beyond light.
It's like the energy out of which light occurs.
The presence of God as light.
And Bill was trying.
He transformed.
And of course, millions of people have benefited from that transformative experience.
And Bill himself was profoundly transformed.
So that energy radiates out into the world.
And the and I think the last book I did, we calibrated the impact of various
religions and various things upon human society, American society.
And of all of them,
the 12 step group calibrated the highest as the most profound positive impact on all of society.
Why is that?
It's because it's living with simplicity and honesty
one day at a time.
And it's a caringness for others, caringness for others.
So we'll talk about practical spirituality because you see the transformation that it had with her.
She didn't expect it at all.
I don't think I'd ever even heard of such thing.
And it triggered our beginning to speak in public at all because of her transformation.
She said, you know, we have to share this with the world.
And I said, well, I don't think anybody out there is interested in this.
She said
Huang Po was not everybody's bedtime reading, you know, so I understood Huang Po.
But anyway, so because of that, we began to speak around and then we got invited to churches
all over the country and we went to the Far East and we traveled all over the from Mexico to Korea
a number of times and people came from around the world to hear it.
And so that's how it got launched through that same light.
So the light that lit up Bill is the room is the same light that you and I
experienced as a transformation in the pits of hell.
All right. So we'll go to practical spirituality,
get a hopeless disease and give up on it.
Give up on it.
All right. Oh, I can look at this.
I can read it now. Look at this.
Wow.
That's pretty good.
Yes, yes. Stay with Holy Company.
Holy Catfish is General Motors, the Holy Company.
No, no.
Stay with Holy Company.
And people in spiritual groups have learned that over the decades,
that there is a benefit, there is a energy to the group
such as a group such as this has a very powerful energy.
What you do with my slide?
Give me back my slide.
OK, stay with Holy Company.
Why? Because the the group itself radiates an energy.
That energizes spiritual awareness within yourself to just be near it or around it.
And people who are hopeless and they say they can't get it.
You tell them it doesn't make any difference whether you get it or you don't get it.
You just go to meetings and sit in the back and shut up.
And if you can't sit up, you lay on the floor in the back
and people who couldn't get it and were
giving up his hope was laid on the floor in the back of the room and went to meetings.
He's just laying on the floor and got sober instantly hit by the light.
They went sober. OK.
So to be aligned with the spiritual group is very profound.
And all the people in the 12 step groups have learned that people in A Course
in Miracles, people who are truly religion, religious in the in the essence of religion
stay with Holy Company.
It has an energy field effect.
And
the real relapse experience of AA is when a person says, I don't need AA anymore
and they quit going to meetings, the relapse rate is extremely high.
And, you know, I mean, they still don't know what they knew.
They've still learned the program.
And yet when they say I can do it on my own, that the relapse rate is extremely high.
So when a person disappears from a 12 step
groups meeting, you know that what's happening, whether it's Al-Anon or AA or
whatever it is,
it's about to relapse into their old behavior because it's saying, I can do it
on my own, I don't need you anymore.
So that's the impersonal energy field effect.
It's not personal.
And that's the relapse experience of AA and of all the 12 step groups.
There's a certain bonding that goes on.
You see that in the famous Band of Brothers.
The bonding that goes on in the military is the same.
The bonding is profound and timeless.
I was just going to say every night before bed, I say prayers
and I always pray for the crew of the YMS 46.
That was 50 years ago.
I don't know when was World War Two, whenever it was.
Anyway, I was in the South Pacific and I was in a minesweeper and we had a small crew,
just a small ship. But
those people bonded together.
And here it is 50 years later or 60 years later or whatever it is.
And they've all died now.
I'm the last one.
So bonding then is a profound way.
If you bond with your church, if you bond with your religion,
you bond with your fellow man in a common enterprise.
That is very powerful.
Very powerful because it also brings unseen forces.
Guard.
Guardian angels.
OK, so the bonding also affects the influence of one's guardian angels resist.
Well, say when you say I don't need you anymore, you're telling your guardian
angels that you folks anymore, I can do it on my own.
So egocentricity then is the op is the is the enemy of spiritual reality.
The spiritual reality then is has to do with the inner humility that I have myself.
Cannot do it.
No, I as a member of
a congregation or a church or a spiritual discipline
there, my capacities are unlimited.
Everybody in this in this room has the capacity to become enlightened.
Everyone here has the potentiality
and capacity to become enlightened, resist by virtue of the energy,
by virtue of the alignment.
By virtue of the intention.
Well, you see what a privilege it is to teach at a group like this.
What a privilege it is.
These are the gurus of times, times yet to come.
There are various cultural paradigms of reality that have quite an effect in today's world.
These cultural paradigms can be very, very misleading.
And that's the real problem with politics is it presents
a paradigm of reality that is a projection of intellectualized fantasy.
It has no parallel in reality.
Karmic influences play quite a profound and significant impact.
So your intentions in this lifetime, of course, are already setting up karmic propensities.
Karma is not understood very well in the West at all.
Although Christianity believes in karma altogether.
You know, the whole story of the creation of mankind has to do with karma.
Adam and Eve wandered and they were told not to mess around with the with the snake.
Was it the snake? The serpent. Right.
So the serpent says, you can eat of that apple.
You know, it's perfectly harmless.
So what happened?
What happened then is that man fell from grace.
He fell from the nonlinear domain of innocence into the linear world.
And then by being in the linear world, they noticed that they were naked.
They noticed that they were naked.
So it's usually interpreted.
And I don't agree with the biblical interpretations of it.
It's interpreted that man's fall from grace is punishment for disobeying God.
I'll say it wasn't that it was the innocence.
The inner innocence of the child is still dominant in everyone's psyche.
And it was Eve's innocence that she
trusted the serpent, not her defiance of God,
but that she trusted the serpent because in her is still the child.
And it's the child in us that listens to everything that goes on.
And it's the innocent child that needs protection.
So we need to protect the innocent child in us that we are not misled by falsehood.
So I always considered Eve to be, frankly, innocent, just naive.
Her limitation was not.
It didn't sound to me like Eve was being defiant of God, saying the heck with you.
It sounded more like she said, well, the serpent is telling me the truth.
You know, you eat of this apple and nothing is going to happen to you.
It's just an apple.
Well, that's what she thought.
So I don't know if we have permission to even ask this audience because it's
good in front of an audience because there's so much centuries and centuries
of tradition in this particular teaching, you see, I myself don't believe because I
tend to see everyone as innocent to begin with.
Was up to me.
Nobody be in hell, you know,
on the other hand, if hell is the only way you get it.
Then we need hell.
So man's experience has been without hell, you wouldn't make that turn around.
And I certainly made a major turn around in the depths of hell because hell,
as it turns out, is far worse than it's ever been
depicted by anybody I know of and or by religion either.
So anyway, the karmic influences will determine,
you know, what what kind of things we're working on right now.
And this does bring.
Up the difference between spiritual versus religious.
Religious tends to be documented and historical and depend on authority,
authority and belief system and alignment and commitment.
And it can be quite restricting.
Spiritual means that you are interested
in the essence of the truth behind that religious teaching.
You're interested in what is the essence of the truth.
You want to know what is the truth, not what is being taught because religion,
you can become you can go to the next slide.
Religion itself can become
whatever happened to the.
Well, religion ism.
I had a chart on religion ism.
The religion itself becomes worshipped eventually.
So I see a lot of religion ism
in which the religion becomes the exact opposite of what it teaches.
And it does it because you're worshiping
the religion and not God.
It's in. Oh, it's in chart four.
OK, yeah.
So you see people worshiping the religion
instead of the truth that the religion is trying to teach.
Religiosity then becomes so people can become very religious.
The Inquisition is probably one of the greatest examples of it or the.
So religion then becomes
still a stultifying and it can become a limitation.
So I look at all religion as it has the essence of truth in it.
But now your your task is not to memorize the religiosity,
but to become the essence of the truth hidden within the religious teaching.
Yes. All right.
So the practical spirituality then breaks down to.
Alignment with the primary teacher,
if you're not going to follow the dictums of a religion,
you know, like a kid in school, then you have to find the teachers.
So therefore, we did put together a list
of 100 hundred teachers to calibrate very well.
And that is very good.
That plus all the writings you have an enormous amount of guidance in this world.
Now, which people lacked in the past.
It was up to good luck and good karma.
Principles above personality means that we're interested in the essence
of truth and not the glamour of the teacher.
There's lots of glamorous teachers out there.
So the chart of authenticated teachers is very practical.
We can say for people in Sudan, probably the best thing to do is avoid all new age
ism and that which is novel.
And exotic.
I remember Bill Wilson hardly died.
Then instantly there were people who were channeling Bill Wilson.
He wasn't
somebody jumped in and grabbed that piece of business.
And I was like,
they were channeling Bill Wilson hysterical.
So any time there's people that channel Clark Gable and Greta Garbo and the
yeah, the people, you know, as soon as something same as you get the Chandler
show up.
And they get a certain amount of
a pump up from the fact that they're they're channeling some kind of a
celebrity channeling Clark Gable.
Oh, yeah, that's a good one.
It's kind of channel Greta Garbo.
Wonderful. All right.
So the chart of thought authenticated teachers is great.
Avoid new age ism in the novel, because unless you're pretty advanced, you can't
tell the real from the fake.
There's so many fake Chandler's around.
There are some that are real.
There is one that calibrates.
He's on TV once in a while.
He calibrates 400 and over.
And then there's another lovely woman
who often appears in morning talk shows and she calibrates about 380.
So there is a tigress capacity for
channeling of entities, et cetera.
On the other hand, I can't find any
indicator benefit to it.
Then remember, I told you I once saw a psychic who said your grandmother said
the plenty of greens is good for your joints.
My grandmother's spirit on the other side
through this psychic is saying they'd be sure to eat your greens.
It's good for your joints.
Well, that is a likelihood that she would have said that.
Oh,
yeah. However, these these things are can become
novelties and become
stop you in your spiritual growth.
It's best until you're very, you know,
pretty sophisticated to avoid channeled entities.
Now, once you learn how to calibrate,
then you can calibrate channeled entities.
But integrity ones aren't that numerical.
OK, so integrity is Chandler's.
We have permission to ask about them.
Probably 50 percent are genuine.
Twenty percent are genuine.
Twenty five percent are about 20 percent of Chandler's are genuine.
The other 80
are out for various other gains.
You see, your chances are one in five.
If you just pick a Chandler and you mean,
you know, that you're going to get a gentleman Chandler to begin with.
So avoid the new ageism and that which is exotic.
And I would avoid channeled entities because, first of all, you don't need them.
What do you need a channeled entity for to find out if your great grandmother went
to heaven or didn't go to heaven? I mean, what is it you want to know
from a channeled entity? Anybody got a good question that you just
want a channeled entity to give them? Anybody got a good question?
Avoid channeled entities until you become very sophisticated.
And when you're very sophisticated,
you don't need channeled entities, so you give them up.
People who call themselves masters,
often tend to parade around, too.
His name is Master Uba Bum.
Where do you get the name Master Buhahum?
He looked in the mirror one day and said, you are a master.
So we've interviewed where we've calibrated a number of masters who've
wandered through town and Sedona, if you live here long enough,
there's a whole parade of masters that come through.
A whole parade of masters.
Because that's
that which is a master doesn't call itself a master, does it?
If somebody where would the humility be
to call yourself the master of something unless you're the master of stupidity
or the master, master of egotism, self-styled masters?
And there were some that wandered through town here not long ago.
All right.
OK, so practical spirituality amounts to study.
So we look at all the list of qualified, calibrated teachers.
And calibrated works.
And then we contemplate and meditate.
So contemplation and meditation we have talked about before.
Meditation tends to take you out of the world.
And if you can find a time and place that is convenient.
The difficulty with meditation is life becomes progressively demanding
and the amount of time that you allot to it begins to diminish.
I allotted an hour in the morning and an hour at night for some 20 or 25 years or so.
I then gave it up to come out west and meditate all day every day.
So when the opposite direction.
All right.
Meditation then is a very effective way.
And of course, there's many meditative techniques and the simpler they are,
the better contemplation is holding a thing in mind and asking God to reveal
the Holy Spirit to reveal to you the what is the meaning of that?
What is the significance of that?
To be as a basic rule, if you only need one thing contemplative and meditative,
I would say to be compassionate towards all of life,
to be compassionate towards all of life in all of its expressions.
You can love chocolate or vanilla.
You can love strawberry or vanilla.
You can love liberals and conservatives.
So to be compassionate.
You begin to say,
you begin to see that everything and everyone is just being what they are.
They're only being what they are.
So what is there to forgive?
You would say, well, the person has the option to be all other than they are.
If they had a real option to be other
than they are, they would be other than they are.
They don't have an option to be other than they are.
That's a hypothetical proposition you
project onto people and say, well, they could be this way or they could be that way.
No, they can't be.
Everybody is innocent because everybody is only being to the fullest that which
they are capable of being and if they are capable of being other than that which
they are, they would be right.
If everybody was capable of being a millionaire, everybody would be one.
If everybody could run the nine, what do you call it, mile?
Four minute?
God, it took me longer than that.
How about the ten minute mile?
When you get to be 80, you got to make the ten minute mile.
Right. OK.
Contemplation then allows you to hold the thing in mind and just question it.
And it's like you look it over.
It's looking at a flower from different levels and different times.
You see different lights shining forth and a greater understanding.
Meditation is a more intense way of doing that.
The balance of.
Faith and reason, then, you know, the great spiritual teachers of all time
whose name I forget.
Balance of faith and reason was the great Catholic theologian Thomas Aquinas.
Oh, yes. And I went to
the university I went to was by the teachers.
There were all members of Jesuits.
Yeah, right.
And Thomas Aquinas was a very big
and Thomas Aquinas caliber is quite high in the 700s.
All right.
So to become a thing instead of just knowing about it.
So many people can repeat back a dictum.
They know about it, but that it's it's a further step to become it.
Therefore, it's best to is not as necessary to avoid all hatred doctrines,
all things that teach hatred, teach hatred.
But be watchful of spiritual ego.
And that's the downfall of a lot of people is
the idea that I know I know the minute your mind says I know
you're in trouble, it's best to merely merely claim that you've heard.
You've heard I've heard I've heard the Buddha said I have heard.
And he didn't say I know anything.
He said I have heard.
That means this is an aspect
of reality that you don't really comprehend until you've contemplated it
sometimes for 40 or 50 years, you know, I mean,
by age 80, a few of the things start to think through.
Oh, I know what you mean.
Oh, yes.
Spiritual ego is the idea that I know I know.
So the only problem with advanced study is the presumption that one knows
that you can safeguard it by, say, I have.
I have heard I have heard.
I've even heard that you can calibrate levels of consciousness.
I've heard I've heard that.
And of course, many people disagree with it.
God bless them.
I don't want people who disagree with me agreeing with me.
It's better to that self be true.
If you doubt it, then doubt it and have a good time telling it.
You have a perfect right to be wrong.
The spiritually aligned person is attracted to beauty in all of its forms,
the beauty of nature, the beauty of all that exists.
There is a time that when you go beyond
the ordinary and the beauty of everything that exists becomes overwhelming.
The beauty of every animal, every bush, every tree.
All things are divinity.
All things are God.
And all that happens is you begin to realize the essence that the essence
of all things are God, the essence of all that exists is God is divinity.
Therefore, when you walk through the woods,
the tree is aware of your walking by the tree is aware of your existence.
Resist the tree is aware of your existence.
All that is alive is aware of your existence.
Aha.
You see how important your existence is that what you have become
radiates out into the world and by a field effect influences everything around you.
If the percentage of people in the population who are meditating are over
1 percent, the crime rate drops down 90 percent.
If only 1 percent of the population is meditating, the crime rate drops profoundly.
Isn't that interesting?
That was done.
A study by the followers of Maharishi Yogi.
Yeah, that of over 1 percent.
So when I came to Sedona, this was this place attracted only spiritually
motivated people for decades.
There was the local business people and then there were all the spiritual people.
So the percentage of people who were meditating, it was probably 50 percent.
And crime never happened in Sedona.
None of us ever took our I never took the.
Ignition switch out of the car.
You parked it in front of the store and you just left the keys in it.
Nobody ever bothered.
Never locked the door at night, never took the key out of the car.
Nothing ever disappeared.
And the crime rate was zero.
Didn't need any cops because nobody ever got arrested for anything.
Because nobody ever did anything illegal.
Well, this thing you could do would be to go over the speed limit.
Go miles an hour.
So beauty then attracts people.
And.
You influence everything around you by that which you have become.
So you don't have to feel like you have to be out there doing good deeds.
Good deism.
The do gooders.
There's a book.
It's really a knockout called The Do Gooders.
I forget who wrote it.
Some lady anyway.
She tracks all these do gooder ideas down through the decades.
What actually happens to them?
And actually what happens is usually the opposite.
You know what I'm saying?
So anyway, so you don't have to be do good.
In fact, it's best not to do any good.
I advise people, please do not do any good.
OK, give me a promise.
You will not stop doing good in this world.
OK, just be what you are to the fullest extent that you can be that.
Why? Because by doing that, you automatically automatically raise
the level of consciousness of all of mankind and mankind has no defense against that.
So if I say you all have to donate to charity, I got everybody's going to have
a resentment right away, you say, oh, I want to donate to charity.
You don't really want to donate to charity unless you got a guilt complex.
You're kind of some kind of a nut job.
The bigger the check, the bigger the guilt complex by your way into heaven.
You know, that's why churches are well endowed.
There's enough people with enough guilt to write big checks before they go.
I asked my local church, are you fixed financially?
There's no problem. No problem.
By your way into heaven, right?
I think it does count when you get there.
I think that's, you know, that you did feel sorry that you were such an SOB.
You know, that check for twenty thousand did help the church, you know.
All right. So music cathedrals, people who are spiritually
become attracted to music.
And we pointed out before that tends to shift the brain function,
the spiritual energy, your right brain and the dendrites,
the dendrites in the brain are constantly forming and then dying.
The brain, even in old age, is constantly producing new neurons all the time.
And if they're not used, this use, they cretinize, they show up and go away.
If they're used, then they,
these these neurons which are going around will connect with each other
because now they form a track and it's a working track.
So the way to take advantage of that, no matter how old you are,
your brain is still producing new neurons all the time.
You can't use old age as an excuse.
Yeah, the brain is producing neurons even into advanced age.
Even this creature here.
BAMO.
Well, the world better look out now, boy.
I can feel those neurons twisting and writhing and doing a dance.
Lot to delete.
How did you get to Tom?
Bum, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum, bum.
That's the dance of the neurons.
The dance of the neurons.
Your neurons are saying, please feed me more beauty.
Please feed me more beautiful movies and gorgeous
things in this world.
Please help me to appreciate and please help me to see the essence of things
rather than the perception, because if you constantly ask to see it,
eventually what is revealed to you, if you live through the experience, is
what's eventually revealed is that all things are God.
Everything is God. All is God.
There is nothing but God. Period.
You see, that's true.
There is nothing but God.
Resist.
Well, I look for God when that's all there is.
So then it dawns on you one day when you're looking at things, the essence of divinity
shines forth, and I've discussed that moment when it happened in my life.
And suddenly the divinity of all things shown forth with such a brilliance that it
was, it laid me out for some years.
I don't think I could do anything for a few years.
Anyway, that spiritual intention then will bring forth that awareness,
that all things are God, all things are God, all things,
because the essence of all that exists is nonlinear.
What you're looking at is the linear, which defines difference.
What you're not seeing is that to exist, the first requirement is to exist.
And to exist is nonlinear.
It has no form.
The essence of existence.
The essence is formless and is actually divinity.
The essence of God is equally this arm, equally this foot, equally this stage,
equally everyone present here.
The next chart will be done soon.
Study, contemplation and meditation, faith and reason.
We did that one.
We were talking about a beauty.
Be watchful of religionism.
You practice the virtues of the great commandments.
Avoid the seven deadly sins.
All right.
Practice of the virtues then becomes sort of automatic.
You know, if you're angry at something, you forgive yourself for being angry.
You tend to ask God to see it differently.
Then you see his innocence and you forgive it.
So therefore, it's the to practice the great commandments.
We say, oh, everybody knows that to bear false witness against your neighbor.
Isn't that one of the Ten Commandments?
Is that right? That's violated every day on television.
Every day on television.
You can hear false distortion of what the other person said.
So to justify hating them and vilifying them.
So the breaking of the great commandments
brings down the consciousness level of all of society.
Yeah.
Practice the great commandments.
We say, well, nobody kills anybody.
Nobody really lies and steals much.
Well, maybe a little.
But I think malice, malice,
false
accusations against your fellow man
are probably the greatest violation we see in today's society.
So we want to avoid on top of the avoiding breaking the great commandments,
the avoidance of the deadly sins and a person who obeys the commandments and
avoids the seven deadly sins.
What are they? Lust and avarice and malice and all the no-no's that you learn in religion.
The thing is to learn how to transcend them.
And the way to transcend it is to see that everything is only being what it can be.
And if it could be something else, it would be.
Therefore, to be accepting of everything as it is, as it appears to be.
Because first of all, you can't see the essence of it.
You can only see how it appears to you.
So there would be no point to try to change it because you're not changing
something that is, you're only changing something that you see.
That's why the famous saying of there's no point of trying to change the world you
see because the world you see doesn't even exist.
Trying to save the world from what?
From what you have projected onto the world and what you think you are seeing.
Besides, many people have earned the right to undo negative karma
and
to gain positive karma.
So if the purpose of this world is
transformational, to undo negative karma and gain positive karma,
then the world is perfect as it is.
So let's ask the arm.
The world is perfect as it is.
Promise me you will stop trying to change the world.
Why? Because if you take away from me the chance, chance to learn that this is
the wrong way to go, how will I learn this is their
wrong way to go? All right.
So avoidance of the deadly sins,
de-glamorize attractions.
Today's world capitalizes on the glamorization of attractions.
And what's the last one?
Because we'll come back to that later.
All right. We'll come back to that later.
So what we're saying today is very simple.
Everything is God.
God is the power to become
and manifest as anything and everything to see the divinity of all that exists.
So you say, Dear God, I asked to see the truth of everything as it is in truth.
I asked to see the essence of everything
rather than a projected perception or some programmed glamorized version.
So out of that simplicity and that humility, you say, I don't know anything.
The dumber you are, the better.
When you're convinced that you're hopelessly endlessly stupid, you're making good progress.
The dumber we are, the better we are.
All right. So we'll take a break and we'll meet you again after lunch.
Where are we? We're right here.
When is it?
It's right now. We're right here right now.
That ends all our problems.
We're all here right now.
We're here because we're here, because we're here.
We're here because we're here.
We're here because we're here because we're here.
All right.
We are going to pick up where we left off.
What's the name of our galaxy?
What's the name of this galaxy?
Archimedes?
Huh?
Who knows what galaxy we're in?
Milky Way.
Andromeda?
Andromeda is a camel, isn't it?
Practical spirituality.
Well, it starts out with goodwill, for those who deserve it, of course.
It means goodwill towards all of life,
to have compassion for all the expressions of life with all its limitations,
to have compassion for all of life.
And all of its expressions.
Without choosing one is good and the other is bad,
because there's no way you can tell what is good and what is bad.
Without all those corpses to walk over, you'd never get to the top of the mountain.
Yes, when you look back over history,
all the hundreds and thousands and millions,
that have died so that we could be here.
Without all of them having gone, we wouldn't be here, would we?
No.
So, we have goodwill towards all the expressions of divinity.
If everything is an expression of divinity, then how we see it expressed would depend
on the karmic balance, you might say.
You might say, this rose has lovely karmic,
or a positive karma, and a prickly pear has negative karma.
So, those would all be projections from our own consciousness.
No such thing exists in the world.
Nothing is either good or bad in and of itself, but only as we see it.
Even the calibrated levels are calibrated levels of various possibilities of existence.
It's not good.
Gooder or badder, it's just the way it is.
So, how it is is how it is.
Everything is what it is.
That's the secret of life.
Everything, what does it mean?
What it means is what it is.
What it is is what it means.
What this thing means here is being a foot.
It's not an elbow.
It's not a tree.
It's not a cactus.
It's not a crowd of Girl Scouts.
It means, that's what it means to be a foot.
You say, oh, that's what it means to be a foot.
Thank you, foot, for telling me what you are.
What everything means is what it is.
What it means is what it is.
That prevents intellectual rambling.
Looking for significances in hidden meanings.
All right.
So, practical spirituality is goodwill towards all of life and all of its expressions.
And the fact that we don't understand it or can't see that that is perfect the way it is,
is our limitation is not a limitation of the world.
Because everything that exists is God.
And if you start criticizing that which is, you're criticizing God.
And he doesn't like that.
You get to heaven, he says, I heard what you said about me.
I heard what you said.
So, we try to non-judgmentally accept all of existence, all of life and all of its expressions.
The day the sun shines and then it rains.
It doesn't mean one is a good day and the other is a bad day.
So, good and bad are then within ourself projected onto the world.
There is no good or bad.
There is only what is.
If everything really is what it is, that makes life very simple.
Everything really is what it is.
It doesn't mean you can't disregard what it is.
If you step into the cage with a poisonous reptile, then you're stepping into a cage with a poisonous reptile.
And you can't pretend that that's just a good doggy in the cage.
The good reptile likes to kill you.
And that's his happiness.
If it makes him happy to kill you, what is your duty?
To make him happy?
There you are.
Got your leg.
Over you go.
He's happy.
And the world got rid of one more fool.
.
All right, so there's a mystification and a glamorization of spiritual teachings, and Sedona is probably the best example of it.
When I came here, it was just one glamorized, seductive course and teacher after another.
And ancient mysteries are always the favorite one.
We'll tell you an ancient mystery for 10 grand.
.
Really.
There's people peddling ancient mysteries, 10,000 books, and I'll tell you some ancient mysteries for a dollar and a half, to tell you the truth.
.
For five bucks, I'll tell you some real ancient mysteries.
Okay.
Ancient mysteries and prophecies, all prophecies are fallacious.
May I have permission to ask this?
That's a fact.
All prophecies are fallacious.
Why is that?
Because a prophecy is based on an expectation of the future.
The future cannot happen until the events of the present have occurred.
The events of the present which are up to the freedom of the will, you haven't made a decision.
Everything that happens is due to at least 10 million contributory causes.
We've explained that before.
For one piece of dust to float from here to here, there are at least 10 million things that have to already be in place.
The earth, the temperature, the humidity, being in Sedona, the circulation of the air in here.
10 million things are necessary to explain rationally any single event.
And that 10 million is a contraction.
The actual number is infinite.
The number of causes for any event, causes in quotes, the number of causes for any event is infinite.
That's a fact.
Resist.
The number of causes are infinite.
You can't tell what's going to happen a minute and a half from now.
So you're going to tell me what's going to happen in 1992.
When's the world coming to an end?
I forget.
When?
Before Christmas or after?
I don't want it to happen before Christmas.
After Christmas.
After New Year's Eve even.
January is sort of boring after Christmas and New Year's Eve.
The world prophecies.
So throughout time there's always some pundit who's making up a great prophecy about the end of the world.
And we've calibrated them.
You remember 70, I think they calibrate.
What's the book in the New Testament?
Revelations.
Revelations, yes, Revelations.
So there's always some pundit having a revelation about the end of the world coming.
And, you know, they stay on every sidewalk.
Repent.
The end is coming.
So you don't have to repent.
The ends are not coming.
Don't have to repent.
I'll let them.
That's trying to bribe God with guilt, you know.
Sackcloth and ashes.
Oh, Lord, great sinner that I am.
Like Eeyore.
Whoa.
Eeyore.
Oh, I'm just a sinner.
Hopeless sinner.
Oh.
I love Eeyore.
So it's best to avoid ancient mysteries and prophecies.
And because they become glamorized and they become, frankly, a racket.
Avoid high-priced gurus with specialness.
They're very, very special and they have a special title.
And for only $5,000 or $10,000, you can spend a day or two with them.
You can hang out with them in Sedona for $5,000 or $10,000 a day.
I'll do it for $20,000.
You can hang out with me for $20,000.
Well, it's because of the specialness.
And what has it got to do with money, anyway?
I mean, what has spirituality got to do with money?
So the idea of specialness, then, is the opposite of the inner experience.
The more advanced one is, the less special one feels.
Until finally you realize that you're that which you think you are, nothing at all.
With some kind of a fleeting imagination.
Okay.
So you want to avoid the seduction by glamor.
Glamorous titles and trappings.
And we've spoken of that before.
Glamorous decor.
Theatrical presentations.
And now we have to bring you the tea.
I have to bring you the teacher.
The curtains part.
And the orchestra strikes up.
The drums beat.
Give me a break.
Hollywoodism.
Avoid.
Okay.
So avoid being seduced by glamour.
Glamour.
The glamour of specialness.
And India specializes in the glamour of the fake guru.
It's the homeland of guru fakery.
And they're expert at it.
The expert at it.
You think you're smarter than they are?
You are not.
They've been at it for hundreds of years.
And you just got born this century.
From India comes all the great special gurus.
And all the tricks that go with it.
So we can avoid all that by being aware of the glamour of the specialness.
And the foreignness of it.
You see, if I have a turban on, now I know a lot more than I did without a turban.
You understand what I'm saying?
If I've got robes on and a big crucifix and sandals and a staff, that's all I need.
And now I know twice as much as I used to.
Boom.
So you want to avoid being seduced by theatrical presentations.
Because that which is real has no need for theatrics.
Because that which it is, its power arises from that which it is.
Not that which it pretends to be or pictures itself as.
But what it actually is.
The power of a thing arises from the essence of that which it really actually is in reality.
And therefore it needs nothing in addition.
Needs nothing in addition to what it is.
You see?
The doggie is an adorable doggie and calibrates 255.
And if I put a hat on the dog and little booties, it's still just, you know, a doggie at 255.
Let's see how things are going there.
We have permission to do Kelsey.
She's over 255, 260, 256, 257.
She's going up, 256.
Just checking out the dog at home, making sure she's all right.
Now, A Course in Miracles, you're all familiar with.
And there one asks for the inner direction.
So the focus is on inner direction.
And now we want to go to the next.
That's it?
That's it.
Oh, you have some questions.
Well, we said that A Course in Miracles, you ask for inner direction.
You ask for God to reveal the essence.
What you're really asking is for God to reveal the essence of the thing.
That you want to see the wolf in the sheep's clothing.
So the A Course in Miracles, you're asking to see the actual reality of that which is by seeing its essence.
And its essence is beyond time.
Beyond time.
And so you're looking for inner direction.
And you're really calling upon your higher.
You're really calling also upon your guardian angels.
You're also asking.
You're also asking your guardian angels for their presence.
Yep.
There you go.
So A Course in Miracles then is involved with angelic presence.
Presences.
Angelic.
Oh, I know.
Angelic energies resist.
Okay.
Angelic energies.
And when they unfold, it is indeed very impressive.
And the miraculous.
Eventually becomes continuous.
The miraculous at first seems astonishing as it occurs.
And then as time goes on, the miraculous become more and more frequent.
And finally they become like ongoing.
Anything can be known without even thinking about it.
It takes a while to trust it.
Yeah.
But eventually all that is known is knowable and known by that which you are in reality.
Which is beyond time.
So you get beyond sequence.
Then, now, and yet to be.
Therefore, based on the reality of, of, of, the spiritual reality, no prophecies of the future are possible.
Let's reinforce that.
No prophecies of the future are possible.
Because all that would be necessary to create the future hasn't even occurred yet.
And is up to you.
To free, to free will.
You see, if the future was predetermined, that would be determinism.
There would be no free will.
There would be no karma one way or the other.
It's impossible to forecast the future.
There used to be.
Over the years I've been in Sedona, there's been so many of them, you know, come through.
There was one guy, he had the truly mustaches that went up.
And he was always forecasting the end of the world was coming.
California was falling off in the ocean and all this.
The time would come and it didn't happen.
And he would just change the dates.
He would just change the dates.
Not 75, it's happening in January of 76.
And 76 would come and go.
And he would just change it to June of 76.
It was hysterical.
And he had just as many people in the crowd.
The days would come and go and nothing happened.
And they would sign up for the next course.
It was really amazing.
But I thought the mustaches turned up like Salvador Dali's.
Like little antennas, you know.
Very adorable.
All right.
Now what did we just say happens next?
Oh, you were going to go over some questions.
Uh-oh.
Now I'm in trouble.
I'm in trouble with questions.
Then people expect answers.
Oh.
Yeah, this will be fun.
All right.
Okay.
If you were to pick out one thing, since we're speaking on practical spirituality.
If you could pick out one thing.
One thing that we could do that would be a practice of this, what would it be?
I think the desire to see, to view everything benevolently.
That each thing has an expression of that which it is.
And goodwill towards all that exists.
Goodwill towards all of life and all of its expressions.
I think is the most beneficial.
Because it's a continuous attitude.
It's not something you do.
It's something you become.
You become aware of the divinity of all that exists eventually.
In the meantime, you're preparing the way by letting go judgmentalism.
So when you let go judgmentalism, you open the way for God to reveal the truth.
The essence of that which things are.
Because all you can see is appearance.
And appearance.
Is one thing and essence is another.
That's the whole idea of the sheep and the wolf and sheep's clothing.
Is because the appearance is one thing.
The essence is another.
You can also have the reverse of that one.
You could have something that looks like a wolf on the outside.
And on the inside it's a sheep.
Thank goodness.
Yeah.
So if we were to practice one thing in a daily, you know, daily.
It would be to look at life benevolently.
Yeah.
To be benevolent.
To have good will towards all of life and all its expressions.
And because you don't want a thing or don't understand the thing.
Doesn't mean that that's not divine will.
That it should be that way.
Yeah.
Well, sometimes that's a little hard to do.
I mean, that's okay for you to say.
But in the real world, that doesn't always apply.
People can't help being the way they are.
Hypothetically, you say they could be.
If they could be, they would be.
The fact that they aren't means that it's only hypothetically that they could be some way other than the way they are.
Because their level of consciousness means that they're projecting a certain point of view upon the world.
So a person who calibrates at 90 sees it as a world of evil and crime and rape and seduction and pain and torture and horrendous things that they do chop people's heads off.
So they see the world that way.
And they think they're doing us a favor by, you know, eliminating us.
You know, eliminating the great white Satan, for instance.
To eliminate the great white Satan is their idea of benevolence, you see.
So their idea of benevolence and your idea of benevolence don't match, you know.
For them to do you a favor is to eliminate you.
So that's the way they please God, you know.
So what we want is to be able to maintain a willingness to see things as they are.
And we ask God to reveal the truth of what we are observing.
Okay.
Well, sometimes the emotions come up before you have that actual concept come into your head.
And the emotion will come up before you even have time to, you know, the reason doesn't come in until after the emotion has already been invented.
So how do you do that?
I mean, how do you change that behavior?
You don't trust emotions beyond it.
There's a certain level beyond which you don't trust.
There's a certain level beyond which you don't trust emotions anymore.
You seek emotions as conditioned responses.
And they're physiologic.
They have nothing to do with reality.
So you can be terrified of that which is harmless and stupidly walk into that which is tremendously dangerous.
So you give up emotionality as a guide to truth.
Emotionality is a guide to comfort but not to truth.
And then you trust the intellect.
More and more.
And then eventually you trust spiritual vision.
Spiritual vision.
And spiritual vision opens up whole new ways of seeing things.
Consciousness is level 630 especially.
It changes the whole way you witness and experience and interpret the world.
So a certain amount of humility that, you know, your emotions are really the animal side of your nature.
The intellect doesn't have emotions.
Emotions have nothing to do with trigonometry or geometry or the distance from here to the moon.
Who cares how you feel about that?
It's not going to alter it.
It's either 93 million miles or it's not.
So you give up emotions and you see them as an accompaniment to life but they're not a guide to life.
You can't use them as your guide to life because emotions come and go.
Somebody says something a little bit sounding a little bit off.
And now you're ticked at them.
But what is the reality of that?
All right.
On the other hand, emotions can be a guide, can be the detective that detects things that the intellect might miss.
A nuance, the emotional tone of a nuance is so important.
And, you know, the wrong emotional tone can turn a friend into an enemy or vice versa.
So the best guidance is to keep a positive attitude towards everyone no matter what it happens, no matter what happens.
And I would say even the headsman, be polite to the headsman so, you know, because he'll do a neater job than if you curse him on the way.
Best to tip him, you see what I'm saying?
Sometimes, you know, especially in this day and age we have so much on the politics and the, you know,
Mm-hmm.
economic times of these times.
You know, we all know that we're probably going to have another year of severe economic problems.
And I know a lot of people out there are wondering how they're going to make it through this year.
So what would be a good attitude to adapt in these trying times?
To expect that very thing.
Well, if you expect that the economy is going to wobble and fall over in various places and stocks are going to drop and all, if you expect that that's the way it's going to be, accept that it's going to be that way, then you don't resist it.
I mean, what difference does it make?
Well, we...
You can have caviar on your rye bread or you can have peanut butter.
Well, you don't get steak as often.
And everybody likes that.
Yeah.
Okay.
So you're dealing with likes and dislikes.
Right.
And, of course...
I see.
Much of financial situations is comfort.
I mean, you're not really more comfortable in a 12-room palatial home than you are in a three-room cozy little cottage.
Mm-hmm.
You're not really happier, nor are you really that much more comfortable.
You can only sleep in one bed at a time.
You can only eat one steak at a time.
You can only sit in one chair at a time.
You can only go to one bathroom at a time.
The fact that you got eight bathrooms in your house doesn't help you.
When you got to go wah-wah, you got to go wah-wah.
I've lived in all those different varieties.
And I also knew people who lived in the extreme of them, multi-billionaires.
And frankly, they were no happier.
Mm-hmm.
Their living room was the more comfortable.
I sat in the chairs of some of the most wealthy people in the world.
And frankly, felt the same.
You go to the bathroom, it flushes the same.
So what you're talking about is the superficial trappings of it all.
So let's say we have the emotional security that the stock market is not going to drop.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, boy, now I'm happy it's not going to drop.
Oh, boy, I was worried the stock market was going to drop.
And I say, no, it's not going to drop.
You say, oh, boy.
Oh, boy.
The stock market is not going to drop.
Oh, shoot.
Then we turn around and we say, oh, that was wrong.
The stock market is going to drop.
Oh, God.
It was my retirement account.
So you can't let yourself, you know, I lived through one depression.
So I've seen it go up and see it go down.
And frankly, I ate more peanut butter than steak during the depression.
But that was really the main difference.
And we drove an older car.
You know, it was a 1927 Model A Ford.
Ha, ha, ha.
Which now is a collector's item.
I wish I had it now.
I'd get you about $35,000 for it.
Ha, ha, ha.
So I think it's considerably what you compare yourself with in fantasy with others.
If you stay with your own people that are just like you, everybody is having peanut butter sandwiches because they can't afford steak.
And it's not a problem.
You know, we never bought something to put your sandwich in.
You know, you just have to get the wax paper that the bread came in and you've wrapped your sandwiches to go to school in them.
And you use the same bread wrapper for about two or three months before it all wore out.
Ha, ha, ha.
So the pleasure of life, then the pleasure of life is not dependent on the externals.
The externals are nice.
It's nice to think you got all that money.
And of course, I always remember Mama's savings account.
Everybody knows that story.
Through depression, you know, the family would worry about.
It was a famous story.
I think it was published in the Reader's Digest.
And they would all worry about money.
And the woman would say, I've got plenty of money in my bank account.
Don't worry about it.
The kids would feel okay again.
And then after the lady died many years later, they found she never had a bank account all those years.
It doesn't even exist.
But she would tell them that the money was in the bank account.
Don't worry.
If we run out of money, we'll take it on Mother's bank account.
So that to me.
Mother's bank account is probably the best explanation of wealth and money and prestige and all those things.
That they have that magical sense of reassurance that you're not really in danger, that you're really in safety.
So I think what people are really worried about in the current economic situation is safety, really safety.
Not so much luxury.
You're not worrying about whether you can get a new Cadillac next year or not.
You're really worrying about survival and security.
So once you reassure yourself about survival and security, then the rest of it is just the excitement and drama of life.
And one of the reasons you decided to be reborn is you want the excitement and the drama of life.
I mean, this is the best TV program around.
You turn on the news in the morning.
Bloomberg says the dollar dropped 300 points yesterday.
Oh.
I said, Susan, guess what, honey?
The Dow dropped 300 points.
She says, where did they drop it?
The NASDAQ is up 122 points.
Wow.
Isn't that exciting?
Yeah, that's exciting.
No, it makes life fun.
The drama of life makes it fun and exciting.
That's why we're all riveted to the screen of our own life, watching it unroll before us.
We're just excited for it.
By the drama of it all.
Will old Doc and Susan make it around the corner there or not?
Oh, they made it.
Oh, thank you.
He actually is there.
Yeah.
The drama of life, yeah?
So life is one endless drama.
You know, we gave in some book someplace about 42 different interpretations of the meaning and significance of life.
And one of them, of course, is drama.
The drama of life, the excitement of it, the vital energy of it, you know?
Yeah.
So because all of us have this emotional level in us, then you're saying that actually that plays out as part of the drama in different situations.
Well, it can also be trained out of your way.
It depends on whether you value it or not.
And traditionally, women have been more accepting of the emotional side of life.
And men tend to be more the logical.
If you're in a business company and a certain bill has to be paid and the means of paying it has to be derived, nobody cares how you feel about it.
Nobody cares how you feel about it.
Okay.
How you feel about it is your problem.
The company doesn't want to know how you feel about it.
They just say, you know, we got to have somebody go to Baltimore and meet with this company and settle this issue.
They have no care.
So men learn to train out the emotions, pay less attention to them.
They may still have them, but they're minimal.
And you can't base a decision on how you feel about it.
Now, on the other hand, there are business executives who are also quite intuitive.
They'll intuit how the market's going to work in this particular area.
But that's not emotion.
That's intuition.
Intuition is putting together the nonverbal and non-described emotions.
Describable.
How the energy fields are moving.
So you could be quite intuitive without necessarily being emotional about it.
You know, it looks like the world may get worse before it gets better.
Well, there's no point of being upset by it.
Just say, well, probably the world's going to get a little worse before it gets better.
So is that okay with everybody?
It could be worse before it gets better.
Just think when it does get better, how relieved we'll be.
I was going to talk to you about, you know, that high experience that I had.
A lot of times we get e-mails from people that say, you know, I have this high experience and I want you to calibrate it.
Well, in my experience, that's the last thing I wanted to do is calibrate it because I knew it was a high experience.
So how do you tell these people that e-mail us and say,
I've had this very high experience?
Well, they're all unique.
Each one is specific.
Well, they want to be unique, though.
Some of them want to be unique.
Yeah, they're looking for specialness.
And a lot of times they're legitimate, too.
They're legitimate questions.
Then there's questions coming out of confusion.
Right.
But those I can understand.
The human psyche is quite complicated.
So is a feeling of elation due to hyper-sensitivity?
Yes.
Is it because you're a manic?
Or is it because you're an advanced consciousness?
So some of them, I look them over.
And I always ask using whatever means I have,
what is the level of this experience?
And how best to give an answer back to the person so that it's helpful?
I don't want to discourage somebody and tell them, you know, that was a delusion you just had.
Smoking that magic weed.
And a stick of coffee, you know.
A lot of people, though, I mean, it's real to them.
Yes.
That experience is very real to them, whether it's delusional or not.
I never discount the reality of the experiential to anybody.
But what they're asking for is to contextualize it.
What does it mean?
And if it's something that's not, tell them it's evolutionary.
That these are energies and experiences that arise through spiritual evolution.
And often this is true.
When you start looking within, you start activating energy fields that are not ordinarily activated.
And you can bring up an awful lot of stuff when you start searching within.
And therefore, I think what they need is reassurance.
So I usually will check the reality of it.
And I'll say, well, once you look within,
you can bring up stacks.
And in Est, they call it stacks.
If you start looking at guilt, you've got stacks of guilt.
Not just the guilt about this, but you've got guilt upon guilt upon guilt.
So if you start pulling up guilt, you can get overwhelmed with guilt.
If you pull up anger, if you pull up any of the so-called negative feelings,
you find that you've got stacks of them.
And then, of course, later on, you discover that you also have stacks about good feelings.
Yeah.
Like, I think about my doggie right now, and I feel a warm brush of love.
See?
And then you think of animals that have attacked you in the past,
and you can think about them, and, you know, suddenly you're scared.
So there's stacks.
When I was a paperboy, you know, I had a long route in Wisconsin,
and there was a couple of customers that had mad dogs and guard dogs.
And as you got near these people's property, I'd get my paper all ready to throw,
and I'd take my feet and hold it up off the paddles,
put them up on the handlebars,
and I'd get going real fast, put my feet up on the handlebars,
and I'd throw the paper like this and keep going,
because I thought,
you would tear your leg off if you got a chance.
And I thought, these idiot people that keep dogs like that on their premises,
I mean, what kind of people are these, you know, that harbor these vicious dogs?
I mean, it says a lot for the owner, but the dog can't help being what it is.
But many a night, I kept my feet on the handlebars,
and went like hell to throw that paper.
So, how do you, so compassion, how can you show compassion without looking weak?
Oh, it's not a matter of showing it.
It's a matter of feeling it from within.
Well, how do you feel?
I mean, for instance, the dog that comes at me to tear my ankle off,
I know he can't help it.
You know, he's trained to be that way.
He's trained to be a watchdog.
So, I don't hate the dog.
On the other hand, I'm not an idiot.
I'm not going to put my foot there for him to chew on.
So, how you see it and how you react to it are two different things.
I usually see most things being what they are,
and that they can't really be any different than they are.
Well, like for instance, I know that prayer is always good to use in those situations.
Because I've seen it too many times in our life where we can't find something.
And so, Dave will pray for a miracle, and all of a sudden, there it is.
It comes out of nowhere.
If it wasn't for the Holy Spirit, I wouldn't be able to get dressed in the morning.
I lose everything.
I can't find it.
I can't see anymore because I can't see it.
So, I say, I ask God, God, where is it?
And all of a sudden, I'll like know where it is.
And I reach out, there it is, by golly.
But it happens over and over in our lives.
It drives you crazy, I know.
It's tough to live with.
Living with an idiot is taking my pills in the morning, I say.
You're supposed to take your heart pill in the morning.
I can never remember whether I took it or not.
I try very hard.
I say, this morning, I will remember whether I took it or not.
She walks back in the kitchen, and I can't remember whether I took it or not.
And the cats want to be fed.
It's always something.
And then he goes, I can't remember.
So, we have this little system with the magnet, whether he took it or not.
I guess that's because you're getting older, you know.
Get older and dumber.
It's just that compassion, when we pray about, when a situation comes up,
I guess what I'm trying to do is come out with a solution on how to handle practical,
practical spirituality.
In other words, when a situation arises that we're hesitant about and we feel that emotion coming up,
does it help to pray for a solution?
Or how would you handle that as a spiritual person?
I always pray to see it differently.
I pray to see it differently.
I pray to see its reality.
I pray to see it for what it is.
Okay.
What I think it is or feel it is.
And it doesn't mean that what you're going to see is necessarily wonderful.
It could be revealed to you quite the opposite.
That it's got long fangs.
And it's best to stay away from it.
So, it isn't that everything gets painted pretty and smelly and nice, you know,
like you've perfumed the universe.
You see it for what it is.
But those depend on the level.
You see, once you get up to the 600s, your vision of the world and experience of the world now begins to change rather globally.
I know, but a lot of us are, you know, down a little bit on that.
Well, better days are coming, you know what I mean?
In the highest space, you know, you see the beauty of the tiger just as he kills you.
What a gorgeous tiger.
Tiger, tiger, burning bright.
How does that poem go?
Tiger, tiger, burning bright in the something of the night, you know?
So, yeah.
I think spiritual evolution is so intriguing because you are experiencing, experiencing fields of realization.
Fields of realization that other people don't go near.
Or if they do, it's just the edge of a dream.
And they quickly leave it.
But we begin to explore it.
So, each facet of the diamond to us is a facet of the diamond.
And then we can see the world a little differently through each facet.
Some people say, well, only these facets are real.
And these are not real.
But that's a limited view.
You realize how multifaceted your experience of reality is as you get older.
All kinds of shades of nuance of feeling and interpretation.
And meaning and importance and significance.
And these fluctuate around.
I always think of it like a diamond.
All the little crystals.
Each one reflecting the light in a little different direction.
So, you never see the same diamond twice.
Never see the same life view twice.
Every time I look at the dog, she looks a little different.
More adorable.
Less adorable.
More, you know.
Everything that you experience, you experience differently.
You experience many different ways.
You know, I experience you in thousands of different ways since we've been together.
In thousands of ways.
Even at this very moment, I'm experiencing it different than at any other moment I've ever experienced you.
I've never experienced you exactly as the diamond is reflecting right now.
A different aspect of you is like coming up into view and presenting itself.
Which doesn't when you're frying bacon and exit home.
That just doesn't come up.
Yeah.
The other delicious side of you comes up then, the bacon and exit home.
Great cook.
Yeah.
But each aspect of life reflects something other.
And I think all those reflections are, to me, are endearing.
They're all endearing.
So, actually, we're all on the path and we should just enjoy the walk.
I don't know about enjoy, but to value it.
To value it equally.
To value it.
Yeah.
I guess you can enjoy valuing, but that sounds a little capricious.
Right.
To value all of life experiences, there are very unpleasant experiences and you wish you could undo them.
You wish, I wish I had never done that and I wish I didn't have to think of that.
But if you hadn't have done that, you wouldn't see the downside of that.
That's right.
Yeah.
So, in other words, if you do something that you're not real proud of, you wouldn't have experienced that you're not proud of that.
It's going to change your life.
Yeah.
So, in other words, the down part of-
Is equally valuable.
Is equally as important as the higher part.
Yeah.
I think if you hold it that way, especially if you pray for it that way, that, dear God,
I really feel bad about that.
What is it I should really see?
What should I really learn about that?
What should I know about that?
So, the down part could be a tool just as important as your higher part.
Yeah.
Even more so at times.
Really?
Yeah.
Some memories are so agonizing that you would never go near that kind of a thing again.
Okay.
Just because you learn how awful it is.
And so, I mean, so you're constantly, when you experience something that's on a low side, you're constantly, at least with me, it would constantly shift me to the higher side.
That's because that's your overall intention.
Other people might use it in reverse.
Their intention might be to justify even more viciousness.
Even more vicious or horrible behavior.
I just can't imagine that.
You can't imagine it because you're spiritually oriented.
But the people in our audience, a painful memory, the lesson of it is to avoid that, to see it differently, to recontextualize it, to ask for forgiveness, to ask to overcome that.
And to give thanks for the karmic, the chance to experience out something negative and you didn't realize how painful it must have been to others when you did it to them.
And that, in some other lifetime.
Yeah, it just seems, I mean, for me, it would be that if anything that was unpleasant would definitely push me towards the more pleasant path.
You know, so, I mean, the downside of life actually sometimes propels you towards the upside.
Oh, it certainly does.
It also is helpful, sometimes I find it helpful, to ask if that was due to karmic influences.
Oh, okay.
I forgot about the karmic influences.
Yeah, I often, you know, sometimes something will come about and it's so strange.
And then when you check back and you say, is that a karmic influence?
And very often you'll get a yes.
I forgot about that.
You know, why did you get fired from five jobs in a row?
Well.
Because you're an idiot.
Yeah.
So, I think checking out karma is also interesting.
Because sometimes it takes the, it makes it a little easier to handle.
Okay.
You know, there was a series of negative things in my life.
And I said, you know, I must have been SLB in some previous lives.
And I checked it out and it said, yes, you were.
I must have been a paranoid, alcoholic son of a bitch.
And it said, yes, you were.
Okay.
If that's the way we undo it then.
We undo it through wisdom and forgiveness and learning the hard way.
So, there's learning the hard way and then there's learning the easy way.
Yeah.
So, all the paths basically lead to the same thing.
We're all trying to become a higher human being.
Realize the reality, the core of our reality.
People who are spiritually oriented are that way.
But you're talking about a very small minority of the population.
Let's see what percentage.
This.
People here represent more than 2% of the population.
3%.
2.5%.
A group like this represents about 2.5% of the population.
Dedicated to truth.
Truth about yourself.
Transcending limitation.
The undoing of negative feelings and grief.
Working through graciously of bad karma.
Thank you, God, for helping me to live through that.
Now I see what that must have been like.
And I ask for guidance in the future.
So, this group here represents not over 3%.
Actually, 2.5%.
This is a very rare group.
You understand that.
We've said that before.
Very rare group for people who put the evolution of their consciousness, enlightenment, salvation above all else.
Above all else.
And dedicate their life to that.
It means you stop doing anything in the world.
Doesn't mean you stop doing anything in the world.
And just meditate all day long.
Although I've done that too.
But it means that your alignment, your intention is very powerful.
Your intention is what makes it powerful.
Intention is to transcend the negatives.
And to facilitate the appearance and the actualization of the positive.
That intention is very powerful.
Very intention.
So we pray for another person in the group, for instance.
Our intention is quite powerful.
We intend for this person to recover.
If it's God's will.
Because it could be the working out of some other karmic things.
I don't want to tell God what to do.
But our intention is very powerful.
And that intention pulls up awareness that does not occur to other people.
Other people will spend a lifetime after a lifetime and frankly not learn anything.
Is that possible?
Karmically, I guess it is.
Yeah, it is.
Lifetime after lifetime and actually learn nothing.
That's amazing.
So a group like this is quite the other way around.
This lifetime, by God, they're going to get all the juice out of it they can.
Learn what you can learn.
Mix with all the highest level people that you can mix with.
You know, search for enlightenment to reach for enlightenment.
Reach for salvation.
Reach for salvation and or enlightenment.
And of course, one is the same as the other.
The Buddhist calls it enlightenment and the Christian calls it salvation.
But in Buddhism, enlightenment is salvation.
We can do all of them at the same time.
Did you have anything else?
Well, we're almost time for a break.
We're about three minutes early.
Oh, three minutes early.
All right.
If you have some words of wisdom.
Well, what we wanted to do was after the break, allow people to ask questions because I think what's really bubbling to come to the surface, somebody feels prompted to say it.
And when you ask a question, very often half a dozen other people were holding it in mind.
And, you know, that's why it bubbles up in you is because as a member of this group, this is a very powerful group.
And if a group like this is holding a question in mind, you can be sure it's going to surface.
There's no way you can hold it down.
It's a very powerful group.
Very powerful group.
Very unique and unusual group, you know.
Statistically, the chances are practically zilch for a group like this to be together anywhere on the planet.
Yeah.
You don't forget many places that are, that sound very holy and very spiritual, you know, ashrams and all.
And all these monks and they'll, you know, .
.
All right, that's lovely.
We'll take the break, you know.