Gloria and excelsius the all glory be to
Gloria and excelsius the all glory be to thee oh Lord. Amen.
That signals a dedication to truth
That signals a dedication to truth and to lovingness
by which we we serve God and uh our
by which we we serve God and uh our fellow man and ourself. Serve God,
fellow man and ourself. Serve God,
fellow man and ourself. Serve God, fellow man and self with a capital S
fellow man and self with a capital S
fellow man and self with a capital S fulfills uh your destiny as a human
fulfills uh your destiny as a human
fulfills uh your destiny as a human being
being
being and you can go back with the past
and you can go back with the past
and you can go back with the past past
and um we were just saying we don't
and um we were just saying we don't think we'll choose protoplasm next time,
think we'll choose protoplasm next time,
think we'll choose protoplasm next time, right? Okay.
Protoplasm. Protoplasm. Huh? We could
Protoplasm. Protoplasm. Huh? We could make a song of that. Protoplasm.
make a song of that. Protoplasm.
make a song of that. Protoplasm. Protoplasm.
If it wasn't for protoplasm, we couldn't
If it wasn't for protoplasm, we couldn't get out of here, would we?
get out of here, would we?
get out of here, would we? Yeah. If you're not ready to leave, the
Yeah. If you're not ready to leave, the
Yeah. If you're not ready to leave, the protoplasm changes your mind. So,
protoplasm changes your mind. So,
protoplasm changes your mind. So, you don't have to worry about getting
you don't have to worry about getting
you don't have to worry about getting out of here. Boy, that's a relief, huh?
out of here. Boy, that's a relief, huh?
out of here. Boy, that's a relief, huh? Let's see. What are we talking about
Let's see. What are we talking about
Let's see. What are we talking about this morning? Do you know?
this morning? Do you know?
this morning? Do you know? >> Um, yes. I have to make some
>> Um, yes. I have to make some
>> Um, yes. I have to make some announcements.
announcements.
announcements. >> That's what we're talking about.
>> That's what we're talking about.
>> That's what we're talking about. >> Okay, please be seated.
>> Okay, with that.
>> Okay, with that. Oh, one more. We're on YouTube. If any
Oh, one more. We're on YouTube. If any
Oh, one more. We're on YouTube. If any of you want to see little clips of us,
of you want to see little clips of us,
of you want to see little clips of us, we're on YouTube. That's our newest
we're on YouTube. That's our newest
we're on YouTube. That's our newest little thing. One of um one of our uh
little thing. One of um one of our uh
little thing. One of um one of our uh people emailed us and asked us if we
people emailed us and asked us if we
people emailed us and asked us if we would go on YouTube and put up some of
would go on YouTube and put up some of
would go on YouTube and put up some of the things because there wasn't anything
the things because there wasn't anything
the things because there wasn't anything about us up there. So, we uh put a
about us up there. So, we uh put a
about us up there. So, we uh put a couple of little clips up there. So, if
couple of little clips up there. So, if
couple of little clips up there. So, if you'd like to take a look, we're up
you'd like to take a look, we're up
you'd like to take a look, we're up there, too. And with that,
there, too. And with that,
there, too. And with that, >> I'll introduce Dr. Hawkins. And we're
>> I'll introduce Dr. Hawkins. And we're
>> I'll introduce Dr. Hawkins. And we're going We have lots of learning to do
going We have lots of learning to do
going We have lots of learning to do today, so it'll be fun.
today, so it'll be fun.
today, so it'll be fun. >> If Jesus were alive today, would he be
>> If Jesus were alive today, would he be
>> If Jesus were alive today, would he be on YouTube?
on YouTube?
on YouTube? >> I don't know.
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know. I don't know.
>> That's a good question.
>> That's a good question. >> Well, your voice doesn't carry too far
>> Well, your voice doesn't carry too far
>> Well, your voice doesn't carry too far from the mount, you know.
from the mount, you know.
from the mount, you know. Yeah.
>> What are we talking about today? You
>> What are we talking about today? You know, oh, faith versus reason. Faith and
know, oh, faith versus reason. Faith and
know, oh, faith versus reason. Faith and reason.
reason.
reason. Let's see. So, first we'll just review a
Let's see. So, first we'll just review a
Let's see. So, first we'll just review a few of the uh older slides
few of the uh older slides
few of the uh older slides and uh just to get oriented. Now, how
and uh just to get oriented. Now, how
and uh just to get oriented. Now, how many people are new today?
many people are new today?
many people are new today? Aha. Oh, boy. All right. So, for the new
Aha. Oh, boy. All right. So, for the new
Aha. Oh, boy. All right. So, for the new people, I we do a recapitulation of some
people, I we do a recapitulation of some
people, I we do a recapitulation of some of the basic slides so that we're all,
of the basic slides so that we're all,
of the basic slides so that we're all, you know, on the same page.
you know, on the same page.
you know, on the same page. And uh
And uh
And uh so let's start with the first slide.
so let's start with the first slide.
so let's start with the first slide. Where's the slide lady?
Just one minute.
Just one minute. >> Oh, we have a projector delay.
>> Oh, we have a projector delay.
>> Oh, we have a projector delay. >> We have technical difficulties.
>> We have technical difficulties.
>> We have technical difficulties. >> Oh, technical difficulties.
>> Oh, technical difficulties.
>> Oh, technical difficulties. That's what you don't want to hear on a
That's what you don't want to hear on a
That's what you don't want to hear on a plane as you're coming into
plane as you're coming into
plane as you're coming into newer airport. We have technical
newer airport. We have technical
newer airport. We have technical difficulties. We will be here in exactly
difficulties. We will be here in exactly
difficulties. We will be here in exactly six hours.
six hours.
six hours. In the end of six hours, they say we
In the end of six hours, they say we
In the end of six hours, they say we continue to have technical difficulties.
continue to have technical difficulties.
continue to have technical difficulties. It will be another three hours
when you get stalled on the tarmac. I
when you get stalled on the tarmac. I guess stalled on the Kramak in in
guess stalled on the Kramak in in
guess stalled on the Kramak in in Athens, Greece one time.
Athens, Greece one time.
Athens, Greece one time. We weren't supposed to land in Athens,
We weren't supposed to land in Athens,
We weren't supposed to land in Athens, but they were having military maneuvers.
but they were having military maneuvers.
but they were having military maneuvers. So, we landed on the tarmac. We sat on
So, we landed on the tarmac. We sat on
So, we landed on the tarmac. We sat on the tarmac for like eight hours or
the tarmac for like eight hours or
the tarmac for like eight hours or something while they did their military
something while they did their military
something while they did their military maneuvers. Oh god.
maneuvers. Oh god.
maneuvers. Oh god. Yeah. So, I avoid uh airlines as much as
Yeah. So, I avoid uh airlines as much as
Yeah. So, I avoid uh airlines as much as possible.
possible.
possible. I'd rather take the bus.
>> Well, where was responsible? We'll have
>> Well, where was responsible? We'll have to be beaten gently.
All right. So, uh,
All right. So, uh, >> the lamp has gone on the projector.
>> the lamp has gone on the projector.
>> the lamp has gone on the projector. It'll be about five minutes.
It'll be about five minutes.
It'll be about five minutes. >> We will land on the tarmac in five
>> We will land on the tarmac in five
>> We will land on the tarmac in five minutes. All right.
Well, the reason we're here then is to
Well, the reason we're here then is to uh we're talking about the reason and
uh we're talking about the reason and
uh we're talking about the reason and faith uh today and trying to contrast
faith uh today and trying to contrast
faith uh today and trying to contrast the two. And St. Thomas Aquinus of
the two. And St. Thomas Aquinus of
the two. And St. Thomas Aquinus of course said that uh faith is enhanced by
course said that uh faith is enhanced by
course said that uh faith is enhanced by reason and reason is enhanced by faith.
reason and reason is enhanced by faith.
reason and reason is enhanced by faith. They're mutually beneficial.
They're mutually beneficial.
They're mutually beneficial. Faith without reason can sometimes be
Faith without reason can sometimes be
Faith without reason can sometimes be sort of stupid
and reason without faith can sometimes
and reason without faith can sometimes be pretty stupid.
be pretty stupid.
be pretty stupid. That it takes a combination of the two.
That it takes a combination of the two.
That it takes a combination of the two. that faith balances the dedication to
that faith balances the dedication to
that faith balances the dedication to truth
truth
truth and therefore alignment with divinity um
and therefore alignment with divinity um
and therefore alignment with divinity um signifies something very uh serious
signifies something very uh serious
signifies something very uh serious about the person and that is they
about the person and that is they
about the person and that is they consider themsel to be accountable
consider themsel to be accountable
consider themsel to be accountable accountable so the thing that worries me
accountable so the thing that worries me
accountable so the thing that worries me about an atheist is I know he doesn't
about an atheist is I know he doesn't
about an atheist is I know he doesn't consider himself accountable
consider himself accountable
consider himself accountable he can say anything he wants and get
he can say anything he wants and get
he can say anything he wants and get away with it you see so you hope that in
away with it you see so you hope that in
away with it you see so you hope that in a gentlemanly way they'll will be uh
a gentlemanly way they'll will be uh
a gentlemanly way they'll will be uh ethical as if you don't believe in God
ethical as if you don't believe in God
ethical as if you don't believe in God the next best thing is ethics. Ethics
the next best thing is ethics. Ethics
the next best thing is ethics. Ethics however depends on perception and reason
however depends on perception and reason
however depends on perception and reason and perception as we know is the
and perception as we know is the
and perception as we know is the quickest way to hell. So
trusting in perception.
trusting in perception. So yeah
So yeah
So yeah uh the other signal of a good reliable
uh the other signal of a good reliable
uh the other signal of a good reliable person is a sense of humor.
person is a sense of humor.
person is a sense of humor. Never trust a person who doesn't have a
Never trust a person who doesn't have a
Never trust a person who doesn't have a sense of humor. Yeah. Because a sense of
sense of humor. Yeah. Because a sense of
sense of humor. Yeah. Because a sense of humor signifies
humor signifies
humor signifies the ability to comprehend context as
the ability to comprehend context as
the ability to comprehend context as well as content. You know, humor is
well as content. You know, humor is
well as content. You know, humor is contrasting content with context and uh
contrasting content with context and uh
contrasting content with context and uh that's where the humor comes forth. You
that's where the humor comes forth. You
that's where the humor comes forth. You see, you see what's said, but then the
see, you see what's said, but then the
see, you see what's said, but then the context tells you what it really means
context tells you what it really means
context tells you what it really means and that's the joke.
and that's the joke.
and that's the joke. So humor is a um very useful spiritual
So humor is a um very useful spiritual
So humor is a um very useful spiritual tool and uh
tool and uh
tool and uh uh it has to do then with acknowledging
uh it has to do then with acknowledging
uh it has to do then with acknowledging disparities. By humor you can take two
disparities. By humor you can take two
disparities. By humor you can take two things that seem dispirit and
things that seem dispirit and
things that seem dispirit and acknowledge
acknowledge
acknowledge the reality of both of them. So it is
the reality of both of them. So it is
the reality of both of them. So it is also quite modest in a way. Humor is
also quite modest in a way. Humor is
also quite modest in a way. Humor is modest in that it acknowledges there's
modest in that it acknowledges there's
modest in that it acknowledges there's more than one way to look at a a thing.
more than one way to look at a a thing.
more than one way to look at a a thing. You may not agree with other people's
You may not agree with other people's
You may not agree with other people's perceptions, but they are at least
perceptions, but they are at least
perceptions, but they are at least you're acknowledging them. Yeah.
What's that?
What's that? You don't have an extra bulb. Say
you have to drive into
you have to drive into You have to drive in town and get a
You have to drive in town and get a
You have to drive in town and get a bulb.
>> Well, while we're waiting, anybody got
>> Well, while we're waiting, anybody got any questions?
Anybody got a question? Put your hand up
Anybody got a question? Put your hand up and ask it and we'll we don't want to
and ask it and we'll we don't want to
and ask it and we'll we don't want to waste time.
waste time.
waste time. What? Say
What? Say
What? Say >> he's up. Oh.
>> he's up. Oh.
>> he's up. Oh. Oh, God bless you.
Oh, God bless you.
Oh, God bless you. the miraculouses
the miraculouses
the miraculouses and we even have a little
now we can proceed. All right. So the
now we can proceed. All right. So the first thing we wanted to do is just uh
first thing we wanted to do is just uh
first thing we wanted to do is just uh for those that are new review the uh the
for those that are new review the uh the
for those that are new review the uh the reason all these lectures started was
reason all these lectures started was
reason all these lectures started was the discovery of uh how to tell truth
the discovery of uh how to tell truth
the discovery of uh how to tell truth from falsehood. That was such a
from falsehood. That was such a
from falsehood. That was such a startling discovery
startling discovery
startling discovery that it knocked me out for quite a
that it knocked me out for quite a
that it knocked me out for quite a while. And then I began to write about
while. And then I began to write about
while. And then I began to write about it and using an investigative technique
it and using an investigative technique
it and using an investigative technique which is ultra simple
which is ultra simple
which is ultra simple uh and therefore complicated to explain
uh and therefore complicated to explain
uh and therefore complicated to explain uh we devised a map that goes from 1 to
uh we devised a map that goes from 1 to
uh we devised a map that goes from 1 to a thousand of all possibility.
a thousand of all possibility.
a thousand of all possibility. Now the the test for truth is very
Now the the test for truth is very
Now the the test for truth is very simple. The mathematics of why it works
simple. The mathematics of why it works
simple. The mathematics of why it works depends on advanced quantum mechanics
depends on advanced quantum mechanics
depends on advanced quantum mechanics and the best explanation is in the new
and the best explanation is in the new
and the best explanation is in the new book by what's his name from book
book by what's his name from book
book by what's his name from book Berkeley
Berkeley
Berkeley >> Henry Stap yes mindful universe uh who
>> Henry Stap yes mindful universe uh who
>> Henry Stap yes mindful universe uh who explains it in a great much greater
explains it in a great much greater
explains it in a great much greater detail than I do that it's based on
detail than I do that it's based on
detail than I do that it's based on quantum the quantum reality that uh in
quantum the quantum reality that uh in
quantum the quantum reality that uh in infinite space the infinite field of
infinite space the infinite field of
infinite space the infinite field of consciousness is there is no location
consciousness is there is no location
consciousness is there is no location everywhere is equally present at all
everywhere is equally present at all
everywhere is equally present at all times. So therefore, if I hold a
times. So therefore, if I hold a
times. So therefore, if I hold a question in my mind, if I hold a
question in my mind, if I hold a
question in my mind, if I hold a statement in my mind,
statement in my mind,
statement in my mind, uh I don't have to be connected with it
uh I don't have to be connected with it
uh I don't have to be connected with it in time or place or distance.
in time or place or distance.
in time or place or distance. And when I press down Susan's arm, then
And when I press down Susan's arm, then
And when I press down Susan's arm, then when I reach a certain level, that will
when I reach a certain level, that will
when I reach a certain level, that will be the level of the truth of what I'm
be the level of the truth of what I'm
be the level of the truth of what I'm holding in mind. Now, she doesn't know
holding in mind. Now, she doesn't know
holding in mind. Now, she doesn't know what I'm holding in mind. She has no
what I'm holding in mind. She has no
what I'm holding in mind. She has no idea what I'm holding in mind.
idea what I'm holding in mind.
idea what I'm holding in mind. Therefore, it has nothing to do with
Therefore, it has nothing to do with
Therefore, it has nothing to do with suggestion or other plausibilities that
suggestion or other plausibilities that
suggestion or other plausibilities that people have suggested such as dowsing or
people have suggested such as dowsing or
people have suggested such as dowsing or something. Um because she doesn't know
something. Um because she doesn't know
something. Um because she doesn't know what I'm holding in mind. There's two
what I'm holding in mind. There's two
what I'm holding in mind. There's two different people. So, how how can she
different people. So, how how can she
different people. So, how how can she respond to what I'm holding in mind?
respond to what I'm holding in mind?
respond to what I'm holding in mind? She does it because I close the gap of
She does it because I close the gap of
She does it because I close the gap of what's possible.
what's possible.
what's possible. I collapse the wave function from
I collapse the wave function from
I collapse the wave function from possibility to actuality.
possibility to actuality.
possibility to actuality. If what I'm holding mind has an
If what I'm holding mind has an
If what I'm holding mind has an actuality, then it has a power and the
actuality, then it has a power and the
actuality, then it has a power and the power makes her arm go strong. If what
power makes her arm go strong. If what
power makes her arm go strong. If what I'm holding in mind is not not real, uh
I'm holding in mind is not not real, uh
I'm holding in mind is not not real, uh then it has no possibility of existing
then it has no possibility of existing
then it has no possibility of existing and her arm goes weak. It's a very the
and her arm goes weak. It's a very the
and her arm goes weak. It's a very the explanation is uh intriguing but it's
explanation is uh intriguing but it's
explanation is uh intriguing but it's very very simple and you you'll see we
very very simple and you you'll see we
very very simple and you you'll see we do it all the time. Not every not
do it all the time. Not every not
do it all the time. Not every not everyone is able to do it. The higher
everyone is able to do it. The higher
everyone is able to do it. The higher the level of consciousness of the people
the level of consciousness of the people
the level of consciousness of the people involved the more accurate the results.
involved the more accurate the results.
involved the more accurate the results. So it means that having the capacity to
So it means that having the capacity to
So it means that having the capacity to be detached and objective.
be detached and objective.
be detached and objective. If you want to know the answer to a
If you want to know the answer to a
If you want to know the answer to a question,
question,
question, then uh let's say I'm going to I'm going
then uh let's say I'm going to I'm going
then uh let's say I'm going to I'm going to refer to a well-known spiritual
to refer to a well-known spiritual
to refer to a well-known spiritual teacher in history today and I need to
teacher in history today and I need to
teacher in history today and I need to calibrate him before the lecture. He's
calibrate him before the lecture. He's
calibrate him before the lecture. He's over 500,
over 500,
over 500, over 550, over 560, 570.
over 550, over 560, 570.
over 550, over 560, 570. He's over 570.
He's over 570.
He's over 570. He's over He's just at 570. Okay.
He's over He's just at 570. Okay.
He's over He's just at 570. Okay. Uh,
Uh,
Uh, now she doesn't know who I'm holding in
now she doesn't know who I'm holding in
now she doesn't know who I'm holding in mind. So, how would she know that it's a
mind. So, how would she know that it's a
mind. So, how would she know that it's a 570,
570,
570, but that's one of the greatest teachers
but that's one of the greatest teachers
but that's one of the greatest teachers of all time, which we'll get to. So, she
of all time, which we'll get to. So, she
of all time, which we'll get to. So, she has no idea who I was holding in mind.
has no idea who I was holding in mind.
has no idea who I was holding in mind. So, how how would she be able to fake
So, how how would she be able to fake
So, how how would she be able to fake it? So, the skeptic cuts his own throat
it? So, the skeptic cuts his own throat
it? So, the skeptic cuts his own throat because he's
because he's
because he's getting rid of something of extreme uh
getting rid of something of extreme uh
getting rid of something of extreme uh use. So what was mindboggling about the
use. So what was mindboggling about the
use. So what was mindboggling about the discovery some decades ago
discovery some decades ago
discovery some decades ago was was that you could tell truth from
was was that you could tell truth from
was was that you could tell truth from falsehood and you could do it about
falsehood and you could do it about
falsehood and you could do it about anything anywhere in time or place. Why?
anything anywhere in time or place. Why?
anything anywhere in time or place. Why? Because the infinite field of
Because the infinite field of
Because the infinite field of consciousness has no dimension and it is
consciousness has no dimension and it is
consciousness has no dimension and it is everywhere equally present.
everywhere equally present.
everywhere equally present. So I can ask about the love life of
So I can ask about the love life of
So I can ask about the love life of Cleopatra
Cleopatra
Cleopatra or anything else and it will be the same
or anything else and it will be the same
or anything else and it will be the same as if uh we go back in time thousands of
as if uh we go back in time thousands of
as if uh we go back in time thousands of years. So so because it's nonlinear.
years. So so because it's nonlinear.
years. So so because it's nonlinear. So the difficulty people have in
So the difficulty people have in
So the difficulty people have in understanding the work is they confuse
understanding the work is they confuse
understanding the work is they confuse the linear and the nonlinear and we'll
the linear and the nonlinear and we'll
the linear and the nonlinear and we'll try and get that cleared up today. So
try and get that cleared up today. So
try and get that cleared up today. So the calibrated levels of consciousness
the calibrated levels of consciousness
the calibrated levels of consciousness then have become relatively well known.
then have become relatively well known.
then have become relatively well known. Uh there's study groups all around the
Uh there's study groups all around the
Uh there's study groups all around the world. The books are all translated into
world. The books are all translated into
world. The books are all translated into all the world's languages.
all the world's languages.
all the world's languages. The technique we we demonstrate is
The technique we we demonstrate is
The technique we we demonstrate is actually used by various governments
actually used by various governments
actually used by various governments etc. And uh so the map of consciousness
etc. And uh so the map of consciousness
etc. And uh so the map of consciousness goes
goes
goes uh from one uh possibility up to a
uh from one uh possibility up to a
uh from one uh possibility up to a thousand. And as you as you can see, I
thousand. And as you as you can see, I
thousand. And as you as you can see, I think everybody here is rather familiar
think everybody here is rather familiar
think everybody here is rather familiar with it. It also uh covers uh the view
with it. It also uh covers uh the view
with it. It also uh covers uh the view of yourself, the view of God. Uh
of yourself, the view of God. Uh
of yourself, the view of God. Uh these are the emotional states of uh
these are the emotional states of uh
these are the emotional states of uh reason and love that we'll be talking
reason and love that we'll be talking
reason and love that we'll be talking about today accompanied by uh
about today accompanied by uh
about today accompanied by uh understanding leading to these various
understanding leading to these various
understanding leading to these various above above 200 is positive and below
above above 200 is positive and below
above above 200 is positive and below 200 is negative. So hating and scorning
200 is negative. So hating and scorning
200 is negative. So hating and scorning and killing and etc are below 200 and
and killing and etc are below 200 and
and killing and etc are below 200 and bin Laden is about uh 20 or 90 I forget
bin Laden is about uh 20 or 90 I forget
bin Laden is about uh 20 or 90 I forget where he is someplace. All right. So
where he is someplace. All right. So
where he is someplace. All right. So anyway we're all familiar with the scale
anyway we're all familiar with the scale
anyway we're all familiar with the scale of consciousness. Anybody got any
of consciousness. Anybody got any
of consciousness. Anybody got any question about it? Anybody got any
question about it? Anybody got any
question about it? Anybody got any question about the scale of
question about the scale of
question about the scale of consciousness? It's arbitrary. You can
consciousness? It's arbitrary. You can
consciousness? It's arbitrary. You can make your own scale of consciousness
make your own scale of consciousness
make your own scale of consciousness from one to 100 or one to a million. And
from one to 100 or one to a million. And
from one to 100 or one to a million. And on your scale then you have to define at
on your scale then you have to define at
on your scale then you have to define at what level uh discern
what level uh discern
what level uh discern discerns truth from falsehood. Okay. So
discerns truth from falsehood. Okay. So
discerns truth from falsehood. Okay. So can you see that little dot back there?
can you see that little dot back there?
can you see that little dot back there? Yeah. Amazing. Okay. We'll go to the
Yeah. Amazing. Okay. We'll go to the
Yeah. Amazing. Okay. We'll go to the next one.
Now unfortunate unfortunately or
Now unfortunate unfortunately or fortunately depending how you look at uh
fortunately depending how you look at uh
fortunately depending how you look at uh for mankind you see that 85% of the
for mankind you see that 85% of the
for mankind you see that 85% of the world is below consciousness level 200.
world is below consciousness level 200.
world is below consciousness level 200. Now the implications, the inference, the
Now the implications, the inference, the
Now the implications, the inference, the meaning of that uh explains to you why
meaning of that uh explains to you why
meaning of that uh explains to you why it is very often a difficult world to
it is very often a difficult world to
it is very often a difficult world to live in because 85% of the people will
live in because 85% of the people will
live in because 85% of the people will steal you blind.
In fact, many people will feel it's
In fact, many people will feel it's their duty to do so.
their duty to do so.
their duty to do so. Well, if you left it out, he deserves
Well, if you left it out, he deserves
Well, if you left it out, he deserves it, doesn't he?
it, doesn't he?
it, doesn't he? So 85% of the world is below 200 which
So 85% of the world is below 200 which
So 85% of the world is below 200 which explains the nature of the world and the
explains the nature of the world and the
explains the nature of the world and the fact that man has been at war 93% of
fact that man has been at war 93% of
fact that man has been at war 93% of recorded time. So war you might say is
recorded time. So war you might say is
recorded time. So war you might say is his natural state 93% of the time. And
his natural state 93% of the time. And
his natural state 93% of the time. And in today's world there's only probably
in today's world there's only probably
in today's world there's only probably five or six wars going on. It's a rather
five or six wars going on. It's a rather
five or six wars going on. It's a rather quiet time.
quiet time.
quiet time. So we'll move to the next.
So we'll move to the next.
So we'll move to the next. So here are the above above 200 there's
So here are the above above 200 there's
So here are the above above 200 there's only 15%.
only 15%.
only 15%. And yet that 15% because they have so
And yet that 15% because they have so
And yet that 15% because they have so much power counterbalance the negativity
much power counterbalance the negativity
much power counterbalance the negativity of the 85% that calibrate below 200.
of the 85% that calibrate below 200.
of the 85% that calibrate below 200. Therefore, an audience like this which
Therefore, an audience like this which
Therefore, an audience like this which is way above 200 is right at this very
is way above 200 is right at this very
is way above 200 is right at this very moment counterbalancing a huge block of
moment counterbalancing a huge block of
moment counterbalancing a huge block of humanity. This audience sitting here now
humanity. This audience sitting here now
humanity. This audience sitting here now is counterbalancing
many millions of uh people that are
many millions of uh people that are below 200. Yes.
below 200. Yes.
below 200. Yes. Uh so we'll move to the next.
Uh so we'll move to the next.
Uh so we'll move to the next. The evolution of consciousness over
The evolution of consciousness over
The evolution of consciousness over time. Yes. So this is uh quantum
time. Yes. So this is uh quantum
time. Yes. So this is uh quantum mechanics. We mentioned Henry Stap. His
mechanics. We mentioned Henry Stap. His
mechanics. We mentioned Henry Stap. His new book is out mindful universe and it
new book is out mindful universe and it
new book is out mindful universe and it explains the um
explains the um
explains the um theoretical physics behind
theoretical physics behind
theoretical physics behind uh what we have just demonstrated. Yeah.
uh what we have just demonstrated. Yeah.
uh what we have just demonstrated. Yeah. That this process here if something has
That this process here if something has
That this process here if something has reality that collapses the wave function
reality that collapses the wave function
reality that collapses the wave function from the potential to the actual.
from the potential to the actual.
from the potential to the actual. The only way you can collapse the wave
The only way you can collapse the wave
The only way you can collapse the wave function is it has to exist in reality.
function is it has to exist in reality.
function is it has to exist in reality. So if what I hold in mind is real then
So if what I hold in mind is real then
So if what I hold in mind is real then it collapses the wave function and the
it collapses the wave function and the
it collapses the wave function and the arm indicates truth versus falsehood.
arm indicates truth versus falsehood.
arm indicates truth versus falsehood. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. Now the next uh slide is uh because
Now the next uh slide is uh because
Now the next uh slide is uh because we're talking about reason today
we're talking about reason today
we're talking about reason today uh I always put the great books of the
uh I always put the great books of the
uh I always put the great books of the western world
western world
western world um because they have such a decisive uh
um because they have such a decisive uh
um because they have such a decisive uh part in history becoming famous
part in history becoming famous
part in history becoming famous uh and of course this this these are the
uh and of course this this these are the
uh and of course this this these are the greatest minds that have have have been
greatest minds that have have have been
greatest minds that have have have been uh on the planet. the greatest minds,
uh on the planet. the greatest minds,
uh on the planet. the greatest minds, Capernicus. Uh,
Capernicus. Uh,
Capernicus. Uh, and
and
and and we notice that the only thing out of
and we notice that the only thing out of
and we notice that the only thing out of step with all these people you see are
step with all these people you see are
step with all these people you see are in the 400s is Karl Marx at 130. The
in the 400s is Karl Marx at 130. The
in the 400s is Karl Marx at 130. The great books of the Western world were
great books of the Western world were
great books of the Western world were put together, I guess, by Mortimer or
put together, I guess, by Mortimer or
put together, I guess, by Mortimer or Adler.
Adler.
Adler. And uh, because of his importance, Karl
And uh, because of his importance, Karl
And uh, because of his importance, Karl Marx and Engles were put in there. The
Marx and Engles were put in there. The
Marx and Engles were put in there. The the difficulty is that Marx has gotten
the difficulty is that Marx has gotten
the difficulty is that Marx has gotten demarxed. He's not called Kar Marx
demarxed. He's not called Kar Marx
demarxed. He's not called Kar Marx anymore. Uh he's called something else
anymore. Uh he's called something else
anymore. Uh he's called something else which they've removed the name Markx.
which they've removed the name Markx.
which they've removed the name Markx. And now the same thinkingness at at
And now the same thinkingness at at
And now the same thinkingness at at below 200 emerges in our society as
below 200 emerges in our society as
below 200 emerges in our society as relativism. Relativism is Marxism
relativism. Relativism is Marxism
relativism. Relativism is Marxism without the word marks.
without the word marks.
without the word marks. that was the result of a deliberate move
that was the result of a deliberate move
that was the result of a deliberate move uh to
uh to
uh to remove any political objection to the
remove any political objection to the
remove any political objection to the name Mark. So they remove marks and uh
name Mark. So they remove marks and uh
name Mark. So they remove marks and uh the same dialectic continues in today's
the same dialectic continues in today's
the same dialectic continues in today's world and people say why what is f why
world and people say why what is f why
world and people say why what is f why why does the far left calibrate so low
why does the far left calibrate so low
why does the far left calibrate so low because it's nothing but mark the
because it's nothing but mark the
because it's nothing but mark the dialectical materialism of Karl Marx at
dialectical materialism of Karl Marx at
dialectical materialism of Karl Marx at 130 angles was only 200. Uhhuh. All
130 angles was only 200. Uhhuh. All
130 angles was only 200. Uhhuh. All right. So that explains the difficulty
right. So that explains the difficulty
right. So that explains the difficulty of the modern world in you know at least
of the modern world in you know at least
of the modern world in you know at least United States. Okay. We will go on to
United States. Okay. We will go on to
United States. Okay. We will go on to the next huh
the next huh
the next huh uh one of the most important
uh one of the most important
uh one of the most important implications of level of consciousness
implications of level of consciousness
implications of level of consciousness is its influence on brain function.
is its influence on brain function.
is its influence on brain function. Below level 200 the brain operates uh in
Below level 200 the brain operates uh in
Below level 200 the brain operates uh in an animal way. The left brain is
an animal way. The left brain is
an animal way. The left brain is dominant and uh fight or flight and
dominant and uh fight or flight and
dominant and uh fight or flight and release of adrenaline. And that part of
release of adrenaline. And that part of
release of adrenaline. And that part of the brain is interested in winning and
the brain is interested in winning and
the brain is interested in winning and in gain and getting the better of a deal
in gain and getting the better of a deal
in gain and getting the better of a deal above level 200. So below 200 you have
above level 200. So below 200 you have
above level 200. So below 200 you have left brain dominance. Uh the mind is
left brain dominance. Uh the mind is
left brain dominance. Uh the mind is focused on linear content. It doesn't
focused on linear content. It doesn't
focused on linear content. It doesn't really grasp context.
really grasp context.
really grasp context. Is it wrong to monitor communications
Is it wrong to monitor communications
Is it wrong to monitor communications between Americans and uh the other side
between Americans and uh the other side
between Americans and uh the other side of the world? Uh you can argue it either
of the world? Uh you can argue it either
of the world? Uh you can argue it either way. It depends uh on context, doesn't
way. It depends uh on context, doesn't
way. It depends uh on context, doesn't it? If we're not at war, then it's an
it? If we're not at war, then it's an
it? If we're not at war, then it's an invasion of privacy. If it's if we are
invasion of privacy. If it's if we are
invasion of privacy. If it's if we are at war, then it's the obligation of the
at war, then it's the obligation of the
at war, then it's the obligation of the government to protect its citizens. So
government to protect its citizens. So
government to protect its citizens. So that's all imagine matter of context.
that's all imagine matter of context.
that's all imagine matter of context. So below 200 people don't get context
So below 200 people don't get context
So below 200 people don't get context that what goes in times of war does not
that what goes in times of war does not
that what goes in times of war does not go in times of peace. vice in versa. Or
go in times of peace. vice in versa. Or
go in times of peace. vice in versa. Or if this person has a certain disease,
if this person has a certain disease,
if this person has a certain disease, you don't allow him to travel uh and
you don't allow him to travel uh and
you don't allow him to travel uh and infect others. Infect others. You see,
infect others. Infect others. You see,
infect others. Infect others. You see, is that a civil rights violation? We
is that a civil rights violation? We
is that a civil rights violation? We don't allow him on the plane. If he's
don't allow him on the plane. If he's
don't allow him on the plane. If he's got an incurable form of very active
got an incurable form of very active
got an incurable form of very active tuberculosis, no, we don't love leave
tuberculosis, no, we don't love leave
tuberculosis, no, we don't love leave him on the plane. Why? Because of the
him on the plane. Why? Because of the
him on the plane. Why? Because of the context.
context.
context. All right? So, the right brain then
All right? So, the right brain then
All right? So, the right brain then works in a different way. It releases
works in a different way. It releases
works in a different way. It releases endorphins
endorphins
endorphins and uh a different set of emotions
and uh a different set of emotions
and uh a different set of emotions to people say what can I do to advance
to people say what can I do to advance
to people say what can I do to advance my own spiritual development. And I
my own spiritual development. And I
my own spiritual development. And I always say be as loving as poss as you
always say be as loving as poss as you
always say be as loving as poss as you can be and considerate of uh of all of
can be and considerate of uh of all of
can be and considerate of uh of all of all of existence and all of life. To be
all of existence and all of life. To be
all of existence and all of life. To be kind and considerate also means not only
kind and considerate also means not only
kind and considerate also means not only to God and your fellow man but also to
to God and your fellow man but also to
to God and your fellow man but also to yourself.
yourself.
yourself. So when people attack themsel with guil
So when people attack themsel with guil
So when people attack themsel with guil guilt, they're violating that principle.
guilt, they're violating that principle.
guilt, they're violating that principle. You can correct yourself without
You can correct yourself without
You can correct yourself without attacking yourself with guilt. You don't
attacking yourself with guilt. You don't
attacking yourself with guilt. You don't really have to hate yourself. Oh, I hate
really have to hate yourself. Oh, I hate
really have to hate yourself. Oh, I hate myself for something. You don't have to
myself for something. You don't have to
myself for something. You don't have to hate yourself. Uh so out of benevolence,
hate yourself. Uh so out of benevolence,
hate yourself. Uh so out of benevolence, so bene this benevolence should be
so bene this benevolence should be
so bene this benevolence should be extended to all living things, all
extended to all living things, all
extended to all living things, all living creatures. You see the little
living creatures. You see the little
living creatures. You see the little beetle with his legs flying in the wind
beetle with his legs flying in the wind
beetle with his legs flying in the wind and you you just put him over on his
and you you just put him over on his
and you you just put him over on his feet so he can walk away again. That
feet so he can walk away again. That
feet so he can walk away again. That same benevolence you forget to
same benevolence you forget to
same benevolence you forget to afford your own self.
afford your own self.
afford your own self. What you would do for the black beetle,
What you would do for the black beetle,
What you would do for the black beetle, please do that for yourself as well.
please do that for yourself as well.
please do that for yourself as well. Include yourself as deserving of
Include yourself as deserving of
Include yourself as deserving of compassion and consideration and
compassion and consideration and
compassion and consideration and lovingness. Yeah. All right. So the
lovingness. Yeah. All right. So the
lovingness. Yeah. All right. So the difficulty these two civilizations,
difficulty these two civilizations,
difficulty these two civilizations, they're really two different
they're really two different
they're really two different civilizations have in getting along is
civilizations have in getting along is
civilizations have in getting along is for one thing, they use different sides
for one thing, they use different sides
for one thing, they use different sides of the brain.
of the brain.
of the brain. So how are you going to get uh uh one
So how are you going to get uh uh one
So how are you going to get uh uh one side of the brain synchronized with the
side of the brain synchronized with the
side of the brain synchronized with the other side of the brain? And that's some
other side of the brain? And that's some
other side of the brain? And that's some we're going to be talking about today.
we're going to be talking about today.
we're going to be talking about today. Yes. Okay. Okay, the next one
Yes. Okay. Okay, the next one
Yes. Okay. Okay, the next one uh this has to do with uh the rate of
uh this has to do with uh the rate of
uh this has to do with uh the rate of happiness.
happiness.
happiness. Uh people uh say that you know happiness
Uh people uh say that you know happiness
Uh people uh say that you know happiness is due to things that are out there or
is due to things that are out there or
is due to things that are out there or it's society's fault or people are being
it's society's fault or people are being
it's society's fault or people are being deprived of happiness.
deprived of happiness.
deprived of happiness. I've been rich and I've been poor and
I've been rich and I've been poor and
I've been rich and I've been poor and frankly I didn't notice it had any
frankly I didn't notice it had any
frankly I didn't notice it had any impact at all on happiness.
impact at all on happiness.
impact at all on happiness. It sure had an impact on what you wear.
I was so poor. People used to laugh at
I was so poor. People used to laugh at my clothes, you know,
my clothes, you know,
my clothes, you know, and I and I got a really sought after
and I and I got a really sought after
and I and I got a really sought after residency at this Mount Sinai Hospital
residency at this Mount Sinai Hospital
residency at this Mount Sinai Hospital in New York, the best analysts and
in New York, the best analysts and
in New York, the best analysts and everybody was on the staff. And one day
everybody was on the staff. And one day
everybody was on the staff. And one day the chief secretary called me and she
the chief secretary called me and she
the chief secretary called me and she said to me, "You can't come you can't
said to me, "You can't come you can't
said to me, "You can't come you can't come here dressed like that. You've got
come here dressed like that. You've got
come here dressed like that. You've got to get better clothes."
to get better clothes."
to get better clothes." I had no money. So where am I going to
I had no money. So where am I going to
I had no money. So where am I going to get better clothes with no money? Yes.
get better clothes with no money? Yes.
get better clothes with no money? Yes. All right.
All right.
All right. The level of h level of happiness has to
The level of h level of happiness has to
The level of h level of happiness has to do with the level of consciousness. Has
do with the level of consciousness. Has
do with the level of consciousness. Has to do with level of consciousness. Uh
to do with level of consciousness. Uh
to do with level of consciousness. Uh and the higher the level of
and the higher the level of
and the higher the level of consciousness, the higher the level of
consciousness, the higher the level of
consciousness, the higher the level of happiness. And you can see as
happiness. And you can see as
happiness. And you can see as consciousness once it goes over level
consciousness once it goes over level
consciousness once it goes over level 200 the the percent of happiness below
200 the the percent of happiness below
200 the the percent of happiness below 200 hardly anybody's happy hardly
200 hardly anybody's happy hardly
200 hardly anybody's happy hardly anybody's happy and uh at 200 suddenly
anybody's happy and uh at 200 suddenly
anybody's happy and uh at 200 suddenly it jump from 22 to 55%
it jump from 22 to 55%
it jump from 22 to 55% and it's consciousness level goes up
and it's consciousness level goes up
and it's consciousness level goes up so in a in a group like this
so in a in a group like this
so in a in a group like this uh what does that say 89
uh what does that say 89
uh what does that say 89 >> all All right. Uh 89% of everybody
>> all All right. Uh 89% of everybody
>> all All right. Uh 89% of everybody sitting here should be happy at least.
If somebody's unhappy, let's cure that
If somebody's unhappy, let's cure that person instantly.
person instantly.
person instantly. Somebody's unhappy out there, please
Somebody's unhappy out there, please
Somebody's unhappy out there, please raise your hand.
raise your hand.
raise your hand. Is there an unhappy person?
Is there an unhappy person?
Is there an unhappy person? Unhappy. Unhappy.
Unhappy. Unhappy.
Unhappy. Unhappy. Unhappy it can be.
Unhappy it can be.
Unhappy it can be. Nobody's miserable today.
Nobody's miserable today.
Nobody's miserable today. Good God. How can I I got to import
Good God. How can I I got to import
Good God. How can I I got to import somebody miserable to sit in the
somebody miserable to sit in the
somebody miserable to sit in the audience. Otherwise, they'll think we're
audience. Otherwise, they'll think we're
audience. Otherwise, they'll think we're faking it.
faking it.
faking it. It couldn't be that everybody in this
It couldn't be that everybody in this
It couldn't be that everybody in this room is happy. Yes, I'd say everybody in
room is happy. Yes, I'd say everybody in
room is happy. Yes, I'd say everybody in this room is relatively happy. Happiness
this room is relatively happy. Happiness
this room is relatively happy. Happiness is relative, you know. Uh, okay. What's
is relative, you know. Uh, okay. What's
is relative, you know. Uh, okay. What's next?
Oh, what does that say? Perception
Oh, what does that say? Perception versus
versus
versus essence. Uh, that's too complicated.
essence. Uh, that's too complicated.
essence. Uh, that's too complicated. Let's move to the next one.
I don't want to
I don't want to bust my brain this morning. Perception
bust my brain this morning. Perception
bust my brain this morning. Perception versus essence. I thought it was a
versus essence. I thought it was a
versus essence. I thought it was a picture.
Let's move to the next one.
Let's move to the next one. All right. We're going to be talking
All right. We're going to be talking
All right. We're going to be talking about reason and faith. Reason and
about reason and faith. Reason and
about reason and faith. Reason and faith. And probably one of the best
faith. And probably one of the best
faith. And probably one of the best exhibits of reason are the great
exhibits of reason are the great
exhibits of reason are the great scientists. The great scientists are all
scientists. The great scientists are all
scientists. The great scientists are all in the mid 400s and they exhibit the
in the mid 400s and they exhibit the
in the mid 400s and they exhibit the great benefit of thinking this uh and
great benefit of thinking this uh and
great benefit of thinking this uh and reason goes up to the highest level of
reason goes up to the highest level of
reason goes up to the highest level of about 499.
about 499.
about 499. 499 is Sigman Freud, Albert Einstein,
499 is Sigman Freud, Albert Einstein,
499 is Sigman Freud, Albert Einstein, uh Sir Isaac Newton
uh Sir Isaac Newton
uh Sir Isaac Newton and of course they have changed all of
and of course they have changed all of
and of course they have changed all of our lives forever. So the 400s are
our lives forever. So the 400s are
our lives forever. So the 400s are extremely powerful
extremely powerful
extremely powerful and we if it wasn't for the 400s most of
and we if it wasn't for the 400s most of
and we if it wasn't for the 400s most of us wouldn't be alive because out of the
us wouldn't be alive because out of the
us wouldn't be alive because out of the 400s came antibiotics
400s came antibiotics
400s came antibiotics and the cures of many diseases
and the cures of many diseases
and the cures of many diseases pasteurizing milk etc. Uh all the things
pasteurizing milk etc. Uh all the things
pasteurizing milk etc. Uh all the things that are responsible for our being alive
that are responsible for our being alive
that are responsible for our being alive have come out of the 400s. So logic and
have come out of the 400s. So logic and
have come out of the 400s. So logic and reason are extremely powerful. So the
reason are extremely powerful. So the
reason are extremely powerful. So the 400s are very po is a very powerful
400s are very po is a very powerful
400s are very po is a very powerful level and most of the people in this
level and most of the people in this
level and most of the people in this room will be in the high 400s and or the
room will be in the high 400s and or the
room will be in the high 400s and or the in the middle of f 5 500s. Okay. So
in the middle of f 5 500s. Okay. So
in the middle of f 5 500s. Okay. So let's move on. So we owe a great deal to
let's move on. So we owe a great deal to
let's move on. So we owe a great deal to science.
science.
science. God versus science of course is very
God versus science of course is very
God versus science of course is very common in today's world. The big
common in today's world. The big
common in today's world. The big argument uh between them and we'll get
argument uh between them and we'll get
argument uh between them and we'll get back to here's St. Thomas Aquinus there.
back to here's St. Thomas Aquinus there.
back to here's St. Thomas Aquinus there. 570. Yes, that's who I was holding in
570. Yes, that's who I was holding in
570. Yes, that's who I was holding in mind. Okay. So, we'll move on.
mind. Okay. So, we'll move on.
mind. Okay. So, we'll move on. Uh
because in every audience there's a die
because in every audience there's a die hard that doesn't want to give up his
hard that doesn't want to give up his
hard that doesn't want to give up his allegiance to perception.
allegiance to perception.
allegiance to perception. This is confrontational.
This is confrontational.
This is confrontational. Uh what a thing looks like is not
Uh what a thing looks like is not
Uh what a thing looks like is not necessarily what it is. What it is, you
necessarily what it is. What it is, you
necessarily what it is. What it is, you know, and that explains politics,
know, and that explains politics,
know, and that explains politics, doesn't it?
doesn't it?
doesn't it? What a thing looks like. Perception is
What a thing looks like. Perception is
What a thing looks like. Perception is not the same as essence. And the most
not the same as essence. And the most
not the same as essence. And the most important thing that we really learn out
important thing that we really learn out
important thing that we really learn out of the work that we've done on
of the work that we've done on
of the work that we've done on consciousness is is how to discern
consciousness is is how to discern
consciousness is is how to discern essence from appearance. Yes. Okay. Next
essence from appearance. Yes. Okay. Next
essence from appearance. Yes. Okay. Next one. So, there's our good old wolf.
one. So, there's our good old wolf.
one. So, there's our good old wolf. Um, now what we're talking about today
Um, now what we're talking about today
Um, now what we're talking about today is the contrast of reason and faith. And
is the contrast of reason and faith. And
is the contrast of reason and faith. And I wasn't quite sure how to organize it.
I wasn't quite sure how to organize it.
I wasn't quite sure how to organize it. I organized it and reorganized it
I organized it and reorganized it
I organized it and reorganized it several times. Uh, but we ended up this
several times. Uh, but we ended up this
several times. Uh, but we ended up this way. Uh,
way. Uh,
way. Uh, there's conflict and then there's
there's conflict and then there's
there's conflict and then there's coherence between reason and faith.
coherence between reason and faith.
coherence between reason and faith. reason and faith can become uh
reason and faith can become uh
reason and faith can become uh hypothetically enemies etc. So conflict
hypothetically enemies etc. So conflict
hypothetically enemies etc. So conflict appear appears between them and the
appear appears between them and the
appear appears between them and the Scopes trial is probably the best
Scopes trial is probably the best
Scopes trial is probably the best example. The Scopes trial which is
example. The Scopes trial which is
example. The Scopes trial which is reemerged in today's society and just
reemerged in today's society and just
reemerged in today's society and just new clothes and different words was in
new clothes and different words was in
new clothes and different words was in 1926
in 1926 and uh you're all familiar with
in 1926 and uh you're all familiar with the Scopes trial. It had to do with
the Scopes trial. It had to do with
the Scopes trial. It had to do with Clarence Darrow
Clarence Darrow
Clarence Darrow and versus
and versus
and versus Brian. Brian was a
Brian. Brian was a
Brian. Brian was a a believer in God. He calibrated over
a believer in God. He calibrated over
a believer in God. He calibrated over 500. Clarence Darrow was no um I mean he
500. Clarence Darrow was no um I mean he
500. Clarence Darrow was no um I mean he was a brainy guy. He calibrated at 450.
was a brainy guy. He calibrated at 450.
was a brainy guy. He calibrated at 450. So the scopes trial was set up
So the scopes trial was set up
So the scopes trial was set up artificially.
artificially.
artificially. It was meant to get publicity for the
It was meant to get publicity for the
It was meant to get publicity for the local town where the population had
local town where the population had
local town where the population had dropped from 3,000 down to 1,000.
dropped from 3,000 down to 1,000.
dropped from 3,000 down to 1,000. So they put it on uh in order to attract
So they put it on uh in order to attract
So they put it on uh in order to attract publicity.
publicity.
publicity. Uh and it was also occasioned by the
Uh and it was also occasioned by the
Uh and it was also occasioned by the founder of the ACLU
founder of the ACLU
founder of the ACLU um to attract attention to the ACLU.
um to attract attention to the ACLU.
um to attract attention to the ACLU. U and of course it was it ended up as a
U and of course it was it ended up as a
U and of course it was it ended up as a famous movie Inherit the Wind and the
famous movie Inherit the Wind and the
famous movie Inherit the Wind and the thing about it is that it it it
thing about it is that it it it
thing about it is that it it it symbolizes the clash between reason and
symbolizes the clash between reason and
symbolizes the clash between reason and faith.
faith.
faith. Now, Daryl was at 450 and Daryl uh and
Now, Daryl was at 450 and Daryl uh and
Now, Daryl was at 450 and Daryl uh and Brian was a was a theist. So, Brian was
Brian was a was a theist. So, Brian was
Brian was a was a theist. So, Brian was a theist. So, he came from faith and
a theist. So, he came from faith and
a theist. So, he came from faith and Daryl came from reason. So, the Scopes
Daryl came from reason. So, the Scopes
Daryl came from reason. So, the Scopes trial is the classic clash between faith
trial is the classic clash between faith
trial is the classic clash between faith and reason.
and reason.
and reason. So, reason uh ridiculed some of the
So, reason uh ridiculed some of the
So, reason uh ridiculed some of the things that Brian believed in. uh it
things that Brian believed in. uh it
things that Brian believed in. uh it took things out of the Bible and uh
took things out of the Bible and uh
took things out of the Bible and uh asked him if he really believed that you
asked him if he really believed that you
asked him if he really believed that you know in light of today's science trying
know in light of today's science trying
know in light of today's science trying to make him look ridiculous. So actually
to make him look ridiculous. So actually
to make him look ridiculous. So actually Daryl couldn't win the argument on the
Daryl couldn't win the argument on the
Daryl couldn't win the argument on the grounds on the grounds of the argument
grounds on the grounds of the argument
grounds on the grounds of the argument and he really uh went to homminum
and he really uh went to homminum
and he really uh went to homminum attacks uh against Brian uh to ridicule
attacks uh against Brian uh to ridicule
attacks uh against Brian uh to ridicule him for believing in things in the
him for believing in things in the
him for believing in things in the Bible. Yeah.
Bible. Yeah.
Bible. Yeah. So the Scopes trial then was a very
So the Scopes trial then was a very
So the Scopes trial then was a very classic conflict. So that's what happens
classic conflict. So that's what happens
classic conflict. So that's what happens when we have conflict. Conflict between
when we have conflict. Conflict between
when we have conflict. Conflict between reason and faith uh ends up is the
reason and faith uh ends up is the
reason and faith uh ends up is the Scopes trial. Now the Scopes trial is
Scopes trial. Now the Scopes trial is
Scopes trial. Now the Scopes trial is very interesting because it exhibits
very interesting because it exhibits
very interesting because it exhibits uh
uh
uh a defect of reasoning. The Scopes trial
a defect of reasoning. The Scopes trial
a defect of reasoning. The Scopes trial is really talking about different
is really talking about different
is really talking about different paradigms. So when we talk about the
paradigms. So when we talk about the
paradigms. So when we talk about the calibrated levels of consciousness those
calibrated levels of consciousness those
calibrated levels of consciousness those are different paradigms
are different paradigms
are different paradigms the mid for the 400s is the par is is
the mid for the 400s is the par is is
the mid for the 400s is the par is is reason and logic that's provability
reason and logic that's provability
reason and logic that's provability and that is uh content and that's linear
and that is uh content and that's linear
and that is uh content and that's linear that is one paradigm of reality
that is one paradigm of reality
that is one paradigm of reality however it does not include the entire
however it does not include the entire
however it does not include the entire universe or that which is infinite
universe or that which is infinite
universe or that which is infinite that's one paradigm And of each paradigm
that's one paradigm And of each paradigm
that's one paradigm And of each paradigm then is its own you might say altitude
then is its own you might say altitude
then is its own you might say altitude from which it looks at the world.
from which it looks at the world.
from which it looks at the world. U
U
U Brian was speaking from faith and faith
Brian was speaking from faith and faith
Brian was speaking from faith and faith is a different paradigm. So the level of
is a different paradigm. So the level of
is a different paradigm. So the level of the 400s is linear provable science
the 400s is linear provable science
the 400s is linear provable science scientific and of great benefit to the
scientific and of great benefit to the
scientific and of great benefit to the world. Uh the level of the 500s is
world. Uh the level of the 500s is
world. Uh the level of the 500s is context. So you can prove content with
context. So you can prove content with
context. So you can prove content with logic and mathematics and science. You
logic and mathematics and science. You
logic and mathematics and science. You cannot prove context. You cannot prove
cannot prove context. You cannot prove
cannot prove context. You cannot prove that it's a nice day today.
You can say I like it today. Well,
You can say I like it today. Well, that's your perception. That doesn't
that's your perception. That doesn't
that's your perception. That doesn't mean it is a nice day. So con context
mean it is a nice day. So con context
mean it is a nice day. So con context then uh changes the significance and the
then uh changes the significance and the
then uh changes the significance and the impact and the meaning of content. So
impact and the meaning of content. So
impact and the meaning of content. So the scopes trial is really two different
the scopes trial is really two different
the scopes trial is really two different paradigms of reality.
paradigms of reality.
paradigms of reality. Two different paradigms
Two different paradigms
Two different paradigms and realizing that the problem is one of
and realizing that the problem is one of
and realizing that the problem is one of paradigms solves a great many problems.
We contrast the scopes trial with which
We contrast the scopes trial with which causes exhibits conflict between reason
causes exhibits conflict between reason
causes exhibits conflict between reason and faith. That's conflict. So how do we
and faith. That's conflict. So how do we
and faith. That's conflict. So how do we bring about coherence? St. Thomas
bring about coherence? St. Thomas
bring about coherence? St. Thomas Aquinus, St. Thomas Aquinus,
Aquinus, St. Thomas Aquinus,
Aquinus, St. Thomas Aquinus, the doctor of the church um calibrates
the doctor of the church um calibrates
the doctor of the church um calibrates at 570.
at 570.
at 570. So Thomas Aquinus said that faith you
So Thomas Aquinus said that faith you
So Thomas Aquinus said that faith you know that faith needs to be reinforced
know that faith needs to be reinforced
know that faith needs to be reinforced by reason and that reason is reinforced
by reason and that reason is reinforced
by reason and that reason is reinforced by faith. As some of theologica, one of
by faith. As some of theologica, one of
by faith. As some of theologica, one of the most famous things ever written, he
the most famous things ever written, he
the most famous things ever written, he synthesizes
synthesizes
synthesizes reason and faith. And by the end of the
reason and faith. And by the end of the
reason and faith. And by the end of the lecture you'll see why today's
lecture you'll see why today's
lecture you'll see why today's you have to integrate reason and faith
you have to integrate reason and faith
you have to integrate reason and faith otherwise you end up with uh
otherwise you end up with uh
otherwise you end up with uh destruction. Yeah. So
destruction. Yeah. So
destruction. Yeah. So St. Thomas Aquinus was a great doctor of
St. Thomas Aquinus was a great doctor of
St. Thomas Aquinus was a great doctor of the church a doctor of theology. He
the church a doctor of theology. He
the church a doctor of theology. He calibrated 570.
calibrated 570.
calibrated 570. And when I went to Catholic uh uh
And when I went to Catholic uh uh
And when I went to Catholic uh uh university
university
university uh we learned a great deal about St.
uh we learned a great deal about St.
uh we learned a great deal about St. Thomas Aquinas. It was the core of many
Thomas Aquinas. It was the core of many
Thomas Aquinas. It was the core of many of the many of the Jesuit lectures.
of the many of the Jesuit lectures.
of the many of the Jesuit lectures. Uhhuh.
Uhhuh.
Uhhuh. So you see what the problem then is the
So you see what the problem then is the
So you see what the problem then is the conflict is one of paradigms
conflict is one of paradigms
conflict is one of paradigms and in how how is this coherent in
and in how how is this coherent in
and in how how is this coherent in traditional America the two paradigms
traditional America the two paradigms
traditional America the two paradigms were uh synthesized. You went to parac
were uh synthesized. You went to parac
were uh synthesized. You went to parac parochial school, you went to church on
parochial school, you went to church on
parochial school, you went to church on Sunday, and then you also learned
Sunday, and then you also learned
Sunday, and then you also learned science in school. But they weren't uh
science in school. But they weren't uh
science in school. But they weren't uh they were incorporated together. They
they were incorporated together. They
they were incorporated together. They were just two different paradigms. Now,
were just two different paradigms. Now,
were just two different paradigms. Now, people didn't use the name par paradigm,
people didn't use the name par paradigm,
people didn't use the name par paradigm, but you didn't see any conflict what you
but you didn't see any conflict what you
but you didn't see any conflict what you learn in science and school and what you
learn in science and school and what you
learn in science and school and what you heard in Sunday school on Sunday.
heard in Sunday school on Sunday.
heard in Sunday school on Sunday. traditional America. Traditional America
traditional America. Traditional America
traditional America. Traditional America then synthesized through its culture
then synthesized through its culture
then synthesized through its culture traditional America
traditional America
traditional America uh
uh
uh a working relationship between reason
a working relationship between reason
a working relationship between reason and faith.
and faith.
and faith. Uh so the parochial school then wasn't
Uh so the parochial school then wasn't
Uh so the parochial school then wasn't in conflict with the secular school. It
in conflict with the secular school. It
in conflict with the secular school. It was just in addition. We've already said
was just in addition. We've already said
was just in addition. We've already said that these shift out in leftbrain and
that these shift out in leftbrain and
that these shift out in leftbrain and right brain function. Uh let's take the
right brain function. Uh let's take the
right brain function. Uh let's take the pledge of allegiance. When I grew up,
pledge of allegiance. When I grew up,
pledge of allegiance. When I grew up, the pledge of allegiance uh we all
the pledge of allegiance uh we all
the pledge of allegiance uh we all started the school day with the pledge
started the school day with the pledge
started the school day with the pledge of allegiance. Pledge of allegiance to
of allegiance. Pledge of allegiance to
of allegiance. Pledge of allegiance to the flag of the United States and to the
the flag of the United States and to the
the flag of the United States and to the country for which it stands, etc. So we
country for which it stands, etc. So we
country for which it stands, etc. So we put our hand over our heart and nobody
put our hand over our heart and nobody
put our hand over our heart and nobody had any problem with it.
Nobody had any problem with it because
Nobody had any problem with it because that was consern considered to be
that was consern considered to be
that was consern considered to be normal. Everybody pledged allegiance.
normal. Everybody pledged allegiance.
normal. Everybody pledged allegiance. And there you had a synthesis of the
And there you had a synthesis of the
And there you had a synthesis of the left brain and the right brain through
left brain and the right brain through
left brain and the right brain through the pledge of allegiance.
the pledge of allegiance.
the pledge of allegiance. You can create an artificial dichotomy
You can create an artificial dichotomy
You can create an artificial dichotomy of church versus state. Um but this it's
of church versus state. Um but this it's
of church versus state. Um but this it's synthesized in the United States
synthesized in the United States
synthesized in the United States Constitution which guarantees not only
Constitution which guarantees not only
Constitution which guarantees not only freedom of religion but freedom from
freedom of religion but freedom from
freedom of religion but freedom from religion.
religion.
religion. Yeah, the Constitution United States
Yeah, the Constitution United States
Yeah, the Constitution United States calibrates higher than any uh on in the
calibrates higher than any uh on in the
calibrates higher than any uh on in the world. I forgot what it calibrated. The
world. I forgot what it calibrated. The
world. I forgot what it calibrated. The last time I calibrated it was many years
last time I calibrated it was many years
last time I calibrated it was many years ago. The US Constitution
ago. The US Constitution
ago. The US Constitution uh calibrates over. Well, I shouldn't
uh calibrates over. Well, I shouldn't
uh calibrates over. Well, I shouldn't tell you what I'm holding in mind. It
tell you what I'm holding in mind. It
tell you what I'm holding in mind. It calibrates over. When I'm holding in
calibrates over. When I'm holding in
calibrates over. When I'm holding in mind, it calibrates over 700, 750, 760,
mind, it calibrates over 700, 750, 760,
mind, it calibrates over 700, 750, 760, 765. Yeah, I remember it was around 770.
765. Yeah, I remember it was around 770.
765. Yeah, I remember it was around 770. There is nothing else on this planet
There is nothing else on this planet
There is nothing else on this planet that calibrates at 770
that calibrates at 770
that calibrates at 770 as the core of the nation.
as the core of the nation.
as the core of the nation. 770
770 freedom of religion and for religion all
freedom of religion and for religion all
freedom of religion and for religion all at the same time. So that means you can
at the same time. So that means you can
at the same time. So that means you can have it both ways. You can have it both
have it both ways. You can have it both
have it both ways. You can have it both ways. That brings social coherence. It
ways. That brings social coherence. It
ways. That brings social coherence. It brings intellectual coh coherence.
Now, the church versus the state, which
Now, the church versus the state, which is conflict,
is conflict,
is conflict, uh is exhibited by the ACLU. As we said,
uh is exhibited by the ACLU. As we said,
uh is exhibited by the ACLU. As we said, the ACLU was founded by a fellow named
the ACLU was founded by a fellow named
the ACLU was founded by a fellow named Baldwin who calibrates at 190. The ACULU
Baldwin who calibrates at 190. The ACULU
Baldwin who calibrates at 190. The ACULU calibrates at 140. I can't help it. They
calibrates at 140. I can't help it. They
calibrates at 140. I can't help it. They just do. the ACU
American civil rights uh versus American
American civil rights uh versus American civil liberties. So this is looking to
civil liberties. So this is looking to
civil liberties. So this is looking to get away from constraint of reason and
get away from constraint of reason and
get away from constraint of reason and logic etc. By liberty they mean uh
logic etc. By liberty they mean uh
logic etc. By liberty they mean uh non-constraint
non-constraint
non-constraint ACU
ACU
ACU which is one a great many cases against
which is one a great many cases against
which is one a great many cases against the reason Christmas came back this year
the reason Christmas came back this year
the reason Christmas came back this year is because of the ACRU
is because of the ACRU
is because of the ACRU at 460. It was started by group of
at 460. It was started by group of
at 460. It was started by group of ministers
ministers
ministers I think in Phoenix actually. So I donate
I think in Phoenix actually. So I donate
I think in Phoenix actually. So I donate to the ACRU because they brought back
to the ACRU because they brought back
to the ACRU because they brought back Christmas.
Remember Christmas was out. Everybody
Remember Christmas was out. Everybody was afraid to say Merry Christmas for fe
was afraid to say Merry Christmas for fe
was afraid to say Merry Christmas for fe for fear uh of the monster here. The
for fear uh of the monster here. The
for fear uh of the monster here. The monster has lots and lots of money and
monster has lots and lots of money and
monster has lots and lots of money and and and and
and and and
and and and will sue you. So you can't say you
will sue you. So you can't say you
will sue you. So you can't say you couldn't say happy merry Christmas in
couldn't say happy merry Christmas in
couldn't say happy merry Christmas in Gimbals because Gimbal's afraid afraid
Gimbals because Gimbal's afraid afraid
Gimbals because Gimbal's afraid afraid this joker here was going to sue him.
this joker here was going to sue him.
this joker here was going to sue him. So the ACU then shows a coherence. You
So the ACU then shows a coherence. You
So the ACU then shows a coherence. You can have freedom and etc all at the same
can have freedom and etc all at the same
can have freedom and etc all at the same time. So what represents then conflict?
time. So what represents then conflict?
time. So what represents then conflict? Michael Nudo like just like Maline
Michael Nudo like just like Maline
Michael Nudo like just like Maline O'Hare. Michael Nudo wants to remove in
O'Hare. Michael Nudo wants to remove in
O'Hare. Michael Nudo wants to remove in God we trust from the from the dollar
God we trust from the from the dollar
God we trust from the from the dollar bill.
bill.
bill. In God we trust. He wants that removed
In God we trust. He wants that removed
In God we trust. He wants that removed from the from United States money. Well
from the from United States money. Well
from the from United States money. Well now you if you picture how much United
now you if you picture how much United
now you if you picture how much United States money is distributed all over the
States money is distributed all over the
States money is distributed all over the planet. Thousands of tons of it. Can you
planet. Thousands of tons of it. Can you
planet. Thousands of tons of it. Can you imagine pulling that all back in and
imagine pulling that all back in and
imagine pulling that all back in and removing God
removing God
removing God from all the dollar dollar bills? It
from all the dollar dollar bills? It
from all the dollar dollar bills? It would cost a trillion dollars, right, to
would cost a trillion dollars, right, to
would cost a trillion dollars, right, to haul it all in. So, Michael Newud uh is
haul it all in. So, Michael Newud uh is
haul it all in. So, Michael Newud uh is our current exhibit. He the last thing
our current exhibit. He the last thing
our current exhibit. He the last thing he tried, he lost in the Supreme Court,
he tried, he lost in the Supreme Court,
he tried, he lost in the Supreme Court, but he did get it to the Supreme Court.
but he did get it to the Supreme Court.
but he did get it to the Supreme Court. uh in the last uh uh generation uh
uh in the last uh uh generation uh
uh in the last uh uh generation uh Maline Marie O'Hare
Maline Marie O'Hare
Maline Marie O'Hare uh she was described as the most hated
uh she was described as the most hated
uh she was described as the most hated person in America. She was the most
person in America. She was the most
person in America. She was the most hated person in America. Uh she
hated person in America. Uh she
hated person in America. Uh she challenged to say the prayer in school.
challenged to say the prayer in school.
challenged to say the prayer in school. So we no longer say the prayer in
So we no longer say the prayer in
So we no longer say the prayer in school, pledge of allegiance because of
school, pledge of allegiance because of
school, pledge of allegiance because of Meline
Meline
Meline who did not calibrate extremely high, in
who did not calibrate extremely high, in
who did not calibrate extremely high, in fact very low. I don't know where she is
fact very low. I don't know where she is
fact very low. I don't know where she is now. She's left the planet.
All right. So the founding fathers are
All right. So the founding fathers are in contrast to Maline O'Hare. The
in contrast to Maline O'Hare. The
in contrast to Maline O'Hare. The founding fathers brought freedom of
founding fathers brought freedom of
founding fathers brought freedom of religion and from religion. All right.
religion and from religion. All right.
religion and from religion. All right. So conflict then comes from secularism
So conflict then comes from secularism
So conflict then comes from secularism which is the attempt to remove any
which is the attempt to remove any
which is the attempt to remove any reference to divinity.
reference to divinity.
reference to divinity. In contrast to that we have get
In contrast to that we have get
In contrast to that we have get coherence from Billy Graham. Billy
coherence from Billy Graham. Billy
coherence from Billy Graham. Billy Graham is is amazing. Billy Graham
Graham is is amazing. Billy Graham
Graham is is amazing. Billy Graham calibrates extremely high. Forget how
calibrates extremely high. Forget how
calibrates extremely high. Forget how high he calibrates. Uh let's see. We
high he calibrates. Uh let's see. We
high he calibrates. Uh let's see. We have permission to do Billy Graham.
have permission to do Billy Graham.
have permission to do Billy Graham. Billy Graham is over 570
Billy Graham is over 570
Billy Graham is over 570 580. He's about the level of Saint 570
580. He's about the level of Saint 570
580. He's about the level of Saint 570 575. He's practically saying 570. The
575. He's practically saying 570. The
575. He's practically saying 570. The level of Santo is around 570. So here is
level of Santo is around 570. So here is
level of Santo is around 570. So here is somebody who counseledled I forget 11
somebody who counseledled I forget 11
somebody who counseledled I forget 11 presidents or 14 presidents.
presidents or 14 presidents.
presidents or 14 presidents. uh stood by every president of the
uh stood by every president of the
uh stood by every president of the United States all these generations all
United States all these generations all
United States all these generations all the presidents.
the presidents.
the presidents. Uh so in contrast to secularism which is
Uh so in contrast to secularism which is
Uh so in contrast to secularism which is conflict
conflict
conflict you have Billy Graham uh as an advisor
you have Billy Graham uh as an advisor
you have Billy Graham uh as an advisor to every president of the United States.
to every president of the United States.
to every president of the United States. I think the last 14 of them and think
I think the last 14 of them and think
I think the last 14 of them and think that I think there's a new book out on
that I think there's a new book out on
that I think there's a new book out on Billy Graham and uh so you really
Billy Graham and uh so you really
Billy Graham and uh so you really understand the the tremendous service
understand the the tremendous service
understand the the tremendous service this man has provided to the people of
this man has provided to the people of
this man has provided to the people of the United States. Uhhuh. And you can
the United States. Uhhuh. And you can
the United States. Uhhuh. And you can imagine the moral conflicts the moral
imagine the moral conflicts the moral
imagine the moral conflicts the moral conflict that every president is in. So
conflict that every president is in. So
conflict that every president is in. So every time I look at a president,
every time I look at a president,
every time I look at a president, what what I see is the tremendous moral
what what I see is the tremendous moral
what what I see is the tremendous moral conflict that he has in almost every
conflict that he has in almost every
conflict that he has in almost every turn. Almost every turn has a moral
turn. Almost every turn has a moral
turn. Almost every turn has a moral implication. Not just a legal, not just
implication. Not just a legal, not just
implication. Not just a legal, not just a political, but also a moral. I mean,
a political, but also a moral. I mean,
a political, but also a moral. I mean, you look at the releasing of the atomic
you look at the releasing of the atomic
you look at the releasing of the atomic bomb at the end of the Second World War.
bomb at the end of the Second World War.
bomb at the end of the Second World War. And imagine uh trying to make up your
And imagine uh trying to make up your
And imagine uh trying to make up your mind about that.
mind about that.
mind about that. Trying to make up your mind.
Trying to make up your mind.
Trying to make up your mind. So Billy Graham then shows the coherence
So Billy Graham then shows the coherence
So Billy Graham then shows the coherence of reason and uh and the success of the
of reason and uh and the success of the
of reason and uh and the success of the putting the two together. Extremism then
putting the two together. Extremism then
putting the two together. Extremism then is uh comes out of conflict whereas
is uh comes out of conflict whereas
is uh comes out of conflict whereas moderation moderation
moderation moderation
moderation moderation uh comes out of coherence.
uh comes out of coherence.
uh comes out of coherence. The when I think of the ACLU I think of
The when I think of the ACLU I think of
The when I think of the ACLU I think of the Grinch.
the Grinch.
the Grinch. The ACLU is just like the Grinch. Did
The ACLU is just like the Grinch. Did
The ACLU is just like the Grinch. Did you all see the Grinch again? Well, they
you all see the Grinch again? Well, they
you all see the Grinch again? Well, they showed it quite a bit this last
showed it quite a bit this last
showed it quite a bit this last Christmas. But the Grinch just hates
Christmas. But the Grinch just hates
Christmas. But the Grinch just hates Christmas. Michael Nunda and Meline
Christmas. Michael Nunda and Meline
Christmas. Michael Nunda and Meline O'Hare in the far left. They just hate
O'Hare in the far left. They just hate
O'Hare in the far left. They just hate they just hate Christmas. So the Grinch,
they just hate Christmas. So the Grinch,
they just hate Christmas. So the Grinch, I never calibrated the Grinch or the
I never calibrated the Grinch or the
I never calibrated the Grinch or the Dickens Christmas Carol. The Grinch
Dickens Christmas Carol. The Grinch
Dickens Christmas Carol. The Grinch symbolizes an energy. Can we have
symbolizes an energy. Can we have
symbolizes an energy. Can we have permission to do the Grinch? The Grinch
permission to do the Grinch? The Grinch
permission to do the Grinch? The Grinch calibrates over 190,
calibrates over 190,
calibrates over 190, 170,
170,
170, 150,
150,
150, 155, 160, 160, 7070, around 165. So the
155, 160, 160, 7070, around 165. So the
155, 160, 160, 7070, around 165. So the Grinch is around 165.
Grinch is around 165.
Grinch is around 165. Uh they Yeah, that's where the founder
Uh they Yeah, that's where the founder
Uh they Yeah, that's where the founder of the ACLU come in came in. The Grinch
of the ACLU come in came in. The Grinch
of the ACLU come in came in. The Grinch Dickens Christmas Carol contrast.
Dickens Christmas Carol contrast.
Dickens Christmas Carol contrast. Dickens Christmas Carol. We have
Dickens Christmas Carol. We have
Dickens Christmas Carol. We have permission to do that. is over 460, 500,
permission to do that. is over 460, 500,
permission to do that. is over 460, 500, 520 is 510. Dickens Christmas Carol is
520 is 510. Dickens Christmas Carol is
520 is 510. Dickens Christmas Carol is 510. It exhibits a totally different
510. It exhibits a totally different
510. It exhibits a totally different paradigm, doesn't it? Uh, so we here we
paradigm, doesn't it? Uh, so we here we
paradigm, doesn't it? Uh, so we here we have the Grinch and and the head Grinch
have the Grinch and and the head Grinch
have the Grinch and and the head Grinch right now is Michael Nudal.
right now is Michael Nudal.
right now is Michael Nudal. Meline turned over her crown to to
Meline turned over her crown to to
Meline turned over her crown to to Michael.
Michael.
Michael. and the the tradition of the Grinch is
and the the tradition of the Grinch is
and the the tradition of the Grinch is carried on. Um Mhm. The Christmas Carol
carried on. Um Mhm. The Christmas Carol
carried on. Um Mhm. The Christmas Carol of course is such a wonderful uh story.
of course is such a wonderful uh story.
of course is such a wonderful uh story. Conflict in today's world is certainly
Conflict in today's world is certainly
Conflict in today's world is certainly centered around the Quran. Uh one reason
centered around the Quran. Uh one reason
centered around the Quran. Uh one reason it's centered around the Quran is that
it's centered around the Quran is that
it's centered around the Quran is that um about 30% of the verses of the Quran
um about 30% of the verses of the Quran
um about 30% of the verses of the Quran calibrate below 200. Actually 15%
calibrate below 200. Actually 15%
calibrate below 200. Actually 15% calibrate calibrate below 100.
Uhhuh.
Uhhuh. Calibrate below 100. All right. The
Calibrate below 100. All right. The
Calibrate below 100. All right. The Quran does not even agree with itself.
Quran does not even agree with itself.
Quran does not even agree with itself. If you've ever read the Quran, how many
If you've ever read the Quran, how many
If you've ever read the Quran, how many people have read the Quran here?
people have read the Quran here?
people have read the Quran here? It's quite a bit bit of work to read
It's quite a bit bit of work to read
It's quite a bit bit of work to read from beginning to end. And uh it's sort
from beginning to end. And uh it's sort
from beginning to end. And uh it's sort of patched together from all kinds of
of patched together from all kinds of
of patched together from all kinds of things. But the difficulty with the
things. But the difficulty with the
things. But the difficulty with the Quran, you see, because we're talking
Quran, you see, because we're talking
Quran, you see, because we're talking about conflict and we can see Quran, the
about conflict and we can see Quran, the
about conflict and we can see Quran, the Quran is central to today's
Quran is central to today's
Quran is central to today's international conflict is that the
international conflict is that the
international conflict is that the verses do not agree with themselves.
verses do not agree with themselves.
verses do not agree with themselves. They do not agree with themselves.
They do not agree with themselves.
They do not agree with themselves. And so there's endless conflict. You can
And so there's endless conflict. You can
And so there's endless conflict. You can say anything you want and then
say anything you want and then
say anything you want and then justify it by the fact that it's in the
justify it by the fact that it's in the
justify it by the fact that it's in the Quran. you can kill all the infidels
Quran. you can kill all the infidels
Quran. you can kill all the infidels and it's there in the Quran. It'll tell
and it's there in the Quran. It'll tell
and it's there in the Quran. It'll tell you kill them all.
you kill them all.
you kill them all. Uh so how do you get some kind of
Uh so how do you get some kind of
Uh so how do you get some kind of coherence out of it? And that is the
coherence out of it? And that is the
coherence out of it? And that is the principle of abrogation. So you can't
principle of abrogation. So you can't
principle of abrogation. So you can't read the Quran without understanding the
read the Quran without understanding the
read the Quran without understanding the principle of abrogation.
principle of abrogation.
principle of abrogation. What it means is that which is towards
What it means is that which is towards
What it means is that which is towards the back of the Quran overrules that
the back of the Quran overrules that
the back of the Quran overrules that which is in the beginning. So if in an
which is in the beginning. So if in an
which is in the beginning. So if in an early chapter it says allow something
early chapter it says allow something
early chapter it says allow something and then in the later chapter it says do
and then in the later chapter it says do
and then in the later chapter it says do not allow something then what you come
not allow something then what you come
not allow something then what you come away with is you do not allow. So
away with is you do not allow. So
away with is you do not allow. So abregation is an attempt
abregation is an attempt
abregation is an attempt to synthesize that which is
to synthesize that which is
to synthesize that which is intrinsically within itself in conflict
intrinsically within itself in conflict
intrinsically within itself in conflict the abrogation. Therefore, you cannot
the abrogation. Therefore, you cannot
the abrogation. Therefore, you cannot read the Quran without being aware that
read the Quran without being aware that
read the Quran without being aware that the later chapters cancel out the early
the later chapters cancel out the early
the later chapters cancel out the early one. Uh
one. Uh
one. Uh one of the biggest impacts in today's
one of the biggest impacts in today's
one of the biggest impacts in today's world is uh addiction and it's certainly
world is uh addiction and it's certainly
world is uh addiction and it's certainly currently in the news.
currently in the news.
currently in the news. All the stars, everybody dying from one
All the stars, everybody dying from one
All the stars, everybody dying from one addiction or another.
addiction or another.
addiction or another. uh all the famous people, the Hollywood
uh all the famous people, the Hollywood
uh all the famous people, the Hollywood stars.
stars.
stars. So addiction then is of course very
So addiction then is of course very
So addiction then is of course very conflictual. It's very poorly
conflictual. It's very poorly
conflictual. It's very poorly understandtood by the public at large.
understandtood by the public at large.
understandtood by the public at large. It's not even well understood by some of
It's not even well understood by some of
It's not even well understood by some of the professionals that come on and talk
the professionals that come on and talk
the professionals that come on and talk learnedly about it.
It certainly uh shows conflict within
It certainly uh shows conflict within the person as well as between the person
the person as well as between the person
the person as well as between the person and the relationships and the world and
and the relationships and the world and
and the relationships and the world and uh the synthesis the synthesis that
uh the synthesis the synthesis that
uh the synthesis the synthesis that allows the resolution of the conflict of
allows the resolution of the conflict of
allows the resolution of the conflict of course is the 12step groups and the
course is the 12step groups and the
course is the 12step groups and the 12step groups have had a major impact uh
12step groups have had a major impact uh
12step groups have had a major impact uh on our culture quietly they have the
on our culture quietly they have the
on our culture quietly they have the most positive impact of any
most positive impact of any
most positive impact of any in the book I just finished we did the
in the book I just finished we did the
in the book I just finished we did the impact of the various religions itself.
impact of the various religions itself.
impact of the various religions itself. So Christianity, Judaism and all those
So Christianity, Judaism and all those
So Christianity, Judaism and all those uh formal tradition religions their
uh formal tradition religions their
uh formal tradition religions their impact in society calibrates at 450
impact in society calibrates at 450
impact in society calibrates at 450 that certainly is a high degree of
that certainly is a high degree of
that certainly is a high degree of goodness that shows a high degree of
goodness that shows a high degree of
goodness that shows a high degree of coherence of uh reason and faith.
coherence of uh reason and faith.
coherence of uh reason and faith. The te the 12step groups however uh
The te the 12step groups however uh
The te the 12step groups however uh impact us society at level 570
impact us society at level 570
impact us society at level 570 that's far beyond the 450.
that's far beyond the 450.
that's far beyond the 450. So the the hit the hit the impact that
So the the hit the hit the impact that
So the the hit the hit the impact that 12step groups have on society is of a
12step groups have on society is of a
12step groups have on society is of a higher level and more profound than even
higher level and more profound than even
higher level and more profound than even classic uh religion. Uh and most people
classic uh religion. Uh and most people
classic uh religion. Uh and most people seek out 12step groups for now for a
seek out 12step groups for now for a
seek out 12step groups for now for a great variety of things, not only
great variety of things, not only
great variety of things, not only alcoholism but all kinds of addictions
alcoholism but all kinds of addictions
alcoholism but all kinds of addictions and misbehaviors
and misbehaviors
and misbehaviors uh and psychological difficulties.
uh and psychological difficulties.
uh and psychological difficulties. Uh because the 12step groups synthesize
Uh because the 12step groups synthesize
Uh because the 12step groups synthesize uh into coherence,
uh into coherence,
uh into coherence, synthesize uh reason and logic. It
synthesize uh reason and logic. It
synthesize uh reason and logic. It synthesizes content in terms of context
synthesizes content in terms of context
synthesizes content in terms of context and the 12 steps of AA uh are really
and the 12 steps of AA uh are really
and the 12 steps of AA uh are really good for everybody to know
good for everybody to know
good for everybody to know u because whatever problem you have in
u because whatever problem you have in
u because whatever problem you have in life if you apply it to the 12 steps to
life if you apply it to the 12 steps to
life if you apply it to the 12 steps to it you'll resolve it. Let's see if
it you'll resolve it. Let's see if
it you'll resolve it. Let's see if that's so. It's an amazing statement,
that's so. It's an amazing statement,
that's so. It's an amazing statement, didn't I? I say that. Yep. That is so.
didn't I? I say that. Yep. That is so.
didn't I? I say that. Yep. That is so. Well,
Well,
Well, even if you're broke, we just Yep.
So, everybody in our society knows that
So, everybody in our society knows that 12step groups uh are benign. Benign in
12step groups uh are benign. Benign in
12step groups uh are benign. Benign in intention. They're totally
intention. They're totally
intention. They're totally non-conlictual.
non-conlictual.
non-conlictual. They have no opinion on outside issues.
They have no opinion on outside issues.
They have no opinion on outside issues. So, you can't get into an argument with
So, you can't get into an argument with
So, you can't get into an argument with them because they don't have any
them because they don't have any
them because they don't have any position you can argue with.
Uh so they they exhibit uh probably the
Uh so they they exhibit uh probably the highest value of a social group in in
highest value of a social group in in
highest value of a social group in in our society and they've infiltrated all
our society and they've infiltrated all
our society and they've infiltrated all levels of government and of course
levels of government and of course
levels of government and of course uh various people who are extremely
uh various people who are extremely
uh various people who are extremely wellknown have recovered in in the
wellknown have recovered in in the
wellknown have recovered in in the 12step groups. So they they form a
12step groups. So they they form a
12step groups. So they they form a paradigm of recovery from uh almost
paradigm of recovery from uh almost
paradigm of recovery from uh almost anything gambling
anything gambling
anything gambling sexual addiction um being a failure.
sexual addiction um being a failure.
sexual addiction um being a failure. Some people are addicted to being a
Some people are addicted to being a
Some people are addicted to being a failure. I mean, you get so much juice
failure. I mean, you get so much juice
failure. I mean, you get so much juice out of being a failure, you just can't
out of being a failure, you just can't
out of being a failure, you just can't help but keep failing over and over
help but keep failing over and over
help but keep failing over and over again. So, you see a negative pattern in
again. So, you see a negative pattern in
again. So, you see a negative pattern in your life, I suggest looking at the into
your life, I suggest looking at the into
your life, I suggest looking at the into the 12step groups and learning the 12
the 12step groups and learning the 12
the 12step groups and learning the 12 steps and applying it to that problem.
steps and applying it to that problem.
steps and applying it to that problem. Even if you're stupid and ugly, you can
Even if you're stupid and ugly, you can
Even if you're stupid and ugly, you can end up happy.
You can just let go on to change it and
You can just let go on to change it and turn it over to God and pray for advice.
turn it over to God and pray for advice.
turn it over to God and pray for advice. And he says, "You may be ugly, but
And he says, "You may be ugly, but
And he says, "You may be ugly, but you're lovable." Oh,
you may be stupid stupid and ugly, but
you may be stupid stupid and ugly, but you're you're huggable. There you go.
you're you're huggable. There you go.
you're you're huggable. There you go. What more do you want?
What more do you want?
What more do you want? What more do you want? All right. So,
What more do you want? All right. So,
What more do you want? All right. So, any questions about that right now?
any questions about that right now?
any questions about that right now? Anybody got any burning question about
Anybody got any burning question about
Anybody got any burning question about about it? How these things calibrate and
about it? How these things calibrate and
about it? How these things calibrate and the contrast between reason and faith?
the contrast between reason and faith?
the contrast between reason and faith? But you can see they can be used to
But you can see they can be used to
But you can see they can be used to support each other or to attack each
support each other or to attack each
support each other or to attack each other that which is conflictual then
other that which is conflictual then
other that which is conflictual then uses it uh to attack. So these these
uses it uh to attack. So these these
uses it uh to attack. So these these extremes here uh bring about uh
extremes here uh bring about uh
extremes here uh bring about uh disruption in society and what we strive
disruption in society and what we strive
disruption in society and what we strive for in our own spiritual life is a
for in our own spiritual life is a
for in our own spiritual life is a synthesis of reason and faith u into a
synthesis of reason and faith u into a
synthesis of reason and faith u into a workable daily daily uh daily life.
workable daily daily uh daily life.
workable daily daily uh daily life. What's the next one now?
What's the next one now?
What's the next one now? Uh next slide.
Uh next slide.
Uh next slide. Uh that slide uh two. Yes.
Uh that slide uh two. Yes.
Uh that slide uh two. Yes. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Yeah, we've got it. Okay. Fine. All
Yeah, we've got it. Okay. Fine. All
Yeah, we've got it. Okay. Fine. All right. So, conflict then comes out of we
right. So, conflict then comes out of we
right. So, conflict then comes out of we said before left brain and right brain
said before left brain and right brain
said before left brain and right brain have different functions and this
have different functions and this
have different functions and this audience is relatively familiar with
audience is relatively familiar with
audience is relatively familiar with that.
that.
that. uh left brain has to do with reason and
uh left brain has to do with reason and
uh left brain has to do with reason and logic and the and right brain has to do
logic and the and right brain has to do
logic and the and right brain has to do with synthesis and love and coherence.
with synthesis and love and coherence.
with synthesis and love and coherence. So there's considerable difficulty and
So there's considerable difficulty and
So there's considerable difficulty and people from these two different uh
people from these two different uh
people from these two different uh populations.
populations.
populations. The leftbrain people have a great deal
The leftbrain people have a great deal
The leftbrain people have a great deal of difficulty understanding rightrain
of difficulty understanding rightrain
of difficulty understanding rightrain people and vice versa. The left brain
people and vice versa. The left brain
people and vice versa. The left brain people are in considerable conflict. And
people are in considerable conflict. And
people are in considerable conflict. And so people will say, "How are we going to
so people will say, "How are we going to
so people will say, "How are we going to bring about accommodation
bring about accommodation
bring about accommodation with that which is enimicable?"
with that which is enimicable?"
with that which is enimicable?" And uh actually you're not.
And I listen to all the accommodation
And I listen to all the accommodation people. I say, "Yeah, right."
people. I say, "Yeah, right."
people. I say, "Yeah, right." Yeah. And I shoot you dead. than that
Yeah. And I shoot you dead. than that
Yeah. And I shoot you dead. than that you walk out the door from the
you walk out the door from the
you walk out the door from the accommodation conference.
The difficulty is left brain and right
The difficulty is left brain and right brain synthesize and see things and
brain synthesize and see things and
brain synthesize and see things and process things differently. And I didn't
process things differently. And I didn't
process things differently. And I didn't didn't bring that slide to you. Well, I
didn't bring that slide to you. Well, I
didn't bring that slide to you. Well, I have the slide but everybody's familiar
have the slide but everybody's familiar
have the slide but everybody's familiar with it that the right brain releases
with it that the right brain releases
with it that the right brain releases endorphins uh different
endorphins uh different
endorphins uh different neurotransmitters
neurotransmitters
neurotransmitters uh than the left brain does.
uh than the left brain does.
uh than the left brain does. So these people live in two different
So these people live in two different
So these people live in two different societies.
societies.
societies. They actually live in two different
They actually live in two different
They actually live in two different societies although the population is
societies although the population is
societies although the population is co-mingled.
co-mingled.
co-mingled. Um
Um
Um the leftrainers live in a different
the leftrainers live in a different
the leftrainers live in a different society than the righters resist.
society than the righters resist.
society than the righters resist. They live in a different society.
They live in a different society.
They live in a different society. So that's one way to help overcome
So that's one way to help overcome
So that's one way to help overcome conflict is to see that people process
conflict is to see that people process
conflict is to see that people process things differently and make allowance
things differently and make allowance
things differently and make allowance for the fact that that's the way they
for the fact that that's the way they
for the fact that that's the way they process things.
That allows them to be wrong without you
That allows them to be wrong without you being mad at them.
It's your right to be wrong.
It's your right to be wrong. The fight and flight emotions then you
The fight and flight emotions then you
The fight and flight emotions then you see
see
see are so dominant in today's society and
are so dominant in today's society and
are so dominant in today's society and everyday's news everyday's
everyday's news everyday's
everyday's news everyday's uh Fox channel or whatever is is the
uh Fox channel or whatever is is the
uh Fox channel or whatever is is the conflict between these endorphins and
conflict between these endorphins and
conflict between these endorphins and the condundolini energy begins to flow
the condundolini energy begins to flow
the condundolini energy begins to flow around uh well level 200
around uh well level 200
around uh well level 200 the condundalini energy then which is
the condundalini energy then which is
the condundalini energy then which is the spiritual energy it has to do with
the spiritual energy it has to do with
the spiritual energy it has to do with context and the content
context and the content
context and the content begins to flow from level 200 up. Yes,
begins to flow from level 200 up. Yes,
begins to flow from level 200 up. Yes, level 200. Kundalini energy um begins to
level 200. Kundalini energy um begins to
level 200. Kundalini energy um begins to flow at level 200. We used to think that
flow at level 200. We used to think that
flow at level 200. We used to think that it did not show up until you're almost
it did not show up until you're almost
it did not show up until you're almost enlightened or something, but no. The
enlightened or something, but no. The
enlightened or something, but no. The minute you um opt for truth over
minute you um opt for truth over
minute you um opt for truth over falsehood and integrity over personal
falsehood and integrity over personal
falsehood and integrity over personal gain, so it really means overcoming uh
gain, so it really means overcoming uh
gain, so it really means overcoming uh narcissism.
narcissism.
narcissism. It means the big big conflict between
It means the big big conflict between
It means the big big conflict between these two realms is narcissism.
these two realms is narcissism.
these two realms is narcissism. The left brain thinks that uh the the
The left brain thinks that uh the the
The left brain thinks that uh the the eye the personal eye uh
eye the personal eye uh
eye the personal eye uh is dominant.
is dominant.
is dominant. The right brain
The right brain
The right brain allows God to be uh God and does not and
allows God to be uh God and does not and
allows God to be uh God and does not and so humility then is the step that
so humility then is the step that
so humility then is the step that switches you from left brain to right
switches you from left brain to right
switches you from left brain to right brain. humility the saying that without
brain. humility the saying that without
brain. humility the saying that without help I'm not sure I know this answer
help I'm not sure I know this answer
help I'm not sure I know this answer the realization and recognition and
the realization and recognition and
the realization and recognition and acceptance of limitation
acceptance of limitation
acceptance of limitation and that's the difference that's the
and that's the difference that's the
and that's the difference that's the difficulty with narcissism and of course
difficulty with narcissism and of course
difficulty with narcissism and of course the pope said that the difficulty the
the pope said that the difficulty the
the pope said that the difficulty the reason western world is falling
reason western world is falling
reason western world is falling is a impact of Islam plus
is a impact of Islam plus
is a impact of Islam plus narcissism
narcissism
narcissism relativism narcissism in the form of
relativism narcissism in the form of
relativism narcissism in the form of relativism
relativism
relativism that uh statement calibrates uh let's
that uh statement calibrates uh let's
that uh statement calibrates uh let's see probably around the same level as
see probably around the same level as
see probably around the same level as the pope I don't know uh that pope's
the pope I don't know uh that pope's
the pope I don't know uh that pope's statement calibrates over 200 resist
statement calibrates over 200 resist
statement calibrates over 200 resist calibrates over 400 480 500
calibrates over 400 480 500
calibrates over 400 480 500 calibrates at at 500
calibrates at at 500
calibrates at at 500 now calibrates at 495 at 500 okay
now calibrates at 495 at 500 okay
now calibrates at 495 at 500 okay so so the pope is correct the decline of
so so the pope is correct the decline of
so so the pope is correct the decline of western and civilization. It's through
western and civilization. It's through
western and civilization. It's through the impact of these two things.
the impact of these two things.
the impact of these two things. Yeah. Uhhuh. And so the combination of
Yeah. Uhhuh. And so the combination of
Yeah. Uhhuh. And so the combination of Marxism in its new clothes in which the
Marxism in its new clothes in which the
Marxism in its new clothes in which the name Marx has been removed. It's now
name Marx has been removed. It's now
name Marx has been removed. It's now called relativism.
called relativism.
called relativism. Uh plus the threat of
Uh plus the threat of
Uh plus the threat of uh aggression
uh aggression
uh aggression and accommodation to that which is
and accommodation to that which is
and accommodation to that which is false. Then it re reduces your own level
false. Then it re reduces your own level
false. Then it re reduces your own level of integrity.
of integrity.
of integrity. The way you can get along with the
The way you can get along with the
The way you can get along with the criminal population is you can become a
criminal population is you can become a
criminal population is you can become a little criminal yourself. But you can
little criminal yourself. But you can
little criminal yourself. But you can see what happens to your calibrated
see what happens to your calibrated
see what happens to your calibrated level. You get along better with the
level. You get along better with the
level. You get along better with the criminals, but you yourself become semi
criminals, but you yourself become semi
criminals, but you yourself become semi criminalized.
criminalized.
criminalized. Conflict between left brain and right
Conflict between left brain and right
Conflict between left brain and right brain. The two different sets of
brain. The two different sets of
brain. The two different sets of emotions and endorphins
emotions and endorphins
emotions and endorphins regulating and liberating the right
regulating and liberating the right
regulating and liberating the right brain. Endorphins completely change
brain. Endorphins completely change
brain. Endorphins completely change context. Endorphins
context. Endorphins
context. Endorphins allow you to see and experience the
allow you to see and experience the
allow you to see and experience the world in a totally different way. With
world in a totally different way. With
world in a totally different way. With endorphins, you automatically become
endorphins, you automatically become
endorphins, you automatically become kind and loving towards all creatures.
kind and loving towards all creatures.
kind and loving towards all creatures. You become kind and loving towards all
You become kind and loving towards all
You become kind and loving towards all of life in all of its expressions.
of life in all of its expressions.
of life in all of its expressions. That's the automatic consequence of the
That's the automatic consequence of the
That's the automatic consequence of the endorphins. You don't have to think it.
endorphins. You don't have to think it.
endorphins. You don't have to think it. You don't have to make a logical
You don't have to make a logical
You don't have to make a logical philosophical decision. It's just the
philosophical decision. It's just the
philosophical decision. It's just the way you have become. So people say,
way you have become. So people say,
way you have become. So people say, "What can I do to influence the world?"
"What can I do to influence the world?"
"What can I do to influence the world?" You influence the world all the time by
You influence the world all the time by
You influence the world all the time by what you are, what you have become, what
what you are, what you have become, what
what you are, what you have become, what you have become. So the spiritual
you have become. So the spiritual
you have become. So the spiritual pathway then is to develop a lovingness,
pathway then is to develop a lovingness,
pathway then is to develop a lovingness, a respect for all that lives.
a respect for all that lives.
a respect for all that lives. You don't have to get in the cage with
You don't have to get in the cage with
You don't have to get in the cage with it. You don't have to get in the cage.
it. You don't have to get in the cage.
it. You don't have to get in the cage. Doesn't mean to become modellin and
Doesn't mean to become modellin and
Doesn't mean to become modellin and stupid and foolish.
stupid and foolish.
stupid and foolish. Jump in the cage with the tiger and give
Jump in the cage with the tiger and give
Jump in the cage with the tiger and give him a hug.
That's not being loving because loving
That's not being loving because loving accepts the limitations of the other
accepts the limitations of the other
accepts the limitations of the other person. If you're really loving towards
person. If you're really loving towards
person. If you're really loving towards the tiger, you don't lead him into a
the tiger, you don't lead him into a
the tiger, you don't lead him into a situation where he's going to commit
situation where he's going to commit
situation where he's going to commit what we consider a horrific crime. So,
what we consider a horrific crime. So,
what we consider a horrific crime. So, you protect people from their own
you protect people from their own
you protect people from their own limitation. That's one form of
limitation. That's one form of
limitation. That's one form of lovingness.
lovingness.
lovingness. We don't see it anymore with the old
We don't see it anymore with the old
We don't see it anymore with the old state hospital. The old state hospital
state hospital. The old state hospital
state hospital. The old state hospital in which I grew up doctor
in which I grew up doctor
in which I grew up doctor was demonized demonized
was demonized demonized
was demonized demonized by movies and all the snake pit and all.
by movies and all the snake pit and all.
by movies and all the snake pit and all. It was demonized to look horrible in the
It was demonized to look horrible in the
It was demonized to look horrible in the eyes of the naive populace. Of course,
eyes of the naive populace. Of course,
eyes of the naive populace. Of course, what is the alternative? what the
what is the alternative? what the
what is the alternative? what the alternative is. They closed all the
alternative is. They closed all the
alternative is. They closed all the state hospitals
state hospitals
state hospitals and now psychotic people uh pervade all
and now psychotic people uh pervade all
and now psychotic people uh pervade all levels of society. I frankly don't like
levels of society. I frankly don't like
levels of society. I frankly don't like to fly on airplanes anymore just by the
to fly on airplanes anymore just by the
to fly on airplanes anymore just by the fact that psychotics um are all over the
fact that psychotics um are all over the
fact that psychotics um are all over the place and plotting your demise.
place and plotting your demise.
place and plotting your demise. They're always thinking up something
They're always thinking up something
They're always thinking up something bizarre like what was this one
bizarre like what was this one
bizarre like what was this one yesterday? He was going to crash his
yesterday? He was going to crash his
yesterday? He was going to crash his plane into a a concert by some fluy
plane into a a concert by some fluy
plane into a a concert by some fluy girl. What her name is, I forget.
girl. What her name is, I forget.
girl. What her name is, I forget. What's her name?
What's her name?
What's her name? >> Hh.
>> Hh.
>> Hh. >> Hannah M.
>> Hannah M.
>> Hannah M. >> Hannah Mann. Anyway,
>> Hannah Mann. Anyway,
>> Hannah Mann. Anyway, anyway, whoever it is, he was going to
anyway, whoever it is, he was going to
anyway, whoever it is, he was going to crash his plane right into her concert.
crash his plane right into her concert.
crash his plane right into her concert. You see, in the old days, he'd be in
You see, in the old days, he'd be in
You see, in the old days, he'd be in Pilgrim State Hospital. You know what
Pilgrim State Hospital. You know what
Pilgrim State Hospital. You know what I'm saying?
Well, they used to picture, you know,
Well, they used to picture, you know, that all kinds of innocent people who
that all kinds of innocent people who
that all kinds of innocent people who weren't really mentally ill were being
weren't really mentally ill were being
weren't really mentally ill were being kept there for wicked, wicked reasons,
kept there for wicked, wicked reasons,
kept there for wicked, wicked reasons, you know, and I was psychiatrist for 50
you know, and I was psychiatrist for 50
you know, and I was psychiatrist for 50 years. And I spent years in the state
years. And I spent years in the state
years. And I spent years in the state hospital system, Pilgrim State, some of
hospital system, Pilgrim State, some of
hospital system, Pilgrim State, some of those had 7,000, 9,000 patients. I never
those had 7,000, 9,000 patients. I never
those had 7,000, 9,000 patients. I never once saw anybody in that hospital that
once saw anybody in that hospital that
once saw anybody in that hospital that didn't need to be there. Never once. Not
didn't need to be there. Never once. Not
didn't need to be there. Never once. Not once.
once.
once. Every single one
Every single one
Every single one had a plausible reason, of course, where
had a plausible reason, of course, where
had a plausible reason, of course, where you could argue except that when he when
you could argue except that when he when
you could argue except that when he when he got out, he was going to go right
he got out, he was going to go right
he got out, he was going to go right back and kill his mother again. So, you
back and kill his mother again. So, you
back and kill his mother again. So, you couldn't really let him out. So, all
couldn't really let him out. So, all
couldn't really let him out. So, all right. But that's the problem with
right. But that's the problem with
right. But that's the problem with reason. Reason can lead you far astray.
reason. Reason can lead you far astray.
reason. Reason can lead you far astray. Uh thinking that you're helping people
Uh thinking that you're helping people
Uh thinking that you're helping people when actually you're denying them the
when actually you're denying them the
when actually you're denying them the help that they could get. In the old
help that they could get. In the old
help that they could get. In the old state hospital, people had medical care.
state hospital, people had medical care.
state hospital, people had medical care. They got dental care. They had a social
They got dental care. They had a social
They got dental care. They had a social worker. They had a psychologist.
worker. They had a psychologist.
worker. They had a psychologist. They were kept off the streets. There
They were kept off the streets. There
They were kept off the streets. There were
were
were they had great advantages, which they
they had great advantages, which they
they had great advantages, which they don't have now.
don't have now.
don't have now. All right. So, that's far-left
All right. So, that's far-left
All right. So, that's far-left relativism against absolutism.
relativism against absolutism.
relativism against absolutism. And uh for some reason, absolutism just
And uh for some reason, absolutism just
And uh for some reason, absolutism just drives some people crazy. I don't know
drives some people crazy. I don't know
drives some people crazy. I don't know what it is about them. I guess they're
what it is about them. I guess they're
what it is about them. I guess they're all atheists. And the idea of absolutism
all atheists. And the idea of absolutism
all atheists. And the idea of absolutism is just a it's such a challenge to the
is just a it's such a challenge to the
is just a it's such a challenge to the narcissistic core of the ego that that
narcissistic core of the ego that that
narcissistic core of the ego that that the thought that there's something else
the thought that there's something else
the thought that there's something else other than yourself as sovereign uh just
other than yourself as sovereign uh just
other than yourself as sovereign uh just can't be handled. And somebody wrote
can't be handled. And somebody wrote
can't be handled. And somebody wrote some long diet tribe about a book I'd
some long diet tribe about a book I'd
some long diet tribe about a book I'd written years and years ago and it's all
written years and years ago and it's all
written years and years ago and it's all about relativism.
about relativism.
about relativism. 14 pages single spaced.
14 pages single spaced.
14 pages single spaced. How am I going to get through 14 pages
How am I going to get through 14 pages
How am I going to get through 14 pages single space? And it's just the far-left
single space? And it's just the far-left
single space? And it's just the far-left rant. And all it is is a denial of
rant. And all it is is a denial of
rant. And all it is is a denial of absolutism.
absolutism.
absolutism. So why does absolute drive these people
So why does absolute drive these people
So why does absolute drive these people crazy? I don't know. I suppose it's
crazy? I don't know. I suppose it's
crazy? I don't know. I suppose it's because it signifies that you are
because it signifies that you are
because it signifies that you are answerable. Yes, you are responsible and
answerable. Yes, you are responsible and
answerable. Yes, you are responsible and you are answerable. And it's not based
you are answerable. And it's not based
you are answerable. And it's not based on just how you look at it, but what it
on just how you look at it, but what it
on just how you look at it, but what it actually is.
actually is.
actually is. All right. So with the far left then and
All right. So with the far left then and
All right. So with the far left then and and that which denies and causes
and that which denies and causes
and that which denies and causes conflict is based on rhetoric. So the
conflict is based on rhetoric. So the
conflict is based on rhetoric. So the value of the right brain is the the
value of the right brain is the the
value of the right brain is the the great books of the western world is
great books of the western world is
great books of the western world is logic Renee Deart etc. And of course
logic Renee Deart etc. And of course
logic Renee Deart etc. And of course Deart's big contribution was rest
Deart's big contribution was rest
Deart's big contribution was rest internal versus rest external
internal versus rest external
internal versus rest external the principle of how life looks uh to be
the principle of how life looks uh to be
the principle of how life looks uh to be to you and then rest externa is how it
to you and then rest externa is how it
to you and then rest externa is how it actually is. So the work we do with
actually is. So the work we do with
actually is. So the work we do with consciousness calibration is to discern
consciousness calibration is to discern
consciousness calibration is to discern perception from essence. A thing may
perception from essence. A thing may
perception from essence. A thing may look very lovely and when you calibrate
look very lovely and when you calibrate
look very lovely and when you calibrate it you find it's very low. Vice versa.
it you find it's very low. Vice versa.
it you find it's very low. Vice versa. Uh how to discern essence from
Uh how to discern essence from
Uh how to discern essence from appearance.
appearance.
appearance. And that that's what saves us from
And that that's what saves us from
And that that's what saves us from Marxism. The great books of the western
Marxism. The great books of the western
Marxism. The great books of the western world have been relinquished uh their
world have been relinquished uh their
world have been relinquished uh their their prominence has been relinquished
their prominence has been relinquished
their prominence has been relinquished in today's academic world. And the
in today's academic world. And the
in today's academic world. And the consequences of course are quite
consequences of course are quite
consequences of course are quite obvious.
obvious.
obvious. Causality, conflict, causality versus
Causality, conflict, causality versus
Causality, conflict, causality versus emergence.
emergence.
emergence. How do the work the worldly evolves from
How do the work the worldly evolves from
How do the work the worldly evolves from the viewpoint of causality is different
the viewpoint of causality is different
the viewpoint of causality is different than emergence. The Newtonian paradigm
than emergence. The Newtonian paradigm
than emergence. The Newtonian paradigm pictures a linear god who then uh from
pictures a linear god who then uh from
pictures a linear god who then uh from like a ball through throws the universe
like a ball through throws the universe
like a ball through throws the universe into gear. And one thing is causes
into gear. And one thing is causes
into gear. And one thing is causes another. So that's the Newtonian
another. So that's the Newtonian
another. So that's the Newtonian universe and that applies only to
universe and that applies only to
universe and that applies only to content.
content.
content. Uh the actual universe, the actual
Uh the actual universe, the actual
Uh the actual universe, the actual universe which is context then comes
universe which is context then comes
universe which is context then comes about as a result not of cause and
about as a result not of cause and
about as a result not of cause and effect but of emergence.
effect but of emergence.
effect but of emergence. And you see potentiality becoming
And you see potentiality becoming
And you see potentiality becoming actuality.
actuality.
actuality. And this is what we uh try to teach at
And this is what we uh try to teach at
And this is what we uh try to teach at every single lecture that there is no
every single lecture that there is no
every single lecture that there is no personal you making a decision to do
personal you making a decision to do
personal you making a decision to do anything that it is all happening
anything that it is all happening
anything that it is all happening spontaneously.
spontaneously.
spontaneously. Everything is done and said
Everything is done and said
Everything is done and said is happening spontaneously as a
is happening spontaneously as a
is happening spontaneously as a consequence of the reality of that which
consequence of the reality of that which
consequence of the reality of that which from which it emerges. And things are
from which it emerges. And things are
from which it emerges. And things are not happening by cause and effect.
not happening by cause and effect.
not happening by cause and effect. They're happening as a consequence of
They're happening as a consequence of
They're happening as a consequence of emergence. The potentiality
emergence. The potentiality
emergence. The potentiality under appropriate conditions as context
under appropriate conditions as context
under appropriate conditions as context then emerges and it looks like change
then emerges and it looks like change
then emerges and it looks like change but it's only one thing becoming its own
but it's only one thing becoming its own
but it's only one thing becoming its own potential. So the caterpillar uh goes
potential. So the caterpillar uh goes
potential. So the caterpillar uh goes into the cocoon and the butterfly comes
into the cocoon and the butterfly comes
into the cocoon and the butterfly comes out at the other side. Now the
out at the other side. Now the
out at the other side. Now the caterpillar doesn't cause cause the
caterpillar doesn't cause cause the
caterpillar doesn't cause cause the butterfly
butterfly
butterfly So it shows the stages of evolution. So
So it shows the stages of evolution. So
So it shows the stages of evolution. So mankind is evolving for potentiality
mankind is evolving for potentiality
mankind is evolving for potentiality into actuality. So every single day is
into actuality. So every single day is
into actuality. So every single day is merely the actuality, the actualization
merely the actuality, the actualization
merely the actuality, the actualization of a potentiality.
of a potentiality.
of a potentiality. Uh and that gets the whole rid of the
Uh and that gets the whole rid of the
Uh and that gets the whole rid of the whole idea of free will. So what you can
whole idea of free will. So what you can
whole idea of free will. So what you can do is you can choose your options. You
do is you can choose your options. You
do is you can choose your options. You choose to be kind and loving towards all
choose to be kind and loving towards all
choose to be kind and loving towards all creatures.
creatures.
creatures. that now becomes a dominant that's a
that now becomes a dominant that's a
that now becomes a dominant that's a dominant field. So in the field of
dominant field. So in the field of
dominant field. So in the field of nonlinear dynamics this becomes a
nonlinear dynamics this becomes a
nonlinear dynamics this becomes a high-powered attractor field that you
high-powered attractor field that you
high-powered attractor field that you have made a decision that when all po
have made a decision that when all po
have made a decision that when all po whenever possible you're going to be
whenever possible you're going to be
whenever possible you're going to be kind and loving towards all living
kind and loving towards all living
kind and loving towards all living creatures. Uh this now begins to
creatures. Uh this now begins to
creatures. Uh this now begins to influence all your lesser options. So
influence all your lesser options. So
influence all your lesser options. So the lesser options which are coming out
the lesser options which are coming out
the lesser options which are coming out of weaker energy fields
of weaker energy fields
of weaker energy fields are reflecting the dominance of the
are reflecting the dominance of the
are reflecting the dominance of the overall field. So spiritual evolution
overall field. So spiritual evolution
overall field. So spiritual evolution comes about then as a consequence of the
comes about then as a consequence of the
comes about then as a consequence of the emergence coming out of a decision a
emergence coming out of a decision a
emergence coming out of a decision a decision that I decide I I will I want
decision that I decide I I will I want
decision that I decide I I will I want to be this way and of course
to be this way and of course
to be this way and of course acknowledging divinity uh when we start
acknowledging divinity uh when we start
acknowledging divinity uh when we start when we say all honor be to thee oh lord
when we say all honor be to thee oh lord
when we say all honor be to thee oh lord that already sets a a powerful context
that already sets a a powerful context
that already sets a a powerful context out of which everything now is subject
out of which everything now is subject
out of which everything now is subject that already sets the context.
that already sets the context.
that already sets the context. So that is the abs that is the opposite
So that is the abs that is the opposite
So that is the abs that is the opposite of absolutism.
of absolutism.
of absolutism. So what we stand for then is the
So what we stand for then is the
So what we stand for then is the opposite of absolutism.
opposite of absolutism.
opposite of absolutism. It's exact o
It's exact o
It's exact o I mean out of of relativism. I'm sorry.
I mean out of of relativism. I'm sorry.
I mean out of of relativism. I'm sorry. Absolutism then is the exact opposite of
Absolutism then is the exact opposite of
Absolutism then is the exact opposite of relativism
relativism
relativism out of co. So this is the Newtonian
out of co. So this is the Newtonian
out of co. So this is the Newtonian causality. But what is actually
causality. But what is actually
causality. But what is actually happening is emergence.
happening is emergence.
happening is emergence. Out of conflict arises is survival and
Out of conflict arises is survival and
Out of conflict arises is survival and war. And out of coherence comes
war. And out of coherence comes
war. And out of coherence comes cooperation.
cooperation.
cooperation. Survival is threatened by war. And 93%
Survival is threatened by war. And 93%
Survival is threatened by war. And 93% of human time. And the only way you can
of human time. And the only way you can
of human time. And the only way you can get around it is by cooperation. So if
get around it is by cooperation. So if
get around it is by cooperation. So if we cooperate with the Iranian government
we cooperate with the Iranian government
we cooperate with the Iranian government despite whatever religious conflicts
despite whatever religious conflicts
despite whatever religious conflicts might be there um financial reality
might be there um financial reality
might be there um financial reality being what it is. So negotiation then is
being what it is. So negotiation then is
being what it is. So negotiation then is the best way to handle
the best way to handle
the best way to handle uh and avoid
uh and avoid
uh and avoid survival and war then are offset by
survival and war then are offset by
survival and war then are offset by cooperation.
cooperation.
cooperation. faith and falsehood is offset by
faith and falsehood is offset by
faith and falsehood is offset by verified level of consciousness. So the
verified level of consciousness. So the
verified level of consciousness. So the technique that we follow is the only way
technique that we follow is the only way
technique that we follow is the only way I know of to avoid placing faith in
I know of to avoid placing faith in
I know of to avoid placing faith in falsehood
falsehood
falsehood and faith in falsehood of course is
and faith in falsehood of course is
and faith in falsehood of course is endemic endemic and the gate the book
endemic endemic and the gate the book
endemic endemic and the gate the book that made it was popular extraordinary
that made it was popular extraordinary
that made it was popular extraordinary popular delusions and the madness of
popular delusions and the madness of
popular delusions and the madness of crowds
crowds
crowds I refer to that very often because it's
I refer to that very often because it's
I refer to that very often because it's a
a
a It's appropriate for today's world. You
It's appropriate for today's world. You
It's appropriate for today's world. You can turn on the television anytime and
can turn on the television anytime and
can turn on the television anytime and you will see an extraordinary popular
you will see an extraordinary popular
you will see an extraordinary popular delusion dominating society right this
delusion dominating society right this
delusion dominating society right this minute.
minute.
minute. It depends on which gets the most money.
It depends on which gets the most money.
It depends on which gets the most money. Whatever the popular delusion is,
extraordinary popular delusions in the
extraordinary popular delusions in the madness of crowds uh is offset by the
madness of crowds uh is offset by the
madness of crowds uh is offset by the verifying the level of consciousness and
verifying the level of consciousness and
verifying the level of consciousness and by the balance of wisdom.
by the balance of wisdom.
by the balance of wisdom. Um
Um
Um you notice how how causes become very
you notice how how causes become very
you notice how how causes become very popular. The narcissistic core of the
popular. The narcissistic core of the
popular. The narcissistic core of the ego loves causes. We're going to save
ego loves causes. We're going to save
ego loves causes. We're going to save this, we're going to save that, we're
this, we're going to save that, we're
this, we're going to save that, we're going to save the other thing. And the
going to save the other thing. And the
going to save the other thing. And the the amount of advertising is staggering.
the amount of advertising is staggering.
the amount of advertising is staggering. Uh
Uh
Uh five minutes. Yeah. And uh we find out
five minutes. Yeah. And uh we find out
five minutes. Yeah. And uh we find out things all the time, you know. Let's say
things all the time, you know. Let's say
things all the time, you know. Let's say I'm going to take something that it
I'm going to take something that it
I'm going to take something that it sounds real great. Uh okay. Uh I'm going
sounds real great. Uh okay. Uh I'm going
sounds real great. Uh okay. Uh I'm going to hold this program in mind. That
to hold this program in mind. That
to hold this program in mind. That program calibrates over 200. Is this
program calibrates over 200. Is this
program calibrates over 200. Is this nets? We're gonna solve malaria with
nets? We're gonna solve malaria with
nets? We're gonna solve malaria with nets. All right, let's take the next
nets. All right, let's take the next
nets. All right, let's take the next one.
one.
one. Let's take the next one. What I'm
Let's take the next one. What I'm
Let's take the next one. What I'm holding in mind calibrates over 200
holding in mind calibrates over 200
holding in mind calibrates over 200 resist.
resist.
resist. We're going to save the Himalayan people
We're going to save the Himalayan people
We're going to save the Himalayan people of the Himalayans.
What do you suppose is spent on those
What do you suppose is spent on those two big ads? They come on every freaking
two big ads? They come on every freaking
two big ads? They come on every freaking night over and over again.
It sounds logical.
It sounds logical. $10 for a net save lives. How come it
$10 for a net save lives. How come it
$10 for a net save lives. How come it calibrates below 200? Tell me.
calibrates below 200? Tell me.
calibrates below 200? Tell me. How about the poor people in the
How about the poor people in the
How about the poor people in the Himalayas
giving money to them? Isn't that going
giving money to them? Isn't that going to help?
to help?
to help? Why is it under 200?
Why is it under 200?
Why is it under 200? If it's so true, why is it under 200?
Sounds great. save life with nuts.
Sounds great. save life with nuts. Most of those deals you send $10 for a
Most of those deals you send $10 for a
Most of those deals you send $10 for a nut and you say, "Well, you could pay a
nut and you say, "Well, you could pay a
nut and you say, "Well, you could pay a whole year in advance, send us 120, and
whole year in advance, send us 120, and
whole year in advance, send us 120, and then
then
then I did that once with one of those
I did that once with one of those
I did that once with one of those things, save the children deals." That's
things, save the children deals." That's
things, save the children deals." That's the way it went. You know, you got
the way it went. You know, you got
the way it went. You know, you got worked up for the money and I don't know
worked up for the money and I don't know
worked up for the money and I don't know where the money went because they're
where the money went because they're
where the money went because they're still after the money.
So, there you got the difference in
So, there you got the difference in appearance and illusion.
appearance and illusion.
appearance and illusion. They take the Daly Lama's picture out of
They take the Daly Lama's picture out of
They take the Daly Lama's picture out of some place and they tack it on to the
some place and they tack it on to the
some place and they tack it on to the end of the ad. And he's he's begging you
end of the ad. And he's he's begging you
end of the ad. And he's he's begging you to please save the people in the
to please save the people in the
to please save the people in the Himalayas.
Himalayas.
Himalayas. Why does he cal Why does it calibrate
Why does he cal Why does it calibrate
Why does he cal Why does it calibrate under 200?
Calibrates under 200. I don't know why
Calibrates under 200. I don't know why the Dalai Lama doesn't calibrate under
the Dalai Lama doesn't calibrate under
the Dalai Lama doesn't calibrate under 200. He's 570.
200. He's 570.
200. He's 570. So somebody took his picture and put it
So somebody took his picture and put it
So somebody took his picture and put it on this thing. So anyway,
on this thing. So anyway,
on this thing. So anyway, once you know how to tell truth from
once you know how to tell truth from
once you know how to tell truth from falsehood, you become a little more
falsehood, you become a little more
falsehood, you become a little more perceptive.
perceptive.
perceptive. You get much sharper at picking up that
You get much sharper at picking up that
You get much sharper at picking up that you're being had all the time.
you're being had all the time.
you're being had all the time. Not a lot of the time.
Not a lot of the time.
Not a lot of the time. All the time.
All the time.
All the time. You're always being had.
You're always being had.
You're always being had. Did you know that
Did you know that
Did you know that they put a product up, they put a star
they put a product up, they put a star
they put a product up, they put a star in your mind? That product is a star,
in your mind? That product is a star,
in your mind? That product is a star, isn't it? You've already been
isn't it? You've already been
isn't it? You've already been programmed.
programmed.
programmed. You're programmed, program, program,
You're programmed, program, program,
You're programmed, program, program, program, program program. So your mind,
program, program program. So your mind,
program, program program. So your mind, which you think is so wonderful, is one
which you think is so wonderful, is one
which you think is so wonderful, is one set of endless stupid programmings.
It's handy for counting your change.
It's handy for counting your change. It's about all it's good for work.
No, you begin to look elsewhere for
No, you begin to look elsewhere for truth. You begin to look elsewhere for
truth. You begin to look elsewhere for
truth. You begin to look elsewhere for truth. And uh
truth. And uh
truth. And uh and uh
orders from headquarters. Yes,
orders from headquarters. Yes, we're going to take a break so you can
we're going to take a break so you can
we're going to take a break so you can get over the the shock of what I just
get over the the shock of what I just
get over the the shock of what I just got through telling you.
got through telling you.
got through telling you. We're not going to cure the world of
We're not going to cure the world of
We're not going to cure the world of malaria.
malaria.
malaria. Uh
so we'll take we'll take a short break.
so we'll take we'll take a short break. We'll be back. Thank you very much.