Um, at this time I'd like to introduce
Dr. Hawkins.
Where do I go?
Where do I go? Okay.
>> Do I go there?
>> Yeah.
You were calling me a relic.
I'm not old enough to be a relic.
I'm a pre prelic.
So glad to see you all today.
And uh the weather is just perfect
and people came from long distances
and so we try to stay as strictly
adhered to time and time limitations.
And uh the lecture for today is on
freedom, morality and ethics. Freedom.
morality and ethics
in uh in today's world especially in the
week just finished.
There's vague boundaries between uh
freedom and morality and ethics. Uh how
much freedom can you have before you
cross over into immorality
and a lack of ethics? Uhhuh. And so
discernment discernment is the answer.
And so that will really be the focus of
today, discernment.
How to differentiate between freedom and
uh
and what does this word here say? What
does that say?
What does that say?
>> Writing.
>> Insurrection.
>> No.
>> Treason.
Revolt.
>> Oh well.
anarchy.
There we go.
>> Thanks.
>> To differentiate when is freedom freedom
and when is it just anarchy?
When is it constructive and when is it
destructive?
When does it take you to liberation or
when does it take you to enslavement?
And so we'll discuss that. It's a very
uh interesting subject and of course
it's been discussed over the centuries
from the days of ancient Greece until
current time
in the days of ancient Greece and the
philosophy of ancient Greece etc were
the kind of things that preoccupied my
mind as an adolescent.
There were three of us that hung
together and uh we spent our our boyhood
listening to classical music. arguing
philosophy, Plato and Socrates
and uh while the other kids were playing
stickball so I don't know which one of
us was
recently one member of the team so that
was what 75 70 years ago
one one of them went west there were
three of us one of them went west and
became a geologist
and the third one is now a professor and
I hadn't heard from him in 60 years I
think and suddenly they got a a message
from him that he had discovered me. And
uh so I've got gotten together in
communication with a friend from from
seven 70 years ago
70 years ago.
what welded us together was classical
music and the aesthetics not only uh
intellectual
but the aesthetics of the intellectual
which is even a greater refinement
and so I thought that's very interesting
how time like stops and then suddenly
starts again like 70 years had never
even gone by very interesting
so today we we're going to do our slides
and then at 10:15 we have a break is
that correct Yes.
>> 10:15. So I better start
>> 11:15.
>> Oh, 11:15.
Uh, all right. You'll let me know. Okay.
Time is somewhere. I don't know what I'm
the time on the way here. Now, let's
see. Let's look at the slides for today.
Uh, we always start with a review. Uh, a
short review depending on how many new
people we have here today. Uh, the new
people raise your hands. So we can see
how many are here. Oh, it's a sizable
number. Oh, wave your hands. Oh,
there there's all the new people. All
right. So for the sake of those who
haven't been here before and as a review
for people that have been uh we do an
abbreviated review of some of the major
uh topics in the development of this
whole field of consciousness research.
Is that does it stay way up there? Is
that where it stays
>> now? You didn't tell me that before.
Well, let's see now. What do we do about
that?
>> You jump high.
Okay, let's see then. Then I need to see
what slides we're reviewing. There we
are. Okay, now watch out.
All right. So I I remember where we are
now.
I remember where we are. We're right
here and it's right now. That solves it.
So we got to start with the map of
consciousness which evolved over a
number of decades and uh really refle
reflects the perennial wisdom. This is
really the perennial wisdom and it's
pretty much in alignment with
psychoanalytic theory and uh great
numerous philosophies
uh in in which the the states into which
man to which a man may become aligned or
eventually imprisoned
uh are are put in a and we are put in a
a line of decreasing integrity.
So we start with the most integrous and
then we move on to man's lower nature.
So here we have above the line man's
higher nature you might say and below
the line man's lower nature.
uh the lower nature is often
emerges with the animal instincts of
kill and be killed and and hate and
the extremes of emotion from high to
low. So during this recent election, we
saw uh this displayed very well across
the television land uh from the most
despicable kinds of comments uh to the
most uplifting. And we ended up happily
on a very uplifting note. And now we're
all waiting with baited breath to see
what kind of a dog goes in the White
House.
I think that's very endearing. You know,
when all the war is put away, everybody
gets down to reality. And what's really
important is what kind of a doggy is it
going to be there? You know, I remember
Franklin D. Roosevelt, you always had f
follow with him. Follow him with a
little black Scotty and FDR have the dog
talking to the great powers of the world
with Fala. He wouldn't try without Fala.
So those things are the the contrast
between uh the most severe, evil, and
hopeless with the most endearing and
encouraging. So long as we worry about
what kind of a dog is in the warehouse,
our country is safe.
Because why? Because it shows that the
heart the heart in the end is the heart
that wins. It's the heart that wins, is
it not? Because even even the candidate
that won really to a great degree won
because of the heart uh involved. There
was the strict politicians and some
became quite vicious. But in the end it
you know it was the heart that people
cheered. So when people cheered they
said well it's a a new breakthrough for
America. and but they meant from the
heart from the heart
that we're all truly equal not just in
words but in deeds.
So that was very uh supportive and uh
and I think it signals perhaps a very
good era upcoming era despite the
economic situations.
All right. So here we have the the
classical levels of consciousness and
the emotions that go with them. And of
course we then calibrated them and this
is the process going on in
consciousness. Uh so the beginning of
this work was really the discovery of uh
how to calibrate things. And the way it
came about is we discovered that certain
things made people go weak and other
things made people go strong. Anything
that's pro-life makes you go strong and
anything that's anti-life makes you go
weak.
That was demonstrated in an early
lecture in kinesiology.
And uh it was the energy that caused
this diff differential between strong
and weak. Then the next thing I was
lecturing on this subject to the staff
at the clinic. I would go around to all
these
lectures and and and pull bring back to
the clinic what whatever I thought was
useful to the staff and the most
interesting thing one of the most
interesting things although people poo
poo kinesiology I'll tell you one thing
they can't poo poo and that is when
people look at a fluorescent light
uh about half the audience will go weak
certain people will look at a
fluorescent light and go weak other
people look at the fluorescent light and
do not go weak and we discovered that
the people who did not go weak. So when
I was going to demonstrate it to the to
the clinic staff I needed some
volunteers. So we had at the same time
the course of miracles people we had an
attitudinal healing center the second
one in the United States
for uh people with hopeless chronic uh
incurable conditions.
And uh so when I needed volunteers, I
they were standing around. So I said,
"Come on over here. I want to
demonstrate something."
And uh so when they looked at the
fluorescent light, they did not go weak.
Huh. So when we picked some other
strangers from the audience, you might
say, they did go weak. So what was it
about the people doing a course of
miracles? Why didn't they go weak when
looking at a fluorescent light?
So fluorescent lights don't have to do
with good and evil. They don't have to
do with religion or belief systems, but
some physiologic capacity to
differentiate that which is pro-life,
that which is anti-life.
So we made I made a clinical study out
of this group and uh
we started with a new group of about
four or five people who were just
starting the course of miracles. So I
took them out of the group that went
week four or five people and um they
began to do the course of miracles and
then we retested them every week or
every month I forget what it was and by
the time they got to about lesson I
forget 80 or 90
>> 75
>> 75 all right so these people who went
weak when they looked at the fluorescent
lights by about less than 75 in a course
of miracles no longer went weak isn't
that incredible
Incredible.
So, you can poo poo it all you want.
It's a fact. And the people who poo poo
what I'm lecturing about all go week.
That's a fact. Some famous professors.
They're very famous professors. Get out
there and poo poo Hawkins and all what
he says on. And then when I did the arm
on them, I went weak. They were all
atheists. Yeah. Every one of them. Uh so
we found out that this uh means of
discerning truth from falsehood does not
work for atheists. So if you're an
atheist, don't waste your time doing it.
Those that deny the source of truth are
denied the fruits thereof is what it
amounted to
that. And and these professors was not
publicly known they were atheists, but
we discovered that it was so. All right.
So this was a very mind-boggling. You
know, I'm a clinician and to me what
impresses me is what works. When you got
a sick patient, I don't care about
theories and what's approved and what's
not approved. You tell people what
works. What works.
Right now, for instance, I had to go for
acupuncture. I I I tore the what do you
call it? Rotator cuff of the left
shoulder. The my dog pulled me down and
it was the dog's fault. bad dog
made me fall on the cement
and I tore this rotator cuff. So, I've
been seeing an acupuncturist. Yeah. And
immediately I got I got immediate help
from it. And of course, they always lie.
They say the needles aren't going to
hurt, but they lie.
They lie. So,
so I have a patch, a warmer patch with
oriental herbs in it. And I see an
acupuncturist. So, you can see I'm not
exactly going to meet the approval of
the American Medical Association.
All right. So, acupuncture, I've told
that story before, is what cured my
chronic intractable ulcer. And I saw the
first I was one of the first acupuncture
patients in the United States. The first
clinic was in Washington DC. It was only
by the approval of the federal
government in the federal health
services and uh so I used to fly from
New York once a week down to uh
Washington from New York and uh they you
had to bring all your X-rays and proof
of what was wrong with you. And I had a
perforating douadal ulcer incurable for
25 years defied everything.
And uh so I thought, well, I'll try
acupuncture. And uh so I was accepted as
a patient. I took all my X-rays, etc.
And I lay down on the couch and I put my
thing out and and he put a needle
through here and I jump about jumped off
the table. Oh, he said, "Bad ulcer."
At this point right here, if you got a
bad ulcer, oh, bad ulcer.
Uh so I'm just trying to point out the
limit the limits of the scientific
domain. the limits of the scientific
domain and the scientific is limited to
that which is provable and logical and
linear and the dimension in which we are
studying and and publishing our own
research findings and experiences is
primar primarily the non-Newtonian and
the nonlinear
better described by quantum mechanics
and by linear causality
and so that's what be talking about
today. Now, the next slide, you're all
familiar with this the slide and uh uh I
better stick to this list here. Well,
what does this say? I can't read it. So,
it says these are whatever it says here.
Uh oh, yes. These are the enlightened
states. The enlightened states. and they
go up to a thousand
and they go all the way up to the 600s,
the 700s, Buddhahood, Christ, Krishna,
etc. So, one can corroborate the
divinity of of these figures throughout
history till we calibrated all the
that's be coming up. We calibrated all
the famous teachers and avatars and and
great spiritual beings over time.
And we found that they all calibrated
extremely high extremely high. And that
which is evil and and
anti-truth, anti-lo and anti- good
calibrates very low. And there's a
differentiating line at calibration
level 200. So from 200 up differentiates
the realm of that which is positive and
below 200 of that which is false and the
commonly termed evil in our society.
So that's the map of consciousness. Now
we want to do the map of uh uh the next
one. Here we are. Uh this one needs to
be corrected. I say that every time we
show this one. uh how the energy level
goes up as the level of consciousness
goes up uh the energy goes up. So the
energy what you're seeing is is the a
field of power as the energy go up. So
the higher the level of consciousness
the greater influence you have on the
world.
Therefore,
relatively few people of high
consciousness
uh have the uh quality of
counterbalancing large numbers of low
consciousness. Next slide. Huh. So,
this is a hard one to see. I say that
every lecture too.
This is 200 and up. This is the
population of the world.
The population of the world from 200 and
up is this many and below 200 is that
many.
That explains many conditions of the
world. Yes. Does it not? The majority of
people the majority of population
calibrates below 200.
Okay. Next slide. And the reason the
world doesn't disintegrate and
self-destruct
is that those over 200 have such a
relatively higher degree of power. As
you see that at the very top
counterbalances all the rest within the
pyramid. So we'll go to the next slide.
This is a different way of showing it
graphically. This 15% of the world
people 200 and over 15% of the world
counterbalance the 85% of the world that
calibrates below 200 below 200.
Now one night I meditated all alone by
myself by my lonesome in the pyramid in
Egypt all night long. Had a whole
pyramid to myself.
Cost me I think 10 bucks.
If you know who to see, it's amazing.
You can have a whole pyramid to
yourself. Don't tell anybody about that
though.
All right, we'll move on to the next. Uh
this is an extremely important one in
our world. Uh these are the great books
of the western world. Uh in which we
calibrated the most significant
um contributions from the intellectual
world.
These arise from the era of development
of mo the modern world called the
enlightenment. The period of the
enlightenment. The emergence of the
intellect as a dominant measure of
integrity and truth.
So these are the great names of history.
You'll recognize many of them. uh uh
John Lock Kepler, Emanuel Kant,
uh Hume, all the great philosophers,
Virgil, and these were when I was a
teenager, these were the people we
argued about. We would read these books
and argue about them.
Signs of a mispent youth, huh? Everybody
else was out playing soccer and we were
with glasses on like four eyes, you
know, sitting at the corner.
Who are you looking at? Four eyes. One
said to me, "What the heck? Who are you
looking at for?" Oh, I told that story
before. We did the course of miracles
and we were imbued with goodwill. So, we
went to Lor's side and there was a in a
very trashy kind of a neighborhood. But
anyway, it was late at night and and
there were all these black bags full of
trash sitting on the curb. So, we left
the course of miracles class. We went
out on the on the street and here was
this old lady poking through the black
bags, you know, like an old hag, you
know. So, um we thought, let's send her
love and goodwill. So,
so we held hands and sent send her love
and goodwill. And all of a sudden out of
the bags comes this old lady's head and
she says, "Who you staring at?" Four
eyes.
That's a true story. Yeah. Who are you
staring at for us? Cuz I had glasses on
at the time. Who are you staring at for
us? So that's a punchline that makes me
laugh every once in a while. If
something horrible happens, I say, "Who
are you staring at for us?
when it's significant to our society and
I didn't realize how much uh it would
mean until we calibrated all of them uh
is Carl Marx at 130. You see they're all
in the mid 400s. The the great books of
the western world calibrate around 450
to 460 which is the world of the
intellect in intellectual integrity
and u marks and angles are at the
lowest. Engles is at 200
and uh Marx was at 130 130. So in the
recent elections with who I forget who
that guy was confronted by Marxian
theory he said what is from each
according to their ability to each
according to their need isn't that
marxian and the guy who was asked about
it just blew apart couldn't answer it
couldn't answer it yes that is quote
from Markx right anyway he just went
what is this a joke he says couldn't
answer it what is this a So
anyway, Marx Marx of course has played a
tremendous uh
factor in ch communist China and
communist countries. We've seen North
Korea and communist China etc. And why
do they all fail? Uh because the basic
philosophy is at 130. If you a society
based on a calibrated level of 130 is
guaranteed to fail. And of course, North
Korea, 1 million starve to death. In
China, 10 million starve to death. And
wherever this philosophy is acted out in
in in the world, uh you see catastrophe.
Uh-huh.
All right. So, freedom is both an up and
a down. Freedom, you can rise up in
one's consciousness. And you also have
freedom to pick that which calibrates
low. All right? So
now what's the next slide?
Uh it's obvious that the great books of
the western world could fill up several
lectures.
Um
this is uh
calibrated levels of goodness and
badness. You see goodness from bad can
go from ghastly horrific horrible. Uh so
it's all a matter of relative. When you
say it's ugly or repulsive,
uh, what you're what you're saying as
compared to what? As compared to what is
a black widow spider ugly or not? I
suppose to a a boy spider. She looks
cute.
Come here, baby.
We'll move on to the next.
Yeah.
uh this uh is to show that there are
various sociologic theories about man's
problems you see and from study you'll
find that most of sociological
conditions are consequences rather than
causes their conccomatants
conccomatants
and we find that the people below and
above 200 process their brains process
things differently Sorry,
the brain processes differently above
200 and below 200.
Below 200, the brain processes the same
as does the animal brain. And it's
dominated by the amygdala. And the
amygdala is the seat of emotions,
especially negative emotions. And the
amygdala calibrates at 180. Yeah. The
prefrontal cortex calibrates at 200.
Uh with spiritual evolution however one
becomes more dominantly rightrain
and the consequences are considerable to
the brain physiology.
At the lower levels you release
adrenaline and the hormones of stress
attack and defense. So that brain is the
animal brain.
Below 200, people are dominated by the
animal brain, which explains the daily
news. Daily news. Unless you realize
that half the people are cal dominated
by the animal brain, you can't make out
why people do what they do. If they're
dominated by the animal brain, then you
say, "Well, naturally, if I was
dominated by the animal brain, I'd kill
him, too. He deserves it."
He held back on the mob.
Hell back on the mob.
Instant solution to the problem.
All right. So below 200, life is simple
because you're basically an animal
response. From 200 and up, however, now
the brain physiology shifts to the right
brain.
You're no longer dominated by the
negative animal brain.
And now uh a whole different set of
neurotransmitters
dominates brain function. From left
brain uh emergency emotions you go to
the so-called welfare emotions and the
brain begins releasing oxytoxin
and things like that. So a shift from
left brain to right brain and shifting
above level 200.
So the world is really held together by
the consciousness level uh 200 and over
otherwise it would have destroyed itself
long ago. So 200 and up then is
important because
the as you begin doing spiritual study
you begin releasing condundolin the you
begin from the atheric body releasing
condundolini energy. The kundalini
energy flows up uh through the chakra
system and it shifts you to the right
brain so that people above 200 and below
200 see the world differently,
experience the world differently,
explain it differently, are motivated
differently.
So as you get advanced you know as you
get really interested in spiritual work
uh sometimes people become dismayed with
the degree of negativity that prevails.
You have to realize that above 200 you
are see thinking seeing feeling
experiencing and remembering things
totally differently than other people.
You're you're thinking how wonderful it
is and they're thinking how horrible it
is. So that explains the the difference.
So in spiritual work, part of your
evolution then is by merely shifting
your allegiance and your attention to
that which is spiritual, you shift your
brain function. And once you shift the
brain function, the endorphins change
and you're now enabled to see and
experience things that other people
cannot. So people will, you know,
ridicule states, spiritual states of
enlightenment or the states of the
mystic, etc. Because from the leftbrain
viewpoint it is not possible for them.
But for the right person as spiritual
evolution uh progresses they become
overwhelming and very powerful and
states of illumination and become
progressive. Okay. So that reviews those
slides up through brain function. Now
this is the rate of happiness isn't it?
I can't see it. Honey does that say rate
of happiness?
>> Yes. Is that what it says?
>> Well, it didn't say happiness. It says
consciousness.
>> I thought it happiness. It says
happiness right there. What's with you?
You'll see that the rate of happiness is
therefore
almost directly related to the level of
consciousness. As the rate of happ as
the rate of consciousness goes up, the
rate of happiness increases rapidly. And
in the higher levels of consciousness,
happiness is almost 100%.
I'm waiting to get there.
No, you really have to uh lose it in
order to really get seriously annoyed.
You get annoyed with the minor things of
life. It's the minor things that drive
me crazy. you know, the important things
has no problem.
But where you left the wrong t-shirt out
and you can't find the right one, now
you're up in the air. I have to laugh at
the things that that
next one.
Just just got over the flu.
A bad bug. Bad bug.
Good bug makes you smile. Bad bug makes
you cough. Who is a bad bug?
Okay. So, the next next slide then uh
has to do with the levels of
consciousness as they relate to
emotionality,
the prevailing level of consciousness.
And you're all familiar with these. So,
we'll go to the next one.
And uh what is that?
>> Oh, the Lou.
Everybody here seen the Lou before? How
many haven't seen the Lou before? Oh,
well. Here you have the Lou, which of
course was the palace of emperors for
centuries.
the some of the most incredible and
beautiful buildings, most beautiful
environment. And the Lou, the buildings
themselves calibrated in the 700s, 700s.
And then in I forget what when it was
the 1980s or something. Uh they wanted
to have a new entrance way to the uh
lower floors and it was a big it was a
contentious thing in France at the time.
those who wanted to be ultramodern that
wanted this senate glass and steel
structure and then the the prevailing
more prevailing opinion was it should be
uh go along with with the prevailing
architecture
but I just thought you'd be interested
what is the what is that terrible
looking pyramid caliber what does that
say 180
>> yeah so this prevailing structure is so
dissonant And it calibrates at 180 and
the surrounding buildings calibrate at
700.
>> Huh?
>> 500.
>> What calibrates at 500?
>> The surrounding buildings?
>> Oh, the surrounding buildings calibrated
500. I said five, didn't I? Oh,
it sounded like seven, but
I just think I put in things like this
for an anecdotal
because a lot of times it's the
anecdotal that you remember rather than
the course of the whole thing, you know,
like what kind of a dog you were going
to have in the White House if it's going
to wipe out everybody's memory of the
whole the whole thing
and all of they're going to remember is
what dog won the one in the end. So
there's so that which is quaint
>> that which is quaint has a special place
in the human heart you know. So this is
you know is an abomination. We were in
it. We were in it and got to experience
it. It's very efficient. It's very
wonderful. It's just that it's totally
in the wrong place. It was in the middle
of New York City. All right. We'll move
on to the next.
Uh
this is just so you know that it exists
that we did in one of the books.
uh the characteristics of uh uh
spiritual teachers uh characteristic of
integrous spiritual teaching because in
in today's world there's all as the same
as in the political world there are
people who make all kinds of claims and
uh and I get lots and lots of probably
more than any other subject letters and
emails and from around the world asking
about various spiritual teachers. Are
they okay or not okay? And uh are we in
safe hands or should we keep looking?
And it's some it's usually somewhat uh
you have to really think how best to
answer it. And
so I refer to that we've got a list of
approved teachers and uh when I when I
get high pressed I'll say well we give
you a list of a couple hundred approved
teachers. Why do you have to dig this
guy up from
Bodia?
Master Slim Papa from Pagodia. I don't
know. I never heard the guy.
And then we do the arm on him and he
calibrates 80 or something. They're
supposed to sign over all their worldly
worldly goods and kiss his bottom every
time he turns around.
Now how do I in inform the inquirer that
perhaps it is not the highest available
teacher? So I don't want to say anything
negative about him because in this blog
word of bloggerism anything is say
essentially on in the blogger world. Uh
so I don't want to discriminate against
anybody. I I usually send something like
perhaps you could keep look uh
searching.
Perhaps there are more or even better
ones you might discover. Yeah.
We have to give him all our money and
and kiss his behind and go to bed with
him.
Do you think he's really all right?
I say well you're in good company you
know a lot of world famous ones do that
so all right so this is the integrous
things I think it's very very practical
the human mind cannot tell truth from
falsehood it cannot discern uh
appearance from essence and therefore
the human mind need needs studies by
people who study such things and
therefore that's one thing we wanted to
do okay next we go
Uh okay, we'll go on next. Uh these are
all
what's what is what are these slides
about? What are these ones?
>> Goes on to about 44.
>> Oh, these are still integrous teachers.
Oh, characteristics of integrous
teachings. Okay.
>> For quite a while.
>> All right. All right. Uh
the difference between mystical and
magical. And that's a confusion that
often comes across our desk, too. The
difference between the the mystical and
the magical and the world of the woo
woos.
When I first came to Sedona, it was it
was all western boots and boots and
everybody wore a gun to town, etc.
Yeah, everybody wearing gun to town and
it's still legal, I guess, but it's just
not fashionable anymore. I don't know
why.
You see the banker, the real estate
broker, they all had boots, jeans and
car and had a gun. And then there were
the woowoos.
And then there were the woo woos and uh
the woo woos always had some psychic on
the other side that told them what to do
and all. Anyway, so this is the levels.
So we'll go on to the next one.
Uh
so so these are characteristics of uh uh
integrous teaching integrous teachings
and organizations because we get a lot
of questions about that. So we'll go to
the next one. Uh
oh this is a a list of teachers. So I
just want people to know that it's
available within the books. I don't
remember which one.
There's a a list of uh the calibration
level of teachers, teachings and
writings and um especially early in the
spiritual game, it's easy to get way li
way laid by that which is dramatic and
and uh attractive but which doesn't
really calibrate that high. So for the
safety of the student, we calibrated uh
a great many spiritual teachers and a
great many spiritual teachings. So after
you've read all these then you can
contact me about the the next one on
your list
enough. So
because I saw so many go off the deep
end and I still see them go off the deep
end uh following erroneous teachings or
erroneous teachers and in the average
spiritual books bookstore 50% is
erroneous. Let me see. Let me question.
I have permission to ask this. In the
average spiritual bookstore, 50% are
erroneous. Resist.
So, wandering through a spiritual
bookstore thinking, "Oh, I'm safe. I'm
here with all these holy god god aligned
people." You know, you can pull out pure
BS 50% of the time. Wow.
>> Swami screw up.
>> This one's by Sister Babelhead.
This is Swami Nicknook.
Because they have mystical names doesn't
mean anything.
Uh-huh.
It's better to have a book by George
Pickle that calibrates 600 than Swami
Mumbong Jamba
that calibrates 42.
It's because the mind has a it's very
difficult for the mind to differentiate
the genuine spiritual from imagination
and from other altered states of
consciousness.
The uh inner state of the mystic of
self- knowingness
is very hard to describe. It's it's very
hard to describe and and it occurs
spontaneously and autonomously
arising out of an energy field. So let's
move to the next one. Huh? In there
Socrates is back in there. One of my
favorites from childhood. So my hero was
Socrates. other people at Babe Ruth.
When I was a kid, Babe Ruth was
everybody's and mine was Socrates.
Signs of a misspent youth, huh?
I wanted to go to the ball field to see
Socrates.
Yeah.
Now, these are the uh what does that say
on the top there? The
um
uh the the names of God. Is that what it
says? Divinity
and avatars. Yes, that requires
clarification too because you can take a
course on avatarism
and there's avocar buses, avocar taxis,
avatar pizza stores
and Avatar then calibrates, you know,
700 up and the great avatars of all time
all calibrated about a thousand. Jesus
Christ and Buddha Krishna
calibrated a thousand
or over. No, the great the great ones
calibrate at infinity. The god of Moses
and Abraham is infinity. Rama
uh Durga all these Krishna they all
calibrate at uh infinity. So the true
avatars, the really divinely
enlightened,
calibrated and and infinity and these
are terms terms to denote the same
thing. All right. So we'll move on. You
see Jehovah calibrates it at 200. So
that requires some looking into
what does the top one say? These are the
me ways of worshiping the Lord etc.
the the twel apostles name of God asm
and instead of am
uh we calibrated Moses Abraham St. Paul
uh etc. Therefore,
this is a way of reviewing. Don't forget
the world's spiritual religious
literature is enormous, voluminous.
The library of the Vatican uh covers
several a quarters quarter of a square
mile. So, the amount of literature that
has evolved is staggering. Therefore,
what can you use as a guide uh to help
you through this maze? So the next one
is
this is u King James version of the
Bible that perhaps is the most
significant one in our world. You see
the King James version of the Bible
calibrates at 475
calibrates that's the standard King
James version 475.
The lamp survival. However, the lamp
survival calibrates at what does it say
there? 700.
>> What does it say?
>> Huh?
>> I can't see.
>> You can't see lumpsa Bible.
What is
>> Oh, I see. Minus the Old Testament.
Yeah. Okay. Lumps of Bible from the
Aramaic 495. Lumps of Bible minus the
Old Testament.
And where is the number?
>> It's at the very top.
>> What does it say?
>> It's on It's uh on this side. At the
very top.
>> 880.
>> 880. Look, we have to fix this slide. We
need the 8080 down here.
Why is it up there? I don't know.
Uh-oh. You know,
we'll have to make a note to fix this
slide.
You see the remarkable difference
the l the traditional Bible as compared
to the lambsa Bible. Now the King James
version is translated from the Greek.
So it couldn't calibrate any higher than
the translation the expertise of the
translations.
The LSA Bible was from the Aramaic the
so-called Eastern manuscripts. which
went all the way to Constantinople.
So you'll see that even the Bible
itself, especially the New Testament, it
makes a big difference whether you're
reading quoting from the Lamsa Bible or
the King James version from the Greek.
In fact, the difference between these
two translations is different is greater
than the difference between
uh religions that are true and religions
that are false. a difference of three
400 points.
All right.
I have permission to ask what I'm
holding on my mind. What he said is what
I think he said. Resist.
And what I think he said is what he did
say. Resist.
All right. Because I know better. Yeah.
Oh Lord, has thou has why hast thou for
go forsaken me?
Jesus Christ said that on the cross.
Resist.
Jesus Christ Christ said, "Dear God,
thou hast not forgotten. Forsaken me.
Resist." Okay. The wrong word. Forsaken.
It always befuddled me how Jesus Christ
on the cross could say
to God, "Why hast thou forsaken me?
In the Lumpsa Bible, it says that thou
hast not forsaken me. Quite a
difference. Just that one thing alone.
You ask yourself rationally, how could
God forget Jesus Christ?
How could you have forgotten? So you see
how disruptive misunderstandings can be
and they don't get resolved over the
centuries. They don't get resolved over
the centuries. Then the lumpsa bible
came along and was the first one I think
to really differentiate that. Mhm.
Uh and it's very important for us to
know because you know which is the
truth.
So we finally have a way to discern the
Let me have your one last thing. I have
permission to ask this again. What Jesus
Christ said on the cross is thank God
thou hast not forget god forsaken me
resist. Thou hast not forsaken me
resist.
That in itself to just know that is
quite otherwise it's really really
devastating. When I first ran across it
in my early Christian days, uh it
devastated me. If even Jesus Christ, you
know, was forsaken by God, what chance
was there for me?
What chance did I have? All right.
The So this is very interesting. I think
the great writings of the western world.
Okay, we'll move on to the next
and that is what does that say up there?
Right.
>> Illumination.
>> Yeah. The states of illumination
uh which unfold from within
the propensity for them to happen is
exhilarated by hanging out with holy
company. So we'll move to the next thing
as this is holy company and uh
>> huh
>> self the states of self-realization
as you can see they're generally called
mystical they they emerge uh of their
own spontaneously
and those of us who've all many people
in this room have had them uh you're
walking along in the park with not
you're not thinking about God or
religion or anything and all of a sudden
the incredible beauty of nature is so
overwhelming that you have to sit down.
That's how it happens, doesn't it? Yes.
It happens to you all the time. She
suddenly the whole world is transformed
and by an inner mystical state and
thinking about it doesn't do any good.
So these states then as your as your own
consciousness advances become
spontaneous
unexpected. We'll move to the next one.
Yes. Uh
life energy not so yes I can't can't
read that I'm afraid. Awareness. Uh
which slide is it?
>> Full enlightenment.
>> Full full enlightenment.
>> Oh yes the full state of is where is it
here on the list? right here.
>> Oh, I see.
>> There's two pages.
>> Oh, two pages to the state of
enlightenment.
Well, if I can't read one, I can't read
two either.
Somebody wrote me this week u uh in a
very sweet little letter and it said uh
please explain to me what is the soul.
That's adorable, huh? Please explain to
me what is the soul. Everybody assumes
they know what the soul is. Everybody
lives with it. They hear it here in
church. The soul of soul things. But to
to delineate it and define it. So that's
my work this week. How to answer this
lady's letter.
>> What is the soul? What is it? And how
does one even know that? She hasn't
gotten that far yet. But what is it?
It's certainly not different than
consciousness itself. Consciousness
because in the beginning in the
beginning it says in Genesis in Genesis
there was the light the light of God.
The word there was the word and then
there was the light and the light was
the energy field of consciousness
itself.
So the light of God is the infinite
field of consciousness itself. resist
the light of God is consciousness. So
here we're studying consciousness
and we're really studying the mind of
God.
Wow. Let's see. That's a fact. Resist.
Oh, that's scary. My god.
Dear G Lord, we don't mean any
disrespectful. But
the field of consciousness. So how how
can it be then that what I hold in mind
can affect uh somebody's strength
strength at a distance with kinesiology
what you do is you hold something like
pesticide over a person's solar plexus
and you press down on their arm it goes
weak
uh but with consciousness research you
don't have to do any such thing
uh
I can say to her uh what I'm holding in
mind calibrates over 200 resist.
She doesn't know what I'm holding in
mind.
So people who are suspicious about it
all, I always point out to them, she has
no way of knowing what I'm holding in
mind. And therefore, how does her
consciousness know what my consciousness
is holding except that there is one
common field of consciousness? So
there's one common field of
consciousness that includes all of us.
Everyone in this room. Everyone in this
room. And this is what the word is meant
by the term holy company. This is what
is meant by the term holy company.
You didn't know what holy company is.
Now I tell you, you are holy company.
Because consciousness is is is
a
influenced by the field.
It's influenced by the field and those
that you associate with and radiate out
of field. And this field itself is
uplifting. To merely be in the field is
to be uplifted.
And many organizations that are
spiritually based their influence is not
just what they teach but the energy
field of the teaching of the groups
themselves.
Uh purely spiritual groups such as
12step groups uh uplift the whole world
just by by the virtue of what they are.
So to to to increase the success of
one's spiritual endeavor to align with a
spiritual group increases the likelihood
of success doesn't mean do you have to
join it you don't have to go to meetings
you don't have to donate anything but to
become aligned with it by intention.
So alignment you see unifies. So if the
whole country is is is
um happily looking forward to what
doggy's going to be in the White House,
you see how that aligns and all the
disruption that occurred during the
election can actually be healed by a
waggy dog in the in the in the White
House. Hi.
That's going to be a great famous dog,
isn't it? So you see how good intention
good intention then brings forth the
human condition of concern and love
compassion for all of life. So whether
they win or they lose we have compassion
for those who have been through the
experience.
Yes.
Did you say something?
Okay. Move move on next.
Yeah.
These are the various inner states uh
which are described as in ineffable.
Ineffable meaning you cannot define
them. You cannot control them. So this
brings up the differentiation between
the linear and the nonlinear.
So the the the spiritual is nonlinear.
It has to do with an overall field of
consciousness. The linear is causality
and that's classically described as the
the Newtonian world of causality
of cause and effect. The world of
science, the world of logic and proof
that which is nonlinear cannot be pro
cannot be proven nor can it be disproven
by the linear. science. With science,
you can neither prove nor disprove
uh
spiritual concepts and therefore the
attempts of people in the linear sort of
prosaic pedestrian world who try to
disprove
uh God and divinity and spiritual
reality are unable to do so because they
are they're confined to a lower realm.
The the linear realm is described as
pedestrian
and the spiritual realm is lofty. It's
energy field 500 and up. So the energy
field of the spiritual is what uplifts
this whole group and it's why we are
influencing
uh all of humanity.
This group is influencing all of
humanity.
All of humanity. Does that sound
grandiose? and pompus and nuts.
This group is influencing all of
humanity. Resist.
That's pretty good for a Saturday
morning.
By virtue not of what we do,
but be because of what we are.
See, in the lower levels, who you are is
is depending on what you have. The next
higher level is what you do
and then the highest level of all is
what you have become.
So it starts out have do and then be.
So in certain levels what you have is
what impresses people money and cars and
all that. the next level, your title.
Your title, you know, the the title,
your president, your vice president,
you're an admiral,
you're Mr. uh gatekeeper, whatever. I
like German because German has a
addresses you with a title of who you
are, mi mr. Train station master.
And what's cute about it is his wife
becomes Mrs. Train Station Master.
And even after he's dead and gone, she's
still Mrs. Mrs. Train Station Master.
That I think that's so adorable about
German, you know, Mrs. Mrs. Train
Station Master.
So the title then uh so you it's not
what you have.
In the end, the world doesn't really
care at all about what you have. It's
all the jackals come after it, but the
world doesn't really care about that. uh
and what is significant is what you do.
What you do of course has a great
influence in the world. You can do good
or you could do evil but what you have
become. So the spiritual endeavor is to
expand
into the possibilities the
transformation of consciousness into the
enlightened states of advanced
consciousness
which influence all of the world and
alter your own brain function. So that
as the condundalini energy rises and
goes up through the chakra system
uh your your the way you are in the
world and the way the world reacts to
you is uh different and I think we
demonstrated this before. We'll ask it
one more time. When a human being who is
evolved passes by the trees know it
resist.
All of nature knows it. All of nature is
aware of the divinity there within the
human consciousness.
So to walk through the park then you're
doing what all that's necessary is to be
just by your being there. The park is
supported and people feel a love and a
peace with nature. So the peace of
nature then and we were noticing it on
the drive here. You pass through a big
canyon and in the mountain ranges and
woods, no matter what you go through,
although it looks different, there is a
prevailing peace. Prevailing peace and
that's one of the reasons I moved to
Arizona in the beginning was because the
the immense
states of peace and uh
I lived all by myself in a state of
infinite peace for years and didn't know
anybody was living there with me. I was
all by myself for years and I didn't
know anybody else who was living in the
house for a while. I can remember
walking past a mirror and saw somebody
in the mirror and it shocked me. There
was somebody in the mirror.
Another time I tried walking through a
wall, went smack into the wall.
Wham!
I was expecting you to go right through
the wall in my atheric body and I forgot
I still had this physical body. Yeah.
So,
you need a friend when you go in those
states. You need a friend somewhere who
knows where you're at.
So, they don't call the police or the
patty wagon.
Let's move to the last next one. Yes. Uh
let's see. These are
what what does it say on top? Theories.
God versus
>> God versus science. Oh yes. Uh many of
the things that uh are scientifically
provable or disprovable you see are
really in a different realm and
therefore
uh to expand beyond science then we have
to include the domain of the nonlinear
that which is nonprovable.
science science is still trying to solve
in and various journals uh fiddle around
about these things. the journal of
consciousness studies and all
are still trying to figure out whether
conscious what how does consciousness
come about and um Crick who was a
atheist you know calibrated I forget
what he calibrated it
the various studies that try to discern
the c the cause of how the mind
influences the brain and they they never
they never have stumbled upon on the
very ob the very obvious. Now the what?
Let me have your arm. The obvious is
what I'm holding in mind. Resist. All
right. Maxwell Maxwell's relationship
between electricity and magnetism
explains how it is that the atheric body
consciousness the power how can a
nonlinear field like consciousness
influence the human brain? Where does it
interact? In other words, and how does
it interact?
And it seems obvious
that it's analogous to Maxwell's
a magnetic field around a wire creates
an electric current.
It and vice versa electric current
around a wire creates a magnetic field.
So the energy field of consciousness
itself which is infinite
then influences the neurons in your
brain.
So whatever your level of consciousness
is, it is activating neurons and it is
also facilitating
the emergence and the synaptic
interchanges
of the neurons in your brain that are
associated with advanced spiritual
awareness. So in the beginning a person
doesn't have advanced spiritual
awareness because the neurons aren't
capable of it yet. the neurons can't put
it together. But as the condolini energy
flows up and you get right brain
dominance and now these neurons who are
constantly proliferating and dying begin
to synapse with each other and the
energy field of your consciousness then
energizes the flow of electricity you
might say in the brain's neurons. So
that's how the emer emergent
uh spiritual state then becomes
conscious and describable.
uh not describable in Newtonian terms.
Now people will say uh suddenly one
morning what was that light you tell
just repeat that one about the light. So
because I want to describe the when the
light came on
>> you want me to describe
>> just to describe what the phenomena was
like subjectively what your inner
experience was like.
>> Okay. You're earning and listening to
the radio or what?
>> What were you doing?
>> I was having a um I was just going
waking up. It was like about 4 in the
morning, 4:00 or 5 in the morning.
>> And all of a sudden, I realized there
was a light coming in from the corner of
a wall. Not there wasn't from the
window, it was a corner.
>> And the light had an energy behind it
>> that came into the room and illuminated
the room. You couldn't see a single
object in the room. It just illuminated
the room. And then all of a sudden, the
light went into me as though it was a
living being.
And after that was when we started to do
the work.
>> That's the subjective inner experience
which cannot be explained scientifically
uh or in any other way. And so that is
the state called illumination which is
spontaneously some spontaneous and
transformative because after that the
life changed altogether
>> life changed completely
>> and it's almost identical to the inner
experience that Bill Wilson had
>> exactly
>> uh who founded Alcoholics Anonymous and
uh he gave up hope of trying to believe
in God because he was a atheist and he
said well if if I have to believe in God
to recover. I guess I'm going to die of
this disease. And he gave up. He just
abandoned the whole thing. And all of a
sudden, the light arose.
>> Mhm.
>> Like a divine energy shone forth from
the corners. And the experience is
identical. So there you got and this was
many years different and uh
>> it's I knew Bill years and years ago and
he would tell the story every October
>> uh of how how the phenomenon occurred
and you had never heard of that at the
time it kept happened to you and never
even heard of it.
>> I never even heard
>> and yet it was identical. So there you
have the nonlinear
verifiable
by its recurrence throughout human
history to various people in various
conditions.
Many of them became saints and happened
to many of the saints. Uh spwell walking
along in the in the desert uh the divine
presence was there. You know the bush
lit up the divine light etc. So I just
want to confirm you know clinically
uh
the reality and believability the c
credibility of inner line nonlinear
experience because as as spiritual
students you begin having them. They may
start out or they may start out major
and you can't always share them with
others. You know you you share it with
your mother she tells you you need a
psychiatrist you know
have you seen a doctor lately dear.
So you cannot so you have to be if one
reason to be in spiritual company is
because within spiritual company such
things are understood and have been
experienced by others. to the
confirmation of human experience across
the centuries
across thousands of years in diverse
parts of the world. The very same
experience close to 2,000 years ago on
the other side of the planet in a
different culture was is identical. So
this experience of the saints,
experience of saints throughout time,
the experience of modern enlightened
people uh are have been the same
despite everything. And that's very
interesting from the scientific
viewpoint. So we'll go to the next
slide. I want to get through all these
that we've done.
>> This is the wolf and sheep's clothing.
This is the wolf and sheep's clothing
and it's time.
>> The wolf and sheep's clothing indicates
that it's time.
That's such a profound thing. This is
what the human mind cannot discern.
That's why we need spiritual teachers,
people who are who are founded in
reality is because the human mind unaded
cannot differentiate appearance from
essence. And in accepting that you
arrive at a humility, the inner humility
of spiritual endeavor is that I of my
own self etc. either know or do not know
of such a thing.
And we see in political times how
extreme that is, how extremely
negative some simple thing can be
portrayed all across TV land. You know
the fact that somebody's sock was
hanging down becomes the news of the
day. His sock was hanging down. It was
not hanging down.
How profoundly disturbing life can be
when uh things are misinterpreted and
then exaggerated. So the difficulty with
the media is that it not only is prone
to being unable to tell the wolf from
sheep's clothing, but it then
exaggerates it.
And some of these uh ads and stories
were on television
150 times a day. 150 times a day on
thousands of stations in worldwide.
And so what you see is the human
condition
uh being coming entrained becoming
entrained that you have been programmed.
So now to create the paran little
exaggerate your paranoia a little more I
want you to realize you have all been
programmed.
You've all been programmed
unwittingly
by image, by smile. If I hold this
product up and I go
or if I hold this product up and I go,
there's one there's an ad for stuff that
keeps your false teeth in
and and it shows you this is supposed to
be the bad side. what what what what
it's like without their product and this
guy's jaws open and you see these
strings of like glue. Man, it's the most
horrible picture.
Then they come on with their product
name. Well, all I can remember is the
product name in that picture. So, I
would never buy this anti-
false teeth remedy because my mind has
already been printed. And I realize it's
been printed. this ugly ugly teeth
coming apart with all this like glue and
then the next comes their product name.
So they've imprinted upon me that
picture and their product. So you know
the people who need the most help are
people in advertising I think. I mean
it's still a hobby I want to get into
someday that they've programmed the
people very negatively about their
product and think what they're spending.
to have that thing repeated over and
over. But just the the awareness
subliminally that we're constantly being
brainwashed, just the awareness that
that goes on makes you more less
susceptible, not quite as naive. You
begin to question things. Is that really
true or is that have I become
indoctrinated? So the media have become
a a means of indoctrination.
So to be more aware, we have to be aware
that whether we like it or not,
subliminally we've been indoctrinated.
We've been indoctrinated. The quicker
you admit that, the more free we will
be. You'll say, "I've been indoctrinated
all over the place." And then once you
realize that, you begin to see it. You
see those false teeth ads. Can't you see
it? I've spoken before about the dog's
wagging tail. Somebody wrote me
recently. The calibration level of an ad
advertisement was tripled when he put
over in the corner the picture of a dog
of a dog's wagging tail. Instantly the
whole advertisement, the consciousness
level, the whole ad went up with a dog's
wagging tail. You know, a dog is wagging
tail is 500 like a kitty's fur. All
right, so it's time for a break and I
thank you very much. That's the end of
the review.
What we did primarily thus far is a
review for all the new people and this a
review for familiarity for the rest.
Amen. Thank you.