Okay.
I need a pen for this. Yeah.
>> Made me go first.
>> They made me go first.
>> You're very quiet.
>> Okay.
It's okay. They will. Okay.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Before I ask my question,
>> what is the actual because coming up
here for me to ask a question or there's
a lot of fear. What
>> you should be afraid.
>> I know. But what am I afraid of?
>> You've approached the great Oz.
And if the great Oz is not pleased with
you.
Oh, it's too horrible to even imagine.
>> Are you going to let him get by with
that?
>> I mean,
>> what is the actual fear? Is it fear of
judgment of the audience or my own
judgment?
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, what will people think of me?
>> Yeah. With them. Who cares what they
think of you?
My question is,
>> you're not narcissistic enough.
>> Believe me, you didn't hear my next
question yet.
Um,
which which brings me to it is
I'm realizing I have I I almost would
call it an addiction, but it's like an
obsession.
And it it it has to do with my physical
my whole physical appearance.
>> Yeah. It's so yeah, narcissism it
but but it's it's almost terrifying to
think like terrifying to let it go. It's
it's like such an identification. I'm
I'm sure there's some positives in it to
stay healthy, look nice
>> that you are your body, huh?
>> Yeah. And and I know intellectually I
know I'm not this body. I know it
>> intellectually.
>> Intellectually. And I and I've also had
some experiences that that I that I do
know on a deeper level. I'm not this
body. But it's upon awakening it it's it
it comes up so strong and it's daily
that it's like almost an obsession. And
I kind of see where it comes from. But
>> I don't know what to do.
>> It's terrifying to let it go. And I
don't know that I want to let it go
either.
>> No, but it but
>> you're talking about body image. Yeah.
>> You're not talking about the body.
>> No, I'm talking about body image.
>> You're talking about the image you have.
Yeah. A picture you have of your body.
>> Yeah.
Well, once you're built like Hercules,
like I am
>> That's great.
>> No, I what what I realize is that uh I
am not I'm not my body.
Uh the body is a tool
and it's very useful.
Without it, you can't be here. for
instance,
that's it. The admission price is having
a body. So, you have to put up with the
body
uh for the purpose of this incarnation,
you know.
Actually, it's a tremendous nuisance,
but uh you get used to it. But you've
learned how to turn it around from a
nuisance to from a a deficit to an
asset. You know what I'm saying?
>> Mhm. I was never happy to have a body
starting at age three. I was
disappointed
that I I was uh that you have this body.
It was bad enough to exist, but to have
a body go with it was really
traumatic, you know. But you've learned
how to turn it around. What would you
call it? Vanity. Vanity. is definitely
vanity and and a lot of my like
self-worth tied up into it. I think or
at least
>> it's there's an aspect of vanity and
there's also an aspect of being a real
late developer as a young man
there was such a there was such like a
want to
>> grow up
>> to grow up and be more manly. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
>> So it's almost like the boy in you
>> Yeah. It's the boy in you that's
impressed with the body of the man.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. So, it isn't the man in you
that's impressed with it.
>> Boy,
>> it's the boy.
>> Man, he
>> today I am a man.
>> Yeah. The boy can't wait till he grows
up and becomes a man. He's sort of
ashamed of being a boy,
>> you know, like you're a secondass
citizen as a boy. And when you're a man,
you're a first class citizen, at least
in our society.
So, I can see how the boy would be
impressed that now he's a man.
>> I remember I did a past life regression.
I came to
uh in that lifetime in the body of a uh
uh
Christ with an anvil and a fire and
>> blacksmith.
>> Blacksmith.
Uh it was a lifetime that I wanted to
recall something that I suspected.
And as the reexperience began to run, I
remember experiencing myself as a
blacksmith. And the first thing I did is
look at myself and I was like a giant
misomorph. I had these huge muscles, you
know what I mean? And of course when I
grew up, you know, the coach told me to
stay off the field
and the school doctor wouldn't let me on
the field. He says, "Oh, your bones will
snap. You're too small." So, it was
really fun to come to in a lifetime with
these powerful biceps and powerful
forearms, you know. So, I really got a
kick out of the muscularity, the feeling
of strength. So, when I watch um I throw
truckers for instance, I'll say I mean,
they've got these they're big misomorphs
with these giant muscles, you know what
I mean? And I was got a kick out of
that. remember experiencing what it was
to be uh pet tattooed me some morph with
giant biceps and you know you could lift
a camel or something.
>> So is it just just being aware that it's
just like the little child wanting to
grow?
>> It's the boy. The boy being thrilled by
becoming a adult male. Yes.
>> Mhm. Yeah. I think it's the boy. Let's
ask. It's the boy that's getting a real
thrill and kick out of being the man.
Resist.
Uhhuh.
Is that going to help me let it go?
>> I think so because you get used to it.
It's like I'm getting a kick out of
being older, you know, and all my my
colleagues from prior days are all
toppling over
and here I am the survivor.
There goes Pete. There goes Joe. You
know what I mean? Yeah. You see, but
it's sort of a kick, you know, to be
able to hang on for a while. And uh so
you get to appreciate old ages. You
know, you miss that in all the lifetimes
when you got shot when you were 26 years
old.
You never got to experience what it is
to be an old cajger.
>> And it's sort of fun being an old
codger. You know what I'm saying? It's
got a big downside. You can't see
anything. You can't hear anything. You
can't remember anything.
You can't lift more than six pounds.
But, you know, you do get you get to do
the old cadre trip. So, these are all
part of the trips that I think we have
to fulfill
trip.
>> You get to be an old gopher. You know
what I'm saying?
>> Yep.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay.
All those brown baggers are dead.
>> I'm not going to tell him the brown
story.
>> Oh, it's funny.
>> No.
>> No. No.
>> Hello.
>> Am I signing these for you?
>> Yes. Oh,
>> all right.
>> For the group, actually, we have two
groups.
>> What?
I can't do that. I have to sign where I
can sign. This is all flapping.
>> What?
I don't know what she's talking about.
Oh, I see here. Okay.
So, what's on your mind today?
Uh I feel like uh touching your feet in
gratitude like I do I did the last year
and the year before. May I please
>> tell me what she said.
>> She's feeling gratitude.
>> Yes.
>> Oh okay.
>> Um tell them where you're from.
>> Well I'm an in I'm from India.
>> Yes.
>> I live in Dubai.
>> Oh yes that's right. Um as a as born as
a Hindu
uh we generally touch the feet of the
guru in gratitude.
>> Oh yes
>> and love.
>> May I do that please with you?
>> Yes.
>> May I please do that?
>> I uh appreciate the Hindu
you know tradition and religion.
>> Yes.
I want to do it right.
Otherwise, you and I'll have to rerun
the whole procedure.
We get on the other side, they're going
to say, "You got to go back and do it
right." Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, sweetheart, for reminding me
of that tradition.
That's how I derive, you know, I derived
certain knowingness
which it the final doorway came to me. I
think that was uh you know my prior
Hindu teachers and the guru the grace of
the guru came through
so I am obligated to my own Hindu
background.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You know everything.
>> I don't want to tell anybody that.
>> Tell them a little bit about the study
group. Yeah, we have we have two study
groups uh study groups of Dr. Hawkins
teachings in Dubai.
>> Yes,
>> there's one on there used to the the one
on Friday started uh almost three years
ago.
>> Yes, that's true.
>> And uh another one is developed on on
Saturdays as well.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Because that's our weekend.
>> That's where the beautiful islands are
being built.
>> Yes. here. So beautiful. Yeah,
>> there's a lot of stuff going on there
under the under the ocean. You know,
they're rebuilding the old
>> Yeah. Well, I sort of follow the sura of
it. It's interesting.
>> Reclaiming land. And the group members,
both group members have sent you lots of
love and gratitude.
>> Yeah. And I thank them from the bottom
of my heart.
>> Yeah. And we watch your DVDs and we
discuss your teachings. Mhm.
>> And do you have any other suggestions?
>> No, I think you're doing well.
>> Yes. And I'm very pleased that we have
groups in Dubai.
>> You have done a lot for us. Thank you.
And continuing to do. Um
you had mentioned the last time uh and
the time before and also muscle tested
it as to
having transmitted no mind
to this to this oric field.
>> What about no mind?
>> You had you had uh transerred
it to the people. No, the I had asked I
had requested you to transmit no mind to
me.
>> Yes.
>> And you had said it's already been done.
>> Automatically.
>> Oh yes.
>> And you had also muscle tested it to uh
to confirm that.
>> Yes.
>> Um
>> Yeah. She received the silent
transmission.
It had nothing to do with the
talkingness.
In fact, the only purpose of the
talkingness is to keep you occupied.
Because the transmission is silent.
It's by the agreement of the teacher. I
look in you say I see who you are and by
agreement I share the reality of that
which is with your with you. Yeah.
>> The thing is
um has it actualized because sometimes I
>> what
>> has it actualized yet? The low mind
hasn't actualized.
>> Oh, it has a way to progress yet.
>> It has a way to progress still.
>> Yeah, don't worry about it.
>> No, I'm not worried. But I do get I do
get I mean I'm sure it will happen
because the guru has said so. But you
know there are moments when there is
tremendous clarity,
tremendous clarity and the mind appears
to be quite still. Yes.
>> So uh really my question
>> and then eventually there is no mind
that stands still.
>> Yes.
>> That's all an illusion.
>> U my real question is those momentary
occasions
are kind of incredible to myself
and I just wanted to know if are they
really genuine?
>> Is what genuine?
>> Some of her um experiences
>> experiences are they genuine? We can
test that.
>> Oh they're all genuine. Yes.
Are they the ultimate state?
>> No.
>> Is what you're asking.
>> Um,
yeah. Okay. I'll ask that.
>> She just wants to know the experiences,
you know,
the highest.
>> Right. Right. Now you're eight years
old. I think
>> you're like a little child playing with
me.
>> No, no, no.
>> Yes, you are. Yes, you are. You're the
child playing with me. I'm not
complaining. You are getting
>> I'm not complaining. I know. I like to
play with children.
>> You got me to ask a question which is
much higher than what I wanted to ask
you.
>> All right. Yes. Yes. I do love you. Yes.
Yes.
>> You know, so have I so progress has been
made although much more progress needs
to be made. Uh
it's not measurable like that, you know,
>> but it's verifiable.
>> Well, it's uh Yes.
>> Would would you please verify Kum?
>> No.
>> Okay. I waited a whole year.
>> I waited so long.
>> No.
>> She wants to know she's making progress.
Yeah.
>> Let's see. Just for fun then. No more
questions.
She is making progress with this. Okay.
Wow. Wow.
Boom.
All of Dubai is shaken to the red snow.
>> Just Since I've come for so many
thousand miles, may I ask one more?
>> What?
>> Since she's come thousands of miles, can
she ask one more question?
>> Oh, geez.
>> Make it a little question.
>> Okay.
>> Actually, the second one can't be
counted because you made me ask it.
>> She saying
>> the second question can't be counted
because you made her ask it.
Okay, Miss Dubai,
move on.
>> Um
>> yeah,
>> we have people waiting.
>> There is uh you know sometimes what
happens is
suddenly the hand gets up and starts to
write all kinds of things that even I
don't know.
>> Yes.
>> You know, and it's
>> they're occurring spontaneously.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> it's very u astonishing.
>> You become the witness. Yeah.
>> Very good. It's autonomous
>> language that I don't even know, you
know. I mean, I'm not in control of or
>> it's a autonomous. So, you're you're
witnessing the that it's autonomous.
>> Yep. That's enough.
>> Okay. May I do the M with you?
>> That's enough.
>> If we do the M, he's not going to be
able to answer.
>> No, no, that's enough.
>> Wait till the end.
>> Okay. you get too demanding.
>> Um if we do if we don't it's going to um
he'll go into a good state everybody
else will and then all the other
questions
>> and I'll come down with a case of omism
>> that's why we don't like to do that
>> we get oh I get
>> owned
>> but I saw one DVD where he's done it
>> okay that's it goodbye
>> thank you thank you Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes.
>> I have some gifts for you.
>> Yes. Give me gifts.
>> Okay.
>> Give me, give me, give me.
>> Give me, give me, give me,
give me, give me, give me.
She told me
>> that's what I'm saying to you.
>> Okay. Thank you, doll.
>> Thank you very much. Sorry.
>> All right.
>> Okay. These are all signed.
>> Yeah.
There we go.
>> Okay,
>> let's go.
>> Otherwise, you'll annoy the great wizard
of M.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. I'm from India.
>> Oh yes.
>> I've been in following Ramana for many
years.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And then Maharaj. I met Maharaj. I've
been there twice before he attained
samadi.
>> Thank you.
>> But I don't know where I am.
>> But what?
>> In my progress.
>> She doesn't know where she is in her
progress.
>> Oh well, you're in the middle of it.
See, we're always in the middle of it.
We're always in the middle of it.
>> Mhm.
>> And then suddenly it comes to an end.
>> Stopped in the middle. Is it
>> from the middle? You go right to the
end.
What happens is the middleism stops.
>> Mhm.
>> The process stops.
>> Mhm. and reveals
>> the ultimate truth to you. Yeah.
>> Pardon?
>> Yeah. It's self-revealing.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. When it's ready to do so.
>> When it's karmically optimal.
>> Mhm.
>> It suddenly reveals itself effortlessly.
>> So, I have it to do anything. Have I
>> You give up. You give up efforting
>> and just be.
>> And you be. You resign yourself.
>> Okay.
>> And let God worry about your
enlightenment. Why should you worry?
>> Okay.
Okay. Now I have to do the same Indian
custom. Please allow me also to touch
your feet.
>> I have to do that.
>> Yes indeed I know. Okay. Come along.
>> Yes. You have to let God be God. You see
we have to let God be God.
>> So when it is time
>> when it's time I sorry I'm sorry.
It's been so long since I've been in
India. I tell you,
>> what do you want me to do? Sign this
>> I I spent many many a lifetime in India.
I remember dying by the side of the
>> river, you know.
>> Yeah.
>> He's often
>> and the body was burned by the guts on
the side of the river
>> in a row. They burned the body in the
gats. G h a ts you know gats.
And Krishna
Krishna came to me and whispered in my
ear. You see?
>> Oh yes. Krishna comes to you as you.
>> What did he whisper?
>> Yeah. Well on the side of the river.
>> H I cannot tell you.
>> Well, I have a very simple question.
It's actually not simple, but it's
bothering me.
>> There's a lot said about forgiveness.
>> Yes,
>> I've had a hard time with forgiveness.
>> Oh,
>> but I have managed to forgive like I
think I've forgiven in that I wish the
people well and
that they should, you know, progress in
their life and everything. But do I have
to become friendly with them again or
can I just say you know like I've
forgiven you and I wish you well but I
don't want you in my life.
>> Limitation limitation you see the the
human condition is one of limitation
and you see that all error and and
ignorance is due to limitation
and the limitation
is by the very structure of the human
mind. It's intrinsically unable to
discern truth from falsehood. It's not
capable of it. It has no means to do so.
And that's the value of the teacher is
because in and of oneself, it is
unlikely that one will realize the
truth, you know.
Yes.
And it's because of the nature of the
mind. So Jesus Christ said that everyone
deserves forgiveness because of the very
limitation of the mind itself. So they
are all
in intrinsically innocent.
Eve when she was tempted in the garden
of Eden, you see
>> was so innocent. She didn't realize the
limitations of the mind and therefore
she was duck soup for the serpent
because he saw her naive.
Well, you're no longer duck soup for
evil once you become more conscious. So
the purpose of all these lectures is to
convert people from
uh
no information to sufficient information
that they can be dep independent
henceforth.
How to tell truth from falsehood. How to
discern perception from essence. That
makes you independent of the teacher.
You've you've already derived everything
that plus the blessing of the teacher is
all that can be given. The rest is up to
you.
>> Yeah.
>> But would I think I mean I feel that I
have forgiven. But if I don't allow that
person back in my life, have I really
forgiven or not?
>> Well, you don't have to allow them back
in your life. A lot of them probably
it'd be a good idea not to.
>> Right. That's that was my
>> I mean I forgive the guy from stealing
from me, but I'm not going to put him in
charge of my bank account again.
>> That was my question. Thank you. Thank
you.
>> The wise learn from the experience of
others. The smart learn from the
experience of their own life. And the
dumb don't learn from either.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> this is my first time here. I'm
>> very terrifyingly nervous.
>> Oh, that you should be terrified of the
great odds.
>> The great odd
shiver and shake, mortal.
>> Yes, mortal. You would
>> my
>> You would dare to speak to the great Oz.
>> Speak. Oh, mortal.
My very humble mortal question,
>> good thing is
>> what is the role of sexuality in
elevating our consciousness? Is it just
juicing our body? Is there
>> what is its role in
>> in attaining
>> as a as a as a pathway to enlightenment?
>> As a pathway to enlightenment.
Well, it' be like asking me what eating
ice cream is like, you know, to get you
into enlightenment or cheesecake alam
mode or
sensual pleasure.
Sensual pleasure
in and of itself is an attachment. The
Buddha said the first thing to be
released is the attachment to the senses
of the body. And the the senses of the
body are constantly craving.
You cannot become enlightened until you
transcend the cravingness of the body.
Huh? The first thing to do would be to
satisfy it. You know,
and then
let go becoming addicted to constantly
seeking physical pleasures. This is if
you're talking about seeking
enlightenment. Yes.
All sexual pleasure is transitory,
right?
How long does an orgasm last? You know,
>> not long.
>> No.
>> Exactly.
>> So, as you attain those higher states,
you don't
>> I don't think it has anything to do with
higher states. I don't believe in
tantra. contric sex and all those kind
of things.
>> Those are all rationalizations to just
indulge yourself. There's nothing wrong
with indulging the senses.
It's being attached to it.
The senses are constantly
experiencing pleasure. So, you can't
stop it. It isn't a matter of stopping
it or avoiding it. It's a matter of not
being attached to it. An orgasm comes
and goes.
The Swiss cheese sandwich comes and
goes. Beautiful music comes and goes.
Yeah. The other night we saw one of my
favorite operas. So that opera comes and
goes. And the final area always comes
and goes.
So
the thing is not to become attached to
that which is transitory and fleeting.
>> Well, that's all of life,
>> right?
If you can't live without a
cheeseburger, then you're you're hooked.
So how do you remain happy in the
institution of marriage and
continue a loving relationship without
>> it's the attachment I said to the
sensuality
>> the attachment to the physicality.
Yeah.
We're talking about a truck stop. I love
truck stops
because you can go in there's this huge
cafeteria. So, there's this guy. He
weighs about 400 pounds and he's got his
tray heaped up and uh I knew sooner
within a few minutes he was back at the
cafeteria
heaping up his tray again. He went back
there four times. He's already 450bs
easily. He's four times back at the at
the trough, you might say.
So the thing is not to get hooked by
sensory pleasures to appreciate them and
enjoy them you know but you don't have
to be hooked hooked on them. All right.
>> Thank you.
>> The big O baby.
Isn't
that familiar with that?
I think it was a book or saying the big
O baby.
>> Yeah.
>> Hi. Hello. Um my question is somewhat
related to your dialogue earlier and you
were talking about the mind patterns and
the untrained mind and how the thoughts
feed into the ego and give it juice. So
my question is
um that I have certain people in my life
i.e. family members that
um
I don't think that I allow the internal
mind dialogue when I'm around them,
but yet they inevitably
I feel myself drawn down to these lower
states and
>> you get you get egged on to joining the
wrestling match. Is that it?
>> It's it's not even a matter of fighting
with them. There's no,
>> it's a matter of what then?
>> It's what happens to me energetically.
>> It's an energetic thing.
>> How do you know what's energetic?
>> Because I lose my vitality
and I get emotionally
sad.
>> Oh.
>> And drained.
>> Uhhuh. So they're negative energ
entities.
>> Yeah. It's when I'm around negative
people.
>> Uhhuh. I'm very good at
maintaining who I am and staying in
love.
>> Yes.
>> Around around most people. But certain
family members
>> Uhhuh.
>> I just
>> certain family members are trying.
>> Yeah.
>> There are there are teachers. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> All right. So you see them as a teacher
and then find out what it is that's
being asked of you.
find out what really is being asked of
you.
To be tolerant, to be compassionate, to
be forgiving, to be patient.
And why don't you avoid them?
>> Well, I do sometimes.
>> Okay, good.
>> So, um,
>> yeah. No, there's always that way.
There's always certain people in the
world that make you feel worse and, uh,
after a while, you become evolved and
they don't affect you anymore. But for a
period of time,
um, you know, you have to realize you're
you're hooking into them. You're hooking
into them. We like to blame them.
They're hooking us. No, you're hooking
into them.
>> Well, I know I'm getting hooked, but
there's I've gotten very good at just I,
you know, I'm praying and I'm staying in
love and I don't engage in that internal
Yes. that mind dialogue that you're
>> So, what is your complaint then?
>> I It's still happening to me on an
energetic level. I just feel so negative
and drawn down.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh. Well, I don't know what to
tell you about it. Just avoid them.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Eventually with with serious spiritual
evolution,
so-called negative entities don't drain
drain you anymore.
Yeah.
>> So, how do I get there? uh by conscious
spiritual work might be you know uh
perfect love, perfect forgiveness,
perfect tolerance, perfect patience
by perfecting the spiritual virtues.
Yeah.
>> Okay.
Thank you.
>> Yep.
>> You perfect the virtues by practice. So
these people give you practice.
What did you do here? You
>> I put the cap on because I didn't want
to draw.
>> I can't sign it with the cap on
right now.
>> Okay.
>> Okay,
>> Doc. I'm going to be the first freebie.
So, I just wanted to bring and tell you
that I love you and the Delaware Valley
group sends their love
>> and thank you both.
>> And um that was
>> my message. Delaware Valley.
>> Delaware.
>> Philadelphia area. Oh, thank you so
much.
>> And do you do we have your
>> Yes. Tom Shatzel is one of the leaders
that
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you.
>> Put it right there, honey.
>> Yep.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you, Doc.
Doc. Uh, the wounded healer archetype is
up.
>> The what?
>> Wounded healer
archetype.
>> What is that?
>> I don't
>> The wounded what?
>> Healer. Healer
>> is What do you mean the archetype is up?
>> I'm hearing it all around me. And
>> you're hearing all around you?
>> I'm hearing the term around
>> healer.
>> Oh, yeah. It's an old terminology. Okay.
Yeah.
>> And so, uh, to me, if I'm hearing it
around me, then I've got some attraction
to it or aversion to that.
>> What does the wounded healer mean to
you?
>> Nothing.
>> Okay, forget about it.
You know, I get tired of people just
hanging in with something because it's
trendy.
>> I don't know. One more person to ask me
if the world's going to come to an end
in 2025. I'm going to
>> jump off the stage or whatever's
>> 2015 or whatever.
>> I mean, you know, it's so trendy.
>> Okay.
>> It's just trendy.
>> All right.
>> You know, it's so new newagy trendy.
>> Is it?
>> The end of the world's coming. Come on.
Give me a break. Okay. Really? Where are
you?
>> I love you, Doc.
>> Jesus. The end of the world. God. Jesus.
>> The woos.
>> Yeah, the woos. Get away. Stay away from
the woo woos.
>> Oh god.
>> UFOs and the end of the world and
>> Well, all right. If if the word world
was to end, if we were all really into
being Christians, it wouldn't make a
difference anyway.
>> No, it wouldn't make a difference. Well,
I say the world will not come to an end
in 2012.
>> 2020.
>> 2020. or 2012
>> 1215 2015
or any of those numbers
>> and if I am wrong I will give you a
million dollars.
>> That was a good one. That was a win-win
situation.
The world comes to an end. You get your
million.
>> Yes.
>> Um after I read your book, Truth versus
Falsehood, I changed my political party
and then I gave up politics alto
together after that. And but now I guess
there's remnants of some civic duty that
keep coming up where I feel like you
know the election coming up and I feel
like it's my duty to vote yet. I haven't
got a clue of any idea of
what who to vote for or
>> Well, let it run it course and you'll be
attracted to one person or the other.
>> Just do what? Excuse me.
>> Let let the let it still has some months
to run. You know,
the uh campaign and by the time your
election day comes around, you'll
probably know which to do.
>> Does it really matter either one? No, it
doesn't really matter and the world
doesn't really care. But you get a
narcissistic gratification that you've
registered your vote and done your
American duty.
>> I get it. Okay. Thank you.
>> Oh, could I have a picture?
>> May the best man win. Yep.
Oops, I said man. May the best person
win.
Yeah. Don't forget the gender.
>> Good God. No.
>> Very imprompt
camera.
>> Yes.
>> Oh, okay. All right. There we go.
Made the best human being. Re
that shows a prejudice for human beings.
May the best entity win.
>> Yes.
>> Hi. Happy birthday.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> Hi.
Um I my question was around um sort of
what you and Susan were talking about
earlier about progressive fields
and I've been able to
experience the witness
and so for instance this week this week
it was lost and there's a sense of
anguish when it's lost. In other words,
there's a period of time, it could be
weeks or even months where
>> it's not lost. It's just you're not
identifying with the witness. You're
you're identifying with the subject
matter that the witness is witnessing.
Yeah. Okay.
Well, you mentioned um being willing to
um endure anguish
and sometimes
if anguish comes
there's a tendency to like I don't know
it's like dislike the ego. It's like, oh
my gosh, you know, I'm in my mind right
now or I'm in my body, you know, place
to be.
>> God, I I was out of here and now I'm in
here,
>> you know. So, there's an aversion almost
to
>> trans transitory state. Yes. But that's
transitory.
>> Well, in fact, as soon as I got in the
car to come here, it started to leave.
>> Mhm.
>> As soon as I got on the plane, it was
better. And as soon as I arrived in
Sedona, it was gone.
>> Yes. Yes. transitory
and and those that th those are normal
fluctuations in awareness. That's normal
normal fluctuations. You don't always
stay in the same state of consciousness
all the time. No,
>> because it's evolving evolving.
So is that
I guess the challenge also is if it's
unconscious if there was nothing
necessarily to cause any trigger.
>> No, there's no cause or effect like
that. They are um you know you see the
clouds in the sky are moving like this.
You know they're not really being caused
by anything because of what they are.
The density, the temperature, the
humidity. This phenomena occurs but
nothing is causing that phenomena to to
occur. It's arising autonomously by the
nature of itself.
So as you begin to study consciousness
as a subject in itself certain changes
begin to take place.
If you begin asking the sky, who are
you? The sky begins to
the stars twinkle brighter and the
clouds come and go.
>> Well, I would just like to share the
intention with everybody that this
clouds part
>> and that they're transient.
>> Yes. So, don't worry about it.
>> Thank you. It's
>> fine.
>> Thank you.
>> Infinite field of consciousness is like
the sky.
And then the content of consciousness is
what you're aware of. Once you identify
with consciousness itself, you won't
complain about what goes on within it.
>> If you're the infinite playing field,
who cares what game is going on? Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah.
Yes.
>> Hi. Uh,
I'd like to thank you and my mentor for
everything that you are
today. You said we're here just to
transcend our karma.
>> I'm not hearing him well.
>> Um, he you said that we were here to
transcend our karma.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Undo negative and gain positive. Yes.
All right. We had a question come up in
our Hawkins group.
>> Just a little bit.
>> A little bit more. Okay. About if you
surrender everything to God, if you
forgive everything, no matter what,
would God's grace come and help
alleviate your karma?
>> Uh what's the question?
>> If say one more time, if you if you
>> surrender everything,
>> surrender everything to God
>> and you forgive everything
>> and you forgive everything.
>> Yes. Would God's grace come and help
relieve your karma?
>> Would God's grace come and help relieve
your karma?
>> Yeah, you've already done it.
>> Okay, great. Thank you.
>> God says, "Shine your shoes and your
shoes are shiny." You've already done
God's will.
>> Yep.
Thank you, mentor.
Yes.
>> I love you, Duck.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Um, I'm in recovery for sex addiction.
>> What?
>> Uh, sex addiction. Compulsive sex.
>> Oh, yes.
>> Yeah. And I find myself uh still
struggling with lust.
>> Still struggling with what?
>> Lust.
>> Oh, yes.
>> Yeah. With lust. And so, I guess I
wanted to
>> That's craving this and desire. Yes.
>> Yeah.
All right. So
what you have to do is when it it
appears first in your mind as an image
>> Yeah.
>> or a recollection and you have to
extinguish it at that moment. You cannot
wait.
A person who's recovering from
alcoholism I tell them the picture of a
drink will appear in your mind. If you
don't extinguish it in that instant, you
will then end up with a drink.
The same with sex. The minute the image
appears in your mind, if you don't
extinguish, so you're not desiring. What
you're triggered by is the image. It
always starts first as an image.
>> Yeah.
>> When it's just an image, you can
extinguish it. If you wait, the image
begins to attracting energy to it. And
now it's too strong. You can't
extinguish it. You have to extinguish it
the minute it appears.
>> Thanks.
>> In today's world, it's hard to do
because lust is paraded across the
television
camera, the television set night after
night.
Lust in one form or another. It's like
an obsession.
Oh, look at my da da da.
school teacher can't appear to talk
about the school principal. She's got to
have cleavage down to here. What does
she need cleavage for? You know, to tell
us about the problem she's having with
her kindergarten.
I was, if I was the producer of that
thing, I'd say, "Get a big safety pin
and button the damn thing up. For
Christ's sake,
we're not running a wh house here. We're
running a school.
The parade of lust is just endless.
We just watch the television, you know,
channel 5 or whatever one we watch. It's
just one after another.
>> Is there any way to uh get the thoughts
to not come up anymore?
>> What
>> is there any way to not have the
thoughts come up anymore?
>> Well, I there's certain operations that
might help.
any any any other way.
>> But what if you have the operation and
the loss still comes up? Then you're
really screwed.
No, I told you it's the truth. It's the
It's the image.
>> Okay.
>> It's the image.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
kill the image and then you won't have
to worry about the energy that follows
the image. But the energy follows the
image.
That's what the advertiser is counting
on. This is what he's pouring all his
money into.
Dr. Hawkins, um, as was just spoken of,
uh, you said a little while ago that our
purpose here on this plane is to
surrender negative karma and obtain
positive karma.
Where does it fit in that Buddha has
said that
>> where does it fit in? What
>> the the this Buddha I I hear that Buddha
has said
that
let's let's call karma merit. If you
come to a life if one comes to life and
collects nothing but positive merit
>> Yes.
>> and dies another comes to life and and
acquires nothing but negative karma and
passes.
>> Yes. Both will be away for a period of
time and both will return for the
balance.
>> I don't know why you're putting forth
that proposition that way.
>> Well, it seems to me that there
>> Buddha said avoid
negative karma. Let go your attachments.
The first attachments are to the senses
>> and the desire. Yes.
But it seems to me that there's
something in there that he's talking
about
obtaining positive karma, just striving
to obtain positive karma. And
>> I don't think striving for karma is
particularly gainful because you're
looking for gain.
>> Let go seeking karma like it's some kind
of a bank account. That's
>> yeah. Look at life as a chance to
fulfill your potential to become
infinitely and unconditionally loving
towards all of life and all of its
expressions.
And that's all you have to do.
Thank you.
>> I mean, it's just like having the ten
commandments. You don't break the ten
commandments, you know?
>> Yes. So, so, so when you you would do
the same thing. In other words, you
would strive to obtain good karma and
try not to.
>> Yeah, that that's all it is.
>> It's only a striving. It's not like a
bank account. That's what you're saying.
>> Well, no, you you seek virtue for its
own sake.
>> Okay.
>> Actually, you do build up a positive
karmic bank account. Okay.
>> And when you need it,
you can draw from your positive karma
bank account. Okay?
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hello.
>> Uh, no question. I'm originally from
Scotland and I know my bagpipe music
very well. I can assure you.
>> Yes.
>> So, what I've done is I've spent several
hours putting together the finest
backpipe music you'll ever hear.
>> That's giving me
>> Oh, thank you.
>> It's special for three reasons, Dr.
Hawkins. Number one, uh, the music you
will hear is all grade one professional
world champion bag piping.
>> Oh,
>> very, very fine. Mhm.
>> Number two, um my brother plays in one
of the bands.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh Victor plays in the band. And number
three, um there's a incredibly fabulous
rendition of Amazing Grace.
>> Oh.
>> Which was um originally recorded in 1991
by the Royal Scots Dragoon Guards in
England, which he's a member of.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And um it's recorded and played in a
church.
>> Oh, very nice.
>> The Garrison Church.
>> It's also a combination of pipes and the
brass band. It's a beautiful rendition.
Oh. Oh.
>> It was so popular, Dr. Hawkins. It sold
so many so many uh my brother said it
sold so many copies out did the Beatles
that year
>> or whatever. So, I hope you and Susan
enjoy it.
>> Oh, we will.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Well, we were at the Edinburgh Tattoo
and what year? I forget it was and heard
all the endless marching
>> 2003
>> whatever year it was and it was a
marvelous marvelous experience
unforgettable.
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins. I'm happy to be here.
Thank you both. Um this winter I uh have
had about seven months of lung problems
and um I had several times when I
couldn't get my next breath. Yes.
>> An absolute terror
came up for me. And
>> yes,
>> I don't know what to do with that
terror.
>> You don't know what?
>> What to do with the terror?
>> Oh, what's the terror about? That you
won't be able to breathe. You'll die.
>> Uh, you know, it's just terror. So, it's
probably that it is that. But
>> which comes first, the terror or the
breathing difficulty?
>> The breathing difficulty.
>> First, the breathing difficulty.
>> Yes. Then the fear of dying. Yes.
Asphyxiation.
>> Yes. I suppose that's the terror. Yes.
>> Yes. And you take medication for this?
>> Yes, I do.
>> Is it working?
>> Well, it didn't work this winter very
well, but I have asthma and lung disease
and I
>> had infections during the winter.
>> Yeah. So then you have to get back on
your activities so as not to overstress
>> the oxygen requirement. Keep them within
the confines. Yes.
>> Yes. Yes.
And uh inhalers and various things like
this is all you can do.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. The anxiety has to do with
survival. And the willingness to or
surrender your survival to God as you
understand him is progressive is
progressive.
You will finally reach a state where if
you breathe, you don't breathe is
immaterial. But that's hard for you to
imagine right now.
>> But it is quite possible. You might
breathe and you might not. I used to
watch and see whether he's going to
breathe or not breathe. So if he
breathes well I guess karmically he's
due to stay here and if he doesn't
breathe time to leave.
>> I I I felt like I
am willing to go.
>> Yes.
>> But when that moment arises it's very
quick. It's the next breath.
>> Well you think you're ready but you're
not. So yeah,
>> you don't have to worry because the fear
extinguishes itself.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Either you will live in which case it
isn't a problem or you will die in which
it is no longer a problem.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> You understand? We're all all going to
die. It's just a matter of sequence.
>> It's just a matter of sequence. That's
all it is. You know, you pull a number
43 46 29
All you get to do is pick a card, you
know, take a card off the top of the
deck.
We all get to, you know, pick a card.
That's it.
And if you understand that the human
condition is collective, it's shared by
all of us here present. Then you'll see
that what you fear is being alone.
Aloneeness.
No, you're not alone. All of us here in
this room share the same anxiety about
the continuation of the physical body.
And what we really feel is separation
from those that we love and care about.
We really fear separation. It's not
death. Death is where you get separated
for all that you care for, value, love,
etc.
So if you understand it more completely,
it's a fear of separation from those you
love and from your community of fellow
humans. Yeah,
>> that makes
>> that makes it a little easier to handle.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> It's not death that it's separation that
you're afraid of.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> Besides the body once you leave it is is
uh not at all attractive.
You wonder how you could have ever been
attached to that stupid thing.
It's so dumb looking.
Anyway, while you're think you're the
body, it becomes very valuable, you
know,
but when you're not in it, it's not so
valuable.
You might try taking the there's courses
that you used to have to go there to uh
Journeys Out of the Body. Do you ever
read Journeys Out of the Body? I did
read it. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Mhm.
>> All right. Well, the courses that they
give are now available apparently on DVD
or whatever those machines are that you
put on both ears. You don't have to
travel all the way there. I would try
them. Learn how to leave the body and
leave it at will. Okay. That'll help you
overcome your fear of it.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> All right.
>> Monroe Institute. Yes. They have
training tapes on DVDs or CDs or
whatever you call these square things
and uh and you can do them at home
without having to go there.
>> All right.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> I have Kenny's wallet up here.
>> Somebody's walnut. Walnut. Walmart.
>> So, you're gonna
name Ken?
>> Ken.
Okay,
>> she's gonna throw it.
>> I'm not a very good pitcher.
>> That was funny.
That was funny. That was funny. Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> Go ahead. Funny.
>> All right. Thank you, doctor. Um I have
a question from the dialogue and um I'm
going to paraphrase so hang in there for
a second. Um
you said that we have the option and no
obligation to see form act in this way
or that or to be this way or that and I
understand with a group like this um
calibration over 200 where willingness
acceptance and all the the positive
emotions are in play. My question is for
those individuals who are operating
under the quote emergency emotions, are
these options still available to them or
are they um is there are their mind
processes um limiting them? So they
really cannot
>> their level of consciousness limits the
options.
>> Thank you.
>> So some people can choose to be
forgiving. Other people
>> aren't that evolved. That's not an
option for them.
>> They can't make that option. they just
are stuck with hatred
>> and uh are going to die that way. So,
>> okay,
>> uh it may take them a lot of lifetimes
before they get off hatred because you
know it's a biggie and it has a big
payoff.
>> Okay, what if Okay, what if they're
willing?
>> Yes.
>> But they don't have the ability. That's
a possibility.
>> Well, if you are willing then you
develop the ability.
>> Uhhuh.
>> But then you'd probably raise your
consciousness level to at least 200 at
that point and move beyond.
>> You wouldn't.
>> Yeah, the willingness is sufficient.
willingness. Okay.
>> If a person says, "I can't," it's
because they won't. Because they're not
really willing. They think they're
willing. They think they ought to be
willing,
>> but they're not willing to let it go.
>> The willingness isn't
>> you got a resentment and you're still
bothering you, it's because you're
unwilling to let it go. You're still
juicing it.
>> Okay?
>> Unwilling to let it go, you know.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Culture cultures hang on to
>> Okay. I'm going to ask that you ask one
question and that you make it short and
brief because this the line is still out
the door and we only have 20 minutes or
so. 25 minutes or 35 minutes actually
hustle
>> to get this done.
>> Hustle hustle.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> I thank you for everything and all your
work. It's so appreciated. My question
is about joy and is it attached to
emotions that as we've learned um under
your toutelage to sacrifice to to have
our connection is joy different? And I
asked that because um I don't want to
kid myself. I thought over the last year
or so I had let go of the highs and the
lows that emotions can bring in our
life. you walked in the room today and
it was huge and I thought, is that
telling me I still have a lot of work to
do in that department?
>> What?
>> Um, no. Um, when you hit a certain state
in 500s, you cry at everything.
Everything is tearful
>> because Yeah. You see the beauty of
everything.
>> Oh, it was beautiful.
>> You see the beauty of everything. Yeah.
The person comes and his dog looks up at
him adoringly and the doggy's tail goes
like this and you cry because you see
the dog adores them and that he adores
the doggy.
So you see the lovingness the lovingness
uh makes you cry with a silent it's
really a joy. You're really crying with
joy.
>> Thank you.
It lasts for several years.
>> Hello, David and Susan.
I don't have a question. Um,
I do want to thank you for your love and
wisdom, and I want to tell you that I
think you've given me enough to get me
through this lifetime.
>> Good.
Good.
I'll make this with you.
>> Oh, it's the bag pipe.
>> Oh, how good. Boy, have I got good bag
pipe karma.
Boom. Boom. Boom.
Boy, oh boy.
They sound better than I would have
anyway.
>> Yes.
>> I want to do a correction first. Three
years ago, I came up and threw myself in
front of you as a clutterer.
And you said this was related to a
rebellion. I says, "No, my mother was a
clutter."
>> Too close to the mic again.
>> He says clutter. He said he was a
clutter three years ago. And he said
that was due to rebellion. And he he
said, "Well, my mother
>> No, he he said it was due to rebellion.
I said it was due to my mother." You
were right.
Anyway, I have a question. Um, I I think
I read it in the eye about cycles per
brain brain cycles per second.
>> Yes.
>> And I was started calibrating mine and
anyway, I was um in the 9 to 11 range
track. Yeah. And I think that's very
Doesn't that make it kind of difficult
to operate efficiently in
>> No. 911 8 is normal beta beta waves.
Yeah.
>> Okay. So it's still in normal range.
>> It's normal.
>> Okay.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you.
Hello.
Um, my question is in relation to my
father who's an alcoholic. He's a
chronic alcoholic in the the late stages
and um I would just like to ask some
help in in being able to accept his
fate.
>> I'm having trouble. What is she asking?
>> Um, her father is
>> is an alcoholic
>> in the late stages and she wants to ask
some
for accepting for acceptance of his
>> uh do you go to Alanon?
>> No,
>> go ahead.
>> That's a good thing.
>> Okay,
>> because that'll help you. And by helping
yourself, you'll be doing all you can do
to help him. You see, I think Elon is a
tremendous asset to experience it.
just to experience the 12step groups uh
has a longlasting
longl lasting effect.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> Alcoholism is a sickness.
There's too many people that don't look
at it as an illness and it is an
illness.
>> It's a physiologic phenomenon.
>> Okay. And genetic runs in families.
watching someone being overtaken by an
addiction like to see them slowly lose
their
>> if it wasn't alcoholism it might be you
know that they they were going to go you
know with illness so look at it as a
sickness
>> rather than
>> anyway Elanon's the answer
>> okay
>> okay thank you
>> what day is today Saturday
>> Saturday
You drew there by Monday.
>> Dr. Hawkins, I've always wanted
with all my heart to do that Hindu
custom that those two Hindu ladies did.
>> And I would do what?
>> That touching your feet. She always
wanted to do that.
>> Oh yes. Yes.
>> The acoustics in here. I don't know. The
sound is bouncing.
>> Did you touch your feet?
>> Yes. you see the blessing
>> because she is a well you're you live
lives as a Hindu are you still a hind
Hindu now
>> I don't know I just always wanted to do
it really badly
>> all right because of the sacred I know I
understand what you're saying God bless
you in the name of the Lord God bless
your devotion to the old Lord
you pray to the Lord
that was gracious
A couple of times during meditation,
it's appeared as if I'm about to go
nowhere and be nowhere. Hopefully, you
didn't already answer this. And um
a fear comes up that if I go nowhere,
how will anyone find me?
>> You'd be lost into the void of
nothingness. Is that correct? It appears
that way.
>> Then only God could find you.
And uh so at that point you ask God for
assurance. Ask you pray to God for that
state
and affirm the that God is present in
the form of love and for some reason
you're blocking it out.
Okay.
>> Okay. Just ask God to lead you to the
light.
>> Okay. Can I have your blessing with
this?
>> Yes. God bless you in your search for
the light. Amen.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank you, sir.
>> Happy birthday.
>> What we've gotten before is that God
cannot refuse a request.
>> Generic generically. He doesn't answer
specifically,
>> but generically. Yeah. I just want to
say thanks from the bottom of my heart
and everything the work you've done and
>> you know it's really just well flipped
my life around. Um
um I'm a school teacher
>> and high school school teacher and uh
you and Susan were dialoguing uh earlier
about
um going deep in the ocean and then you
know the body kind of runs itself.
If I'm in a classroom of 39th graders
and I and I've tried to practice Yeah.
and I'm I'm going deep in the ocean and
you know the infinite silence.
>> Will the body kind of take over and do
the discipline and the and the stuff
that needs to be done or
>> I don't know if I do it during class.
No.
>> Okay.
So don't
>> you need your linear linear ego.
>> Okay. So Okay. So don't get
contemplated.
>> No, stay on your toes when you're with
ninth graders.
>> Okay.
>> All right.
>> I myself would frisk them all as they
came.
>> Thank you. Appreciate it.
>> Today's classroom, I would frisk them
all and put them through metal
detectors.
>> It's not that I don't trust them. It's
just that I don't trust them.
>> Hi. Uh
I guess I'm looking for some help in uh
kind of uh developing the spiritual
practice so that it's constant like
without reservation.
>> Oh yes
>> constant.
>> Yes.
That takes years to perfect.
uh but eventually it becomes constant
>> that one is always aware
of what is happening from a
from the viewpoint of awareness witness
awareness
you become the witness awareness and you
identify that what you are is the
witness not the content of what you're
witnessing
with a little um practice that can be
can become automatic
>> all right good to hear
>> yep
>> I I have a I have a gift for you. I was
going to give it to you for your
birthday, but it didn't come on time
from the
You can show it to him. It's
>> That's funny.
>> It's a movie that's coming out
making fun of gurus. And uh here you
want to read the It's a little
catchphrase down here.
>> You have to read it back.
>> His karma is huge.
I was going to try to trick Doc into
reading that, but
>> anyway, it's a new movie coming out.
>> Yeah, it it looks like it'll be it'll be
funny. So,
>> all right.
>> Thank you.
>> That is funny.
>> It is funny.
>> The mustache.
>> Yeah. Um, when consciousness reaches
the void,
what is it that refutes the void?
>> The will.
I don't know. I think this is gone.
I'm afraid this pen just went.
>> No.
>> The will.
>> And does consciousness have to remain in
the void for any duration until it is
refuted?
>> No.
All right.
>> Doesn't have to serve time there. No,
>> it's to be appreciated. As I said, it is
a wondrous state. It is incredibly
wondrous.
And that's why one thinks this must be
the ultimate state because it is truly
wondrous and is truly infinite and tr
and truly still and infinite peace.
This must be the great state.
>> All right. Thank you very much.
I'm nervous.
This uh kind of goes along what you were
saying earlier. negation
uh to go to get to the void going up the
branches
and uh and and kind of the crest of the
wave. I mean, they're two they're two
different things, I'm thinking.
And uh I guess which one would you do
first? Like try to be on the crest of
the wave
in the moment, but then I'm thinking I
have to think
to do the best in every situation that
pops up to go up the branches. So, is
that making sense?
>> No.
>> We got a tree and an ocean and I don't
know what else.
>> Well, the crest of the wave to be in the
moment.
>> All right. Yes.
>> And uh but okay. What is negation?
That'd be my question. What is negation?
>> What is negation?
>> The pathway of negation
is na na. Not this, not that. I am not
this, I am not that. I am not this. I am
not that. I refuse this and refuse that
>> and in every situation
>> in you. Yes. Constantly.
>> Constantly
>> kind of like from the course of miracles
mind like thinkingness.
>> So you deny the reality of
all form. See the infinite reality of
existence is not form but that within
form is the formless. It is the formless
within the form which gives it
existence.
But that's a sophisticated
understanding.
>> So it's more of a radical approach so to
speak. Uh I'm not this, I'm not that.
But the easier path may be always doing
kindness at every
>> always choosing kindness in every
situation.
>> I don't I can't hear so well.
>> No, it it's not it's not always choosing
kindness. It's always choosing the
better good
>> in every situation.
situation. So you always choose the
better good rather than kindness. You
always choose the better good. Okay. So
you're like the little iron filing, you
know, you want to Okay, the iron filing
is here. You if you choose this, it goes
down. If you choose this, it goes up. So
you choose this and then it goes up like
this and up like this.
>> And that's not a bad I can think that.
Yeah.
>> Is my intention and be fine.
>> I'm Yeah. I'm sorry. I'm just nervous.
>> That's all right. I'm just having
trouble hearing today. All right. Thank
you.
>> The sound effect the sound uh
>> it's kind of echoing
>> echoing playback or something. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> But we're okay.
>> Where did this come from?
>> Okay.
>> Oh. Oh.
>> Hi, doctor. Hi, Susan.
>> Yes. Hi.
>> My question today is about Alzheimer's
disease.
I heard you say once, I think, that the
soul begins to withdraw from the body in
advanced Alzheimer's disease. And I was
curious if you could say more about that
or say something about what's what's
most useful for someone working with
someone like that.
>> What's the most useful thing that she
can do with the And I never say this
right. Alzheimer's.
>> Alzheimer's.
>> Alzheimer's. Yes.
>> What's the What's I can I can never say.
You mean a relative or somebody you work
on?
>> I I work with Alzheimer's patients.
>> Huh?
>> I work with them
>> with patients.
>> Oh, the patients. Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> What about it?
>> Well, you said that the that the soul
starts to leave the body.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it does. Yeah.
>> Okay. Well, expand on that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I can't expand on it. It's
just that
>> Okay. People
will feel upset and sorry for
Alzheimer's and what they're feeling
upset and sorry for is themsel because
every Alzheimer is said, you know, how
are things here, Gertrude? She says,
"Oh, they're lovely." So true.
>> How long have you been here? Oh, I don't
care about such things anymore. So,
what's the problem? The problem is in
the witness. Oh, poor old granny. So, if
you get off the poor old granny and let
poor old granny be, gr poor old granny
is just fine.
Anything I can do for you? No, they they
take care of me here.
>> I never heard Alzheimer's complain about
anything.
>> Okay, thank you.
>> Except the porridge was cold this
morning.
>> Yeah.
>> No, they don't even complain about that
because they don't remember that it was
cold this morning.
>> You can push them around because they
won't remember you pushed them around,
right?
>> Oh, did you?
Thanks so much. Love you both.
>> No, they're usually sweet and lovable.
And if you ask them how are things,
they'll say, "Well, they're just fine.
How did they treat you here?" Oh, just
fine. Come on.
>> Thank you. God bless. Traffic stopped
there, huh?
>> God bless you, Doc. Um, I've had type
one insulin for 44 years and I've begun
the spiritual releasing, surrendering.
Uh, how do you deal with all the details
of using a pump and all that stuff and
not let that
>> reinforce it?
>> He was a diabetic. Yes. A number of
years. He says, "How do you use all the
>> gizmos that you have to use, you know,
for diabetic?" Yeah. And not let that
affect you. I mean,
>> what do you mean affect you? you let go
of resisting it and accept the fact that
for karmic reasons you've got some kind
of an illness and you take care of it.
So what is the problem?
>> Um one time you talked about you had
released some kind of illness and when
you went to do a lecture on the basis of
all that it kind of tended to bring it
back up and that's what I'm kind of a
little concerned about all the details
of the care reinforcing that linear
reality. They just surrender that and
that's good enough.
>> Yes.
>> Are you saying what he's asking?
>> How what what has this got to do with
your life with you?
>> Well, I'm just worried concerned that
being in all the details of the thing.
Does that reinforce the linear reality
vein? Details of what illness?
>> The diabetes.
>> You have diabetes.
>> Yeah. I got signs and symptoms for
>> All right. So,
what you'd like to do is let go your
belief in diabetes. Oh, yes. Okay. Okay.
Now, I understand what you're saying.
Yes, you can let go. You can let go of
it. It may or may not. Don't forget many
things are they're physical, mental, and
spiritual. And spiritual also means
karmic. And it's also genetic. So,
whether it will get better or not, you
don't know. But if you completely
surrender to it and release on it,
whether it gets better or not becomes
irrelevant, as strange as that sounds.
>> Okay.
>> So, it'll either get better or you won't
give a damn. How's that?
>> Works for me. God bless you.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> It's like the
>> It's like being ugly. The folks out in
front are the ones that get the shock.
You know what I mean?
after looking in the mirror doesn't
upset you anymore. It's the folks out in
traffic.
>> Hi.
>> Hello, Susan. I'm from Australia. Yes.
>> And it's my first time up here
>> and uh I really want to ask um last time
actually I came to your class and you
very kindly came over to the edge of the
platform and I gave you a little book,
Mrs. Twinkle.
>> Yes. Yeah. Yes. Yeah. So, I just want to
classify. Anyway, um I have trouble with
my aura. I had a big near-death
experience eight years ago, and the I've
got very strong again, but I still am
very
um what's the word? Weakened by
electromagnetic waves. Uh I can't be
near mobile tower units. Can't sleep
near them. Can't use a mobile phone.
>> Okay, get it. She she's got she's what
she has is her aura.
>> Yes.
>> Has a defect in it that she cannot
>> um
>> use
>> use like mobile phones, you know.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah.
>> Mobile phones and computers and or or
sleep near a a big large mobile unit.
Okay. And so I always carry a little
thing which helps to uh just to make it
dissipate the electromagnetic waves.
It's a special little machine.
>> And I was just wondering how I can
strengthen this.
>> I know what you're going to say.
>> How you can how she can strengthen this
so she doesn't
>> strengthen my aura so that
>> so she doesn't have to do what?
>> So she doesn't have to carry this thing
around.
>> Carry it around or Yes. Uh these things
are usually passing.
>> It's usually a passing phase like a
readjustment of bodily energies.
>> Yes.
>> It's usually a passing phase and as you
meditate and do other things.
>> Yes.
>> You spend all night in the pyramid or
something like that in Egypt.
>> Yes.
>> It's been eight years, but
>> go walk the stupid.
>> Yes.
>> Yes, that is a good idea.
>> Walk the labyrinth. Yeah.
>> Or the labyrinth.
>> Walk the labyrinth. Yes. Walk the
labyrinth.
>> Yes.
>> Here in
>> uh there's labyrinthes if you inquire
around, you know.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> The original is in the cathedral.
>> Uh there's a labyrinth in Sedona.
>> Yes.
>> At the St. Andrews Episcopal Church.
There's a labyrinth that you can go
anytime.
>> Oh, good.
>> Yeah. It's laid out in the parking lot.
Walk the walk walk the labyrinth at St.
Andrews, the Episcopal Church on Aoyo
100 Aoyo Pinion Drive.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Right off Strike Creek Road and they
have a they have a whole labyrinth
there.
>> Yes.
>> And I that very often will alter that
kind of an energy and get you unhooked.
>> Oh, thank you very much. And could I ask
for a blessing for my country and
>> for Australia?
>> Yes. and friends and who live there and
uh and my family.
>> Oh my gosh. And your neighbors
>> and everybody here
>> and the government.
>> Well, I certainly love the people of
Australia.
>> Yes.
>> And I certainly send them my love and my
blessing and I think they're wonderful
people. Yes.
>> Well, thank you for being in our lives,
Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes.
>> Very much.
>> And it makes me jump around to think of
them.
Thank you. Byebye.
>> She's from Australia.
>> Thank you.
>> See the way to enlightenment is don't be
serious about anything.
>> Keep be light-hearted. Wear the world
like a light garment, you know.
>> And it's all for amusement. Don't forget
what is that? You turned it upside down.
I don't know which end to write with.
This end.
>> Oh,
>> I don't know.
>> I have another one
>> there. I got it.
>> Put that away.
>> What's the
>> Yes. No, this one's fine. Yeah.
>> Very nice to see you again.
>> Got an opportunity to Yes. be with you.
You spo spoke about greeting people uh
when they are dying. Just remember this
morning when you told that when my
brother died a few years ago, I had a
dream after he died that I was with him
in the in the hospital.
>> Yeah.
>> And he was
there like sleeping and like sick. And I
told him, "What are you doing there?
You're you're dying. You you you're dead
now. You can go away from this bed and
just jump around.
>> Yeah.
>> So So is it possible that we can have a
contact in a dream state?
>> This is in the dream.
>> Yes.
>> He comes back to you in a dream state.
>> Yeah.
>> So we can move in a dream state like
it's like
>> visit you in a dream state. Yes.
>> Okay.
I have another question that I have like
done meditation for years but in my
spiritual teaching before I never had
answer about that
>> now I'm not getting
>> okay okay when I had some meditation I
had like some vibration around the spine
>> when he had a medit when getting went
into meditation he had a vibration
around the spine
>> oh okay
>> yes very subtle
>> yes
>> going stronger
along the body.
>> Yes,
>> it made me left the leave the body and
sometimes almost having like orgasm, a
very profound orgasm.
>> Uh never had that before.
But that that vibration became so strong
in a sense that I was thinking that I
will die because of this. Is it possible
that this vibration what happened
exactly with
He wants to know what what that
vibration might have been that he was
having when he did meditation.
>> Yeah. Kundalini energy.
>> Yes.
>> It's condolini.
>> Okay. Can
>> condolini energy. Yes.
>> Gopy Krishna wrote an interesting book
about it. Did you ever read the book by
Gopy Krishna?
>> No.
>> Yeah. Look up by Gopi Krishna. He gives
very interesting
subjective account of the flow of the
condolini energy and how it flowed into
one side of his
brain and he was lopsided for years.
>> Yes. But it came
>> Gopi Krishna read the book. Yeah.
>> Okay. But he explained about this. We
cannot die.
>> I just got through answering your
question.
>> Okay.
>> Get the book by Gopi Krishna.
>> It has to become energy.
>> Yeah. The lady energy. Yeah.
>> Okay. That's not not dangerous.
>> Not dangerous.
>> All right. What?
>> That's all.
>> Not dangerous.
>> Yeah. No, it's not dangerous.
>> Thank you.
>> Unless you're a lunatic, then it might
kill you.
>> I'm very in the world.
Can I have the blessings for myself and
all the love people around myself too?
>> For who?
>> Blessings. He He wants the blessings.
>> The people I love and
>> the people around him and himself.
What people around you?
>> All the friends and family.
>> Friends and family.
>> All the friends and family. I don't know
if I can do that or not.
>> Anyway, we certainly can bless you and
your intention and then you bless the
friends and family around you. Thank
>> you.
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Yes.
>> You can be a relay station.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Hi.
Um uh Monday I um this physicality
became really weak
just very suddenly it was very weak and
it's lasted
and it's um it's still very weak um but
with this um came this feeling of um
like I'm I'm I'm more space
like a feeling that I'm
>> I don't know if she's too close to the
mic or too far. I don't know what.
>> No, she she had a a physic physically
she feels weak.
>> Yes.
>> And like
spicy, you know, like
>> Yes.
>> concentrated.
>> Yeah.
>> And it happened earlier this week.
>> Oh. Mhm.
>> Yeah. Those states come and go. Yeah.
you uh if it stays you become a space
cadet,
>> right?
>> No th those phenomena come and go when
you're doing spiritual work.
>> Mhm. There's a shifting of the various
energies and the shifting of the
condolini energy
>> and uh a rebalancing of it just so by
commitment uh and align commitment your
spiritual commitment aligns the energy
correctly up through the chakra system.
Yes.
>> Right. Right. Yeah. because some
>> more sophisticated techniques have to do
with breathing.
>> The condolini energy up from the lower
through the higher chakras.
>> Mhm.
>> And uh following the instructions.
There's many books showing you how the
chakra system and how you can
>> uh raise the energy of the chakras and
unblock it so that it flows naturally.
Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> And then it naturally flows higher and
higher.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Thanks.
Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Hi.
>> Um I was focusing lately on surrendering
the thoughts
and um like um becoming the witness of
the thoughts and um today you talked
about um that one could elim eliminate
the thoughts before they manifest.
>> Eliminate the thoughts before they
manifest.
>> Yes. And I guess my question is um which
way to go like uh what would be the best
um approach for me like going going the
way where you're witnessing the thoughts
being the witnesser or trying to
eliminate
>> whether he's confused as to whether you
are the witnesser of the thoughts or if
you're trying to eliminate the thoughts.
So
>> no, you just witness them
and then you uh let go wanting to have
them. They're there just because you
want them to be there. So first you
become the witness and then you realize
that the recognition of them is by your
own valition
and you would draw your interest from
them.
Who cares what your mind is thinking?
It's stupid whatever it is. So why
bother?
>> And
Um, is he said I'm withdrawing the
volition. Is there is there a specific
focus to it or is it an automatic
process?
>> I don't know what he's asking.
>> Um,
>> you got to work on your accent. It's
still too heavy.
>> How long you've been in this country?
>> I guess long enough.
>> Tell me how long.
>> Um, since 2005.
>> Huh?
>> 2005.
>> All right. You got to work on your
accent. You need a somebody to help you
with it because it's going to hold you
back.
I can't speak bad German if I'm in
Germany for three or four years still
speaking bad German. I need a German
teacher. So I have to practice my
vocabulary so I can communicate better
with any other people.
So that as a practical person I would
advise that.
>> Okay.
>> Is that a good idea? Of course.
>> Let me hear you say that is a good idea.
>> It's a good idea.
>> No, not it is a good idea.
>> That that say that
>> that
>> is
>> a
>> good
>> idea.
>> Idea.
>> That is a good idea.
>> Okay, now say hey.
Hey,
>> back to my question.
>> I want you to s I want you to succeed in
the world. I want you to succeed. And if
your accent is too heavy, you won't
succeed because people don't have the
energy to try and figure out what you're
talking about. They just say, "Uh-huh.
Uh-huh." You understand? I want you to
succeed and be happy, etc. That's why
you have to perfect your vocabulary and
enunciation
and you could do it in small pieces, you
know what I mean? Just for the fun of
it.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Now, what was your question?
>> So, when I study German, you you can't
just get away with sloppy German. The
German teacher says,
>> which is what?
>> I just made that up.
>> I don't know.
It's fun to practice a language until
you perfect it. See, because I don't I
don't want you to miss out on what you
could have what would come to you
otherwise. It might be a blockade, you
know.
>> Okay.
>> I only say that because I care about
you.
>> Thank you very much.
>> As you struggle with it,
so you need an eleution teacher. want me
to speak and help you practice,
practice, practice. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And well, back to my question.
>> Okay.
>> Um, you said the valition withdraws from
the thoughts.
>> Yeah.
>> And um is an automatic process or
>> after a while?
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. First you practice it, then you
lose interest in the thinkingness
itself. And you see that the
thinkingness is a way of of juicing you.
The ego is juicing via thinkingness and
you refuse it. You refuse it. Oh, how
bad my life has been. Oh, how scary the
future looks. Oh, how risky life is.
And then uh the way to get rid of it is
to say, give me a break.
>> Okay. So it's a general refusion. It's
not finding the specifics. It's just a
general refusing it.
>> What?
>> It's not refining.
>> It's it's it's a general a general
refusing of the thoughts and not finding
the specific truth.
>> It's a general refusing of the thought.
>> Yeah.
>> Without being specific.
>> Right. Yes.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yeah.
>> It's good.
Hello Doc. I'm one of your students from
England and um I'm aware that some human
beings who've guided us who've read
who've written books such as Pilgrims
Progress and from the Arab world, the
book of Murdad and other people I know
even maybe myself.
>> She said monotone.
>> Okay, I'll try to speak more clearly.
I'm aware that some human beings have
had extremely deep and extreme
experiences
and the pilgrim's progress the book of
murd
and I am aware that an American
psychiatrist Dr. Stan Grath. I worked
with a psychotherapist trained by him
and I'm aware that there's an overlap
between maybe what he describes
spiritual emergency
and psychosis. And my question
my question is to give hope to those on
the spiritual journey who accidentally
stray.
>> What's the question? The question,
>> you're giving me a long dissertation.
What is
>> The question is, just because you're
mad, you don't have to be bad, do you?
>> I've got a question. She's referring to
Stan Grath and all kinds of things,
>> right?
>> What's it got to do with anything?
>> Um, it's it's my question. What I need
help and clarification with is to
validate
some work I feel I have to continue
>> work that I feel I
>> I can't she's saying
>> okay she's referring to all this
different work and then she says you
don't have to be mad to be bad
>> well in Pilgrim's Progress for example
>> I haven't read the book so I'm sorry I'm
not familiar with any of the work you're
talking about?
>> Okay. I'm sorry.
>> So, I don't know.
>> Human beings searching for God
>> sometimes, as you've said, go through
very turbulent years, turbulent
experiences, taken to extremes.
>> Yes.
>> This can sometimes present as madness.
>> I don't know what she's telling.
>> She said that the turbulent times in the
spiritual quest sometimes is interpreted
as madness rather than
>> That's true. Yes. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
>> so
>> what hope for those in that desert out
there?
>> Is it Are you treating them or what is
your concern about? You're speaking from
the hypothetical.
>> No, I'm speaking from other
>> experience. What hope is there for the
ones that are lost in this limbo that
are interpreted as mad rather than
actually a spiritual seeker? You know,
there's something
>> going Yeah, sure.
>> Because she's asking a sociologic
question. What hope is there?
>> Yeah.
>> Why are you considering concerned about
that? Are you do you have that problem
or somebody
>> I don't have that problem now, but in
the past?
>> What did you read it in a book or what?
I don't get You're dealing with a
hypothetical. No, I'm dealing with the
experiential because I myself went
through many turbulent experiences.
>> Oh, you went through many turbulent
experiences and you could have been
diagnosed as being mad.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah, maybe you were. Yeah,
>> sure. Oh, probably.
>> So, what about help for others?
>> Don't worry about others. Let God worry
about others. You know, worry about
yourself.
>> I I do, Doc. But I wanted you to
validate that
you did just validate.
And that's what I need
>> there. Yes, there are states that the
world would be happier to call you
totally mad.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you. Okay.
>> And it does happen.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> That's right.
>> I can't deal with recitations. I have to
have a question. What is the question?
>> I just wanted to ask you what the the
core or essence of of your teaching is.
I just wanted you to state that.
after I've been talking all day long.
>> Yeah.
>> I just want to know what I'm talking
about today.
>> No, no, no. I just want the What is the
the essence of your teaching?
>> The the core just the ultimate
>> what is the ultimate core of my
teaching?
>> Were you here today?
We're talking about the difference
between essence and appearance.
>> If I had if I had to say
>> he is a teacher that guides you to on
the path of enlightenment. That's
>> yeah.
>> He is a teacher that would be a teacher
or a stepping stone on your path to
enlightenment
>> by discerning truth from falsehood. Yes.
>> That's how I would describe your work.
>> How to discern truth from falsehood.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Okay.
>> But
um how do they have another event coming
in?
It's five o'
>> So we will have to terminate at five
o'clock. Is that correct?
>> Well, it's a little after
>> I don't have a question. Just a request.
Uh two weeks ago I was uh MRI was done.
Had this uh aortic uh root had a little
bit of uh calcium deposit like 5.5. My
goal is in seven months I have to redo
it again for then it to be 2.5. I ask
your blessings on that.
>> Yes, indeed. I was no I have no
reluctance to give it.
>> That's it. Thanks a lot. I'm glad I was
here. Thank you.
>> Yes. Do Yeah. We're going to get
together and do a healing prayer and a
blessing.
There are a number of members of the
group that have uh severe illnesses. um
uh cancer of the breast, various things
like that. And um we ask God's blessing.
We ask God's blessing on these persons
uh with their infirmities
and um that an understanding of the
significance and the value what we have
to learn from such things. And we ask
for a the blessing of a healing where it
is permissible
and uh
send them our love
and and the wish and the blessing for
their recovery and their healing. Yes.
At the same time, we surrender our
willfulness to God and allow the healing
or the blessing to be a fulfillment of
God's destiny for that particular
person. Yes.
Thank you. Amen. So we all pray for such
persons and we have a number of them in
the group right now who've asked for our
special blessing and that's why we wish
wish them all uh a blessing. Yes,
we all have something wrong with us.
We all we all do you realize that we're
all aliens? Yeah, sure.
>> We all have something.
It seems to be part of the human
condition, does it not?
That we all all have from a certain
viewpoint
uh an imperfection
somewhere. We have an imperfection
somewhere.
all of us have as a gift from God an
imperfection
and it also serves to undo certain
karmic propensities.
So there's no point to complain and
whail about infirmities like I do.
No, by by prayer and surrender,
uh what was a bad ankle and a swollen
foot was recovered enough that I could
walk all around today and be okay. So I
know that the recovery is possible.
And uh
so to be grace means that we ask God's
help in certain matters that we are un
unable to handle all by our lonesome and
then we surrender to the answer and we
stop insisting that God
you know do it our way. That's called
outlining. So we don't outline to God
how he is supposed to do this and when
he's supposed to do and where.
We just pray and hope for the best. I
said, "Well, God, I need my ankle better
by Saturday for because otherwise I
can't walk around and I can't stand up
here and chatter away and and it's
better." So,
it's possible. It's possible.
So, some things are heal healable, other
things
are slow.
And when this life has run itself out,
it won't make any difference anyway.
Some of us were just born ugly and we
can't help it.
The ultimate fear, of course, is that of
dying.
And to me, the fear of dying is nothing
but a fear of separation. We're afraid
of being separated from loved ones.
You're not afraid of dying. You're
afraid of being left alone from people
that you still care about. Yes. And
that's what the fear is.
So we reassure each other that we as a
group tend to sweep in together and we
tend to sweep out together and therefore
nobody's going to be left alone.
Nobody's going to be left alone. You
know that we're all going to be
together. And as we get on the other
side, we'll say, "Hi, so and so." you
know, gleing each other as we come
across. So, we've we've affirmed with
the arm that we've often swept in
together, you know, by together, I mean,
you know, the same half of a century or
something and and then sweep out
together. So, we have the fun of being
together uh lifetime after lifetime and
uh we come in together and we sort of
leave together.
Resist
Darham says that's true.
We come in together and we leave
together, you know, by a few together. I
mean, you know, within a few decades or
so, one way or the other, 20, 40, 50
years isn't much
in infinite time, right? You know, we
come in in the same century, you know,
that's pretty much almost like being
together. We came in the same century,
you know. Uh so, but it's close touch.
So for some reason we uh learned with
each other and we experienced with each
other and we love with each other and
we're a very powerful group. Actually
God said you're a very powerful group.
Why? Because of your willingness to be
loving to the fullest extent which you
can. And for this we give thanks to thee
oh Lord God uh for thy divine love and
for the love of this group.
I give thanks for the love of this
group. This group is God's gift to me.
Thank you, Lord God.
That I have a chance to be with such a
wonderful group of people. Yeah.
So, we give thanks for each other.
Thanks for each other's love. And I look
around, I see all the faces I love. And
some of them I only see when we have
these meetings. And so, I have to live
from meeting to meeting to see them
again.
So I I do indeed love you all and I
thank you for your love. Amen.
Oh, that'll last a couple hundred years.
That should get us all on the planet,
back off again, and back on again.
So, I love you all, dear hearts, and
look forward to seeing you next time.
Amen.
>> God bless. Thank you guys.
Hallelujah.