All right.
All right. >> All ready.
>> All ready.
>> All ready. >> Okay. After consuming all six of your
>> Okay. After consuming all six of your
>> Okay. After consuming all six of your books and many CDs, my intention is to
books and many CDs, my intention is to
books and many CDs, my intention is to produce consciousness music that's
produce consciousness music that's
produce consciousness music that's beneficial and uplifting for mankind.
beneficial and uplifting for mankind.
beneficial and uplifting for mankind. Bach and Brahms and Beethoven all knew
Bach and Brahms and Beethoven all knew
Bach and Brahms and Beethoven all knew they were writing for God and they all
they were writing for God and they all
they were writing for God and they all produced music that calibrated over 500.
produced music that calibrated over 500.
produced music that calibrated over 500. By all accounts, they were kind of
By all accounts, they were kind of
By all accounts, they were kind of grumpy men.
grumpy men.
grumpy men. So my question is do you have any tips?
So my question is do you have any tips?
So my question is do you have any tips? So even if I'm not calibrating over 500,
So even if I'm not calibrating over 500,
So even if I'm not calibrating over 500, how would one produce
how would one produce
how would one produce music or
music or
music or >> you uplift mankind by that which you are
>> you uplift mankind by that which you are
>> you uplift mankind by that which you are and that which you are then finds
and that which you are then finds
and that which you are then finds multiple modes of expression. With you
multiple modes of expression. With you
multiple modes of expression. With you it's music. With me it's teaching and
it's music. With me it's teaching and
it's music. With me it's teaching and doing research, you know. So, but each
doing research, you know. So, but each
doing research, you know. So, but each of those is our own way of uh trying to
of those is our own way of uh trying to
of those is our own way of uh trying to serve God and serve our fellow men and
serve God and serve our fellow men and
serve God and serve our fellow men and by doing uh so also serve our own inner
by doing uh so also serve our own inner
by doing uh so also serve our own inner self with a capital S.
self with a capital S.
self with a capital S. >> Just sign
Yeah. So, so your intention is what sets
Yeah. So, so your intention is what sets the energy.
the energy.
the energy. Your intention is what sets the energy
Your intention is what sets the energy
Your intention is what sets the energy and it then is a consequence of that
and it then is a consequence of that
and it then is a consequence of that which you have become which you're that
which you have become which you're that
which you have become which you're that which you are.
which you are.
which you are. That which you are expresses itself in
That which you are expresses itself in
That which you are expresses itself in your music. There there are people who
your music. There there are people who
your music. There there are people who personalities were isolated from their
personalities were isolated from their
personalities were isolated from their muse. You know, they were expressing
muse. You know, they were expressing
muse. You know, they were expressing their muse.
their muse.
their muse. What you're asking is that your muse and
What you're asking is that your muse and
What you're asking is that your muse and yourself be one in the same thing.
yourself be one in the same thing.
yourself be one in the same thing. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Mhm.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> So, it's a noble intention.
>> Oh, can I get a picture?
>> Oh, can I get a picture? >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> Sometimes you don't please people even
>> Sometimes you don't please people even
>> Sometimes you don't please people even though you do that. You see, and
though you do that. You see, and
though you do that. You see, and everybody likes Kabalki, you know.
>> Moart's birthday is tomorrow.
>> Moart's birthday is tomorrow. >> Mozart's birthday is tomorrow.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Uh, my name's Denise.
>> Uh, my name's Denise.
>> Uh, my name's Denise. I um don't have a spiritual group where
I um don't have a spiritual group where
I um don't have a spiritual group where I live.
I live.
I live. I've been doing um your practices and
I've been doing um your practices and
I've been doing um your practices and listening to your information.
listening to your information.
listening to your information. Um
Um
Um and I'm uh I'm getting those strange uh
and I'm uh I'm getting those strange uh
and I'm uh I'm getting those strange uh energetic surges and
energetic surges and
energetic surges and some kind of convulsion type things. And
some kind of convulsion type things. And
some kind of convulsion type things. And um
I mostly just think, okay, you know, uh
I mostly just think, okay, you know, uh whatever.
whatever.
whatever. Uh
they're getting a little out of control.
they're getting a little out of control. I don't really know.
I don't really know.
I don't really know. >> Well, slow down the spiritual work then.
Slow slow it down a bit until you catch
Slow slow it down a bit until you catch up. Yeah.
up. Yeah.
up. Yeah. Yeah. You have to take periods of rest.
Yeah. You have to take periods of rest.
Yeah. You have to take periods of rest. You know, even in a monastery where they
You know, even in a monastery where they
You know, even in a monastery where they prayed many hours a day, they take off
prayed many hours a day, they take off
prayed many hours a day, they take off times and go out and do uh gardening.
times and go out and do uh gardening.
times and go out and do uh gardening. You know, gardening is classically uh
You know, gardening is classically uh
You know, gardening is classically uh done in monasteries
done in monasteries
done in monasteries because otherwise you dry you dry up.
because otherwise you dry you dry up.
because otherwise you dry you dry up. They say you dry up. You dry up and you
They say you dry up. You dry up and you
They say you dry up. You dry up and you start becoming mechanical, you know.
start becoming mechanical, you know.
start becoming mechanical, you know. Mhm. So in a monastery they pray and
Mhm. So in a monastery they pray and
Mhm. So in a monastery they pray and they meditate and then they go out and
they meditate and then they go out and
they meditate and then they go out and garden. So you need more gardening.
garden. So you need more gardening.
garden. So you need more gardening. Yeah.
>> Okay. And so when these things get out
>> Okay. And so when these things get out of hand then uh just
of hand then uh just
of hand then uh just >> I don't know what you mean by things
>> I don't know what you mean by things
>> I don't know what you mean by things getting out of hand like the United
getting out of hand like the United
getting out of hand like the United States government or what
States government or what
States government or what >> she's saying.
>> she's saying.
>> she's saying. >> I don't know what she means by
>> I don't know what she means by
>> I don't know what she means by convulsion. Well, I just have I do have
convulsion. Well, I just have I do have
convulsion. Well, I just have I do have the surges and occasionally uh
the surges and occasionally uh
the surges and occasionally uh well, I'll just kind of do a little
well, I'll just kind of do a little
well, I'll just kind of do a little >> I told you what to do about it.
>> I told you what to do about it.
>> I told you what to do about it. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> All right.
Hi.
Hi. >> Now they have it with Jin Singh, so it's
>> Now they have it with Jin Singh, so it's
>> Now they have it with Jin Singh, so it's even more sacred.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. My name is Karen and
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. My name is Karen and Hi, Susan.
Hi, Susan.
Hi, Susan. >> I've come from Australia. Just um felt a
>> I've come from Australia. Just um felt a
>> I've come from Australia. Just um felt a really strong pull to come and
really strong pull to come and
really strong pull to come and >> she had to speak closer to the mic. I
>> she had to speak closer to the mic. I
>> she had to speak closer to the mic. I can't hear her.
can't hear her.
can't hear her. >> She's from Australia.
>> She's from Australia.
>> She's from Australia. >> From Australia. I felt a really
>> From Australia. I felt a really
>> From Australia. I felt a really >> That's why I can't hear her. She's
>> That's why I can't hear her. She's
>> That's why I can't hear her. She's talking from Australia.
talking from Australia.
talking from Australia. >> Funny accent.
>> Funny accent.
>> Funny accent. I've got a really strong pull to come
I've got a really strong pull to come
I've got a really strong pull to come here to see you and I wanted to thank
here to see you and I wanted to thank
here to see you and I wanted to thank you for all your work
you for all your work
you for all your work >> and um I was thinking about that last
>> and um I was thinking about that last
>> and um I was thinking about that last night how precious your work is to me
night how precious your work is to me
night how precious your work is to me and um
and um
and um >> she has to be closer to the microphone.
>> she has to be closer to the microphone.
>> she has to be closer to the microphone. >> I was thinking last night how how
>> I was thinking last night how how
>> I was thinking last night how how precious your work is to me and how
precious your work is to me and how
precious your work is to me and how passionate I am. And all of a sudden
passionate I am. And all of a sudden
passionate I am. And all of a sudden this fear rose up that what if I leave
this fear rose up that what if I leave
this fear rose up that what if I leave this body and come back again another
this body and come back again another
this body and come back again another body and I've never heard of Dr.
body and I've never heard of Dr.
body and I've never heard of Dr. Hawkins.
Hawkins.
Hawkins. >> I don't know what she's asking. She
>> I don't know what she's asking. She
>> I don't know what she's asking. She says, "What if she she has this fear and
says, "What if she she has this fear and
says, "What if she she has this fear and came up in her
came up in her
came up in her >> of what?
>> of what?
>> of what? >> Of what if she left this body and didn't
>> Of what if she left this body and didn't
>> Of what if she left this body and didn't get a chance to hear you?"
get a chance to hear you?"
get a chance to hear you?" >> Oh. Oh. Well, you can hear me on the
>> Oh. Oh. Well, you can hear me on the
>> Oh. Oh. Well, you can hear me on the other side. I'm on channel 18 on the
other side. I'm on channel 18 on the
other side. I'm on channel 18 on the other side.
other side.
other side. >> My question is, if I came back in
>> My question is, if I came back in
>> My question is, if I came back in another body, um, would I still have all
another body, um, would I still have all
another body, um, would I still have all that you've taught me? I had this fear
that you've taught me? I had this fear
that you've taught me? I had this fear that because your work is so precious to
that because your work is so precious to
that because your work is so precious to me, if I came back in another body,
me, if I came back in another body,
me, if I came back in another body, would I
would I
would I >> Your intention your intention then
>> Your intention your intention then
>> Your intention your intention then prevails. Your intention plus your
prevails. Your intention plus your
prevails. Your intention plus your karmic propensities prevail. Prevail.
karmic propensities prevail. Prevail.
karmic propensities prevail. Prevail. >> And you said before,
>> And you said before,
>> And you said before, >> you're not going to be thrust someplace
>> you're not going to be thrust someplace
>> you're not going to be thrust someplace that's improper
that's improper
that's improper >> against your will. No.
>> against your will. No.
>> against your will. No. >> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. >> God look at looks after his own.
>> God look at looks after his own.
>> God look at looks after his own. >> Oh, thanks.
>> Oh, thanks.
>> Oh, thanks. It's a It's summer time down there,
It's a It's summer time down there,
It's a It's summer time down there, isn't it?
>> yeah. Some I wanted to get him to
>> yeah. Some I wanted to get him to Australia someday.
>> I've always wanted to see it.
>> I've always wanted to see it. >> Oh, wait. Don't.
Dear Lord, give me a Mercer Benz.
Dear Lord, give me a Mercer Benz. >> No.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. I I came to see you in September. That
I I came to see you in September. That
I I came to see you in September. That was the first time. And um I'm in two
was the first time. And um I'm in two
was the first time. And um I'm in two groups in Boulder studying your work.
groups in Boulder studying your work.
groups in Boulder studying your work. And then I went to uh to see the Buddha
And then I went to uh to see the Buddha
And then I went to uh to see the Buddha relics. And since I've seen you, um, all
relics. And since I've seen you, um, all
relics. And since I've seen you, um, all the has hit the fan karmmically.
the has hit the fan karmmically.
the has hit the fan karmmically. >> Holy
>> Holy
>> Holy >> And I heard what you said to the other
>> And I heard what you said to the other
>> And I heard what you said to the other person about slow down, but I don't want
person about slow down, but I don't want
person about slow down, but I don't want to slow down. Um,
to slow down. Um,
to slow down. Um, >> well, then don't complain.
>> You're saying, "How can I eat too much
>> You're saying, "How can I eat too much and not feel full?" You can't.
and not feel full?" You can't.
and not feel full?" You can't. No. If you uh if you're driven
No. If you uh if you're driven
No. If you uh if you're driven spiritually driven then there's certain
spiritually driven then there's certain
spiritually driven then there's certain side effects from being spiritually
side effects from being spiritually
side effects from being spiritually driven. You know
driven. You know
driven. You know >> the question I had for you is I'm in a a
>> the question I had for you is I'm in a a
>> the question I had for you is I'm in a a course of miracles group and a lot of
course of miracles group and a lot of
course of miracles group and a lot of people in the course of mira course in
people in the course of mira course in
people in the course of mira course in miracles group uh start talking about
miracles group uh start talking about
miracles group uh start talking about that they no longer once they're into
that they no longer once they're into
that they no longer once they're into forgiveness that they no longer have
forgiveness that they no longer have
forgiveness that they no longer have personal karma and that seems
personal karma and that seems
personal karma and that seems >> well there's lots of other karmas
>> well there's lots of other karmas
>> well there's lots of other karmas besides forgiveness.
besides forgiveness.
besides forgiveness. Guilt is the only is not the only
Guilt is the only is not the only
Guilt is the only is not the only determinant of karma.
That would be true if guilt was the only
That would be true if guilt was the only one. It's not the only one.
one. It's not the only one.
one. It's not the only one. Multiple determinants of karma. Every
Multiple determinants of karma. Every
Multiple determinants of karma. Every thought, every action, every choice
thought, every action, every choice
thought, every action, every choice determines karma.
determines karma.
determines karma. >> Is there any impact u with forgiveness
>> Is there any impact u with forgiveness
>> Is there any impact u with forgiveness on karma?
on karma?
on karma? >> Of course.
>> Of course.
>> Of course. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. But but the course of miracles is
Yeah. But but the course of miracles is
Yeah. But but the course of miracles is not the be end all and end all.
not the be end all and end all.
not the be end all and end all. >> You know, it calibrates around 550
>> You know, it calibrates around 550
>> You know, it calibrates around 550 and um that's good, but it's not the
and um that's good, but it's not the
and um that's good, but it's not the most overwhelming. 12 step groups
most overwhelming. 12 step groups
most overwhelming. 12 step groups calibrate higher than that.
calibrate higher than that.
calibrate higher than that. The um workbook itself calibrates 600.
The um workbook itself calibrates 600.
The um workbook itself calibrates 600. The book, the main the big book
The book, the main the big book
The book, the main the big book calibrates around 550.
calibrates around 550.
calibrates around 550. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yep.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. >> Thank you. It loosens you to the degree
>> Thank you. It loosens you to the degree
>> Thank you. It loosens you to the degree that guilt is holding you down. But
that guilt is holding you down. But
that guilt is holding you down. But there's lots of things that are holding
there's lots of things that are holding
there's lots of things that are holding you down besides guilt.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Cheers.
>> Cheers.
>> Cheers. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. Um, a question has puzzled me for a long
Um, a question has puzzled me for a long
Um, a question has puzzled me for a long time.
time.
time. that is I could be in a specific um
that is I could be in a specific um
that is I could be in a specific um let's say level of consciousness which I
let's say level of consciousness which I
let's say level of consciousness which I can perceive
can perceive
can perceive a wide spacious context understanding
a wide spacious context understanding
a wide spacious context understanding and then within let's say with even
and then within let's say with even
and then within let's say with even within the same day I could experience
within the same day I could experience
within the same day I could experience many levels of lower consciousness.
many levels of lower consciousness.
many levels of lower consciousness. So more specifically, how could someone
So more specifically, how could someone
So more specifically, how could someone who is at level 500, let's say, in the
who is at level 500, let's say, in the
who is at level 500, let's say, in the same day experience guilt? I don't
same day experience guilt? I don't
same day experience guilt? I don't understand the process very much. And
understand the process very much. And
understand the process very much. And what's
what's
what's >> happen? It's because you're picturing it
>> happen? It's because you're picturing it
>> happen? It's because you're picturing it as some kind of a sensible uh geometric
as some kind of a sensible uh geometric
as some kind of a sensible uh geometric progression, you know, it doesn't work
progression, you know, it doesn't work
progression, you know, it doesn't work that way. It's more chaotic, you know.
that way. It's more chaotic, you know.
that way. It's more chaotic, you know. Uh
Uh
Uh it's more transient.
it's more transient.
it's more transient. And uh the predominant motif begins to
And uh the predominant motif begins to
And uh the predominant motif begins to shift but uh it's very uh you know
shift but uh it's very uh you know
shift but uh it's very uh you know chaotic in a way.
>> The the resolution depends on a level of
>> The the resolution depends on a level of consciousness
consciousness
consciousness and the prevailing overall
and the prevailing overall
and the prevailing overall you know you might say the statistical
you know you might say the statistical
you know you might say the statistical average
average
average uh only shifts very slowly. Huh?
>> Yeah, the images shift very fast. What
>> Yeah, the images shift very fast. What are you saying about shifting images?
are you saying about shifting images?
are you saying about shifting images? >> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Dave from Reno. Uh,
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Dave from Reno. Uh,
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Dave from Reno. Uh, I have a question. as as I look at many
I have a question. as as I look at many
I have a question. as as I look at many of your charts and whatnot uh say for
of your charts and whatnot uh say for
of your charts and whatnot uh say for instance for teachers or for prayers
instance for teachers or for prayers
instance for teachers or for prayers calibrating at different levels um of
calibrating at different levels um of
calibrating at different levels um of course if I was say 300 or something and
course if I was say 300 or something and
course if I was say 300 or something and I I look at m saying repeatedly that one
I I look at m saying repeatedly that one
I I look at m saying repeatedly that one of the most highly calibrated prayers is
of the most highly calibrated prayers is
of the most highly calibrated prayers is it necessarily for
it necessarily for
it necessarily for might there be others of lower
might there be others of lower
might there be others of lower calibration but above where I'm at that
calibration but above where I'm at that
calibration but above where I'm at that would be more appropriate for someone or
would be more appropriate for someone or
would be more appropriate for someone or is it best always to go with that which
is it best always to go with that which
is it best always to go with that which calibrates the highest.
calibrates the highest.
calibrates the highest. >> You don't always have to go with that
>> You don't always have to go with that
>> You don't always have to go with that which calibrates the highest, but you
which calibrates the highest, but you
which calibrates the highest, but you should just be conscious and aware of
should just be conscious and aware of
should just be conscious and aware of the impact of that which you're doing.
the impact of that which you're doing.
the impact of that which you're doing. You see,
I mean, uh this group of people in in
I mean, uh this group of people in in this generation are highly educated
this generation are highly educated
this generation are highly educated about spiritual matters and
about spiritual matters and
about spiritual matters and consciousness matters and no previous
consciousness matters and no previous
consciousness matters and no previous generation had had this uh tool, you
generation had had this uh tool, you
generation had had this uh tool, you know.
know.
know. So there isn't any historic classic
So there isn't any historic classic
So there isn't any historic classic directions on the most appropriate use
directions on the most appropriate use
directions on the most appropriate use for it. We're the ones that are blazing
for it. We're the ones that are blazing
for it. We're the ones that are blazing the trail.
the trail.
the trail. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Yeah.
Someday will be history.
Someday will be history. Way way back in 1995. What year is this,
Way way back in 1995. What year is this,
Way way back in 1995. What year is this, honey? 2000. Way way back. And I guess
honey? 2000. Way way back. And I guess
honey? 2000. Way way back. And I guess that's where I cut out. 95. Anyway,
that's where I cut out. 95. Anyway,
that's where I cut out. 95. Anyway, way way back. back in 2008.
>> Did I sign this one?
>> Did I sign this one? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. My name is Mary Joe and
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. My name is Mary Joe and
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. My name is Mary Joe and I have a two-part question. I know
I have a two-part question. I know
I have a two-part question. I know you've done thousands of calibrations
you've done thousands of calibrations
you've done thousands of calibrations and actually wrote a book about it and
and actually wrote a book about it and
and actually wrote a book about it and um we also talked a little bit today
um we also talked a little bit today
um we also talked a little bit today about those politicians and I was just
about those politicians and I was just
about those politicians and I was just curious as to whether our country has
curious as to whether our country has
curious as to whether our country has ever had a president that calculated 500
ever had a president that calculated 500
ever had a president that calculated 500 or over and have you also looked at the
or over and have you also looked at the
or over and have you also looked at the current poll of candidates in this
current poll of candidates in this
current poll of candidates in this election and looked at the range of
election and looked at the range of
election and looked at the range of calibrations for those candidates?
calibrations for those candidates?
calibrations for those candidates? Well, and I haven't done it on politics
Well, and I haven't done it on politics
Well, and I haven't done it on politics because I'm tired of politics.
Now, we had great don't forget we had
Now, we had great don't forget we had great great beings that helped. I said
great great beings that helped. I said
great great beings that helped. I said the United States Constitution
the United States Constitution
the United States Constitution um that was set up by theists and Das
um that was set up by theists and Das
um that was set up by theists and Das calibrates at 770.
calibrates at 770.
calibrates at 770. So, those were of course great uh
So, those were of course great uh
So, those were of course great uh statesmen, great statesmen. that there's
statesmen, great statesmen. that there's
statesmen, great statesmen. that there's a difference between a statesman and a
a difference between a statesman and a
a difference between a statesman and a politician. In today's world, what's
politician. In today's world, what's
politician. In today's world, what's celebrated is politicians.
celebrated is politicians.
celebrated is politicians. Statesmanship, you know, only comes up
Statesmanship, you know, only comes up
Statesmanship, you know, only comes up when you discuss like Winston Churchill
when you discuss like Winston Churchill
when you discuss like Winston Churchill or somebody. And Rean very often comes
or somebody. And Rean very often comes
or somebody. And Rean very often comes up as statesmanship,
up as statesmanship,
up as statesmanship, you know, when he said to Russia, "Take
you know, when he said to Russia, "Take
you know, when he said to Russia, "Take down this wall." He was speaking as a
down this wall." He was speaking as a
down this wall." He was speaking as a statesman, not as a president. He
statesman, not as a president. He
statesman, not as a president. He already was president, so he didn't have
already was president, so he didn't have
already was president, so he didn't have to speak towards presidency. He was
to speak towards presidency. He was
to speak towards presidency. He was speaking as a statesman. Mr. Kerch
speaking as a statesman. Mr. Kerch
speaking as a statesman. Mr. Kerch Kersech take down this wall.
Kersech take down this wall.
Kersech take down this wall. So he was speaking as a statesman. So I
So he was speaking as a statesman. So I
So he was speaking as a statesman. So I differentiate between politician and
differentiate between politician and
differentiate between politician and statesman
statesman
statesman and I feel to become president you
and I feel to become president you
and I feel to become president you should go through a statesmanship
should go through a statesmanship
should go through a statesmanship training and shouldn't be elected unless
training and shouldn't be elected unless
training and shouldn't be elected unless you've graduated from statesmanship
you've graduated from statesmanship
you've graduated from statesmanship school
school
school which understands um political
There he goes on politics again. All
There he goes on politics again. All right.
right.
right. That's men for you, honey. I'm sorry.
>> That's what fills me with guilt is being
>> That's what fills me with guilt is being so good.
so good.
so good. >> If you'd razle at me, I could Well,
>> If you'd razle at me, I could Well,
>> If you'd razle at me, I could Well, >> thank you.
>> thank you.
>> thank you. We were talking about the value of uh
We were talking about the value of uh
We were talking about the value of uh the GRA's book. You know, men are from
the GRA's book. You know, men are from
the GRA's book. You know, men are from Mars and women are from Venus.
Mars and women are from Venus.
Mars and women are from Venus. >> Didn't we calibrate that most presidents
>> Didn't we calibrate that most presidents
>> Didn't we calibrate that most presidents have to be four?
have to be four?
have to be four? >> Well, they've all been Yeah, they've all
>> Well, they've all been Yeah, they've all
>> Well, they've all been Yeah, they've all been pretty pretty high. Yeah, they all
been pretty pretty high. Yeah, they all
been pretty pretty high. Yeah, they all have been.
have been.
have been. >> Before they can get the office of
>> Before they can get the office of
>> Before they can get the office of president, they have to calibrate at
president, they have to calibrate at
president, they have to calibrate at 460.
>> Yes. Hi. Um
>> Yes. Hi. Um my name is Phil. I'm from Sacramento.
my name is Phil. I'm from Sacramento.
my name is Phil. I'm from Sacramento. I'm a course in miracle student and a
I'm a course in miracle student and a
I'm a course in miracle student and a student of Tara Singh a former teacher
student of Tara Singh a former teacher
student of Tara Singh a former teacher and u I recently retired and I have now
and u I recently retired and I have now
and u I recently retired and I have now have time to devote more time to
have time to devote more time to
have time to devote more time to spiritual things and in the past
spiritual things and in the past
spiritual things and in the past something's always kind of showed up you
something's always kind of showed up you
something's always kind of showed up you know like the course and you know and
know like the course and you know and
know like the course and you know and then and even coming here just kind of
then and even coming here just kind of
then and even coming here just kind of happened you know it sort of showed up
happened you know it sort of showed up
happened you know it sort of showed up for me. But now things seem to be kind
for me. But now things seem to be kind
for me. But now things seem to be kind of stagnated
of stagnated
of stagnated and my my question is I guess
and my my question is I guess
and my my question is I guess >> stagnated since when? Since five minutes
>> stagnated since when? Since five minutes
>> stagnated since when? Since five minutes ago.
ago.
ago. >> No, since for a few years, you know,
>> No, since for a few years, you know,
>> No, since for a few years, you know, with a few exceptions, it seems to have
with a few exceptions, it seems to have
with a few exceptions, it seems to have kind of slowed down as far as
kind of slowed down as far as
kind of slowed down as far as >> stuff showing up. You know what I mean?
>> stuff showing up. You know what I mean?
>> stuff showing up. You know what I mean? In a sense like that.
In a sense like that.
In a sense like that. >> Do you belong to any spiritual groups or
>> Do you belong to any spiritual groups or
>> Do you belong to any spiritual groups or churches, unity church or?
churches, unity church or?
churches, unity church or? >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> Oh, okay. Mhm.
>> Oh, okay. Mhm.
>> Oh, okay. Mhm. >> But my question is more to what extent
>> But my question is more to what extent
>> But my question is more to what extent should one try to initiate something
should one try to initiate something
should one try to initiate something versus waiting for it to,
versus waiting for it to,
versus waiting for it to, you know, come.
you know, come.
you know, come. >> Well, you may wait quite a few lifetimes
>> Well, you may wait quite a few lifetimes
>> Well, you may wait quite a few lifetimes for it to just drift into your backyard,
for it to just drift into your backyard,
for it to just drift into your backyard, you know,
you know,
you know, >> but I'm concerned if I do something
>> but I'm concerned if I do something
>> but I'm concerned if I do something myself, it could be of the ego and,
myself, it could be of the ego and,
myself, it could be of the ego and, you know, may take me off on the wrong
you know, may take me off on the wrong
you know, may take me off on the wrong path.
path.
path. >> What would be the wrong path?
>> What would be the wrong path?
>> What would be the wrong path? Well, any integrous spiritual work,
Well, any integrous spiritual work,
Well, any integrous spiritual work, anything that calibrates over, you know,
anything that calibrates over, you know,
anything that calibrates over, you know, 400 and up, and we have a whole list of
400 and up, and we have a whole list of
400 and up, and we have a whole list of integrous teachers. You could just grab
integrous teachers. You could just grab
integrous teachers. You could just grab any one of them and start
any one of them and start
any one of them and start uh learning uh for the fun of the
uh learning uh for the fun of the
uh learning uh for the fun of the learning.
learning.
learning. >> It's all right.
>> It's all right.
>> It's all right. >> Sign right here.
>> Sign right here.
>> Sign right here. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Well, that's part of it that a a lot of
>> Well, that's part of it that a a lot of
>> Well, that's part of it that a a lot of them seem to have appeal at this point.
them seem to have appeal at this point.
them seem to have appeal at this point. a lot of different ones,
a lot of different ones,
a lot of different ones, you know, including, you know, your
you know, including, you know, your
you know, including, you know, your works. And
works. And
works. And >> well, it's like chocolate, mint, or
>> well, it's like chocolate, mint, or
>> well, it's like chocolate, mint, or vanilla to take your pick. You know, I
vanilla to take your pick. You know, I
vanilla to take your pick. You know, I can't tell you which one to take a pick.
can't tell you which one to take a pick.
can't tell you which one to take a pick. >> Well, that's my question, I guess, is
>> Well, that's my question, I guess, is
>> Well, that's my question, I guess, is how do I, if I'm going to initiate
how do I, if I'm going to initiate
how do I, if I'm going to initiate something, how would I decide what to
something, how would I decide what to
something, how would I decide what to pick?
pick?
pick? >> I can't tell you.
>> I can't tell you.
>> I can't tell you. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Chocolate, mint, or vanilla? It's not a
>> Chocolate, mint, or vanilla? It's not a
>> Chocolate, mint, or vanilla? It's not a big problem.
big problem.
big problem. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Hello.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. >> Hi. My name's uh Donna. I'm from BC in
>> Hi. My name's uh Donna. I'm from BC in
>> Hi. My name's uh Donna. I'm from BC in Canada. And um I've been working with a
Canada. And um I've been working with a
Canada. And um I've been working with a medical chiong group and I'm very drawn
medical chiong group and I'm very drawn
medical chiong group and I'm very drawn to the healing arts. One of the
to the healing arts. One of the
to the healing arts. One of the strategies that they use.
strategies that they use.
strategies that they use. >> You got to talk closer to the mic.
>> You got to talk closer to the mic.
>> You got to talk closer to the mic. You're with a medical what
You're with a medical what
You're with a medical what >> John?
>> John?
>> John? >> Medical chiong.
>> Medical chiong.
>> Medical chiong. >> Chiong.
>> Chiong.
>> Chiong. >> Oh, she's talking about chong. Oh god.
>> Oh, she's talking about chong. Oh god.
>> Oh, she's talking about chong. Oh god. >> And one of the strategies that they use
>> And one of the strategies that they use
>> And one of the strategies that they use is entity removal. And I'm just not sure
is entity removal. And I'm just not sure
is entity removal. And I'm just not sure about that.
about that.
about that. >> They use what
>> They use what
>> They use what >> entity
>> entity
>> entity >> entity to you know like
>> entity to you know like
>> entity to you know like >> to remove entities.
>> to remove entities.
>> to remove entities. >> Um,
>> Um,
>> Um, >> keep going.
>> keep going.
>> keep going. >> Exorcism. Exorcism.
>> Exorcism. Exorcism.
>> Exorcism. Exorcism. >> Yeah. You want to get into that? I don't
>> Yeah. You want to get into that? I don't
>> Yeah. You want to get into that? I don't >> Oh,
>> Oh,
>> Oh, >> then don't.
>> then don't.
>> then don't. >> No, I'm just not that sure how I feel
>> No, I'm just not that sure how I feel
>> No, I'm just not that sure how I feel about that. So, I'm just wondering how
about that. So, I'm just wondering how
about that. So, I'm just wondering how you feel about that.
you feel about that.
you feel about that. >> It is not the direction I would go.
>> It is not the direction I would go.
>> It is not the direction I would go. >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> No.
>> No. >> So, is Chiang a direction
>> So, is Chiang a direction
>> So, is Chiang a direction >> that I would go? No.
>> that I would go? No.
>> that I would go? No. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. >> See, a lot of these things are
>> See, a lot of these things are
>> See, a lot of these things are attractive because they sound esoteric.
attractive because they sound esoteric.
attractive because they sound esoteric. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. If I tell you it's Mugoo Pie, it's going
If I tell you it's Mugoo Pie, it's going
If I tell you it's Mugoo Pie, it's going to sound more mysterious to you than if
to sound more mysterious to you than if
to sound more mysterious to you than if I tell you it's Reverend Bucker out here
I tell you it's Reverend Bucker out here
I tell you it's Reverend Bucker out here in the audience right now.
in the audience right now.
in the audience right now. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You go to a couple of sermons by a local
>> You go to a couple of sermons by a local
>> You go to a couple of sermons by a local minister and you're going to get all
minister and you're going to get all
minister and you're going to get all you're ever going to get out of anything
you're ever going to get out of anything
you're ever going to get out of anything >> because if you have the capacity you're
>> because if you have the capacity you're
>> because if you have the capacity you're going to to get it, you're going to get
going to to get it, you're going to get
going to to get it, you're going to get it like that,
it like that,
it like that, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> See? Right.
>> See? Right.
>> See? Right. >> What what group are you in?
>> What what group are you in?
>> What what group are you in? >> Keep going. I know, but what's who's the
>> Keep going. I know, but what's who's the
>> Keep going. I know, but what's who's the head of that group?
head of that group?
head of that group? >> Um, his name is Ming Clots Quan.
>> Um, his name is Ming Clots Quan.
>> Um, his name is Ming Clots Quan. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, I'm familiar with it. Yes.
I'm familiar with it. Yes.
I'm familiar with it. Yes. >> Okay, good. Thank you.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> I love your work.
Laughter is the quickest way to heaven.
Laughter is the quickest way to heaven. >> My question is,
>> My question is,
>> My question is, >> you cry alone.
>> you cry alone.
>> you cry alone. >> Sorry.
>> Sorry.
>> Sorry. >> How can I do a solitary kinesiology
>> How can I do a solitary kinesiology
>> How can I do a solitary kinesiology test?
test?
test? How can what
How can what
How can what >> a solitary kinesiology test.
>> a solitary kinesiology test.
>> a solitary kinesiology test. >> Oh yeah, there's the O-ring finger
>> Oh yeah, there's the O-ring finger
>> Oh yeah, there's the O-ring finger >> or either any finger really.
>> or either any finger really.
>> or either any finger really. >> Yeah, the O-ring finger trying to break
>> Yeah, the O-ring finger trying to break
>> Yeah, the O-ring finger trying to break the strength of it. I say the simplest
the strength of it. I say the simplest
the strength of it. I say the simplest way is take a stack of books and you'll
way is take a stack of books and you'll
way is take a stack of books and you'll find out. You hold Jesus Christ in in
find out. You hold Jesus Christ in in
find out. You hold Jesus Christ in in your mind and you lift the books and
your mind and you lift the books and
your mind and you lift the books and then you hold bin Lenon in mind and you
then you hold bin Lenon in mind and you
then you hold bin Lenon in mind and you pick the books and it's very obvious
pick the books and it's very obvious
pick the books and it's very obvious which one is above 200 which is below
which one is above 200 which is below
which one is above 200 which is below 200
200 >> and would anything develop with practice
>> and would anything develop with practice
>> and would anything develop with practice or is it kind of just like you
or is it kind of just like you
or is it kind of just like you automatically know?
automatically know?
automatically know? >> Both go at the same time on the one hand
>> Both go at the same time on the one hand
>> Both go at the same time on the one hand intuitively you know and secondly you
intuitively you know and secondly you
intuitively you know and secondly you learn from practice also
learn from practice also
learn from practice also like anything you get better with
like anything you get better with
like anything you get better with practice.
practice.
practice. >> Thank you. A lot of people have
>> Thank you. A lot of people have
>> Thank you. A lot of people have different techniques. You know, some
different techniques. You know, some
different techniques. You know, some people will fall forward with a yes and
people will fall forward with a yes and
people will fall forward with a yes and backward with a no using the whole body
backward with a no using the whole body
backward with a no using the whole body as a pendulum. So, you can, you know,
as a pendulum. So, you can, you know,
as a pendulum. So, you can, you know, whatever is attractive to you and you
whatever is attractive to you and you
whatever is attractive to you and you find that it's useful, you know.
find that it's useful, you know.
find that it's useful, you know. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> Some people go they use the fingernail
>> Some people go they use the fingernail
>> Some people go they use the fingernail like if it's a no, it'll hang up and
like if it's a no, it'll hang up and
like if it's a no, it'll hang up and they pull it. If it's yes, it'll be
they pull it. If it's yes, it'll be
they pull it. If it's yes, it'll be smoother. So, there's a lot of different
smoother. So, there's a lot of different
smoother. So, there's a lot of different techniques. Anything that that tests uh
techniques. Anything that that tests uh
techniques. Anything that that tests uh muscle muscle strength, you know, muscle
muscle muscle strength, you know, muscle
muscle muscle strength, you know, muscle strength, comparative muscle strength.
strength, comparative muscle strength.
strength, comparative muscle strength. >> All right.
>> Hello. Um, Shri Ranji heads the um,
>> Hello. Um, Shri Ranji heads the um, oneness movement for North America. And
oneness movement for North America. And
oneness movement for North America. And I wondered if
I wondered if
I wondered if >> I'm having trouble hearing already.
>> I'm having trouble hearing already.
>> I'm having trouble hearing already. >> Shiranji,
>> Shiranji,
>> Shiranji, Shri Ranji,
Shri Ranji,
Shri Ranji, >> Shiranji,
>> Shiranji,
>> Shiranji, >> Sri and then Rigi.
>> Sri and then Rigi.
>> Sri and then Rigi. She heads But the main thing, the
She heads But the main thing, the
She heads But the main thing, the question would be more around the
question would be more around the
question would be more around the oneness movement. something I've been
oneness movement. something I've been
oneness movement. something I've been introduced to recently and I wonder
introduced to recently and I wonder
introduced to recently and I wonder >> echoing. I'm not getting it at all.
>> echoing. I'm not getting it at all.
>> echoing. I'm not getting it at all. >> Here, sit back just ahead because you're
>> Here, sit back just ahead because you're
>> Here, sit back just ahead because you're echoing and he can't.
echoing and he can't.
echoing and he can't. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> It's coming through on
>> It's coming through on
>> It's coming through on >> How's that? Does that sound better?
>> How's that? Does that sound better?
>> How's that? Does that sound better? >> Better.
>> Better.
>> Better. >> Yeah. Okay. My question then would be
>> Yeah. Okay. My question then would be
>> Yeah. Okay. My question then would be the oneness movement. I'm interested.
the oneness movement. I'm interested.
the oneness movement. I'm interested. >> The one movement
>> The one movement
>> The one movement >> one what?
>> one what?
>> one what? >> Oneness. Oneness movement.
>> Oneness. Oneness movement.
>> Oneness. Oneness movement. >> Oneness. A oneness movement. I I'm not
>> Oneness. A oneness movement. I I'm not
>> Oneness. A oneness movement. I I'm not familiar with the oneness movement.
familiar with the oneness movement.
familiar with the oneness movement. Okay. Go ahead and tell me. Well, that
Okay. Go ahead and tell me. Well, that
Okay. Go ahead and tell me. Well, that was I was just wondering if you they had
was I was just wondering if you they had
was I was just wondering if you they had been you had calibrated them and your
been you had calibrated them and your
been you had calibrated them and your view around the oneness movement. It's
view around the oneness movement. It's
view around the oneness movement. It's that new
that new
that new >> I've not heard of it. No. No.
>> I've not heard of it. No. No.
>> I've not heard of it. No. No. >> Yeah, it's real new for me, too.
>> Yeah, it's real new for me, too.
>> Yeah, it's real new for me, too. >> What is it?
>> What is it?
>> What is it? >> Uh, it's a it's called the diksha in the
>> Uh, it's a it's called the diksha in the
>> Uh, it's a it's called the diksha in the Indian tradition and it's a energy work.
Indian tradition and it's a energy work.
Indian tradition and it's a energy work. It's a
It's a
It's a >> Oh, that's the diksha when you pay
>> Oh, that's the diksha when you pay
>> Oh, that's the diksha when you pay $10,000 to get initiated. Forget it. It
$10,000 to get initiated. Forget it. It
$10,000 to get initiated. Forget it. It >> uh Yeah,
>> uh Yeah,
>> uh Yeah, that
that
that >> that's the answer. Okay.
>> that's the answer. Okay.
>> that's the answer. Okay. What you want?
I just wondered I wondered if it
I just wondered I wondered if it >> they got a cashier at the door to
>> they got a cashier at the door to
>> they got a cashier at the door to heaven. No, I don't think so.
heaven. No, I don't think so.
heaven. No, I don't think so. >> Yeah,
>> I think that's my answer. Very good. All
>> I think that's my answer. Very good. All right. Appreciate your time. Thank you.
right. Appreciate your time. Thank you.
right. Appreciate your time. Thank you. >> Yeah. No, that's too way too It's like
>> Yeah. No, that's too way too It's like
>> Yeah. No, that's too way too It's like >> we've been asked on that that particular
>> we've been asked on that that particular
>> we've been asked on that that particular initiation before.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. Um, I've observed something in myself
Um, I've observed something in myself
Um, I've observed something in myself sometimes that although I'm extremely
sometimes that although I'm extremely
sometimes that although I'm extremely excited about hearing a particular
excited about hearing a particular
excited about hearing a particular teacher, there's this subtle idea that,
teacher, there's this subtle idea that,
teacher, there's this subtle idea that, "Oh, but that won't happen to me."
"Oh, but that won't happen to me."
"Oh, but that won't happen to me." And I've heard other people saying that,
And I've heard other people saying that,
And I've heard other people saying that, too. There's this idea that, wow, oh,
too. There's this idea that, wow, oh,
too. There's this idea that, wow, oh, but that won't happen for me.
but that won't happen for me.
but that won't happen for me. >> What won't happen?
>> What won't happen?
>> What won't happen? >> What won't happen? the progression, the
>> What won't happen? the progression, the
>> What won't happen? the progression, the the enlightenment, the reaching the
the enlightenment, the reaching the
the enlightenment, the reaching the higher levels. And I'm wondering, is
higher levels. And I'm wondering, is
higher levels. And I'm wondering, is that just the I'm special syndrome in
that just the I'm special syndrome in
that just the I'm special syndrome in reverse? I'm not good enough to get it.
reverse? I'm not good enough to get it.
reverse? I'm not good enough to get it. >> Yeah, it is.
>> Yeah, it is.
>> Yeah, it is. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You see, it's it's not how far you've
>> You see, it's it's not how far you've
>> You see, it's it's not how far you've gone. It's the direction you're in. It's
gone. It's the direction you're in. It's
gone. It's the direction you're in. It's the direction that you've set your
the direction that you've set your
the direction that you've set your compass. See, and if your compass is set
compass. See, and if your compass is set
compass. See, and if your compass is set this way, it's only a matter of time
this way, it's only a matter of time
this way, it's only a matter of time before you eventually end up where where
before you eventually end up where where
before you eventually end up where where you would like to go. Yeah. Mhm. It's
you would like to go. Yeah. Mhm. It's
you would like to go. Yeah. Mhm. It's your overall intention
your overall intention
your overall intention to be kind to all living things.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> You don't need an initiation for that.
Hi, my name is Sham and I'm from
Hi, my name is Sham and I'm from basically I'm from India but I live in
basically I'm from India but I live in
basically I'm from India but I live in New Jersey.
New Jersey.
New Jersey. >> And he's what?
>> And he's what?
>> And he's what? >> He's basically from India but he lives
>> He's basically from India but he lives
>> He's basically from India but he lives in New Jersey.
in New Jersey.
in New Jersey. >> Oh, that's I remember you from before.
>> Oh, that's I remember you from before.
>> Oh, that's I remember you from before. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Yes, I remember him.
>> Yes, I remember him.
>> Yes, I remember him. >> No. Oh,
>> My question is for a spiritual aspirant
>> My question is for a spiritual aspirant intellectual conviction and willing
intellectual conviction and willing
intellectual conviction and willing willpower. Yeah, I have talked that
willpower. Yeah, I have talked that
willpower. Yeah, I have talked that before. What is the question again?
before. What is the question again?
before. What is the question again? >> Out of
>> Out of
>> Out of >> what do you what is the question again?
>> what do you what is the question again?
>> what do you what is the question again? Um
Um
Um >> out of willpower and devotion and
>> out of willpower and devotion and
>> out of willpower and devotion and intellectual convention does anything
intellectual convention does anything
intellectual convention does anything take predominance over the other or
take predominance over the other or
take predominance over the other or should a spiritual aspirant practice
should a spiritual aspirant practice
should a spiritual aspirant practice them in balance like the synthesis of
them in balance like the synthesis of
them in balance like the synthesis of it?
it?
it? >> Okay. Um what he wants to know is a
>> Okay. Um what he wants to know is a
>> Okay. Um what he wants to know is a spiritual aspirant.
spiritual aspirant.
spiritual aspirant. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Um which takes he's trying to put it
>> Um which takes he's trying to put it
>> Um which takes he's trying to put it into categories prior whether it's
into categories prior whether it's
into categories prior whether it's intellectual or
intellectual or
intellectual or >> willpower.
>> willpower.
>> willpower. >> Willpower devotion or devotion.
>> Willpower devotion or devotion.
>> Willpower devotion or devotion. >> It's all of it then. Yeah.
>> It's all of it then. Yeah.
>> It's all of it then. Yeah. >> All of it.
>> All of it.
>> All of it. >> All right. So was is there any of those
>> All right. So was is there any of those
>> All right. So was is there any of those three that would take precedence over
three that would take precedence over
three that would take precedence over the others?
the others?
the others? >> It depends on one's personal karma.
>> It depends on one's personal karma.
>> It depends on one's personal karma. Many people first uh read about it and
Many people first uh read about it and
Many people first uh read about it and then they become interested.
then they become interested.
then they become interested. Some people get taken to a meeting where
Some people get taken to a meeting where
Some people get taken to a meeting where a spiritual speaker is speaking and they
a spiritual speaker is speaking and they
a spiritual speaker is speaking and they become uh you know desirous because of
become uh you know desirous because of
become uh you know desirous because of the exposure. Then what the what the
the exposure. Then what the what the
the exposure. Then what the what the initiating incident is irrelevant.
>> Now I want to ask a question
>> Now I want to ask a question >> since we're all here because we want to
>> since we're all here because we want to
>> since we're all here because we want to become enlightened.
become enlightened.
become enlightened. in some lifetime or at some time.
>> Doesn't that mean that we'll all
>> Doesn't that mean that we'll all eventually reach that?
eventually reach that?
eventually reach that? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Because this is the path we've chosen to
>> Because this is the path we've chosen to
>> Because this is the path we've chosen to take.
take.
take. >> That's correct.
>> That's correct.
>> That's correct. >> This lifetime, then it may be another.
>> This lifetime, then it may be another.
>> This lifetime, then it may be another. >> Well, that's chopping it chapters into
>> Well, that's chopping it chapters into
>> Well, that's chopping it chapters into lifetimes. There is chapters in one
lifetimes. There is chapters in one
lifetimes. There is chapters in one lifetime.
lifetime.
lifetime. >> I mean, because we've chosen this path
>> I mean, because we've chosen this path
>> I mean, because we've chosen this path eventually end up.
eventually end up.
eventually end up. >> Yes. Those who choose enlightened become
>> Yes. Those who choose enlightened become
>> Yes. Those who choose enlightened become enlightened.
enlightened.
enlightened. So that should be your answer.
>> Those who choose enlightenment become
>> Those who choose enlightenment become enlightened.
enlightened.
enlightened. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> I understand. Okay. God bless. God
>> I understand. Okay. God bless. God
>> I understand. Okay. God bless. God bless.
bless.
bless. Uhhuh.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. I mean that was I think it's true. Those
I mean that was I think it's true. Those
I mean that was I think it's true. Those who choose enlightened they become
who choose enlightened they become
who choose enlightened they become enlightened.
Hi. Uh, just wanted to thank you for
Hi. Uh, just wanted to thank you for your work. Um, every morning my wife and
your work. Um, every morning my wife and
your work. Um, every morning my wife and I read your books to our African gray
I read your books to our African gray
I read your books to our African gray parrot, Boo Boo.
parrot, Boo Boo.
parrot, Boo Boo. >> I can't read the books to Boooo, the
>> I can't read the books to Boooo, the
>> I can't read the books to Boooo, the African gray.
African gray.
African gray. >> Boo Boo.
>> Boo Boo.
>> Boo Boo. >> Boo Boo. She gave Broccoli a present
>> Boo Boo. She gave Broccoli a present
>> Boo Boo. She gave Broccoli a present recently.
recently.
recently. >> That's right.
>> That's right.
>> That's right. >> For Christmas.
>> For Christmas.
>> For Christmas. >> That's right. Broccoli got a present
>> That's right. Broccoli got a present
>> That's right. Broccoli got a present from a fellow admirer.
>> I've been chanting namo ringo
>> I've been chanting namo ringo uh for the last 22 years um twice a day
uh for the last 22 years um twice a day
uh for the last 22 years um twice a day every day to the ghanszan
every day to the ghanszan
every day to the ghanszan uh are you familiar? You know the
uh are you familiar? You know the
uh are you familiar? You know the ghanszan is the object of worship that
ghanszan is the object of worship that
ghanszan is the object of worship that nitrand daonin inscribed
nitrand daonin inscribed
nitrand daonin inscribed uh for the with the intention of
uh for the with the intention of
uh for the with the intention of um to transfer his enlightenment
um to transfer his enlightenment
um to transfer his enlightenment >> you know as a as something to focus on.
>> you know as a as something to focus on.
>> you know as a as something to focus on. Uh, I've
Uh, I've
Uh, I've just uh wondered, you know, I I haven't
just uh wondered, you know, I I haven't
just uh wondered, you know, I I haven't practiced within the organization for
practiced within the organization for
practiced within the organization for quite a while because it seems kind of
quite a while because it seems kind of
quite a while because it seems kind of polarized with the with the uh
polarized with the with the uh
polarized with the with the uh priesthood or a whole bunch of stuff has
priesthood or a whole bunch of stuff has
priesthood or a whole bunch of stuff has gone on around that. And so I just
gone on around that. And so I just
gone on around that. And so I just practice just chant
practice just chant
practice just chant uh with the idea that to just just with
uh with the idea that to just just with
uh with the idea that to just just with the intention of being unconditionally
the intention of being unconditionally
the intention of being unconditionally loving and um connecting to divinity and
loving and um connecting to divinity and
loving and um connecting to divinity and uh hopefully
uh hopefully
uh hopefully >> connecting to my Buddha nature.
>> connecting to my Buddha nature.
>> connecting to my Buddha nature. >> Yes. Um, but I wonder if it's necessary
>> Yes. Um, but I wonder if it's necessary
>> Yes. Um, but I wonder if it's necessary to chant to this object
to chant to this object
to chant to this object or
or
or >> to this object.
>> to this object.
>> to this object. >> The it's an object. Yeah, it's an
>> The it's an object. Yeah, it's an
>> The it's an object. Yeah, it's an object.
object.
object. >> It's instead of a Buddha, it's like an
>> It's instead of a Buddha, it's like an
>> It's instead of a Buddha, it's like an object. You chant to
object. You chant to
object. You chant to >> you chant to the object.
>> you chant to the object.
>> you chant to the object. >> It's it's a the original. It's it's a
>> It's it's a the original. It's it's a
>> It's it's a the original. It's it's a replica of of an object of worship that
replica of of an object of worship that
replica of of an object of worship that the founder of Namo Ringo inscribed.
the founder of Namo Ringo inscribed.
the founder of Namo Ringo inscribed. >> Oh yeah.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Oh yeah. >> In 1250 whatever that year right in
>> In 1250 whatever that year right in
>> In 1250 whatever that year right in around the mid
around the mid
around the mid >> mid3th century.
>> mid3th century.
>> mid3th century. >> Um
>> Um
>> Um >> what's the question?
>> what's the question?
>> what's the question? >> The question is is it necessary to chant
>> The question is is it necessary to chant
>> The question is is it necessary to chant to that or chant at all? Uh
to that or chant at all? Uh
to that or chant at all? Uh >> is it necessary to chant
>> is it necessary to chant
>> is it necessary to chant >> for the
>> for the
>> for the >> No.
for the evolution of this particular
for the evolution of this particular entity's consciousness. That's that
entity's consciousness. That's that
entity's consciousness. That's that that's my question.
that's my question.
that's my question. >> Did Jesus Christ chant?
>> Did Jesus Christ chant?
>> Did Jesus Christ chant? >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> Did the Buddha chant?
>> Did the Buddha chant?
>> Did the Buddha chant? >> No, I don't.
>> No, I don't.
>> No, I don't. >> Did Christian chant?
>> Did Christian chant?
>> Did Christian chant? >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> Then why why do you ask?
>> Then why why do you ask?
>> Then why why do you ask? >> Thank you.
>> Yeah. What's effective is the devotion.
>> Yeah. What's effective is the devotion. The devotion.
The devotion.
The devotion. What's effective is the devotion to a
What's effective is the devotion to a
What's effective is the devotion to a higher state to a higher being.
higher state to a higher being.
higher state to a higher being. >> Namaste Dr. Hawkins.
>> Namaste Dr. Hawkins.
>> Namaste Dr. Hawkins. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Uh thank you for you doing for all of
>> Uh thank you for you doing for all of
>> Uh thank you for you doing for all of us. Uh my question is about healing. Uh
us. Uh my question is about healing. Uh
us. Uh my question is about healing. Uh my wife was recently diagnosed with
my wife was recently diagnosed with
my wife was recently diagnosed with bipolar.
bipolar.
bipolar. >> This question is about what?
>> This question is about what?
>> This question is about what? >> Healing.
>> Healing.
>> Healing. >> Healing. Healing.
>> Healing. Healing.
>> Healing. Healing. >> Healing.
>> Healing.
>> Healing. >> Healing.
>> Healing. >> Healing. Healing. There's an L in
>> Healing. Healing. There's an L in
>> Healing. Healing. There's an L in healing. Yes. Okay.
healing. Yes. Okay.
healing. Yes. Okay. >> My wife was diagnosed with bipolar
>> My wife was diagnosed with bipolar
>> My wife was diagnosed with bipolar disorder. And I understand that uh
disorder. And I understand that uh
disorder. And I understand that uh healing comes on all three levels.
healing comes on all three levels.
healing comes on all three levels. Physical, mental, and spiritual.
Physical, mental, and spiritual.
Physical, mental, and spiritual. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> What kind of treatment would you
>> What kind of treatment would you
>> What kind of treatment would you recommend for all three levels?
recommend for all three levels?
recommend for all three levels? >> What kind of what? Um, what kind of
>> What kind of what? Um, what kind of
>> What kind of what? Um, what kind of treatment would you recommend for all
treatment would you recommend for all
treatment would you recommend for all three levels with her
three levels with her
three levels with her >> physical, mental, and spiritual? Yes.
>> physical, mental, and spiritual? Yes.
>> physical, mental, and spiritual? Yes. >> She's bipolar?
>> She's bipolar?
>> She's bipolar? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Yes.
>> Yes. >> All right. So, she sees a physician,
>> All right. So, she sees a physician,
>> All right. So, she sees a physician, psychiatrist.
psychiatrist.
psychiatrist. >> Yes, he does.
>> Yes, he does.
>> Yes, he does. >> And he has her on antibipolar
>> And he has her on antibipolar
>> And he has her on antibipolar medication, right? Yes.
medication, right? Yes.
medication, right? Yes. >> Uh, she also has a therapist, maybe the
>> Uh, she also has a therapist, maybe the
>> Uh, she also has a therapist, maybe the same person, who helps her resolve any
same person, who helps her resolve any
same person, who helps her resolve any psychological conflicts that may be
psychological conflicts that may be
psychological conflicts that may be complicating it. Yes.
complicating it. Yes.
complicating it. Yes. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> So, what else do you want to do? plus
>> So, what else do you want to do? plus
>> So, what else do you want to do? plus spiritual intention and prayer. Yes.
spiritual intention and prayer. Yes.
spiritual intention and prayer. Yes. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> That's all you can do.
>> That's all you can do.
>> That's all you can do. >> Perfect.
>> Perfect.
>> Perfect. >> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. >> Physical, mental, and spiritual. You're
>> Physical, mental, and spiritual. You're
>> Physical, mental, and spiritual. You're taking care of all three of them. So,
taking care of all three of them. So,
taking care of all three of them. So, that's very good. But more can you
that's very good. But more can you
that's very good. But more can you guess? That's very good.
>> They're not neglecting it or denying it.
>> They're not neglecting it or denying it. And uh yes, they're doing everything
And uh yes, they're doing everything
And uh yes, they're doing everything they can.
they can.
they can. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. And pharmacologically, you know, new and
And pharmacologically, you know, new and
And pharmacologically, you know, new and better things are coming along
better things are coming along
better things are coming along constantly.
constantly.
constantly. >> Yes, they are.
>> Newer and better things are coming along
>> Newer and better things are coming along all the time.
all the time.
all the time. >> Hi, I'm Jim from Morirana and I've uh
>> Hi, I'm Jim from Morirana and I've uh
>> Hi, I'm Jim from Morirana and I've uh read a lot of uh books about Edgar Casey
read a lot of uh books about Edgar Casey
read a lot of uh books about Edgar Casey and his work and I was wondering, have
and his work and I was wondering, have
and his work and I was wondering, have you ever uh calibrated him?
you ever uh calibrated him?
you ever uh calibrated him? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yes,
>> Yes,
>> Yes, >> the question is did I ever recalibrate
>> the question is did I ever recalibrate
>> the question is did I ever recalibrate him?
him?
him? >> Yes. What would the calibration be, sir?
>> Yes. What would the calibration be, sir?
>> Yes. What would the calibration be, sir? >> I think it was No, it was not. It was
>> I think it was No, it was not. It was
>> I think it was No, it was not. It was not high. It was about 285 or something.
not high. It was about 285 or something.
not high. It was about 285 or something. >> Edgar Casey.
>> Edgar Casey.
>> Edgar Casey. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> I don't remember what his calibration.
>> I don't remember what his calibration.
>> I don't remember what his calibration. >> Well, I'm telling you, you asked me and
>> Well, I'm telling you, you asked me and
>> Well, I'm telling you, you asked me and I'm telling you what
I'm telling you what
I'm telling you what the book get
the book get
the book get all this stuff.
all this stuff.
all this stuff. >> Anyway, Casey is not all that high. You
>> Anyway, Casey is not all that high. You
>> Anyway, Casey is not all that high. You know, he's like 300s or something, high
know, he's like 300s or something, high
know, he's like 300s or something, high 200s or something.
200s or something.
200s or something. >> He's in one of our books. Psychic
>> He's in one of our books. Psychic
>> He's in one of our books. Psychic ability is not the same as Yeah. Yeah.
ability is not the same as Yeah. Yeah.
ability is not the same as Yeah. Yeah. He's I think in the three 300s.
He's I think in the three 300s.
He's I think in the three 300s. >> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. >> Yep.
>> No, because it's not spiritual, it's
>> No, because it's not spiritual, it's psychic.
psychic.
psychic. >> Yeah. He's not spiritually evolved. He's
>> Yeah. He's not spiritually evolved. He's
>> Yeah. He's not spiritually evolved. He's psychically evolved. Okay. you know. So,
psychically evolved. Okay. you know. So,
psychically evolved. Okay. you know. So, >> um I seem to be having some difficulty
>> um I seem to be having some difficulty
>> um I seem to be having some difficulty with
with
with >> um creating and sticking to like
>> um creating and sticking to like
>> um creating and sticking to like spiritual practice and daily routines
spiritual practice and daily routines
spiritual practice and daily routines like you know prayer and meditation in
like you know prayer and meditation in
like you know prayer and meditation in the mornings and the evening and I was
the mornings and the evening and I was
the mornings and the evening and I was hoping that you could maybe give some
hoping that you could maybe give some
hoping that you could maybe give some advice on that.
advice on that.
advice on that. >> Just uh don't do it on a regular basis.
>> Just uh don't do it on a regular basis.
>> Just uh don't do it on a regular basis. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> Do it inspirationally.
>> Do it inspirationally.
>> Do it inspirationally. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. You know, I did it uh both regular and
You know, I did it uh both regular and
You know, I did it uh both regular and inspirational.
inspirational.
inspirational. And who's to say which is the most
And who's to say which is the most
And who's to say which is the most beneficial
beneficial
beneficial you know you can go into a very
you know you can go into a very
you know you can go into a very impassioned state and re reach a very
impassioned state and re reach a very
impassioned state and re reach a very high level of consciousness.
high level of consciousness.
high level of consciousness. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> All right. Thank you very much.
>> All right. Thank you very much.
>> All right. Thank you very much. >> And you can also practice on a daily
>> And you can also practice on a daily
>> And you can also practice on a daily basis and think nothing is happening
basis and think nothing is happening
basis and think nothing is happening whereas actually you're ripening and
whereas actually you're ripening and
whereas actually you're ripening and maturing you know. Yeah.
maturing you know. Yeah.
maturing you know. Yeah. Both ways serve.
Both ways serve.
Both ways serve. It's the intention behind it that makes
It's the intention behind it that makes
It's the intention behind it that makes it serve.
it serve.
it serve. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. >> Thank you.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Yes. Um,
>> Yes. Um,
>> Yes. Um, I uh I I I graduated relatively recently
I uh I I I graduated relatively recently
I uh I I I graduated relatively recently and uh I'm going into the the workforce
and uh I'm going into the the workforce
and uh I'm going into the the workforce and everything like that and um I
and everything like that and um I
and everything like that and um I decided I kind of like advertising
decided I kind of like advertising
decided I kind of like advertising and um I almost feel guilty about that
and um I almost feel guilty about that
and um I almost feel guilty about that because of the whole programming thing
because of the whole programming thing
because of the whole programming thing and um
and um
and um >> programming thing are you referring to?
>> programming thing are you referring to?
>> programming thing are you referring to? >> Well, the fact that advertising programs
>> Well, the fact that advertising programs
>> Well, the fact that advertising programs you to buy products.
you to buy products.
you to buy products. >> Was that wrong?
>> Was that wrong?
>> Was that wrong? >> I don't know.
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know. >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> No. People make their living, people
>> No. People make their living, people
>> No. People make their living, people survive, children eat. If it wasn't for
survive, children eat. If it wasn't for
survive, children eat. If it wasn't for business,
business,
business, whe they'd be digging turnipss or what.
>> And um I don't know if you still do
>> And um I don't know if you still do this. Um
this. Um
this. Um >> yeah,
>> yeah,
>> yeah, >> but I was wondering if you could
>> but I was wondering if you could
>> but I was wondering if you could calibrate whether or not the current
calibrate whether or not the current
calibrate whether or not the current agency I'm working for is above 200.
agency I'm working for is above 200.
agency I'm working for is above 200. >> The current agency
>> The current agency
>> The current agency >> the current agency he's working for, is
>> the current agency he's working for, is
>> the current agency he's working for, is it above 200?
it above 200?
it above 200? >> Oh, let's ask. Uh we have permission to
>> Oh, let's ask. Uh we have permission to
>> Oh, let's ask. Uh we have permission to answer it.
answer it.
answer it. Uh the agency he's working for is over
Uh the agency he's working for is over
Uh the agency he's working for is over 200. Yes. You don't have to tell us the
200. Yes. You don't have to tell us the
200. Yes. You don't have to tell us the name. All right.
name. All right.
name. All right. >> All right. Cool.
>> I think advertising is very fascinating.
>> I think advertising is very fascinating. >> I do too.
>> I do too.
>> I do too. >> And they haven't even they don't even
>> And they haven't even they don't even
>> And they haven't even they don't even realize what they could do with it with
realize what they could do with it with
realize what they could do with it with consciousness techniques, you know.
consciousness techniques, you know.
consciousness techniques, you know. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Hello. This question has to do with the
>> Hello. This question has to do with the
>> Hello. This question has to do with the relationship between levels of
relationship between levels of
relationship between levels of consciousness and the nervous system and
consciousness and the nervous system and
consciousness and the nervous system and physiological functioning. The question
physiological functioning. The question
physiological functioning. The question is this
is this
is this >> the the ner the physiology of the
>> the the ner the physiology of the
>> the the ner the physiology of the nervous system
nervous system
nervous system >> the the relationship between levels of
>> the the relationship between levels of
>> the the relationship between levels of consciousness
consciousness
consciousness >> and the nervous system. And my question
>> and the nervous system. And my question
>> and the nervous system. And my question is this. Prior to anything that is
is this. Prior to anything that is
is this. Prior to anything that is arising in consciousness, there seems to
arising in consciousness, there seems to
arising in consciousness, there seems to be a kind of pure
be a kind of pure
be a kind of pure conscious possibility
conscious possibility
conscious possibility >> that that has no content and has no
>> that that has no content and has no
>> that that has no content and has no possibility of actually being observed.
possibility of actually being observed.
possibility of actually being observed. >> I have heard this mentioned and it is an
>> I have heard this mentioned and it is an
>> I have heard this mentioned and it is an awareness that I have myself. But my
awareness that I have myself. But my
awareness that I have myself. But my question is this that basic awareness to
question is this that basic awareness to
question is this that basic awareness to what extent is it influenced by or
what extent is it influenced by or
what extent is it influenced by or dependent upon the nervous system
dependent upon the nervous system
dependent upon the nervous system >> without the nervous system you know
>> without the nervous system you know
>> without the nervous system you know to process it. So the state prior to
to process it. So the state prior to
to process it. So the state prior to consciousness prior to awareness is is
consciousness prior to awareness is is
consciousness prior to awareness is is the state of is the condition of
the state of is the condition of
the state of is the condition of consciousness itself
consciousness itself
consciousness itself you know which is then evolves into
you know which is then evolves into
you know which is then evolves into awareness
awareness
awareness and then into the content of awareness.
and then into the content of awareness.
and then into the content of awareness. So you can beware I mean you can be
So you can beware I mean you can be
So you can beware I mean you can be aware
aware
aware of the potentiality as always being
of the potentiality as always being
of the potentiality as always being there.
there.
there. the potentiality. If you focus on the
the potentiality. If you focus on the
the potentiality. If you focus on the potentiality, it no longer has content.
potentiality, it no longer has content.
potentiality, it no longer has content. It's just an energy field.
It's just an energy field.
It's just an energy field. >> Yep.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. >> Does that energy field need a nervous
>> Does that energy field need a nervous
>> Does that energy field need a nervous system?
system?
system? >> Then what
>> Then what
>> Then what >> does that energy field need a a nervous
>> does that energy field need a a nervous
>> does that energy field need a a nervous system?
system?
system? >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> No. Because when you're out of body, u
>> No. Because when you're out of body, u
>> No. Because when you're out of body, u you're just as conscious as when you're
you're just as conscious as when you're
you're just as conscious as when you're in body.
in body.
in body. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. >> Yeah.
>> Consciousness activates the neuronal
>> Consciousness activates the neuronal circus
circus
circus like Maxwell's law. Like Maxwell,
like Maxwell's law. Like Maxwell,
like Maxwell's law. Like Maxwell, >> my question is also of physiology. The
>> my question is also of physiology. The
>> my question is also of physiology. The um spiritual journey for me has been an
um spiritual journey for me has been an
um spiritual journey for me has been an amazing ride, a roller coaster of
amazing ride, a roller coaster of
amazing ride, a roller coaster of emotions and physiology.
emotions and physiology.
emotions and physiology. And I find it exciting when those lower
And I find it exciting when those lower
And I find it exciting when those lower emotions spill into my physiology and my
emotions spill into my physiology and my
emotions spill into my physiology and my higher consciousness recognizes that
higher consciousness recognizes that
higher consciousness recognizes that lower emotion. And if the 15% above 200
lower emotion. And if the 15% above 200
lower emotion. And if the 15% above 200 balances the 85% below,
balances the 85% below,
balances the 85% below, as human beings in the human experience,
as human beings in the human experience,
as human beings in the human experience, do we have that same balance of
do we have that same balance of
do we have that same balance of potentials like the child, the adult,
potentials like the child, the adult,
potentials like the child, the adult, and the um the parent.
and the um the parent.
and the um the parent. And when those
And when those
And when those emotions spill and we realize it's okay,
emotions spill and we realize it's okay,
emotions spill and we realize it's okay, is it our higher consciousness that
is it our higher consciousness that
is it our higher consciousness that pulls us closer to enlightenment?
pulls us closer to enlightenment?
pulls us closer to enlightenment? >> Yes.
>> And
>> And >> it takes it takes advantage of takes
>> it takes it takes advantage of takes
>> it takes it takes advantage of takes advantage of things. See
advantage of things. See
advantage of things. See >> utilizes
>> utilizes
>> utilizes everything is miss for the grill. Gris
everything is miss for the grill. Gris
everything is miss for the grill. Gris for the mill. Miss for the grill.
for the mill. Miss for the grill.
for the mill. Miss for the grill. Mister for the grill. No, Christopher
Mister for the grill. No, Christopher
Mister for the grill. No, Christopher the Miller. What
the Miller. What
the Miller. What >> an earlier question was if you feel like
>> an earlier question was if you feel like
>> an earlier question was if you feel like you're running too fast and you fall
you're running too fast and you fall
you're running too fast and you fall harder, you said to slow down and I'm
harder, you said to slow down and I'm
harder, you said to slow down and I'm finding that running fast and
finding that running fast and
finding that running fast and discovering
discovering
discovering I'm quicker to come to the awareness of
I'm quicker to come to the awareness of
I'm quicker to come to the awareness of those lower emotions and excited to
those lower emotions and excited to
those lower emotions and excited to solve them. Is that ego-based or is that
solve them. Is that ego-based or is that
solve them. Is that ego-based or is that just
just
just >> you can do whatever you know from the
>> you can do whatever you know from the
>> you can do whatever you know from the viewpoint of pragmatism.
viewpoint of pragmatism.
viewpoint of pragmatism. Whatever seems to be the most workable
Whatever seems to be the most workable
Whatever seems to be the most workable model and it may change over the years
model and it may change over the years
model and it may change over the years too. What might be workable at one era
too. What might be workable at one era
too. What might be workable at one era is no longer appealing and you've
is no longer appealing and you've
is no longer appealing and you've already done that. You'll move on to a
already done that. You'll move on to a
already done that. You'll move on to a different one in a different era of your
different one in a different era of your
different one in a different era of your life.
life.
life. >> Relationships seem to spill the most
>> Relationships seem to spill the most
>> Relationships seem to spill the most emotion. Are they a useful tool in that
emotion. Are they a useful tool in that
emotion. Are they a useful tool in that regard?
regard?
regard? >> Oh indeed.
>> Oh indeed.
>> Oh indeed. Okay,
Okay,
Okay, >> thank you.
Hi, Dr. Ar and Susan
Hi, Dr. Ar and Susan overcome.
overcome.
overcome. Thank you so much both of you for your
Thank you so much both of you for your
Thank you so much both of you for your work.
work.
work. My girlfriend introduced me to you guys
My girlfriend introduced me to you guys
My girlfriend introduced me to you guys work eight months ago and she's been
work eight months ago and she's been
work eight months ago and she's been doing it for quite a while and the
doing it for quite a while and the
doing it for quite a while and the intent
intent
intent uh the intent of our relationship is to
uh the intent of our relationship is to
uh the intent of our relationship is to form a spiritual partnership and
form a spiritual partnership and
form a spiritual partnership and obviously that's what you guys do and at
obviously that's what you guys do and at
obviously that's what you guys do and at times for us it gets really intense and
times for us it gets really intense and
times for us it gets really intense and seems to bring out like the worst in me
seems to bring out like the worst in me
seems to bring out like the worst in me >> but do you guys have any advice or
>> but do you guys have any advice or
>> but do you guys have any advice or >> I don't know what I don't know what he's
He says sometimes he wants to do this,
He says sometimes he wants to do this, he wants to form this partnership, but
he wants to form this partnership, but
he wants to form this partnership, but sometimes it gets really intense.
sometimes it gets really intense.
sometimes it gets really intense. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> For him.
>> For him.
>> For him. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> I said I'll just let it rip.
>> I said I'll just let it rip.
>> I said I'll just let it rip. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. All right.
>> I'm some like afraid to be taken over by
>> I'm some like afraid to be taken over by the emotions. So instead, it's maybe
the emotions. So instead, it's maybe
the emotions. So instead, it's maybe better just to watch them or
better just to watch them or
better just to watch them or >> Well, you can learn to become detached
>> Well, you can learn to become detached
>> Well, you can learn to become detached from them.
from them.
from them. You know, you witness the emotions
You know, you witness the emotions
You know, you witness the emotions without having to necessarily experience
without having to necessarily experience
without having to necessarily experience them out.
them out.
them out. You know,
You know,
You know, it's more profitable to witness the
it's more profitable to witness the
it's more profitable to witness the emotion.
emotion.
emotion. There's no great value in wallowing in
There's no great value in wallowing in
There's no great value in wallowing in them, you know.
them, you know.
them, you know. >> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. >> You witness them.
>> You witness them.
>> You witness them. >> Thank you. May
>> Thank you. May
>> Thank you. May >> because they're phenomenal. They're phen
>> because they're phenomenal. They're phen
>> because they're phenomenal. They're phen phenomenal logic. You see, they have no
phenomenal logic. You see, they have no
phenomenal logic. You see, they have no intrinsic reality to them. But what? No.
intrinsic reality to them. But what? No.
intrinsic reality to them. But what? No. Yes. Okay. Thank you.
Yes. Okay. Thank you.
Yes. Okay. Thank you. >> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you. >> Yeah.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> Hi, Susan. Doc.
>> Um, my wife and I met on the spiritual
>> Um, my wife and I met on the spiritual path five years ago, and we love being
path five years ago, and we love being
path five years ago, and we love being on the path together.
on the path together.
on the path together. And the path led us to you last summer.
And the path led us to you last summer.
And the path led us to you last summer. And I can't tell you how beautiful our
And I can't tell you how beautiful our
And I can't tell you how beautiful our lives have become since you came into
lives have become since you came into
lives have become since you came into our life. And I just wanted to come up
our life. And I just wanted to come up
our life. And I just wanted to come up and shake your hand and say thank you.
and shake your hand and say thank you.
and shake your hand and say thank you. >> It's a privilege. Thank you.
>> It's a privilege. Thank you.
>> It's a privilege. Thank you. >> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Yeah. He wants you to sign his book for
>> Yeah. He wants you to sign his book for
>> Yeah. He wants you to sign his book for him, please.
him, please.
him, please. >> Right here.
>> You find you signed the back of your
>> You find you signed the back of your hand by mistake. I'm sorry.
hand by mistake. I'm sorry.
hand by mistake. I'm sorry. You'll have to take that with you.
>> Namaste, Dr. Hawkins. My name is
>> Namaste, Dr. Hawkins. My name is Richard. I'm from Toronto
Richard. I'm from Toronto
Richard. I'm from Toronto and this is my first time here. I've
and this is my first time here. I've
and this is my first time here. I've been studying your work for about one
been studying your work for about one
been studying your work for about one year
year
year and my question revolves around a
and my question revolves around a
and my question revolves around a terrifying experience I had about 40
terrifying experience I had about 40
terrifying experience I had about 40 years ago
years ago
years ago and and uh I still wonder if it bothers
and and uh I still wonder if it bothers
and and uh I still wonder if it bothers me to this day. Uh I was a young man
me to this day. Uh I was a young man
me to this day. Uh I was a young man about 20 years of age going into a
about 20 years of age going into a
about 20 years of age going into a religious in religious college and um I
religious in religious college and um I
religious in religious college and um I was going to sleep one night and as I
was going to sleep one night and as I
was going to sleep one night and as I was going to sleep um this presence came
was going to sleep um this presence came
was going to sleep um this presence came on me. I it suddenly paralyzed me. I
on me. I it suddenly paralyzed me. I
on me. I it suddenly paralyzed me. I couldn't move my body at all. I couldn't
couldn't move my body at all. I couldn't
couldn't move my body at all. I couldn't open my eyes. And all I saw was this
open my eyes. And all I saw was this
open my eyes. And all I saw was this pure darkness. And these wolves eyes
pure darkness. And these wolves eyes
pure darkness. And these wolves eyes started to appear like orange slits in
started to appear like orange slits in
started to appear like orange slits in the dark. And they got more and more of
the dark. And they got more and more of
the dark. And they got more and more of them. Suddenly there was just hundreds
them. Suddenly there was just hundreds
them. Suddenly there was just hundreds of them looking at me. And I felt I was
of them looking at me. And I felt I was
of them looking at me. And I felt I was going to be invaded or taken over,
going to be invaded or taken over,
going to be invaded or taken over, possessed.
possessed.
possessed. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And it was I was just I couldn't open my
>> And it was I was just I couldn't open my
>> And it was I was just I couldn't open my mouth to even uh ask for help.
mouth to even uh ask for help.
mouth to even uh ask for help. >> Yep.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. and and at the last second all I could
and and at the last second all I could
and and at the last second all I could think of doctor was to just call out on
think of doctor was to just call out on
think of doctor was to just call out on the name of Jesus Christ.
the name of Jesus Christ.
the name of Jesus Christ. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Within seconds
>> Within seconds
>> Within seconds everything released.
everything released.
everything released. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Demon Demons hate the Jesus and the name
>> Demon Demons hate the Jesus and the name
>> Demon Demons hate the Jesus and the name of Jesus.
of Jesus.
of Jesus. >> You're exploring some of the lower lower
>> You're exploring some of the lower lower
>> You're exploring some of the lower lower astral realms. Yeah.
astral realms. Yeah.
astral realms. Yeah. >> So what I'm wondering is has that um
>> So what I'm wondering is has that um
>> So what I'm wondering is has that um those two those two experiences happened
those two those two experiences happened
those two those two experiences happened within a year of each other.
within a year of each other.
within a year of each other. >> Yes. And
>> Yes. And
>> Yes. And h am I still vulnerable to that sort of
h am I still vulnerable to that sort of
h am I still vulnerable to that sort of experience? Are there parasitic negative
experience? Are there parasitic negative
experience? Are there parasitic negative entities that I still have to contend
entities that I still have to contend
entities that I still have to contend with in my life?
with in my life?
with in my life? >> Uh no because uh you can order them away
>> Uh no because uh you can order them away
>> Uh no because uh you can order them away in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ.
in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ.
in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ. You can order them be gone demons.
You can order them be gone demons.
You can order them be gone demons. You have the power of Jesus Christ to
You have the power of Jesus Christ to
You have the power of Jesus Christ to cast out demons. I cast thee out in the
cast out demons. I cast thee out in the
cast out demons. I cast thee out in the name of my Lord Jesus Christ. Get the
name of my Lord Jesus Christ. Get the
name of my Lord Jesus Christ. Get the hints and order them out. They cannot
hints and order them out. They cannot
hints and order them out. They cannot refuse
refuse
refuse >> or any other n or any other entities
>> or any other n or any other entities
>> or any other n or any other entities whatsoever.
whatsoever.
whatsoever. >> Well, I'm talking about negative
>> Well, I'm talking about negative
>> Well, I'm talking about negative entities. You're not going to tell the
entities. You're not going to tell the
entities. You're not going to tell the angels to go to hell, are you?
You're talking about demons.
You're talking about demons. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> The Buddha was beset by demons. Jesus
>> The Buddha was beset by demons. Jesus
>> The Buddha was beset by demons. Jesus Christ was beset by demons.
Christ was beset by demons.
Christ was beset by demons. >> Yes. Yes.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Yes. Yes. >> The instruction is to order them to be
>> The instruction is to order them to be
>> The instruction is to order them to be gone in the name of Jesus Christ,
gone in the name of Jesus Christ,
gone in the name of Jesus Christ, >> who is reality and truth, whereas they
>> who is reality and truth, whereas they
>> who is reality and truth, whereas they stand for falsehood. Mhm.
stand for falsehood. Mhm.
stand for falsehood. Mhm. >> So you have the power to I call it
>> So you have the power to I call it
>> So you have the power to I call it forget what they call it the discernment
forget what they call it the discernment
forget what they call it the discernment of spirits. You have the the permission
of spirits. You have the the permission
of spirits. You have the the permission to order them hence.
to order them hence.
to order them hence. >> I see
>> I see
>> I see >> get thee hence and leave my presence and
>> get thee hence and leave my presence and
>> get thee hence and leave my presence and that is the order from my from Jesus
that is the order from my from Jesus
that is the order from my from Jesus Christ.
Christ.
Christ. They cannot refuse.
They cannot refuse.
They cannot refuse. >> Good to know. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Good to know. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Good to know. Thank you. Thank you. >> Yeah.
Thanks again.
Thanks again. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> It's called the something or other of
>> It's called the something or other of
>> It's called the something or other of demons. It's a Christian term. I forget.
>> I forget. Yeah. I I did say it before
>> I forget. Yeah. I I did say it before and then I went forgot it again. Yeah.
I can't believe I'm here.
I can't believe I'm here. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Let me see if you sign with my pen,
>> Let me see if you sign with my pen,
>> Let me see if you sign with my pen, please.
please.
please. >> He can't read.
>> He can't read.
>> He can't read. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> See where he's writing.
>> See where he's writing.
>> See where he's writing. >> Good afternoon, Doc. My name is Vinnie
>> Good afternoon, Doc. My name is Vinnie
>> Good afternoon, Doc. My name is Vinnie Mone. I'm from Brooklyn.
Mone. I'm from Brooklyn.
Mone. I'm from Brooklyn. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And uh
>> I can't believe I'm here. When you
>> I can't believe I'm here. When you walked out on stage, I just bam, I got
walked out on stage, I just bam, I got
walked out on stage, I just bam, I got blasted, you know, and uh it was
blasted, you know, and uh it was
blasted, you know, and uh it was awesome. Uh I was struck sober 20 years
awesome. Uh I was struck sober 20 years
awesome. Uh I was struck sober 20 years ago and my life has been so changed and
ago and my life has been so changed and
ago and my life has been so changed and I dedicate myself on a consistent basis
I dedicate myself on a consistent basis
I dedicate myself on a consistent basis to God and all the teachings I've been
to God and all the teachings I've been
to God and all the teachings I've been through. Your yours is the cherry on the
through. Your yours is the cherry on the
through. Your yours is the cherry on the cake. Yours is the icing on it. It's
cake. Yours is the icing on it. It's
cake. Yours is the icing on it. It's it's like all my life there was a puzzle
it's like all my life there was a puzzle
it's like all my life there was a puzzle and the pieces were missing and you
and the pieces were missing and you
and the pieces were missing and you filled in all the pieces. There's
filled in all the pieces. There's
filled in all the pieces. There's nothing left to mystery. There's nothing
nothing left to mystery. There's nothing
nothing left to mystery. There's nothing left to Oh, that's that's fate. Take
left to Oh, that's that's fate. Take
left to Oh, that's that's fate. Take that on faith. No, you've answered and
that on faith. No, you've answered and
that on faith. No, you've answered and you've made me a lot more confident on
you've made me a lot more confident on
you've made me a lot more confident on the path that I'm on. And my question is
the path that I'm on. And my question is
the path that I'm on. And my question is that periodically I get this sense of
that periodically I get this sense of
that periodically I get this sense of doubt. It's like something that comes up
doubt. It's like something that comes up
doubt. It's like something that comes up here and and I take a I step back a
here and and I take a I step back a
here and and I take a I step back a little bit and I get scared because for
little bit and I get scared because for
little bit and I get scared because for me to veer from this path would be to
me to veer from this path would be to
me to veer from this path would be to die. There's no question about it.
die. There's no question about it.
die. There's no question about it. >> Would to veer from the path would to be
>> Would to veer from the path would to be
>> Would to veer from the path would to be like die.
like die.
like die. >> To die. There's no doubt about it. I'm
>> To die. There's no doubt about it. I'm
>> To die. There's no doubt about it. I'm >> Well, you're not going to veer from the
>> Well, you're not going to veer from the
>> Well, you're not going to veer from the path. I'm I'm in I I live within the
path. I'm I'm in I I live within the
path. I'm I'm in I I live within the parameters of the 12 steps. Oh yeah. And
parameters of the 12 steps. Oh yeah. And
parameters of the 12 steps. Oh yeah. And I'm in
I'm in
I'm in >> the you know aa I am part of it. I
>> the you know aa I am part of it. I
>> the you know aa I am part of it. I petition.
petition.
petition. >> You're not gonna leave the path. No way.
>> You're not gonna leave the path. No way.
>> You're not gonna leave the path. No way. >> But uh it it just why why does that
>> But uh it it just why why does that
>> But uh it it just why why does that sense of doubt and uh feeling of less
sense of doubt and uh feeling of less
sense of doubt and uh feeling of less than periodically that still comes up
than periodically that still comes up
than periodically that still comes up and I and I surrender it and I
and I and I surrender it and I
and I and I surrender it and I surrender.
surrender.
surrender. >> Yeah. Doubt and what's the other thing?
>> Yeah. Doubt and what's the other thing?
>> Yeah. Doubt and what's the other thing? >> Yeah. And being less
>> Yeah. And being less
>> Yeah. And being less >> less.
>> less.
>> less. >> Less than you know like I said
>> Less than you know like I said
>> Less than you know like I said >> being less than. less than.
>> being less than. less than.
>> being less than. less than. >> In other words, unworthy.
>> In other words, unworthy.
>> In other words, unworthy. >> Oh, you are unworthy. You're just a
>> Oh, you are unworthy. You're just a
>> Oh, you are unworthy. You're just a punk. Worthless.
punk. Worthless.
punk. Worthless. >> Worthless. No good.
>> Worthless. No good.
>> Worthless. No good. >> I look with the chin.
>> I look with the chin.
>> I look with the chin. >> God tolerates you is behind me, you
>> God tolerates you is behind me, you
>> God tolerates you is behind me, you know.
Well, because doubt is uh is very
Well, because doubt is uh is very common, you know. It's it's very common
common, you know. It's it's very common
common, you know. It's it's very common and uh it's it's a normal thing for this
and uh it's it's a normal thing for this
and uh it's it's a normal thing for this phenomena to come up. You see, uh, don't
phenomena to come up. You see, uh, don't
phenomena to come up. You see, uh, don't forget you're working through stacks of
forget you're working through stacks of
forget you're working through stacks of karma.
karma.
karma. And in this, in those stacks, there was
And in this, in those stacks, there was
And in this, in those stacks, there was the denial of spiritual reality. There
the denial of spiritual reality. There
the denial of spiritual reality. There was the denial of God, etc. And so this
was the denial of God, etc. And so this
was the denial of God, etc. And so this time when the doubt comes up, you have
time when the doubt comes up, you have
time when the doubt comes up, you have to reject the doubt and choose divinity
to reject the doubt and choose divinity
to reject the doubt and choose divinity and ask the Holy Spirit for miracles
and ask the Holy Spirit for miracles
and ask the Holy Spirit for miracles to see it as it is in truth. That's all.
to see it as it is in truth. That's all.
to see it as it is in truth. That's all. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Thank you so much, Doc.
>> Thank you so much, Doc.
>> Thank you so much, Doc. >> 11. Just take the 11th step. Ask God to
>> 11. Just take the 11th step. Ask God to
>> 11. Just take the 11th step. Ask God to show you through prayer and meditation.
show you through prayer and meditation.
show you through prayer and meditation. You know, 11 step
You know, 11 step
You know, 11 step >> 11 step groups are fantastic.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> How you doing?
>> How you doing?
>> How you doing? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Uh I was wanting to ask you about
>> Uh I was wanting to ask you about
>> Uh I was wanting to ask you about situational ethics.
situational ethics.
situational ethics. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> You mentioned before.
>> You mentioned before.
>> You mentioned before. >> Yes. um
>> Yes. um
>> Yes. um and intention. Both of those, it's our
and intention. Both of those, it's our
and intention. Both of those, it's our intentions that
intentions that
intentions that um govern everything. Everything is
um govern everything. Everything is
um govern everything. Everything is perfect.
perfect.
perfect. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> And everything's unfolding in
>> And everything's unfolding in
>> And everything's unfolding in perfection.
perfection.
perfection. >> So
>> So
>> So what I mean is sometimes things can look
what I mean is sometimes things can look
what I mean is sometimes things can look like they're bad and not so loving, but
like they're bad and not so loving, but
like they're bad and not so loving, but really be loving behind it.
really be loving behind it.
really be loving behind it. >> Correct.
>> Correct.
>> Correct. Mhm. And
Mhm. And
Mhm. And >> so that's a matter of discernment is
>> so that's a matter of discernment is
>> so that's a matter of discernment is what you're talking about, right?
what you're talking about, right?
what you're talking about, right? >> Yeah. So you just trust your intentions
>> Yeah. So you just trust your intentions
>> Yeah. So you just trust your intentions and
and
and >> that the cards play out. Correct.
>> that the cards play out. Correct.
>> that the cards play out. Correct. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> All right. Thank you.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> All right. Thank you. >> Yeah. Discernment to get the essence of
>> Yeah. Discernment to get the essence of
>> Yeah. Discernment to get the essence of him
him
him which is set by intention. Set by
which is set by intention. Set by
which is set by intention. Set by intention.
Um, I just recently graduate graduated
Um, I just recently graduate graduated from college. Yes. From architecture.
from college. Yes. From architecture.
from college. Yes. From architecture. And um,
And um,
And um, >> I have this overwhelming feeling that I
>> I have this overwhelming feeling that I
>> I have this overwhelming feeling that I am constantly being graded in everything
am constantly being graded in everything
am constantly being graded in everything I do. And I was
I do. And I was
I do. And I was >> now that you're out of school.
>> now that you're out of school.
>> now that you're out of school. >> Now that I'm out of school.
>> Now that I'm out of school.
>> Now that I'm out of school. >> Now that you're out of school. Well, you
>> Now that you're out of school. Well, you
>> Now that you're out of school. Well, you probably are being Yes. Right.
probably are being Yes. Right.
probably are being Yes. Right. >> Well, my question is, um, is it
>> Well, my question is, um, is it
>> Well, my question is, um, is it beneficial to know one's own calibration
beneficial to know one's own calibration
beneficial to know one's own calibration and to keep with it kind of like
and to keep with it kind of like
and to keep with it kind of like stepping on a scale or is it something
stepping on a scale or is it something
stepping on a scale or is it something that will just
that will just
that will just >> reveal itself to you? isn't necessary.
>> reveal itself to you? isn't necessary.
>> reveal itself to you? isn't necessary. No, if you look on the scale of
No, if you look on the scale of
No, if you look on the scale of consciousness, you see there's there's
consciousness, you see there's there's
consciousness, you see there's there's there there's descriptions of the those
there there's descriptions of the those
there there's descriptions of the those states, you see, and what you do is you
states, you see, and what you do is you
states, you see, and what you do is you find yourself on the description of
find yourself on the description of
find yourself on the description of those states. See, is it in devotional?
those states. See, is it in devotional?
those states. See, is it in devotional? Is it experimental? I mean, what right
Is it experimental? I mean, what right
Is it experimental? I mean, what right now you're trying to find where to put
now you're trying to find where to put
now you're trying to find where to put your weight on your feet. Is that is
your weight on your feet. Is that is
your weight on your feet. Is that is that right?
that right?
that right? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And are you working for a firm now or
>> And are you working for a firm now or
>> And are you working for a firm now or what?
what?
what? >> Um, I'm looking for a job. We're on a
>> Um, I'm looking for a job. We're on a
>> Um, I'm looking for a job. We're on a road trip to see you and
road trip to see you and
road trip to see you and >> visit a road trip to see you
>> visit a road trip to see you
>> visit a road trip to see you >> and to visit grad schools and things,
>> and to visit grad schools and things,
>> and to visit grad schools and things, but when when I go back to Austin and
but when when I go back to Austin and
but when when I go back to Austin and have to find my job and
have to find my job and
have to find my job and >> Oh, I see. Yes. Well, I love
>> Oh, I see. Yes. Well, I love
>> Oh, I see. Yes. Well, I love architecture and I've done uh some of it
architecture and I've done uh some of it
architecture and I've done uh some of it myself. I've enjoyed really enjoyed it.
myself. I've enjoyed really enjoyed it.
myself. I've enjoyed really enjoyed it. I I enjoy the creativity
I I enjoy the creativity
I I enjoy the creativity and the thoughtfulness and the ingenuity
and the thoughtfulness and the ingenuity
and the thoughtfulness and the ingenuity and projecting yourself into the space
and projecting yourself into the space
and projecting yourself into the space and what your life would be like if
and what your life would be like if
and what your life would be like if that's if you really had to be in that
that's if you really had to be in that
that's if you really had to be in that space and anticipate those things and
space and anticipate those things and
space and anticipate those things and then you come up with things that nobody
then you come up with things that nobody
then you come up with things that nobody else would think about because people
else would think about because people
else would think about because people don't do it that way.
don't do it that way.
don't do it that way. You know, project yourself into it
You know, project yourself into it
You know, project yourself into it >> as to what you would be like, what you
>> as to what you would be like, what you
>> as to what you would be like, what you would be doing, what your life is like.
would be doing, what your life is like.
would be doing, what your life is like. Here's your desk. Where's the bathroom?
Here's your desk. Where's the bathroom?
Here's your desk. Where's the bathroom? You're gonna have to go to the bathroom
You're gonna have to go to the bathroom
You're gonna have to go to the bathroom 10 times a day, right? Where's the
10 times a day, right? Where's the
10 times a day, right? Where's the bathroom? Where's the water cooler?
bathroom? Where's the water cooler?
bathroom? Where's the water cooler? Where you know what is the what is the
Where you know what is the what is the
Where you know what is the what is the what is the the view from from this
what is the the view from from this
what is the the view from from this window, etc.
window, etc.
window, etc. Put yourself uh project yourself ahead
Put yourself uh project yourself ahead
Put yourself uh project yourself ahead as to actually living through what you
as to actually living through what you
as to actually living through what you would be doing and who you are in that
would be doing and who you are in that
would be doing and who you are in that situation. And then you can anticipate
situation. And then you can anticipate
situation. And then you can anticipate other things that other people don't
other things that other people don't
other things that other people don't think about. They're only looking at it
think about. They're only looking at it
think about. They're only looking at it as visual
as visual
as visual geometry and a way. Mhm.
geometry and a way. Mhm.
geometry and a way. Mhm. >> Or stylistically, you know,
>> Or stylistically, you know,
>> Or stylistically, you know, >> but they're not really looking at what
>> but they're not really looking at what
>> but they're not really looking at what it would be to actually be there to be
it would be to actually be there to be
it would be to actually be there to be there, you know.
there, you know.
there, you know. >> I think architecture is uh really
>> I think architecture is uh really
>> I think architecture is uh really wonderful. It's very aesthetically
wonderful. It's very aesthetically
wonderful. It's very aesthetically pleasing, creatively pleasing.
pleasing, creatively pleasing.
pleasing, creatively pleasing. >> Well, can I shake your hand?
>> Well, can I shake your hand?
>> Well, can I shake your hand? >> And it's not airy fairy. It's it's
>> And it's not airy fairy. It's it's
>> And it's not airy fairy. It's it's surreal, you know.
surreal, you know.
surreal, you know. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yep.
Yes. I love architecture.
Yes. I love architecture. And what I used to always do is first
And what I used to always do is first
And what I used to always do is first design it from all directions. And then
design it from all directions. And then
design it from all directions. And then I would make a cardboard model to scale.
I would make a cardboard model to scale.
I would make a cardboard model to scale. Make a cardboard model to scale and
Make a cardboard model to scale and
Make a cardboard model to scale and picture yourself as a tiny living
picture yourself as a tiny living
picture yourself as a tiny living there.
there.
there. And you find out how hard it is to get
And you find out how hard it is to get
And you find out how hard it is to get to the stairway the way you got it
to the stairway the way you got it
to the stairway the way you got it designed. So you change it around. No.
designed. So you change it around. No.
designed. So you change it around. No. Here
Here
Here I'm telling you all the secrets and he's
I'm telling you all the secrets and he's
I'm telling you all the secrets and he's wandering away.
>> Oh yes.
>> Oh yes. >> Hello Dr. Hawkins. I'm Tara Carson.
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins. I'm Tara Carson.
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins. I'm Tara Carson. Um my question is what is the best way
Um my question is what is the best way
Um my question is what is the best way to hold um yeah I mean I excuse me hold
to hold um yeah I mean I excuse me hold
to hold um yeah I mean I excuse me hold another person in mind in terms of a
another person in mind in terms of a
another person in mind in terms of a spiritual intention. I understand
spiritual intention. I understand
spiritual intention. I understand holding it for myself, but is it
holding it for myself, but is it
holding it for myself, but is it inappropriate to hold the hope that
inappropriate to hold the hope that
inappropriate to hold the hope that somebody will awaken?
somebody will awaken?
somebody will awaken? >> Inappropriate to hold
>> Inappropriate to hold
>> Inappropriate to hold >> to hold it in mind that
>> to hold it in mind that
>> to hold it in mind that >> that someone else that someone else
>> that someone else that someone else
>> that someone else that someone else would awaken spiritually.
would awaken spiritually.
would awaken spiritually. >> Oh, of course you can. We did it for
>> Oh, of course you can. We did it for
>> Oh, of course you can. We did it for George Soros this morning.
George Soros this morning.
George Soros this morning. >> We did. I held him in mind and suddenly
>> We did. I held him in mind and suddenly
>> We did. I held him in mind and suddenly I saw him very lovingly. I saw him like
I saw him very lovingly. I saw him like
I saw him very lovingly. I saw him like a grandfather who just sort of missed
a grandfather who just sort of missed
a grandfather who just sort of missed the boat at some turn, but that didn't
the boat at some turn, but that didn't
the boat at some turn, but that didn't detract from him as an old grandfather
detract from him as an old grandfather
detract from him as an old grandfather kind of a guy,
kind of a guy,
kind of a guy, >> you know. So, I mean, your intention and
>> you know. So, I mean, your intention and
>> you know. So, I mean, your intention and you hold that in mind,
you hold that in mind,
you hold that in mind, then it depends on the other person's
then it depends on the other person's
then it depends on the other person's karma.
karma.
karma. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> But is it it is it through prayer or
>> But is it it is it through prayer or
>> But is it it is it through prayer or intention the best way to do it or both?
intention the best way to do it or both?
intention the best way to do it or both? >> Yes. Prayer is, you know, a way of
>> Yes. Prayer is, you know, a way of
>> Yes. Prayer is, you know, a way of exhibiting intention. Yes.
exhibiting intention. Yes.
exhibiting intention. Yes. >> And it's not violating their
>> And it's not violating their
>> And it's not violating their >> Oh, no. Because you're not forcing
>> Oh, no. Because you're not forcing
>> Oh, no. Because you're not forcing anything. Okay.
anything. Okay.
anything. Okay. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> You're not forcing anybody. I mean, if
>> You're not forcing anybody. I mean, if
>> You're not forcing anybody. I mean, if George Rose George goes to church Sunday
George Rose George goes to church Sunday
George Rose George goes to church Sunday morning, that mean it'll be on his own,
morning, that mean it'll be on his own,
morning, that mean it'll be on his own, you know? I'm not forcing him.
>> Thank you. May I shake your hand?
>> Thank you. May I shake your hand? >> Yeah.
>> Well, he's going to be my hobby now.
>> Well, he's going to be my hobby now. >> Hello. Yeah,
>> Hello. Yeah,
>> Hello. Yeah, >> I only heard about you from an
>> I only heard about you from an
>> I only heard about you from an astrologer in Illinois in October, you
astrologer in Illinois in October, you
astrologer in Illinois in October, you know, and I'm from California. So, I
know, and I'm from California. So, I
know, and I'm from California. So, I wanted to come because she said you are
wanted to come because she said you are
wanted to come because she said you are a very highly evolved spiritual being.
a very highly evolved spiritual being.
a very highly evolved spiritual being. So, I thought, let me go and see what a
So, I thought, let me go and see what a
So, I thought, let me go and see what a highly evolved spiritual being looks
highly evolved spiritual being looks
highly evolved spiritual being looks like. And I believe I have seen it. So,
like. And I believe I have seen it. So,
like. And I believe I have seen it. So, thank you very much.
>> It's already signed.
>> It's already signed. >> Oh, I forgot to ask. Are we born at a
>> Oh, I forgot to ask. Are we born at a
>> Oh, I forgot to ask. Are we born at a certain caliber or do we change
certain caliber or do we change
certain caliber or do we change throughout life as we evolve or
throughout life as we evolve or
throughout life as we evolve or >> Yes, you constantly evolve. Yes.
>> Yes, you constantly evolve. Yes.
>> Yes, you constantly evolve. Yes. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. You constantly evolve.
You constantly evolve.
You constantly evolve. That's why we have mechanisms like guilt
That's why we have mechanisms like guilt
That's why we have mechanisms like guilt and desire and disappointment and
and desire and disappointment and
and desire and disappointment and those that's all the baggage along the
those that's all the baggage along the
those that's all the baggage along the way.
It's good to see the two of you again.
It's good to see the two of you again. Um, I do hands-on energy healing and I
Um, I do hands-on energy healing and I
Um, I do hands-on energy healing and I have a new client
have a new client
have a new client uh who is eight years old.
uh who is eight years old.
uh who is eight years old. He has uh leukemia.
He has uh leukemia.
He has uh leukemia. It's been a while since I spoke
It's been a while since I spoke
It's been a while since I spoke eight-year-old and I've kind of
eight-year-old and I've kind of
eight-year-old and I've kind of forgotten the language.
forgotten the language.
forgotten the language. So, I was wondering if you would have
So, I was wondering if you would have
So, I was wondering if you would have some advice for me to
some advice for me to
some advice for me to uh relate to this child and what can I
uh relate to this child and what can I
uh relate to this child and what can I tell him to do to help uh heal himself?
tell him to do to help uh heal himself?
tell him to do to help uh heal himself? >> What is his function?
>> What is his function?
>> What is his function? >> Um he's he's a hands-on healer.
>> Um he's he's a hands-on healer.
>> Um he's he's a hands-on healer. >> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. >> He has a leukemia patient. Oh, you got a
>> He has a leukemia patient. Oh, you got a
>> He has a leukemia patient. Oh, you got a leukemia patient. Yes.
leukemia patient. Yes.
leukemia patient. Yes. >> So, what can he do that will what advice
>> So, what can he do that will what advice
>> So, what can he do that will what advice or what information?
or what information?
or what information? >> Oh, the patient is eight years old.
>> Oh, the patient is eight years old.
>> Oh, the patient is eight years old. >> Where does he pray? Does he go to
>> Where does he pray? Does he go to
>> Where does he pray? Does he go to church? What does he do?
church? What does he do?
church? What does he do? >> Yes. Yes.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Yes. Yes. >> Oh, that's all he can do.
>> Oh, that's all he can do.
>> Oh, that's all he can do. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Pray, go to church, be as good as he can
>> Pray, go to church, be as good as he can
>> Pray, go to church, be as good as he can be.
be.
be. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> And you know, karma is karma. So, what
>> And you know, karma is karma. So, what
>> And you know, karma is karma. So, what will be will be,
will be will be,
will be will be, >> right? Yeah.
>> right? Yeah.
>> right? Yeah. Okay. Oh, and you're writing a book on
Okay. Oh, and you're writing a book on
Okay. Oh, and you're writing a book on healing, too. Will that be out soon?
healing, too. Will that be out soon?
healing, too. Will that be out soon? next year, you know.
next year, you know.
next year, you know. >> Okay. All righty. Okay. Thank you.
>> Everything's physical, mental, and
>> Everything's physical, mental, and spiritual.
spiritual.
spiritual. My own medical history is disastrous.
My own medical history is disastrous.
My own medical history is disastrous. So, I speak from authority.
So, I speak from authority.
So, I speak from authority. >> Hello. Hello.
>> Hello. Hello.
>> Hello. Hello. >> My name is Rachel and I'm from New
>> My name is Rachel and I'm from New
>> My name is Rachel and I'm from New Jersey and um I'm also on a spiritual
Jersey and um I'm also on a spiritual
Jersey and um I'm also on a spiritual path basically by getting rid of, you
path basically by getting rid of, you
path basically by getting rid of, you know, egos, fears, and attachments. But
know, egos, fears, and attachments. But
know, egos, fears, and attachments. But um there's one area that I've chosen
um there's one area that I've chosen
um there's one area that I've chosen consciously not to um get rid of and
consciously not to um get rid of and
consciously not to um get rid of and that's my attachment towards my children
that's my attachment towards my children
that's my attachment towards my children and their future. Basically, I'm very
and their future. Basically, I'm very
and their future. Basically, I'm very driven to drive them and I know that's
driven to drive them and I know that's
driven to drive them and I know that's coming from my ego. And so I'm just
coming from my ego. And so I'm just
coming from my ego. And so I'm just hoping maybe you have some words of
hoping maybe you have some words of
hoping maybe you have some words of wisdom. Is it okay to continue that in
wisdom. Is it okay to continue that in
wisdom. Is it okay to continue that in attachment? And can I further along my
attachment? And can I further along my
attachment? And can I further along my spiritual path with that or
Well, let's see. You you have a partial
Well, let's see. You you have a partial influence, an important one, but a
influence, an important one, but a
influence, an important one, but a partial one. So, you influence by your
partial one. So, you influence by your
partial one. So, you influence by your choices, by what you value because they
choices, by what you value because they
choices, by what you value because they identify with you. And um
identify with you. And um
identify with you. And um as far I would I would, you know, as far
as far I would I would, you know, as far
as far I would I would, you know, as far as trying to forget trying to control
as trying to forget trying to control
as trying to forget trying to control them, I try to attract them in that
them, I try to attract them in that
them, I try to attract them in that direction.
direction.
direction. >> Try to attract them in that direction.
>> Try to attract them in that direction.
>> Try to attract them in that direction. What What direction do you want them to
What What direction do you want them to
What What direction do you want them to go? What do you want them to do? Oh, I
go? What do you want them to do? Oh, I
go? What do you want them to do? Oh, I want my son to be like the next Stephen
want my son to be like the next Stephen
want my son to be like the next Stephen Hawkins.
Hawkins.
Hawkins. No, I'm just very driven in that way.
No, I'm just very driven in that way.
No, I'm just very driven in that way. And I know it's from an ego place. I
And I know it's from an ego place. I
And I know it's from an ego place. I know it's trying to drive them through.
know it's trying to drive them through.
know it's trying to drive them through. >> All right. So, it is and I understand
>> All right. So, it is and I understand
>> All right. So, it is and I understand that. But I feel like I would be letting
that. But I feel like I would be letting
that. But I feel like I would be letting them down if and so it's a it's a
them down if and so it's a it's a
them down if and so it's a it's a dilemma within me that if I don't
dilemma within me that if I don't
dilemma within me that if I don't >> help them become all they can be in
>> help them become all they can be in
>> help them become all they can be in terms of that way.
terms of that way.
terms of that way. >> Yeah. So you try to give them the
>> Yeah. So you try to give them the
>> Yeah. So you try to give them the opportunity
opportunity
opportunity and uh follow up with uh supporting
and uh follow up with uh supporting
and uh follow up with uh supporting whatever skills they exhibit in that
whatever skills they exhibit in that
whatever skills they exhibit in that direction
direction
direction >> and um the millu in which they grow up
>> and um the millu in which they grow up
>> and um the millu in which they grow up greatly influences them without
greatly influences them without
greatly influences them without coercion.
coercion.
coercion. You know, I grew up around music, but
You know, I grew up around music, but
You know, I grew up around music, but all my family played the piano or were
all my family played the piano or were
all my family played the piano or were musicians or singers or dancers or
musicians or singers or dancers or
musicians or singers or dancers or something, you know? So, I didn't have
something, you know? So, I didn't have
something, you know? So, I didn't have to try and control somebody. Hey, you
to try and control somebody. Hey, you
to try and control somebody. Hey, you got to go take lessons. I mean, they're
got to go take lessons. I mean, they're
got to go take lessons. I mean, they're in that whole millu.
in that whole millu.
in that whole millu. >> I hear
>> I hear
>> I hear >> it's hard to keep them away from the
>> it's hard to keep them away from the
>> it's hard to keep them away from the piano. See?
piano. See?
piano. See? >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yep. I understand what you're trying to
>> Yep. I understand what you're trying to
>> Yep. I understand what you're trying to say. Thank you very much.
>> Yeah. You influence them by by your own
>> Yeah. You influence them by by your own interest.
interest.
interest. Doesn't always work.
Well, my mother was crazy about baseball
Well, my mother was crazy about baseball and I always thought baseball was so
and I always thought baseball was so
and I always thought baseball was so boring I couldn't stand it. She'd have
boring I couldn't stand it. She'd have
boring I couldn't stand it. She'd have the dopey baseball game on and she'd be
the dopey baseball game on and she'd be
the dopey baseball game on and she'd be keeping score on all the batters and I
keeping score on all the batters and I
keeping score on all the batters and I thought, "What the hell did she see in
thought, "What the hell did she see in
thought, "What the hell did she see in that?" You know what I'm saying?
that?" You know what I'm saying?
that?" You know what I'm saying? >> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Uh,
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Uh,
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Uh, >> hi. Uh, my name is Wenut. Uh, I'm
>> hi. Uh, my name is Wenut. Uh, I'm
>> hi. Uh, my name is Wenut. Uh, I'm actually from India.
actually from India.
actually from India. uh I've uh read a lot of spiritual books
uh I've uh read a lot of spiritual books
uh I've uh read a lot of spiritual books uh starting from Paramahamsai
uh starting from Paramahamsai
uh starting from Paramahamsai Yogaandanda Nisaratam Maharaja and uh
Yogaandanda Nisaratam Maharaja and uh
Yogaandanda Nisaratam Maharaja and uh you know lots of books ekart as well but
you know lots of books ekart as well but
you know lots of books ekart as well but uh your books were really amazing and uh
uh your books were really amazing and uh
uh your books were really amazing and uh they've actually changed me a lot and uh
they've actually changed me a lot and uh
they've actually changed me a lot and uh I just wanted to thank you for your
I just wanted to thank you for your
I just wanted to thank you for your work. Thanks a lot.
work. Thanks a lot.
work. Thanks a lot. >> Thank you for thanking me. Yes and thank
>> Thank you for thanking me. Yes and thank
>> Thank you for thanking me. Yes and thank you
This is well read.
This is well read. >> What does this mean?
>> What does this mean?
>> What does this mean? >> Course of miracles book.
>> Course of miracles book.
>> Course of miracles book. >> Oh man.
>> Oh man.
>> Oh man. >> Yeah, right.
>> Yeah, right.
>> Yeah, right. >> With all that tape on it and you must be
>> With all that tape on it and you must be
>> With all that tape on it and you must be pretty holy by now.
>> And duct tape. Duct tape will fix
>> And duct tape. Duct tape will fix everything, right?
everything, right?
everything, right? >> It will.
>> It will.
>> It will. >> Well, firstly, I I uh always like to
>> Well, firstly, I I uh always like to
>> Well, firstly, I I uh always like to start with I love you, Dr. Hawkins.
start with I love you, Dr. Hawkins.
start with I love you, Dr. Hawkins. Thank you. I love you too, Susan.
Thank you. I love you too, Susan.
Thank you. I love you too, Susan. >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> thank you. I was reading I
>> thank you. I was reading I
>> thank you. I was reading I >> Oh,
>> Oh,
>> Oh, >> the latest uh read is I and it speaks of
>> the latest uh read is I and it speaks of
>> the latest uh read is I and it speaks of uh silent transmission in the grace of
uh silent transmission in the grace of
uh silent transmission in the grace of the teacher.
the teacher.
the teacher. >> Yes. And there on the airplane
>> Yes. And there on the airplane
>> Yes. And there on the airplane yesterday,
yesterday,
yesterday, I read a description of the self and um
I read a description of the self and um
I read a description of the self and um would just ask if I can hold your hand
would just ask if I can hold your hand
would just ask if I can hold your hand and receive that transmission.
and receive that transmission.
and receive that transmission. >> Yeah. He pass it on to you with great
>> Yeah. He pass it on to you with great
>> Yeah. He pass it on to you with great joy.
joy.
joy. >> Thank you. And I'd like to share it with
>> Thank you. And I'd like to share it with
>> Thank you. And I'd like to share it with everyone in this audience.
everyone in this audience.
everyone in this audience. >> Hold on to the eons.
>> Hold on to the eons.
>> Hold on to the eons. >> Thank you, sir.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Thank you, sir. Thank you.
>> Right here, please.
>> Right here, please. >> What?
>> What?
>> What? >> Sign right here.
>> Sign right here.
>> Sign right here. >> Sign
>> Sign
>> Sign >> right here.
>> right here.
>> right here. >> Sign here.
>> Sign here.
>> Sign here. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> I owe you $22,843.
>> Okay. Whatever you say.
>> Okay. Whatever you say. >> That's a bill.
Thank you.
Thank you. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> Boom.
>> Boom. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> Hello. I finished it. But first, I have
>> Hello. I finished it. But first, I have a surprise. Hi, Doc. Hi, Susie.
a surprise. Hi, Doc. Hi, Susie.
a surprise. Hi, Doc. Hi, Susie. >> Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. >> I know your love for teners
>> I know your love for teners
>> I know your love for teners and and I know that you've told me that
and and I know that you've told me that
and and I know that you've told me that I remind you of Bachelli. And I figured
I remind you of Bachelli. And I figured
I remind you of Bachelli. And I figured you have every Bachelli recording there
you have every Bachelli recording there
you have every Bachelli recording there is. So, I brought you three Mo Teners.
is. So, I brought you three Mo Teners.
is. So, I brought you three Mo Teners. >> Mo Teners.
>> Mo Teners.
>> Mo Teners. >> And And it's a wonderful wonderful
>> And And it's a wonderful wonderful
>> And And it's a wonderful wonderful presentation. It's a DVD.
presentation. It's a DVD.
presentation. It's a DVD. >> Oh.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. >> And I think you'll enjoy it. It's three
>> And I think you'll enjoy it. It's three
>> And I think you'll enjoy it. It's three languages, seven different styles of
languages, seven different styles of
languages, seven different styles of music.
music.
music. >> Oh, yeah. And it's wonderful.
>> Oh, yeah. And it's wonderful.
>> Oh, yeah. And it's wonderful. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> You're welcome. When I first came to
>> You're welcome. When I first came to
>> You're welcome. When I first came to Sedona in April, I gave you a copy,
Sedona in April, I gave you a copy,
Sedona in April, I gave you a copy, spiralbound copy of what I thought was a
spiralbound copy of what I thought was a
spiralbound copy of what I thought was a pretty much finished book, except that I
pretty much finished book, except that I
pretty much finished book, except that I had the I asked for the grace for the
had the I asked for the grace for the
had the I asked for the grace for the calibration to come up to the level so
calibration to come up to the level so
calibration to come up to the level so that other people could get a healing
that other people could get a healing
that other people could get a healing from it.
from it.
from it. And since that time, the book has
And since that time, the book has
And since that time, the book has rewritten me.
rewritten me.
rewritten me. And um the title's changed. It's called
And um the title's changed. It's called
And um the title's changed. It's called The Struggle to Surrender: Love,
The Struggle to Surrender: Love,
The Struggle to Surrender: Love, Consciousness, and the Quantum Field.
Consciousness, and the Quantum Field.
Consciousness, and the Quantum Field. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> And it says inside with deep gratitude
>> And it says inside with deep gratitude
>> And it says inside with deep gratitude to Sir David Hawkins, MD, PhD, whose
to Sir David Hawkins, MD, PhD, whose
to Sir David Hawkins, MD, PhD, whose recontextualization of reality has
recontextualization of reality has
recontextualization of reality has rocked my boat and given me wings. Thank
rocked my boat and given me wings. Thank
rocked my boat and given me wings. Thank you so much.
you so much.
you so much. >> Oh, very nice of you to say such a nice
>> Oh, very nice of you to say such a nice
>> Oh, very nice of you to say such a nice thing. Thank you so much.
thing. Thank you so much.
thing. Thank you so much. >> Okay. Thank you so much
>> Okay. Thank you so much
>> Okay. Thank you so much >> and thank you Susan for encourage me to
>> and thank you Susan for encourage me to
>> and thank you Susan for encourage me to uh
uh
uh >> thank you
>> thank you
>> thank you >> to do this.
>> to do this.
>> to do this. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> That's lovely.
>> That's lovely.
>> That's lovely. >> That's how it propagates down through
>> That's how it propagates down through
>> That's how it propagates down through the stages.
the stages.
the stages. Isn't that nice?
Very nice.
Very nice. >> Hello.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. I came to you and I asked you uh with
I came to you and I asked you uh with
I came to you and I asked you uh with regards to my daughter's health
regards to my daughter's health
regards to my daughter's health if there was hope.
if there was hope.
if there was hope. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Dr. Hawkins,
>> Dr. Hawkins,
>> Dr. Hawkins, I have been given so much hope. Um
I have been given so much hope. Um
I have been given so much hope. Um she went from worshiping the devil. She
she went from worshiping the devil. She
she went from worshiping the devil. She was an atheist and didn't think anything
was an atheist and didn't think anything
was an atheist and didn't think anything of taking her life for my own. And her
of taking her life for my own. And her
of taking her life for my own. And her ideal and her dream in life was to grow
ideal and her dream in life was to grow
ideal and her dream in life was to grow up and marry Marilyn Manson, who was a
up and marry Marilyn Manson, who was a
up and marry Marilyn Manson, who was a well-known Satanist.
well-known Satanist.
well-known Satanist. >> Oh, yes.
>> Oh, yes.
>> Oh, yes. >> And be a burlesque stripper.
>> And be a burlesque stripper.
>> And be a burlesque stripper. >> And
>> And
>> And >> Exactly. La. So, as a mom, I was very
>> Exactly. La. So, as a mom, I was very
>> Exactly. La. So, as a mom, I was very devastated six months ago.
devastated six months ago.
devastated six months ago. >> But since she's been here and had the
>> But since she's been here and had the
>> But since she's been here and had the prayer of the group last week, she came
prayer of the group last week, she came
prayer of the group last week, she came to me and she said, "I want to go to
to me and she said, "I want to go to
to me and she said, "I want to go to college.
college.
college. I want to be a therapist like Dr.
I want to be a therapist like Dr.
I want to be a therapist like Dr. Hawkins and I want to help teenage
Hawkins and I want to help teenage
Hawkins and I want to help teenage children. And I said, "How do you think
children. And I said, "How do you think
children. And I said, "How do you think you're going to serve them?" She goes,
you're going to serve them?" She goes,
you're going to serve them?" She goes, "Look at all the tools that Dr. Hawkins
"Look at all the tools that Dr. Hawkins
"Look at all the tools that Dr. Hawkins has given me."
has given me."
has given me." She's never been left alone because
She's never been left alone because
She's never been left alone because she's been so unstable with her
she's been so unstable with her
she's been so unstable with her seizures. Dr. Hawkins, for the first
seizures. Dr. Hawkins, for the first
seizures. Dr. Hawkins, for the first time in her 17 years, she's apart from
time in her 17 years, she's apart from
time in her 17 years, she's apart from me, home alone in Texas.
me, home alone in Texas.
me, home alone in Texas. It has been miraculous that I'm here and
It has been miraculous that I'm here and
It has been miraculous that I'm here and she's experiencing a normal life without
she's experiencing a normal life without
she's experiencing a normal life without the lower astrials. And not only that,
the lower astrials. And not only that,
the lower astrials. And not only that, children are coming to her and they're
children are coming to her and they're
children are coming to her and they're telling her, "We see them too and our
telling her, "We see them too and our
telling her, "We see them too and our parents don't believe us." And she's
parents don't believe us." And she's
parents don't believe us." And she's teaching them how to pray.
teaching them how to pray.
teaching them how to pray. >> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> Like you taught her how to pray. And
>> Like you taught her how to pray. And
>> Like you taught her how to pray. And when she says, they ask me what they can
when she says, they ask me what they can
when she says, they ask me what they can do. And I tell them to do the course in
do. And I tell them to do the course in
do. And I tell them to do the course in miracles.
miracles.
miracles. >> Oh.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. >> To study Dr. Hawkins because he is my
>> To study Dr. Hawkins because he is my
>> To study Dr. Hawkins because he is my mom's teacher and he is my teacher. And
mom's teacher and he is my teacher. And
mom's teacher and he is my teacher. And even though the world's going to think
even though the world's going to think
even though the world's going to think you're a branch dividian because they
you're a branch dividian because they
you're a branch dividian because they think we're crazy, too. You have to be
think we're crazy, too. You have to be
think we're crazy, too. You have to be very careful who you tell it to because
very careful who you tell it to because
very careful who you tell it to because she tells the children this, but she
she tells the children this, but she
she tells the children this, but she says, "You can come to our house and you
says, "You can come to our house and you
says, "You can come to our house and you can pray and we'll pray together." And
can pray and we'll pray together." And
can pray and we'll pray together." And you just tell them, "In the name of
you just tell them, "In the name of
you just tell them, "In the name of Jesus Christ, I refuse you. I rebuke
Jesus Christ, I refuse you. I rebuke
Jesus Christ, I refuse you. I rebuke you." So, for the first time,
you." So, for the first time,
you." So, for the first time, I came to her and I said, "I'm going to
I came to her and I said, "I'm going to
I came to her and I said, "I'm going to leave you alone and I'm going to go see
leave you alone and I'm going to go see
leave you alone and I'm going to go see Dr. Hawkins." And she goes, "I was
Dr. Hawkins." And she goes, "I was
Dr. Hawkins." And she goes, "I was waiting for you to give up this
waiting for you to give up this
waiting for you to give up this attachment of leaving me, mom, cuz I'm
attachment of leaving me, mom, cuz I'm
attachment of leaving me, mom, cuz I'm not going to die."
not going to die."
not going to die." So I transcended past.
So I transcended past.
So I transcended past. >> So you're making great progress.
>> So you're making great progress.
>> So you're making great progress. >> I am making such great progress.
>> I am making such great progress.
>> I am making such great progress. >> You are doing fine with the whole team,
>> You are doing fine with the whole team,
>> You are doing fine with the whole team, you know.
So my path today, my daughter sent me
So my path today, my daughter sent me here. She goes, "You don't have to put
here. She goes, "You don't have to put
here. She goes, "You don't have to put me on my path. I'm there. Mom, you go
me on my path. I'm there. Mom, you go
me on my path. I'm there. Mom, you go take care of yours." So
take care of yours." So
take care of yours." So >> yeah,
>> yeah,
>> yeah, >> I have no questions for you. I simply
>> I have no questions for you. I simply
>> I have no questions for you. I simply wanted to share my gratitude with the
wanted to share my gratitude with the
wanted to share my gratitude with the group and I just wanted to know what
group and I just wanted to know what
group and I just wanted to know what it's like to be in your presence without
it's like to be in your presence without
it's like to be in your presence without so much despair. May I just sit here for
so much despair. May I just sit here for
so much despair. May I just sit here for a moment?
a moment?
a moment? >> Yes. Yes.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Yes. Yes. So all turns out for the best. Yes.
So all turns out for the best. Yes.
So all turns out for the best. Yes. >> Better than the best.
>> Better than the best.
>> Better than the best. I have a little Hawkins at home that's
I have a little Hawkins at home that's
I have a little Hawkins at home that's 17 that's like spreading the word of
17 that's like spreading the word of
17 that's like spreading the word of Hawkins.
Hawkins.
Hawkins. She is such a devoted to
She is such a devoted to
She is such a devoted to >> very good sweetheart. Very good.
>> very good sweetheart. Very good.
>> very good sweetheart. Very good. >> I sure that what you
>> I sure that what you
>> I sure that what you >> sherish are the principles and not the
>> sherish are the principles and not the
>> sherish are the principles and not the person through which which you heard the
person through which which you heard the
person through which which you heard the principles.
principles.
principles. >> She heard your voice above all else.
>> She heard your voice above all else.
>> She heard your voice above all else. >> All right.
>> All right.
>> All right. >> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Principles above personalities.
It's the principles, not the where you
It's the principles, not the where you heard him from.
>> It's a phase. Yeah.
>> It's a phase. Yeah. >> Oh, yeah.
>> Hi, Doc. Susan.
>> Hi, Doc. Susan. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Um, I just wanted to pray to you and and
Um, I just wanted to pray to you and and
Um, I just wanted to pray to you and and to God in your presence
to God in your presence
to God in your presence for um our unrelenting fixity of focus
for um our unrelenting fixity of focus
for um our unrelenting fixity of focus >> for what?
>> for what?
>> for what? >> For our unrelenting fixity of focus
>> For our unrelenting fixity of focus
>> For our unrelenting fixity of focus to surrender every thought and emotion
to surrender every thought and emotion
to surrender every thought and emotion to God like you did
to God like you did
to God like you did >> constantly surrendering. Yes. Yes.
>> constantly surrendering. Yes. Yes.
>> constantly surrendering. Yes. Yes. That's the quickest way.
That's the quickest way.
That's the quickest way. As it arises, you surrender it to God as
As it arises, you surrender it to God as
As it arises, you surrender it to God as it arises.
it arises.
it arises. Turn everything to over to God as it
Turn everything to over to God as it
Turn everything to over to God as it arises.
arises.
arises. Yes.
In the beginning, it's like valitional
In the beginning, it's like valitional and then it takes up a an energy of its
and then it takes up a an energy of its
and then it takes up a an energy of its own. It does it of its own.
own. It does it of its own.
own. It does it of its own. Everything automatically turns over.
Doc, I was just wondering if I may
Doc, I was just wondering if I may receive I think you call it diction,
receive I think you call it diction,
receive I think you call it diction, >> a transmission.
>> a transmission.
>> a transmission. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> I think you call it diction. I'm not
>> I think you call it diction. I'm not
>> I think you call it diction. I'm not sure of the correct term.
sure of the correct term.
sure of the correct term. >> Oh, it has no term.
>> Oh, it has no term.
>> Oh, it has no term. >> Has no term.
>> Has no term.
>> Has no term. >> Mhm. If I could sit before you and
>> Mhm. If I could sit before you and
>> Mhm. If I could sit before you and receive.
receive.
receive. >> It's your intention. Plus my intention.
Zap
Zap comes Diane. It travels on through time.
comes Diane. It travels on through time.
comes Diane. It travels on through time. See
your desire for that type of energy and
your desire for that type of energy and my desire to transmit it just
my desire to transmit it just
my desire to transmit it just and then it's it's happens.
and then it's it's happens.
and then it's it's happens. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Yeah. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Thank you. Thank you. >> This is wonderful.
>> This is wonderful.
>> This is wonderful. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Here's books. Look at that face.
>> Here's books. Look at that face.
>> Here's books. Look at that face. >> Oh my god. You're going to knock me out
>> Oh my god. You're going to knock me out
>> Oh my god. You're going to knock me out with that if you're careful.
with that if you're careful.
with that if you're careful. >> I know.
>> I know.
>> I know. >> I'll pass out. I'll pass right out of
>> I'll pass out. I'll pass right out of
>> I'll pass out. I'll pass right out of here.
here.
here. >> Fall out of the chair.
>> Such a cute little face.
>> Such a cute little face. >> Yeah.
Mhm.
Mhm. What you love is is lovingness and the
What you love is is lovingness and the
What you love is is lovingness and the expression of it.
expression of it.
expression of it. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yes. All right. We'll be done by then.
>> Yes. All right. We'll be done by then.
>> Yes. All right. We'll be done by then. We'll be done. Yes.
We'll be done. Yes.
We'll be done. Yes. >> Right. I got these three.
>> Right. I got these three.
>> Right. I got these three. >> We just keep moving right there, honey.
>> We just keep moving right there, honey.
>> We just keep moving right there, honey. That's ours. Okay.
That's ours. Okay.
That's ours. Okay. That's our stack of things.
That's our stack of things.
That's our stack of things. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Is this still writing? Yes, I think it
>> Is this still writing? Yes, I think it
>> Is this still writing? Yes, I think it is.
I just wanted to see if you could
I just wanted to see if you could elaborate a little bit on u what they
elaborate a little bit on u what they
elaborate a little bit on u what they had first spoken about about um
had first spoken about about um
had first spoken about about um surrendering everything but the yin
surrendering everything but the yin
surrendering everything but the yin posture that you had uh I've heard you
posture that you had uh I've heard you
posture that you had uh I've heard you speak about prior
speak about prior
speak about prior >> um just the being the
>> um just the being the
>> um just the being the >> that what about it.
>> that what about it.
>> that what about it. >> Um, just elaborate on it. I I mean I
>> Um, just elaborate on it. I I mean I
>> Um, just elaborate on it. I I mean I >> elaborating on it. How do I elaborate on
>> elaborating on it. How do I elaborate on
>> elaborating on it. How do I elaborate on it?
it?
it? >> It's unspeakable. I realize that, but uh
>> It's unspeakable. I realize that, but uh
>> It's unspeakable. I realize that, but uh >> it's a it's a mode of being.
>> it's a it's a mode of being.
>> it's a it's a mode of being. >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> that's it.
>> that's it.
>> that's it. It's a wordless mode,
It's a wordless mode,
It's a wordless mode, a style
a style
a style to be the receptive cup. You see
to be the receptive cup. You see
to be the receptive cup. You see to be the receptive cup the chalice
to be the receptive cup the chalice
to be the receptive cup the chalice into which the wisdom pours. See the
into which the wisdom pours. See the
into which the wisdom pours. See the function of the chalice
function of the chalice
function of the chalice is to receive
is to receive
is to receive divinity you know in whatever form it
divinity you know in whatever form it
divinity you know in whatever form it may be available at that time
may be available at that time
may be available at that time symbolically wine or whatever.
symbolically wine or whatever.
symbolically wine or whatever. >> Yeah. water, baptism of water,
>> Yeah. water, baptism of water,
>> Yeah. water, baptism of water, uh the wine of communion in whatever
uh the wine of communion in whatever
uh the wine of communion in whatever form it may exist at the time
form it may exist at the time
form it may exist at the time or the fishes and the loaves and the
or the fishes and the loaves and the
or the fishes and the loaves and the fishes in whatever way it may be
fishes in whatever way it may be
fishes in whatever way it may be profered at the time.
profered at the time.
profered at the time. >> Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. >> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> I'm sorry.
>> I'm sorry.
>> I'm sorry. Thank you.
>> Hello. Hello.
>> Hello. Hello. >> A couple of years ago, I started some
>> A couple of years ago, I started some
>> A couple of years ago, I started some training
training
training in a new modality and I put things on
in a new modality and I put things on
in a new modality and I put things on hold while I turn my focus onto my
hold while I turn my focus onto my
hold while I turn my focus onto my writing. And the training was with uh
writing. And the training was with uh
writing. And the training was with uh Dr. David Pessik who is a student and
Dr. David Pessik who is a student and
Dr. David Pessik who is a student and disciple of Bernard Jensen on iodology
disciple of Bernard Jensen on iodology
disciple of Bernard Jensen on iodology and Dr. Pessik calls it uh holistic
and Dr. Pessik calls it uh holistic
and Dr. Pessik calls it uh holistic idology now and recently I've been
idology now and recently I've been
idology now and recently I've been turning my focus on to reading a lot of
turning my focus on to reading a lot of
turning my focus on to reading a lot of books on neuroscience
books on neuroscience
books on neuroscience >> and neuros
>> and neuros
>> and neuros >> on neuroscience.
>> on neuroscience.
>> on neuroscience. >> Oh yeah. Okay. And I was thinking of uh
>> Oh yeah. Okay. And I was thinking of uh
>> Oh yeah. Okay. And I was thinking of uh the iris as a way as a non-invasive way
the iris as a way as a non-invasive way
the iris as a way as a non-invasive way to to uh get a shortcut to looking at
to to uh get a shortcut to looking at
to to uh get a shortcut to looking at what paths one can take to uh accelerate
what paths one can take to uh accelerate
what paths one can take to uh accelerate their path for to wellness.
their path for to wellness.
their path for to wellness. And so my question is
And so my question is
And so my question is uh is this a worthwhile direction to go
uh is this a worthwhile direction to go
uh is this a worthwhile direction to go and is it in my um calling to be part of
and is it in my um calling to be part of
and is it in my um calling to be part of my bag of tricks? We uh have permission
my bag of tricks? We uh have permission
my bag of tricks? We uh have permission as this. It would serve his highest good
as this. It would serve his highest good
as this. It would serve his highest good to follow ourology. Resist.
to follow ourology. Resist.
to follow ourology. Resist. >> Yes. Oh,
>> Yes. Oh,
>> Yes. Oh, >> thank you very much.
>> thank you very much.
>> thank you very much. >> Yeah, that sounds very interesting.
>> My name is Ben. Uh my name is Ben. My
>> My name is Ben. Uh my name is Ben. My father's here, too. Um, I just wanted to
father's here, too. Um, I just wanted to
father's here, too. Um, I just wanted to say that uh the words that you present
say that uh the words that you present
say that uh the words that you present in your teachings about the allness of
in your teachings about the allness of
in your teachings about the allness of divinity and its presence everywhere has
divinity and its presence everywhere has
divinity and its presence everywhere has changed all of our lives completely and
changed all of our lives completely and
changed all of our lives completely and will never be the same. And so I made
will never be the same. And so I made
will never be the same. And so I made this small picture as just a tiny token
this small picture as just a tiny token
this small picture as just a tiny token of my gratitude to both of you.
of my gratitude to both of you.
of my gratitude to both of you. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> That's a great gift.
>> That's a great gift. Let me see it. Can
>> That's a great gift. Let me see it. Can you see it?
you see it?
you see it? I don't know how to see it. Okay.
I don't know how to see it. Okay.
I don't know how to see it. Okay. I I can't see that. Well, no. Okay. It's
I I can't see that. Well, no. Okay. It's
I I can't see that. Well, no. Okay. It's some other time with light. Yeah.
Thank you.
Thank you. >> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Hello, Susan.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Hello, Susan.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Hello, Susan. >> Uh, first of all, my deepest gratitude
>> Uh, first of all, my deepest gratitude
>> Uh, first of all, my deepest gratitude and my love to you both for all that you
and my love to you both for all that you
and my love to you both for all that you have given us. Thank you. Thank you. Um,
have given us. Thank you. Thank you. Um,
have given us. Thank you. Thank you. Um, I wanted to ask a favor.
I wanted to ask a favor.
I wanted to ask a favor. I've been very blessed to attend some of
I've been very blessed to attend some of
I've been very blessed to attend some of your lectures where at the end you hold
your lectures where at the end you hold
your lectures where at the end you hold space. You hold a vibration of love and
space. You hold a vibration of love and
space. You hold a vibration of love and bless us with your gazing upon us and
bless us with your gazing upon us and
bless us with your gazing upon us and that has always moved me very deeply.
that has always moved me very deeply.
that has always moved me very deeply. And I would like to request that you do
And I would like to request that you do
And I would like to request that you do that for us at the end of our time
that for us at the end of our time
that for us at the end of our time today. if you could just take a few
today. if you could just take a few
today. if you could just take a few moments and hold that vibration.
moments and hold that vibration.
moments and hold that vibration. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Of love for all of us.
>> Of love for all of us.
>> Of love for all of us. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Thank you.
Dr. Hawkins, many people are attaching
Dr. Hawkins, many people are attaching importance to the date December 21st,
importance to the date December 21st,
importance to the date December 21st, 2012, similar to the harmonic
2012, similar to the harmonic
2012, similar to the harmonic convergence date in 1987.
convergence date in 1987.
convergence date in 1987. Do you have any suggestions for what we
Do you have any suggestions for what we
Do you have any suggestions for what we could do at this next state that looks
could do at this next state that looks
could do at this next state that looks like it could be another harmonic
like it could be another harmonic
like it could be another harmonic convergence type event since it seems
convergence type event since it seems
convergence type event since it seems like so many around the world will be
like so many around the world will be
like so many around the world will be gathering together to pray and meditate
gathering together to pray and meditate
gathering together to pray and meditate at the same time on that day?
at the same time on that day?
at the same time on that day? >> That date is the next harmonic
>> That date is the next harmonic
>> That date is the next harmonic convergence
convergence
convergence >> of of that type of event.
>> of of that type of event.
>> of of that type of event. >> It's the end of the world.
>> It's the end of the world.
>> It's the end of the world. >> But let's not mix let's not mix these
>> But let's not mix let's not mix these
>> But let's not mix let's not mix these things up. Harmonic convergence is one
things up. Harmonic convergence is one
things up. Harmonic convergence is one thing.
thing.
thing. >> I have to sign this because it didn't go
>> I have to sign this because it didn't go
>> I have to sign this because it didn't go through. I'm sorry. Do it one more time.
through. I'm sorry. Do it one more time.
through. I'm sorry. Do it one more time. >> Harmonic convergence is one thing. End
>> Harmonic convergence is one thing. End
>> Harmonic convergence is one thing. End of the world is something else.
>> 2012
>> 2012 is the end.
is the end.
is the end. >> December 21st, 2015 is the
>> December 21st, 2015 is the
>> December 21st, 2015 is the Mayan calendar, the end of a kalpa,
Mayan calendar, the end of a kalpa,
Mayan calendar, the end of a kalpa, which is a 56,000
which is a 56,000
which is a 56,000 year cycle.
year cycle.
year cycle. And uh is the world going to come to an
And uh is the world going to come to an
And uh is the world going to come to an end at that time? The answer is no.
end at that time? The answer is no.
end at that time? The answer is no. >> Let's say although it won't come to an
>> Let's say although it won't come to an
>> Let's say although it won't come to an end since so many people are gathering
end since so many people are gathering
end since so many people are gathering to pray and meditate.
to pray and meditate.
to pray and meditate. >> It's not going to come to an end without
>> It's not going to come to an end without
>> It's not going to come to an end without the people. They can stay home and the
the people. They can stay home and the
the people. They can stay home and the world's not going to come to an end.
world's not going to come to an end.
world's not going to come to an end. >> Okay. Um
>> Okay. Um
>> Okay. Um >> but he's saying that the saying the
>> but he's saying that the saying the
>> but he's saying that the saying the plants are lining up again.
plants are lining up again.
plants are lining up again. >> No, that's something different. That's
>> No, that's something different. That's
>> No, that's something different. That's not the end of the world is one thing.
not the end of the world is one thing.
not the end of the world is one thing. Harmonic convergence is another. They're
Harmonic convergence is another. They're
Harmonic convergence is another. They're not identical. Yeah.
not identical. Yeah.
not identical. Yeah. >> Let's say just the idea that many will
>> Let's say just the idea that many will
>> Let's say just the idea that many will be gathering together to pray and
be gathering together to pray and
be gathering together to pray and meditate.
meditate.
meditate. >> That's always wonderful. Yes.
>> That's always wonderful. Yes.
>> That's always wonderful. Yes. >> You don't suggest kind of passing the
>> You don't suggest kind of passing the
>> You don't suggest kind of passing the word around so more people may pray and
word around so more people may pray and
word around so more people may pray and meditate at that time.
meditate at that time.
meditate at that time. >> I don't want to control things.
If if the world is destined to come to
If if the world is destined to come to an end on 2015, so the world comes to an
an end on 2015, so the world comes to an
an end on 2015, so the world comes to an end in 2015, what's the problem?
>> If it all ends December 21st, 2005 or
>> If it all ends December 21st, 2005 or 200, whatever
200, whatever
200, whatever >> they're called mint bliss.
>> they're called mint bliss.
>> they're called mint bliss. >> Couldn't be 2005 or we'd be gone
>> Couldn't be 2005 or we'd be gone
>> Couldn't be 2005 or we'd be gone already.
already.
already. 2025 2015 that made a difference.
2025 2015 that made a difference.
2025 2015 that made a difference. >> Well, if
>> Well, if
>> Well, if >> the world comes to an end, goodbye.
>> the world comes to an end, goodbye.
>> the world comes to an end, goodbye. >> If you're spiritual, if you're
>> If you're spiritual, if you're
>> If you're spiritual, if you're spiritually align, what difference would
spiritually align, what difference would
spiritually align, what difference would it make it comes to end or not?
it make it comes to end or not?
it make it comes to end or not? >> It doesn't. That's what you're saying.
>> It doesn't. That's what you're saying.
>> It doesn't. That's what you're saying. What difference does it make?
What difference does it make?
What difference does it make? >> You're going to go sooner or later. So,
>> You're going to go sooner or later. So,
>> You're going to go sooner or later. So, why not now, you know?
why not now, you know?
why not now, you know? >> Right. Um, doc, you know, I I really
>> Right. Um, doc, you know, I I really
>> Right. Um, doc, you know, I I really appreciate it. You talk about guilt. Um,
appreciate it. You talk about guilt. Um,
appreciate it. You talk about guilt. Um, and when you were talking about
and when you were talking about
and when you were talking about unconscious guilt, I just realized it
unconscious guilt, I just realized it
unconscious guilt, I just realized it was like a huge flash that I have a lot
was like a huge flash that I have a lot
was like a huge flash that I have a lot of unconscious guilt.
of unconscious guilt.
of unconscious guilt. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And I put myself in these situations
>> And I put myself in these situations
>> And I put myself in these situations where you said it'll bring up to I don't
where you said it'll bring up to I don't
where you said it'll bring up to I don't know. I just put myself in these weird
know. I just put myself in these weird
know. I just put myself in these weird situations. Um, so I was wondering how
situations. Um, so I was wondering how
situations. Um, so I was wondering how how do I bring up that unconscious guilt
how do I bring up that unconscious guilt
how do I bring up that unconscious guilt to be conscious so I can clear it so I
to be conscious so I can clear it so I
to be conscious so I can clear it so I don't have to put myself through these
don't have to put myself through these
don't have to put myself through these situations?
situations?
situations? >> It comes up uh if you ask for it.
>> It comes up uh if you ask for it.
>> It comes up uh if you ask for it. >> Also, you can do it through therapy.
>> Also, you can do it through therapy.
>> Also, you can do it through therapy. Also you can do it by clearing levels of
Also you can do it by clearing levels of
Also you can do it by clearing levels of energy and as you clear them uh
energy and as you clear them uh
energy and as you clear them uh karmically the next level comes up
karmically the next level comes up
karmically the next level comes up >> you know
>> you know
>> you know >> um yeah
>> um yeah
>> um yeah >> you don't have to force it just your
>> you don't have to force it just your
>> you don't have to force it just your intention to clear your karma is enough
intention to clear your karma is enough
intention to clear your karma is enough to already start it coming up
to already start it coming up
to already start it coming up >> okay um because I feel a lot of um
>> okay um because I feel a lot of um
>> okay um because I feel a lot of um energy in my heart chakra is that is
energy in my heart chakra is that is
energy in my heart chakra is that is that what's going on is that clearing
that what's going on is that clearing
that what's going on is that clearing >> I would guess so yeah
>> I would guess so yeah
>> I would guess so yeah >> yeah okay
>> yeah okay
>> yeah okay >> I would guess so
>> I would guess so
>> I would guess so >> thank you very much Okay.
>> I forget when the world's supposed to
>> I forget when the world's supposed to end. December 21st.
end. December 21st.
end. December 21st. >> 2012.
>> 2012.
>> 2012. >> 2012 or 2015?
>> 2012 or 2015?
>> 2012 or 2015? >> No. 2012.
>> No. 2012.
>> No. 2012. >> 2012.
>> 2012.
>> 2012. >> 2012.
>> 2012. >> Well, we better pay up the mortgage,
>> Well, we better pay up the mortgage,
>> Well, we better pay up the mortgage, right?
right?
right? >> No. We may not know.
>> No. We may not know.
>> No. We may not know. >> That's right. You won't know anything.
>> I am 15 weeks pregnant.
>> I am 15 weeks pregnant. And I came today, thank you. I came
And I came today, thank you. I came
And I came today, thank you. I came today because I wanted my baby to have
today because I wanted my baby to have
today because I wanted my baby to have the opportunity to be in your presence.
the opportunity to be in your presence.
the opportunity to be in your presence. And as
>> right here,
>> right here, >> playing music.
>> playing music.
>> playing music. >> I know. I know. It's like playing
>> I know. I know. It's like playing
>> I know. I know. It's like playing classical music.
classical music.
classical music. >> So, as a new mom to be, um, one of my
>> So, as a new mom to be, um, one of my
>> So, as a new mom to be, um, one of my concerns is autism.
concerns is autism.
concerns is autism. So, I was wondering what is the linear
So, I was wondering what is the linear
So, I was wondering what is the linear cause of autism and then what is the
cause of autism and then what is the
cause of autism and then what is the spiritual purpose of autism?
spiritual purpose of autism?
spiritual purpose of autism? >> I don't know what the linear cause. I
>> I don't know what the linear cause. I
>> I don't know what the linear cause. I don't know that it falls into cause and
don't know that it falls into cause and
don't know that it falls into cause and I haven't kept up on the most recent
I haven't kept up on the most recent
I haven't kept up on the most recent research on autism. You know, it's
research on autism. You know, it's
research on autism. You know, it's genetic uh predisposition and all.
genetic uh predisposition and all.
genetic uh predisposition and all. Uh so I can't give you anything
Uh so I can't give you anything
Uh so I can't give you anything authoritative on autism uh from a
authoritative on autism uh from a
authoritative on autism uh from a scientific viewpoint
>> if it is appropriate. Would you bless
>> if it is appropriate. Would you bless the baby?
the baby?
the baby? >> If it's permitted.
>> If it's permitted.
>> If it's permitted. It's permitted uh to uh bless this baby.
It's permitted uh to uh bless this baby.
It's permitted uh to uh bless this baby. Resist.
Resist.
Resist. So
So
So by consent we all bless this baby in the
by consent we all bless this baby in the
by consent we all bless this baby in the name of the Lord. Amen.
name of the Lord. Amen.
name of the Lord. Amen. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Amen.
>> That was cute. I've never had an unborn
>> That was cute. I've never had an unborn baby. That was it.
baby. That was it.
baby. That was it. >> Hi Dr. Hawkins. Hi Susan. Hi. Uh, no
>> Hi Dr. Hawkins. Hi Susan. Hi. Uh, no
>> Hi Dr. Hawkins. Hi Susan. Hi. Uh, no questions. Thank you very much. Really
questions. Thank you very much. Really
questions. Thank you very much. Really grateful for her teachings.
grateful for her teachings.
grateful for her teachings. Uh, life is great.
And here the world's going to come to an
And here the world's going to come to an end.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. >> All right. The world, let me ask the
>> All right. The world, let me ask the
>> All right. The world, let me ask the question. The world's going to come to
question. The world's going to come to
question. The world's going to come to an end on that prescribed date. Resist.
We've done that so many times.
We've done that so many times. >> Keep paying the mortgage, you know.
>> Keep paying the mortgage, you know.
>> Keep paying the mortgage, you know. We've asked that over and over.
We've asked that over and over.
We've asked that over and over. >> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Uh doomsday forecasts have been a
>> Uh doomsday forecasts have been a recurrent throughout history. You know,
recurrent throughout history. You know,
recurrent throughout history. You know, the book of Revelations, all of it. It
the book of Revelations, all of it. It
the book of Revelations, all of it. It always calibrates as negative.
always calibrates as negative.
always calibrates as negative. >> Hello.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. >> Yes. I am just here to thank you again
>> Yes. I am just here to thank you again
>> Yes. I am just here to thank you again for your blessings and express my
for your blessings and express my
for your blessings and express my gratitude for the love that you given to
gratitude for the love that you given to
gratitude for the love that you given to us and also I'm so glad to see all these
us and also I'm so glad to see all these
us and also I'm so glad to see all these people here
people here
people here >> who I always feel good to be with.
>> who I always feel good to be with.
>> who I always feel good to be with. >> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Yeah, it's good to see you. Yes.
>> Yes. Um it seems that there's a high
>> Yes. Um it seems that there's a high powerlessness or lack of control over
powerlessness or lack of control over
powerlessness or lack of control over thoughts and deeds.
thoughts and deeds.
thoughts and deeds. >> Over what?
>> Over what?
>> Over what? >> Thoughts and deeds. There's a lack of
>> Thoughts and deeds. There's a lack of
>> Thoughts and deeds. There's a lack of control over thoughts and deeds.
control over thoughts and deeds.
control over thoughts and deeds. >> And um the question is um you also said
>> And um the question is um you also said
>> And um the question is um you also said um everybody's accountable for their
um everybody's accountable for their
um everybody's accountable for their thoughts and deeds.
thoughts and deeds.
thoughts and deeds. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Well um
>> Well um
>> Well um >> you have limited control over it.
>> you have limited control over it.
>> you have limited control over it. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You have options
>> You have options
>> You have options also. You have the option to reject it.
And let's say if somebody surrenders
And let's say if somebody surrenders everything as it arises then the
everything as it arises then the
everything as it arises then the intention itself would be surrendered
intention itself would be surrendered
intention itself would be surrendered then there would be no int intention
then there would be no int intention
then there would be no int intention left but what would be then the karma
left but what would be then the karma
left but what would be then the karma >> it's a complex question he's mixing
>> it's a complex question he's mixing
>> it's a complex question he's mixing things
things
things >> you're mixing things
>> you're mixing things
>> you're mixing things >> if I
>> if I
>> if I >> make it a simple question simple
>> make it a simple question simple
>> make it a simple question simple >> if I give up intention
>> if I give up intention
>> if I give up intention if I give up intention like surrender
if I give up intention like surrender
if I give up intention like surrender everything as it arises.
everything as it arises.
everything as it arises. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Um, what would be the karmic consequence
>> Um, what would be the karmic consequence
>> Um, what would be the karmic consequence of the deeds that
of the deeds that
of the deeds that >> What would be the karmic consequence of
>> What would be the karmic consequence of
>> What would be the karmic consequence of what
what
what >> deeds
>> deeds
>> deeds >> or the thoughts? Mhm.
>> or the thoughts? Mhm.
>> or the thoughts? Mhm. >> I don't understand.
>> I don't understand.
>> I don't understand. >> Thoughts or whatever.
>> Thoughts or whatever.
>> Thoughts or whatever. >> Thoughts or or deeds?
>> Thoughts or or deeds?
>> Thoughts or or deeds? >> The question doesn't make sense.
>> The question doesn't make sense.
>> The question doesn't make sense. >> There wouldn't be any any deeds.
>> There wouldn't be any any deeds.
>> There wouldn't be any any deeds. >> If you're giving every everything as it
>> If you're giving every everything as it
>> If you're giving every everything as it arises, there wouldn't be any
arises, there wouldn't be any
arises, there wouldn't be any >> there are no deeds. But the body would
>> there are no deeds. But the body would
>> there are no deeds. But the body would still
still
still >> do it deeds spontaneously.
>> do it deeds spontaneously.
>> do it deeds spontaneously. >> What would happen? Would the body do the
>> What would happen? Would the body do the
>> What would happen? Would the body do the deeds spontaneously?
deeds spontaneously?
deeds spontaneously? >> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. >> But there would be no karmic
>> But there would be no karmic
>> But there would be no karmic consequences.
consequences.
consequences. >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> The animal has no karmic consequences.
>> The animal has no karmic consequences.
>> The animal has no karmic consequences. >> Has it?
>> Has it?
>> Has it? >> I hope I understand your question. It's
>> I hope I understand your question. It's
>> I hope I understand your question. It's very complicated.
very complicated.
very complicated. >> I think
>> I think
>> I think >> presenting it. So I don't know if
>> presenting it. So I don't know if
>> presenting it. So I don't know if >> I think I understand. Once there's no
>> I think I understand. Once there's no
>> I think I understand. Once there's no intention, there's no karma.
intention, there's no karma.
intention, there's no karma. >> Is there Once there's no intention, is
>> Is there Once there's no intention, is
>> Is there Once there's no intention, is there no karma?
there no karma?
there no karma? >> I wouldn't be that broad about it. It's
>> I wouldn't be that broad about it. It's
>> I wouldn't be that broad about it. It's a different karma.
a different karma.
a different karma. It's a different kind of karma. You
It's a different kind of karma. You
It's a different kind of karma. You might say karma comes in different
might say karma comes in different
might say karma comes in different flavors.
flavors.
flavors. >> Lemon, lime, vanilla, chocolate. You
>> Lemon, lime, vanilla, chocolate. You
>> Lemon, lime, vanilla, chocolate. You know,
know,
know, >> um I've been also asked to ask you for
>> um I've been also asked to ask you for
>> um I've been also asked to ask you for an M.
an M.
an M. >> They want a M from you.
>> They want a M from you.
>> They want a M from you. >> M.
>> M.
>> M. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> M who?
>> M who?
>> M who? >> Um I don't know.
>> About 2,500 years old.
>> About 2,500 years old. >> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. >> Older than that.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Okay, we're playing.
Okay, we're playing.
Okay, we're playing. >> Dr. Hawkins, thank you so much for your
>> Dr. Hawkins, thank you so much for your
>> Dr. Hawkins, thank you so much for your work.
spiritual ambition
spiritual ambition and
and
and willfulness and spiritual ambition.
willfulness and spiritual ambition.
willfulness and spiritual ambition. >> How can you surrender spiritual
>> How can you surrender spiritual
>> How can you surrender spiritual ambition?
ambition?
ambition? Don't surrender to the end.
>> Like making money, don't surrender it
>> Like making money, don't surrender it until you're rich.
uh it it will come to you when spiritual
uh it it will come to you when spiritual ambition is is has become an impediment
ambition is is has become an impediment
ambition is is has become an impediment when it's an expression of spiritual ego
when it's an expression of spiritual ego
when it's an expression of spiritual ego but it requires a certain maturity to
but it requires a certain maturity to
but it requires a certain maturity to even contemplate the the problem
even contemplate the the problem
even contemplate the the problem and so I wouldn't push it you know ask
and so I wouldn't push it you know ask
and so I wouldn't push it you know ask uh the Holy Spirit for for an
uh the Holy Spirit for for an
uh the Holy Spirit for for an understanding of it that you can have
understanding of it that you can have
understanding of it that you can have spiritual orientation without spiritual
spiritual orientation without spiritual
spiritual orientation without spiritual ambition necessarily. So you're talking
ambition necessarily. So you're talking
ambition necessarily. So you're talking about
about
about uh surrendering the spiritual ego. You
uh surrendering the spiritual ego. You
uh surrendering the spiritual ego. You know you can surrender your spiritual
know you can surrender your spiritual
know you can surrender your spiritual evolution and the rate of it and the
evolution and the rate of it and the
evolution and the rate of it and the characteristics of it to to God.
characteristics of it to to God.
characteristics of it to to God. That's not difficult.
That's not difficult.
That's not difficult. That's easy.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. >> Yeah.
Yes. He wants to circumvent spiritual
Yes. He wants to circumvent spiritual ego.
ego.
ego. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Hello.
Hello.
Hello. >> Hi. Hi, precious.
>> Hi. Hi, precious.
>> Hi. Hi, precious. >> Yes. Mhm.
>> Yes. Mhm.
>> Yes. Mhm. I want to thank you for
being with me always these four and a
being with me always these four and a half years. You just never ever left my
half years. You just never ever left my
half years. You just never ever left my side through it all. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you. >> Um Doc, with the advent of
>> Um Doc, with the advent of
>> Um Doc, with the advent of Homosspiritus,
Homosspiritus,
Homosspiritus, is consciousness evolving another
is consciousness evolving another
is consciousness evolving another spiritual body.
>> Get the question.
>> Get the question. >> Say it one more time.
>> Say it one more time.
>> Say it one more time. >> The advent of
>> The advent of
>> The advent of >> homospiritus.
>> homospiritus.
>> homospiritus. >> So with the advent of homosspiritis,
>> So with the advent of homosspiritis,
>> So with the advent of homosspiritis, >> yes, man becomes evol as evolutionary
>> yes, man becomes evol as evolutionary
>> yes, man becomes evol as evolutionary development,
development,
development, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> He develops spiritual awareness and then
>> He develops spiritual awareness and then
>> He develops spiritual awareness and then the condolini energy comes up. It
the condolini energy comes up. It
the condolini energy comes up. It activates the spiritual energy. Yes. And
activates the spiritual energy. Yes. And
activates the spiritual energy. Yes. And then what? So that's the birth of a new
then what? So that's the birth of a new
then what? So that's the birth of a new being. Same body, same appearance, but
being. Same body, same appearance, but
being. Same body, same appearance, but quite a different being.
quite a different being.
quite a different being. >> Is there another spiritual body with
>> Is there another spiritual body with
>> Is there another spiritual body with that?
that?
that? >> You're talking about the etheric body?
>> You're talking about the etheric body?
>> You're talking about the etheric body? >> No. Uh like the Buddha atmic.
>> No. Uh like the Buddha atmic.
>> No. Uh like the Buddha atmic. >> Huh?
>> Huh?
>> Huh? like the Buddha body at
like the Buddha body at
like the Buddha body at >> Buddhic body.
>> Buddhic body.
>> Buddhic body. >> Oh. Oh, you're talking about the levels
>> Oh. Oh, you're talking about the levels
>> Oh. Oh, you're talking about the levels the Yeah. Uh yes. E each um development
the Yeah. Uh yes. E each um development
the Yeah. Uh yes. E each um development spiritually awakens higher chakras.
spiritually awakens higher chakras.
spiritually awakens higher chakras. Yeah. I forget how many there is above
Yeah. I forget how many there is above
Yeah. I forget how many there is above the crown chakra. Five, seven, I forget
the crown chakra. Five, seven, I forget
the crown chakra. Five, seven, I forget already.
already.
already. Essenteric psychology. Mhm.
Essenteric psychology. Mhm.
Essenteric psychology. Mhm. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> I'm so grateful.
>> I'm so grateful.
>> I'm so grateful. I forget the names of all those various
I forget the names of all those various
I forget the names of all those various spiritual bodies above the
spiritual bodies above the
spiritual bodies above the above the crown chakra.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Tripping everybody.
>> Tripping everybody.
>> Tripping everybody. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Hi Dr. Hawkins. Hi Susan. Hi.
>> Hi Dr. Hawkins. Hi Susan. Hi.
>> Hi Dr. Hawkins. Hi Susan. Hi. >> Hi. Um, I I wanted to thank you for uh
>> Hi. Um, I I wanted to thank you for uh
>> Hi. Um, I I wanted to thank you for uh for for everything and thank you for
for for everything and thank you for
for for everything and thank you for sharing between the two of you again
sharing between the two of you again
sharing between the two of you again today. It's very um precious to me. And
today. It's very um precious to me. And
today. It's very um precious to me. And Susan, I wonder if if you would sign
Susan, I wonder if if you would sign
Susan, I wonder if if you would sign those for me.
those for me.
those for me. >> What?
Oh, you got to sign them. Oh, they're
Oh, you got to sign them. Oh, they're very pretty. Very pretty, aren't they?
very pretty. Very pretty, aren't they?
very pretty. Very pretty, aren't they? Those are very good shots.
Those are very good shots.
Those are very good shots. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> And um I'd like to share my gratitude um
>> And um I'd like to share my gratitude um
>> And um I'd like to share my gratitude um for you, Susan, too, and and all your
for you, Susan, too, and and all your
for you, Susan, too, and and all your wonderful work um
wonderful work um
wonderful work um your um
in living form here and in my presence.
in living form here and in my presence. Thank you.
And um I would like to ask if we um
And um I would like to ask if we um could all um speak Gloria and Excelsius
could all um speak Gloria and Excelsius
could all um speak Gloria and Excelsius Dio.
Dio.
Dio. >> I can't together.
>> I can't together.
>> I can't together. >> She sing.
>> She sing.
>> She sing. >> She wants us all to say Gloria and
>> She wants us all to say Gloria and
>> She wants us all to say Gloria and Excel.
Excel.
Excel. >> Well, you want us all to say it.
>> Well, you want us all to say it.
>> Well, you want us all to say it. in honor of God.
in honor of God.
in honor of God. >> In honor of divinity
>> In honor of divinity
>> In honor of divinity >> and devotion to divinity.
>> and devotion to divinity.
>> and devotion to divinity. >> I don't get it. But
>> I don't get it. But
>> I don't get it. But >> she wouldn't just say it as unity.
>> she wouldn't just say it as unity.
>> she wouldn't just say it as unity. >> Oh,
>> Oh,
>> Oh, >> we'll do that at the end. We're going to
>> we'll do that at the end. We're going to
>> we'll do that at the end. We're going to >> We want to shake everyone's hand and
>> We want to shake everyone's hand and
>> We want to shake everyone's hand and everything. So, we'll do that as a
everything. So, we'll do that as a
everything. So, we'll do that as a closing.
closing.
closing. >> Yeah, we'll do that at the end. Okay.
>> Yeah, we'll do that at the end. Okay.
>> Yeah, we'll do that at the end. Okay. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> Thank you. Thank you, Dr.
>> Thank you. Thank you, Dr.
>> Thank you. Thank you, Dr. When you say glory to God in the
When you say glory to God in the
When you say glory to God in the highest, all the ne all the demons leave
highest, all the ne all the demons leave
highest, all the ne all the demons leave the room.
the room.
the room. Any demons still hanging out?
Any demons still hanging out?
Any demons still hanging out? No. God, don't go in that place. They're
No. God, don't go in that place. They're
No. God, don't go in that place. They're telling each other all around out there.
telling each other all around out there.
telling each other all around out there. Do not go in that auditorium.
Do not go in that auditorium.
Do not go in that auditorium. >> Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. >> You'll be liquefied, evaporated. And
>> You'll be liquefied, evaporated. And
>> You'll be liquefied, evaporated. And >> okay, now we have 10 minutes to five.
>> okay, now we have 10 minutes to five.
>> okay, now we have 10 minutes to five. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Have to shake hands. Well, we better
>> Have to shake hands. Well, we better
>> Have to shake hands. Well, we better start checking in now.
start checking in now.
start checking in now. >> Well, pretty soon.
>> Well, pretty soon.
>> Well, pretty soon. >> All right. You got to run faster.
>> All right. You got to run faster.
>> All right. You got to run faster. >> Speak loudly and clearly into the
>> Speak loudly and clearly into the
>> Speak loudly and clearly into the microphone.
microphone.
microphone. >> Is it all right for me to use a pendulum
>> Is it all right for me to use a pendulum
>> Is it all right for me to use a pendulum to test for truth?
to test for truth?
to test for truth? >> Is it all right for me to what?
>> Is it all right for me to what?
>> Is it all right for me to what? >> To use a pendulum.
>> To use a pendulum.
>> To use a pendulum. >> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. >> Yeah. Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Okay. Thank you. >> Yeah. It's no,
>> Yeah. It's no,
>> Yeah. It's no, >> you know, if you really want something
>> you know, if you really want something
>> you know, if you really want something though important, you want to check, I
though important, you want to check, I
though important, you want to check, I would do it with someone else.
would do it with someone else.
would do it with someone else. >> Someone else. Okay. Thank you.
>> Someone else. Okay. Thank you.
>> Someone else. Okay. Thank you. >> You can do little things.
>> You can do little things.
>> You can do little things. Don't don't dow negative things to see
Don't don't dow negative things to see
Don't don't dow negative things to see how far down in hell you can go with it.
how far down in hell you can go with it.
how far down in hell you can go with it. >> Stay in the positive.
>> Stay in the positive.
>> Stay in the positive. >> Hi Susan.
>> Hi Susan.
>> Hi Susan. >> Stay in the positive dimension which
>> Stay in the positive dimension which
>> Stay in the positive dimension which you're going to be using that technique.
you're going to be using that technique.
you're going to be using that technique. Stay just with that which is positive.
Stay just with that which is positive.
Stay just with that which is positive. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Hi Doc.
>> Hi Doc.
>> Hi Doc. >> I just wanted to get up here and thank
>> I just wanted to get up here and thank
>> I just wanted to get up here and thank you as well because I've been coming
you as well because I've been coming
you as well because I've been coming down here for five years now from
down here for five years now from
down here for five years now from Toronto.
Toronto.
Toronto. >> Yep. and it's been absolutely
>> Yep. and it's been absolutely
>> Yep. and it's been absolutely outstanding. Uh when when I attended my
outstanding. Uh when when I attended my
outstanding. Uh when when I attended my first lecture, you suggested that there
first lecture, you suggested that there
first lecture, you suggested that there would be
would be
would be >> ups and downs associated with this path.
>> ups and downs associated with this path.
>> ups and downs associated with this path. And boy, that was an understatement. But
And boy, that was an understatement. But
And boy, that was an understatement. But boy, the the profound changes that have
boy, the the profound changes that have
boy, the the profound changes that have happened to me and those that within my
happened to me and those that within my
happened to me and those that within my family because of the changes that have
family because of the changes that have
family because of the changes that have been wrought upon me, I've just been so
been wrought upon me, I've just been so
been wrought upon me, I've just been so amazing and I'm just so incredibly
amazing and I'm just so incredibly
amazing and I'm just so incredibly grateful for being here and thank you
grateful for being here and thank you
grateful for being here and thank you because your presence brings forth
because your presence brings forth
because your presence brings forth things in us that would not come forth
things in us that would not come forth
things in us that would not come forth were it not for you.
were it not for you.
were it not for you. >> Well, thank you.
>> Well, thank you.
>> Well, thank you. >> And of course, we also had a chance to
>> And of course, we also had a chance to
>> And of course, we also had a chance to visit Toronto and go underneath the
visit Toronto and go underneath the
visit Toronto and go underneath the Great Falls there and had a wondrous
Great Falls there and had a wondrous
Great Falls there and had a wondrous time.
time.
time. >> Yes. And of course, he being the being
>> Yes. And of course, he being the being
>> Yes. And of course, he being the being the sort of rascal he was, he got he got
the sort of rascal he was, he got he got
the sort of rascal he was, he got he got in trouble with the security guard and
in trouble with the security guard and
in trouble with the security guard and the security guard had to bring him back
the security guard had to bring him back
the security guard had to bring him back to us, too. So that that was a fun
to us, too. So that that was a fun
to us, too. So that that was a fun experience.
experience.
experience. His inner child is still active for
His inner child is still active for
His inner child is still active for sure.
sure.
sure. >> Oh yeah, that's right. My inner child
>> Oh yeah, that's right. My inner child
>> Oh yeah, that's right. My inner child got away with it.
got away with it.
got away with it. >> Now I do have one question because a
>> Now I do have one question because a
>> Now I do have one question because a number of people in this lecture and
number of people in this lecture and
number of people in this lecture and others have come up and asked you for uh
others have come up and asked you for uh
others have come up and asked you for uh the blessing or the grace or the
the blessing or the grace or the
the blessing or the grace or the transmission and to hold your hand. Now
transmission and to hold your hand. Now
transmission and to hold your hand. Now is it absolutely necessary for them to
is it absolutely necessary for them to
is it absolutely necessary for them to do that here or by actually asking
do that here or by actually asking
do that here or by actually asking silently in the audience uh is that does
silently in the audience uh is that does
silently in the audience uh is that does that suffice or should everyone come up
that suffice or should everyone come up
that suffice or should everyone come up here and uh
here and uh
here and uh >> if they so desire and ask that question
>> if they so desire and ask that question
>> if they so desire and ask that question let's see
let's see
let's see >> the silent transmission
>> the silent transmission
>> the silent transmission does not require physicality resist does
does not require physicality resist does
does not require physicality resist does not require physicality
not require physicality
not require physicality >> okay
>> okay
>> okay Um
Um
Um the transmission is silent
and to merely be here already
and to merely be here already accomplishes the desired end resist.
accomplishes the desired end resist.
accomplishes the desired end resist. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> The the vibration of any great teacher
>> The the vibration of any great teacher
>> The the vibration of any great teacher that I visited throughout many lifetimes
that I visited throughout many lifetimes
that I visited throughout many lifetimes was already present in this lifetime.
was already present in this lifetime.
was already present in this lifetime. So the advanced states that I reached at
So the advanced states that I reached at
So the advanced states that I reached at age three or age 12 etc which is unusual
age three or age 12 etc which is unusual
age three or age 12 etc which is unusual at such ages was a consequence of those
at such ages was a consequence of those
at such ages was a consequence of those uh that I picked up from great gurus in
uh that I picked up from great gurus in
uh that I picked up from great gurus in past lives resist I' never asked that
past lives resist I' never asked that
past lives resist I' never asked that before. Yeshu
before. Yeshu
before. Yeshu so the same with this group here will
so the same with this group here will
so the same with this group here will last throughout many lifetimes you know.
last throughout many lifetimes you know.
last throughout many lifetimes you know. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> It's a permanent imprint.
>> It's a permanent imprint.
>> It's a permanent imprint. >> Yes. Okay. Well, thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Uh my name is Kiran
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Uh my name is Kiran
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins. Uh my name is Kiran from I'm from New Jersey.
from I'm from New Jersey.
from I'm from New Jersey. Um I have decided uh to uh
Um I have decided uh to uh
Um I have decided uh to uh uh be on the spiritual path for this
uh be on the spiritual path for this
uh be on the spiritual path for this life.
life.
life. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> What is your advice for me?
>> You've already chosen the spiritual
>> You've already chosen the spiritual path. Now uh you pick out some teachers.
path. Now uh you pick out some teachers.
path. Now uh you pick out some teachers. As you read through through some various
As you read through through some various
As you read through through some various teachers and see who attracts you, who
teachers and see who attracts you, who
teachers and see who attracts you, who you feel like you resonate to,
you feel like you resonate to,
you feel like you resonate to, feel familiar with, um
feel familiar with, um
feel familiar with, um that you enjoy, teachers who you enjoy,
that you enjoy, teachers who you enjoy,
that you enjoy, teachers who you enjoy, who you intuitit their integrity, and uh
who you intuitit their integrity, and uh
who you intuitit their integrity, and uh that you would be willing to be devoted
that you would be willing to be devoted
that you would be willing to be devoted to in an ashram, let's say.
to in an ashram, let's say.
to in an ashram, let's say. So certain figures would appeal to you,
So certain figures would appeal to you,
So certain figures would appeal to you, others would not.
others would not.
others would not. >> Yes,
>> Yes,
>> Yes, >> there's many karmic propensities that
>> there's many karmic propensities that
>> there's many karmic propensities that you cannot explain.
you cannot explain.
you cannot explain. See, like Ramana Maharshi would appeal
See, like Ramana Maharshi would appeal
See, like Ramana Maharshi would appeal to certain people. Being a Hindu
to certain people. Being a Hindu
to certain people. Being a Hindu aesthetic doesn't appeal to me now. At
aesthetic doesn't appeal to me now. At
aesthetic doesn't appeal to me now. At one time in my life, it did. And I got
one time in my life, it did. And I got
one time in my life, it did. And I got almost as thin as he is.
Uh yeah.
Uh yeah. >> Uh would you be able to calibrate uh the
>> Uh would you be able to calibrate uh the
>> Uh would you be able to calibrate uh the person I'm holding in mind to whom I
person I'm holding in mind to whom I
person I'm holding in mind to whom I would uh like to devote?
would uh like to devote?
would uh like to devote? >> I don't get the question.
>> I don't get the question.
>> I don't get the question. >> Um he wants us to calibrate the person
>> Um he wants us to calibrate the person
>> Um he wants us to calibrate the person he's holding in mind to whom he would
he's holding in mind to whom he would
he's holding in mind to whom he would like to to work with or that he
like to to work with or that he
like to to work with or that he >> work with as a teacher. You mean
>> work with as a teacher. You mean
>> work with as a teacher. You mean >> yes.
>> yes.
>> yes. >> What you really want to know is what the
>> What you really want to know is what the
>> What you really want to know is what the person you hold in mind would be
person you hold in mind would be
person you hold in mind would be appropriate. Okay. We have permission to
appropriate. Okay. We have permission to
appropriate. Okay. We have permission to ask this.
ask this.
ask this. The teacher he's holding in mind would
The teacher he's holding in mind would
The teacher he's holding in mind would be appropriate for him. Resist. Yes.
be appropriate for him. Resist. Yes.
be appropriate for him. Resist. Yes. >> Would you be able to calibrate the path?
>> Would you be able to calibrate the path?
>> Would you be able to calibrate the path? It's traditional adita.
It's traditional adita.
It's traditional adita. >> What do you say?
>> What do you say?
>> What do you say? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> You can't even calibrate the path he's
>> You can't even calibrate the path he's
>> You can't even calibrate the path he's been contemplating on taking. Well, we
been contemplating on taking. Well, we
been contemplating on taking. Well, we already got that.
already got that.
already got that. >> No, we've got the teacher
>> No, we've got the teacher
>> No, we've got the teacher >> that the teacher was fine. I we you
>> that the teacher was fine. I we you
>> that the teacher was fine. I we you know,
know,
know, >> is it from the list of teachers that I
>> is it from the list of teachers that I
>> is it from the list of teachers that I listed that have high hat calibrations?
listed that have high hat calibrations?
listed that have high hat calibrations? >> No.
>> No.
>> No. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> He's not the teacher in that. Oh yeah.
>> He's not the teacher in that. Oh yeah.
>> He's not the teacher in that. Oh yeah. So why do you pick this person?
So why do you pick this person?
So why do you pick this person? >> Uh just like you said, it resonates. Uh
>> Uh just like you said, it resonates. Uh
>> Uh just like you said, it resonates. Uh >> oh. Oh,
>> oh. Oh,
>> oh. Oh, >> intuitively.
>> intuitively.
>> intuitively. >> So the person he's holding in mind is
>> So the person he's holding in mind is
>> So the person he's holding in mind is Integress. Oh, thank you, Lord. And he's
Integress. Oh, thank you, Lord. And he's
Integress. Oh, thank you, Lord. And he's over 400,
over 400,
over 400, 500, 600,
500, 600,
500, 600, 550,
550,
550, 540. 540 is unconditional love. That's
540. 540 is unconditional love. That's
540. 540 is unconditional love. That's very wonderful.
very wonderful.
very wonderful. >> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. >> Unconditional love is a very high
>> Unconditional love is a very high
>> Unconditional love is a very high unconditional love is a very high level
unconditional love is a very high level
unconditional love is a very high level of spiritual alignment.
of spiritual alignment.
of spiritual alignment. >> Can I Can I touch your feet?
>> Oh yes. Right.
>> Oh yes. Right. >> God bless you. God bless you. God bless
>> God bless you. God bless you. God bless
>> God bless you. God bless you. God bless your devotion.
Spiritual level 540
Spiritual level 540 is uh responsible for the recovery of
is uh responsible for the recovery of
is uh responsible for the recovery of millions of people on the planet. All
millions of people on the planet. All
millions of people on the planet. All the members of AA, millions of them
the members of AA, millions of them
the members of AA, millions of them around the globe. All as a result of
around the globe. All as a result of
around the globe. All as a result of consciousness level 540 unconditional
consciousness level 540 unconditional
consciousness level 540 unconditional love.
love.
love. So that'll do for starters
if you can cure an incurable ailment.
if you can cure an incurable ailment. Yes.
Yes.
Yes. >> Hi. Uh, my name is Scott. I'm from New
>> Hi. Uh, my name is Scott. I'm from New
>> Hi. Uh, my name is Scott. I'm from New Jersey and I had a question about music.
Jersey and I had a question about music.
Jersey and I had a question about music. Uh, I know you've calibrated uh certain
Uh, I know you've calibrated uh certain
Uh, I know you've calibrated uh certain music in your books and I wanted to know
music in your books and I wanted to know
music in your books and I wanted to know if you ever calibrated
if you ever calibrated
if you ever calibrated the way the music was recorded basically
the way the music was recorded basically
the way the music was recorded basically uh analog versus digitalized recordings.
uh analog versus digitalized recordings.
uh analog versus digitalized recordings. >> No, no,
>> No, no,
>> No, no, >> no. I just did the music of the
>> no. I just did the music of the
>> no. I just did the music of the composer.
composer.
composer. No, not productions of it. Do you think
No, not productions of it. Do you think
No, not productions of it. Do you think it's possible the way music is recorded
it's possible the way music is recorded
it's possible the way music is recorded could uh turn positive music into
could uh turn positive music into
could uh turn positive music into negative? Uh
negative? Uh
negative? Uh >> I don't think so.
>> I don't think so.
>> I don't think so. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> You know, the music is the music of it.
>> You know, the music is the music of it.
>> You know, the music is the music of it. >> Um so I wanted to give you an article
>> Um so I wanted to give you an article
>> Um so I wanted to give you an article from Dr. John Diamond who uh wrote a
from Dr. John Diamond who uh wrote a
from Dr. John Diamond who uh wrote a paper on that.
paper on that.
paper on that. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> And uh
>> And uh
>> And uh >> this is uh human stress provoked by
>> this is uh human stress provoked by
>> this is uh human stress provoked by digitalized recordings.
digitalized recordings.
digitalized recordings. >> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. >> And I wasn't sure if you were aware of
>> And I wasn't sure if you were aware of
>> And I wasn't sure if you were aware of this.
this.
this. >> No, I wasn't aware of this. Is it all
>> No, I wasn't aware of this. Is it all
>> No, I wasn't aware of this. Is it all right if uh it to you just for your
right if uh it to you just for your
right if uh it to you just for your >> What's the year that you wrote that?
>> What's the year that you wrote that?
>> What's the year that you wrote that? >> There was a postcript in 2003.
>> There was a postcript in 2003.
>> There was a postcript in 2003. >> 2003. It was a postcript. It was first
>> 2003. It was a postcript. It was first
>> 2003. It was a postcript. It was first published in 1980.
published in 1980.
published in 1980. >> Oh, okay. I may have read it. Yes. Okay.
>> Oh, okay. I may have read it. Yes. Okay.
>> Oh, okay. I may have read it. Yes. Okay. Uh be glad for it, I guess.
Uh be glad for it, I guess.
Uh be glad for it, I guess. >> Thank you.
>> Hello, doctor.
>> Hello, doctor. >> Yes, I'm Adash. I have a small question.
>> Yes, I'm Adash. I have a small question.
>> Yes, I'm Adash. I have a small question. What I mean I do two sins and I I I said
What I mean I do two sins and I I I said
What I mean I do two sins and I I I said 10 times Om. So will that get
10 times Om. So will that get
10 times Om. So will that get cancelceled? I mean is there an does the
cancelceled? I mean is there an does the
cancelceled? I mean is there an does the karma get cancelled instantly?
karma get cancelled instantly?
karma get cancelled instantly? >> I mean if he does certain deeds right?
>> I mean if he does certain deeds right?
>> I mean if he does certain deeds right? Yes.
Yes.
Yes. >> If he does certain deeds by saying would
>> If he does certain deeds by saying would
>> If he does certain deeds by saying would that cancel those deeds?
that cancel those deeds?
that cancel those deeds? >> What do you mean cancel? Well, you know,
>> What do you mean cancel? Well, you know,
>> What do you mean cancel? Well, you know, uh, in other words,
uh, in other words,
uh, in other words, >> bad karma.
>> bad karma.
>> bad karma. >> Yeah, bad karma group. But in other
>> Yeah, bad karma group. But in other
>> Yeah, bad karma group. But in other words, say if he did a bad deed, would
words, say if he did a bad deed, would
words, say if he did a bad deed, would saying, "Oh, would that kill?"
saying, "Oh, would that kill?"
saying, "Oh, would that kill?" >> Oh, no. It's not going to change it. No.
>> Oh, no. It's not going to change it. No.
>> Oh, no. It's not going to change it. No. It' be
like graffiti
like graffiti in Lur's Cathedral.
>> Okay. So what would what would he do if
>> Okay. So what would what would he do if he did a bad deed? What would he do to
he did a bad deed? What would he do to
he did a bad deed? What would he do to cancel that bad deed?
cancel that bad deed?
cancel that bad deed? >> Oh. Oh.
>> Oh. Oh.
>> Oh. Oh. >> Remorse.
>> Remorse.
>> Remorse. >> Oh yes. You regret, you ask, you know,
>> Oh yes. You regret, you ask, you know,
>> Oh yes. You regret, you ask, you know, you ask for forgiveness and you go on
you ask for forgiveness and you go on
you ask for forgiveness and you go on and do good deeds to cancel it out.
and do good deeds to cancel it out.
and do good deeds to cancel it out. Everyone has done things that they wish
Everyone has done things that they wish
Everyone has done things that they wish they had not done. You know what I'm
they had not done. You know what I'm
they had not done. You know what I'm saying? Because we weren't born perfect.
saying? Because we weren't born perfect.
saying? Because we weren't born perfect. And if we were born perfect, if we were
And if we were born perfect, if we were
And if we were born perfect, if we were perfect, we wouldn't be here. So
perfect, we wouldn't be here. So
perfect, we wouldn't be here. So yeah. And one more is why do we uh
yeah. And one more is why do we uh
yeah. And one more is why do we uh forget our past past births? I mean
forget our past past births? I mean
forget our past past births? I mean >> why do we forget our past lives?
>> why do we forget our past lives?
>> why do we forget our past lives? >> I mean if we remember all that we
>> I mean if we remember all that we
>> I mean if we remember all that we >> it's not within one's present sense of
>> it's not within one's present sense of
>> it's not within one's present sense of reality. You can go into an altered
reality. You can go into an altered
reality. You can go into an altered state of consciousness and go back into
state of consciousness and go back into
state of consciousness and go back into a previous lifetime just like that. And
a previous lifetime just like that. And
a previous lifetime just like that. And um
um
um I could explain more about it but it's
I could explain more about it but it's
I could explain more about it but it's too involved.
too involved.
too involved. What you presume to be the center of
What you presume to be the center of
What you presume to be the center of your importance right now is where you
your importance right now is where you
your importance right now is where you focus.
focus.
focus. If in a different circumstance what you
If in a different circumstance what you
If in a different circumstance what you were at other times is more important
were at other times is more important
were at other times is more important then you can for instance you can go to
then you can for instance you can go to
then you can for instance you can go to the whatchamacallit institute in east
the whatchamacallit institute in east
the whatchamacallit institute in east coast
coast
coast >> mean I mean maro
>> mean I mean maro
>> mean I mean maro >> oh yeah you can go to the monro inst
>> oh yeah you can go to the monro inst
>> oh yeah you can go to the monro inst institute and learn various techniques
institute and learn various techniques
institute and learn various techniques to go out of body and visit previous
to go out of body and visit previous
to go out of body and visit previous lifetimes etc and it's quite intriguing
lifetimes etc and it's quite intriguing
lifetimes etc and it's quite intriguing and sometimes you learn things that are
and sometimes you learn things that are
and sometimes you learn things that are useful and sometimes not
useful and sometimes not
useful and sometimes not you You know, I learned a lot negative
you You know, I learned a lot negative
you You know, I learned a lot negative karma with horses that way.
karma with horses that way.
karma with horses that way. >> Can I touch your feet?
>> Can I touch your feet?
>> Can I touch your feet? >> And I forgave the horses and I forgave
>> And I forgave the horses and I forgave
>> And I forgave the horses and I forgave myself and now we're fine.
God bless you.
God bless you. >> Thank you.
You're going to learn all these cameras.
You're going to learn all these cameras. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Hello Dr.
>> Hello Dr.
>> Hello Dr. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Hello Dr. Hawkins. Uh my name is Barat
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins. Uh my name is Barat
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins. Uh my name is Barat and we are all from New Jersey and
>> just last uh
>> just last uh >> uh we have been on the spiritual path
>> uh we have been on the spiritual path
>> uh we have been on the spiritual path for a year now. Can you hear me? Yeah.
for a year now. Can you hear me? Yeah.
for a year now. Can you hear me? Yeah. We we have been on the spiritual path
We we have been on the spiritual path
We we have been on the spiritual path for a year now and we just got
for a year now and we just got
for a year now and we just got introduced to you
introduced to you
introduced to you >> uh through my cousin and your teachings
>> uh through my cousin and your teachings
>> uh through my cousin and your teachings and we just got introduced to you. So we
and we just got introduced to you. So we
and we just got introduced to you. So we here to take your blessings.
here to take your blessings.
here to take your blessings. >> We would like to touch your teeth and
>> We would like to touch your teeth and
>> We would like to touch your teeth and bless bless us to grow in at a higher
bless bless us to grow in at a higher
bless bless us to grow in at a higher spiritual level.
spiritual level.
spiritual level. >> It's a beautiful family to bless.
>> It's a beautiful family to bless.
>> It's a beautiful family to bless. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> God bless you all in the name of the
>> God bless you all in the name of the
>> God bless you all in the name of the Lord. Amen.
Lord. Amen.
Lord. Amen. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Would I touch your feet?
>> Would I touch your feet?
>> Would I touch your feet? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Uh the very I see very Yes. God bless
>> Uh the very I see very Yes. God bless
>> Uh the very I see very Yes. God bless you.
you.
you. God bless you. Yes. God bless you. God
God bless you. Yes. God bless you. God
God bless you. Yes. God bless you. God bless you. The act of devotion in itself
bless you. The act of devotion in itself
bless you. The act of devotion in itself is bless is blessing.
is bless is blessing.
is bless is blessing. You're already blessed by your
You're already blessed by your
You're already blessed by your intention.
Your tradition of uh the teacher in
Your tradition of uh the teacher in India is that of the guru and different
India is that of the guru and different
India is that of the guru and different than American or western styles.
It's an act of uh commitment and u
It's an act of uh commitment and u intention.
>> Thank you so much for your devotion and
>> Thank you so much for your devotion and faith.
>> So
>> So >> now what?
>> now what?
>> now what? >> We're done.
>> We're done.
>> We're done. >> We're done
>> We're done
>> We're done >> kind of. Oh,
all right. So,
all right. So, we needed some music to conclude with
we needed some music to conclude with
we needed some music to conclude with and we plan play promised we were going
and we plan play promised we were going
and we plan play promised we were going to do something at the end.
to do something at the end.
to do something at the end. >> We're going to shake hands. So,
>> We're going to shake hands. So,
>> We're going to shake hands. So, >> no. First, we're going to bless the
>> no. First, we're going to bless the
>> no. First, we're going to bless the crowd.
crowd.
crowd. >> All right. We're going to do the silence
>> All right. We're going to do the silence
>> All right. We're going to do the silence prayer and then we're going to shake
prayer and then we're going to shake
prayer and then we're going to shake hands.
hands.
hands. >> We're going to do what?
>> We're going to do what?
>> We're going to do what? >> We're going to do the blessing of snow.
>> We're going to do the blessing of snow.
>> We're going to do the blessing of snow. >> Oh. Oh, yes indeed. Oh my god. I don't
>> Oh. Oh, yes indeed. Oh my god. I don't
>> Oh. Oh, yes indeed. Oh my god. I don't know if I can handle it.
through us. The energy of divinity
through us. The energy of divinity sweeps through mankind.
sweeps through mankind.
sweeps through mankind. That's a fact.
By being together, we serve
By being together, we serve God,
God,
God, our fellow man,
our fellow man,
our fellow man, and also our higher self.
and also our higher self.
and also our higher self. Three acts of devotion in one.
And we thank thee oh Lord for the
And we thank thee oh Lord for the blessing
blessing
blessing of those present.
>> We come in together
>> We come in together and we live together.
And I do bless you all in the name of
And I do bless you all in the name of the Lord Almighty God now and forever.
the Lord Almighty God now and forever.
the Lord Almighty God now and forever. Amen.
And we all collectively indeed
And we all collectively indeed are one.
are one.
are one. And so we love each other now and
And so we love each other now and
And so we love each other now and forever. Amen.
Thank you so much.
Thank you so much. The blessing of your presence.
So when this moment
So when this moment >> passes all of time
having transcended time, we are no
having transcended time, we are no longer subject to it. Thank you, Lord.