Thank you
Yes, go ahead. I
Would like to add that your mic is not on Oh
Thank you, dr. Hawkins, I would like to hold you gotta come forward one
I'd like to hold her hold my spiritual teacher in my mind and ask consciousness
permission for calibration
And ask us to calibrate them you want me to calibrate what you're holding in mind. Yeah of my teacher. I'll make you join my mind
my permission and it's a
It's advisable to do this resist not advisable to do this, okay
so
Is there any other way I could ask it or it just says no?
Okay, thank you
Audience yeah
Because the nature of the audience hello, dr. Hawkins. Oh
I used to be an Orthodox bishop, but I'm currently a professor at a community college
Where I use your levels of consciousness chart when I talk about understanding human behavior. Yes
The question actually relates to since I was a child
I've always had memories of myself and my family from
My last lifetime being murdered being murdered. Yes. Yes, and
That's sort of a backdrop of fear that is sort of
Colored my life and I and recently I was contemplating that and I realized many of the
Worst decisions I've made in my life were at times when that fear has raised itself and associated with that
Is a lot of thoughts
William James talks about a stream of consciousness. I call it a river of thoughts
So my question is how
do I
Get rid of all these thoughts
They're kind of like the Energizer bunny. They just keep going and going and going
That's because you're resisting them
Okay
So what's wrong would be it getting murdered you gotta go get your objection to that rather slowly
Was that your agony and pain?
Well, that was a lot faster.
So you try not to dictate to God the nature of your death
because the nature of your death is already a karmic propensity.
Okay.
So maybe the only way you could undo having murdered others
is you get to experience getting murdered
and you see it's a miserable way to go.
Okay.
Yeah?
So I wouldn't resist it.
However it was, served its purpose at the time, you know?
Okay.
I recall deaths from previous lifetimes,
and each one of them subserved a greater purpose.
I learned something of great importance through each occasion, you know?
And the fear, this underlying fear...
Is resisting it.
Is resisting it, okay.
So if you surrender yourself,
to God,
let's picture you're one of the sacrifices
of the early South American religions.
They need a volunteer to sacrifice themselves to the gods
to stop the starvation of the people and the earthquakes and all.
And they ask for a volunteer.
You volunteer.
So you volunteer your death to serve a higher purpose
and then you lose the fear of it.
Yes?
All right.
Thank you.
We all hope that our death would serve some higher purpose
other than just the elimination of this corporeal existence, you know?
Which is sort of biologic, but rabbits do that and mice do that.
So what's human about that?
To give it a greater dimension,
the significance of your leaving the world
would be serving some higher purpose, you know?
So you ask the Lord,
if it is thy will that I leave this world in such a way
to serve a higher purpose, you know?
Yeah?
Otherwise, it's just the fulfillment of the karmic limitations of protoplasm,
which is sort of dreary.
I always just need an excuse to come up here.
That's always my hello, hi.
I wanted you to talk more directly, if you could,
about a couple of things you've said,
if you could interweave a couple of things.
Speak close to the microphone and sort of slowly, okay?
Closer and slowly.
Is that better?
All right.
Yes, that's better.
Okay.
Is that better?
No.
Okay.
So what do you want to know?
What do I want to know?
Yeah.
I want to know how your direct experience
of three things that you've said,
if you would interweave them.
So one of you have said devotion for its own sake,
and sometimes something you don't see any progress for 10 years,
and surrendering at great depths to the will of God,
and kind of the context of when something doesn't appear to be happening.
I can't answer your question.
You're giving a 40-page lecture.
Ask a question.
Okay.
What was the context you held if you went through really long periods
where it appeared nothing was happening, a 10-year span?
The knowledge that such is typical.
Okay.
So just expecting that just made it.
If you read the lives of the saints, et cetera,
you'll see they all had long periods
where they felt they were making no progress, et cetera, dry periods.
So Mother Teresa complained about it, right?
Okay.
All right.
So just knowing that's typical.
Those serve who also stand in wait.
Say that again?
Those serve who stand in wait.
Oh, okay.
I don't just kind of echo it.
It's hard to hear.
Yeah, you can't be center stage all the time.
No.
Okay.
God's got other people to take care of besides you.
He'll get them back to you after a while.
All right.
Get busy for 10 years, and I'll get back to you, okay?
Sounds good.
Can I get a picture of me and my husband and you and Susan?
Yeah, whatever you like.
You know, there's long, dry periods,
and you read the lives of all the saints.
They all went through periods where they're despairing,
or that they're not making progress.
Because how do you know whether you're making progress or not?
Progress is how you define it, you see?
People like fireworks and great illuminations
and visitations by angels and all that's very exciting.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
I've got an announcement and a question.
My announcement is that there's a David Hawkins study group in Los Angeles.
So if anybody is interested in participating in that,
if you could e-mail me,
at telly at earthlink.net.
Telly is to e-mail you?
Okay.
E-mail us on that.
And can I spell the, okay.
Telly is spelled T like Tom, E-L-Y, at earthlink.net.
And I will e-mail you also.
My question is, earlier you said that your choices decide your fate.
Your personal choices or your freedom of choice decides your fate.
Personal choices decide your fate.
And I'm wondering if you could help me understand how to reconcile that with non-causality?
Causality is a Newtonian concept of a this causing a that
in a linear conceptual framework which calibrates in the mid-400s.
That's what causality is, yes?
Yes.
And what is your question?
So when you say your choices decide your fate.
Oh, yes.
Because they change your direction.
They don't cause anything.
But you can.
But you shift from this stream to this stream by choice.
Yeah.
You're not causing anything.
Nothing is being caused.
So then is the choice, is that choice that you're going to make predetermined that you will make that choice?
You have karmic propensities, the likelihoods.
Karmic propensities are likelihoods.
If you choose to devote yourself to God, the likelihood is greater that you will make these particular choices
rather than the other.
So it's cascading levels of dominance.
And there's a psychiatrist who writes about it.
I've mentioned his name before, and nobody can find him on the Internet, so I don't want to mention his name again.
Medina.
M-E-D-I-N-A.
Talks about cascading levels.
In other words, a decision here has a determining effect on increasing the likelihood of this and this and this.
Right?
I mean, it's only common sense, but at least...
I'm waiting.
I don't have the book.
Okay, all right.
No, no, no.
Yeah.
Medina, if you look him up on the Internet, you won't find him for some reason.
He writes all the time for the psychiatric news and psychiatric newspapers.
Cascading levels of dominance.
The likelihood.
So I'd refer to the same thing in the book Power vs. Forest.
In the nonlinear dynamics, there are attractor fields that are more powerful than others.
So if you invoke...
If you invoke a very powerful field, then the likelihood is that similar type decisions will be made, yeah?
So in other words, our choices create a likelihood of something happening rather than actually causing...
That's so, that's so.
But you're not dictated, but you're very likely.
Great.
If you have a high regard for life, you'll try to avoid hitting the rabbit on the road.
Okay.
It doesn't mean you can't run over the rabbit, but the likelihood is very slim.
Gotcha.
The likelihood is you may even risk your own life rather than run over to the rabbit.
Yeah, you may even risk your own life rather than run over to the rabbit, you know?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
All right?
Thank you very much.
Yes.
Great.
I have this book, so I'll sign in here.
I'll leave it here.
Yes.
One question, just a quick one.
Kind of, you know, maybe selfish a little bit.
I'm a professional musician.
Professional musician, yes.
I've been writing music, healing music, the last 15 years.
It's very popular worldwide.
My new CD just came out.
I want to see if it's possible.
I want you to calibrate it before I release it.
I don't do it, no.
Can we?
No.
Don't calibrate it.
Everybody, otherwise everybody brings the paintings, drawings, books, if I print it,
you know, pottery.
Okay.
Just was wondering.
You know what your intention was.
Yeah, I really know.
So that's going to reflect.
Is that enough?
That's going to reflect your intention.
Yeah.
Therefore, whatever your intention is, that will come across, yeah?
Okay.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Your intention automatically goes into your work.
Great.
Thank you.
All the time.
Yeah, that was kind of a doubting answer.
My friend forced me.
That's fine.
I'll just offer this to you.
You can take it home.
Thanks.
This is it.
Oh, thank you.
Yes, I'm just fine.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
Great.
Thank you.
Dr. Hawkins.
Yes.
Hello, Suzanne.
Hi.
I would like to ask you, Dr. Hawkins, about this condition that I've been experiencing
lately, about two years.
Two years ago, I am sort of hypersensitive to energy of people, and I can't...
You have hypersensitivity to people's energy?
Yes.
What do you mean by hypersensitivity?
You get a rash or what?
It's okay.
I'm glad that you said that.
Well, I can feel sometimes the good energy.
I can feel it in people, and that feels wonderful.
How do you know if that's right?
Yeah, I don't know if you're right.
I don't know if it's good or bad.
It's just what I feel.
I see.
You like the dog.
No, it feels okay.
Yeah, the dog can tell when you're up to no good.
So you've got a good doggy in you, huh?
No, no, no.
Then what happens is...
Dr. Hawkins, you're here for...
It's helping me just by that.
For my problem.
Thank you.
So what's your question?
My problem is that...
No problem.
My question is that when I feel the negative...
What I sense as negative or uncomfortable energy to me, okay?
When I sense that energy, I can't stand it.
I can't...
Like if I'm near a person and I can feel that negative energy,
I can't be there.
So you don't like negative people.
Yeah, negative energy is right.
Not that I don't like it.
It's that I...
It's...
I cannot...
I cannot stand or...
I feel drained.
Yes?
Yes, I feel drained and I...
Yes, that's true.
That's true?
Yes.
Yes, and what can I do about that?
Stay away from those people.
What do you think?
Sometimes I can't because they're very near me all the time.
What, do you ride the subway to work every day or what do you think?
Well, sometimes, you know, that...
I'm not surrounded by people whose energy I don't like.
No, no, no, but even maybe that same person is not like that all the time
and I can sometimes sense that...
That's different.
That's different?
They're having...
They're dealing with their own problems.
Yeah, so I...
There was a psychic who used to say people were either magnetic or electric.
Either drain your energy or they give you energy.
People either drain your energy if they're below 200
or they give you energy if they're above 200.
So avoid people that are below 200.
Okay.
Don't be a bus...
Bus driver.
Well, I mean, you know, there's jobs there.
If you have this kind of a problem, you avoid them.
The answer is it's common sense, is it not?
Yes, I guess.
There's all kinds of people I avoid because I think their energy is awful, you know?
Oh, then it's not...
There's nothing I have to do or anything.
Nothing you have to do except avoid them.
Avoid.
Or go places where I...
You're going to try and build up some kind of a guard around yourself.
You'll get involved with all kinds of psychics
and they'll be building...
all kinds of energy lights around you
and you can have a good time for 20, 30 years fooling around with it.
Okay, so there's nothing to do.
Okay.
No, it's not a problem.
Okay, thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
Thank you very much.
Yes.
Thank you, sir.
I just sense there are bad times, so I have to take it in.
That's the problem.
I don't know how to not take it in.
Eventually you can learn how to guard yourself against that.
Thank you.
Witness them without interacting with them.
There's some honey books here.
My God, what is it?
Yeah.
I was wondering if it is for my highest good
to continue doing the enlightenment retreats that I've been doing.
Okay.
I was wondering if it's for my highest good
to continue doing the enlightenment retreats that I've been doing.
To continue doing what?
Enlightenment.
Enlightenment retreat.
It's for your highest good?
Yes.
Well, your intention is that it should be
and it's called enlightenment.
Enlightenment retreat.
So what is the question?
You think they're teaching demonology or what?
Let's all take our clothes off and have sex.
I mean, there was a sex like that.
Yeah, there was.
They're gone now.
Well, there was.
Enlightenment.
What?
You mentioned on one of your posters about birds.
Yeah.
And they do some breathing and they do some breathing stuff.
I don't get what she's saying.
She said they do some breathing techniques.
Oh.
You listed some breathing techniques.
Well, the breathing techniques, they have their place.
It's hard to say yes or no about it.
It gets imbued with magic after a while, you know, magic.
The enlightened states that have occurred
in this lifetime were never the accompaniment of any kind
of energy manipulation or breathing techniques.
None of them.
Not a one.
I meditated for many years, many hours.
There's been more time in meditation than a lot
of people have been alive on the planet.
Thank you.
You're talking about the various yogas, you see.
And I myself am now unimpressed by the various yogas.
But I think it makes these various yoga exercises work
as the power of the intention.
If you think a certain breathing technique is going
to increase your consciousness, it will because
of the intention.
But I'll tell you, pranayana calibrates at 190.
Okay.
Pranayana is probably the most well-known, right?
Yeah.
You know what pranayana is?
I don't know.
Oh, all right, all right.
Well, pranayana, which has all kinds of breathing alternately
for one nostril than the other, calibrates at 190.
It interferes with your consciousness evolution.
And what about surrender yoga?
What?
Surrender yoga.
I don't know what that is.
I don't know.
What I teach is surrender yoga, to give up
your own personal intention all the time.
Thank you.
The minute you add yoga to it, it
gets a mystical, magical woo-woo.
Sounds like my hometown.
They get into woo-woo about the yoga of this and that, you know?
What you hold in mind tends to manifest.
That doesn't have to become a yoga, you know what I mean?
Hello.
Yeah.
I'm just here for a spiritual blessing.
I'm just here for a spiritual blessing and a picture.
Yes.
May I hold you?
Yep.
I know books.
What would you like, my love?
You want to be blessed?
Yes, please.
You're blessed by the presence of God as the source of your own existence.
Amen.
Thank you.
In as much as we were all created by divinity, we've all been blessed from the very onset.
Even if you got all kinds of bad karma to live through, that's a blessing that you're
given the chance to live through.
And become exonerated.
Yes.
The fact that you exist is a sign of God's favor, is it not?
Hi.
Is everybody in favor of that?
The fact that we exist is already such a great blessing.
To become consciously aware as a human is exceptionally good, positive karma.
Yes.
Hi.
I love you, Dr. Hawkins.
Love you, Susan.
Thank you.
I love you, Susan.
I was reading I and came across the Final Door chapter and I had to ask something about
the Final Door.
You write that it comes unannounced.
Yes.
And statistically not many can pass.
Correct.
So one question would be why is that?
I have no idea.
Okay.
You spoke earlier.
Rare it is for a human being to have sufficient faith and confidence
that they're willing to absolutely surrender their existence to God
at a very deep level.
It doesn't happen very often.
The surrender is always provisional.
Provisional.
Just like somebody wants to dictate how they're going to die.
God doesn't need to be told what's the most beneficial way
for me to leave the planet.
You spoke earlier today about familiarity.
So would you then repeat the instructions for the final door?
I have to recall how it goes, how it went.
I would have to recall.
Having surrendered everything, there was nothing left.
I was in a very high space, very, how would you say,
rarefied, extremely rarefied space,
in which there was no one,
and very few beings had passed through this space.
Yes.
That's when you let go of all the ego, see?
And in this infinite space of almost nothingness,
there had been a couple of beings pass through this pass.
It's like a high pass.
I saw who had been there.
They leave a track, a permanent track.
I saw Jesus Christ had been there.
I saw the agony in the Garden of Gethsemane
was the letting go.
The agony of one's own existence.
Surrendering it to God, you see?
And there was nothing left to surrender.
And then came the knowingness, yes, accept your life.
And then I got, this too must be surrendered to thee, O Lord.
And I realized that there's the inner belief inside the ego
that it is God.
That it is the source of your existence.
And I saw that this, too, had to be surrendered to God.
As I surrendered the source of life itself,
I surrendered life itself to God.
You surrender everything but life itself.
And as I surrendered life itself,
came forth an agony of dying.
Severe and a true agonized agony.
And the agony lasted, and I said,
I'm going to die.
And it lasted an earthly time,
perhaps a minute or a couple of minutes,
but it was severe.
And I just kept surrendering to it,
and I kept surrendering it to it.
And I saw that that which is called I
would never again exist
because its source of life
was now being extinguished and surrendered.
So I let go, resisting the agony of it.
The agony was a terror, a deep terror.
A deep terror, the terror of non-existence.
And then came forth the saying from a guru somewhere in the distant past.
All fear is illusion, surrender it to God.
So I surrendered the fear of non-existence and losing life forever,
becoming extinguished, in other words.
I surrendered it out of faith to my teacher.
That's the value of the energy field of the aura of the teacher.
The true teacher is one who has experienced it absolutely through and through
and speaks from the authority of having experienced it,
not read about it, heard about it, learned about it, but done it.
Therefore, the courage came forth, as I say.
The fear and the terror was severe.
And on the other side of that,
the doorway of death, all of life opened up,
all of existence opened up and shone forth as the glory of God,
which is what shines forth in this room at this moment.
What shines forth to me in this moment right now is the glory of God,
expressing itself as the phenomena that we are now collectively witnessing.
Thank you.
I need your arm a second.
I just said Calvary said 1,000 resist.
Thank you.
1,000.
Yes?
I simply ask that divine grace be present in this moment with you.
Divine grace is present.
Thank you.
Divine grace expresses itself as asking for divine grace in the first place.
Only by divine grace would you ever even be asking such a thing.
The world is full of people.
The last thing they would ask for is divine grace.
A new car maybe, but not divine grace.
Give me.
Give me a Mercedes-Benz.
I just wanted to thank you, Dr. Hawkins, for everything.
You are.
Thank you.
And I want a picture.
What was her name saying in that song?
Janice Joplin.
Hi.
I got to sign all these?
Yep.
I sat next to Janice Joplin at the Fillmore East many a year ago.
Janice was sitting right next to me, and she was drinking Southern Comfort.
We were in the first row.
So anyway, then it came time.
She played with Big Brother and the Holding Company in those days.
So they were ready for her.
So she went up on stage, did ball and chain.
When she did ball and chain, in the middle of ball and chain, there's a long hesitation where the music stops.
And the whole crowd just went insane.
They were just like in a hypnotic state.
And then after this long silence, she hits this high note.
Bang.
After this long silence.
And the whole crowd just went insane.
They stood on their chairs and leaped and screamed with joy and happiness.
That was Janice, yeah.
God bless her.
So many died of drugs in those years in that era.
Dr. Hawkins, I'm one of those people who have been a lifelong spiritual student.
I started as a teenager and was disciplined sometimes more in life and sometimes less.
But nevertheless, always very serious about it.
Thank you.
And I would have thought that now that I've had my 50th birthday, I'd be a little further along than this.
And quite honestly, my question is, how far can you progress in one life?
And is it possible to reach enlightenment in one life?
Oh, of course.
Then what did I not do?
Who says you're not enlightened?
Who says it?
I guess me.
You?
I saw your chart.
And I don't meet those numbers.
How would you know whether you're enlightened or not?
You'd have to be enlightened to know whether you're enlightened or not.
Why do you say you're not enlightened?
You expect a mysterious, magical phenomena to occur.
Yes.
A mystical, magical phenomena.
It's enlightened to seek enlightenment, is it not?
One in 10 million.
If we stop 10 million people on the street and ask them, what is your primary goal?
My goal in life, do you know that it's less than one in 10 million will say, become enlightened?
That's a fact.
Less than one in 10 million people will say, my goal in life is to become enlightened.
So I want you to appreciate how rare it is in the first place to even choose such a destiny.
And you don't know how far you are along the path.
You have no idea.
You're just looking for certain subjective phenomena.
Forget all that.
The difference between being enlightened and unenlightened is one ten-thousandth of a second.
It takes exactly one ten-thousandth of a second to go from an ego-dominated state to a non-ego state.
It takes one ten-thousandth of a second.
All of a sudden, you're in a different dimension.
Don't worry about it.
Thank you.
You have to surrender.
Surrender.
Your will to God in the matter, you see.
God doesn't want you enlightened right now because you've got other things to do.
And then you get enlightened later when it serves God's better purpose, you see.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
I may need you to teach kindergarten right now.
It's good to see you both again.
I'm getting enlightened all over the place.
Yeah.
So my question is based on understanding karma.
Your body of work has really helped me understand my pain and move on from it.
I've had a very challenging childhood.
My father was drunk every day of my life, and there was sexual abuse in my family, and that was a very difficult thing for me to comprehend.
I became an atheist when I learned that priests molested children, and then I had a great understanding and epiphany through reading your body of work of how to separate God from the predators or the people that indulge in that.
So now I have a very strong faith in God, and all that's fine.
I've forgiven my father.
I've moved on.
And my question is the karma on my end and my sister's end and my brother's end of being born into this family.
I never really understood the whole we choose our family for that.
Because you maybe were a perpetrator prior, and now you got to be a victim and undo it.
Very often what happens is you really become, you experience what you perpetrated on others.
That's been my, you know, that's happened in this lifetime.
That I've subjectively experienced really great agony, and it was the equivalent to what I had caused to others.
That was the full undoing of it.
So that's all you can do is say, well, I hope that undoes that negative karma.
I hope it pays back that karmic debt or whatever.
Am I supposed to sign this?
No, I think I did that one.
All right.
That's been my own experience.
I've gone through some great periods of agony, frankly.
That was the undoing.
The undoing of having imposed that very significant, that specific agony on another human being in another lifetime.
So we chose to overcome the hurdle of what we had done in the past.
Yeah.
The undoing of the karma is a very, the undoing is very often you experience it out.
Excellent.
Thank you.
Because it could be your own inner judge that is judging that that is the way it should go.
Right.
It was, for sure.
It may not be divinity that makes that decision, but you yourself.
That was what I understood about forgiving my father.
I understood that he was limited.
His choices were limited by his conditioning and karma.
Right.
And then, but I didn't understand because I'm in my experience.
I couldn't understand mine.
So I'd heard that, yeah, maybe I had been an alcoholic before, been, could have been a murderer, a pedophile or any of that.
And I'm here to experience the other end of it.
Is that kind of what you're saying?
Yeah.
You may not remember it or you may not know it.
Right.
If you go into past life recall, which is a whole area of research in itself, you can
go to Monroe Institute, you know, and learn altered states of consciousness, go into past
life research.
You can learn to count yourself down to level 10, 12, 14, something like this, and go back
into a previous lifetime and re-experience it.
Not witness it, but experience it.
Literally.
The movie starts and you're in the movie.
You're not witnessing the movie.
You're in the movie.
The whole phenomenon.
The whole phenomenon of the previous lifetime.
I've always had a desire to do that, but I don't know if it's for my highest good.
What is the...
You may not need to do it for your highest good.
You know, you could ask the arm, is it for his highest good?
Does he need to do that?
I doubt you do.
Okay.
Unless you're going to be a spiritual teacher or something where you've got to know every
nook and cranny, you know.
Excellent.
Thank you.
That helps.
No, the perfectionist in us makes excessive demands and they're not realistic.
It's not.
It's not necessary to do all that.
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
Okay.
Hello.
I worked with horses in a therapeutic way with patients that were in recovery for alcohol
and drug addictions.
I know that you've worked with people in therapeutic ways with horses and I'm interested in just
hearing your thoughts about the way that horses serve.
Horses, what is she saying?
Horses, horses?
Horses, horses.
Horses?
Yeah, like giddy up.
Oh, okay.
What do horses got to do with it?
I'm sorry?
She said that she knows you work like at the girls' ranch and you use the horses for
the...
Yeah, right.
We teach self-esteem, responsibility, make them responsible for the horses' welfare
so they learn to care for somebody other than themselves, you know.
Yes, I was chief of staff at a place.
Prescott Valley, 100 students, I forget, staff of a couple hundred, 300 acres, we
had 35 horses and that was part of the therapy to resume dignity, self-confidence, responsibility
for others.
It was part of the rehab, a very effective part too.
And how did the horses, I guess, consciousness contribute to that?
I guess that was my question.
It doesn't have to do with the horses' consciousness.
It has to do with being responsible for the welfare of something other than your personal
self.
And it has to do with learning self-discipline and how to coordinate yourself with another.
So there's certain things you can't really define what they learn out of it, but very
definitely there was a benefit to the girls, you know.
As I say, we had a lot of them, 60s.
I think 60 girls at one time, yeah.
I think 60 girls, yeah.
35 horses.
Okay, great.
Thank you.
You see, any animal can be used in a beneficial way because of your intention.
Many years ago, I owned a monkey, a macaque monkey.
And I used to take the monkey to the clinic.
I had a very big clinic then.
I would take the macaque monkey to work, you know, and the child therapist would use the
monkey as a third person.
And the child would project all kinds of stuff on the monkey.
And the child therapist would use the monkey as a third person.
monkey and say, oh, that monkey's mad at me because of this, or the monkey's
afraid of me because of this, and I say, what do you think the monkey's doing? Oh,
the monkey's going to get even with me. The child projects all their stuff onto the monkey.
So any animal can have a beneficial
service, you know, when using a therapeutic modality.
Okay, I just finished answering that last question. Dr. Hawkins,
what are the conditions in which the aura of the teacher is transmitted to the student?
Uh, there isn't any particular conditions.
It's one of volition. That, um, one
is, uh, let's see how we would say it works. It works, uh,
let's see, does it work without their permission?
It works without the permission of the student, resist.
Works without the permission of the student, doesn't need your permission, it just is a fact.
Is it, uh, geographical in closeness with the teacher, or
does, you know,
I think it can be, it can be at a distance. Uh, it can be at a distance.
It can be at a distance by aligning yourself with the teacher,
the teacher's image, teaching, sound of voice.
Excellent, thank you very much. It's most powerful to
actually experience the physical aura of energy.
That's what came to my rescue anyway in that
place where of terror. Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Yeah. Too close. I want to know,
would it be a good idea for me to start my own business?
That's too general question again, isn't it?
Okay.
If you're in doubt, I'd say no.
You better be convinced that it's the right thing if you want to do a business.
When you're starting a business, don't tend to be iffy.
Hi. I read, um, somewhere one time that you wrote that it was,
it was something to the effect that a spiritual, uh, student asked you a question,
and the question was regarding, um, what's the quickest way to either transcend barriers,
duality, or to get to enlightenment. And you wrote something to the effect of
understanding the nature of consciousness. Can you clarify that?
We gave a whole long lecture for a couple hours. Were you there this afternoon?
No, I'm, I'm, I'm, no, seriously, because like when, when I, when I first read it,
Seriously?
No, seriously.
When I, when I first, when I first read that, um,
What?
When I first read that, what, what you said, like, uh, that statement, it kind of struck me,
but it struck me in a way that like, I can't explain it, but I, I, it kind of like, it, it, it, it feeds me.
I don't know how to, do you know what I'm talking about?
No.
You don't either.
Okay, what, okay, understanding, okay, what is, can you give me a practical tool into, uh, understanding the nature of consciousness?
A tool?
Yeah.
You're a tool.
Thank you. You're pretty, too.
I guess I'm a failure as a teacher, huh? I met my Waterloo.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Hi.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Yes, ma'am.
Okay.
Um, I would like you to expand a little bit on the experiences that you had at the Great Pyramids.
I don't know that I can really tell you much about it. Uh, I spent the night by myself, meditating the entire night through.
And I understood things not understandable otherwise.
Napoleon, for one thing.
Napoleon's consciousness when he entered the pyramid, and Napoleon's consciousness when he left the pyramid.
Many things came as a revelation, and I cannot really describe it verbally.
It was a spiritual experiment.
In those days, I was, I was researching all kinds of different, uh, approaches to spiritual reality and, uh, consciousness.
Uh, you know, you go to Machu Picchu.
You go to Machu Picchu.
You, uh, you, uh, visit the pyramids.
Rarely do you get a chance to meditate all night in the pyramids. That's sort of rare.
But those are all forms of spiritual seeking.
You get to visit spiritual teachers and pick up their aura, if nothing else, you know?
And, uh, some were delightful and fun, and others were sort of boring.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
I never really, again, Machu Picchu.
I got a kick out of Machu Picchu. I really liked him.
And, you know, Machu Picchu would have a whole bushel basket of orange knit caps next to him.
And he'd put the orange knit cap on him, on himself, say hello to a few people.
And then he'd throw it out in the audience, and everybody would run out to grab the orange knit cap because it had the energy of his aura in the cap, you know?
So people would run out.
Just like they do with baseball stars.
Baseball, you know, to get the looking on to his funny.
He would throw the cap up in the air, and everybody would rush to grab the orange cap.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Thank you for answering my question.
Yes.
Oh, thank you.
What is this here?
I don't know.
Left in here. What is it?
It's a flag thing.
Hmm?
Hmm.
That's nice.
Thank you for being here.
Both of you.
Recently, more commonly, there are moments of silence where there is no thought.
And then something comes up and says to me, you're not supposed to be living like this.
You're supposed to be thinking.
And you can't live like that.
You can't live silently?
Recently, there was a nonverbal message of you can't let me go after I've suffered so much.
So I thought it would help me to not give it any more importance if I could hear some validation that.
It's just an evil spirit hanging under your ego, huh?
Is it?
Yeah.
Get the hints.
Order it.
It will leave you in the name of God, in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ.
And it has to leave you.
So what you're telling me is that I'm possessed?
I did not say that at all.
You're disclaiming that it's not me.
You're disclaiming that it's your mind saying this, are you?
Whose will is being expressed?
That's what I want to clear up today.
I'm just clearing it for you.
Tell it to go the hell way.
That's all I have to do.
That's all.
Order it in the name of your Lord Jesus Christ and order it to leave you alone.
So that's just my ego and then that's just the ego and I just tell it that and then I'm free?
You demand that it leave you in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ.
And then I live in that moment of clarity forever?
What?
Then she lives in a moment of clarity forever.
That one I had, I live in that moment and the moments that keep coming up.
Yeah, but that isn't what she's asking about.
She's not asking about the moment of clarity.
No.
I just tell it to leave me.
You were saying that a voice is telling you you cannot live in that state.
It's not really a voice.
It's non-verbal.
There's...
Is there non-verbal knowingness?
Just a non-verbal...
That you cannot live in that state.
Exactly.
So then you'll have to die.
I've been mourning my death for the past two years.
What?
I've been mourning my own death for the past two years.
Mourning?
Mourning.
Why do you want to mourn it?
There's just a sense that I am dying.
Don't you know it's on the other side?
No, I guess I...
I guess...
You've been dying for years already.
Yeah.
All right.
So why hurry it up, you retarded?
Why don't you just surrender to...
God's will.
Surrender to God's will in the matter of your own spiritual evolution.
It's that thing to tell God how to do it.
Now, then, this way, that way.
Yeah?
Okay.
We all believe in God as long as he does it our way, you know?
That's true.
That's too true.
Please let me get in the light, but not right now.
Because I still have to do this.
First of all, Dr. Harkness, I'd like to say thank you.
And I have a question.
First of all, I'd like to know if a soulmate actually exists.
If what?
The human conception of soulmates.
Soulmate.
And if so, if you could elaborate about that.
It's a romantic notion.
I don't know if there is such a thing or not.
A soulmate is a romantic notion.
It's just...
It's not...
It's not a spiritual reality.
It can be a spiritual reality.
It's elective.
It's an elective spiritual...
An elective experiential reality.
Okay.
Thank you.
I think the reason you know there are soulmates is because you're with them.
I feel like I've entered the last door.
Can we only achieve enlightenment with the grace and blessings of a guru?
That's an ancient question.
In the Hindu tradition, there was a saying...
In the Hindu tradition, there was a saying, no!
No!
The same thing you said...
In the Hindu tradition, no!
The same thing you said, no!
It requires the blessing of the teacher.
In the Christian tradition, it's not a fact.
The Christian mystics, saints...
I've heard their allegiance to their own teachers were.
I think they just surrendered to Jesus Christ as Lord, period.
Jesus Christ was their guru.
What's your take on it?
What's your take?
I've been with a guru since I was a child.
And I feel as though there's a widening gap between our relationship.
You don't need to be with a glue on a permanent basis.
You need a few seconds with a guru, that's all.
You really only need a moment.
There's a flash, and that flash, the deed is done.
So you don't have to be a permanent resident in guru land, you know.
But to be with a guru in his physical state is also remarkable as well.
Is also what?
Remarkable as well.
To be with a guru in his physical state.
Yes, that's true, yes.
You know, that's a very positive kind of karma.
That permission to be around a very advanced level of consciousness
for periods of time is a very positive karmic gift, yes, yes.
Thank you.
So through selfless service, you see.
The state that I realized at the point of death came about
through my previous work, transmission from a guru of, I think,
five lifetimes before that.
They say seek holy company.
That's always advisable.
Seek holy company.
Dr. Hawkins, I felt very good this morning when you hold my hand for a few seconds,
so I'm here to get some more blessings from you.
That'll be a dollar.
You don't have any more questions?
No questions.
No more questions?
No.
Oh, thank goodness.
Thank goodness.
Then you're done.
Thank you all.
Can I get a picture with you as well?
A picture.
Now she wants a picture.
Next will be one of my socks or something.
Thank you.
She's a fun person.
She's a funny girl.
Thank you for your teachings.
I just have a question.
I followed the teachings of one of the gurus that you listed on your list of credible teachers
for many years and have used the meditation techniques that came from that organization
that sprouted up around him.
And at a certain point, in order to get...
Yeah.
...other initiates into some of the meditation techniques, we signed an oath.
And I was wondering what the consequences of that are as it was taken innocently.
And if there are consequences, how do I transcend them in my journey towards enlightenment?
Let me have the arms.
The oath that he took calibrated over 200.
So you're bound by it.
So he's bound by the oath.
So why don't you just serve the oath?
Okay.
Now you have a question about the integrity of the teacher.
Is that what you're saying?
Well, the integrity of the organization, perhaps, that asked the oath.
Is there a differentiation between the organization and the teacher?
All right.
Okay.
So let's see.
We have permission to ask this.
The organization calibrates over 200.
The teacher calibrates over 200.
Yeah, that happens with a lot of teachers.
The organization goes down.
Some of them are quite famous.
Thank you.
I think it's best to rely on truth.
It stands on its own.
Truth doesn't need an organization to proselytize.
Truth stands on its own.
Truth doesn't need an organization to proselytize, to sell it to the world.
Of course, there were missionaries, you know.
Jesus, grace.
First, I'd like to thank you for everything you've done for me and everyone else.
So, I'm in marketing.
My question is, if I market to a group that's below 200, what is the optimal calibration
of the advertisement for maximum sales and also the spiritual benefit but also the spiritual
benefit of the people.
You want to sell your soul, sell their souls and everybody's BEC.
Well, let's say I have to be an S&M specialist or what?
No, no, I'm in fitness.
S&M, Squibb, sorry.
Fitness, I think fitness.
Oh, fitness.
Right, right.
But there's a lot of people, right, that maybe calibrate at 125, let's just say for an example, if they want to lose weight.
So I don't know where to calibrate my advertising to attract them and also benefit them, help them.
Gee whiz, I don't know.
I really don't know how to answer that.
Because I think that's a behavioral characteristic which crosses all levels of consciousness.
But this morning you...
It's a behavioral characteristic, just like alcoholism.
It inflicts a whole parade of people, you know, from presidents to hobos.
So that behavior is one of addiction, yeah?
That's addiction, yeah.
So what you want to try to teach is how to release yourself from an addiction, you know?
Okay.
Because this morning you mentioned you'd like to be an advertising man, if you can.
Well, yeah, I see things in advertising that I would do much more effectively.
Okay.
That's kind of what I would like to know.
How would you do it more effectively?
For instance, they try to sell AARP.
You know what AARP is?
No.
That's old folks.
American Association of Retired Persons, and they try and sell them health programs and AARP life insurance and health insurance and all.
Okay.
So who do you suppose they have on the TV ad trying to sell them all this stuff for the elderly?
Some young middle-aged pipsqueak of a guy.
I don't care what he thinks about retired people and the benefits of all that.
And I can see somebody with gray hair who looks like he's 70 or something and is facing the reality of how do you cover your medical expenses here,
and then AARP health insurance would make sense.
But some whippersnapper age 39 or 42 is trying to tell me about it, and what does he know about it?
You know what I mean?
It's just not age appropriate.
Okay.
Language appropriate.
I try to do that right now, so okay.
All right.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Can I have a picture, please?
Yeah, I think advertising is fun.
I think it's a, it would be a great hobby to do advertising.
Hello.
Hi.
Your book.
Geico is the best in the world.
Hello.
Hi.
I have been experiencing sin.
Since the Christmas holidays, a consistent pounding in my heart, or fluttering of my heart.
So I've gone to the medical profession and had it all.
Everything is fine.
But often I'm either in a place with people or just even by myself where I feel like my heart is breaking.
Breaking?
Breaking.
And I actually will say that to myself.
I feel like my heart is breaking.
And it's around what is happening either to others in the world.
And the funny part of it is, is that what I do in my life is to assist, I hope, others
with their health.
To assist what?
Others with their health.
Yeah.
By providing.
Well, this is a poor profession for somebody who's going to have a heartbreak at every
tragedy you see around you, isn't it?
Yes.
Oh.
It is.
On one hand, although I see it as the driver, if my heart is breaking for others, it's my
driver to assist them to move forward in their life.
So you're relieving their pain to relieve your own pain, is that it?
That's certainly a perspective.
I mean, that is a perspective.
I haven't thought of it from that perspective.
Well, a professional is detached, you see.
And you see each person living out.
Life's lessons, which are dictated by divinity and the very act of creation of human life,
et cetera.
And you just accept the forms that it takes without having to go through personal identification
with it.
So it's about.
You're doing personal identification with it.
So it's about detaching from that and providing the information, detaching myself and providing
the information to others.
Yes.
You have to detach yourself.
Because you're not serving them.
No.
You're not serving them to the highest possible good by going through the whole thing yourself.
You're not serving them to the highest good.
The highest good would be more accepting their condition, accepting their condition for their
highest good, for their highest good, for their highest good.
Not trying to cure them for your highest good.
Okay.
Thank you.
I got that.
Yeah.
You know, they, I used to go to, nobody wanted to go to the nursing home, you see.
So for some years, I was the only psychiatrist.
I was the only one.
I was the only psychiatrist.
They would go to the nursing homes in the county, you know.
I went all across.
If it doesn't, I'm on the way home every day.
And the concern, the family would be concerned about the person having Alzheimer's, you know.
Yes.
You know, dementia.
And the pain was all on the part of the witnessing of the family.
The patient wasn't suffering anything.
I'd say, mom, how you doing?
Oh, they treat me fine here.
I say, how's the food?
Oh, it's very good.
You got any complaints?
No complaints.
Oh, it's very good.
You got any complaints?
No?
No.
You feeling all right?
I all feel fine.
Yeah.
The family is weeping and carrying on.
And the reality here, you know, is fine.
Her reality is perfect.
Yeah, all right.
So what you project onto the situation, I never know anybody with Alzheimer's who
was actually suffering, tell you the truth.
I say how's the food here, mom?
Oh, pretty good.
How did they treat you?
OK.
less complaints than i do you know i'm saying i'm supposed to feel sorry for them no it's just the
model and sympathy of the family oh poor old mother she doesn't remember us anymore yeah
it doesn't remember you that's what's bothering you so it's the ego doesn't remember me that
ain't gonna bother you but it's the narcissism of the people involved i remember my grandmother
was 99 in a visitor in a nursing home and uh you know she didn't know who i was you know
but finally i kept telling her uh you know she she said oh you're a psychiatrist i said yeah
oh i have a grandson he's a psychiatrist in new york city i said gee that certainly sounds
interesting granny and then we kept on talking and i wanted her to tell me more about her grandson
and all of a sudden she was 99 at the time and all of a sudden she broke into tears and said oh
really
that's beautiful thank you yeah then she began to cry oh it's you it's you
thank you very much one time a psychic told me your
grandmother's on the other side and wants you to know you should eat your greens
be sure to eat your greens
good for your joints eat the greens eat your greens hi dr hawkins um you
say in your books that um guilt is the waste product of human thought
guilt is the waste product of human thought i didn't say waste product no byproduct
waste product makes better i said sometimes guilt is therapeutic you know yeah a lot of things you
should feel guilty about so my i mean because it serves a purpose to change your behavior you know
so my question is as thinkingness
begins to subside in us is there an eroding of that guilt of that ego
is that ego karma eroding as the thinkingness subsides it diminishes in its importance and
intensity and uh it it no longer represents uh you know truth on a certain level just how you happen
to feel and you know that it's going to pass okay today you feel guilty tomorrow you won't about the
same thing you know okay good thank you thank you thank you thank you thank you thank you thank you
contextualize it differently thank you hi yes uh dr hawkins i will be engaging in a practice of
holistic iridology very soon and i plan to conduct some serious research
in holistic iridology by itself and also in conjunction with vedic astrology since i'm a advanced
vedic astrologer i've been trained in advanced vedic astrology so my question is is that likely
is the research likely to bear fruit for some impact on the health uh industry or
mental illness for mankind and also how do i overcome the resistance from the medical
establishment for doing this sort of thing if they enter find out you're interested in vedic
astrology they're going to lose their interest in vedic astrology with me and i hope that's the case
they're going to lose their interest in vedic astrology they're going to lose their interest in
Instantly, right
So is there any way around that as a private matter?
But how can I do the conduct research in both fields if I don't announce the Vedic astrology?
Who's going to join you in Vedic astrology? I don't know a single human being who's gonna work
I'm sorry who's going to what I?
Can't imagine who would join you in Vedic astrology
Who is also in medicine? Oh, I'm not asking for someone to join me
I just I was curious about the attacks that I may get from the medical establishment for doing this type of research
Oh, no, they they won't attack you be there. We even know you exist. They just figure you're a wacko out there on your own
With this type of research likely to bear some fruits as far as I don't know
Vedic astrology no the along with holistic iridology
You got me
Is that something that could be calibrated or I don't know because I don't know how to hold it even what you're saying
I don't know what Vedic astrology is. Oh, it's Indian astrology. It's instead of the
tropical
Zodiac
The sidereal Zodiac is used. Yes in this ancient tradition of 5,000 years old
Yeah, Vedic astrology is much older than Western astrology. Yeah, but then holistic iridology is it's been around for years
And is used is much more proven prevalent in Europe
and
I'm thinking of using both disciplines for some serious
We just like a photo if we could thanks, yes it was too remote for me the view
I don't know
Oh, I know
know iridology that the doctor is doing on consciousness and iridology, it was cupillometry.
I really just wanted to come up and say thank you and shake your hand, but if I did have
a question it would be, can I take the two of you home with me?
Yes.
He wants to take us home.
He's adopting us.
Oh, oh.
Or the other way around.
It doesn't really matter.
Then you've got a fetus and everything.
Thanks.
Hi, Doug.
I've studied it a little.
I see.
Just being here, I thought I had some questions and they don't seem relevant anymore.
It's just...
That's a common experience. It's a common experience.
To have a question in your mind, go to a teacher
intending to ask it, and by the time you get there
it's disappeared. That's very common. The answer is already solved
itself. It's already solved itself.
May I consider you my teacher?
May she refer to you as her teacher?
Yes, that's your choice. It's your choice.
Thank you. It's your choice.
You want me to sign all these things here?
Can't help it.
Thank you so much for being here today. It's been just an awesome experience.
I have many questions,
but the one I guess I would like a better understanding
maybe from you is I really experience a lot of
fear.
I've narrowed it down to a fear of loss, and it could be a loss
of material, a loss of status, a loss of
physical. Confrontation is
difficult for me. I've been through
several different trainings and things and
face your fears and things like that are suggested, but those
to me seem like they might be a building up of the ego.
I was just wondering if you could have
had an idea of how to exercise through that
loss of fear or fear of loss.
Well, all right. So some magical
some magical quality has been ascribed to the things that
you fear the loss of like what money, your good looks,
millionaires, what is it you're going to lose?
Or friendship, you know, esteem.
So you're suffering from loss.
Lack and insufficiency, that you lose this friend that's going
to be the end of the line for you.
Yeah. Yeah.
So there's the work called Glamour, which, of course, says
that specialness, specialness is something we project on to
others. Specialness.
So if you lose one thing, you'll just project the specialness
onto something else.
You won't you won't suffer from lack of things upon which to
project.
Specialness until you stop projecting that the source of happiness is
something outside yourself.
The source of happiness is within you and the source is not outside
oneself. The source is not outside oneself.
Why? Because it's not experienced out there.
If the source is out there, you experienced out there, but it's
experienced in here.
That proves that the source is within yourself.
And.
Is that just a process of through prayer?
And yes, you very gradually work your way through it.
Okay.
You know, specialness is something that gets projected onto the
external, especially, you know, whatever the form of the specialness
is, it's still a specialness that without it, you'll be incomplete
and unhappy and miserable and so.
So as I become aware of these things, I'll just discard that.
Because.
Becoming aware of it already releases its hold.
You know, okay.
Okay.
You never, you know, in the common ones are fame will bring me happiness.
Money will bring me happiness.
Good looks, a super sex life, you know, becoming a star.
I mean, those are all the common ones.
We see it acted out every day on television.
We see all the superstars and, you know, they're all in rehab, you know?
They even fail rehab.
It's a contradiction in terms.
Yeah.
How can you be in rehab and also, you know, in a recovery program?
The two are mutually exclusion, exclusory.
Okay.
Yeah.
Very good.
Thank you.
You know, everything, every time something new comes into life that's
ultra pleasing, the thought comes up, you know, what if I get attached to this or something, you know?
Let's do another ohm.
Let's you and I do an ohm?
Let's all do it together.
Oh, let's all do an ohm.
Can we do an ohm today?
We did an ohm.
Yeah, we did one ohm, that's enough.
We did one ohm already today.
Ohm.
I'm being Broadway.
Hi, doc.
Hi.
I was making an effort to surrender the fear of not having a question and
surrender all thought so that.
I wouldn't have a question.
And had I done that very well, I wouldn't have a question.
But I do indeed have a question.
And that is, I'm here with a group of some extraordinary people and we were wondering if you
would like to have dinner with us at Rock Bottom, the place you have to hit before you go up there.
Thank you for your consideration and thank you for being here.
It's been an honor and a pleasure.
All right, thank you.
Thank you for being here.
One of the reasons.
I come here, so I'm hoping to feel your.
Yes.
One of my question is, in some seminar I heard that some people are distant for enlightenment,
so that assume that maybe not everybody are.
Here, sit back, just sit here.
We're not, we're getting some feedback.
Okay, like this?
So in some seminar I heard that not everybody, some are distant.
I don't understand what she's saying at all.
In some seminar she heard.
Some people are distant.
Are distant.
For enlightenment.
Are destined for what?
Enlightenment.
Yeah, in a seminar she heard that some people are destined for enlightenment.
Yes, that's true, yes.
For enlightenment.
Does that mean some are not?
Is that what?
Does that mean some are not distant?
Does that mean that some are not destined?
I wouldn't say that, but it's freedom of choice.
You refuse that.
Okay.
possible. You know, like swimming, you can either refuse it or just drown, you know.
You're not karmically slated to swim or not swim. So karma entails human choice,
so it's a matter of choice, you see. To choose to serve God to the greatest
degree of which one is capable is a decision with profound karmic
implications and consequences, yes. And how do you help someone that would be
autistic, that is autistic? Is there anything to help them out in this prayer?
Other than prayer, there's nothing you can do. Otherwise there would be no karmic
benefit to, or you know, you can't impose your will upon them, you see, okay?
Hello there.
I want to thank you for your books. I've enjoyed several of them. I'm reading
The Truth Versus Falsehood right now. I found the introduction to be just fascinating.
My question, actually it's two parts. It seems as though in the 400 range or 500 range
of our consciousness is where our problems are made and it's where they're solved.
It's the people who run our government and who are running for office. What is
the role in the day-to-day world of people who have enlightenment beyond that, in that
we need it so badly? And I see that so much.
Go ahead.
Okay, I'm saying that we're living in the lower 500s.
Who's living in the lower 500s? Hardly anybody's living in the lower 500s.
The country.
Everybody lives about 200.
Yeah, yeah. I mean, it's in that lower range.
Yeah.
And yet, it seems like we need guidance for the problems that are stacking up. We
have global warming, we have energy reduction, you know, the loss of energies. What...
It's all just news.
I know it's news, but is it real?
You don't have much fact in it, yeah. It's all fallacious, frankly.
So the role of the persons, the people that are of a higher level of consciousness, how
do they interact and influence this?
How do they interact?
How do they influence? When a person is of a higher consciousness, how do they influence?
They don't bother influencing it.
They don't?
Why should they bother influencing it?
So it's just an individual thing?
Yeah.
Well, that's sad.
No, it doesn't, because...
What gathers a lot of political momentum in big parades in Central Park is all fallacious.
You calibrate it with your arm. You get your arm. You get your arm. You get your arm. You
get your arm. You get your arm. You get your arm. You get your arm. You get your arm. You get
your arm. You'll get it negative.
But we need greater vision of how to solve these problems that are coming ahead.
I have a granddaughter that's just starting, and I see her world in 50 years is gonna be
totally different than anything I've ever known.
Oh, yes, yes. You wanna change the course of the world?
Or to improve it?
Do you wanna improve it? Well we're gonna have a meeting in Central Park.
How to improve the world, you can join us.
All right. Are you serious?
course i is he no thank you no muscle testing on that one i've been to so many in central park
saving the world from this saving the world for that saving the world for the other
well the reason i said leary was going to save the world we saved the world at woodstock
well bin laden is a 10 or whatever but he may have a nuclear bomb i mean yeah yeah he made
no he doesn't have one but people like him may well yes does a leader have to spring up within
them within that group you're asking something about the future human knowledge the only the
other counter active influence is human knowledge you know human knowledge is the only thing to
counteract ignorance so all we do is try to share what we have learned in a mode of
learning that the world has not been familiar with before and you can quickly find out for
yourself that which is integrous that which is truthful that which is meaningful and not waste
a lot of time on political hoopla yeah i try to do that so all right well thank you the best thing a
lot of people could do for the world is to stay home and stay out of trouble get off the internet
and stay out of trouble and stay out of trouble and stay out of trouble and stay out of trouble
hi dr hawkins yeah i've been a sales professional for 24 years and one of my concerns is that when
i make promises to clients commitments and service i have other colleagues in the company who break
those promises who don't deliver the service yeah is is it am i karmically responsible for
my company failing those clients who have trusted me with the service i don't know it's a hard one
it's a hard one
i don't know how to answer it because i they trust me and and here i'm making promises yeah
commitment i can think of various instances like that too yeah a company was actually
integrity from anyone then they began to uh franchise out and the franchisees
use the company name to rip people off yeah yeah yeah what can you do about it it's a difficult one
24 years of a lot of broken promises and i'm as a burden yeah you know i'm worrying it's
going to be on my shoulders for a long time i don't know how to answer that it's a difficult
situation yeah maybe i should just quit do something for it how old are you i'm i'm 59
59 and my corporation pushes me for sales i'm the top producer i've been that way for years
and i'm tired of it he's a top producer and he's been that way for years and he's tired of it i'm
tired why don't you do your job to the most integralist level you can do it and try to
influence others to be integrists also i mean i quit jobs that when i realized that they that
they were not integrists yeah but i was very young and it was not a very important thing you know
to do it after 26 years it'd be different i think i tried to use my influence to bring it
more to integrity alignment yes yes that i will do until i retire i'll do my best i think i would
probably do okay a little too late to change horses yes sir yeah thank you very much
hi i just want to look you in the eye yes what's up you
and we're gonna we're gonna get a picture yeah all right yeah that's
tough you've been with the company quite a while and you find out they're
policing the customers and sometimes companies change they start out in figures and then go down
i don't know benny to start but start off below the level and move up
hello
thank you i bet you're tired um sort of piggybacking on the other question last year i
went around the world and as i got further closer to america it was you know people who hate bush
and hate the war and as i got closer to iran and iraq i don't understand what she's saying she's
saying she went around the world and then she got closer to iran and iran
iran and iraq
further away it was um people saying if if we weren't there would be genocide it would be awful
there would be more many many more people killed so about the middle east right right so with it
our president's tends to suppress well it's the dilemma of the consciousness of trying to
rise and evolve and which is worse to be at war to not be at war people are going to suffering
work our families our children our kids our children our children our children our kids and
people are going to be killed either way, how do you reconcile it?
Reconcile it with what?
With whether we should be there or not, what the war status situation is.
What's your question?
My question is, should we stay in Iraq or should we pull out?
That's all you want, just a little question like that, right?
Oh, gee, it's a good thing you didn't ask me a hard one.
It's a good thing you didn't ask me a hard one.
But it's important.
Important to you.
Yeah, it is important to me.
Do you have relatives in Iraq?
No.
Why is it important to you?
Because.
Because you've made it important in your head.
In and of itself, it's probably of no importance to the evolution of mankind in the latest.
Oh, it's not important to evolution of mankind?
I doubt it.
It's just a blimp on the.
Radar screen, like other wars and things, is just something that.
Man has been at war 97% of recorded time.
Why should he change?
Okay, so surrender.
Surrender.
Surrender to God, not.
That's what I'm saying, am I?
Okay, thank you.
97% of recorded history, man has been at war.
Okay, thank you very much.
He makes all kinds of money.
He makes all, he becomes famous.
He becomes a hero.
He becomes Napoleon.
He becomes the victim.
I mean, the payoff of war is tremendous.
The profits to me made are dazzling.
One defense contract is worth billions, billions.
Right.
You tell me how you're going to bring it to an end, okay?
When you figure it out, give me a call.
The glamour of war, the glamour of it, the parades, the macho.
Okay, so today you said something.
We can't just depend on the evolution of consciousness
because it fluctuates, it rises and subsides.
It was at 207, it dropped to 204.
So my question is, if we can't depend on the evolution of consciousness,
when consciousness is all that exists, how can we not depend on it?
And what do we depend on?
Well, you're mixing levels there.
Consciousness is an infinite field of energy, you see.
No.
Human consciousness.
Human consciousness is just one expression of it, you see.
It's not the same thing as the infinite field of consciousness itself,
which is nonlinear and doesn't have any content, much less humanness,
but it does incorporate humanness as well.
So what is the question again?
So if we're depending on the evolution of human consciousness.
No, you can't depend on it.
I didn't say anything about depending on it.
Right, you said we can't just depend.
The level of the sea is this high and now it's this high.
You can't depend on it.
No.
So what do we depend on?
Your own self.
Okay.
Your own spiritual awareness.
Right, which is my consciousness, right?
It's yours, not the world's.
You're talking about consciousness as an abstract universality.
Well, or collective.
I'm talking about collective.
Your own personal consciousness.
I never say anything about depending on the overall level of consciousness.
The overall level of consciousness was 207 calibrated.
Now it's 204, right?
See?
So I don't know what you mean by depending on it.
I mean expecting it to constantly get better was a false premise.
It goes up and apparently it also goes down.
Right, but isn't it like anything that we, you know, thoughts arise, they subside.
There's times that we make quantum leaps in our life.
Yes.
And then there's times we fall back.
But then when we move forward, we're usually going further than where we were before we...
Right.
Could be and could be not, you know.
Yeah.
Yes and no.
Okay.
Thank you.
You can't depend on it, in other words, is what I'm saying.
Okay, I have a question.
If the consciousness level has dropped, could it be that someone of a high calibration has left the planet
and that no one has replaced him at that time?
That's a possibility.
Yes, that's a possibility.
Okay.
Yeah, baby.
I'll show him.
I'll mess with you.
I want to talk to Chase.
Okay, I want you to read this to him so that he'll sign it.
He signed it twice, but...
My question is, I work with cancer patients in intensive care, cancer hospital,
and I drive two hours a day and I listen to your tapes and all that.
Is that helpful to keep listening to them?
Because I'm obsessed with them.
Lots of people do.
I listen to them.
It becomes second nature.
Okay.
In other words...
They learn it by familiarity, and then through familiarity, it just seems obvious.
You say, well, that's obvious.
And that's helpful.
You do it all along, you know?
That also would be helpful to the patients.
Well, you're not doing it...
I mean, yes, of course, everything...
In other words, if your consciousness advances, you're going to be of greater benefit to the patients, yes.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Sometimes I would have patients hanging on to life because they...
They didn't have permission to leave, and I'd say, you know, it's okay to die, it's okay to let go of the body, it's okay...
Do your pictures.
It's okay to die.
Oh, okay.
And they go, oh, and die.
They're hanging on for the family, they're hanging on for all kinds of things.
I'd say, it's okay to leave, it's okay.
Oh, okay.
Yes.
I would like to thank Susan for making sure you keep...
Keep eating, and that...
And that you don't wear shirts with holes in them.
Oh, he still does.
He does.
I have an experience.
A couple of weeks ago, meditating, I was totally blank, which in itself is a little unusual.
And then I had a very, very strong picture in my mind of going...
I was up in an elevator, and there were streaks of light, so I could visualize going up, okay?
And I kept going up and up, and then the thought came to me, gee, maybe I'm going to have a knowingness when I hit 500.
That may be...
And in that instant, the picture left.
That was it.
Is that meaningful at all?
Yeah, it can be.
That's a fact.
Yeah.
It's a fact.
It's a fact, yes.
What meaning does it have?
Can you tell me?
What does level 500 mean?
Oh, 500 to me means loving.
Well, to you, too.
In other words, that you let go of anything that is non-loving in your life, and dedicate your life to loving this, which is really the fastest way to God that I know of.
To let go of that which is ungodly.
Okay.
When I hit 500, will I have a knowingness, or just I'll be there and...
You don't need a knowingness.
I don't.
No.
I love my new dog.
My new dog loves me.
Neither of us need a knowingness, you know what I'm saying?
Oh, is it wussy-wussy, and the dog goes wussy-wussy, and...
Do you want to hear about my dog?
It's about five minutes right there, isn't it?
Okay.
You just enjoy the reality of what it is.
When you notice the beauty of all of nature.
It's stunning.
And you're just awesome.
All of a sudden, you say, my God.
My God.
You look at the bark of that tree, and how it is, and you can see that it's almost breathing, and it comes as a revelation, you know?
Well, I've almost had that experience.
Yeah, you're close to it.
It won't be happening.
Okay.
Don't worry about it.
Thank you.
Don't worry, God's love.
It's all well.
Thank you.
Small gift for you, Susie.
I'd love to.
Last time I was here, I didn't have a question for you, and I left experiencing, for the first time in my life, something that I understood to be unconditional loving.
And I just feel enormous gratitude for having been in the presence.
And I did have a question as well about contemplation and meditation.
You recommend contemplation, but you also speak about...
I've heard you on one occasion say you recommend everyone to do some meditating, and I was wondering what you recommend, and then I thought...
Well, there's meditation and contemplation, and I think contemplation is more useful in many ways.
The meditation, you usually set aside a time of the day and a certain place and a certain style, and it sort of removes you from the ongoing course of daily life.
And then, if your life gets...
If your life gets very busy, what happens is the time assigned to meditation gets smaller and smaller.
And finally, you know, you can't really...
You're not going to catch the subway in time.
You can sort of skip it.
It's more vulnerable, although I did it for many years.
Contemplation is more a lifestyle, a lifestyle in which you relate to life through the level of awareness, consciousness awareness itself, rather than focused meditation.
I was wondering if you had an actual...
What type of meditation that you'd recommend for someone who...
Yeah, there's a classic Zen meditation, you know.
You know, it's classic.
I'm on the First Zen Institute back in the 1950s.
I forget what it was.
Yeah.
They said we could go 15 minutes over.
They changed it, and we're already 10 over, so yeah.
Right, so if we have to come to an end, we will come to an end.
I didn't know what time they said we should leave.
Thank you.
We're happy to be cooperative in any way that serves the highest good.
What a blessing to be here with you all this beautiful day.
Usually we've got some beautiful music that we can conclude with, but you know it's the end.
Oh.
You hold intention in mind to see what happens.
What a great blessing.
What a wonderment.
What a miracle.
So many make...
Magnificent people here all at one time.
We join together, you know.
We join together as a very far powerful force to counteract the negativity of the world.
People say, what can I do?
Please do nothing.
Please be.
Be that.
And then you don't have to do anything.
Why?
Because when you do, the world resists.
If you try to save the world, it's going to resist you.
Probably have you arrested and assassinated.
If possible.
We influence everything by what we have become.
Become the ultimate fulfillment of what you know your spiritual capacity is, you know.
That way we bless all of human life.
There's nothing they can do about it.
If you raise the level of the sea, you raise the level of all the ships at sea.
What the human ego wants to do is go around lifting ships.
We'll lift this ship.
And we'll lift this ship.
And we'll save these people and lift this ship.
That's very hard.
Very expensive.
Catastrophic.
We're going to save the people in foreign countries.
You've got to first save yourself.
So what we do is by unconditional lovingness, we try to lift the level of the sea.
You know, you raise the level of the sea.
And when you raise the level of the sea, you raise the level of the sea.
You raise every ship afloat without having to lift one single ship.
So our lovingness radiates forth into the world.
The world can't do anything about it.
If you choose to be forgiving and love and try to see the upside of everyone,
even those who are insanely wicked, you say, I'm sorry, oh, Lord.
The only pleasure they have is to be forgiven.
The only pleasure they have is left is that of wickedness.
I mean, how pathetic.
How pathetic.
The only pleasure you have left is the suffering of others.
That is the most pathetic condition I can imagine.
Forsaken completely by God, by your own rejection of divinity, denial of God.
Uh-huh.
We all give thanks for our existence.
Right now, let's just go like this and say, silently in our mind,
I think the old.
Oh, Lord, for my existence, the great gift of life itself, do I treasure.
I give thanks to thee, oh, Lord, in the name of all of mankind.
I think that's all we can do for the human condition.
So I think we've just done what we can do for the human condition.
Is it not?
To bless everyone with unconditional love.
Let's see if there's anything more we can do.
Oh.
Is that all we can do?
Yes.
So that means nothing left.
Nothing left for us to feel guilty about.
That we didn't do this and we didn't do that.
You know how the human ego likes guilt.
And so we don't have anything left to feel guilty about.
Isn't that going to be a tough evening?
How are we going to get by without anything to feel guilty about?
Uh-oh.
I can feel guilty that I don't feel guilty about anything.
Oh.
Thank you, Lord, for saving me.
Let's give him a good blessing.
She says I have to bless everybody and then let him go.
God bless you all.
I love you all.
I adore you all.
In God's name I do bless thee.
Amen.
Get it out.
God bless you all.
Thank you so much.
Without you, the work would not, would not work.
Thank you.
Would not be what it is today.
We want to thank you, each and every one of you.
And thank you so much for your presence here.
We appreciate it.
Thank you again.
Thank you.
Look at those beautiful flowers.
Isn't that beautiful?
Look at those.
What do they call these?
This is awesome.
And the leaves behind them.
Isn't that awesome?
Yeah.