uh
uh is
uh is this
uh is this mic
uh is this mic for
uh is this mic for phone
uh is this mic for phone on?
As
As I
uh is this mic for phone on?
As I pointed
As I pointed out
uh is this mic for phone on?
As I pointed out the
As I pointed out the nature
uh is this mic for phone on?
As I pointed out the nature of
As I pointed out the nature of the
uh is this mic for phone on?
As I pointed out the nature of the field
of
of consciousness,
there
there is
of consciousness,
there is no
there is no here
of consciousness,
there is no here or
there is no here or there.
There
There is
There is no
There is no center.
And
And the
There is no center.
And the other
And the other thing
There is no center.
And the other thing I
And the other thing I didn't
There is no center.
And the other thing I didn't point
And the other thing I didn't point out,
there
there is
there is no
there is no then
there is no then or
there is no then or now.
All
All time
there is no then or now.
All time is
All time is available
there is no then or now.
All time is available now.
Consequently,
Consequently, because
Consequently, because the
Consequently, because the it's
nonlinear,
there's
there's no
there's no then
there's no then and
there's no then and no
there's no then and no now.
So,
So, if
there's no then and no now.
So, if I
So, if I ask
there's no then and no now.
So, if I ask what
So, if I ask what is
there's no then and no now.
So, if I ask what is the
So, if I ask what is the energy
there's no then and no now.
So, if I ask what is the energy of
Cleopatra,
I
I can
Cleopatra,
I can ask
I can ask it
Cleopatra,
I can ask it now.
I can ask it now. Even
Cleopatra,
I can ask it now. Even though
I can ask it now. Even though your
Cleopatra,
I can ask it now. Even though your mind
says,
says, well,
says, well, that
says, well, that was
says, well, that was a
says, well, that was a couple
says, well, that was a couple thousand
years
years ago.
In
In a
In a linear
In a linear interpretation
In a linear interpretation of
In a linear interpretation of the
In a linear interpretation of the field
of
of consciousness,
In a linear interpretation of the field
of consciousness, there's
of consciousness, there's a
In a linear interpretation of the field
of consciousness, there's a then
of consciousness, there's a then and
In a linear interpretation of the field
of consciousness, there's a then and a
now.
In
In reality,
now.
In reality, there
In reality, there is
now.
In reality, there is only
In reality, there is only now.
now.
In reality, there is only now. There
In reality, there is only now. There is
only
only the
only the present.
only the present. All
only the present. All time
only the present. All time is
only the present. All time is equally
now.
All
All space
All space and
All space and dimensions
All space and dimensions are
All space and dimensions are here.
Therefore,
Therefore, everything
All space and dimensions are here.
Therefore, everything is
Therefore, everything is knowable
All space and dimensions are here.
Therefore, everything is knowable here
and
and now.
and now. Okay,
and now. Okay, we
and now. Okay, we just
and now. Okay, we just that's
and now. Okay, we just that's the
and now. Okay, we just that's the truth.
Truth
Truth is
everything
everything is
everything is knowable
everything is knowable here
everything is knowable here and
everything is knowable here and now
right
right this
everything is knowable here and now
right this minute.
right this minute. Everything
everything is knowable here and now
right this minute. Everything that
right this minute. Everything that ever
was
was historically
is
is the
was historically
is the same
is the same as
was historically
is the same as now.
So
So when
So when I
So when I ask
So when I ask her
So when I ask her for
So when I ask her for the
>> what?
Oh,
Oh, I
Oh, I forgot
Oh, I forgot to
Oh, I forgot to interpret
Oh, I forgot to interpret it.
>> Actually,
>> Actually, the
Oh, I forgot to interpret it.
>> Actually, the old
>> Actually, the old Koreans
Oh, I forgot to interpret it.
>> Actually, the old Koreans are
>> Actually, the old Koreans are are
Oh, I forgot to interpret it.
>> Actually, the old Koreans are are well
familiar
familiar with
familiar with his
familiar with his teaching.
>> No,
>> No, I
familiar with his teaching.
>> No, I figure
>> No, I figure you
familiar with his teaching.
>> No, I figure you will
>> No, I figure you will assimilate
familiar with his teaching.
>> No, I figure you will assimilate what
>> No, I figure you will assimilate what I
said
said and
said and interpret
said and interpret it
said and interpret it back
said and interpret it back to
said and interpret it back to them.
>> There
>> There is
said and interpret it back to them.
>> There is no
>> There is no then
said and interpret it back to them.
>> There is no then or
>> There is no then or now.
said and interpret it back to them.
>> There is no then or now. There's
>> There is no then or now. There's only
now.
now. Yeah.
There's
There's no
now. Yeah.
There's no here
There's no here or
now. Yeah.
There's no here or there
and
and there's
and there's only
and there's only now.
and there's only now. Oh,
and there's only now. Oh, yeah.
and there's only now. Oh, yeah. Okay.
>> No,
>> No, you
and there's only now. Oh, yeah. Okay.
>> No, you go
>> No, you go ahead
and there's only now. Oh, yeah. Okay.
>> No, you go ahead and
>> No, you go ahead and say
and there's only now. Oh, yeah. Okay.
>> No, you go ahead and say what
>> No, you go ahead and say what I
and there's only now. Oh, yeah. Okay.
>> No, you go ahead and say what I said.
Yes,
>> there's
>> there's no
Yes,
>> there's no then,
>> there's no then, no,
Yes,
>> there's no then, no, there's
>> there's no then, no, there's only
Yes,
>> there's no then, no, there's only now.
>> Uh,
there's
there's only
>> Uh,
there's only here
there's only here right
>> Uh,
there's only here right now.
there's only here right now. That's
>> Uh,
there's only here right now. That's all
there
there is.
>> Yeah.
So
every
every anything
So
every anything that's
every anything that's ever
So
every anything that's ever been
every anything that's ever been known
any
any time
any time in
any time in all
any time in all of
any time in all of history
any time in all of history is
any time in all of history is knowable
right
right here,
any time in all of history is knowable
right here, right
right here, right now.
Um,
>> okay.
>> First
>> First question.
>> First question. Um,
>> First question. Um, it's
>> First question. Um, it's for
>> First question. Um, it's for him.
>> First question. Um, it's for him. Um,
>> First question. Um, it's for him. Um, I
have
have a
>> First question. Um, it's for him. Um, I
have a hearing
have a hearing disability
and
and when
and when I
>> I
>> I have
a
a hearing
a hearing disability
>> and
Yeah,
Yeah, I
Yeah, I like
Yeah, I like that.
And
And then
Yeah, I like that.
And then um
And then um when
Yeah, I like that.
And then um when I'm
And then um when I'm alone,
Yeah, I like that.
And then um when I'm alone, I
And then um when I'm alone, I don't
experience
experience myself
experience myself as
experience myself as one
experience myself as one who
experience myself as one who has
experience myself as one who has that
disability,
disability, but
experience myself as one who has that
disability, but when
disability, but when I'm
experience myself as one who has that
disability, but when I'm with
disability, but when I'm with others,
experience myself as one who has that
disability, but when I'm with others, I
experience
experience myself
experience myself as
experience myself as somebody
experience myself as somebody with
hearing
hearing disability.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Is
>> Is there
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Is there any
>> Is there any advice
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Is there any advice that
>> Is there any advice that you
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Is there any advice that you want
>> Is there any advice that you want to
give
>> in
>> in relation
give
>> in relation to
>> in relation to this?
>> Uh
it
it doesn't
>> Uh
it doesn't make
it doesn't make any
>> Uh
it doesn't make any difference
it doesn't make any difference which
>> Uh
it doesn't make any difference which way
you
you hold
you hold it.
One
One is
you hold it.
One is holding
One is holding it
you hold it.
One is holding it more
One is holding it more linear
and
and the
and the other
and the other is
and the other is more
and the other is more nonlinear.
It
It doesn't
and the other is more nonlinear.
It doesn't make
It doesn't make any
and the other is more nonlinear.
It doesn't make any difference.
>> It
>> It won't
>> It won't really
>> It won't really make
>> It won't really make any
>> It won't really make any difference
>> It won't really make any difference how
how
how you
>> It won't really make any difference how
how you hold
how you hold it.
>> It won't really make any difference how
how you hold it. Yeah.
Mhm.
>> I'll
>> I'll write
Mhm.
>> I'll write him
>> I'll write him later.
Mhm.
>> I'll write him later. Yeah,
>> I'll write him later. Yeah, I'm
Mhm.
>> I'll write him later. Yeah, I'm going
>> I'll write him later. Yeah, I'm going to
write
write him.
write him. I'm
write him. I'm going
write him. I'm going to
write him. I'm going to write
write him. I'm going to write him
write him. I'm going to write him the
answer.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. Mhm.
>> Okay.
Yes.
Yes. When
Yes. When you're
Yes. When you're with
Yes. When you're with other
Yes. When you're with other people,
Yes. When you're with other people, you
have
have to
Yes. When you're with other people, you
have to remember
have to remember that
Yes. When you're with other people, you
have to remember that you're
have to remember that you're hard
Yes. When you're with other people, you
have to remember that you're hard of
hearing
because
because you're
hearing
because you're used
because you're used to
hearing
because you're used to it
because you're used to it by
hearing
because you're used to it by yourself.
And
And I
And I find
And I find myself
And I find myself saying,
And I find myself saying, "What?
And I find myself saying, "What? What?"
When
When I'm
And I find myself saying, "What? What?"
When I'm by
When I'm by myself,
And I find myself saying, "What? What?"
When I'm by myself, I
When I'm by myself, I don't
And I find myself saying, "What? What?"
When I'm by myself, I don't have
When I'm by myself, I don't have to
And I find myself saying, "What? What?"
When I'm by myself, I don't have to say
what
I
I drive
what
I drive Susan
I drive Susan crazy
what
I drive Susan crazy with.
I drive Susan crazy with. What?
>> Then
>> Then she
>> Then she speaks
>> Then she speaks louder.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. uh
>> Then she speaks louder.
>> Okay. uh deep
>> Okay. uh deep inside
>> Then she speaks louder.
>> Okay. uh deep inside me
>> Okay. uh deep inside me there
>> Then she speaks louder.
>> Okay. uh deep inside me there is
>> Okay. uh deep inside me there is a
>> Then she speaks louder.
>> Okay. uh deep inside me there is a deep
sorrow
sorrow and
sorrow and emotional
sorrow and emotional agitation
and
and because
sorrow and emotional agitation
and because of
and because of that
sorrow and emotional agitation
and because of that I
and because of that I I'm
sorrow and emotional agitation
and because of that I I'm having
and because of that I I'm having problem
with
with the
with the my
with the my liver
with the my liver and
with the my liver and my
with the my liver and my whole
with the my liver and my whole back
with the my liver and my whole back I
have
have a
with the my liver and my whole back I
have a sort
have a sort of
with the my liver and my whole back I
have a sort of cracking
have a sort of cracking pain
with the my liver and my whole back I
have a sort of cracking pain and
have a sort of cracking pain and it's
been
been for
been for 10
been for 10 years
>> and
>> and how
been for 10 years
>> and how can
>> and how can I
been for 10 years
>> and how can I be
>> and how can I be cure
been for 10 years
>> and how can I be cure of
>> and how can I be cure of this
>> oh
>> oh stop
>> oh stop trying
>> oh stop trying to
>> oh stop trying to cure
>> oh stop trying to cure it
uh
uh surrender
>> oh stop trying to cure it
uh surrender to
uh surrender to it
>> oh stop trying to cure it
uh surrender to it at
uh surrender to it at great
>> oh stop trying to cure it
uh surrender to it at great depth
>> and
>> and stop
>> and stop trying
>> and stop trying to
>> and stop trying to cure
>> and stop trying to cure it.
You
You cannot
>> and stop trying to cure it.
You cannot cure
You cannot cure it
but
but you
but you can
but you can disappear
but you can disappear it.
>> Two
>> Two different
but you can disappear it.
>> Two different things.
That
That which
That which you
That which you don't
That which you don't resist
That which you don't resist you
disappear.
>> And
>> And that
>> And that which
>> And that which you
>> And that which you resist
>> And that which you resist you
>> And that which you resist you propagate.
Uh
he
he I'm
he I'm sure
he I'm sure he's
he I'm sure he's tried
he I'm sure he's tried prayer
he I'm sure he's tried prayer and
meditation.
>> Huh?
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, that's
>> Huh?
>> Yeah, that's what
>> Yeah, that's what I'm
>> Huh?
>> Yeah, that's what I'm doing.
So
So don't
So don't resist
So don't resist it.
>> Don't
>> Don't label
So don't resist it.
>> Don't label it
>> Don't label it anything.
>> Don't
>> Don't call
>> Don't call it
>> Don't call it anything.
and
and try
>> Don't call it anything.
and try acupuncture.
We're
We're we're
We're we're stuck
We're we're stuck with
We're we're stuck with what
We're we're stuck with what we
We're we're stuck with what we resist.
>> So
>> So you
We're we're stuck with what we resist.
>> So you surrender
>> So you surrender all
We're we're stuck with what we resist.
>> So you surrender all resistance.
In
In that
In that way
In that way you
In that way you disappear
In that way you disappear it.
So
So you
In that way you disappear it.
So you can't
So you can't cure
In that way you disappear it.
So you can't cure it
So you can't cure it but
In that way you disappear it.
So you can't cure it but you
So you can't cure it but you can
disappear
disappear it
by
by non-resistance.
The
The rest
The rest is
The rest is up
The rest is up to
The rest is up to karma.
It's
It's like
The rest is up to karma.
It's like you
It's like you have
The rest is up to karma.
It's like you have a
It's like you have a certain
The rest is up to karma.
It's like you have a certain amount
It's like you have a certain amount of
suffering
suffering that
suffering that you've
suffering that you've caused
suffering that you've caused others
and
and now
suffering that you've caused others
and now to
and now to undo
suffering that you've caused others
and now to undo it
and now to undo it karmically,
suffering that you've caused others
and now to undo it karmically, you
and now to undo it karmically, you take
it
it back
it back upon
it back upon yourself.
>> So
>> So you
it back upon yourself.
>> So you thank
>> So you thank God
it back upon yourself.
>> So you thank God for
>> So you thank God for the
it back upon yourself.
>> So you thank God for the suffering.
Thank
Thank God
that
that I
Thank God
that I can
that I can undo
Thank God
that I can undo this
that I can undo this negative
Thank God
that I can undo this negative karma.
So
So eventually
So eventually you
So eventually you will
So eventually you will rise
So eventually you will rise above
So eventually you will rise above it.
Eventually
Eventually you
So eventually you will rise above it.
Eventually you will
Eventually you will rise
So eventually you will rise above it.
Eventually you will rise above
Eventually you will rise above it.
>> So
>> So do
>> So do good
>> So do good works
and
and love
>> So do good works
and love everything
and love everything that
>> So do good works
and love everything that love
and love everything that love everything
as
as it
as it is
>> and
>> and surrender
as it is
>> and surrender it
>> and surrender it to
as it is
>> and surrender it to God.
Then
Then it's
Then it's God's
Then it's God's problem
right
right now.
Then it's God's problem
right now. You're
right now. You're taking
Then it's God's problem
right now. You're taking on
right now. You're taking on God's
problem.
problem. Let
problem. Let God
problem. Let God worry
problem. Let God worry about
problem. Let God worry about it.
problem. Let God worry about it. God
created
created you.
Um
Um when
Um when you
Um when you said
Um when you said that
Um when you said that you
Um when you said that you created
Um when you said that you created a
certain
certain amount
Um when you said that you created a
certain amount of
certain amount of suffering
Um when you said that you created a
certain amount of suffering to
certain amount of suffering to others,
are
are you
are you saying
are you saying that
are you saying that he
are you saying that he did
are you saying that he did it
are you saying that he did it in
are you saying that he did it in the
are you saying that he did it in the in
past
past life
are you saying that he did it in the in
past life or
past life or in
are you saying that he did it in the in
past life or in this
past life or in this life?
are you saying that he did it in the in
past life or in this life? Past
past life or in this life? Past life.
>> Past
>> Past life.
>> So
it's
it's a
it's a way
it's a way of
it's a way of regaining
it's a way of regaining karmic
it's a way of regaining karmic merit.
Karmic
Karmic merit.
So
So you
So you surrender
So you surrender everything
So you surrender everything to
So you surrender everything to God
and
and stop
So you surrender everything to God
and stop complaining.
and
and bump.
He's
He's already
and bump.
He's already believed.
You
You know
You know the
You know the story.
A
A man
You know the story.
A man is
A man is is
all
all kinds
all kinds of
all kinds of illnesses.
And
And his
all kinds of illnesses.
And his wife
And his wife is
all kinds of illnesses.
And his wife is mean
And his wife is mean to
all kinds of illnesses.
And his wife is mean to him.
And
And all
And all his
And all his bones
And all his bones hurt
>> and
>> and he's
And all his bones hurt
>> and he's always
>> and he's always in
And all his bones hurt
>> and he's always in pain
>> and he's always in pain and
And all his bones hurt
>> and he's always in pain and suffering.
So
So he
So he says,
So he says, "God,
So he says, "God, God,
So he says, "God, God, what
So he says, "God, God, what is
So he says, "God, God, what is it?"
A
A voice
So he says, "God, God, what is it?"
A voice comes
A voice comes out
So he says, "God, God, what is it?"
A voice comes out of
A voice comes out of the
So he says, "God, God, what is it?"
A voice comes out of the heaven.
>> Peter,
>> Peter, there's
>> Peter, there's something
>> Peter, there's something about
>> Peter, there's something about you
>> Peter, there's something about you that
just
just pisses
>> Peter, there's something about you that
just pisses me
just pisses me off.
Is
Is it
Is it is
Is it is that
Is it is that to
Is it is that to him
Is it is that to him or
>> That's
>> That's funny.
>> No,
>> No, it's
>> it's
>> it's a
>> No, it's
>> it's a joke.
>> it's a joke. But
>> No, it's
>> it's a joke. But uh
>> it's
>> it's a
>> it's a joke.
>> It's
>> It's a
>> it's a joke.
>> It's a joke.
>> It's a joke. You
>> it's a joke.
>> It's a joke. You know
>> that's
>> that's right
>> because
>> because all
>> that's right
>> because all of
>> because all of us
>> that's right
>> because all of us when
>> because all of us when we
>> that's right
>> because all of us when we suffer
>> because all of us when we suffer things
go
go badly
go badly you
go badly you know
go badly you know in
go badly you know in a
go badly you know in a way
go badly you know in a way we
go badly you know in a way we say
go badly you know in a way we say why
why
why me
go badly you know in a way we say why
why me god
why me god you
go badly you know in a way we say why
why me god you know
why me god you know why
go badly you know in a way we say why
why me god you know why you
why me god you know why you know
I
I think
I think we
I think we also
I think we also share
I think we also share in
I think we also share in the
I think we also share in the collective
consciousness
consciousness of
I think we also share in the collective
consciousness of mankind
and
and a
and a certain
and a certain amount
and a certain amount of
and a certain amount of suffering
and a certain amount of suffering is
and a certain amount of suffering is not
personal
personal but
and a certain amount of suffering is not
personal but collective
because
because of
because of the
because of the fact
because of the fact that
because of the fact that you're
because of the fact that you're human
Fore!
Foreign! Foreign!
You
You don't
stand
stand finished.
Part
Part of
stand finished.
Part of it
Part of it is
stand finished.
Part of it is the
Part of it is the collective
stand finished.
Part of it is the collective karma
Part of it is the collective karma of
humanness
humanness itself.
Don't
Don't forget
humanness itself.
Don't forget in
Don't forget in the
humanness itself.
Don't forget in the B
Don't forget in the B the
humanness itself.
Don't forget in the B the biblical
Don't forget in the B the biblical in
the
the Bible
the Bible it
the Bible it says
the Bible it says man
the Bible it says man fell
the Bible it says man fell from
the Bible it says man fell from grace
fell
fell from
the Bible it says man fell from grace
fell from grace
fell from grace from
the Bible it says man fell from grace
fell from grace from the
fell from grace from the garden
the Bible it says man fell from grace
fell from grace from the garden of
fell from grace from the garden of Eden
from
from the
from the nonlinear
from the nonlinear world
from the nonlinear world of
enlightenment
enlightenment and
from the nonlinear world of
enlightenment and non-suffering
enlightenment and non-suffering he
from the nonlinear world of
enlightenment and non-suffering he fell
into
into the
into the linear
into the linear world
into the linear world uh
into the linear world uh where
into the linear world uh where he's
subject
subject to
into the linear world uh where he's
subject to suffering.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, next
>> Okay, next question.
>> Okay, next question. Um
>> yes,
>> yes, go
>> Okay, next question. Um
>> yes, go ahead.
>> yes, go ahead. He
he
he likes
he likes um
he likes um his
he likes um his problem
he likes um his problem is
he likes um his problem is he
he likes um his problem is he likes
criminals
criminals and
he likes um his problem is he likes
criminals and an
criminals and an antisocial
he likes um his problem is he likes
criminals and an antisocial sort
criminals and an antisocial sort of
psychopath.
>> He
>> He likes
psychopath.
>> He likes them.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Yeah. And then
>> Yeah. And then not
>> Yeah. And then not not
>> Yeah. And then not not only
>> Yeah. And then not not only that,
>> Yeah. And then not not only that, he
tends
tends to
>> Yeah. And then not not only that, he
tends to identify
tends to identify with
>> Yeah. And then not not only that, he
tends to identify with them
tends to identify with them and
>> Yeah. And then not not only that, he
tends to identify with them and he
tends to identify with them and he wants
to
to get
to get out
to get out of
to get out of this.
>> Oh
>> Oh yes.
>> Bad
>> Bad state.
>> He
>> He needs
>> Bad state.
>> He needs salvation.
The
The only
The only way
The only way you
The only way you reach
The only way you reach salvation
The only way you reach salvation is
The only way you reach salvation is you
have
have to
The only way you reach salvation is you
have to rebuke.
have to rebuke. Rebuke
The only way you reach salvation is you
have to rebuke. Rebuke and
have to rebuke. Rebuke and deny
that
that which
that which is
that which is negative.
It
It is
that which is negative.
It is like
It is like the
that which is negative.
It is like the criminal
It is like the criminal who
that which is negative.
It is like the criminal who keeps
getting
getting pulled
getting pulled back
getting pulled back into
getting pulled back into the
getting pulled back into the criminal
gang
and
and he
and he and
and he and he
and he and he goes
and he and he goes to
and he and he goes to prison
and he and he goes to prison over
and he and he goes to prison over and
over
over and
and he and he goes to prison over and
over and over
over and over again.
I
I think
I think it's
I think it's only
I think it's only curable
I think it's only curable by
I think it's only curable by spiritual
methods.
Many
Many people
Many people in
Many people in the
Many people in the 12step
Many people in the 12step group,
Many people in the 12step group, AA
groups,
led
led lives
led lives of
led lives of drunkenness,
led lives of drunkenness, violence,
criminality,
imbecility,
and
and they
imbecility,
and they would
and they would do
imbecility,
and they would do it
and they would do it over
imbecility,
and they would do it over and
and they would do it over and over
imbecility,
and they would do it over and over and
over
over again.
Um,
alcohol.
So
So something
alcohol.
So something similar
So something similar to
alcohol.
So something similar to the
So something similar to the 12step
groups.
groups. 12step
groups. 12step groups
like
like aa
is
is the
is the only
is the only answer
is the only answer we
is the only answer we know
is the only answer we know so
is the only answer we know so far.
There's
There's a
is the only answer we know so far.
There's a fellow
There's a fellow in
is the only answer we know so far.
There's a fellow in today's
There's a fellow in today's news
is the only answer we know so far.
There's a fellow in today's news that's
back
back in
back in in
back in in trouble
back in in trouble in
back in in trouble in prison
back in in trouble in prison again
back in in trouble in prison again for
violating
who's
who's the
who's the famous
who's the famous football
who's the famous football player
>> OJ.
>> OJ. OJ.
who's the famous football player
>> OJ. OJ. Yeah.
>> OJ. OJ. Yeah. Over
who's the famous football player
>> OJ. OJ. Yeah. Over and
>> OJ. OJ. Yeah. Over and over
who's the famous football player
>> OJ. OJ. Yeah. Over and over again.
>> OJ. OJ. Yeah. Over and over again. Over
and
and over
and over again.
and over again. Back
and over again. Back into
and over again. Back into the
and over again. Back into the same
thing.
thing. He
and over again. Back into the same
thing. He gets
thing. He gets off
and over again. Back into the same
thing. He gets off one
thing. He gets off one crime.
and over again. Back into the same
thing. He gets off one crime. He's
thing. He gets off one crime. He's got
and over again. Back into the same
thing. He gets off one crime. He's got a
gun
gun and
gun and he
gun and he goes
gun and he goes in
gun and he goes in and
gun and he goes in and commits
gun and he goes in and commits another
crime
crime even
gun and he goes in and commits another
crime even when
crime even when he
gun and he goes in and commits another
crime even when he knows
crime even when he knows all
gun and he goes in and commits another
crime even when he knows all the
crime even when he knows all the lights
are
are on
are on him.
So
So it's
are on him.
So it's like
So it's like something
are on him.
So it's like something who's
So it's like something who's that's
attracted
attracted to
attracted to that
attracted to that attracted
attracted to that attracted to
attracted to that attracted to that.
Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Stay
>> Stay out
>> Yes.
>> Stay out of
>> Stay out of the
>> Yes.
>> Stay out of the lion's
>> Stay out of the lion's den.
So
the
the attraction,
So
the attraction, the
the attraction, the seduction
So
the attraction, the seduction of
the attraction, the seduction of evil.
See,
See, evil
See, evil is
See, evil is glad.
See, evil is glad. The
See, evil is glad. The glamour,
See, evil is glad. The glamour, the
glamour
glamour of
See, evil is glad. The glamour, the
glamour of evil,
glamour of evil, the
See, evil is glad. The glamour, the
glamour of evil, the seduction
glamour of evil, the seduction of
See, evil is glad. The glamour, the
glamour of evil, the seduction of evil.
To
To be
To be one
To be one of
To be one of the
To be one of the tough
To be one of the tough guys,
To be one of the tough guys, to
To be one of the tough guys, to be
covered
covered with
To be one of the tough guys, to be
covered with tattoos,
to
to be
to be feared
to be feared in
to be feared in the
to be feared in the neighborhood.
Dirty
Dirty Dave.
Who
Who was
Who was Scarface?
>> Alapone.
>> Who
>> Who is
>> Who is Scarface?
>> Alapone.
>> Al
>> Al Capone.
>> Al Capone. Yes.
>> Al Capone. Yes. Alapone.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You
>> Al Capone. Yes. Alapone.
>> Yeah. You only
>> Yeah. You only want
>> Al Capone. Yes. Alapone.
>> Yeah. You only want to
>> Yeah. You only want to be
>> Al Capone. Yes. Alapone.
>> Yeah. You only want to be bad.
>> Yeah. You only want to be bad. You
>> Al Capone. Yes. Alapone.
>> Yeah. You only want to be bad. You want
to
to be
to be a
to be a big
to be a big shot
to be a big shot amongst
to be a big shot amongst the
to be a big shot amongst the bad.
So
So it's
to be a big shot amongst the bad.
So it's a
So it's a perverse
to be a big shot amongst the bad.
So it's a perverse way
So it's a perverse way of
to be a big shot amongst the bad.
So it's a perverse way of being
somebody.
>> So
>> So prayer
somebody.
>> So prayer in
>> So prayer in a
somebody.
>> So prayer in a 12step
>> So prayer in a 12step group,
somebody.
>> So prayer in a 12step group, a
>> So prayer in a 12step group, a spiritual
life,
life, eventually
life, eventually God
life, eventually God feels
life, eventually God feels sorry
life, eventually God feels sorry for
life, eventually God feels sorry for you
and
and you
life, eventually God feels sorry for you
and you start
and you start turning
life, eventually God feels sorry for you
and you start turning your
and you start turning your corner.
Well,
Well, the
Well, the 12th
Well, the 12th step
Well, the 12th step groups
you're
you're still
>> the
>> the 12step
>> the 12step groups
>> the 12step groups worldwide
transform
transform people
>> the 12step groups worldwide
transform people who
transform people who are
>> the 12step groups worldwide
transform people who are addicted
transform people who are addicted to
>> the 12step groups worldwide
transform people who are addicted to the
evil,
evil, negative,
evil, negative, and
evil, negative, and self-destructive
evil, negative, and self-destructive to
that
that which
evil, negative, and self-destructive to
that which is
that which is positive.
So,
So, it's
So, it's possible
So, it's possible to
So, it's possible to do
So, it's possible to do it
So, it's possible to do it in
So, it's possible to do it in a
So, it's possible to do it in a group
setting
setting like
So, it's possible to do it in a group
setting like that.
setting like that. Okay.
So, it's possible to do it in a group
setting like that. Okay. Yeah.
setting like that. Okay. Yeah. All
right.
His
question
question is
question is um
question is um he
question is um he wants
question is um he wants to
question is um he wants to know
question is um he wants to know the
question is um he wants to know the he
he's
he's got
question is um he wants to know the he
he's got a
he's got a lot
question is um he wants to know the he
he's got a lot of
he's got a lot of bad
question is um he wants to know the he
he's got a lot of bad uh
he's got a lot of bad uh uh
question is um he wants to know the he
he's got a lot of bad uh uh negative
emotions
emotions coming
emotions coming up
emotions coming up during
emotions coming up during the
emotions coming up during the day
emotions coming up during the day and
emotions coming up during the day and he
wants
wants to
emotions coming up during the day and he
wants to overcome
wants to overcome his
emotions coming up during the day and he
wants to overcome his negative
wants to overcome his negative karma.
>> Well,
>> Well, the
>> Well, the answer
>> Well, the answer to
>> Well, the answer to all
>> Well, the answer to all these
>> Well, the answer to all these questions
are
are by
>> Well, the answer to all these questions
are by dedication
are by dedication to
>> Well, the answer to all these questions
are by dedication to spiritual
work.
prayer,
>> meditation,
>> yoga,
>> uh
>> uh becoming
>> uh becoming involved
>> uh becoming involved with
>> uh becoming involved with spiritual
groups,
yes,
caring
caring about
yes,
caring about others.
So
So that
So that which
So that which is
So that which is negative
So that which is negative can
So that which is negative can be
replaced
replaced by
So that which is negative can be
replaced by that
replaced by that which
So that which is negative can be
replaced by that which is
replaced by that which is positive.
Be
Be kind
Be kind to
Be kind to all
Be kind to all living
Be kind to all living things.
>> Yeah.
Okay.
Thank
Thank Thank
Okay.
Thank Thank you
Thank Thank you very
Okay.
Thank Thank you very much.
um
um in
um in everything
um in everything um
um in everything um whether
um in everything um whether I'm
um in everything um whether I'm studying
or
or doing
um in everything um whether I'm studying
or doing spiritual
or doing spiritual practice
he
he feels
he feels his
he feels his sort
he feels his sort of
he feels his sort of weak
he feels his sort of weak need
he feels his sort of weak need and
doesn't
doesn't have
he feels his sort of weak need and
doesn't have a
doesn't have a spiritual
he feels his sort of weak need and
doesn't have a spiritual will
doesn't have a spiritual will so
he feels his sort of weak need and
doesn't have a spiritual will so he
doesn't have a spiritual will so he give
up
up in
up in the
up in the middle
so
so um
he
he thinks
he thinks that
he thinks that he
he thinks that he need
he thinks that he need some
he thinks that he need some help
he thinks that he need some help from
Buddha
Buddha or
he thinks that he need some help from
Buddha or you.
There
There comes
There comes a
There comes a time
in
in spiritual
There comes a time
in spiritual searching
in spiritual searching and
There comes a time
in spiritual searching and endeavor
that
that after
that after a
that after a certain
that after a certain amount
that after a certain amount of
that after a certain amount of effort,
there
there arises
that after a certain amount of effort,
there arises a
there arises a drivenness.
that after a certain amount of effort,
there arises a drivenness. A
there arises a drivenness. A drivenness
like
like a
like a madness.
A
A drivenness.
like a madness.
A drivenness. No
A drivenness. No matter
like a madness.
A drivenness. No matter what.
A drivenness. No matter what. No
like a madness.
A drivenness. No matter what. No matter
what.
If
If the
what.
If the knees
If the knees give
what.
If the knees give you
If the knees give you pain,
what.
If the knees give you pain, so
If the knees give you pain, so what?
So
So they
So they give
So they give you
So they give you pain.
>> I
>> I mean
So they give you pain.
>> I mean we
>> I mean we need
So they give you pain.
>> I mean we need in
>> I mean we need in terms
So they give you pain.
>> I mean we need in terms of
>> I mean we need in terms of uh
So they give you pain.
>> I mean we need in terms of uh um
>> I mean we need in terms of uh um lack
So they give you pain.
>> I mean we need in terms of uh um lack of
spiritual
spiritual will.
>> Oh
>> Oh lack
spiritual will.
>> Oh lack of
>> Oh lack of spiritual
spiritual will.
>> Oh lack of spiritual will.
The
The it
The it means
The it means perseverance.
The it means perseverance. Perseverance.
You
You ask
The it means perseverance. Perseverance.
You ask God
You ask God for
The it means perseverance. Perseverance.
You ask God for help.
To
To persevere.
There
There eventually
To persevere.
There eventually you
There eventually you hit
To persevere.
There eventually you hit a
There eventually you hit a level
To persevere.
There eventually you hit a level of
There eventually you hit a level of like
driven
driven drivenness
driven drivenness driven.
Uh
>> and
>> and if
>> and if you
>> and if you keep
>> and if you keep going
>> and if you keep going down
>> and if you keep going down eventually
you
you will
>> and if you keep going down eventually
you will hit
driven
driven drivenness
because
because that's
driven drivenness
because that's the
because that's the only
driven drivenness
because that's the only way
because that's the only way out
driven drivenness
because that's the only way out of
because that's the only way out of hell
>> going
>> going down.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Let's
>> going down.
>> Yeah. Let's say
>> Yeah. Let's say he
>> going down.
>> Yeah. Let's say he says
>> Yeah. Let's say he says I
>> going down.
>> Yeah. Let's say he says I keep
>> Yeah. Let's say he says I keep getting
worse
worse and
worse and worse.
So
So quit
worse and worse.
So quit resisting
So quit resisting it.
worse and worse.
So quit resisting it. get
So quit resisting it. get worse
worse and worse.
So quit resisting it. get worse and
worse
worse and
worse and you'll
worse and you'll hit
worse and you'll hit a
worse and you'll hit a love
worse and you'll hit a love the
worse and you'll hit a love the level
worse and you'll hit a love the level of
hell
hell where
worse and you'll hit a love the level of
hell where the
hell where the drivenness
worse and you'll hit a love the level of
hell where the drivenness to
hell where the drivenness to get
worse and you'll hit a love the level of
hell where the drivenness to get out
hell where the drivenness to get out of
there
there will
there will supersede
there will supersede all
there will supersede all resistance.
Yeah.
Yeah. You
there will supersede all resistance.
Yeah. You want
Yeah. You want to
there will supersede all resistance.
Yeah. You want to hit
Yeah. You want to hit the
there will supersede all resistance.
Yeah. You want to hit the level
Yeah. You want to hit the level of
drivenness.
It's
It's because
drivenness.
It's because although
It's because although you
drivenness.
It's because although you have
It's because although you have suffered,
you
you haven't
you haven't suffered
you haven't suffered enough.
Eventually
Eventually the
you haven't suffered enough.
Eventually the suffering
Eventually the suffering gets
you haven't suffered enough.
Eventually the suffering gets so
Eventually the suffering gets so severe
that
that you
that you let
that you let go
that you let go of
that you let go of resistance.
It's
It's the
that you let go of resistance.
It's the ego's
It's the ego's fight
that you let go of resistance.
It's the ego's fight for
It's the ego's fight for survival.
The
The ego
The ego fights
The ego fights for
The ego fights for survival.
The ego fights for survival. That's
The ego fights for survival. That's what
it
it is.
>> It's
>> It's the
>> It's the ego's
>> It's the ego's fight
>> It's the ego's fight for
>> It's the ego's fight for survival
with
with him.
>> It's the ego's fight for survival
with him. Resist.
Yeah.
Yeah. The
Yeah. The narcissistic
Yeah. The narcissistic core
Yeah. The narcissistic core of
Yeah. The narcissistic core of the
Yeah. The narcissistic core of the ego
fights
fights to
Yeah. The narcissistic core of the ego
fights to the
fights to the bitter
Yeah. The narcissistic core of the ego
fights to the bitter end
until
until finally
until finally it's
until finally it's vanquished.
until finally it's vanquished. It's
called
called hitting
until finally it's vanquished. It's
called hitting bottom.
And
And therefore,
And therefore, you
And therefore, you go
And therefore, you go until
And therefore, you go until you
And therefore, you go until you hit
bottom.
And
And when
And when you
And when you hit
And when you hit bottom,
And when you hit bottom, you're
And when you hit bottom, you're willing
to
to let
And when you hit bottom, you're willing
to let it
to let it go.
And when you hit bottom, you're willing
to let it go. The
to let it go. The ego
And when you hit bottom, you're willing
to let it go. The ego is
to let it go. The ego is willing
And when you hit bottom, you're willing
to let it go. The ego is willing to
to let it go. The ego is willing to let
go.
go. Yeah.
go. Yeah. Um
The
The suffering
go. Yeah. Um
The suffering gets
The suffering gets worse
go. Yeah. Um
The suffering gets worse and
The suffering gets worse and worse.
Yeah.
Um
when
when ego
when ego is
when ego is completely
when ego is completely and
when ego is completely and forever
when ego is completely and forever uh
when ego is completely and forever uh um
sort
sort of
when ego is completely and forever uh um
sort of um
sort of um disappear
when ego is completely and forever uh um
sort of um disappear or
sort of um disappear or diminished
>> the
>> the ego
>> ego
is
is it
is it the
is it the level
is it the level 600
>> uh
>> or
>> or is
>> or is it
>> or is it after
>> or is it after the
>> or is it after the 800
40 level
40 level known
>> or is it after the 800
40 level known as
40 level known as the
>> or is it after the 800
40 level known as the the
40 level known as the the final
>> or is it after the 800
40 level known as the the final doorway.
>> Well,
>> Well, there's
>> Well, there's remnants
>> Well, there's remnants of
>> Well, there's remnants of the
>> Well, there's remnants of the ego
which
which let
>> Well, there's remnants of the ego
which let go
which let go as
>> Well, there's remnants of the ego
which let go as soon
which let go as soon as
>> Well, there's remnants of the ego
which let go as soon as you
which let go as soon as you get
>> Well, there's remnants of the ego
which let go as soon as you get into
which let go as soon as you get into the
positive
positive numbers.
positive numbers. Even
positive numbers. Even if
positive numbers. Even if you
positive numbers. Even if you move
positive numbers. Even if you move up
positive numbers. Even if you move up to
60,
60, that
positive numbers. Even if you move up to
60, that is
60, that is much
positive numbers. Even if you move up to
60, that is much higher
60, that is much higher than
positive numbers. Even if you move up to
60, that is much higher than 20,
60, that is much higher than 20, you
know.
know. So
the
the ego
know. So
the ego will
the ego will persist
until
until karmically
until karmically and
until karmically and through
until karmically and through spiritual
endeavor
endeavor one
until karmically and through spiritual
endeavor one has
endeavor one has transcended
until karmically and through spiritual
endeavor one has transcended that
endeavor one has transcended that level
and
and then
and then you
and then you will
and then you will move
and then you will move to
and then you will move to the
and then you will move to the next
and then you will move to the next level
and
and then
and then you will move to the next level
and then you
and then you work
and then you will move to the next level
and then you work on
and then you work on that
and then you will move to the next level
and then you work on that level.
and then you work on that level. So
and then you will move to the next level
and then you work on that level. So it's
like
like your
like your consciousness
like your consciousness rises
uh
uh on
like your consciousness rises
uh on and
uh on and on.
Perfection
Perfection is
Perfection is uh
Perfection is uh you
Perfection is uh you might
Perfection is uh you might say
Perfection is uh you might say 1,00
Buddha
Jesus
Jesus Christ.
>> So
>> So until
Jesus Christ.
>> So until thousand
>> So until thousand there
Jesus Christ.
>> So until thousand there is
>> So until thousand there is some
Jesus Christ.
>> So until thousand there is some remnants
of
of ego
of ego ego
>> there's
>> there's uh
yes
yes yes
yes yes there's
yes yes there's remnants
yes yes there's remnants of
yes yes there's remnants of uh
yes yes there's remnants of uh not
yes yes there's remnants of uh not of
the
the ego
yes yes there's remnants of uh not of
the ego but
the ego but it's
yes yes there's remnants of uh not of
the ego but it's residual
the ego but it's residual belief
yes yes there's remnants of uh not of
the ego but it's residual belief systems
because
because they
because they just
because they just haven't
because they just haven't been
recognized
recognized yet.
because they just haven't been
recognized yet. Um
The
The ego's
The ego's persistence
The ego's persistence in
The ego's persistence in believing
The ego's persistence in believing that
it
it is
your
your yourself
your yourself and
your yourself and your
your yourself and your source
your yourself and your source of
your yourself and your source of your
life
persists
persists up
persists up to
persists up to 8:40
persists up to 8:40 but
persists up to 8:40 but then
persists up to 8:40 but then it
disappears
disappears beyond
persists up to 8:40 but then it
disappears beyond there.
You
You realize
You realize that
You realize that it
You realize that it is
You realize that it is not
You realize that it is not the
You realize that it is not the source
You realize that it is not the source of
your
your life.
Then
Then I
Then I his
Then I his his
Then I his his question
Then I his his question um
Then I his his question um probably
Then I his his question um probably then
uh
uh then
Then I his his question um probably then
uh then 600
is
is the
is the beginning
is the beginning of
is the beginning of alignment
is the beginning of alignment that
is the beginning of alignment that does
it
it mean
is the beginning of alignment that does
it mean that
it mean that it's
is the beginning of alignment that does
it mean that it's the
it mean that it's the uh
is the beginning of alignment that does
it mean that it's the uh sort
it mean that it's the uh sort of
annihilation
annihilation of
annihilation of ego
annihilation of ego yet?
>> No,
>> No, it
annihilation of ego yet?
>> No, it means
>> No, it means its
annihilation of ego yet?
>> No, it means its dominance
>> No, it means its dominance has
annihilation of ego yet?
>> No, it means its dominance has suddenly
diminished
>> it
>> it no
diminished
>> it no longer
>> it no longer dominates.
diminished
>> it no longer dominates. At
>> it no longer dominates. At 600
diminished
>> it no longer dominates. At 600 there
>> it no longer dominates. At 600 there is
a
a like
a like a
a like a revelation.
Also
Also at
a like a revelation.
Also at 600
Also at 600 you
a like a revelation.
Also at 600 you realize
Also at 600 you realize you
a like a revelation.
Also at 600 you realize you don't
Also at 600 you realize you don't have
to
to stay
to stay with
to stay with the
to stay with the body
to stay with the body at
to stay with the body at all.
to stay with the body at all. You're
free
free to
to stay with the body at all. You're
free to leave
free to leave if
to stay with the body at all. You're
free to leave if you
free to leave if you want.
It's
It's a
It's a state
It's a state of
It's a state of bliss.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
It's a state of bliss.
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
It's a state of bliss.
>> Thank you very much. Can
>> Thank you very much. Can you
It's a state of bliss.
>> Thank you very much. Can you hold
>> Thank you very much. Can you hold my
hands
hands just
hands just one
hands just one time?
>> What?
>> What? He
hands just one time?
>> What? He wants
>> What? He wants to
hands just one time?
>> What? He wants to hold
>> What? He wants to hold your
hands just one time?
>> What? He wants to hold your hand
>> What? He wants to hold your hand just
for
for just
for just one
for just one time.
>> Just
>> Just one
for just one time.
>> Just one time.
>> That'll
>> That'll be
>> That'll be a thousand
>> That'll be a thousand dollars.
>> Two
>> Two hands
>> That'll be a thousand dollars.
>> Two hands is
>> Two hands is 2,000.
>> God
>> God bless
>> God bless you.
Such
Such be
>> God bless you.
Such be beautiful
Such be beautiful people.
If
If you
If you have
If you have good
If you have good karma,
If you have good karma, beautiful
If you have good karma, beautiful people
ask
ask you
If you have good karma, beautiful people
ask you beautiful
ask you beautiful questions.
Yes,
>> I
>> I actually
Yes,
>> I actually um
uh
uh I
uh I thought
uh I thought I'd
uh I thought I'd have
uh I thought I'd have a
uh I thought I'd have a question
uh I thought I'd have a question maybe,
but
but I
uh I thought I'd have a question maybe,
but I just
but I just kind
uh I thought I'd have a question maybe,
but I just kind of
but I just kind of came
uh I thought I'd have a question maybe,
but I just kind of came up
but I just kind of came up here,
uh I thought I'd have a question maybe,
but I just kind of came up here, I
guess,
guess, out
guess, out of
guess, out of courage.
guess, out of courage. Um
guess, out of courage. Um I
guess, out of courage. Um I don't
guess, out of courage. Um I don't know.
>> Yeah,
this
this is
this is your
this is your question.
>> Actually,
>> Actually, she
this is your question.
>> Actually, she spoke
>> Actually, she spoke in
this is your question.
>> Actually, she spoke in English.
Okay.
So,
>> so
>> so you
>> so you translate
>> so you translate what
>> so you translate what she
>> so you translate what she said
>> actually.
>> actually. Uh,
>> so you translate what she said
>> actually. Uh, she
>> actually. Uh, she said
>> so you translate what she said
>> actually. Uh, she said she
>> actually. Uh, she said she thought
>> so you translate what she said
>> actually. Uh, she said she thought she
had
had a
had a question.
had a question. Oh,
>> but
>> but then
had a question. Oh,
>> but then she
>> but then she said
had a question. Oh,
>> but then she said just
>> but then she said just out
had a question. Oh,
>> but then she said just out of
>> but then she said just out of courage
she
she wanted
she wanted to
she wanted to appear
she wanted to appear come
she wanted to appear come up
she wanted to appear come up here
she wanted to appear come up here and
then
then she
she wanted to appear come up here and
then she stopped.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> You
>> You have
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> You have a
>> You have a question.
>> Yes.
>> Um
>> come
>> come back
>> come back later.
>> Not
>> Not right.
Come
Come back
Come back later.
She
She just
Come back later.
She just went
She just went blank,
Come back later.
She just went blank, you
She just went blank, you know.
Come back later.
She just went blank, you know. Yes,
that
that I
that I described
that I described that
that I described that in
that I described that in the
that I described that in the books
that I described that in the books very
often.
often. You
that I described that in the books very
often. You have
often. You have a
that I described that in the books very
often. You have a question
often. You have a question in
that I described that in the books very
often. You have a question in mind
often. You have a question in mind and
you
you approach
you approach a
you approach a spiritual
you approach a spiritual teacher
you approach a spiritual teacher and
you approach a spiritual teacher and the
question
question disappears.
you approach a spiritual teacher and the
question disappears. It
question disappears. It was
you approach a spiritual teacher and the
question disappears. It was a
question disappears. It was a very
common
common phenomena.
Yes.
Um
Um uh
Um uh his
Um uh his question
Um uh his question is
Um uh his question is um
Um uh his question is um he
Um uh his question is um he wants
Um uh his question is um he wants to
know
know the
sort
sort of
sort of karma
sort of karma that
sort of karma that he
sort of karma that he needs
sort of karma that he needs to
sort of karma that he needs to overcome
and
and how
sort of karma that he needs to overcome
and how to
and how to overcome
sort of karma that he needs to overcome
and how to overcome it.
and how to overcome it. He
sort of karma that he needs to overcome
and how to overcome it. He wants
and how to overcome it. He wants to
sort of karma that he needs to overcome
and how to overcome it. He wants to know
what
what sort
what sort of
what sort of karma
what sort of karma he
what sort of karma he wants
what sort of karma he wants to
what sort of karma he wants to uh
what sort of karma he wants to uh he
needs
needs to
what sort of karma he wants to uh he
needs to overcome.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
>> Oh, I don't
>> Oh, I don't know.
>> Oh, I don't know. You
>> Oh, I don't know. You could
>> Oh, I don't know. You could you
>> Oh, I don't know. You could you have
>> Oh, I don't know. You could you have to
look
look at
>> Oh, I don't know. You could you have to
look at your
look at your present
>> Oh, I don't know. You could you have to
look at your present life
look at your present life and
>> Oh, I don't know. You could you have to
look at your present life and see
look at your present life and see get
>> Oh, I don't know. You could you have to
look at your present life and see get uh
symptoms
symptoms and
symptoms and signs
symptoms and signs that
symptoms and signs that would
symptoms and signs that would indicate.
You
You can't
symptoms and signs that would indicate.
You can't ask
You can't ask a
symptoms and signs that would indicate.
You can't ask a blank
You can't ask a blank question
symptoms and signs that would indicate.
You can't ask a blank question like
that.
And
And the
that.
And the thing
And the thing is
that.
And the thing is don't
And the thing is don't worry
that.
And the thing is don't worry about
And the thing is don't worry about the
bad
bad karma.
>> Just
>> Just do
bad karma.
>> Just do that
>> Just do that which
bad karma.
>> Just do that which is
>> Just do that which is virtuous
bad karma.
>> Just do that which is virtuous and
acquire
acquire good
acquire good karma.
Just
Just acquire
acquire good karma.
Just acquire good
Just acquire good karma.
acquire good karma.
Just acquire good karma. Forget
Just acquire good karma. Forget about
undoing
undoing bad
undoing bad karma
undoing bad karma because
undoing bad karma because pursuit
undoing bad karma because pursuit of
good
good karma
undoing bad karma because pursuit of
good karma automatically
good karma automatically undoes
undoing bad karma because pursuit of
good karma automatically undoes it.
Thank
Thank you
Thank you very
Thank you very much.
And
And he
Thank you very much.
And he has
And he has uh
Thank you very much.
And he has uh a
And he has uh a a
Thank you very much.
And he has uh a a 16-month-old
uh
uh female
uh female baby
uh female baby and
uh female baby and she
uh female baby and she is
uh female baby and she is suffering
uh female baby and she is suffering from
uh
uh tubberoscllerosis.
Tubarosclleris.
>> Tuberculosis.
>> No.
>> No. No,
>> No. No, it's
>> No. No, it's not
>> No. No, it's not tuberculus.
>> No. No, it's not tuberculus. It's
>> No. No, it's not tuberculus. It's a
>> No.
>> Tuberous.
>> Tuberosis.
>> Tuberos.
>> Tuberos. Scaris.
>> Huh?
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't see
>> I don't see anything.
>> I don't see anything. So,
>> he
>> he can't
>> I don't see anything. So,
>> he can't read
>> he can't read because
it's
it's some
it's some defect
it's some defect in
it's some defect in DNA.
it's some defect in DNA. Some
it's some defect in DNA. Some defect
it's some defect in DNA. Some defect in
DNA.
DNA. Yeah.
>> Uh,
>> Uh, metabolic
>> Uh, metabolic disorder.
>> Uh, metabolic disorder. Huh.
some
some I'm
>> Uh, metabolic disorder. Huh.
some I'm not
some I'm not familiar
>> Uh, metabolic disorder. Huh.
some I'm not familiar with
some I'm not familiar with the
terminology
terminology here,
terminology here, but
terminology here, but he
terminology here, but he uh
terminology here, but he uh his
terminology here, but he uh his daughter
is
is suffering
terminology here, but he uh his daughter
is suffering from
is suffering from that
terminology here, but he uh his daughter
is suffering from that and
is suffering from that and she's
terminology here, but he uh his daughter
is suffering from that and she's only
is suffering from that and she's only 16
months
months old.
>> Yeah.
>> And
>> And he's
>> And he's been
>> And he's been showing
uh
uh his
>> And he's been showing
uh his daughter
uh his daughter your
>> And he's been showing
uh his daughter your DVD.
>> Yeah.
>> Since
>> Since she
>> Yeah.
>> Since she was
>> Since she was uh
>> Yeah.
>> Since she was uh 8
>> Since she was uh 8 months
>> Oh.
>> old.
>> old. Yeah.
>> Oh.
>> old. Yeah. Yeah.
>> old. Yeah. Yeah. And
>> he
>> he wants
>> he wants to
>> he wants to know
>> he wants to know as
>> he wants to know as a
>> he wants to know as a father
>> he wants to know as a father what
>> he wants to know as a father what uh
>> he wants to know as a father what uh he
should
should do
>> he wants to know as a father what uh he
should do a
should do a daughter
>> he wants to know as a father what uh he
should do a daughter like
should do a daughter like that
>> he wants to know as a father what uh he
should do a daughter like that daughter
suffering
suffering from
suffering from that
suffering from that sort
suffering from that sort of
suffering from that sort of dis.
>> Well,
>> Well, he
suffering from that sort of dis.
>> Well, he doing
>> Well, he doing what
suffering from that sort of dis.
>> Well, he doing what he
>> Well, he doing what he can.
suffering from that sort of dis.
>> Well, he doing what he can. He
>> Well, he doing what he can. He follows
medical.
He
He tries
medical.
He tries to
He tries to surround
medical.
He tries to surround the
He tries to surround the child
medical.
He tries to surround the child with
He tries to surround the child with high
spiritual
spiritual energy.
spiritual energy. He
spiritual energy. He prays
spiritual energy. He prays for
spiritual energy. He prays for her
and
and that's
spiritual energy. He prays for her
and that's all
and that's all he
spiritual energy. He prays for her
and that's all he can
and that's all he can do.
No,
No, you
No, you have
No, you have to
No, you have to let
No, you have to let go
No, you have to let go the
No, you have to let go the idea
No, you have to let go the idea that
No, you have to let go the idea that if
I
I do
No, you have to let go the idea that if
I do all
I do all that,
No, you have to let go the idea that if
I do all that, the
I do all that, the child
No, you have to let go the idea that if
I do all that, the child will
I do all that, the child will get
No, you have to let go the idea that if
I do all that, the child will get normal
or
or survive.
or survive. That
or survive. That may
or survive. That may not
or survive. That may not be
or survive. That may not be the
or survive. That may not be the case
or survive. That may not be the case at
all.
The
The child
The child has
The child has its
The child has its own
The child has its own karma.
>> You
>> You may
The child has its own karma.
>> You may not
>> You may not be
The child has its own karma.
>> You may not be able
>> You may not be able to
The child has its own karma.
>> You may not be able to over
>> You may not be able to over oversee
The child has its own karma.
>> You may not be able to over oversee it,
overcome
overcome it.
So
So the
overcome it.
So the idea
So the idea is
overcome it.
So the idea is to
So the idea is to be
overcome it.
So the idea is to be the
So the idea is to be the best
overcome it.
So the idea is to be the best parent
So the idea is to be the best parent you
can
can be
can be during
can be during the
can be during the period
can be during the period of
can be during the period of time
can be during the period of time that
you
you have
can be during the period of time that
you have to
you have to be
can be during the period of time that
you have to be with
you have to be with that
can be during the period of time that
you have to be with that person.
Yes.
His
question
question his
question his question
question his question is
question his question is what
question his question is what is
question his question is what is a
meaning
meaning of
question his question is what is a
meaning of a
meaning of a family
question his question is what is a
meaning of a family and
meaning of a family and for
question his question is what is a
meaning of a family and for a
meaning of a family and for a spiritual
seeker
seeker how
seeker how he
seeker how he should
seeker how he should look
seeker how he should look at
seeker how he should look at his
seeker how he should look at his own
family?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Uh
yes
yes because
>> Yes. Uh
yes because there
yes because there are
>> Yes. Uh
yes because there are various
yes because there are various teachings
that
that you
that you should
that you should leave
that you should leave your
that you should leave your family
that you should leave your family and
all
all that.
that you should leave your family and
all that. The
all that. The rule
that you should leave your family and
all that. The rule is
all that. The rule is no
that you should leave your family and
all that. The rule is no attachments.
all that. The rule is no attachments. No
attachments
attachments or
attachments or aversions.
So
So the
attachments or aversions.
So the you
So the you learn
attachments or aversions.
So the you learn to
So the you learn to love
attachments or aversions.
So the you learn to love without
necessarily
necessarily being
necessarily being attached.
So
So the
necessarily being attached.
So the family
So the family then
necessarily being attached.
So the family then how
So the family then how to
necessarily being attached.
So the family then how to hold
So the family then how to hold the
importance
importance of
importance of family
the
the the
importance of family
the the family
the the family is
importance of family
the the family is that
the the family is that which
importance of family
the the family is that which you
the the family is that which you love
and
and at
and at the
and at the same
and at the same time
and at the same time love
and at the same time love without
and at the same time love without being
attached.
Some
Some more
Some more severe
Some more severe teachings
Some more severe teachings say
Some more severe teachings say give
Some more severe teachings say give up
all
all family,
Some more severe teachings say give up
all family, give
all family, give up
Some more severe teachings say give up
all family, give up all
all family, give up all relationships.
Many
Many of
Many of these
Many of these things
Many of these things are
Many of these things are suitable
for
for a
Many of these things are suitable
for a certain
for a certain period
Many of these things are suitable
for a certain period of
for a certain period of time
Many of these things are suitable
for a certain period of time in
for a certain period of time in a
certain
certain lifetime,
but
but they're
certain lifetime,
but they're not
but they're not suitable
certain lifetime,
but they're not suitable for
but they're not suitable for everybody
all
all the
all the time.
It's
It's like
all the time.
It's like thinking
It's like thinking you
all the time.
It's like thinking you can't
It's like thinking you can't become
enlightened
enlightened unless
enlightened unless you
enlightened unless you become
enlightened unless you become a
vegetarian.
That's
That's a
That's a limitation.
uh
uh his
That's a limitation.
uh his um
uh his um his
That's a limitation.
uh his um his question
uh his um his question is
um
um if
um if I'm
um if I'm become
um if I'm become loving
um if I'm become loving toward
um if I'm become loving toward all
um if I'm become loving toward all that
exist
exist then
is
is there
is there any
is there any sort
is there any sort of
is there any sort of uh
is there any sort of uh should
is there any sort of uh should I
is there any sort of uh should I have
any
any favoritism
is there any sort of uh should I have
any favoritism toward
any favoritism toward my
is there any sort of uh should I have
any favoritism toward my family
any favoritism toward my family because
they
they are
they are sort
they are sort of
they are sort of we
they are sort of we can
they are sort of we can we
they are sort of we can we can
they are sort of we can we can see
they are sort of we can we can see them
as
as karmically
they are sort of we can we can see them
as karmically related.
as karmically related. Yeah.
Well,
like
like the
Well,
like the course
like the course of
Well,
like the course of miracles
like the course of miracles uh
Well,
like the course of miracles uh warns
against
against specialness
that
that because
against specialness
that because you
that because you they're
against specialness
that because you they're your
that because you they're your family,
they're
they're special.
So,
So, you
they're special.
So, you try
So, you try to
they're special.
So, you try to see
So, you try to see them
they're special.
So, you try to see them as
So, you try to see them as very
meaningful
meaningful to
meaningful to you,
meaningful to you, but
meaningful to you, but not
meaningful to you, but not necessarily
special
special in
meaningful to you, but not necessarily
special in and
special in and of
meaningful to you, but not necessarily
special in and of itself.
uh
family.
>> So
>> So family
>> So family is
>> So family is more
>> So family is more meaningful.
Yeah.
Yeah. But
>> So family is more meaningful.
Yeah. But not
Yeah. But not necessarily
>> So family is more meaningful.
Yeah. But not necessarily more
Yeah. But not necessarily more special.
>> Everybody
>> Everybody has
>> Everybody has a
>> Everybody has a family.
Thank
Thank you.
>> See
>> See eventually
>> See eventually you
>> See eventually you love
>> See eventually you love everyone
as
as though
>> See eventually you love everyone
as though you
as though you are
>> See eventually you love everyone
as though you are they
as though you are they are
>> See eventually you love everyone
as though you are they are your
as though you are they are your family.
So
So this
So this group
So this group sitting
So this group sitting here
So this group sitting here which
So this group sitting here which has
been
been here
So this group sitting here which has
been here before
been here before together
has
has a
has a sense
has a sense of
has a sense of family
has a sense of family within
has a sense of family within that
special
special sense
has a sense of family within that
special sense of
special sense of family.
has a sense of family within that
special sense of family. Not
special sense of family. Not biologic
family
family but
family but family
family but family by
family but family by mutual
family but family by mutual alignment
and
and mutual
family but family by mutual alignment
and mutual agreement.
They
They constitute
They constitute a
They constitute a spiritual
They constitute a spiritual family.
Yeah.
Uh
Uh recently
Uh recently ly
Uh recently ly he's
Uh recently ly he's very
Uh recently ly he's very concerned
Uh recently ly he's very concerned with
uh
uh about
Uh recently ly he's very concerned with
uh about marriage.
>> Marriage.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Marriage.
>> Marriage.
>> Yeah. Marriage. And
>> Yeah. Marriage. And then
>> Marriage.
>> Yeah. Marriage. And then what
>> Yeah. Marriage. And then what he's
asking
asking what
asking what is
asking what is your
asking what is your view
asking what is your view on
asking what is your view on marriage?
>> You
>> You don't
asking what is your view on marriage?
>> You don't want
>> You don't want to
asking what is your view on marriage?
>> You don't want to hear
>> You don't want to hear now.
Now
Now we
Now we mean
Now we mean we
Now we mean we make
Now we mean we make a
Now we mean we make a joke
Now we mean we make a joke out
Now we mean we make a joke out of
Now we mean we make a joke out of it.
Now we mean we make a joke out of it. We
make
make a
Now we mean we make a joke out of it. We
make a joke
make a joke out
Now we mean we make a joke out of it. We
make a joke out of
make a joke out of it.
Now we mean we make a joke out of it. We
make a joke out of it. Uh
make a joke out of it. Uh because
Now we mean we make a joke out of it. We
make a joke out of it. Uh because that's
the
the human
the human condition.
the human condition. You
the human condition. You know
the
the marriage
the human condition. You know
the marriage is
the marriage is the
the human condition. You know
the marriage is the best
the marriage is the best relationship
that
that uh
that uh God
that uh God could
that uh God could figure
that uh God could figure out.
God
God created
that uh God could figure out.
God created Adam.
So
So he
So he created
So he created Adam
So he created Adam and
So he created Adam and then
So he created Adam and then he
So he created Adam and then he saw
So he created Adam and then he saw that
Adam
Adam all
So he created Adam and then he saw that
Adam all alone
Adam all alone without
So he created Adam and then he saw that
Adam all alone without a
Adam all alone without a companion
So he created Adam and then he saw that
Adam all alone without a companion would
be
be lonely.
is
is so
be lonely.
is so he
is so he took
be lonely.
is so he took a
is so he took a rib
be lonely.
is so he took a rib out
is so he took a rib out of
be lonely.
is so he took a rib out of Adam
is so he took a rib out of Adam and
created
created woman
created woman so
created woman so that
created woman so that man
created woman so that man would
created woman so that man would have
created woman so that man would have a
companion
out
out of
out of companion.
out of companion. So
out of companion. So part
out of companion. So part of
out of companion. So part of the
out of companion. So part of the human
condition
condition that
out of companion. So part of the human
condition that is
condition that is companion
and
and so
and so the
and so the two
and so the two serve
and so the two serve each
and so the two serve each other
and so the two serve each other they
and so the two serve each other they are
of
of course
and so the two serve each other they are
of course it's
of course it's expressed
and so the two serve each other they are
of course it's expressed it
of course it's expressed it in
and so the two serve each other they are
of course it's expressed it in the
of course it's expressed it in the male
they
they could
they could have
they could have been
they could have been he
they could have been he could
they could have been he could have
they could have been he could have been
he
he created
they could have been he could have been
he created woman
he created woman and
they could have been he could have been
he created woman and out
he created woman and out of
they could have been he could have been
he created woman and out of the
he created woman and out of the woman's
rib
rib he
rib he created
rib he created man
rib he created man for
rib he created man for the
rib he created man for the same
rib he created man for the same reason
I
I think
rib he created man for the same reason
I think it
I think it would
rib he created man for the same reason
I think it would be
I think it would be equally
rib he created man for the same reason
I think it would be equally valid
and
and I
and I don't
and I don't think
and I don't think he
and I don't think he created
and I don't think he created one
and I don't think he created one gender
before
before the
and I don't think he created one gender
before the other
before the other anyway
and I don't think he created one gender
before the other anyway because
sequences
sequences within
sequences within the
sequences within the linear
sequences within the linear domain
sequences within the linear domain and
historic
historic uh
sequences within the linear domain and
historic uh domain,
but
but he
but he saw
but he saw that
but he saw that man
but he saw that man needed
but he saw that man needed and
but he saw that man needed and woman
needed
needed companionship
and
and each
and each other's
and each other's help.
and each other's help. And
and each other's help. And that's
and each other's help. And that's also
why
why he
and each other's help. And that's also
why he created
why he created the
and each other's help. And that's also
why he created the animal
why he created the animal to
and each other's help. And that's also
why he created the animal to be
why he created the animal to be to
and each other's help. And that's also
why he created the animal to be to be
why he created the animal to be to be a
companion
companion to
companion to man.
companion to man. Isn't
companion to man. Isn't that
companion to man. Isn't that nice?
companion to man. Isn't that nice? The
kitties
kitties and
companion to man. Isn't that nice? The
kitties and the
kitties and the doggies
companion to man. Isn't that nice? The
kitties and the doggies and
kitties and the doggies and the
companion to man. Isn't that nice? The
kitties and the doggies and the donkeys
and
and the
and the horses.
>> Okay.
Many
Many things
Many things are
Many things are metaphorical.
metaphorical.
>> So
>> So that
>> So that he
>> So that he first
>> So that he first created
>> So that he first created man
>> So that he first created man and
>> So that he first created man and then
>> So that he first created man and then he
created
created woman
>> So that he first created man and then he
created woman out
created woman out of
>> So that he first created man and then he
created woman out of a
created woman out of a man's
>> So that he first created man and then he
created woman out of a man's rib
created woman out of a man's rib is,
>> So that he first created man and then he
created woman out of a man's rib is, you
know,
know, like
know, like a
know, like a metaphor
know, like a metaphor for
know, like a metaphor for reality.
know, like a metaphor for reality. You
can
can picture
know, like a metaphor for reality. You
can picture God
can picture God with
know, like a metaphor for reality. You
can picture God with with
can picture God with with just
know, like a metaphor for reality. You
can picture God with with just a
can picture God with with just a man
there
there and
there and then
there and then he
there and then he shakes
there and then he shakes the
there and then he shakes the man,
there and then he shakes the man, takes
his
his rib
there and then he shakes the man, takes
his rib out
his rib out and
there and then he shakes the man, takes
his rib out and creates
his rib out and creates a
there and then he shakes the man, takes
his rib out and creates a woman.
his rib out and creates a woman. I
there and then he shakes the man, takes
his rib out and creates a woman. I mean,
it's
it's a
it's a little
it's a little absurd,
it's a little absurd, you
it's a little absurd, you know.
Yeah.
Yeah. By
it's a little absurd, you know.
Yeah. By metaphor
Yeah. By metaphor we
it's a little absurd, you know.
Yeah. By metaphor we mean
Yeah. By metaphor we mean symbolic.
Symbolically
Symbolically it's
Symbolically it's like
Symbolically it's like a
Symbolically it's like a legend.
Symbolically it's like a legend. A
symbolic
symbolic legend.
Yeah.
Thank
Thank you
Yeah.
Thank you very
Thank you very much.
Nice
Nice to
Nice to meet
Nice to meet you.
>> Closer.
>> Dr.
>> Dr. Hawkins,
>> Dr. Hawkins, you
>> Dr. Hawkins, you said
>> Dr. Hawkins, you said work
>> Dr. Hawkins, you said work to
>> Dr. Hawkins, you said work to the
>> Dr. Hawkins, you said work to the all
fair
fair no
>> Dr. Hawkins, you said work to the all
fair no matter
fair no matter what.
>> Dr. Hawkins, you said work to the all
fair no matter what. I
fair no matter what. I want
>> Dr. Hawkins, you said work to the all
fair no matter what. I want to
fair no matter what. I want to know
>> Dr. Hawkins, you said work to the all
fair no matter what. I want to know this
praise
praise more
praise more precise.
I
I want
praise more precise.
I want to
I want to know
praise more precise.
I want to know what
I want to know what he
praise more precise.
I want to know what he said
>> once
>> once more
>> word
>> word to
>> once more
>> word to the
>> word to the all
>> once more
>> word to the all fair
>> word to the all fair no
>> once more
>> word to the all fair no matter
>> word to the all fair no matter what
Hawkins
Hawkins you
Hawkins you said
Hawkins you said this
Hawkins you said this praise
Hawkins you said this praise I
Hawkins you said this praise I want
Hawkins you said this praise I want to
know
know this
Hawkins you said this praise I want to
know this phrase
know this phrase more
Hawkins you said this praise I want to
know this phrase more precise
>> fair
>> fair to
>> fair to all
>> fair
>> fair to
>> fair to all
>> um
>> um in
>> um in one
>> um in one of
>> um in one of your
>> um in one of your saying
>> um in one of your saying you
>> um in one of your saying you in
>> um in one of your saying you in one
>> um in one of your saying you in one of
your
your saying
>> um in one of your saying you in one of
your saying you
your saying you said
>> um in one of your saying you in one of
your saying you said be
your saying you said be fair
>> um in one of your saying you in one of
your saying you said be fair to
your saying you said be fair to all
>> um in one of your saying you in one of
your saying you said be fair to all and
he
he wants
he wants to
he wants to know
he wants to know the
he wants to know the meaning
he wants to know the meaning of
he wants to know the meaning of it
he wants to know the meaning of it uh
more
more specifically
he wants to know the meaning of it uh
more specifically Y
>> to
>> to be
>> to be kindly
>> to be kindly kind
towards
towards all
>> to be kindly kind
towards all living
towards all living things.
>> to be kindly kind
towards all living things. To
towards all living things. To be
>> to be kindly kind
towards all living things. To be kind
towards
towards all
towards all of
towards all of life
towards all of life in
towards all of life in all
towards all of life in all of
towards all of life in all of its
expressions.
expressions. To
towards all of life in all of its
expressions. To be
expressions. To be kind
towards all of life in all of its
expressions. To be kind to
expressions. To be kind to life
towards all of life in all of its
expressions. To be kind to life in
expressions. To be kind to life in all
of
of its
of its expression.
>> And
>> And part
of its expression.
>> And part of
>> And part of kindness
of its expression.
>> And part of kindness is
>> And part of kindness is to
of its expression.
>> And part of kindness is to be
respectful.
Respectful
of
of all
of all of
of all of life
of all of life in
of all of life in all
of all of life in all of
of all of life in all of its
expressions.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Thank
>> Yes. Thank you.
The
The sacrament
>> Yes. Thank you.
The sacrament of
aaristic
in
in the
>> sacrament
>> sacrament of
>> sacrament of eucharistic
>> sacrament.
>> sacrament. Sacrament
>> sacrament of eucharistic
>> sacrament. Sacrament of
>> Eucharistic.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Sacment
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Sacment Eucharist.
>> Okay. Sacment Eucharist. Okay.
>> Sacrament
>> Sacrament of
>> Sacrament of Eucharist.
>> In
>> In the
>> Sacrament of Eucharist.
>> In the Christian
>> In the Christian church.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. She
>> Yes. She wants
>> Yes. She wants to
>> Yes. She wants to know
>> Yes. She wants to know the
>> Yes. She wants to know the calibrated
level
level of
>> Yes. She wants to know the calibrated
level of 700.
level of 700. 700.
>> What
>> What influence
>> What influence does
>> What influence does this
>> What influence does this have
>> What influence does this have on
>> What influence does this have on the
current
current humanity?
>> What
>> What effect
>> What effect does
>> What effect does this
>> What effect does this have?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
Each
Each each
Each each each
Each each each human
Each each each human being
Each each each human being contributes
to
to the
Each each each human being contributes
to the collective
to the collective consciousness.
So
So to
So to go
So to go for
So to go for communion
So to go for communion is
So to go for communion is uh
So to go for communion is uh an
So to go for communion is uh an act
So to go for communion is uh an act of
worship
and
and an
and an act
and an act of
and an act of worship
and an act of worship then
and an act of worship then contributes
in
in a
and an act of worship then contributes
in a positive
in a positive way
and an act of worship then contributes
in a positive way to
in a positive way to the
and an act of worship then contributes
in a positive way to the collective
consciousness
consciousness of
consciousness of mankind.
consciousness of mankind. An
consciousness of mankind. An act
consciousness of mankind. An act of
worship
like
like kneeling
like kneeling prayer.
>> Yes.
>> For
>> For instance,
>> For instance, the
>> For instance, the Korean
>> For instance, the Korean people
>> For instance, the Korean people by
>> For instance, the Korean people by their
reverence
reverence for
>> For instance, the Korean people by their
reverence for life
uplifts
uplifts all
uplifts all of
uplifts all of mankind.
their
their career
uplifts all of mankind.
their career helps
their career helps uplift
uplifts all of mankind.
their career helps uplift the
their career helps uplift the world.
>> Huh?
>> He's
>> He's going
>> Huh?
>> He's going to
>> He's going to say
>> Huh?
>> He's going to say it
>> He's going to say it in
>> Huh?
>> He's going to say it in English
>> He's going to say it in English and
>> Huh?
>> He's going to say it in English and now
you
you got
you got to
you got to translate
you got to translate it.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, right,
you got to translate it.
>> Oh, right, right,
>> Oh, right, right, right.
you got to translate it.
>> Oh, right, right, right. I
>> Oh, right, right, right. I thought
you got to translate it.
>> Oh, right, right, right. I thought my
role
role is
role is over.
>> Hi,
>> Hi, Dr.
role is over.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. My
role is over.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. My name
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. My name is
role is over.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. My name is John.
>> Um
>> Um my
>> Um my question
>> Um my question is
>> Um my question is I've
>> Um my question is I've been
>> Um my question is I've been on
>> Um my question is I've been on a
spiritual
spiritual path
>> Um my question is I've been on a
spiritual path for
spiritual path for several
>> Um my question is I've been on a
spiritual path for several years
spiritual path for several years and
feel
feel that
feel that it's
feel that it's uh
feel that it's uh uh
feel that it's uh uh I've
feel that it's uh uh I've progressed
feel that it's uh uh I've progressed in
most
most areas
feel that it's uh uh I've progressed in
most areas of
most areas of my
feel that it's uh uh I've progressed in
most areas of my life
most areas of my life uh
feel that it's uh uh I've progressed in
most areas of my life uh to
most areas of my life uh to a
feel that it's uh uh I've progressed in
most areas of my life uh to a large
degree.
degree. Uh
degree. Uh but
degree. Uh but my
degree. Uh but my vocational
degree. Uh but my vocational life,
degree. Uh but my vocational life, my
work
work life
degree. Uh but my vocational life, my
work life has
work life has sort
degree. Uh but my vocational life, my
work life has sort of
work life has sort of it's
degree. Uh but my vocational life, my
work life has sort of it's taken
work life has sort of it's taken the
opposite
opposite effect
opposite effect and
uh
uh you
opposite effect and
uh you know
uh you know life
opposite effect and
uh you know life is
uh you know life is short.
opposite effect and
uh you know life is short. Okay.
uh you know life is short. Okay. Well,
that
That's
That's simple.
that
That's simple. You
That's simple. You turn
that
That's simple. You turn your
That's simple. You turn your work
that
That's simple. You turn your work into
an
an act
an act of
an act of worship.
And
And if
an act of worship.
And if you
And if you uh
an act of worship.
And if you uh if
And if you uh if if
an act of worship.
And if you uh if if you
And if you uh if if you uh
an act of worship.
And if you uh if if you uh have
And if you uh if if you uh have the
resources
resources and
resources and want
resources and want to
resources and want to try
resources and want to try a
resources and want to try a new
resources and want to try a new training
or
or new
resources and want to try a new training
or new skill,
or new skill, is
resources and want to try a new training
or new skill, is there
or new skill, is there a
resources and want to try a new training
or new skill, is there a would
or new skill, is there a would you
resources and want to try a new training
or new skill, is there a would you use
like
like muscle
like muscle testing
like muscle testing to
like muscle testing to to
like muscle testing to to use
like muscle testing to to use that
like muscle testing to to use that as
like muscle testing to to use that as a
to
to try
like muscle testing to to use that as a
to try to
to try to find
like muscle testing to to use that as a
to try to find a
to try to find a direction
like muscle testing to to use that as a
to try to find a direction if
to try to find a direction if you
like muscle testing to to use that as a
to try to find a direction if you don't
feel
feel particularly
feel particularly focused?
>> Well,
>> Well, you
feel particularly focused?
>> Well, you must
>> Well, you must know
feel particularly focused?
>> Well, you must know what
>> Well, you must know what you
feel particularly focused?
>> Well, you must know what you like
>> Well, you must know what you like and
it's
it's a
it's a matter
it's a matter of
it's a matter of following
it's a matter of following what
it's a matter of following what what
it's a matter of following what what is
meaningful
meaningful in
it's a matter of following what what is
meaningful in that
meaningful in that which
it's a matter of following what what is
meaningful in that which you
meaningful in that which you like.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Thank you,
>> Okay. Thank you, Dr.
>> Okay. Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
to
to create
>> Okay. Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
to create beauty,
to create beauty, to
>> Okay. Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
to create beauty, to create
to create beauty, to create usefulness,
to
to provide
to provide that
to provide that which
to provide that which is
to provide that which is necessary
and
and provide
to provide that which is necessary
and provide crutches
and provide crutches when
to provide that which is necessary
and provide crutches when you
and provide crutches when you need
crutches.
Okay,
Okay, thank
crutches.
Okay, thank you.
Hi.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. I
Hi.
>> Hello. I am
>> Hello. I am here
Hi.
>> Hello. I am here to
>> Hello. I am here to thank
Hi.
>> Hello. I am here to thank you
>> Hello. I am here to thank you and
Hi.
>> Hello. I am here to thank you and show
gratitude
gratitude and
gratitude and courage
gratitude and courage at
gratitude and courage at the
gratitude and courage at the same
gratitude and courage at the same time
that
that I
gratitude and courage at the same time
that I appreciate
that I appreciate your
gratitude and courage at the same time
that I appreciate your works
that I appreciate your works and
gratitude and courage at the same time
that I appreciate your works and you've
made
made a
made a huge
made a huge change
made a huge change in
made a huge change in me.
Thank
Thank you
made a huge change in me.
Thank you so
Thank you so much.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. I
>> Thank you. I have
>> Thank you. I have uh
>> Thank you. I have uh one
>> Thank you. I have uh one question.
>> Thank you. I have uh one question. I
>> Thank you. I have uh one question. I I
would
would like
>> Thank you. I have uh one question. I I
would like to
would like to say
>> Thank you. I have uh one question. I I
would like to say uh
would like to say uh we
>> Thank you. I have uh one question. I I
would like to say uh we are
would like to say uh we are grateful
>> Thank you. I have uh one question. I I
would like to say uh we are grateful for
the
the love
the love and
the love and truth
the love and truth um
the love and truth um that
the love and truth um that you've
provided.
provided. Um
the love and truth um that you've
provided. Um I
provided. Um I ask
the love and truth um that you've
provided. Um I ask you
provided. Um I ask you if
the love and truth um that you've
provided. Um I ask you if if
provided. Um I ask you if if you
the love and truth um that you've
provided. Um I ask you if if you would
consider
consider um
consider um calibrating
consider um calibrating a
consider um calibrating a a
book.
book. It's
consider um calibrating a a
book. It's an
book. It's an online
consider um calibrating a a
book. It's an online book.
book. It's an online book. I
consider um calibrating a a
book. It's an online book. I know
book. It's an online book. I know the
gentleman
gentleman that
gentleman that wrote
gentleman that wrote it,
gentleman that wrote it, but
gentleman that wrote it, but I
gentleman that wrote it, but I don't
really
really have
gentleman that wrote it, but I don't
really have any
really have any um
gentleman that wrote it, but I don't
really have any um personal
really have any um personal involvement
in
in it.
in it. Uh
in it. Uh it's
in it. Uh it's domain
in it. Uh it's domain of
in it. Uh it's domain of man
in it. Uh it's domain of man and
in it. Uh it's domain of man and it's
in it. Uh it's domain of man and it's uh
written
written about
in it. Uh it's domain of man and it's uh
written about the
written about the histo
man.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. What
man.
>> Okay. What is
>> Okay. What is he
man.
>> Okay. What is he saying?
>> Okay. What is he saying? I
man.
>> Okay. What is he saying? I can't
>> Okay. What is he saying? I can't hear
him.
>> Um
>> Um he
him.
>> Um he uses
>> Um he uses a
him.
>> Um he uses a calibrated
>> Um he uses a calibrated book.
>> Yeah.
>> For
>> For what
>> Yeah.
>> For what purpose?
>> What
>> What purpose?
>> What purpose? It's
>> What purpose? It's a
>> What purpose?
>> What purpose? It's a very
>> What purpose? It's a very detailed
hissterosity
hissterosity of
hissterosity of man
hissterosity of man that
hissterosity of man that gentleman
hissterosity of man that gentleman that
wrote
wrote it
hissterosity of man that gentleman that
wrote it spent
wrote it spent 10
hissterosity of man that gentleman that
wrote it spent 10 years.
wrote it spent 10 years. He
the
the purpose
the purpose perhaps
the purpose perhaps is
the purpose perhaps is to
the purpose perhaps is to give
the purpose perhaps is to give something
if
if it
the purpose perhaps is to give something
if it calibrated
if it calibrated high
the purpose perhaps is to give something
if it calibrated high enough
if it calibrated high enough to
the purpose perhaps is to give something
if it calibrated high enough to be
possibly
possibly uh
possibly uh some
possibly uh some truth
possibly uh some truth or
possibly uh some truth or very
possibly uh some truth or very truthful.
>> Why
>> Why this
possibly uh some truth or very truthful.
>> Why this book?
>> Why this book? What
possibly uh some truth or very truthful.
>> Why this book? What is
>> Why this book? What is it
possibly uh some truth or very truthful.
>> Why this book? What is it about
>> Why this book? What is it about this
book?
>> It's
>> It's about
book?
>> It's about the
>> It's about the histo
book?
>> It's about the histo man.
>> It's about the histo man. The
book?
>> It's about the histo man. The what
>> It's about the histo man. The what histo
what
to
to do
what
to do with
to do with this
what
to do with this book.
>> Is
>> Is he
>> Is he talking
>> Is he talking about
>> Is he talking about the
>> Is he talking about the history
>> Is he talking about the history of
>> Is he talking about the history of man?
>> It's
>> It's a
>> Is he talking about the history of man?
>> It's a book
>> It's a book about
taking
taking archa
taking archa the
taking archa the way
taking archa the way I
taking archa the way I describe
taking archa the way I describe it
taking
taking archaeologically
back
back man
back man with
back man with religion.
>> Archaeologically.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. So
>> Oh. So what's
>> Oh. So what's archaeology
>> Oh. So what's archaeology got
>> Oh. So what's archaeology got to
>> Oh. So what's archaeology got to do
>> Oh. So what's archaeology got to do with
religion
religion then?
>> Oh. So what's archaeology got to do with
religion then? It
religion then? It just
>> Oh. So what's archaeology got to do with
religion then? It just it
religion then? It just it goes
>> Oh. So what's archaeology got to do with
religion then? It just it goes backs
religion then? It just it goes backs I
would
would suppose
would suppose and
would suppose and it
would suppose and it ties
would suppose and it ties I'm
would suppose and it ties I'm I'm
would suppose and it ties I'm I'm not
would suppose and it ties I'm I'm not I
don't
don't know
would suppose and it ties I'm I'm not I
don't know that
don't know that much
would suppose and it ties I'm I'm not I
don't know that much about
don't know that much about the
would suppose and it ties I'm I'm not I
don't know that much about the book.
don't know that much about the book. Uh
>> why
>> why are
>> why are you
>> why are you asking?
>> It
>> It ties
>> why are you asking?
>> It ties in
>> It ties in the
>> Is
>> Is it
>> Is it idle
>> Is it idle curiosity?
Uh
I
I I
I I have
I I have a
I I have a feeling
I I have a feeling that
I I have a feeling that that
I I have a feeling that that it
I I have a feeling that that it it
I I have a feeling that that it it could
be
be a
I I have a feeling that that it it could
be a powerful
be a powerful work
uh
uh for
uh for humanity
>> because
>> because of
uh for humanity
>> because of his
>> because of his archaeologic
uh for humanity
>> because of his archaeologic background
>> because
>> because he
>> because he ties
>> because he ties Egyptology,
>> because he ties Egyptology, biblical
>> because he ties Egyptology, biblical and
uh
>> Egyptology.
>> Egyptology. Yes.
>> Egyptology. Yes. Uh-huh.
>> Ties
>> Ties ties
>> Egyptology. Yes. Uh-huh.
>> Ties ties the
>> Ties ties the names
>> Egyptology. Yes. Uh-huh.
>> Ties ties the names involved
>> Ties ties the names involved in
Egyptology,
the
the Bible,
Egyptology,
the Bible, and
the Bible, and others.
>> Question
>> Question though,
>> Question though, what
>> Question though, what is
>> Question though, what is this
>> Question though, what is this book
calibrate?
>> All right.
>> All right. Okay.
>> All right. Okay. Uh,
>> All right. Okay. Uh, we
>> All right. Okay. Uh, we have
>> All right. Okay. Uh, we have permission
to
to calibrate
>> All right. Okay. Uh, we have permission
to calibrate the
to calibrate the book
>> All right. Okay. Uh, we have permission
to calibrate the book he's
to calibrate the book he's talking
about.
We
We do
about.
We do not
We do not have
about.
We do not have permission
We do not have permission to
about.
We do not have permission to calibrate
that
that book.
that book. Resist.
that book. Resist. I
that book. Resist. I don't
that book. Resist. I don't know
that book. Resist. I don't know why.
>> Okay.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know. I
>> I don't know. I don't
>> I don't know. I don't either.
>> I
>> I have
>> I don't know. I don't either.
>> I have no
>> I have no interest
>> I don't know. I don't either.
>> I have no interest in
>> I have no interest in it.
>> Well,
>> Well, Egyptian
>> Well, Egyptian history
>> Well, Egyptian history is
>> Well, Egyptian history is fascinating,
you
you know,
>> Well, Egyptian history is fascinating,
you know, and
you know, and I
>> Well, Egyptian history is fascinating,
you know, and I was
you know, and I was in
>> Well, Egyptian history is fascinating,
you know, and I was in Egypt
you know, and I was in Egypt and
>> Well, Egyptian history is fascinating,
you know, and I was in Egypt and I
meditated
meditated all
meditated all night
meditated all night in
meditated all night in one
meditated all night in one of
meditated all night in one of the
meditated all night in one of the great
pyramids,
pyramids, in
meditated all night in one of the great
pyramids, in fact,
pyramids, in fact, you
meditated all night in one of the great
pyramids, in fact, you know,
pyramids, in fact, you know, and
meditated all night in one of the great
pyramids, in fact, you know, and uh
pyramids, in fact, you know, and uh I
got
got a
got a great
got a great deal
got a great deal out
got a great deal out of
got a great deal out of visiting
uh
uh Egypt.
got a great deal out of visiting
uh Egypt. Its
uh Egypt. Its ancientness,
you
you know,
you know, it
you know, it it
you know, it it was
the
the civilization
you know, it it was
the civilization of
the civilization of Egypt
you know, it it was
the civilization of Egypt was
the civilization of Egypt was 10,000
years
years old
years old when
years old when the
years old when the Western
years old when the Western world
years old when the Western world was
just
just born.
years old when the Western world was
just born. And
just born. And that
years old when the Western world was
just born. And that gives
just born. And that gives you
years old when the Western world was
just born. And that gives you a
just born. And that gives you a certain
respect
respect for
respect for Egyptology.
Thank
Thank you
respect for Egyptology.
Thank you very
Thank you very much.
>> 10,000
>> 10,000 years
>> 10,000 years before
>> 10,000 years before the
>> 10,000 years before the modern
>> 10,000 years before the modern era
>> 10,000 years before the modern era even
began.
>> I'll
>> I'll leave
>> I'll leave that.
>> I'll leave that. Can
>> I'll leave that. Can I
>> I'll leave that. Can I leave
>> I'll leave that. Can I leave that
>> I'll leave that. Can I leave that with
you?
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> And
>> And King
>> Thank you.
>> And King Tut's
>> And King Tut's tomb
>> Thank you.
>> And King Tut's tomb is
>> And King Tut's tomb is very
>> Thank you.
>> And King Tut's tomb is very fascinating.
>> I
>> I never
>> I never calibrated
>> I never calibrated it.
>> Yes.
>> No,
>> No, I
>> No, I think
>> No, I think I
>> No, I think I did
>> No, I think I did calibrate
>> No, I think I did calibrate it
>> No, I think I did calibrate it once.
>> No, I think I did calibrate it once. I
forgot
forgot what
>> No, I think I did calibrate it once. I
forgot what it
forgot what it was.
Yes.
Yes. Egypt.
Yes. Egypt. If
Yes. Egypt. If you're
Yes. Egypt. If you're fascinated
Yes. Egypt. If you're fascinated by
Yes. Egypt. If you're fascinated by the
origins
origins of
Yes. Egypt. If you're fascinated by the
origins of religion,
the
the Middle
the Middle East
the Middle East and
the Middle East and then
>> Hi,
>> Egypt,
>> Egypt, they're
>> Egypt, they're great
>> Egypt, they're great places
>> Egypt, they're great places to
>> Egypt, they're great places to go.
>> Hi,
>> Hi, Doc.
>> Yes.
>> Hi.
Um,
Um, I
Um, I need
Um, I need help
Um, I need help with
Um, I need help with step
Um, I need help with step six.
>> Is
>> Is he
Um, I need help with step six.
>> Is he speaking
>> Is he speaking closer
Um, I need help with step six.
>> Is he speaking closer than
>> Is he speaking closer than I
Um, I need help with step six.
>> Is he speaking closer than I can?
>> I
>> I need
>> I need help
>> I need help with
>> I need help with step
>> I need help with step six.
>> He
>> He needs
>> I need help with step six.
>> He needs help
>> He needs help with
>> I need help with step six.
>> He needs help with what?
>> Step
>> Step six.
>> Step six. What's
>> Step six. What's that?
became
became entirely
became entirely ready
became entirely ready to
became entirely ready to have
became entirely ready to have God
became entirely ready to have God remove
all
all these
became entirely ready to have God remove
all these defects
all these defects of
became entirely ready to have God remove
all these defects of character.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
What's
What's your
>> Oh, okay.
What's your problem
What's your problem with
>> Oh, okay.
What's your problem with it?
>> What's
>> What's your
>> What's your problem
>> What's your problem with
>> What's your problem with it?
>> What's
>> What's my
>> What's your problem with it?
>> What's my problem
>> What's my problem with
>> What's your problem with it?
>> What's my problem with it?
>> What's my problem with it? Um,
>> you
>> you don't
>> you don't want
>> you don't want God
>> you don't want God to
>> you don't want God to remove
>> you don't want God to remove your
defects
defects of
>> you don't want God to remove your
defects of character,
>> right?
>> right? I
>> right? I don't
>> right? I don't I
>> right? I don't I don't
>> right? I don't I don't have
>> right? I don't I don't have any.
>> I
>> I can't
>> right? I don't I don't have any.
>> I can't remember.
ready
ready to
ready to have
ready to have God
ready to have God remove
ready to have God remove them.
ready to have God remove them. See,
ready to have God remove them. See, the
questions
questions we've
ready to have God remove them. See, the
questions we've gotten
questions we've gotten so
ready to have God remove them. See, the
questions we've gotten so far,
questions we've gotten so far, the
person
person is
person is taking
person is taking divine
person is taking divine responsibility
to
to raise
person is taking divine responsibility
to raise your
to raise your level
person is taking divine responsibility
to raise your level of
to raise your level of consciousness.
What
What can
What can I
What can I do
What can I do to
What can I do to do?
Now,
Now, what
What can I do to do?
Now, what you're
Now, what you're bringing
What can I do to do?
Now, what you're bringing up
Now, what you're bringing up is
something
something of
something of a
something of a higher
something of a higher order.
The
The willingness
something of a higher order.
The willingness to
The willingness to surrender
something of a higher order.
The willingness to surrender these
defects
defects to
defects to God,
defects to God, to
defects to God, to surrender
defects to God, to surrender them
defects to God, to surrender them to
God.
God. The
defects to God, to surrender them to
God. The sixth
God. The sixth step.
defects to God, to surrender them to
God. The sixth step. Yes.
Became
Became entirely
Became entirely willing.
If
If you're
Became entirely willing.
If you're not
If you're not willing,
Became entirely willing.
If you're not willing, it
If you're not willing, it means
Became entirely willing.
If you're not willing, it means you're
still
still getting
still getting juice
still getting juice out
still getting juice out of
still getting juice out of it.
still getting juice out of it. So
still getting juice out of it. So you
have
have to
still getting juice out of it. So you
have to be
have to be willing
still getting juice out of it. So you
have to be willing to
have to be willing to let
still getting juice out of it. So you
have to be willing to let go
have to be willing to let go of
still getting juice out of it. So you
have to be willing to let go of the
juice.
>> It's
>> It's not
juice.
>> It's not the
>> It's not the limitation.
juice.
>> It's not the limitation. It's
>> It's not the limitation. It's the
juice.
>> It's not the limitation. It's the juice
that
that you
that you get
that you get out
that you get out of
that you get out of the
that you get out of the limitation.
>> Yes.
>> Actually,
>> Actually, since
>> Actually, since there
>> Actually, since there are
>> Actually, since there are so
>> Actually, since there are so many
>> Actually, since there are so many I
think
think there
>> Actually, since there are so many I
think there are
think there are so
>> Actually, since there are so many I
think there are so many
think there are so many we
>> Is
>> Is he
>> Is he from
>> Is he from Korea?
>> We
>> We can
>> Is he from Korea?
>> We can create.
>> Are
>> Are you
>> Are you from
>> Are you from Korea?
>> Are you from Korea? No.
>> But
>> But the
>> Are you from Korea? No.
>> But the Koreans
>> But the Koreans don't
>> Are you from Korea? No.
>> But the Koreans don't know
>> But the Koreans don't know what
>> Are you from Korea? No.
>> But the Koreans don't know what you're
saying
>> actually.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
>> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see. For
>> Oh, I see. For him.
>> Oh, I see. For him. I
>> Oh, I see. For him. I was
>> Oh, I see. For him. I was waiting
>> Oh, I see. For him. I was waiting for
him
him to
>> Oh, I see. For him. I was waiting for
him to translate
him to translate him.
>> Are
>> Are we
>> Are we getting
are
are we
>> Are we getting
are we getting
are we getting this
>> Are we getting
are we getting this in
are we getting this in uh
>> Are we getting
are we getting this in uh DVD?
are we getting this in uh DVD? Then
>> Are we getting
are we getting this in uh DVD? Then we
have
have no
have no problem.
have no problem. Then
have no problem. Then I
have no problem. Then I think
have no problem. Then I think so
have no problem. Then I think so many
people
people are
have no problem. Then I think so many
people are lined
people are lined up.
have no problem. Then I think so many
people are lined up. So
people are lined up. So we
have no problem. Then I think so many
people are lined up. So we better
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> So
>> So if
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> So if if
>> So if if I
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> So if if I don't
>> So if if I don't translate,
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> So if if I don't translate, it'll
>> So if if I don't translate, it'll save
some
some time.
>> Willingness
>> Willingness to
some time.
>> Willingness to surrender.
>> Willing
>> Willing to
translate
translate this
>> Willing to
translate this English.
The
The willingness
The willingness to
The willingness to surrender
The willingness to surrender means
The willingness to surrender means that
you've
you've taken
The willingness to surrender means that
you've taken all
you've taken all the
The willingness to surrender means that
you've taken all the juice
you've taken all the juice out
The willingness to surrender means that
you've taken all the juice out of
you've taken all the juice out of it
that
that you
that you can
that you can get.
that you can get. And
that you can get. And if
that you can get. And if you're
that you can get. And if you're clinging
to
to it,
that you can get. And if you're clinging
to it, you're
to it, you're still
that you can get. And if you're clinging
to it, you're still getting
to it, you're still getting juice
that you can get. And if you're clinging
to it, you're still getting juice out
to it, you're still getting juice out of
it.
So
So all
it.
So all you
So all you got
it.
So all you got to
So all you got to be
it.
So all you got to be do
So all you got to be do willing
it.
So all you got to be do willing to
So all you got to be do willing to is
it.
So all you got to be do willing to is to
let
let go
let go the
let go the juice
let go the juice you're
let go the juice you're getting
let go the juice you're getting out
let go the juice you're getting out of
it.
it. Okay.
>> Does
>> Does that
>> Does that mean
>> Does that mean that
>> Does that mean that you
>> Does that mean that you have
>> Does that mean that you have to
>> Does that mean that you have to hit
bottom
bottom on
>> Does that mean that you have to hit
bottom on certain
bottom on certain defects
>> Does that mean that you have to hit
bottom on certain defects of
bottom on certain defects of character
or
>> That's
>> That's for
or
>> That's for sure.
couldn't
couldn't be
couldn't be plainer
couldn't be plainer stated
couldn't be plainer stated than
couldn't be plainer stated than it
couldn't be plainer stated than it is.
Um,
>> yeah,
>> I
>> I was
>> yeah,
>> I was fortunate
>> I was fortunate enough
>> yeah,
>> I was fortunate enough to
>> I was fortunate enough to meet
>> yeah,
>> I was fortunate enough to meet a
>> I was fortunate enough to meet a friend
of
of yours.
of yours. Um,
of yours. Um, you
of yours. Um, you went
of yours. Um, you went across
of yours. Um, you went across to
of yours. Um, you went across to Egypt
and
and you
of yours. Um, you went across to Egypt
and you went
and you went and
of yours. Um, you went across to Egypt
and you went and met
and you went and met Moo
of yours. Um, you went across to Egypt
and you went and met Moo Dandanda
together.
together. I
together. I was
together. I was wondering
together. I was wondering if
together. I was wondering if he
together. I was wondering if he would
together. I was wondering if he would be
a
a valuable
together. I was wondering if he would be
a valuable in
a valuable in help
together. I was wondering if he would be
a valuable in help assisting
a valuable in help assisting me
together. I was wondering if he would be
a valuable in help assisting me in
a valuable in help assisting me in that
process
of
of steps.
What's
What's the
What's the question?
>> Um,
>> Um, if
What's the question?
>> Um, if the
>> Um, if the if
What's the question?
>> Um, if the if the
>> Um, if the if the friend
What's the question?
>> Um, if the if the friend that
>> Um, if the if the friend that um
>> I
>> I can't
>> I can't hear
>> I can't hear what
>> I can't hear what he's
>> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> He
>> He said
>> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> He said he
>> He said he met
>> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> He said he met a
>> He said he met a friend
>> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> He said he met a friend of
>> He said he met a friend of yours.
>> Mhm.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And I
>> And I was
>> And I was wondering
>> And I was wondering if
>> And I was wondering if he'd
>> And I was wondering if he'd be
>> And I was wondering if he'd be a
>> And I was wondering if he'd be a a
valuable
valuable asset
>> And I was wondering if he'd be a a
valuable asset in
valuable asset in going
>> And I was wondering if he'd be a a
valuable asset in going through
valuable asset in going through that
process
process of
process of the
process of the steps
process of the steps and
process of the steps and learning
process of the steps and learning more
about
about myself
process of the steps and learning more
about myself through
about myself through the
process of the steps and learning more
about myself through the steps.
>> How
>> How do
>> How do I
>> How do I know?
>> How do I know? I
>> How do I know? I couldn't
>> How do I know? I couldn't tell
>> How do I know? I couldn't tell you.
>> How do I know? I couldn't tell you. You
know,
know, you're
>> How do I know? I couldn't tell you. You
know, you're attracted
know, you're attracted to
>> How do I know? I couldn't tell you. You
know, you're attracted to the
know, you're attracted to the steps
>> How do I know? I couldn't tell you. You
know, you're attracted to the steps and
you're
you're interested
you're interested in
you're interested in spiritual
advancement.
advancement. So
you're interested in spiritual
advancement. So you
advancement. So you work
you're interested in spiritual
advancement. So you work the
advancement. So you work the 12
you're interested in spiritual
advancement. So you work the 12 steps
advancement. So you work the 12 steps to
the
the best
the best of
the best of your
the best of your advancement.
And
And you,
the best of your advancement.
And you, you
And you, you know,
the best of your advancement.
And you, you know, as
And you, you know, as far
the best of your advancement.
And you, you know, as far as
And you, you know, as far as picking
the best of your advancement.
And you, you know, as far as picking a
sponsor,
sponsor, that's
sponsor, that's a
sponsor, that's a different
sponsor, that's a different thing.
sponsor, that's a different thing. And
intu
intu intuition
sponsor, that's a different thing. And
intu intuition plus
uh
uh good
uh good luck.
uh good luck. You
uh good luck. You get
uh good luck. You get a
uh good luck. You get a good
uh good luck. You get a good one.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Do
>> Do we
>> Yeah.
>> Do we have
>> Do we have enough
>> Yeah.
>> Do we have enough time?
>> Do we have enough time? Do
>> Yeah.
>> Do we have enough time? Do I
>> Do we have enough time? Do I do
>> Yeah.
>> Do we have enough time? Do I do I
>> Do we have enough time? Do I do I have
to
to keep
to keep translating
to keep translating or
>> No,
>> okay.
>> okay. Actually,
>> okay. Actually, I
>> okay. Actually, I just
>> okay. Actually, I just want
>> okay. Actually, I just want to
>> okay. Actually, I just want to I
>> okay. Actually, I just want to I don't
want
want to
>> okay. Actually, I just want to I don't
want to take
want to take take
>> okay. Actually, I just want to I don't
want to take take up
want to take take up time.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, no.
>> Oh, no. You
>> Oh, no. You can
>> Oh, no. You can translate,
>> Oh, no. You can translate, but
>> Oh, no. You can translate, but we'll
just
just try
>> Oh, no. You can translate, but we'll
just try to
just try to abbreviate
>> Oh, no. You can translate, but we'll
just try to abbreviate it.
>> Yes.
>> Hi.
>> Um
>> Yes.
>> Um Dr.
>> Um Dr. Hawkins,
>> Yes.
>> Um Dr. Hawkins, I've
>> Um Dr. Hawkins, I've um
>> Yes.
>> Um Dr. Hawkins, I've um been
>> Um Dr. Hawkins, I've um been having
>> Yes.
>> Um Dr. Hawkins, I've um been having a
feeling
feeling on
feeling on my
feeling on my heart
feeling on my heart chakra.
A
A a
feeling on my heart chakra.
A a feeling
A a feeling on
feeling on my heart chakra.
A a feeling on my
A a feeling on my heart
feeling on my heart chakra.
A a feeling on my heart chakra.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. In
>> Yes. In your
>> Yes. In your heart.
>> Yes. In your heart. Yeah.
>> Right.
>> Right. Um,
and
and it
and it feels
and it feels like
and it feels like u
and it feels like u like
and it feels like u like a
and it feels like u like a egess
and it feels like u like a egess um
and it feels like u like a egess um like
um
um like
um like just
um like just commumulative
um like just commumulative egoess.
um like just commumulative egoess. Um
>> put
>> put her
um like just commumulative egoess. Um
>> put her put
>> put her put them
um like just commumulative egoess. Um
>> put her put them right
>> put her put them right closer
um like just commumulative egoess. Um
>> put her put them right closer to
>> put her put them right closer to her
mouth
mouth and
mouth and very
>> Oh,
>> Oh, it
mouth and very
>> Oh, it feels
>> Oh, it feels it
mouth and very
>> Oh, it feels it feels
>> Oh, it feels it feels like
mouth and very
>> Oh, it feels it feels like egess
>> Oh, it feels it feels like egess like
mouth and very
>> Oh, it feels it feels like egess like a
feeling
feeling of
feeling of of
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, like
feeling of of
>> Yeah, like collect
>> Yeah, like collect my
feeling of of
>> Yeah, like collect my collective
>> Yeah, like collect my collective ego
like
like my
like my ego.
>> And
>> what
>> what the
>> what the heck
>> what the heck does
>> what the heck does that
>> what the heck does that feel
>> what the heck does that feel like?
I
I know,
>> what the heck does that feel like?
I know, but
I know, but it's
>> what the heck does that feel like?
I know, but it's a
I know, but it's a matter
>> what the heck does that feel like?
I know, but it's a matter of
I know, but it's a matter of heart.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's
>> Yeah. It's a
>> Yeah. It's a lot
>> Yeah. It's a lot of
>> Yeah. It's a lot of negative
>> Yeah. It's a lot of negative energy
basically.
>> Me
>> Me me.
>> Me me. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Me me. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And it
>> Yeah. And it gets
>> Me me. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And it gets really
>> Yeah. And it gets really really
overwhelming
overwhelming to
overwhelming to the
overwhelming to the point
overwhelming to the point where
overwhelming to the point where it
overwhelming to the point where it feels
like
like almost
overwhelming to the point where it feels
like almost terror.
>> So
>> So it's
>> So it's blocked.
>> Yeah.
>> You
>> You got
>> You got to
>> You got to breathe
>> You got to breathe it
>> You got to breathe it up
>> You got to breathe it up to
>> You got to breathe it up to the
>> You got to breathe it up to the throat
and
and then
>> You got to breathe it up to the throat
and then to
and then to the
>> You got to breathe it up to the throat
and then to the eye.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Yeah. And I
>> Yeah. And I feel
>> Yeah. And I feel it
>> Yeah. And I feel it going
>> Yeah. And I feel it going up
>> Yeah. And I feel it going up to
>> Yeah. And I feel it going up to the
throat
throat and
>> Yeah. And I feel it going up to the
throat and it
throat and it feels
>> Yeah. And I feel it going up to the
throat and it feels like
throat and it feels like hard
>> Yeah. And I feel it going up to the
throat and it feels like hard right
throat and it feels like hard right here
and
and hard
and hard on
and hard on my
and hard on my heart
and hard on my heart like
and hard on my heart like a
and hard on my heart like a pressure.
>> Well,
>> Well, you
and hard on my heart like a pressure.
>> Well, you got
>> Well, you got to
and hard on my heart like a pressure.
>> Well, you got to breathe
>> Well, you got to breathe it
and hard on my heart like a pressure.
>> Well, you got to breathe it then
>> Well, you got to breathe it then from
the
the throat
the throat up
the throat up to
the throat up to the
the throat up to the third
the throat up to the third eye.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So,
>> Yeah. So, if
>> Yeah. So, if you're
>> Yeah. So, if you're going
>> Yeah. So, if you're going to
>> Yeah. So, if you're going to use
>> Yeah. So, if you're going to use a
>> Yeah. So, if you're going to use a yoga
kind
kind of
>> Yeah. So, if you're going to use a yoga
kind of meditation,
kind of meditation, you
>> Yeah. So, if you're going to use a yoga
kind of meditation, you breathe
kind of meditation, you breathe it
>> Yeah. So, if you're going to use a yoga
kind of meditation, you breathe it up
and
and you
and you picture
and you picture the
and you picture the energy
and you picture the energy flowing
and you picture the energy flowing up
and you picture the energy flowing up uh
through
through the
and you picture the energy flowing up uh
through the chakra
through the chakra system
and you picture the energy flowing up uh
through the chakra system eventually
through the chakra system eventually to
the
the crown
the crown chakra.
>> Okay.
>> And
>> And you
>> And you pray
>> And you pray to
>> And you pray to God
>> And you pray to God for
>> And you pray to God for help
>> And you pray to God for help with
>> And you pray to God for help with the
endeavor.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
>> So, um
>> So, um I
>> So, um I was
>> So, um I was just
>> So, um I was just wondering,
>> So, um I was just wondering, do
>> So, um I was just wondering, do I
>> So, um I was just wondering, do I have
to
to surrender
>> So, um I was just wondering, do I have
to surrender to
to surrender to anything?
>> So, um I was just wondering, do I have
to surrender to anything? Cuz
to surrender to anything? Cuz um
>> So, um I was just wondering, do I have
to surrender to anything? Cuz um like
last
last night
last night it
last night it just
last night it just got
last night it just got really
overwhelming
overwhelming right
last night it just got really
overwhelming right on
overwhelming right on the
last night it just got really
overwhelming right on the heart.
overwhelming right on the heart. Um
last night it just got really
overwhelming right on the heart. Um like
this,
this, you
this, you know,
this, you know, negative.
>> So,
>> So, you're
this, you know, negative.
>> So, you're blocking
>> So, you're blocking what
this, you know, negative.
>> So, you're blocking what would
>> So, you're blocking what would you
this, you know, negative.
>> So, you're blocking what would you be
blocking
blocking it
blocking it about?
blocking it about? I
blocking it about? I was
blocking it about? I was just
blocking it about? I was just wondering
if
letting
letting go,
letting go, wanting
letting go, wanting to
letting go, wanting to control
letting go, wanting to control because
that's
that's what
letting go, wanting to control because
that's what I've
that's what I've been
letting go, wanting to control because
that's what I've been doing.
that's what I've been doing. I
letting go, wanting to control because
that's what I've been doing. I I
that's what I've been doing. I I haven't
been
been breathing
been breathing it
been breathing it up.
been breathing it up. I've
been breathing it up. I've just
>> All right.
>> All right. Keep
been breathing it up. I've just
>> All right. Keep breathing
>> All right. Keep breathing it
been breathing it up. I've just
>> All right. Keep breathing it up
>> All right. Keep breathing it up to
been breathing it up. I've just
>> All right. Keep breathing it up to the
third
third eye.
third eye. Okay.
third eye. Okay. And
third eye. Okay. And then
third eye. Okay. And then from
third eye. Okay. And then from the
third eye. Okay. And then from the third
eye
eye to
third eye. Okay. And then from the third
eye to the
eye to the crown
third eye. Okay. And then from the third
eye to the crown chakra,
>> okay?
>> And
>> And you
>> okay?
>> And you ask
>> And you ask God
>> okay?
>> And you ask God to
>> And you ask God to assist
>> okay?
>> And you ask God to assist you.
>> And you ask God to assist you. And
>> okay?
>> And you ask God to assist you. And you
picture
picture the
picture the condolini
picture the condolini energy
uh
uh flowing
picture the condolini energy
uh flowing up
uh flowing up to
picture the condolini energy
uh flowing up to to
uh flowing up to to the
picture the condolini energy
uh flowing up to to the chakra
uh flowing up to to the chakra system.
Uh
Uh eventually
Uh eventually to
Uh eventually to the
Uh eventually to the crown
Uh eventually to the crown chakra.
Beyond
Beyond that,
Uh eventually to the crown chakra.
Beyond that, there's
Beyond that, there's some
Uh eventually to the crown chakra.
Beyond that, there's some couple
Beyond that, there's some couple of
centers
centers above
centers above the
centers above the crown
centers above the crown chakra.
centers above the crown chakra. You
worry
worry about
centers above the crown chakra. You
worry about them
worry about them next
centers above the crown chakra. You
worry about them next year.
>> Okay.
Thank
Thank you
>> Okay.
Thank you very
Thank you very much.
>> Okay.
Thank you very much. Okay.
ground
ground checker.
ground checker. Yeah.
>> How
>> How are
ground checker. Yeah.
>> How are you?
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> Um I'd
>> Yeah.
>> Um I'd just
>> Um I'd just like
>> Yeah.
>> Um I'd just like to
>> Um I'd just like to ask
>> Yeah.
>> Um I'd just like to ask if
>> Um I'd just like to ask if it's
>> Yeah.
>> Um I'd just like to ask if it's in
>> Um I'd just like to ask if it's in the
highest
highest good
highest good to
highest good to be
highest good to be starting
highest good to be starting a
highest good to be starting a particular
project.
So
So if
So if I
So if I give
So if I give you
So if I give you the
So if I give you the name
So if I give you the name of
So if I give you the name of that
project,
project, can
So if I give you the name of that
project, can I
project, can I see
So if I give you the name of that
project, can I see if
project, can I see if it's
So if I give you the name of that
project, can I see if it's in
project, can I see if it's in the
highest
highest good
highest good to
>> We
>> We have
highest good to
>> We have permission
>> We have permission to
highest good to
>> We have permission to ask
>> We have permission to ask if
highest good to
>> We have permission to ask if this
>> We have permission to ask if this would
serve
serve h
serve h his
serve h his highest
serve h his highest good.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Um
>> Okay. Um the
>> Okay. Um the name
>> Okay. Um the name of
>> Okay. Um the name of the
>> Okay. Um the name of the project
>> Okay. Um the name of the project is
>> Okay. Um the name of the project is the
conscious
conscious web.
>> Okay. Um the name of the project is the
conscious web. The
>> conscious
>> conscious web.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. The
>> conscious web.
>> Yes. The conscious
>> Yes. The conscious web.
>> The
>> The conscious
>> The conscious web
>> The conscious web would
>> The conscious web would serve
>> The conscious web would serve the
highest
highest good.
>> The conscious web would serve the
highest good. Resist.
>> Thanks
>> Thanks for
>> Thanks for your
>> Thanks for your help.
Uh,
may
may I
may I hold
may I hold your
may I hold your hand?
>> Hello,
>> Hello, Dr.
may I hold your hand?
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins and
may I hold your hand?
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins and Susan.
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins and Susan. I
may I hold your hand?
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins and Susan. I have
>> Hello, Dr. Hawkins and Susan. I have a
question
question of
question of the
question of the highest
question of the highest good
question of the highest good to
question of the highest good to ask
question of the highest good to ask of
my
my daughter's
question of the highest good to ask of
my daughter's condition.
my daughter's condition. She
question of the highest good to ask of
my daughter's condition. She has
my daughter's condition. She has now
turned
turned 18
turned 18 and
turned 18 and she's
turned 18 and she's being
turned 18 and she's being transferred
from
from a
turned 18 and she's being transferred
from a pediatric
from a pediatric epito
here
here in
here in Phoenix.
here in Phoenix. I
here in Phoenix. I want
here in Phoenix. I want you
here in Phoenix. I want you to
here in Phoenix. I want you to put
here in Phoenix. I want you to put the
microphone
microphone closer
here in Phoenix. I want you to put the
microphone closer and
microphone closer and speak
here in Phoenix. I want you to put the
microphone closer and speak slower.
>> Okay.
>> Start
>> Start over.
>> Start over. Okay.
>> Start over. Okay. So,
>> Start over. Okay. So, my
>> Start over. Okay. So, my daughter
>> Start over. Okay. So, my daughter just
turned
turned 18.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And she's
>> Yes.
>> And she's no
>> And she's no longer
>> Yes.
>> And she's no longer able
>> And she's no longer able to
>> Yes.
>> And she's no longer able to be
>> And she's no longer able to be treated
by
by a
by a pediatric
by a pediatric epitologist
by a pediatric epitologist at
by a pediatric epitologist at Mayo
by a pediatric epitologist at Mayo in
Rochester.
>> Yes.
>> So,
>> So, they're
>> Yes.
>> So, they're moving
>> So, they're moving her
>> Yes.
>> So, they're moving her to
>> So, they're moving her to Phoenix.
>> Yes.
>> So, they're moving her to Phoenix. And
>> So, they're moving her to Phoenix. And I
wanted
wanted to
wanted to ask
wanted to ask if
wanted to ask if it's
wanted to ask if it's in
wanted to ask if it's in the
wanted to ask if it's in the highest
good
good that
wanted to ask if it's in the highest
good that I
good that I let
wanted to ask if it's in the highest
good that I let her
good that I let her stay
wanted to ask if it's in the highest
good that I let her stay at
good that I let her stay at the
wanted to ask if it's in the highest
good that I let her stay at the Phoenix
Mayo.
>> If
>> If it's
Mayo.
>> If it's in
>> If it's in the
Mayo.
>> If it's in the highest
>> If it's in the highest good
Mayo.
>> If it's in the highest good that
>> If it's in the highest good that what
>> her
>> her daughter
>> her daughter stays
>> her daughter stays at
>> her daughter stays at the
>> may
>> in
>> in Phoenix.
>> in Phoenix. We
>> in Phoenix. We have
>> in Phoenix. We have permission
>> in Phoenix. We have permission to
>> in Phoenix. We have permission to ask
this.
this. It
>> in Phoenix. We have permission to ask
this. It would
this. It would serve
>> in Phoenix. We have permission to ask
this. It would serve the
this. It would serve the daughter's
highest
highest good
highest good to
highest good to stay
highest good to stay with
highest good to stay with the
highest good to stay with the Mayo
Clinic.
Clinic. Resist.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Okay.
>> Yes. Okay. Um
>> Yes. Okay. Um I'd
>> Yes. Okay. Um I'd also
>> Yes. Okay. Um I'd also like
>> Yes. Okay. Um I'd also like to
>> Yes. Okay. Um I'd also like to let
>> Yes. Okay. Um I'd also like to let you
know
know that
>> Yes. Okay. Um I'd also like to let you
know that um
know that um the
>> Yes. Okay. Um I'd also like to let you
know that um the miracle
know that um the miracle that
>> Yes. Okay. Um I'd also like to let you
know that um the miracle that has
happened
happened in
happened in the
happened in the last
happened in the last 6
happened in the last 6 months,
happened in the last 6 months, she
graduated
graduated high
happened in the last 6 months, she
graduated high school
graduated high school a
happened in the last 6 months, she
graduated high school a year
graduated high school a year early.
She's
She's been
She's been accepted
She's been accepted to
She's been accepted to go
She's been accepted to go to
She's been accepted to go to Yavapai
She's been accepted to go to Yavapai and
she
she starts
She's been accepted to go to Yavapai and
she starts in
she starts in January
She's been accepted to go to Yavapai and
she starts in January with
she starts in January with a
She's been accepted to go to Yavapai and
she starts in January with a psychology
degree.
degree. And
degree. And I
degree. And I wanted
degree. And I wanted to
degree. And I wanted to tell
degree. And I wanted to tell you
degree. And I wanted to tell you thank
you
you and
degree. And I wanted to tell you thank
you and I
you and I love
degree. And I wanted to tell you thank
you and I love you
you and I love you so
degree. And I wanted to tell you thank
you and I love you so so
you and I love you so so much.
degree. And I wanted to tell you thank
you and I love you so so much. I
you and I love you so so much. I love
you
you so
you so much
you so much for
you so much for what
you so much for what you've
you so much for what you've given,
you so much for what you've given, the
hope
hope and
you so much for what you've given, the
hope and the
hope and the inspiration
you so much for what you've given, the
hope and the inspiration and
hope and the inspiration and the
guidance
guidance and
guidance and the
guidance and the advice.
guidance and the advice. I
guidance and the advice. I love
guidance and the advice. I love you
guidance and the advice. I love you so
much.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Glad
>> Thank you. Glad things
>> Thank you. Glad things are
>> Thank you. Glad things are working
>> Thank you. Glad things are working out.
>> That
>> That was
>> Thank you. Glad things are working out.
>> That was the
>> That was the lady
>> Thank you. Glad things are working out.
>> That was the lady that
>> That was the lady that had
>> Thank you. Glad things are working out.
>> That was the lady that had struggled
with
with their
with their daughter's
with their daughter's health
with their daughter's health for
with their daughter's health for a
with their daughter's health for a long
time.
>> Right.
>> Right. Right.
>> Right. Right. Right.
>> They're
>> They're either
>> Right. Right. Right.
>> They're either too
>> They're either too close
>> Right. Right. Right.
>> They're either too close to
>> They're either too close to the
>> Right. Right. Right.
>> They're either too close to the mic
>> They're either too close to the mic or
not
not or
not or not
not or not far
not or not far enough.
not or not far enough. I
not or not far enough. I don't know.
Hi,
Hi, are
not or not far enough. I don't know.
Hi, are there
Hi, are there angels
not or not far enough. I don't know.
Hi, are there angels on
Hi, are there angels on earth
not or not far enough. I don't know.
Hi, are there angels on earth in
Hi, are there angels on earth in human
form?
>> We
>> We have
form?
>> We have permission
>> We have permission to
form?
>> We have permission to ask
>> We have permission to ask this.
The
The answer
The answer is
The answer is yes.
There
There are
The answer is yes.
There are angels
There are angels in
The answer is yes.
There are angels in human
There are angels in human form.
There
There are
There are not
There are not angels
There are not angels in
There are not angels in human
There are not angels in human form.
Oh,
Oh, angels
There are not angels in human form.
Oh, angels by
Oh, angels by definition
There are not angels in human form.
Oh, angels by definition are
Oh, angels by definition are nonlinear.
Angels
Angels by
Angels by definition
Angels by definition are
Angels by definition are something
Angels by definition are something else.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
Angels by definition are something else.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> So
>> So angels
>> So angels are
>> So angels are within
>> So angels are within within
>> So angels are within within the
>> So angels are within within the angelic
realm.
They
They influence
They influence the
They influence the physical
They influence the physical realm.
>> They
>> They influence
They influence the physical realm.
>> They influence it
>> They influence it but
They influence the physical realm.
>> They influence it but they
>> They influence it but they are
They influence the physical realm.
>> They influence it but they are not
>> They influence it but they are not of
the
the same
the same domain.
the same domain. Yeah.
the same domain. Yeah. Okay.
Over
the
the past
the past eight
the past eight months
the past eight months um
the past eight months um my
the past eight months um my sense
the past eight months um my sense of
disorientation
disorientation has
the past eight months um my sense of
disorientation has increased.
disorientation has increased. There's
the past eight months um my sense of
disorientation has increased. There's an
intense
intense condundalini
intense condundalini um
intense condundalini um pressure
intense condundalini um pressure in
intense condundalini um pressure in the
middle
middle of
intense condundalini um pressure in the
middle of my
middle of my forehead
intense condundalini um pressure in the
middle of my forehead and
middle of my forehead and I
intense condundalini um pressure in the
middle of my forehead and I see
middle of my forehead and I see that
intense condundalini um pressure in the
middle of my forehead and I see that as
blocking
blocking uh
blocking uh the
blocking uh the fear
blocking uh the fear for
blocking uh the fear for what
blocking uh the fear for what might
occur
occur to
blocking uh the fear for what might
occur to me
occur to me if
blocking uh the fear for what might
occur to me if my
occur to me if my disorientation
intensifies
intensifies as
intensifies as I
intensifies as I pursue
intensifies as I pursue the
intensifies as I pursue the path.
intensifies as I pursue the path. I
intensifies as I pursue the path. I see
that
that as
intensifies as I pursue the path. I see
that as a
that as a block
intensifies as I pursue the path. I see
that as a block to
that as a block to um
intensifies as I pursue the path. I see
that as a block to um living
that as a block to um living in
intensifies as I pursue the path. I see
that as a block to um living in silence.
Every
Every now
Every now and
Every now and then
Every now and then I
Every now and then I have
Every now and then I have moments
Every now and then I have moments of
silence
silence and
Every now and then I have moments of
silence and I
silence and I see
Every now and then I have moments of
silence and I see myself
silence and I see myself resisting
Every now and then I have moments of
silence and I see myself resisting them
out
out of
out of fear
out of fear of
out of fear of disorientation
out of fear of disorientation because
out of fear of disorientation because I
live
live alone.
>> What's
>> What's your
>> What's your question?
>> What's your question? So
>> What's your question? So if
>> What's your question? So if you
>> What's your question? So if you have
anything
anything that
>> What's your question? So if you have
anything that you
anything that you could
>> What's your question? So if you have
anything that you could tell
anything that you could tell me
>> What's your question? So if you have
anything that you could tell me to
contextualize
contextualize this
contextualize this situation
contextualize this situation so
contextualize this situation so that
contextualize this situation so that my
devotion
devotion or
contextualize this situation so that my
devotion or that
devotion or that I
contextualize this situation so that my
devotion or that I can
devotion or that I can have
contextualize this situation so that my
devotion or that I can have a
devotion or that I can have a context
contextualize this situation so that my
devotion or that I can have a context to
carry
carry me
carry me through
carry me through that
carry me through that fear
carry me through that fear and
relinquish
relinquish the
carry me through that fear and
relinquish the I
relinquish the I suppose
carry me through that fear and
relinquish the I suppose the
relinquish the I suppose the fear
carry me through that fear and
relinquish the I suppose the fear of
relinquish the I suppose the fear of the
disorientation
>> fear
>> fear of
disorientation
>> fear of going
>> what's
>> what's the
>> what's the fear
>> what's the fear of
>> what's the fear of fear
>> what's the fear of fear of
>> what's the fear of fear of what
>> that
>> that I
>> what's the fear of fear of what
>> that I won't
>> that I won't function
>> what's the fear of fear of what
>> that I won't function well
>> that I won't function well that
>> what's the fear of fear of what
>> that I won't function well that I
>> that I won't function well that I won't
I
I live
I live alone
I live alone and
I live alone and that
I live alone and that I
I live alone and that I won't
I live alone and that I won't be
I live alone and that I won't be able
I live alone and that I won't be able to
take
take care
I live alone and that I won't be able to
take care of
take care of myself
I live alone and that I won't be able to
take care of myself and
take care of myself and function
I live alone and that I won't be able to
take care of myself and function and
>> you'll
>> you'll become
>> you'll become a
>> you'll become a babbling
>> you'll become a babbling idiot.
>> I'm
>> I'm probably
>> What's
>> What's wrong
>> What's wrong with
>> What's wrong with that?
>> I
>> I became
>> What's wrong with that?
>> I became a
>> I became a babbling
>> What's wrong with that?
>> I became a babbling idiot
>> I became a babbling idiot for
>> What's wrong with that?
>> I became a babbling idiot for a
>> I became a babbling idiot for a long
time.
time. I
time. I live
time. I live by
time. I live by myself.
>> I
>> I can't
time. I live by myself.
>> I can't um
>> I
>> I didn't
>> I didn't in
>> I didn't in the
>> I didn't in the world.
>> I didn't in the world. I
>> I didn't in the world. I didn't
>> I didn't in the world. I didn't function
in
in the
>> I didn't in the world. I didn't function
in the world.
in the world. I
>> I didn't in the world. I didn't function
in the world. I didn't
in the world. I didn't work.
>> It's
>> It's hard
>> It's hard to
>> It's hard to remember
>> It's hard to remember things.
>> It's hard to remember things. I
>> It's hard to remember things. I have
>> It's hard to remember things. I have to
put
put post-its
>> It's hard to remember things. I have to
put post-its everywhere
put post-its everywhere and
>> It's hard to remember things. I have to
put post-its everywhere and I
>> what
>> I
>> I put
>> what
>> I put postit
>> I put postit signs
>> what
>> I put postit signs all
>> I put postit signs all over
>> what
>> I put postit signs all over my
refrigerator.
refrigerator. I
refrigerator. I don't
refrigerator. I don't remember
refrigerator. I don't remember a
refrigerator. I don't remember a lot
refrigerator. I don't remember a lot of
things
things and
refrigerator. I don't remember a lot of
things and I
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. Well,
>> Oh, yeah. Well, you're
>> Oh, yeah. Well, you're you're
>> Oh, yeah. Well, you're you're you're
>> Oh, yeah. Well, you're you're you're in
that
that uh
>> Oh, yeah. Well, you're you're you're in
that uh befuddled
that uh befuddled state.
>> Oh, yeah. Well, you're you're you're in
that uh befuddled state. Just
that uh befuddled state. Just leave
>> Oh, yeah. Well, you're you're you're in
that uh befuddled state. Just leave it
alone
alone and
alone and stay
alone and stay that
alone and stay that way.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Italy
alone and stay that way.
>> Okay. Italy either
>> you
>> you just
>> you just persist
>> you just persist with
>> you just persist with a
>> you just persist with a spiritual
pathway,
pathway, spiritual
>> you just persist with a spiritual
pathway, spiritual technique.
You
You just
You just persist
and
and you
You just persist
and you go
and you go through
You just persist
and you go through periods
and you go through periods of
You just persist
and you go through periods of confusion,
periods
periods of
periods of elation,
periods of elation, periods
periods of elation, periods of
periods of elation, periods of joy,
periods
periods of
periods of elation, periods of joy,
periods of despair,
periods of despair, but
periods of elation, periods of joy,
periods of despair, but eventually
periods of despair, but eventually you
come
come out
come out of
come out of it.
come out of it. Okay,
>> that's
>> that's a
come out of it. Okay,
>> that's a promise.
>> If
>> If it
>> If it doesn't
>> If it doesn't happen,
>> If it doesn't happen, give
>> If it doesn't happen, give me
>> If it doesn't happen, give me a
>> If it doesn't happen, give me a call.
I
I will
>> from
>> from the
>> from the lunatic
>> from the lunatic asylum.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Now,
>> Now, there's
>> Now, there's the
>> Now, there's the fear
>> Now, there's the fear of
>> Now, there's the fear of abandoning
>> Now, there's the fear of abandoning uh
the
the ego's
>> Now, there's the fear of abandoning uh
the ego's linear
the ego's linear style
and
and uh
and uh entering
and uh entering the
and uh entering the world
and uh entering the world of
and uh entering the world of uh
and uh entering the world of uh I
and uh entering the world of uh I know
the
the world
and uh entering the world of uh I know
the world she's
the world she's talking
and uh entering the world of uh I know
the world she's talking about.
the world she's talking about. As
and uh entering the world of uh I know
the world she's talking about. As I
the world she's talking about. As I told
you,
you, I
you, I used
you, I used to
you, I used to try
you, I used to try to
you, I used to try to walk
you, I used to try to walk through
you, I used to try to walk through walls
for
for a
you, I used to try to walk through walls
for a while.
I
I remember
I remember trying
I remember trying to
I remember trying to walk
I remember trying to walk through
I remember trying to walk through a
I remember trying to walk through a wall
and
and I
I remember trying to walk through a wall
and I was
and I was surprised
I remember trying to walk through a wall
and I was surprised when
and I was surprised when the
I remember trying to walk through a wall
and I was surprised when the wall
and I was surprised when the wall came
up
up and
up and hit
up and hit me.
up and hit me. Smackle
up and hit me. Smackle right
up and hit me. Smackle right in
up and hit me. Smackle right in the
nose.
I
I used
I used to
I used to be
I used to be in
I used to be in my
I used to be in my atheric
I used to be in my atheric body
I used to be in my atheric body and
I used to be in my atheric body and I
just
just walk
I used to be in my atheric body and I
just walk through
just walk through walls.
>> Yes.
>> I'll
>> I'll get
>> Yes.
>> I'll get the
>> I'll get the essence.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I'm
>> Oh, I'm sorry.
I
I actually
>> Oh, I'm sorry.
I actually just
I actually just want
>> Oh, I'm sorry.
I actually just want to
I actually just want to come
>> Oh, I'm sorry.
I actually just want to come up
I actually just want to come up and
>> Oh, I'm sorry.
I actually just want to come up and just
say
say thank
say thank you.
say thank you. Um
say thank you. Um I've
say thank you. Um I've been
say thank you. Um I've been following
work
work for
say thank you. Um I've been following
work for about
work for about four
say thank you. Um I've been following
work for about four years
work for about four years now
say thank you. Um I've been following
work for about four years now and
work for about four years now and um
say thank you. Um I've been following
work for about four years now and um I
can't
can't say
can't say that
can't say that I
can't say that I really
can't say that I really know
can't say that I really know anything.
um
um you
can't say that I really know anything.
um you know
um you know just
can't say that I really know anything.
um you know just in
um you know just in in
can't say that I really know anything.
um you know just in in the
um you know just in in the process
can't say that I really know anything.
um you know just in in the process of
being
being on
being on this
being on this path
being on this path has
being on this path has been
being on this path has been a
being on this path has been a very
unique
unique unique
being on this path has been a very
unique unique trip
unique unique trip the
being on this path has been a very
unique unique trip the whole
unique unique trip the whole thing
being on this path has been a very
unique unique trip the whole thing and
um
um I
um I wouldn't
um I wouldn't trade
um I wouldn't trade it
um I wouldn't trade it for
um I wouldn't trade it for anything
um I wouldn't trade it for anything and
um
um I've
um I wouldn't trade it for anything and
um I've experienced
um I've experienced about
um I wouldn't trade it for anything and
um I've experienced about everything
um I've experienced about everything uh
more
more much
more much more
more much more than
more much more than I
more much more than I could
more much more than I could ever
more much more than I could ever imagine
but
but I
more much more than I could ever imagine
but I just
but I just want
more much more than I could ever imagine
but I just want to
but I just want to say
more much more than I could ever imagine
but I just want to say thank
but I just want to say thank you
more much more than I could ever imagine
but I just want to say thank you very
much
much um
much um for
much um for your
much um for your dedication
much um for your dedication to
much um for your dedication to the
much um for your dedication to the Lord
and
and um
much um for your dedication to the Lord
and um hallelujah
>> thank
>> thank you
ginger
ginger red
ginger red cookies
ginger red cookies if
ginger red cookies if you
ginger red cookies if you like
>> and
>> and a
ginger red cookies if you like
>> and a merry
>> and a merry Christmas
and
and you're
and you're free
and you're free to
and you're free to not
and you're free to not believe
and you're free to not believe in
Christmas
Christmas if
and you're free to not believe in
Christmas if you
Christmas if you wish.
Hello
Hello doc.
Hello doc. At
Hello doc. At the
Hello doc. At the last
Hello doc. At the last lecture,
Hello doc. At the last lecture, you
Hello doc. At the last lecture, you said
um
um that
Hello doc. At the last lecture, you said
um that you
um that you respect
uh
uh Islamic
uh Islamic radicals
uh Islamic radicals and
uh Islamic radicals and you
uh Islamic radicals and you respect
their
their beliefs
>> like
>> like I
>> like I do.
>> like I do. Uh
uh
uh yes,
>> like I do. Uh
uh yes, I
uh yes, I respect
>> like I do. Uh
uh yes, I respect it.
uh yes, I respect it. Yes.
>> like I do. Uh
uh yes, I respect it. Yes. Yes.
>> I
>> I I
>> I I was
>> I I was wondering
>> I I was wondering if
>> I I was wondering if you
>> I I was wondering if you could
>> I I was wondering if you could just
expand
expand on
>> I I was wondering if you could just
expand on that.
>> Like
>> Like I
>> Like I do
>> Like I do u
>> Like I do u komoded
>> Like I do u komoded dragon.
I
I respect
>> Like I do u komoded dragon.
I respect the
I respect the komoded
>> Like I do u komoded dragon.
I respect the komoded dragon.
I respect the komoded dragon. A
>> Like I do u komoded dragon.
I respect the komoded dragon. A fool
puts
puts his
puts his foot
puts his foot in
puts his foot in the
puts his foot in the cage
puts his foot in the cage with
puts his foot in the cage with a
puts his foot in the cage with a Komodo
dragon.
dragon. But
puts his foot in the cage with a Komodo
dragon. But I
dragon. But I respect
puts his foot in the cage with a Komodo
dragon. But I respect the
dragon. But I respect the Komodo
dragon's
dragon's integrity
dragon's integrity that
dragon's integrity that he's
dragon's integrity that he's committed
to
to his
dragon's integrity that he's committed
to his own
to his own state
dragon's integrity that he's committed
to his own state of
to his own state of being.
So
So a
So a good
So a good Islamic
will
will ask
So a good Islamic
will ask you,
will ask you, would
So a good Islamic
will ask you, would you
will ask you, would you be
So a good Islamic
will ask you, would you be willing
will ask you, would you be willing to
accept
accept Muhammad
accept Muhammad as
accept Muhammad as your
accept Muhammad as your savior
accept Muhammad as your savior as
accept Muhammad as your savior as divine
divine?
divine? If
accept Muhammad as your savior as divine
divine? If you
divine? If you say
accept Muhammad as your savior as divine
divine? If you say no,
divine? If you say no, he's
accept Muhammad as your savior as divine
divine? If you say no, he's obligated
divine? If you say no, he's obligated to
cut
cut chop
cut chop your
cut chop your head
cut chop your head off.
If
If you
cut chop your head off.
If you don't
If you don't believe
cut chop your head off.
If you don't believe that,
If you don't believe that, read
cut chop your head off.
If you don't believe that, read the
Quran.
Quran. All
Quran. All the
Quran. All the people
Quran. All the people mumble
Quran. All the people mumble lumble
about
you
you about
you about Islam.
you about Islam. You
you about Islam. You ask
you about Islam. You ask them,
you about Islam. You ask them, "Did
you about Islam. You ask them, "Did you
ever
ever read
you about Islam. You ask them, "Did you
ever read the
ever read the Quran
you about Islam. You ask them, "Did you
ever read the Quran for
ever read the Quran for Christ
you about Islam. You ask them, "Did you
ever read the Quran for Christ sake?"
You
You know,
You know, first
You know, first read
You know, first read the
You know, first read the Quran
You know, first read the Quran and
You know, first read the Quran and then
ask
ask me
You know, first read the Quran and then
ask me the
ask me the question
You know, first read the Quran and then
ask me the question because
ask me the question because they're
You know, first read the Quran and then
ask me the question because they're all
answered
answered there.
answered there. The
answered there. The Quran
answered there. The Quran includes
answered there. The Quran includes all
the
the information
answered there. The Quran includes all
the information you
the information you ever
answered there. The Quran includes all
the information you ever need
the information you ever need to
answered there. The Quran includes all
the information you ever need to know
throughout
throughout your
throughout your whole
throughout your whole life
throughout your whole life about
everything.
>> You
>> You want
>> You want me
>> You want me to
>> You want me to go
>> You want me to go read
>> You want me to go read it?
to
to know
>> You want me to go read it?
to know what
to know what you're
>> You want me to go read it?
to know what you're talking
to know what you're talking about.
Either
Either that
Either that or
Either that or don't
Either that or don't talk
Either that or don't talk about
Either that or don't talk about it.
There
There is
Either that or don't talk about it.
There is only
There is only two
Either that or don't talk about it.
There is only two people
There is only two people in
Either that or don't talk about it.
There is only two people in the
There is only two people in the world,
believers
believers and
believers and non-believers.
believers and non-believers. All
non-believers
non-believers are
believers and non-believers. All
non-believers are infidels
non-believers are infidels and
believers and non-believers. All
non-believers are infidels and all
infidels
infidels deserve
infidels deserve to
infidels deserve to be
infidels deserve to be beheaded.
>> Okay.
So
So to
So to respect
So to respect them
So to respect them means
So to respect them means to
So to respect them means to be
So to respect them means to be aware
So to respect them means to be aware of
what
what they
So to respect them means to be aware of
what they are.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, that
>> Yes, that you
>> Yes, that you got
>> Yes, that you got it.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. to
>> Yes, that you got it.
>> Okay. to not
>> Okay. to not pretend,
>> Yes, that you got it.
>> Okay. to not pretend, you
>> Okay. to not pretend, you know,
>> Yes, that you got it.
>> Okay. to not pretend, you know, with
>> Okay. to not pretend, you know, with the
wishy-washy
wishy-washy relativism.
wishy-washy relativism. Oh,
wishy-washy relativism. Oh, we
wishy-washy relativism. Oh, we should
wishy-washy relativism. Oh, we should be
nice
nice to
wishy-washy relativism. Oh, we should be
nice to them
nice to them and
wishy-washy relativism. Oh, we should be
nice to them and they'll
nice to them and they'll be
wishy-washy relativism. Oh, we should be
nice to them and they'll be nice
nice to them and they'll be nice to
wishy-washy relativism. Oh, we should be
nice to them and they'll be nice to us.
>> You
>> You be
>> You be nice
>> You be nice to
>> You be nice to the
>> You be nice to the Komodo
>> You be nice to the Komodo dragon
>> You be nice to the Komodo dragon and
>> You be nice to the Komodo dragon and the
Komodo
Komodo dragon
>> You be nice to the Komodo dragon and the
Komodo dragon will
Komodo dragon will be
>> You be nice to the Komodo dragon and the
Komodo dragon will be nice
Komodo dragon will be nice to
>> You be nice to the Komodo dragon and the
Komodo dragon will be nice to you.
No,
you
you have
No,
you have to
you have to understand
No,
you have to understand what
you have to understand what a
No,
you have to understand what a thing
you have to understand what a thing is,
what
what a
what a thing
what a thing is
what a thing is and
what a thing is and not
what a thing is and not pretend
what a thing is and not pretend that
what a thing is and not pretend that it
is
is something
what a thing is and not pretend that it
is something that
is something that it
what a thing is and not pretend that it
is something that it is
is something that it is not.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Thank
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> It
>> It doesn't
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> It doesn't mean
>> It doesn't mean to
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> It doesn't mean to make
>> It doesn't mean to make them
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> It doesn't mean to make them wrong
>> It doesn't mean to make them wrong for
it.
it. I
it. I don't
it. I don't make
it. I don't make a
it. I don't make a komodo
it. I don't make a komodo dragon
it. I don't make a komodo dragon wrong.
I
I don't
it. I don't make a komodo dragon wrong.
I don't see
I don't see it
it. I don't make a komodo dragon wrong.
I don't see it as
I don't see it as evil.
it. I don't make a komodo dragon wrong.
I don't see it as evil. I
I don't see it as evil. I just
it. I don't make a komodo dragon wrong.
I don't see it as evil. I just see
I don't see it as evil. I just see it
it. I don't make a komodo dragon wrong.
I don't see it as evil. I just see it as
something
something you
something you don't
something you don't want
something you don't want to
something you don't want to put
something you don't want to put your
hand
hand in
something you don't want to put your
hand in the
hand in the cage.
Yeah.
So,
So, the
Yeah.
So, the people
So, the people are
Yeah.
So, the people are carrying
So, the people are carrying on,
Yeah.
So, the people are carrying on, you
know,
know, what
know, what they
know, what they believe
know, what they believe to
know, what they believe to be
know, what they believe to be the
highest
highest good.
It's
It's very
It's very narcissistic
It's very narcissistic in
It's very narcissistic in my
It's very narcissistic in my personal
view
view of
It's very narcissistic in my personal
view of it.
view of it. you
It's very narcissistic in my personal
view of it. you know
view of it. you know that
It's very narcissistic in my personal
view of it. you know that you
view of it. you know that you kill
It's very narcissistic in my personal
view of it. you know that you kill 30
children
children in
children in a
children in a bus
children in a bus so
children in a bus so that
children in a bus so that you
children in a bus so that you get
children in a bus so that you get to
children in a bus so that you get to go
to
to heaven,
but
but that
but that belief
but that belief system
but that belief system thinks
but that belief system thinks that's
possible.
Blow
Blow up
Blow up 30
Blow up 30 innocent
Blow up 30 innocent children
and
and then
Blow up 30 innocent children
and then you
and then you will
Blow up 30 innocent children
and then you will go
and then you will go to
Blow up 30 innocent children
and then you will go to heaven.
That
That seems
That seems like
That seems like a
That seems like a very
That seems like a very strange
That seems like a very strange belief
system.
Uh
Uh but
Uh but it's
Uh but it's probably
Uh but it's probably logical
Uh but it's probably logical in
Uh but it's probably logical in the
Uh but it's probably logical in the year
700.
It's
It's not
It's not logical
It's not logical now
It's not logical now because
It's not logical now because we
It's not logical now because we expect
that
truth
truth and
truth and logic
truth and logic reason
truth and logic reason upholds
truth and logic reason upholds faith
truth and logic reason upholds faith and
and
and reason
truth and logic reason upholds faith and
and reason will
and reason will uphold
truth and logic reason upholds faith and
and reason will uphold each
and reason will uphold each other.
truth and logic reason upholds faith and
and reason will uphold each other. We
don't
don't expect
don't expect them
don't expect them to
don't expect them to be
don't expect them to be at
don't expect them to be at variance.
don't expect them to be at variance. to
say.
Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Yes,
>> Dr.
>> Dr. Hawkins.
Yes,
>> Dr. Hawkins. It
>> Dr. Hawkins. It seems
Yes,
>> Dr. Hawkins. It seems that
>> Dr. Hawkins. It seems that uh
Yes,
>> Dr. Hawkins. It seems that uh healing
takes
takes place
takes place from
takes place from karmic
takes place from karmic propensities
takes place from karmic propensities or
from
from internal
takes place from karmic propensities or
from internal spiritual
from internal spiritual work.
takes place from karmic propensities or
from internal spiritual work. Uh
from internal spiritual work. Uh so
takes place from karmic propensities or
from internal spiritual work. Uh so how
does
does health
does health care
does health care bring
does health care bring about
does health care bring about healing
does health care bring about healing and
evolution
evolution and
does health care bring about healing and
evolution and consciousness?
>> What
>> What is
>> What is the
>> What is the question?
>> Um
everything
everything is
everything is mental,
everything is mental, spiritual
everything is mental, spiritual and
>> physical.
>> physical. Yes.
>> So
>> So what's
>> So what's the
>> So what's the question?
>> So
>> So how
>> So what's the question?
>> So how does
>> So how does health
>> So what's the question?
>> So how does health care
>> So how does health care bring
>> So what's the question?
>> So how does health care bring about
healing
healing and
healing and evolution
healing and evolution of
healing and evolution of consciousness?
>> What
>> how
>> how does
>> how does healthc
>> how does healthc care
>> how does healthc care bring
>> how does healthc care bring about
healing
in
in the
in the evolution
in the evolution of
in the evolution of consciousness?
>> It's
>> It's the
in the evolution of consciousness?
>> It's the other
>> It's the other way
in the evolution of consciousness?
>> It's the other way around.
>> It's the other way around. You
in the evolution of consciousness?
>> It's the other way around. You know
>> It's the other way around. You know the
healing
healing is
healing is physical,
healing is physical, mental
healing is physical, mental is
spiritual.
You
You address
You address it
You address it on
You address it on all
You address it on all levels
simultaneously.
It's
It's a
It's a mental
It's a mental belief
It's a mental belief system.
It's a mental belief system. It's
It's a mental belief system. It's a
physical
physical manifestation
and
and it
and it also
and it also it's
and it also it's a
and it also it's a reflection
and it also it's a reflection of
and it also it's a reflection of a
spiritual
uh
uh level
uh level of
uh level of consciousness.
uh level of consciousness. So
uh level of consciousness. So you
uh level of consciousness. So you work
on
on it
uh level of consciousness. So you work
on it all
on it all three
uh level of consciousness. So you work
on it all three ways.
on it all three ways. You
uh level of consciousness. So you work
on it all three ways. You take
on it all three ways. You take uh
uh level of consciousness. So you work
on it all three ways. You take uh you
know
know aspirin
know aspirin to
know aspirin to relieve
know aspirin to relieve uh
know aspirin to relieve uh which
know aspirin to relieve uh which have
what
what do
know aspirin to relieve uh which have
what do they
what do they call
know aspirin to relieve uh which have
what do they call I
what do they call I think
know aspirin to relieve uh which have
what do they call I think rotator
what do they call I think rotator cuff
ibuprofen
ibuprofen for
ibuprofen for the
ibuprofen for the rotator
ibuprofen for the rotator cuff.
ibuprofen for the rotator cuff. You
ibuprofen for the rotator cuff. You also
see
see the
ibuprofen for the rotator cuff. You also
see the acupuncturist.
You
You also
You also meditate
You also meditate on
You also meditate on what
could
could have
You also meditate on what
could have been
could have been involving
You also meditate on what
could have been involving the
could have been involving the left
shoulder
shoulder that
shoulder that produced
shoulder that produced some
shoulder that produced some negative
karma
karma and
shoulder that produced some negative
karma and you
karma and you ask
shoulder that produced some negative
karma and you ask God's
karma and you ask God's help
shoulder that produced some negative
karma and you ask God's help with
karma and you ask God's help with the
matter.
matter. So,
matter. So, you're
matter. So, you're working
matter. So, you're working on
matter. So, you're working on it
matter. So, you're working on it in
matter. So, you're working on it in all
three
three levels.
In
In the
In the meantime,
In the meantime, you
In the meantime, you get
In the meantime, you get Dr.
In the meantime, you get Dr. French's
bone
bone and
In the meantime, you get Dr. French's
bone and joint
bone and joint spray.
Dr.
Dr. French's
Dr. French's bone
Dr. French's bone and
Dr. French's bone and joint
Dr. French's bone and joint homeopathic
spray.
spray. I
Dr. French's bone and joint homeopathic
spray. I saw
spray. I saw it
Dr. French's bone and joint homeopathic
spray. I saw it on
spray. I saw it on the
Dr. French's bone and joint homeopathic
spray. I saw it on the TV
spray. I saw it on the TV one
Dr. French's bone and joint homeopathic
spray. I saw it on the TV one day
spray. I saw it on the TV one day and
Dr. French's bone and joint homeopathic
spray. I saw it on the TV one day and um
his
his sincerity
his sincerity sort
his sincerity sort of
his sincerity sort of grabbed
his sincerity sort of grabbed me.
his sincerity sort of grabbed me. I
mean,
mean, this
his sincerity sort of grabbed me. I
mean, this guy
mean, this guy gets
his sincerity sort of grabbed me. I
mean, this guy gets up
mean, this guy gets up there
his sincerity sort of grabbed me. I
mean, this guy gets up there and
mean, this guy gets up there and tells
you
you absolutely
you absolutely it
you absolutely it works.
you absolutely it works. I
you absolutely it works. I thought,
unless
unless he's
you absolutely it works. I thought,
unless he's a
unless he's a complete
you absolutely it works. I thought,
unless he's a complete liar.
unless he's a complete liar. So,
you absolutely it works. I thought,
unless he's a complete liar. So, we
unless he's a complete liar. So, we got
no
no he's
no he's not
no he's not lying.
no he's not lying. So,
no he's not lying. So, well,
no he's not lying. So, well, well,
animal
animal bone
no he's not lying. So, well, well,
animal bone and
animal bone and cartilage,
no he's not lying. So, well, well,
animal bone and cartilage, you
animal bone and cartilage, you know,
you're
you're talking
you're talking about
you're talking about the
you're talking about the mamalian
species.
species. So,
you're talking about the mamalian
species. So, if
species. So, if it
you're talking about the mamalian
species. So, if it works
species. So, if it works on
you're talking about the mamalian
species. So, if it works on dogs,
species. So, if it works on dogs, it
would
would work
would work on
would work on me.
would work on me. So,
would work on me. So, I
would work on me. So, I asked
would work on me. So, I asked the
would work on me. So, I asked the arm,
if
if it
would work on me. So, I asked the arm,
if it works
if it works on
would work on me. So, I asked the arm,
if it works on dogs,
if it works on dogs, would
would work on me. So, I asked the arm,
if it works on dogs, would it
if it works on dogs, would it work
would work on me. So, I asked the arm,
if it works on dogs, would it work on
me?
me? Okay.
me? Okay. So,
me? Okay. So, Dr.
me? Okay. So, Dr. French's
me? Okay. So, Dr. French's bone
me? Okay. So, Dr. French's bone and
joint
joint homeopathic
me? Okay. So, Dr. French's bone and
joint homeopathic remedy
joint homeopathic remedy is
me? Okay. So, Dr. French's bone and
joint homeopathic remedy is helpful
joint homeopathic remedy is helpful to
me.
me. Resist
wolf
wolf woof
me. Resist
wolf woof woof
wolf woof woof woof.
So,
So, no
So, no sooner
So, no sooner did
So, no sooner did we
So, no sooner did we find
So, no sooner did we find out
So, no sooner did we find out that
So, no sooner did we find out that it
was
was helpful
So, no sooner did we find out that it
was helpful and
was helpful and I
So, no sooner did we find out that it
was helpful and I sent
was helpful and I sent away
So, no sooner did we find out that it
was helpful and I sent away for
was helpful and I sent away for some.
So, no sooner did we find out that it
was helpful and I sent away for some. I
immediately
immediately started
immediately started to
immediately started to take
immediately started to take it
immediately started to take it and
immediately started to take it and all
of a
of a sudden
immediately started to take it and all
of a sudden Dr.
of a sudden Dr. French's
immediately started to take it and all
of a sudden Dr. French's homeopathic
bone
bone and
bone and joint
bone and joint medicine
bone and joint medicine for
bone and joint medicine for humans
bone and joint medicine for humans came
out
out on
bone and joint medicine for humans came
out on the
out on the TV.
But
But I
But I was
But I was already
But I was already taking
But I was already taking it.
But I was already taking it. So
But I was already taking it. So the
But I was already taking it. So the kind
I
I have
But I was already taking it. So the kind
I have at
I have at home
But I was already taking it. So the kind
I have at home is
I have at home is her
But I was already taking it. So the kind
I have at home is her animals.
>> But
>> But it
>> But it certainly
>> But it certainly works.
>> But it certainly works. You
>> But it certainly works. You see
>> But it certainly works. You see that
works
works very
>> But it certainly works. You see that
works very well
>> without
>> without Dr.
>> without Dr. French's
>> without Dr. French's bone
>> without Dr. French's bone and
>> without Dr. French's bone and joint.
>> So
>> So that's
>> without Dr. French's bone and joint.
>> So that's what
>> So that's what I
>> without Dr. French's bone and joint.
>> So that's what I mean
>> So that's what I mean by
>> without Dr. French's bone and joint.
>> So that's what I mean by using
>> So that's what I mean by using all
modalities.
modalities. Common
modalities. Common sense,
modalities. Common sense, exercise,
acupuncture,
acupuncture, meditation,
modalities. Common sense, exercise,
acupuncture, meditation, healings,
acupuncture, meditation, healings, going
to
to church.
You
You get
to church.
You get bad
You get bad enough
to church.
You get bad enough you
You get bad enough you go
to church.
You get bad enough you go to
You get bad enough you go to church.
to church.
You get bad enough you go to church. You
know
know what I'm
know what I'm saying?
Thank
Thank you.
I
I just
I just want
I just want to
I just want to know
I just want to know if
I just want to know if there's
I just want to know if there's a
distinction
distinction between
I just want to know if there's a
distinction between the
distinction between the human
I just want to know if there's a
distinction between the human ego
distinction between the human ego and
the
the spiritual
the spiritual ego.
the spiritual ego. And
the spiritual ego. And if
the spiritual ego. And if there
the spiritual ego. And if there is,
the spiritual ego. And if there is, what
is
is it
the spiritual ego. And if there is, what
is it that
is it that holds
the spiritual ego. And if there is, what
is it that holds the
is it that holds the spiritual
the spiritual ego. And if there is, what
is it that holds the spiritual ego
is it that holds the spiritual ego in
the spiritual ego. And if there is, what
is it that holds the spiritual ego in in
place?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well,
place?
>> Yeah. Well, the
>> Yeah. Well, the human
place?
>> Yeah. Well, the human e
>> Yeah. Well, the human e Oh,
place?
>> Yeah. Well, the human e Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah. Well, the human e Oh, yeah. Is
place?
>> Yeah. Well, the human e Oh, yeah. Is you
want
want to
want to translate
want to translate that?
What's
What's the
want to translate that?
What's the difference
What's the difference between
want to translate that?
What's the difference between the
What's the difference between the human
ego
ego and
ego and the
ego and the spiritual
ego and the spiritual ego?
The
The spiritual
ego and the spiritual ego?
The spiritual ego
The spiritual ego usually
ego and the spiritual ego?
The spiritual ego usually means
The spiritual ego usually means that
ego and the spiritual ego?
The spiritual ego usually means that the
uh
uh in
uh in ego
uh in ego inflation
is
is moved
uh in ego inflation
is moved from
is moved from the
uh in ego inflation
is moved from the self
is moved from the self to
uh in ego inflation
is moved from the self to one's
spiritual
spiritual level
spiritual level of
spiritual level of of
spiritual level of of progress
that
that um
spiritual level of of progress
that um one
that um one is
spiritual level of of progress
that um one is more
that um one is more enlightened
spiritual level of of progress
that um one is more enlightened than
other
other people.
other people. more
other people. more enlightened
other people. more enlightened than
other
other people
other people. more enlightened than
other people and
other people and uh
other people. more enlightened than
other people and uh that
other people and uh that they
other people. more enlightened than
other people and uh that they therefore
speak
speak from
speak from a
speak from a different
sense
sense of
speak from a different
sense of importance.
So
So the
So the ego
So the ego inflation
So the ego inflation then
So the ego inflation then moves
So the ego inflation then moves to
So the ego inflation then moves to the
uh
uh level
So the ego inflation then moves to the
uh level of
uh level of spiritual
So the ego inflation then moves to the
uh level of spiritual education
uh level of spiritual education and
arudition.
arudition. Yes.
Now
Now they're
arudition. Yes.
Now they're not
Now they're not uh
self-important
self-important because
self-important because of
self-important because of money
self-important because of money or
wealth
wealth or
self-important because of money or
wealth or good
wealth or good looks
self-important because of money or
wealth or good looks or
wealth or good looks or something.
self-important because of money or
wealth or good looks or something. Now
they're
they're self-important
they're self-important because
uh
uh they're
they're self-important because
uh they're spiritually
uh they're spiritually educated
they're self-important because
uh they're spiritually educated or
uh they're spiritually educated or have
a
a big
a big name,
a big name, you
a big name, you know.
>> And
>> And make
statements
statements to
statements to the
statements to the press.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
You
You notice
You notice the
You notice the Buddha
You notice the Buddha says
You notice the Buddha says uh
You notice the Buddha says uh so
You notice the Buddha says uh so I
You notice the Buddha says uh so I have
heard.
heard. He
You notice the Buddha says uh so I have
heard. He does
heard. He does not
You notice the Buddha says uh so I have
heard. He does not say
heard. He does not say I
You notice the Buddha says uh so I have
heard. He does not say I know.
So
So I
So I have
So I have heard.
>> Yeah.
Uh
Uh about
Uh about last
Uh about last Sunday
Uh about last Sunday I
Uh about last Sunday I happened
Uh about last Sunday I happened to
Uh about last Sunday I happened to come
to
to Arizona
Uh about last Sunday I happened to come
to Arizona for
to Arizona for this
Uh about last Sunday I happened to come
to Arizona for this and
to Arizona for this and spend
Uh about last Sunday I happened to come
to Arizona for this and spend the
to Arizona for this and spend the week
down
down here.
down here. But
down here. But uh
down here. But uh I
down here. But uh I met
down here. But uh I met a
down here. But uh I met a a
down here. But uh I met a a gentleman
down here. But uh I met a a gentleman at
the
the Unity
down here. But uh I met a a gentleman at
the Unity Church
the Unity Church that
down here. But uh I met a a gentleman at
the Unity Church that I
the Unity Church that I just
down here. But uh I met a a gentleman at
the Unity Church that I just found
the Unity Church that I just found on
the
the internet
and
and he
the internet
and he showed
and he showed me
the internet
and he showed me an
and he showed me an invention
the internet
and he showed me an invention that
could
could uh
could uh produce
could uh produce a
could uh produce a real
could uh produce a real cheap
could uh produce a real cheap energy
could uh produce a real cheap energy and
offered
offered to
could uh produce a real cheap energy and
offered to let
offered to let me
could uh produce a real cheap energy and
offered to let me be
offered to let me be a
could uh produce a real cheap energy and
offered to let me be a part
offered to let me be a part of
could uh produce a real cheap energy and
offered to let me be a part of helping
to
to get
to get that
to get that out
to get that out into
to get that out into humanity.
to get that out into humanity. And
to get that out into humanity. And I'm
just
just wondering
to get that out into humanity. And I'm
just wondering if
just wondering if it's
to get that out into humanity. And I'm
just wondering if it's something
just wondering if it's something that
to get that out into humanity. And I'm
just wondering if it's something that I
should
should do
should do or
should do or if
should do or if it's
should do or if it's the
should do or if it's the right
should do or if it's the right thing
should do or if it's the right thing to
do
do or
should do or if it's the right thing to
do or not.
The
The answer
The answer is
The answer is no.
The answer is no. Resist.
>> Don't
>> Don't do
The answer is no. Resist.
>> Don't do it.
>> Everybody's
>> Everybody's brother
>> Everybody's brother comes
>> Everybody's brother comes to
>> Everybody's brother comes to the
>> Everybody's brother comes to the door
with
with a
>> Everybody's brother comes to the door
with a new
with a new machine
>> Everybody's brother comes to the door
with a new machine or
with a new machine or technique
>> Everybody's brother comes to the door
with a new machine or technique or
invention
invention to
invention to create
invention to create cheap
invention to create cheap energy.
If
If you
invention to create cheap energy.
If you want
If you want cheap
invention to create cheap energy.
If you want cheap energy,
If you want cheap energy, go
invention to create cheap energy.
If you want cheap energy, go sit
If you want cheap energy, go sit in
invention to create cheap energy.
If you want cheap energy, go sit in the
sun.
>> Creative
>> Creative inventive
sun.
>> Creative inventive schemes
>> Creative inventive schemes to
sun.
>> Creative inventive schemes to create
uh
uh free
uh free energy.
uh free energy. I
uh free energy. I mean
uh free energy. I mean there
uh free energy. I mean there everybody's
inventiveness
inventiveness is
uh free energy. I mean there everybody's
inventiveness is trying
inventiveness is trying to
uh free energy. I mean there everybody's
inventiveness is trying to figure
inventiveness is trying to figure out
uh free energy. I mean there everybody's
inventiveness is trying to figure out a
way.
way. So
it's
it's to
way. So
it's to be
it's to be understood
way. So
it's to be understood that
it's to be understood that that
way. So
it's to be understood that that it's
it's to be understood that that it's a
great
great need
great need and
great need and therefore
great need and therefore many
great need and therefore many human
minds
minds are
great need and therefore many human
minds are putting
minds are putting themselves
great need and therefore many human
minds are putting themselves to
minds are putting themselves to the
task.
Yeah.
Um
Um in
Um in in
Um in in in
Um in in in your
Um in in in your lecture
Um in in in your lecture you
Um in in in your lecture you once
Um in in in your lecture you once me
once
once you
Um in in in your lecture you once me
once you said
once you said that
Um in in in your lecture you once me
once you said that all
once you said that all fear
Um in in in your lecture you once me
once you said that all fear is
once you said that all fear is illusion.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. And
>> Yes. And when
>> Yes. And when you
>> Yes. And when you said
>> Yes. And when you said that,
>> Yes. And when you said that, what
>> Yes. And when you said that, what sort
of
of fear
>> Yes. And when you said that, what sort
of fear are
of fear are you
>> Yes. And when you said that, what sort
of fear are you referring
of fear are you referring to?
>> Yes. And when you said that, what sort
of fear are you referring to? And
of fear are you referring to? And he
>> Yes. And when you said that, what sort
of fear are you referring to? And he is
uh
uh obviously
uh obviously uh
uh obviously uh feeling
uh obviously uh feeling some
uh obviously uh feeling some fear.
uh obviously uh feeling some fear. So
uh obviously uh feeling some fear. So he
wants
wants to
uh obviously uh feeling some fear. So he
wants to go
wants to go straight.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And you're
>> Yes.
>> And you're asking
>> And you're asking for
>> Yes.
>> And you're asking for your
>> And you're asking for your advice.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. See,
>> Yeah. See, caution
>> Yeah. See, caution is
>> Yeah. See, caution is based
>> Yeah. See, caution is based on
>> Yeah. See, caution is based on a
reality,
not
not to
not to put
not to put your
not to put your foot
not to put your foot in
not to put your foot in the
not to put your foot in the p
not to put your foot in the p cage
not to put your foot in the p cage with
the
the Komodo
not to put your foot in the p cage with
the Komodo dragon.
But
But you're
But you're not
But you're not doing
But you're not doing that
But you're not doing that out
But you're not doing that out of
But you're not doing that out of fear.
You're
You're doing
But you're not doing that out of fear.
You're doing that
You're doing that out
But you're not doing that out of fear.
You're doing that out of
You're doing that out of your
But you're not doing that out of fear.
You're doing that out of your awareness
and
and respect
and respect for
and respect for reality.
Just
Just like
and respect for reality.
Just like when
Just like when you
and respect for reality.
Just like when you drive
Just like when you drive the
and respect for reality.
Just like when you drive the car,
Just like when you drive the car, you
don't
don't close
don't close your
don't close your eyes
don't close your eyes at
don't close your eyes at 60
don't close your eyes at 60 miles
don't close your eyes at 60 miles an
hour
hour down
don't close your eyes at 60 miles an
hour down the
hour down the highway.
don't close your eyes at 60 miles an
hour down the highway. So
hour down the highway. So that's
don't close your eyes at 60 miles an
hour down the highway. So that's respect
for
for the
for the linear
for the linear realities
for the linear realities of
for the linear realities of this
for the linear realities of this world.
The
The fears
for the linear realities of this world.
The fears that
The fears that we're
for the linear realities of this world.
The fears that we're talking
The fears that we're talking about
for the linear realities of this world.
The fears that we're talking about are
fears
fears of
fears of the
fears of the unknown
and
and other
fears of the unknown
and other other
and other other fears
fears of the unknown
and other other fears that
and other other fears that are
fears of the unknown
and other other fears that are not,
and other other fears that are not, you
know,
know, respect
know, respect for
know, respect for uh
know, respect for uh physical
know, respect for uh physical realities.
Okay.
So
So it
So it isn't
So it isn't out
So it isn't out of
So it isn't out of fear
So it isn't out of fear that
So it isn't out of fear that you
So it isn't out of fear that you don't
drive
drive 60
So it isn't out of fear that you don't
drive 60 miles
drive 60 miles an
So it isn't out of fear that you don't
drive 60 miles an hour
drive 60 miles an hour with
So it isn't out of fear that you don't
drive 60 miles an hour with your
drive 60 miles an hour with your eyes
closed.
closed. It's
closed. It's out
closed. It's out of
closed. It's out of respect
closed. It's out of respect for
closed. It's out of respect for the
physical
physical reality
closed. It's out of respect for the
physical reality of
physical reality of the
closed. It's out of respect for the
physical reality of the world,
physical reality of the world, but
closed. It's out of respect for the
physical reality of the world, but not
fear.
And
>> and
>> and the
>> and the fear
>> and the fear that
>> and the fear that you
>> and the fear that you are
>> and the fear that you are referring
>> and the fear that you are referring to.
Can
Can you
>> and the fear that you are referring to.
Can you say
Can you say more
>> and the fear that you are referring to.
Can you say more on
Can you say more on the
>> and the fear that you are referring to.
Can you say more on the fear?
>> The
>> The it
>> The it isn't
>> The it isn't the
>> The it isn't the fear.
>> The it isn't the fear. It's
>> The it isn't the fear. It's the
>> The it isn't the fear. It's the respect
for
for the
>> The it isn't the fear. It's the respect
for the reality.
for the reality. So
>> The it isn't the fear. It's the respect
for the reality. So fear
for the reality. So fear alone
>> The it isn't the fear. It's the respect
for the reality. So fear alone won't
keep
keep you
keep you alive
keep you alive in
keep you alive in this
keep you alive in this world.
Fear
Fear won't
keep you alive in this world.
Fear won't keep
Fear won't keep you
keep you alive in this world.
Fear won't keep you alive.
Fear
Fear won't
Fear won't keep
Fear won't keep you
Fear won't keep you alive.
Fear won't keep you alive. Respect
Fear won't keep you alive. Respect for
reality
reality is
Fear won't keep you alive. Respect for
reality is what
reality is what keeps
Fear won't keep you alive. Respect for
reality is what keeps you
reality is what keeps you alive.
So
So a
So a fear
So a fear is
So a fear is a
So a fear is a poor
So a fear is a poor substitute
So a fear is a poor substitute for
So a fear is a poor substitute for a
sense
sense of
So a fear is a poor substitute for a
sense of reality.
So
So when
So when people
So when people drink
So when people drink too
So when people drink too much,
they
they lose
So when people drink too much,
they lose their
they lose their sense
So when people drink too much,
they lose their sense of
they lose their sense of reality
So when people drink too much,
they lose their sense of reality and
turn
turn their
turn their automobiles
turn their automobiles over
turn their automobiles over on
turn their automobiles over on the
highway.
And
And they're
And they're probably
And they're probably fearless
And they're probably fearless when
And they're probably fearless when they
do
do that.
So
So fear
So fear is
So fear is a
So fear is a respect
So fear is a respect for
So fear is a respect for reality,
So fear is a respect for reality, cause
and
and effect
So fear is a respect for reality, cause
and effect in
and effect in the
So fear is a respect for reality, cause
and effect in the linear
and effect in the linear domain.
Yes.
Thank
Thank you
Yes.
Thank you very
Thank you very much.
Thank
Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Many
>> Many of
>> Many of your
>> Many of your students
>> Many of your students are
>> Many of your students are also
practicing
practicing the
>> Many of your students are also
practicing the course
practicing the course in
>> Many of your students are also
practicing the course in miracles.
>> Yes.
Do
Do we
>> Yes.
Do we need
Do we need to
>> Yes.
Do we need to have
Do we need to have any
>> Yes.
Do we need to have any concern
Do we need to have any concern that
>> Yes.
Do we need to have any concern that the
course
course in
course in miracles
course in miracles at
course in miracles at 600
course in miracles at 600 in
course in miracles at 600 in any
course in miracles at 600 in any way
dilutes
dilutes your
course in miracles at 600 in any way
dilutes your teachings
dilutes your teachings on
course in miracles at 600 in any way
dilutes your teachings on enlightenment
at
at a
at a thousand?
>> No.
>> And
>> And is
>> And is there
>> And is there a
>> And is there a preferred
>> And is there a preferred way
>> And is there a preferred way to
>> And is there a preferred way to blend
the
the two?
>> Well,
>> Well, you
>> Well, you would
>> Well, you would have
>> Well, you would have to
>> Well, you would have to do
>> Well, you would have to do it
>> Well, you would have to do it in
>> Well, you would have to do it in a
>> Well, you would have to do it in a way
that
that makes
>> Well, you would have to do it in a way
that makes sense
that makes sense to
>> Well, you would have to do it in a way
that makes sense to you.
>> Read
>> Read the
>> Read the books,
>> Read the books, practice
>> Read the books, practice the
>> Read the books, practice the course,
>> Read the books, practice the course, and
don't
don't worry
>> Read the books, practice the course, and
don't worry about
don't worry about it.
>> There
>> There you
>> There you go.
>> There you go. Thank
>> There you go. Thank you.
and
and and
>> There you go. Thank you.
and and do
and and do the
>> There you go. Thank you.
and and do the 12
and and do the 12 steps
>> There you go. Thank you.
and and do the 12 steps in
and and do the 12 steps in the
>> There you go. Thank you.
and and do the 12 steps in the meantime.
>> What
>> What happens
>> What happens now,
>> What happens now, honey?
>> We're
>> We're going
>> What happens now, honey?
>> We're going to
>> We're going to do
>> What happens now, honey?
>> We're going to do our
>> We're going to do our goodbye.
>> Oh
>> Oh my
>> Oh my god.
>> Oh my god. Okay.
So,
So, now
>> Oh my god. Okay.
So, now we
So, now we will
>> Oh my god. Okay.
So, now we will close
So, now we will close the
>> Oh my god. Okay.
So, now we will close the meeting
So, now we will close the meeting and
>> Oh my god. Okay.
So, now we will close the meeting and I
>> I
>> I will
>> I will walk
>> I will walk out
>> I will walk out in
>> I will walk out in front.
Yeah.
And
And we
And we have
And we have the
And we have the music
And we have the music to
And we have the music to help
And we have the music to help us
And we have the music to help us close.
Yes,
Yes, I
And we have the music to help us close.
Yes, I think
Yes, I think we
And we have the music to help us close.
Yes, I think we help.
Yes, I think we help. That
And we have the music to help us close.
Yes, I think we help. That helps
Yes, I think we help. That helps us
close.
Who's
Who's this?
close.
Who's this? Santa
Who's this? Santa Claus.
>> Dr.
>> Oh
>> Oh my
>> Dr.
>> Oh my god.
>> Oh my god. Isn't
>> Dr.
>> Oh my god. Isn't that
>> Oh my god. Isn't that something?
You
You are
You are you
You are you are
You are you are God's
You are you are God's gift
You are you are God's gift to
You are you are God's gift to me
for
for which
You are you are God's gift to me
for which I
for which I give
You are you are God's gift to me
for which I give thanks.
I
I give
I give thanks
I give thanks for
I give thanks for all
I give thanks for all all
I give thanks for all all who
I give thanks for all all who are
present
because
by
by commitment
because
by commitment to
by commitment to the
because
by commitment to the truth
we
we are
we are together
forever.
That's
That's a
That's a fact.
That's a fact. Resist.
By
By virtue
That's a fact. Resist.
By virtue of
By virtue of our
That's a fact. Resist.
By virtue of our commitment,
we
we are
we are karmically
we are karmically aligned.
Those
Those who
we are karmically aligned.
Those who are
Those who are destined
we are karmically aligned.
Those who are destined to
Those who are destined to become
enlightened.
So
So in
enlightened.
So in this
So in this room
are
are the
are the future
are the future spiritual
are the future spiritual teachers
of
of generations
are the future spiritual teachers
of generations to
of generations to come.
are the future spiritual teachers
of generations to come. Generations
of generations to come. Generations to
come.
My
My teacher
come.
My teacher was
My teacher was five
come.
My teacher was five or
My teacher was five or six
come.
My teacher was five or six lifetimes
My teacher was five or six lifetimes ago
and
and I
and I just
and I just got
and I just got around
and I just got around to
and I just got around to it
and I just got around to it now.
What
What I
and I just got around to it now.
What I said
What I said is
and I just got around to it now.
What I said is true.
Within
Within this
Within this room
Within this room are
Within this room are the
Within this room are the great
Within this room are the great teachers
of
of the
Within this room are the great teachers
of the future.
of the future. Resist.
Within
Within this
Within this realm
Within this realm are
Within this realm are great
Within this realm are great teachers
Within this realm are great teachers of
spiritual
spiritual truth
Within this realm are great teachers of
spiritual truth of
spiritual truth of the
Within this realm are great teachers of
spiritual truth of the future.
Some
Some even
Some even at
Some even at the
Some even at the present
Some even at the present already
perhaps.
What
What a
What a divine
What a divine blessing.
What a divine blessing. What
What a divine blessing. What more
What a divine blessing. What more could
one
one ask
What a divine blessing. What more could
one ask from
one ask from God?
Money
Money comes
Money comes and
Money comes and goes.
Money comes and goes. Good
Money comes and goes. Good lucks
Money comes and goes. Good lucks come
and
and go.
Strength
Strength comes
Strength comes and
Strength comes and goes.
Money
Money comes
Strength comes and goes.
Money comes and
Money comes and goes.
Spiritual
Spiritual truth
Spiritual truth is
Spiritual truth is eternal.
And
And the
Spiritual truth is eternal.
And the destiny
of
of having
of having been
of having been a
of having been a human
is
is eternal
of having been a human
is eternal salvation.
Eternal.
So
So our
Eternal.
So our destiny
So our destiny is
Eternal.
So our destiny is eternal.
The
The idea
The idea that
The idea that we're
The idea that we're separate
dissolves
dissolves as
The idea that we're separate
dissolves as an
dissolves as an illusion.
We're
We're not
We're not separate.
We're
We're all
We're not separate.
We're all one.
Speaking
Speaking through
Speaking through a
Speaking through a variety
Speaking through a variety of
Speaking through a variety of bodies.
There
There is
Speaking through a variety of bodies.
There is only
There is only one
Speaking through a variety of bodies.
There is only one here.
There is only one here. Resist.
There
There is
There is only
There is only one
in
in this
There is only one
in this entire
in this entire room.
That's
That's the
That's the true
That's the true truth.
That's the true truth. Resist.
There's
There's only
That's the true truth. Resist.
There's only one
in
in this
in this whole
in this whole room
pervading
pervading the
in this whole room
pervading the consciousness
pervading the consciousness of
in this whole room
pervading the consciousness of all
pervading the consciousness of all of
in this whole room
pervading the consciousness of all of us
simultaneously.
Wow,
that's
that's exciting.
I
I never
that's exciting.
I never discovered
I never discovered that
that's exciting.
I never discovered that before.
I never discovered that before. Thank
you,
you, Lord.
That
That there
you, Lord.
That there is
That there is only
you, Lord.
That there is only the
That there is only the one
you, Lord.
That there is only the one and
That there is only the one and we're
you, Lord.
That there is only the one and we're it.
Resist.
We
We share
Resist.
We share in
We share in it.
Resist.
We share in it. Yes,
We share in it. Yes, we
Resist.
We share in it. Yes, we share
We share in it. Yes, we share in
Resist.
We share in it. Yes, we share in it.
Wow.
Thank
Thank God
Wow.
Thank God for
Thank God for some
Wow.
Thank God for some good
Thank God for some good karma.
Everybody
Everybody worries
Everybody worries about
Everybody worries about their
Everybody worries about their bad
Everybody worries about their bad karma.
How
How long
Everybody worries about their bad karma.
How long does
How long does it
Everybody worries about their bad karma.
How long does it take
How long does it take to
Everybody worries about their bad karma.
How long does it take to undo
How long does it take to undo bad
Everybody worries about their bad karma.
How long does it take to undo bad karma?
How
How long?
Yeah,
Yeah, I
How long?
Yeah, I thought
Yeah, I thought that
How long?
Yeah, I thought that long.
That's
That's gone.
The
The bad
That's gone.
The bad karma
The bad karma has
That's gone.
The bad karma has gone
The bad karma has gone in
That's gone.
The bad karma has gone in one
The bad karma has gone in one instant
That's gone.
The bad karma has gone in one instant by
an
an act
an act of
an act of the
an act of the will.
By
By surrendering
an act of the will.
By surrendering to
By surrendering to God,
an act of the will.
By surrendering to God, by
By surrendering to God, by saying
an act of the will.
By surrendering to God, by saying glory
to
to God
to God in
to God in the
to God in the highest,
all
all glory
to God in the highest,
all glory and
all glory and power
to God in the highest,
all glory and power is
all glory and power is thine,
to God in the highest,
all glory and power is thine, oh
all glory and power is thine, oh Lord.
In
In that
In that one
In that one act,
In that one act, you
In that one act, you undo
In that one act, you undo all
In that one act, you undo all the
ignorance
ignorance of
In that one act, you undo all the
ignorance of past
ignorance of past life.
So
So what
So what is
So what is bad
So what is bad karma?
So what is bad karma? Nothing
So what is bad karma? Nothing but
ignorance.
Jesus
Jesus Christ
Jesus Christ and
Jesus Christ and the
Jesus Christ and the Buddha,
Jesus Christ and the Buddha, they
Jesus Christ and the Buddha, they all
said
all
all that
all that the
all that the world
all that the world calls
all that the world calls negative.
Nothing
Nothing but
all that the world calls negative.
Nothing but ignorance.
Ignorance.
There
There is
Ignorance.
There is no
There is no evil.
Ignorance.
There is no evil. There's
There is no evil. There's only
ignorance.
There's
There's only
ignorance.
There's only ignorance.
To
To be
To be enlight
To be enlight means
To be enlight means to
To be enlight means to surrender
To be enlight means to surrender that
ignorance
out
out of
out of humility.
Not
Not out
out of humility.
Not out of
Not out of desperation,
out of humility.
Not out of desperation, not
Not out of desperation, not out
out of humility.
Not out of desperation, not out of
wantingness,
but
but out
wantingness,
but out of
but out of humility.
wantingness,
but out of humility. You
but out of humility. You surrender
wantingness,
but out of humility. You surrender that
ignorance.
I
I myself
ignorance.
I myself do
I myself do not
ignorance.
I myself do not know.
I myself do not know. Oh
ignorance.
I myself do not know. Oh Lord,
I
I have
I have myself
I have myself do
I have myself do not
I have myself do not know.
So
So we
I have myself do not know.
So we surrender
So we surrender our
I have myself do not know.
So we surrender our ignorance
So we surrender our ignorance and
I have myself do not know.
So we surrender our ignorance and our
limitation
limitation and
limitation and our
limitation and our not
limitation and our not knowingness
to
to God.
And
And in
And in return,
we
we become
And in return,
we become enlightened.
People
People think
People think enlightenment
People think enlightenment is
People think enlightenment is way
People think enlightenment is way in
People think enlightenment is way in the
future
future and
People think enlightenment is way in the
future and it's
future and it's way
People think enlightenment is way in the
future and it's way up
future and it's way up there.
People think enlightenment is way in the
future and it's way up there. I'll
future and it's way up there. I'll tell
you
you where
you where enlightenment
you where enlightenment is.
you where enlightenment is. It's
you where enlightenment is. It's right
here.
here. It's
you where enlightenment is. It's right
here. It's right
here. It's right now.
you where enlightenment is. It's right
here. It's right now. It's
here. It's right now. It's right
you where enlightenment is. It's right
here. It's right now. It's right here
and
and right
and right now.
and right now. This
and right now. This is
and right now. This is enlightenment.
Resist.
So
So there's
So there's no
So there's no point
So there's no point to
So there's no point to pray
So there's no point to pray about
So there's no point to pray about being
enlightened
enlightened in
So there's no point to pray about being
enlightened in the
enlightened in the future.
So there's no point to pray about being
enlightened in the future. It's
enlightened in the future. It's right
here,
here, right
here, right now
as
as you
you
you are
you are it.
So
So you
you are it.
So you share
So you share the
you are it.
So you share the joy
So you share the joy of
you are it.
So you share the joy of that
So you share the joy of that knowingness
with
with the
with the world,
but
but you
with the world,
but you don't
but you don't tell
with the world,
but you don't tell them.
We
We are
We are what
We are what the
We are what the world
We are what the world has
We are what the world has been
We are what the world has been waiting
for.
Yes,
Yes, doctor.
Put
Put him
Yes, doctor.
Put him away
Put him away again.
Yes, doctor.
Put him away again. Yeah.
All right.
All right. We
All right. We give
All right. We give thanks
All right. We give thanks that
All right. We give thanks that we
All right. We give thanks that we can
All right. We give thanks that we can be
of
of service
All right. We give thanks that we can be
of service to
of service to the
All right. We give thanks that we can be
of service to the Lord
by
by fulfilling
by fulfilling our
by fulfilling our spiritual
by fulfilling our spiritual potential
by fulfilling our spiritual potential to
the
the best
by fulfilling our spiritual potential to
the best that
the best that we
by fulfilling our spiritual potential to
the best that we can.
You
You don't
You don't have
You don't have to
You don't have to become
You don't have to become Buddha.
You don't have to become Buddha. You
don't
don't have
You don't have to become Buddha. You
don't have to
don't have to become
You don't have to become Buddha. You
don't have to become Jesus.
don't have to become Jesus. You
You don't have to become Buddha. You
don't have to become Jesus. You don't
have
have to
have to become
have to become Krishna.
You
You acknowledge
have to become Krishna.
You acknowledge their
You acknowledge their presence
have to become Krishna.
You acknowledge their presence already
within
within you.
Krishna,
Krishna, Buddha,
within you.
Krishna, Buddha, Jesus.
Jesus
Jesus Christ
Jesus Christ is
Jesus Christ is within
Jesus Christ is within all
Jesus Christ is within all of
Jesus Christ is within all of us
Jesus Christ is within all of us now.
Resist.
Resist. It's
Jesus Christ is within all of us now.
Resist. It's within
Resist. It's within all
Jesus Christ is within all of us now.
Resist. It's within all of
Resist. It's within all of us
Jesus Christ is within all of us now.
Resist. It's within all of us now.
And
And how
And how do
And how do we
And how do we acknowledge
And how do we acknowledge it?
By
By giving
And how do we acknowledge it?
By giving thanks
By giving thanks for
And how do we acknowledge it?
By giving thanks for it.
By giving thanks for it. Lord
And how do we acknowledge it?
By giving thanks for it. Lord God,
By giving thanks for it. Lord God, I
give
give thanks.
That
That divine
give thanks.
That divine presence
expressed
expressed as
expressed as all
expressed as all of
expressed as all of us
expressed as all of us here
expressed as all of us here at
expressed as all of us here at this
moment.
And
And in
And in this
And in this moment,
And in this moment, we
And in this moment, we love
And in this moment, we love each
And in this moment, we love each other
eternally.
Wow.
Why
Why is
Wow.
Why is that?
Why is that? Because
Wow.
Why is that? Because we
Why is that? Because we cannot
Wow.
Why is that? Because we cannot be
Why is that? Because we cannot be any
other
other way.
You
You can't
other way.
You can't say
You can't say I
other way.
You can't say I think
You can't say I think I
other way.
You can't say I think I love
You can't say I think I love this
other way.
You can't say I think I love this one
and
and this
and this one
and this one and
and this one and not
and this one and not this
and this one and not this one
and this one and not this one and
and this one and not this one and then
this
this one.
and this one and not this one and then
this one. You
this one. You either
and this one and not this one and then
this one. You either love
this one. You either love everybody
and this one and not this one and then
this one. You either love everybody or
you
you don't
you don't love
you don't love anybody.
Now,
Now, everyone
you don't love anybody.
Now, everyone here
Now, everyone here has
you don't love anybody.
Now, everyone here has already
moved
moved into
moved into an
moved into an incredible
moved into an incredible state
moved into an incredible state of
consciousness.
We
We serve
We serve God
We serve God by
We serve God by being
We serve God by being that
We serve God by being that which
We serve God by being that which we
We serve God by being that which we are
to
to the
We serve God by being that which we are
to the fullest
to
to love
to love everything
to love everything to
to love everything to the
to love everything to the fullest
to love everything to the fullest that
we
we can
to love everything to the fullest that
we can to
we can to see
to love everything to the fullest that
we can to see the
we can to see the intrinsic
to love everything to the fullest that
we can to see the intrinsic beauty.
Even
Even in
Even in the
Even in the Kimod
Even in the Kimod dragon,
Even in the Kimod dragon, he
Even in the Kimod dragon, he he
Even in the Kimod dragon, he he goes
Even in the Kimod dragon, he he goes the
way
way he
Even in the Kimod dragon, he he goes the
way he goes
way he goes because
Even in the Kimod dragon, he he goes the
way he goes because that's
way he goes because that's the
Even in the Kimod dragon, he he goes the
way he goes because that's the only
way he goes because that's the only way
he
he knows
he knows how
he knows how to
he knows how to be.
So
So you
he knows how to be.
So you can't
So you can't just
he knows how to be.
So you can't just restrict
So you can't just restrict it
he knows how to be.
So you can't just restrict it to
So you can't just restrict it to cute
doggies.
But
But everything
doggies.
But everything that
But everything that lives,
all
all the
all the world
all the world as
all the world as it
all the world as it is,
when
when you
all the world as it is,
when you love
when you love it
all the world as it is,
when you love it unre
when you love it unre unreservedly,
you
you realize
you realize that
you realize that creation
you realize that creation is
you realize that creation is divinity.
Creation
Creation and
you realize that creation is divinity.
Creation and divinity
Creation and divinity are
you realize that creation is divinity.
Creation and divinity are one
Creation and divinity are one in
you realize that creation is divinity.
Creation and divinity are one in the
same
same thing.
So
So you
same thing.
So you live
So you live in
same thing.
So you live in the
So you live in the presence
same thing.
So you live in the presence of
So you live in the presence of divinity.
You
You live
You live all
You live all the
You live all the time
You live all the time in
You live all the time in the
You live all the time in the presence
You live all the time in the presence of
divinity.
There's
There's no
There's no point
There's no point in
There's no point in waiting
There's no point in waiting till
There's no point in waiting till we'll
wait
wait till
There's no point in waiting till we'll
wait till after
wait till after I
There's no point in waiting till we'll
wait till after I die
wait till after I die and
There's no point in waiting till we'll
wait till after I die and then
wait till after I die and then I'll
There's no point in waiting till we'll
wait till after I die and then I'll go
to
to heaven
to heaven and
to heaven and then
to heaven and then we'll
to heaven and then we'll worship
to heaven and then we'll worship God.
If
If you
to heaven and then we'll worship God.
If you can't
If you can't worship
to heaven and then we'll worship God.
If you can't worship God
If you can't worship God here
to heaven and then we'll worship God.
If you can't worship God here and
If you can't worship God here and now,
you're
you're not
you're not going
you're not going to
you're not going to worship
you're not going to worship God
you're not going to worship God in
heaven.
heaven. You're
you're not going to worship God in
heaven. You're just
heaven. You're just going
you're not going to worship God in
heaven. You're just going to
heaven. You're just going to wander
around
around in
around in your
around in your atheric
around in your atheric body
around in your atheric body having
around in your atheric body having a
good
good time
around in your atheric body having a
good time flirting
good time flirting with
around in your atheric body having a
good time flirting with the
good time flirting with the other
bodies.
I've
I've been
bodies.
I've been in
I've been in it.
bodies.
I've been in it. I
I've been in it. I know.
No,
No, your
No, your commitment
No, your commitment here
No, your commitment here and
No, your commitment here and now
No, your commitment here and now is
No, your commitment here and now is what
will
will prevail
No, your commitment here and now is what
will prevail when
will prevail when you
No, your commitment here and now is what
will prevail when you leave
will prevail when you leave the
No, your commitment here and now is what
will prevail when you leave the body.
That
That which
That which you
That which you really
That which you really are
That which you really are then
That which you really are then prevails.
So
So our
That which you really are then prevails.
So our love
So our love for
That which you really are then prevails.
So our love for each
So our love for each other
That which you really are then prevails.
So our love for each other is
So our love for each other is eternal.
Our
Our love
Our love for
Our love for Dr.
Our love for Dr. Moon,
for
for all
Our love for Dr. Moon,
for all our
for all our visitors
Our love for Dr. Moon,
for all our visitors from
for all our visitors from Korea,
Our love for Dr. Moon,
for all our visitors from Korea, by
for all our visitors from Korea, by whom
we
we are
we are whose
we are whose presence
we are whose presence we
we are whose presence we are
we are whose presence we are blessed
this
this day
we are whose presence we are blessed
this day and
this day and for
we are whose presence we are blessed
this day and for whom
this day and for whom we
we are whose presence we are blessed
this day and for whom we give
this day and for whom we give thanks.
We
We can
We can all
We can all hum
We can all hum to
We can all hum to the
We can all hum to the music.
Hallelujah.
Yes,
Hallelu
Hallelujah.
Oh.
Okay,
Okay, that's
Oh.
Okay, that's beautiful.
And
And it's
And it's not
And it's not against
And it's not against the
And it's not against the law
And it's not against the law to
And it's not against the law to hug
And it's not against the law to hug the
person
person next
And it's not against the law to hug the
person next to
person next to you.
And it's not against the law to hug the
person next to you. God
person next to you. God bless
And it's not against the law to hug the
person next to you. God bless you
person next to you. God bless you all.
Until
Until I
Until I see
Until I see you
Until I see you next
Until I see you next time.
Until I see you next time. Amen.
>> How
>> How about
Until I see you next time. Amen.
>> How about one?
>> I
>> I know.
>> I use
>> I use the
>> I know.
>> I use the M
>> I use the M to
>> I know.
>> I use the M to get
>> I use the M to get me
>> I know.
>> I use the M to get me off
>> I use the M to get me off the
>> I know.
>> I use the M to get me off the singing
and
and then
and then I
and then I need
and then I need something
and then I need something to
and then I need something to get
and then I need something to get me
and then I need something to get me off
the
Oh,
Oh, God
Oh, God bless
Oh, God bless everyone
Oh, God bless everyone here.
Oh, God bless everyone here. Amen.
>> Yes.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu