And with that, I'd like to introduce my
hubby.
>> Well, she's raised me right. You can
tell that.
Now today we're talking about uh
today we're talking about um
practical spirituality.
So we uh how many people here are new?
How many new people?
Wave your hand. I can't see unless you
wave it. Wave. Wave.
>> Okay. So that gives me an idea how much
this time to spend on review.
I'd like to do a quick review to refresh
people's memory of what we've been
talking about for the last few years and
for new people to give them an
orientation
and uh the Sedona uh group you know is
usually people who've been here before.
So, we don't spend a lot of time on
review. Uh, but we show you where the
review is. And if you have any
questions, you can holler on when we do
the review.
If you got any kind of a question, you
could just put your hand up and holler
and and Susan will call on you.
She can see where you are. And I just
hear it. Oh.
So, just put up your hand and wave if
you got a question.
And so we're going to do a quick re
review that will take us through all the
previous lectures. We're going we're
putting out a book of uh a collection of
all the slides of all the lectures
because
uh we realized that when you play a DVD,
it doesn't, you know, it doesn't show up
with sufficient clarity because, you
know, the camera is quite away from the
screen and it's hard to read it. So this
way we have it flip over. you could flip
over and and follow what is on the
screen in the DVD.
So we'll start then with a review of a
quick review of the slides to bring us
up to date. We always start with the map
of consciousness as a common point of
reference.
Uh
as a common point of reference
uh
these are levels of consciousness. These
are emotional states.
These are attitudes all boiled into one.
And so
we see the view of yourself and how you
understand God. We should have society
in there. How you view society.
Uh
the levels are called peace, joy, go
they go go all the way down to pride and
anger and hatred and and um
disaster
today's internet.
Yeah. And the log the log of it tells us
uh the relative power because these are
exponential levels. Uh and therefore
even a rise of a few points makes a
considerable difference.
Uh
the emotion that's that's along with it.
We'll talk more about that later.
uh and you see many that predominate in
today's world. All kinds of hatred and
of course political contests such as uh
the one we're currently involved in
seems to bring out the worst in mankind,
don't doesn't it? It brings up all kinds
of trivialities that we uh make fun of
people and uh and hatred gets this is a
time for hatred. And what people forget
is that
I use the example of strawberry versus
vanilla.
See, if you pick strawberry, it doesn't
mean you have to hate vanilla. And you
can pick vanilla, you don't have to hate
strawberry. You know what I mean?
You can just pick what you pick. You
don't have to hate the other people. Is
that okay?
Yeah. But people like an excuse for
hatred, don't they? They love a hate
parade.
Protest, protest, protest. People love a
hate parade. I don't want to deprive
them of that.
Once every four years, they can hate
without feeling guilty about it. They
can feel patriotic.
Patriotic about it.
Oh god, it's hysterical. So anyway,
it'll be over before long and uh we'll
all have survived it. Every four years
we go through this. Yeah. Uh so the
slides for today then let's see we're
doing a quick review. So we do the map
of consciousness. Now the next one we do
is any questions? Any questions on any
of these slides, you just holler and put
your hand up and we will uh try to
answer it.
Those lights sort of fade out the slide.
See? So, that's one reason for putting
out the a collection of slides is
because now if you see this on a DVD, I
can hardly see it myself. How would you
read it? So, this way if we put the
slides out so you can flip over on them
at home.
uh an explanation of the world's dilemma
is shown by this graph
that 85% of the world's population
calibrates below 200.
Now we know that 200 is the level of
integrity and truth and reliability
uh and the capacity to really comprehend
truth to discern the difference between
appearance and essence.
Below 200 is falsehood and all that is
negative in life. And 200 and up is all
that is positive in life. And what's
dismaying is to notice
this is the mass of the world's
population.
85% of the world's population calibrates
below 200.
85%
cannot tell the difference between truth
and falsehood. They cannot tell the
difference. It's all the same to them.
Like a child, you say, "Here, honey.
This is arsenic and this is candy." And
take the arsenic.
Arsenic tastes sweet. Do you ever eat
any arsenic?
If you want to poison somebody, you put
it in the dessert.
If you're enemy for dinner and he eats a
dessert and he goes
goes on, you say, "It was in the
dessert.
It was in the plum pudding."
85% of the world's population
explains many phenomena
and uh instead of feeling depressed and
upset about the world's conditions in
various places. You just recall that the
majority of mankind uh is unable to
discern truth from falsehood. unable
inherently unable
just like a person with an IQ of 60 you
know can't get through postgraduate
college in the university
all right so now the next one is uh
well what is the consequence of this
consequence of this is that although the
majority of the world's population
calibrates below 200
those that calibrate above 200 which is
only 15%
of the world's population.
Their power is so enormous that they
counterbalance. So 85% of the world is
counterbalanced
by 15% of the world that is capable of
discerning truth from falsehood. And so
there are people that lead and sustain.
They sustain not by what they do
uh but by what they are.
A group like this doesn't have to do
anything. Please don't do anything to
save the world. Everybody promise me
don't do anything to save the world.
Please give me a break.
You just be what you are to the fullest
extent that you can be that. And by
doing that you're fulfilling your
destiny to the ultimate. By being what
you can be to the ultimate then which is
the subject of today's lectures to be
all that you can be to the fullest
extent is already fulfilling your
obligation and doing more than any kind
of good-hearted doingness can do for the
world.
So these this 15% merely by being what
they are next slide
by merely being what they are. You see
this 15%
outweighs this 85%.
If that were not so, mankind would have
self-destructed centuries ago.
The sheer mass of negativity would have
destroyed uh all of human life.
So the a group like this has a very
important function. And I think we've
calibrated before how many people this
group just this group sitting here
offsets
uh let's see we have permission to is
this this group offsets
uh on the negative side more than 50
million people 100 million
150 million 200 million 175 million on
hundreds of millions of people. See,
because the power goes up exponentially,
exponentially.
Uh therefore, a group like this offsets
uh the negativity l literally of
millions of people
uh just by uh what you are. All you have
to do to help the world to the greatest
extent possible is breathe in and out.
Everybody able to do that?
you back there
with your head noggin. Hey,
thank you. Keep breathing again.
Next.
All right. Evolution of consciousness.
Percent of elapsed time. Uh, this has to
be brought up to date and it's sitting
on my desk waiting for me to bring it up
to date. the percent of elapsed time
calibrated consciousness level of man of
of elapsed time. You see consciousness
is only shot up in very very recent
times uh almost like yesterday. It's
really only yesterday that we move from
the dinosaur
uh to human consciousness. All right,
the next one. Uh,
we if we align these with the earth
epics, you see the slow evolution of
consciousness over actually millions of
years, millions and millions of years,
the Cambrian period, the
Deonian period, all these fancy sounding
names. Uh
so consciousness evolved at a snail's
pace over millions of years and here we
have the various
uh forms of life that occurred at the
time. In the beginning there was only
bacteria and algae and they calibrate as
one and two. And then we see the
beginning of the fishes and the reptiles
and the evolution of consciousness up
through the mamon
and to present day. Yes. Next. Uhhuh.
And here we have the animals. You see
the animal kingdom. Uh you see the
entire thing displayed.
Uh here's the octopus. Our old friend
octopus. And the old friend Kimod
dragon.
Uh, don't go walking barefoot in his
cage, please.
Here we have the snake, the alligator,
the whale, the dolphin.
And I think it's just fascinating to
look at the animal kingdom
because we have a certain commonality
with the animal kingdom. And I always
look at all animals as friends. Even
those that are not friendly, I consider
them friends because they share they
share animal existence and animal
consciousness. And there's an intuitive
understanding that goes on. If you're
wide awake, you have an intuitive
understanding of where an animal is at.
And if that bear is dangerous, you
intuit it and you slowly say, "Bye bear.
Bye bear.
So we love the animals and part of one
of the pleasures of human life is the
loving of the animals and and everybody
who loves uh animals of course is
helping the world because love uh
uplifts mankind. And I told you I had
patients that I that lived alone and
they were so self-centered and
depressed. And I told them that I would
not treat them unless you get a canary
or a kitty or a doggy or a puppy. Uh
because if you're only concerned about
you, I can't really help you much.
The big me. That's all you're concerned
about. Me me. I mean you can't even take
care of a couple snails or goldfish. I
mean, something other than your own
wonderful, marvelous self.
Now, there are people that can't even
take care of a goldfish.
All right? So, they're stuck where
they're stuck, and there they are. And
here we see the animals that we have
learned to love and we've got to know
them. I mean, gotten to know Koko, the
trained gorilla, and uh that wonderful
gray parrot who is actually at 400 able
to comprehend
uh the parrot I have at home is what is
that one calibrated at? I forget. We
calibrated her. What's what's the what's
the little calibration of our Oh, what's
her name? The bird.
>> Broccoli. calibrates over 200, 300, 350,
340, 350.
So, we have an African gray calibrates
at 340 right now.
And you're sitting there quietly and all
of a sudden you'll hear, "What's going
on?
What's going on? What's going on? What's
going on?
What's going on? Uh it's funny. Uh so we
have u the delight the delight of the
animal kingdom. We're talking about the
delight of awareness of your own
existence.
The delight in the beauty of nature. The
delight in
just the effect of your own existence.
The delight that you share existence and
consciousness with the animal kingdom.
It's fun to walk in the woods by
yourself.
It's twice as much fun to walk in the
woods with a doggy
in that. So somebody's sharing to so to
share with another person it's more fun
or with a with a kid it's more fun even
with a doggy it's more fun or with a
horse even lead a horse along at least
there's somebody sharing the world with
you
without animals mankind would not have
existed
couldn't have survived because he didn't
have the strength to plow he needed a
horse to plow didn't have milk without
the cow didn't have wool without the
sheep.
He begins to realize he didn't have meat
without killing the deer. He didn't have
clothing without the to hide in the
pelts and he wouldn't have shoes. So
that was the world without plastic.
Um so the to delight in your own
existence means to share the awareness
of the divinity of existence itself. Uh
to exist is already it's a tremendous
miracle. So we have here the dog's
wagging tail at 500.
Somebody is studying uh a member of our
group here is studying uh the effect uh
advertising.
And so you can calibrate the power of an
advertisement.
And uh he found that if you put a little
dog in the corner of the advertisement
with a wagging tail, the power of the
advertisement like quadruples
quadruples.
So
that's the way to get friends.
is to wag your tail
and purr
and sing. Um,
all right. So, these are all
fascinating. We've fallen in love with
them and many of us follow them. Alex
the trained African gray parrot. Oscar
the cat. Oscar is the that cat that can
tell when somebody's due to die.
Remember that one?
Within 72 hours if this I think it's a
cat or was it a dog? I forget. It was
Oscar.
If you see Oscar coming to sleep with
you.
Hi Oscar.
>> All right. So we see the fascination
that man has had with his animal
friends. So we view other people as
friends. We view animals as friends. We
view all of nature as friends. And that
way that helps us to live in a positive
uh awareness of our of ourself and the
reality of our own existence. We'll go
to the next one. I forget how many we
got here. Maybe I better early on. Oh,
great books of the western world is
significant for people that are, you
know, students of consciousness. Uh
because here you find uh the answer to
what goes on with society currently
as well as for some centuries. You see
um
the
calibration of the intellectual
uh foundation of western world is in the
400s.
Great books of the western world.
This is the product of man's best
thinking over the centuries. It runs all
the way up to 480 all the way to 505.
Darwin at 450. Decart 490
angles goes down quite a bit 200.
And then there's one that calibrates the
lowest of all. Who's that one? I forget.
>> What's his first name? Marks.
>> Carl.
Carl. Marks.
That marks. Oh,
that marks at 1:30 slipped in.
And that marks is the downside
of current society in which the marxian
dialectic
has been
reframed uh verbally and now appears as
various sociologic theories uh all of
which calibrate below 200.
All right. So that we see as uh one of
the intellectual disasters of mankind,
intellectual
and that people cannot tell truth from
falsehood. And these things of course
sound seductive. Sound seductive,
you know, you have nothing to lose but
your chains. Bang a bang. And it always
makes for a great parade. A great parade
and heroes. And you get t-shirts for
this
hero freeing the oppressed.
Who are the oppressed in today's
society?
You're the oppressed.
You realize you're the oppressed.
Which way is society going?
It's going to uh
it's leaving spirituality. It's going to
secular, right? Goodbye spiritual.
Yeah. society is moving away from uh
this tradition in the back here and it's
moving more towards
atheistic
uh socialism Marx Marxism.
All right. So the fallen decline of the
western civilization which is pointed
out of course by the pope as well is due
the to leaving one field of a high
energy level and moving to a lower one
uh by popularization.
Yes. So that is what's going on you know
politically in today's world. That's all
it is. So the next one is
uh
yes the muscle test response
uh which we've spoken about and and
explained many times uh has many
explanations. A biologic one that it was
necessary for survival
for primitive organis organisms to be
able to tell that which is true and
healthy from that which is poisonous and
false.
And uh
it's moved all the way through now that
we have an explanation
uh from quantum mechanics.
The the observation which led to
calibrating the levels of consciousness
was quite simple. Quite simple. We found
that if you hold something
uh noxious next to a person's solar
plexus and press on their arm, their arm
goes weak.
If you hold something healthful,
uh, their arm goes strong.
So, you don't have to be a genius to
display that or understand it. That
which is truthful, integrous, and
pro-life,
makes you go strong. When I press down,
that which is anti-life, poisonous, will
kill you, false, deceptive, and
delusional makes your arm go weak.
It does so despite what you might think
about it. So if I put a person's name in
an envelope and I put another person's
name in another envelope, now I don't
tell the person. I say
it's a blind test. What's in this
envelope is the name of somebody who
calibrates over 200. Their arm goes
really weak. Then I take the other
envelope. I say the name of this person
calibrates over 200. they go strong and
I open it up and the one that made him
go weak, which we've done many times, is
Karl Marx. Just the name alone puts you
down
and Jesus Christ puts you up. You know,
it's a very simple test.
You have to have an IQ over at least 40
or 50 to get it.
Anybody doesn't get it.
People who have an invested interest in
falsehood uh get very upset with this
test and have done everything they can
to discredit it and vilify it and you
know say that it's all trickery and
stage magic and all that. But we've done
it many, many times, many audiences over
decades. And the results are always the
same. If I hold Abraham Lincoln in my
mind and I say, "What am I holding in
mind?" She goes, "Strong."
If I hold Adolf Hitler in my mind and I
say, "What I'm holding in mind
calibrates over 200, she goes weak."
Now, I didn't tell her what I'm holding
in mind. How would she know? I'm not
going to tell her because she might
cheat on me. Cheat.
No, I wouldn't trust it just because of
the sheer suggestion of it. So if what I
hold in mind is over 200, I say to her,
what I'm holding in mind is over 200 and
I get a yes or a no. We've done this
probably close to 10,000 times.
We've done it over 8,000 times. Let's
see.
We've We've done it over 8,000 times.
7500 7,500
7,000 times. All right. We've done it
over 7,000 times.
Well, you have to you have to get some
sleep in, do you?
Anyway, we do it whenever. So, we find
it very pragmatically useful. Very
pragmatically useful. All right. So
we've explained the uh collapse of the
wave function and advanced theoretical
physics and the book mindful universe uh
by Henry Stap professor of physics at
Berkeley uh gives a rational
explanation. It's not necessary to know
any of this. Therefore, forget it. Go to
the next slide.
All right, just take my word for it.
uh physi there's a physiologic basis
which is very important also you see not
85% of the population cannot tell truth
and falsehood and one of the reasons is
has to do with cerebral dominance has to
do with whether you process things uh
consciousness level below 200 or above
200 processes things differently in the
brain. One reason people at this level
can't comprehend this level is because
you have to use this side of the brain.
This side side of the brain
has a very positive effect, positive
emotions and releases of importantly
endorphins. The endorphins are uh
peaceful, harmonious, pleasant. And one
of the benefits of spa spiritual
endeavor is that you shift more and more
over to the endorphins which are
releasing uh hormones which do play
their part in altering how you see and
experience the world. It's hard for a
person dominated by the left brain to
see the world as friendly.
And for a person dominated by the right
brain, it seems rather simple.
to a rightbrain person they say well you
walk around Sedona it's lovely and
weather is great here and mountains are
gorgeous and I mean what more do you
want
a person very far in the lift brain says
it's too hot around here and they charge
too much and
and the restaurants all rip you off
they're all there's no parking place I
mean you know you see a negative view of
the world versus a positive view of the
world it's all the same world so it's
just perception we'll go on to the next
One,
the correlation of levels of
consciousness with social problems is of
considerable sociologic
uh uh import uh politically unpopular
too and and because
the the cause the cause of things the
conditions that precipitate them uh
people have a political position about
uh they think that
thing these consequences are caused from
without instead of from within. Instead
of from within, we see that the pro the
incidence of problems of all kinds from
poverty to crime
to the suicide rate, the homicide rate,
the rate of imprisons.
The higher the level of consciousness,
uh the rate of employ of unemployment is
zero. Uh the rate of poverty is zero,
happiness is 100%. and the rate of
criminality is zero.
So people are are spiritually highly
motivated and caring and care about
their fellow fellow human beings care
about life in general have a positive
uplifting viewpoint.
Therefore the level of consciousness the
higher it goes the rate of unemployment
drops eventually uh to zero and poverty
unhappiness disappears.
So what we have then we're left with
people who are extremely low level of
consciousness for reasons that are
karmic, biologic, sociological as well.
And you reach
people where the rate of unemployment is
as close to 100%, the rate of poverty is
100%.
Rate of happiness is 0%. And criminality
is common.
the current economic crisis was due due
to
trusting that people would have
uh this kind of a reliability.
If the government guarantees their
mortgages, anybody and everybody could
have one. So all the people from here
flew into the mortgages. They instantly
stopped paying them. They stopped
cleaning out the attic. They stopped
sweeping the sidewalk and the thing went
into poverty collapse.
that because there is no reliability
here. You see this and it's not uh for
any other reason other than the level of
consciousness itself. The level of
consciousness in a high level of
consciousness you make sure that
everything gets paid, taken care of,
cleaned up, tidied up that the screens
are put on in the summer and the storms
are put on in the winter. It seems
obvious, but their whole populations
where it does does not even occur. And
uh I used to own some rental properties
back east and I had some of those people
living there.
I didn't discover it until delayed.
Anyway, I had rented this lovely gate
house, you know, an English tutor, slate
roof, all brick, gorgeous place for a
pittance. And um this guy was living
there and I noticed the garbage never
seemed to go out. See? So, one day I
went by to see how he was doing and I
just knocked on the door and he was
sitting at the kitchen table and all
over the kitchen table was marijuana and
he was
I said, "How are things going, Pete?"
Oh, okay.
Where does all the garbage go that
should be out by the side of the house?
He said, "Uh, well, I don't know. Maybe
over there." So, I went and opened the
door. That was the door to the basement.
The entire basement was filled a fill
halfway up the stairway with trash. What
he did with trash, old grapefruit rind
and garbage and all is he just opened
the door of the basement and threw it
down there and he closed the door.
He got a mortgage, of course.
Well, people want an explanation of what
is the current economic situation.
That's all it is. It's missing that the
level of consciousness is going to uh
tell you how reliable
uh a a a contract is. Uh people here pay
great deal of attention to contracts.
They say, you know, that's a contract.
We agreed to that. And people here say,
uh, oh, that's a contract.
Oh, well, wipe your feet on it. So, all
right, we'll move to the next
the rate of happiness. And here we have
correlation of levels of consciousness
and rate of happiness. And here you see
the log of the level of consciousness
and the rate of happiness.
So spiritual endeavor tends to, you
know, pull you higher and higher on this
uh map and you reach a level where your
only complaint is you're never unhappy
and you got nothing to complain about.
I haven't got anything to complain
about.
How can people control you if you got
nothing to complain about? because what
they do is they pick on your complaints
and play them up and uh and make
political hay out of it. All right? So,
the rate of happiness goes up based not
on externals, how much money you have,
whether you went to college, any of
those things. It's based solely on one's
level of consciousness. So it seemed to
me the most efficient way to improve
your life overall is to pursue advancing
your level of consciousness because you
increase your rate of happiness, you
increase your productivity and uh it's
beneficial to yourself and everybody
around you including the world. Yes.
Next slide. I don't know where we are on
the slides.
Here we have a quick review of spiritual
teachers. People often write me from all
over the world and want to know about a
certain spiritual teacher and I tell
them how to find out what that teacher
calibrates at themselves. And I also
point out
that here's over a hundred spiritual
teachers. They're all calibrated. And
next we'll have the writings of these
teachers are calibrated
and somehow they always find somebody
in the middle of nowhere honky donker
who claims to be the descendant of the
master of wahi
and suggested we turn over all our
material goods to him
and would you advise our following him
and I say Well, I've already done enough
and I we we've told you how to do it. Uh
what's the next slide?
Yeah, these are the great avatars of all
time and the Christian apostles at 980.
Uh this has to do with the relics of the
J the relics uh calibrated 900. We know
that the bones underneath the basilica
in Rome calibrate over 900. It just
affirms uh affirms
uh the spiritual level of the 12
apostles
and uh
John the Baptist, Moses, Abraham, St.
Paul, Muhammad and Muhammad after age
later age. Let's go to the next one.
Uh great spiritual writings.
Uh so when people are lost or confused,
I say, "Look here, here you've got a
hundred teachers and well over a hundred
books and uh any one of these will take
you a lifetime to really work it
through."
Anyone said, "This will take care of the
next 40 or 50 lifetimes.
When you come back, work on this one.
And then when you come back again, can
work on this one. And when you get to
the bottom here, you don't have to come
back anymore.
When you finish the Zohar, that
catapults you right off the planet,
shot out into infinite space by the
Zohar, which calibrates at 95
>> 05. Yep. I see some people start with
this one.
Some people start there. You can start
anywhere. All right. So the I think this
is a very handy reference because this
kind of diagnostic work has never been
done before. So the value of the work is
that we were able to learn things that
mankind has never had a chance to
verify. It's always been the authority
of religion,
the authority of the good book, the
authority of the Torah, the Bible.
So
belief then was based on
authoritarianism.
That led to many people becoming
atheists
because the authority the institutions
themselves made serious errors over the
centuries and consequently just one
error and a doubter can say well any
organization that does so and so can't
know the truth about anything. Well,
they might know the truth about 98% of
the things and not know the truth about
2%.
So, this is very practical, very
practical. And you see a major division
even in the calibration of the Christian
Bible, whether it's the Lumpsa Bible or
the King James version. The difference
between the King's James version and the
Lumpsa Bible is considerable.
I don't know where the LASA Bible is on
there. I can't see it. But anyway, the
lumps of Bible is in the 600s, I think.
Can you see it? 300.
The King James version calibrates in the
high 400s. 475.
Oh, here's the lava right here. Right in
front of my eyeballs. No one aren't
going to see it. Calibrates at 700. Is
that correct? What is it? I I can't read
it.
>> Oh, yeah. It depends on whether you know
you leave it depends on whether you
leave the New Testament in or not. Yes.
In any case, the lamb of Bible
calibrates higher than the King James
version. Uh so even if one says it's in
the New Testament, uh you need to know
whose translation.
Uh because the lamso is from the Aramaic
and the other B and the more common one
is from the Greek.
So
the translation from the Greek
calibrates less than the one from uh the
Eastern so-called Eastern manuscripts of
the Eastern Church. Okay. So we'll go to
the next one.
Uh fashionable philosophies.
Uh
this has to do with moral equivalency
and
uh all kinds of uh all kinds of things
that we see flash across the television
uh screen. Uh all kinds of bizarre
things. Free speech of course which is
now be supplanted God and divinity on
the church. Free speech
a at the time of World War II calibrated
at 255.
Free speech in the US as of currently is
180. So free speech then due to the
media
is now focused on uh popularization and
appeal and dramatization rather than
truth. Yes. Free speech then is the real
road. It was theoretically the royal
road to freedom but in practice is the
royal road to the collapse of our own
society.
If falsehood has equal privilege with
truth, then what would hold up uh the
columns of our society?
So the New York Times for instance, New
York Times, I hate to even calibrate
where the New York Times is right now. I
better not calibrate the New York Times
because they'll have a editorial.
>> Huh?
>> Well, they vary. Anyway, right now the
New York Times is probably Let's just do
it one more time. We have permission. We
have permission to do the New York
Times. We have permission to do the New
York Times.
It calibrates currently over 170,
165,
160.
The New York Times calibrates at 160.
What does that say about the prognosis
of American society?
The banking system collapses. The New
York Times calibrates at 160.
Are we seeing the fall and collapse of
Western civilization? Is that what's h
going on?
When I grew up, the New York Times
probably calibrated around 400.
When I grew up,
when I was growing up, the New York
Times calibrated over 400. This 405
New York Times calibrated at 400 when I
was growing up. Now calibrates at what
did we say?
God, we don't want the comedies to hear
about that, do we?
The New York Times calibrates at 160.
So, I guess we are seeing the fallen
decline of Western civilization. Let's
ask that.
We have permission to ask about it. We
are seeing the progression of the fallen
decline of Western civilization. Resist.
No, we are not seeing the fallen decline
of Western civilization. We're only
seeing a bump. Oh, we're only seeing a
bump.
Oh boy.
Just a jiggle in
a jiggle in evolutionary time.
one of those.
Okay, let's go on to the next.
>> Of course, we all know what this is.
>> Yeah, there's the New York Times.
That's a marvelous I just love that.
That's the one of my favorite slides. Uh
because you know it's like everyday
television. You hear the the you know
somebody's spending 150 million a week
on TV advertising a week.
150 million a week.
And therefore there you have the sheep's
clothing. Okay. So, next
uh
Oh,
I don't think that's supposed to be in
there. Where are the isms?
No.
Oh, I see. You were going backwards.
Where are the isms?
Um, yes. what we just talked about all
these isms that fade across the screen
and become uh uh elitist and uh it's the
current fad and populism.
Uh so populism has replaced truth if a
thing is a populace. So, when you see a
political rally, you know, 10,000 people
cheering, you think it's a high school
uh basketball game. Sounds like a
college soccer game. And these are
people trying to decide on who to look
for the president of the United the
United States.
And they've turned it into a kids soccer
game. Pooping and hollering and shouting
and playing with banners. That's uh fun.
It's fun. And of course it is fun
and that's all it is. But I do you think
that
the fa fate of the banking system I
really don't want the fate of the
banking system up to a cheering cheer
squad
all in favor of
so we have the collapse of the economy
right now worldwide.
All right. So let's go to the next world
the isms spiritual practices and daily
life.
Is that what we're talking about today?
Yes. Spiritual practices and daily life.
All right.
I still can't see where the fiddly darn
here. Which one are we on here, honey?
Here. What are we on?
>> 95.
>> 95. Oh, okay. Good.
All right. Thank you. 95.
spiritual practices that are suitable
for daily life. They merge right in with
the lecture for today which has to do
with practical spirituality. These are
the many many things that you can do.
Education is the one we all pursue out
of education. We always end up favoring
a teacher or a certain teachers or group
of teachers and we tend to become
aligned with that particular pathway
and uh
we make meditation and prayer part of
our daily routine. Is everybody here
well everybody here pray every morning?
Does everybody pray every night?
Does everybody pray morning and night?
Anybody pray all day long?
All right. So, we know that
it requires attention. It it requires
avoiding be the distractions of the
world. So the distraction the biggest
enemy of uh the essence of goodness is
not evil. The biggest enemy is the
distractions of the world.
Yeah. The reason you don't do many of
these things is you're too busy.
It's not that there's evil demons out
there trying to steal your soul.
That's a relief to know, isn't it?
No, it's just that uh human life has
become so busy. The demands for our
attention are so constant and so
cleverly done. So cleverly done. The
media is so good at distracting us and
attracting us and seducing us and
getting our attention that, you know,
you don't want to go back to prayer
until you finish this movie on TV. And
by that time, you're too sleepy, you
figure, I'll pray tomorrow.
You can always do a quick prayer.
I want you to go, "Thank you, God, for
everything." Amen.
Let's do that. Thank you, God, for
everything. Amen.
>> Okay, so we did our praying for today.
Thank God.
Thanks, God. Thanks for everything.
Amen. Thank you, God, for everything.
Well, that's all that you really have to
do, isn't it? Say,
you know, if you say to a waitress,
"Gee, thanks a lot. You did a great
job." She goes, "Oh,
she's happy. You don't have to have a
parade. You don't have to build the
castles to God. You could just say,
"Dear God, I give thanks." So
thankfulness is one of the most
powerful. Giving thanks uh one day at a
time. Living one day at a time, living
in the moment and giving thanks uh
through prayer, through acknowledgement.
So we acknowledge that the source of our
life is divinity. We acknowledge that it
its divinity is the energy of life
itself and we we empower a thing when we
acknowledge it.
The way to empower anything in your life
is to merely acknowledge it and that
instantly empowers it. So whatever you
want to empower in your life, you
acknowledge and you acknowledge the gift
of it
to do all these positive things. you
then come up on the willingness to
surrender the negatives. People delight
in hatred and uh hateful comments and
the the current political news is full
of hatefulness.
Uh and people get a lot of mileage out
But spiritually oriented people don't
need hatefulness.
As you said, you can pick vanilla. You
don't have to hate chocolate because you
picked vanilla. You don't have to hate
strawberry because you picked lemonade.
You don't have to hate the opposite. You
just pick what you want and ignore the
other. Just pick what you want and
ignore the other. You don't have to hate
the opposite because people seem to feel
you have to. You can't just cheer for
your team. You've got to cheer against
the other team.
You know, the plunkers have come to town
to play the boopers. And when the
plumpers come on, you got to go boo.
And when the plinkers go on, you go.
So to elevate life to something beyond a
high school basketball game is the whole
point of spiritual reality.
To see it as something a little bit more
than a than a high school basketball
game where you have to jeer the other
side. You know, you don't have to jer
vanilla cuz you choose chocolate. You
can just choose chocolate because you
like chocolate.
That's what he said, wasn't it? You just
choose chocolate because you like
chocolate. You never know what kind of
you're going to get, right? Who is that
said that
>> Forest Forest Gump?
>> That's it.
>> Forest Gump is one of my heroes. And uh
uh Forest Gump uh to me is a is a a
great enlightened being. Let's see. Uh
Forest Gump.
>> Forest Gump calibrates over 450,
480,
500, 510. I knew Car Forest Gump
calibrates at 500.
Do you recognize why Forest Gump is at
500?
I decided to run because I thought
that's what would feel good and that it
would be a nice thing to do.
The sheer simplicity of absolute truth
said what he forest gone ran for three
years
and everywhere he ran around the country
people started to follow him. Pretty
soon there's a whole train of people
running after Forest Gum.
Well, there's a guy current politics,
Joe the plumber or something. He's sort
of like poor Gump.
The way to solve things is to be more
responsible and solve them. You know,
people say, "Man, what political genius
this guy is.
Probably shouldn't close Congress right
in the middle of a crisis. go a vacation
for six weeks. That's right. I don't
think I'd do that.
Joe's gonna be a great American hero.
That's for sure. Great American hero.
The stock market collapsing, the world
collapsing. And and Joe said, "Well, I
just wouldn't do that. Just wouldn't
make much sense."
>> Hopkins.
>> Yes.
I never did that. I don't know if I have
permission to do it. I know his cal I
mean I don't think I have permission to
do that but I just intuit it that he
calibrates quite high as a person. Yeah.
Yeah. Tom Hanks calibrated quite high as
a person resist. I don't want to say a
number because
uh but he himself got very quiet quite
apparently
certainly was a genius in detecting that
certain energy and then radiating that
the simplicity and honesty of it you
know it's almost like an animal
simplicity that smells good so I think
I'll eat that and that smells bad so I
don't think I'll eat
Man, you got to be a goddamn genius. You
got to be prankly.
You got to be a Buddha.
Killers are bad people. Oh, they are.
Oh,
I thought they were misled.
Well, they're misled to badness. Okay.
Anyway, I think that you know it's such
a beautiful uh beautiful movie and we're
wa we're watching it again reviewing it
because there was so much to learn from
it
and it presents uh many uh it's really
uh existentialism. What is the meaning
and significance of human existence is
really what the core of that movie is
about. what's what is the what is the
reality
and the meaning and the significance of
human existence is what that movie is
all about and uh I think it's a
stunningly spiritual
very high calibration kind of movie and
it's after you watch it you're sort of
spill bomb for quite a while existential
questions you know the value and
significance of human life and what
things make it valuable.
And if you just run when you feel like
running, is that what life's all about?
Yes, it is.
You want to run for president. You just
run for president because you feel like
running for president.
All right. So that's beautiful spiritual
practice in daily life. So the
willingness to to let go of the negative
and the human ego loves to juice the
negative. It loves to juice hatred.
Can't wait to stab somebody. Can't wait
to punish them. Get revenge.
And therefore, the negative is in
competition all the time with the
spiritual.
So, we're willing to surrender all the
negatives and we look at the gift of
life itself. We looked at the gift of
life itself. And so, we're getting
closer to what our lecture is about
today. That's enough review. We'll move
on to the next one. Then we'll have
reviewed the mole. What number is this
one?
>> 96.
>> Huh?
>> I can't read it all. What does that say?
Where's 96? There.
>> Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
>> Oh, there we are. Thank you very much.
We're almost to where we're going. Well,
if we keep going in the direction we're
going, we're going to end up where we're
headed for.
Choose holy company.
Practice Socrates view. See others as
programmed. All right. So here's what we
do. We become loving towards all of
life, grateful for all that we have and
benevolent. So benevolence is an
attitude in which we are gracious
towards all of life in all of its
creation. It benevolence then is a way
of looking at the world. One can also be
benevolent towards oneself. To be
benevolent towards oneself
to be merciful towards oneself. People
are safer to be with who are merciful
towards themsel
because vicious people what they do is
they project it outward onto you. You
see? So unless a person is kind to
themsself, learns how to be kind to
themsel, they're not really safe to be
with because that can turn on you any
second. So we want to teach people to be
easygoing with themsself, to be
accepting of your own limitations
without going into guilt and
self-hatred,
without becoming self-punitive,
to be kindly towards oneself. You can't
be kindly towards others if you're not
kindly toward yourself. You can go
through the gestures of it, but you're
not really being it. So being it means
that which you would wish for others uh
you now wish and employ towards
yourself.
You talked about being kind and
understanding and helpful to others. Now
now what's important is that you be that
way to to you. Is everyone here kind and
loving and benevolent towards themsel?
Are we
anybody hate yourself?
Boo. I hate anybody who hates himself.
We have to kill anybody who hates
himself. We don't want any. All right.
So being benevolent and compassionate
towards all of life and all of its
expressions
to be compassionate towards all of life
and all of its expressions including its
expression as you
then is the very heart and source of a
spiritual area edition see which does
not require any book. It merely realizes
the kindness towards yourself and
towards others is what uplifts mankind
because as you what the way you uplift
mankind. People say what can I do to
help mankind? What you can do is to be
the highest highest being you can be to
be as kind and considerate towards all
of life and all of its expressions.
You see the beauty of all exists. Some
things have to be displayed like these
flowers.
So stunning, so stunning before you
finally see it. But then after a while,
you see it in every every living thing.
You see it in every tree. And I think
we've asked this question before. Let's
ask I'll see if I have this question. I
have permission to ask this question.
Resist.
Every living thing is aware of the
divinity of your existence as you walk
by. resist. Every living thing, every
tree,
all the grass,
all living things are aware that you
have walked by.
Wow.
Therefore, just to be
and to be in who what you are uplifts
the world.
You don't have to run out there and sign
up for pledges for things. You just be
what you are to the fullest capacity.
Appreciate with with joy your own
existence, your own creation. We thank
thee, oh Lord, for our existence.
We thank you for our creation.
By being thankful for our own creation,
we bless all of creation.
Amen.
So, we'll stop there for now and then
we'll take a break. And when do we
resume?
>> 11:30.
>> Huh?