We say Gloria and Excelsius Dio.
All praise be to thee, O Lord.
Amen.
I asked the Lord if I should give this lecture today
and the arm said yes.
So here I am.
All right.
So we're going to cover uh basic things
and uh we're going to cover them a little differently.
Uh I want things to be uh so familiar
that you know it just due to familiarity.
You don't have to think.
You don't have to memorize anything.
You don't have to learn anything.
And uh the best teacher is familiarity.
Uh everything just becomes second nature
and you don't have to think about it.
Where's our slides for today?
Oh my god.
There we go.
All right.
So, boy, these are clearer here.
This is wonderful.
uh some places you can't see what the slide is
that you're talking about.
Anyway, we're putting together uh all the slides.
I think there's 139 of them already.
All the lecture slides,
we're going to put them together
and make them available in spiral bound
or some kind of printed form because they say
that that when you play the DVD at home,
you you know it's not clear
because the camera doesn't pick up sufficient detail.
So we decided we would make all the uh all of these
available uh to the public.
All right.
So going back to the basics,
the basic understanding comes from the nature of
consciousness itself.
Uh so in consciousness then all things are known.
All things are knowable.
Within consciousness all things are are known.
Everything can be defined.
The reason this is so is because everything that exists
or ever existed gives off an energy field.
Everything that ever existed
or is now existent gives off a specific energy.
Unique, unique, and trackable through all of time.
And this reason for this is has to do with the nature of
the infinite field of consciousness itself
which is poorly un understood even by organizations
that devote themselves to the study of consciousness
and then never mention mention consciousness again
which is just as well bec
because not one of them address consciousness at all.
they all address there's going to be a big conference in
London $40 million or something
and uh consciousness will never really be defined
accurately uh because what goes on in these conferences
has to do with mind.
So the failure to differentiate mind
which is content from consciousness
which is context a con for the failure of anything all
these attempts at science and consciousness
and theology and all don't make progress.
The infinite field of consciousness then includes all
that has ever been is or could be.
Everything leads a trackable track within the infinite
field of consciousness which itself is timeless
and non-local.
Within the field of consciousness then all time is now
and everywhere is here.
Everywhere is right here into my fingertip.
Anything anywhere in the universe can be calibrated.
Why is that?
Because the tip of my finger is everywhere.
There is no beginning, no end.
And the thing that people have difficulty with is
that consciousness is nonlinear.
It does not traverse time.
It doesn't go from here to there.
It doesn't start there or end here.
It's everywhere present.
Now what Cleopatra thought did what she calibrated at is
as knowable now as it was at the time of Cleopatra
because between then
and now there is no time in a nonlinear universe beyond
time or dimension.
All places are here.
All time is now.
Is that simple enough?
Everybody got that?
Everywhere is right here and all time is right now
because otherwise having distance
and time would be linear.
Linear consciousness is nonlinear.
So consciousness is the infinite context.
Yeah, that's simple.
Everybody knows that here.
Everybody already knows that here.
Yes.
We don't have to spend $40 million to find that out.
They let me speak today without wearing a red power tie.
I hope you noticed that.
I had to pass security clearance.
Said, "You don't have a red tie.
" I said, "All right.
I forgot my power tie, honey.
Well, now what am I going to do?
Well,
I will trap the trust in the infinite power of almighty
God.
Oh, that'll do.
Everything is what it is as a consequence of of
that which it is, not how it's defined or perceived,
but by virtue of its essence,
everything radiates an energy field.
This energy field radiates itself invisibly.
It does not radiate itself across space or time.
So the things I'm going to ask during the lecture,
the answers already exist prior to my asking the question.
Is that simple?
With no linear time, there's no before or after,
no sequence.
All of that is a mentalization.
What is sequent sequential is your mentalization about
phenomena.
The phenomena themselves are not sequential.
What's sequential is your witnessing of them.
And because you witness them in a sequential nature,
you think that that's the way the world is sequential.
Yeah.
Sequential is only how we process it.
Everything that ever existed exists now
and it exists right here.
That means then that anything I hold in mind,
anything I hold in mind, if it's true, has a match.
If I hold the statement in mind
that matches what exists in reality,
then her arm goes strong.
If what I'm holding in mind does not match what exists in
reality within consciousness itself, her arm goes weak.
And in previous lectures,
we've tried to outline how this came about uh over the
evolution of life on this planet
that it was necessary for life to survive to be able to
differentiate that which is pro-life or true
and that which is anti-life or poisonous
because the little amoeba doesn't know poison from food.
So he had to learn
and so the mind developed uh as a consequence of having
to discern that which is pro-life and that
which is anti-life and the failure to do that means
that that life form would expire.
That life form would expire and um so we're hoping
that mankind will learn the same thing as protozoa
and that's why we give these lectures.
" The amiebas made it and bacteria made it.
Therefore, man can make it, too.
So,
they only had to put up with what's negative in nature.
And we have to put up with what what is negative
that man can create that nature didn't even think of.
You know what I'm saying?
All right.
So the uh that we stratified the levels of consciousness
as a result of our earliest research back in the 70s
when we noticed that some things made people go strong
and some people things made people go weak.
And what what evolved was a stratified uh calibrated
level of consciousness
that goes from 1 to a thousand
where where one is merely existence
and 1,000 is the highest energy
that exists in this pl in this plane.
The entities that calibrated a thousand are all the great
spiritual teachers of time.
the avatars, Jesus Christ, the Buddha,
all the great avatars,
then calibrate at the maximum level possible within the
human domain.
Then your energies go beyond that.
Then you have to go to other dimensions.
You can't uh this world is not made to handle calibrated
energies over a thousand.
Uh then we move move on to the other uh realms move move
on to the other uh realms which calibrate thou 1,000
and even higher uh to the super realms.
Anyway,
the map of consciousness allows us then to define
anything in a term
that we can translate into a calibratable scale
which is pragmatically useful.
So it's one thing to know it and intuitit it
and confirm it with the arm
and then it's another thing to describe
that fact to somebody else.
" It just glowed with a certain radiance, you know.
So, that dog is a 255.
255.
So, we did the arm on it.
You can, you know,
the three of us what we'd be like in a dog pound.
Susan.
Susan, we should take Kelsey home with us.
Resist.
Yep.
So, we took Kelsey home with us.
And as usual, the arm was right at 255,
which exceeds about 3/4 of the human population.
Doug is friendly, kind response to affection,
is family oriented,
and values love and the good things in life.
And that sets she's not out to kill anybody
or convert anybody.
She doesn't drive on the highway.
So anyway, so what did 255 tell us?
Well,
we knew that we knew that on our scale of consciousness,
dogs dog was about 250 and a family dog was about 255.
a family dog, a dog that's been around humans,
becomes even more conscious,
becomes aware of human uh signals,
and becomes very smart indeed.
Uh so anyway,
I just thought I'd tell you
that for what reason I don't remember anymore.
Oh, yes.
Yeah,
they the family dog calibrates higher than some of the
people who've run for president in past elections.
They were at 190.
Our current election, we're pretty pretty lucky.
Everybody's over everybody's over 200.
Thank God.
All right.
So,
we found that the map of consciousness was uh extremely
useful, pragmatically so.
And uh that anything in the universe
that is ever anything that's ever existed uh
or could exist can be calibrated.
Th this cor corresponded with my training in
psychoanalysis and psychiatry
because Columbia University psychoanalytic clinic called
everything below 200 the emergency emotions
and everything from 200 and up uh the welfare emotions.
The welfare emotions produce positive uh responses in the
neurologic system
and the negative ones bring about bring on pathologic
changes.
So the view of God
which you see we put God over here on the left.
He said he wanted to be on the left.
I said you want to be on the right left.
He said put me on the left.
So this is people's view of God.
Uh and quite a you see how it divides mankind.
Is God vicious and demands
that you rip the beating heart of a virgin uh out of her
out and throw her body down the stairs?
Ancient Mayan Incan religions somehow they always go for
young virgins.
Whatever the sacrifice is got to be young virgins.
You think some of those religions would run out of young
virgins because they tore all their hearts out there.
We run out of young virgins here.
Why does it always have to be a young virgin?
You know, not a macho guy.
They don't tear out the heart of a macho guy.
It's always a harmless little maiden.
Age 14.
Oh my god.
Uh to the view view then of God.
Is God uh uh vengeful, vindictive, punitive,
uh uh vengeful, vindictive, punitive, condemning?
And so we run into what are classically the anthrop
anthropomorphic depictions of God in which God is blamed.
We say how did God get such a negative uh view?
You know people fear God.
God causes catastrophes and disasters and floods
and how does uh this all come about?
It all came about
because primitive man needed an explanation for the
phenomena of nature and blamed it on God.
The gods must be angry.
The thunder, the earthquake, the lightning.
They assumed that it was the angry gods.
So the anthropomorphic depictions of divinity
which still exist
and carry great weight in the minds of many people.
And they expect in fact
that this god is going to wipe us all out of here in 2012
or something.
What do we got to be off this planet?
2012.
We all have to be off this planet by 2012.
December 21st,
2012 when the great God of the Incas
and you know is going to wipe us all out.
The only thing is God might be dead by then
and we'll be saved.
There's those who believe that God is dead, you know.
So this the levels of consciousness then explain the
mankind's difficulty in understanding the nature of
divinity and what man has done primarily is
anthropomorphic.
In other words,
humanlike attributes are then projected onto God.
God is angry, jealous, fitful, vengeful.
So that's the God below calibrated level 200.
He's punitive.
He gets even with you.
He punishes you.
He doesn't care about you.
He throws your hell, your soul into hell.
He's vindictive.
He gets even with you.
Can you imagine a God who gets even with you now?
You went and sinned already.
And you will have to be punished for sinning.
Why did man sin?
because he was created defective.
" We'd like to know the difference between truth
and falsehood.
" So I said, "Okay, okay.
He's going to give you an F in godism.
" So just in order to curry favor with divinity,
I put this whole map of consciousness together.
Please go God and get off the hook with him, you know.
All right.
So the view of God then is a reflection of one's
understanding which is a reflection of one's evolved
level of consciousness.
Evolved level of consciousness.
If mankind is dependent on religious authority to define
these attributes of God
because he did not really understand them himself
coherently except for some cultures
which the world would call primitive who frankly had very
evolved understandings of the nature of God.
The Native American Indian for one,
the Native American Indians understanding of God is
extremely high.
God is the allpresent source of life
and all is done in the name of God.
And when you sacrifice an animal,
you do so with reverence to the spirit of the animal
and with thanks to God.
That's about as evolved a view of God as you can get
without a PhD from any theological school.
Yeah.
Uh so God is uh loving and wise as infinitely merciful.
Now what does merciful mean is already in dispute in
various cultures uh on the planet right now is it not?
What is the nature of an infinitely merciful God?
All all merciful God.
Does it mean you should behead infidels
or merciful means to do them a favor?
We'll just behead them.
Oh, thank you, God, for beheading us all.
That was loving and and heartwarming
and very very inspiring.
Very inspiring, though.
If you screw up, you'll be beheaded.
Oh, okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
So,
cultural understandings then uh poured down over the
centuries whether God is uh anthropomorphic
and subject to human anger, resentment and punishment.
So these are the negative depictions of divinity
which have great power over large segments of of the
world even uh today even today
and they predominated in earlier religions
and as we said the origin of it was earthquake
and flood and catastrophe and primitive man thought
that the gods must be angry
and therefore they sacrificed more and more virgins
and They couldn't keep up with enough virgins to keep God
satisfied.
Correlated with this view of God is the way you see
yourself and the level of consciousness from psychiatry,
psychoanalysis and other sources.
The perennial wisdom calibrates these levels as we always
did in psychiatry, psychoanalysis, psychology.
At the top is peace and then that is joy and love
and reason and acceptance and willingness and above
that and below that neutrality.
Now the the big uh political thrusts in our society
currently are in the 300s and they were in the past.
It's really in the 300s.
Um who are the 300s?
The 300s are the volunteer firemen in the city of New
York.
They're the policemen.
There's the they're the uh heroic people.
They're the people who build uh uh big empires.
The 300s are very powerful.
It has to do with doingness and optim optimism.
It has to do with uh goodwill.
Good will, hard work, and service to others.
So that's about
where both the political parties are right now.
They both have an intention uh to serve
and to be uh uh a willingness to to be of service
and available and both parties I think are in the high
300s and I remember the former Clinton administration was
also the ele the elect it's because that's
where the electorate is the current American electorate
is around seeing as politics is
so much uh in the news the current American electorate is
around 300 over 370, 375, 374, 373.
The current American electorate is around 373.
So for a political party to win,
they should aim at that level.
373 is a very good level.
And both parties really are pretty much aimed that way.
So it's come see kamsa seeing as uh they're both aiming
for the same type of uh credible integrous service etc.
Uhhuh.
All right.
So that level is is harmonious.
So although things come up sort of negative within
political campaigns,
uh it's really uh hopeful
and what they're really trying for is harmony
and what they're really trying for is optimism.
Optimism.
All right.
So that means America's in a good place politically
despite what people say about it.
And if you calibrate both parties,
it won't make much difference who wins.
It won't make that much difference.
Why?
Because America is a great electorate
and you can only go so far with the whole public.
So you always have the public is a rudder.
The public is a rudder
that will keep them from from going off on the edge of
the cliff.
All right.
So we have the these numbers uh these are mathematical
numbers at the calibrated levels uh
which go up to a thousand and go down as far as 20.
It even goes below 10.
I think Ben Lden is 10.
Yeah, bin Lenon I think is 10.
He he's he's the prize winner in today's he's he's the
prize winner in today's negative contest.
Bin Lden is at 10.
There was that mad killer
that machine shoot shot everybody.
He was about five.
So Ben Len has a has a has a a contestant.
That guy that went on video
and then shot up all his classmates.
He calibrated at five.
Cho.
Yeah.
>> Cho.
>> Cho calibrates at five.
Oh Bowen, you just lost the race.
Cho beat boy.
All right.
So the levels then are very very significant.
They really tell us a whole uh lot.
They're also very reassuring.
" And then when you use the arm and you calibrate it,
you see, well, you know,
you can make a lot of different am lot of noise over
little differences.
But all in all, there's still going to be both around 370.
What did we say the elector was?
373.
>> 373.
>> Huh?
>> Yeah.
So, the electorate is at 373.
All right.
So, that's a pretty safe, sensible,
sane uh world to live in.
373.
Uh it should bring about peaceful understanding.
Eventually it'll bring about a synthesis of the two
parties and you know as far as functioning in the world.
Okay.
So that's enough of red tie
and politics in the world we live in.
How about the next slide?
Yeah.
Uh,
one of the things we did with consciousness calibration,
one of the first things we did was calibrate the reality
of spirit, spiritual realities.
Are there such things as angels?
Yes.
Archangels?
Uh, is there such a thing as heaven?
Yes.
Does there more than one heaven?
So for the first time man could calibrate you know
discern realities
that are not available to the intellect not available to
the intellect and you solve a lot of uh problems
when you ask certain things like I'll say we have
permission to ask there are multiple heavens resist
multiple heavens all right various religious den
denominations have their own neighborhood.
Where's it?
They got their own neighborhood.
You know,
the Mormons don't have to mix with the like goes to like.
So those that uh
so when the religion tells you you must do a certain
thing in order to get to heaven,
what they mean is their heaven.
They're talking about their heaven.
If you're not a Mormon,
you're not going to get into Mormon heaven.
It doesn't mean you can't get into heaven, period.
It means you can't get into Mormon heaven.
Well, if you're not a Mormon,
why would you want to go to Mormon heaven anyway?
So, there's nothing to feel bad about.
I don't think there's an atheist heaven, though.
I suspect there is an agnostic equivalent to heaven.
Those are people who say, "Lord,
I in and of myself can't make up my mind whether there is
a god or there isn't a god.
" Well,
I was brought up very religious about as religious as you
can get.
And then I went through a period of disillusionment
and became a dedicated atheist.
First a dedicated religionist, then a dedicated atheist,
then a dedicated agnostic.
And they say atheism was naive too.
Agnostic was more sophisticated.
If you can't prove the existence of God one way
or the other, you can't say God doesn't exist.
That's not stupid.
So you can just say I of myself am unable to know.
So where does agnostic on this thing here?
Where is he?
He's not even on there.
He's not called an enlightened state.
It's called an intellectually sophisticated state.
So the agnostic then represents intellectual
sophistication that you've thought about the subject
and realize that the mind alone is unable to solve it.
So the agnostic is integrous in
that he it realizes the limitation of the human intellect
in and of itself cannot handle the question of the
infinite nonlinear domain of consciousness itself.
Huh?
It exists within it.
So how can it answer it when it is within it itself?
So the infinite realm of consciousness itself with no
beginning and own end no end is a source of infinite
power.
As we have said before one cubic cm of empty space has
more intrinsic power within it than the mass of the
entire universe.
Those who are interested in the advances of scientific
advances in consciousness,
uh there's the new book by the professor of physics at
Berkeley, uh whose name I always forget.
>> What's his name?
>> Staff.
>> Henry Stap.
Yeah, I know.
All right.
Henry Staf's new book called Mindful Universe uh
integrates modern science
and consciousness in a very elegant way
and is about as sophisticated as you need to get from a
scientific viewpoint.
Yes.
Uh the enlightened divine states then the supreme godhead
these all calibrated at a thousand or 5,000
and archangel is 5,000 and up.
uh Christ Buddhahood had within this realm uh the great
avatar is calibrated at a thousand um all these are the
states about which man has wondered and written
and it's and they're the most difficult to define
because that which is uh called uh enlightenment is a
nonlinear condition
and there's no one to whom it occurs
and there is no person who becomes enlightened.
What happens is that which is linear disappears
and the linear is replaced by the nonlinear.
The nonlinear is a knowingness with neither subject nor
predicate nor adjective nor verb.
It's a state of being and awareness and it exists in
and of itself and it is not an attribute of any person.
So no person becomes enlightened.
What happens is that that
which was is replaced by an infinite state.
So the what exists then is this is an infinite state in
the service of which the body speaks and walks around etc.
And this condition comes on unwittingly of its own.
There are certain karmic propensities.
And of course in spiritual work what we try to do is
remove the obstacles.
So we don't create an enlightened state.
We don't create a enlightened state.
Uh what happens is we remove the obstacles.
And when you remove the obstacles,
which is the purpose that we're talking today,
when you remove the obstacles,
then the state it prevails of its own
and you really recognize that it's there
and that it's been there all along.
Ordinarily,
what you do is you begin to eliminate all conceptual
thought.
All conceptual thought.
Why?
Because conceptual thought all has to do with appearance
and reality has to do with essence.
When we calibrate something,
what are we we're what we're asking is what is it?
It's it's its absolute reality.
What is the essence, not the appearance?
So, we know what appearance looks like.
It looks like uh uh the blog blogger world.
What do they call the blogger world?
Internet bloggerism.
Whatever that is.
It charters away about appearance.
You know,
it goes from ridiculous to absurd to uh some sometimes at
least factually accurate.
But what it's talking about is what a thing appears uh to
be.
Nancy, the former president's wife,
who was in feeble condition, you know,
and then the internet came on saying things that were
so spectacularly horrible.
You can't believe they were said.
and and then suddenly they disappeared.
So at least there's a bit of sanity left someplace to say
such wicked things about people, you know.
All right.
So appearance then has nothing to do with reality.
And we what we try to teach you in these co classes is
the difference between appearance and essence.
What a thing looks like
and what it is are two widely divergent things.
And frankly without calibrating the level of
consciousness uh very often it's impossible to to tell
whether a thing is true or not true.
And uh everybody can put their hand on a stack of Bibles
and then lie.
Done in court every day.
Put your hand in the Bible.
You swore Bible tell I do.
Then they get up and they lie.
That would scare the wits out of me.
What?
Imagine your your final moments on life.
You're gonna meet God in a couple of seconds.
And you think of all the stuff you swore.
What's the truth on the Bible?
" I take that all back.
I take that all back, Lord.
Yeah.
So,
we can verify that which is not accessible to the
ordinary human mind.
The human mind deals in the linear world of logic
and reason in addition to feeling.
So between feeling and logic
and reason it then reaches its limit.
From that point on then what's what prevails is the field
of consciousness itself.
It's because of consciousness we have awareness
and because of awareness we're able to discern reality.
So these are the supreme states
that we calibrated very earlier in this work
and uh per the purpose was to see these run from 600
and up.
So the enlightened states calibrate levels 600 and up.
Uh the satananda begins at 600.
The state does not announce itself.
a state of bliss takes over a state of completeness at
level 600.
So most spiritual students are aiming at least for this
this is a a doable reachable state
where you let go all the negatives
and surrender them all to divinity.
You stop listening to the mind
and propagating conceptual thinking and you focus
and and pray uh to God to understand the essence of the
essence of divinity,
the essence of love
and then in one happy moment with karmic uh propensities
prevail.
The state emerges of its own.
People get close to it sometimes with very beautiful
music.
Very beautiful music can bring you very close to
beatificates which uh with some practice you can turn
slowly turn off the music and the state will continue.
The state will continue of its own without being propped
up by the music.
Although the music will certainly set you in the right
dimension, the right mood.
Um the music we see we see on channel 8 for instance uh
the beatotific music we were listening to is over uh 600
700 650.
All right.
So the beautiful music you see on channel 8 recently uh
PBS station um calibrated the music itself is at 650 um
Celtic Woman and uh what was the other one?
Huh?
>> Celtic woman.
Celtic woman.
Yes.
And uh the great teners, etc.
Anyway,
great classical music will lift you all the way to 700s.
So there is a crossover
if if you you can't get to the 600s or if
if you you can't get to the 600s
or 700s through thinking this.
So reading a book isn't going to get you there.
Uh so what would set give you a sense of what it's like?
The sense of what it's like is you're walking through the
woods when and when and you completely forget
when and when and you completely forget about time
or place and the infinite silence of the wood is
enchanting or infinitely beautiful music
that makes you cry.
The kind of beautiful music that makes you cry
because it's so incredibly beautiful is bringing you very
close to the divi to that divine state
and is letting you know
that that divine state is available
and that you can experience the same state without the
prop of music itself.
But I think great music.
So we know that great music especially in childhood has a
profoundly positive experience on the way your neurons
connect and prop you know potentiate later spiritual
evolution.
Then it was discovered that the neurons, you know,
the neurons proliferate at a greater rate than they're
needed and the excess are are are trimmed out.
And uh then it's been discovered in the recent decades
that the creation of new neurons
and therefore to be correct connected uh in the right
brain continues on into a age age the older you are.
So even age age the older you are.
So even though you're 70 or 80,
your mind is still proliferating new no new new neurons
and you can still learn things
that you failed to learn when you were young.
It was thought before that unless you learned it
when you were young, you know, you would never learn it.
So we find that the same things that propitiate uh
or potentiate spiritual comprehension
and understanding in youth continues to work into
adulthood.
peace and music and uh such things.
Great beauty uh great beauty potentiates it.
The sensitivity,
it isn't just the music uh
but the sensitivity to music uh
and we've spoken over the years about some of the kind of
music that tends to bring tears to your eyes.
The kind of music
that tends to bring tears to your eyes is the kind
that brings you closest to God.
So yeah.
So we'll move to the next slide.
Huh?
Well, we had said, which slide was that?
We skipped one.
We had we went backwards.
Oh, yeah.
This is uh where the world's population is.
You see, we've shown these slides over and over again.
85% of the world's population lives below this critical
level of 200.
That sort of modifies your expectations of the world.
Your expectation expectations of the world is
that the majority of the world's population then is below
the level of truth and integrity at 200.
You can sell them anything and they'll buy anything
and they'll kill you for any reason.
Does that sound pessimistic?
No, not pessimistic, but limited.
but limited.
When you ride the subway, subways,
keep your billfold where you know where it is.
That's just reality oriented.
Reality oriented, right?
All right.
So, 85% of the world's population.
Therefore, an audience such as this is exceptional.
The chances of an audience like this being together in
one place in the world are practically zero.
001% that such a group of people therefore this group of
people here is influencing the level of consciousness of
all of mankind.
That is true.
Oh Lord, this audience now here assembled here,
right here,
right now is profoundly affecting the level of mankind.
profoundly affecting the level of consciousness of all of
mankind.
resist that and indeed is a gift and a responsibility.
Is it not?
That by virtue of that which you have become,
by virtue of that which you are,
not by virtue of what you do or say,
by virtue of what you have become and what you are,
you're preventing the ship from sinking.
just folks like you just breathing in
and out is doing the whole universe a favor.
You understand what I'm saying?
People always want to have a save the globe uh conference
and we're going to have a parade in in Central Park
and we'll have bands and flags and save the world.
Then they have the riot police.
You know what I'm saying?
It isn't what you do then.
It's what you have become.
It's by virtue of what you have become
that you're you're profoundly influencing the
consciousness level of mankind to give up wickedness in
all its ways.
All we need is some kind of guidance to tell us
which way is the truth and which way is falsehood,
which way is heaven, which way is hell.
You don't have to go
and get a master's degree to figure that out.
See?
uh but for 85% of the world's population then uh exists
below level of level 200 they are dedicated to falsehood
and non- integrity and dishonesty.
Yes.
All right.
Let's move on to the next story.
Oh, here here's a different way of depicting it.
We're going over the basics this time
because we don't want to go through these basics again.
We want them so familiar.
You don't have to think about it.
As you can see,
a group like this is is somewhere a group like this is
somewhere near the very top peak of the of the pyramid.
Well, the great of the of the pyramid.
Well, the great the farther consciousness has evolved,
the greater is its power.
So, you don't have to do anything to save the world.
Just be what you are as loving
and kind towards all of life as you can.
Yeah.
To be as loving and forgiving as as you can.
To look at the negatives with a sense of humor.
And I think one of the most powerful spiritual tools is a
sense of humor.
Without a sense of humor, you're you going to last long.
A sense of humor then is the capacity to look at the
other side of a story uh of what could be termed
depressing and reprehensible and be able to handle it
and let it bounce off let it bounce off you say self
and say yes I know that exists in the world it's just
that I don't subscribe to it
so this is a very profoundly important uh group of people
here today California is lucky isn't this California.
This is California.
Is this California?
Yes, we're somewhere in California.
Hollywood or No, we're in Los Angeles.
No, Long Beach.
I knew we'd get there.
Okay, let's go to the next one.
" Because these people right here in this congregation
right here are really the tip, the tip, you see?
And just by breathing in and out,
you see that you calibrate the great uh mass of mankind.
" Yes.
But what you do by just sitting there and breathing in
and out is you keep it from destroying itself.
If it wasn't for a group like this,
mankind would have already destroyed itself.
Very close to it.
flirts with it all the time.
Nuclear bombs and stuff.
If it wasn't for this group here,
mankind would probably have destroyed itself already.
Resist.
Yeah.
Well, we all should get some kind of a button.
I saved the world.
We could get a save the world card, official stamp on it.
You know, I help save the world.
When you get to the uh when you get to the pearly gates,
St.
Peter now has a computer, you understand?
And he looks up your card number.
Okay, you may pass.
How you racking up there, St.
Peter?
He's got you on his computer.
So, at this end, he he says, uh,
you can go that line over there.
this end he says that you can stand in line the other one.
All right,
we go to the next just
that we're familiar with these things evolution of
consciousness.
Now I was mistaken on this.
I thought this is over the laps time in the consciousness
level you see was rising up to what what is called now
and I thought it was going to continue to go up.
No, it didn't.
It went up to to 207 or something like
that and then it curled around and came back to 204 H.
So that means the consciousness level can advance
and then it can go down and then it can advance again
and go down.
So it it's not a straight linear progression
and um events on the planet and man's reaction to them.
Let's see what man is co-overall.
Now we have permission to do man overall right now.
Mankind overall is over 204 205 204.
He was up to 207.
Mankind was up to 207.
Now he's down to the 204 again.
>> You're not working hard.
>> Got to get more lectures.
Now the people that need to hear what we got to say not
going to come to a lecture
and this is all hogwash with them goody goody two shoes
stuff be kind to goody goody two shoes stuff be kind to
your neighbor and all that jazz I say
if he don't agree with you b him that's what I say chop
him sit off there
that solves the problem where's guillotine
when we need it.
You know, guillotine chopped off 15,000 heads.
Boy, that's a lot of work, wouldn't you say?
15,000 people got beheaded by the in the name of freedom
and democracy.
15,000 people to get.
All right, next uh slide.
This is uh earth epics and calibrated levels.
uh this can't be seen very easily from this audience.
There's one reason we're going to put the all these
charts out in a book form
or uh uh some available form is
because these can't really be seen by the seat from the
seats.
But all it shows is
that the the level of the energy of life itself on the
planet uh has evolved over great eons of time.
It began at calibrated level of one.
Bacteria, algae,
first signs of life
and then the invertebrates uh calibrated level of eight.
Then the fish first traces of land life
and you see how the calibrated level of uh of life on
this planet over the great uh ages slowly evolved uh the
ages of the dinosaur etc.
How life itself is evolutionary.
So life itself is evolutionary.
We're evolutionary.
Life is evolutionary.
Mankind is evolutionary.
So that takes care of the evolution versus creation
argument because man was created in an evolutionary
pattern.
So the creation creation is
that you know God was mankind was created by God.
So the trouble with the evolutionist,
the radical evolutionists,
is they think the world is only 6,000 years old.
So they they don't make much sense at all.
they they don't make much sense at all.
Man was created to be evolutionary.
So there is no conflict between creation
and evolution because man was created to be evolutionary,
to learn, to grow, to evolve, to fulfill his potential.
Uh yes.
And to fly to the moon.
Fly to the moon.
Okay.
That's that's the next this is uh the animal kingdom
which we touch upon
because again it sort of tends to cement these things in
your mind.
Uh and we have the the dog's wagging tail.
We did we did our new dog a new dog at 255.
That was the family dog.
Yeah.
Well, the the family dog is 250.
Anyway, uh this dog Kelsey is a 255.
Uh then we notice we have a gray parrot at home, too.
We don't have a trained gorilla.
We'd like to have one.
" I said, "All right, whatever you want, honey.
" No drink.
Okay.
We also have three cats.
and a dog's wagging tail now.
So,
three cats purring at 500
and a dog's wagging tail wagging at 500
and and a bird a bird singing and talking at 405.
Uh,
you can see why things are pretty good around the house.
It's hard to stay mad at anything.
It's hard to stay mad at anything
because if the bird doesn't get you,
the bird tell gives our phone number out to everybody.
answers the phone and makes a click like it's saying up.
Hello 2824469.
Bye.
Is the parrot talking?
" You see the world you create for yourself is one of
love and affection.
So the way to enlightenment is to be loving towards all
of life and all of its expressions.
Uh to be unconditionally loving towards all of life
and all its expressions.
To be loving means also to make allowance for limitation.
And that can't really be done without humor.
There's no way you can handle some of the extreme
negatives of life uh without humor.
So humor allow is a spiritual tool,
one that's uh under represented in the world's great
religions.
He seems so grim about everything.
You know what I'm saying?
Jesus.
Crack a smile would kill him.
You know what I mean?
Without a sense of humor,
then you'll have a hard time maintaining spiritual
principles.
How can you remain loving towards life
when you see some of the absurdities that go on
and represent the ultimate cruelties and sadism etc.
And so the last thing we need to to save our sanity then
is an explanation for those things
that cannot be handled by humor etc.
And therefore an understanding of karma is essential I
think to serious spiritual students
because there's no other way you can textualize things
that are inexplicable that happened to you.
You can be the most saintly per person on the on the
planet and get run over by a cab.
She's on their way to help the poor.
Bags of food and money
and medicine for the sick sick children.
Arm loads of sick children.
Medicine in the taxi cab.
How can you explain that?
So the last thing we need then to fit it all together,
the calibrated levels of consciousness,
the awareness that the brain is constantly proliferating
new new neurons
and therefore you can become more spiritually adept the
older you get which is contrary to what people used to
think.
Then you add the understanding of karma
and now you've got all that you need.
You can't really become enlightened without understanding
karma and my understanding of it etc.
Because how would you handle all the negatives?
Well, you'd say, "What is that?
" I mean, how do you handle that stuff?
So, without a sense of humor, then you can't.
And the answer then it comes to the teachings of the
Buddha and Karma uh Hindu Hindu uh and Hindu Hindu uh
and comes from the eastern cultures
and understanding of karma.
So we can use then consciousness calibration to confirm
is karma a valid uh reality.
Okay, we have permission to ask this.
Resist.
Karma is a valid reality.
A valid confirmable reality.
Resist.
Right.
Yes.
All right.
So then you have the last spiritual tool you need.
You can't really handle spiritual evolution without an
understanding of karma
because there's no explanation for the seemingly negative
or the seemingly bizarre.
And if you go into past life recall
and there are various techniques
which you can learn to do
that very simple self hypnosis uh you can find out some
of the things that explain unexplain unexplainable in
your life.
I sp sp sp sp sp sp sp sp sp sp sp sp sp sp sp sp sp sp
sp sp sp spontaneously sp sp sp sp sp sp sp sp
spontaneously had such recalls
and they were very very vivid uh very vivid it's not like
you remember something uh it's not like you're watching a
movie of something
that happened with past life recall what happens is the
movie restarts and you're you're on stage you're not
witnessing somebody's pain out there you're feeling it in
your leg you reexperience
and suddenly what went on in
that lifetime uh makes complete sense And you can see an
exact uh connection between uh an obligation.
So one of the reasons for spiritual work then is to speed
up uh the evolution of karmic your karmic evolution to
undo the negatives.
So how do we undo the negatives?
We undo the negatives by service to others by modesty
humility by goodwill and lovingness towards others.
So the traditional way is by selfless service karma yoga.
Uh we undo the negatives by virtue of of the positive.
The way it isn't
so much we undo negative karma as we overbalance it by
creating good karma.
So traditionally in our culture then karma yoga is not
called karma yoga of course it's called volunteering
giving to the poor etc is not called karma yoga
but we know that selfless service however it might be it
can be done you know in civil service it could be done in
many ways um so the last tool we need then to put it all
together so you can remain rational reasonable educ
educated and and spiritual,
you need the understanding of karma,
the understanding of the calibrated levels of
consciousness.
And then when you tap that off with devotion
and commitment.
So all we need then to become enlightened is what we do
at the beginning of the lecture.
We say glory and excelsius to you.
We say, "Oh, glory be to thee, oh Lord.
All glory be to thee, oh Lord.
I may that I may be of infinite service.
Amen.
That's all we have to do.
And then the rest is up to God.
And the rest is up to the Holy Spirit.
And the rest is up to our our good guides.
Our heavenly guides.
Let's see.
We have permission to ask about heavenly guides.
Everybody has guardian angels.
Resist.
That's the good news, folks.
Everybody's got guardian angels.
Just some of you have pissed them off.
That's the only problem.
My guardian angels are jokers.
I mean,
they tell me those things
and I just say what they put in my mind.
They put it there.
I didn't think that at all.
What time do we have to take a break?
I think >> um we have about 10 more minutes.
>> Oh, yeah.
Okay.
All right.
Is that good news?
Does everybody know that you have guardian angels?
Anybody think you don't have any spiritual guardian
angels?
No skeptics?
Where's the skeptics?
Where's the rebellious adolescence?
Come on.
When I was a teenager,
there'd be all kinds of hands up guardian angels.
Man, that's spooky stuff.
I don't believe all we do have guardian angels.
And you can learn to relate to them and pray to them.
And I always thank my guardian angels, you know, uh,
all the time.
" Just miss the taxi cab misses the the pedestrian say,
"Whoops, thanks for that one.
One time I was a cab driver
and I was approaching the main intersection of town at a
great rate and I was going to break down right before the
intersection and I stepped on the brake
and the master cylinder went the cab careen madly through
this crazy traffic and all these pedestrians
and came to arrest quietly on the curb on the other side
of the main drag, you know,
and u that's what you all happy karmic consequence.
" The guy actually knew.
" I said,
"The brake goes all the way down
and there's nothing there,
but I could have killed many people.
I went right right between all these people
and right right between all these people
and didn't kill anybody or run over anybody, you know.
So, if it isn't a guardian angel, well, I mean,
in their guardian angels all got together
and a gang of them desired.
I never would have gotten through medical school
otherwise, you know.
So, we learn a lot.
Then when whatever you we use consciousness calibration
whenever we research what is the nature of the essence of
things we always find out things that are helpful
and uh each little piece of knowledge seems to fit in
another brick in the wall you know it's like each one
fits in and reinforces our overall understanding
and so we see all these great uh animals over great uh
periods of time some of whom as you know are my favorites.
I love the octopus and the komodo dragon
and all those little friend friendly type creatures
and uh then we notice as we said
that the consciousness level of the animal kingdom is
below 200 and then suddenly you get to the herbivores.
So you see the carnivores the carnivores they live by the
death of others.
The carnivores stays carnivor stays alive by the virtue
of the death of others.
The dinosaur can't exist unless it eats kills somebody.
And then at 200 we hit the herbivores.
These are the grazers.
The deer doesn't have to kill anybody.
The bison, the piggy, elk, dairy cow,
none of these animals have to kill anybody in order to
stay alive.
So the cost of life then is the killing of innocent
others.
You know, the killing of others.
Uh and then at level 200,
consciousness evolves
where we don't have to kill others to survive.
A very significant jump in consciousness at consciousness
level 200.
And so we'll move on to the next yeah three more minutes.
The other uh I'm putting together the pieces upon
which the whole consciousness uh research is based the
profound significance in our culture.
So I'm trying to emphasize the things
that are of profound significance in our culture
and the great books of the western world are one of the
is the bricks in the wall of western culture.
Uh this is the area edition
that has come about uh through the best thinking of
mankind and re reawakened from ancient uh Greece during
the reformation during the age of enlightenment.
And these are the great minds
which have shaped uh western civilization or the not
so great minds which have threatened it.
And of course Karl Marx Carl Marx at one level level 130
then is dialectical materialism
which exists now in new political clothes
but still undermines all of the sanity of today's world.
So these are the great minds of all time
and these were the books of my childhood.
Other people were reading comic books
and I was reading the apherisms of Marcus Aurelius.
So I was an oddball kid as you can see.
Oddball kid.
Rather than play football or baseball,
I'd rather read the affisms of Marcus Curelius.
All right.
So the these uh the great area edition was ancient uh
Greece, ancient Athens, the great minds of uh history.
Now modern man is still struggling with things
that were answered in the year 400.
uh the current uh political discourse is really rehashing
things that have been solved for thousands of years.
You know,
one says uh I I see uh the world I see is different than
the world you see.
Uh that was the argument which Plato answered.
You know uh the argument was
but I see the world I see is a different world than the
world you see.
So we live in different worlds.
That of course is facious.
It means uh because your perception what you're talking
about is opinion and opinion is perception.
What a thing looks like is not its reality.
And what we've done with consciousness calibration is
we've gone through what a thing looks like to find out
the essence of what it really is.
So truth is based on essence not on appearance.
And the way you can save yourself all kinds of trouble
and buying the wrong stocks in the stock market etc.
is you can't go by appearance you have to go by essence.
I remember all the glamour computer stocks.
remember WorldCom and all them uh
and people were shooting fortune.
They were making fortunes overnight.
We calibrated them.
They were at 190.
They were 190 and Walmart was at 440.
So guess which one we bought stock in.
So people at that time politically were taking pot shots
at Walmarts and buying WorldCom.
I always said well that's not knowing perception from
essence the perception is one thing
and the essence is another you know
so what we we want to put our feet on is
that which is is truthful
and the only way you can tell how truthful a thing is is
by calibrating its level of consciousness.
So these are the great minds
that have shaped all western society
and the collapse of these uh teachings in academia is why
academia is currently uh falling at a rapid rate.
Current academia is calibrating below 200.
And that's the end of that.
She said that was