Here
we are in divine company.
Let's look at each other and just
realize how blessed we are. Thank you,
Lord.
Now, we're going to go on to the new
slides. We are We going to do the
Mystic?
>> Yeah.
>> Well, we'll just do a quick pass at the
Mystic.
>> And um it was suggested if I stand back
farther from the field, I could see it.
Huh.
Oh,
yeah. the mis the world of the mystic
that's the inner path leading to union
with the divine we heard a presentation
of union with the divine as a as the
experience of illumination
and uh the classic stages are you try to
get rid of attractions and aversions
attractions and aversions surrender your
will to God at all times and uh if you
finally let attractions and aversions.
You you reach a indescribable state. In
that state, if it persists, if the
person goes back into the world again,
becomes classified as a sage.
Many a mystic does not return to the
world. The state of illumination takes
you out of the world.
But if it's one's karmic propensities,
one stays in the world and becomes a
teacher. uh the sage. So the inner
mysticism does not uh result in
returning to the world unless there is
sort of a commitment to do so. So we'll
go on to the next one. And the reason
that we do is merely to share
information that's never been had
before. Uh what's the name of this? I
can't read it. Spirituality
Oh well, we don't need this one.
It's too complicated.
Got doubt, skepticism. This probably
won't be any good anyway.
Uh what's important is Decart's
differentiation between the world as you
see it and the world as it is.
There's the world as you see it and then
there's the world as it is. And very few
people think there's any difference.
Most people naively presume that the way
you see it is the way it is. And these
are the kind of things we would argue
when I was a teenager.
Uh ancient Greek uh theoretical
philosophy is the world the way it is or
is it the way you see it? And uh
Socrates basic dictim which we live by.
All right. So
narcissism then is is what really
distorts the whole picture. We decide
that our way of seeing it is not only
the the right way, not not only the way,
but the right way. So whatever kind of a
dog they pick from the White House, you
can be sure half the people will be
against it and half them will be for it
and they're sure that how they see it is
the right way. Okay, let's go to the
next
doubt, skepticism. All right. So, now
we're getting to today's lecture. And uh
it's written in great big letters that
any idiot could see.
It's written in great big letters that
any idiot could see. Oh, I know what it
is. It's these lights here. I don't know
if you can turn those lights out. Those
lights drowned the screen.
>> These lights here drowned the screen.
>> See it from back there.
>> I can't see it. Can't go them.
I don't care if they can see it. I have
to see it.
>> There it is. Right there.
>> Oh, here. Right in front of my very nose
is freedom, morality, and ethics. Oh,
so we differentiate what is freedom
actually. And I define it as an inner
state.
Freedom is not out in the world. You
can't give anybody freedom.
You can't give anybody freedom because
they're bound they're slaves to so many
things that freedom is just a
a political slogan.
True free freedom is a inner state and
it comes about as a consequence of one's
choices.
To be really free means you're neither
bound to attraction nor aversion. No
attractions, no aversions.
Therefore you have true freedom to to
think what you think.
Uh
now this capacity is limited. It's very
much karmically determined. We never
asked this one before. True inner
freedom
is considerably uh karmic resist. The
capacity for it is karmic resist. Okay.
So we know that
many people in the world are impaired
are completely unable to be objective.
So there's no point in criticizing them
because they're born that way. 55% of
people in America calibrate below 200.
So how are they going to differentiate
truth from falsehood?
Uh there below 200 you can't really do
it.
There is a congenital compa capacity
genetic genetic which shows up by age
three. By age three, you know the people
at the very bottom of the levels of
consciousness.
By age three, a psychologist, you you
give a child a child sit there and and
here you give them a candy bar and you a
small candy bar and you say, "If I don't
eat this, by the time I come back, I'll
give you two candy bars.
and you leave the the psychologist
stopwatch uh leaves the room for I
forget whether it's one minute or three
minutes or what and comes back and a
certain percentage of children will be
unable unable to not eat that candy bar.
They don't have the capacity of
self-control, discernment or control.
And this is congenital diagnosible by
age three. And the prisons, the prisons
everywhere in the world are loaded with
them.
Within the prison is the child, the
inner child who cannot delay
gratification. Inability to delay
gratification for a greater reward. So I
just wanted to
when we talk about freedom, morality and
ethics realize that that's a choice
that's limited to a very small
percentage of the world. Freedom as an
inner state of consciousness.
Uh
the next limitation that we run into
which is also considerably genetic is
that understanding is comprehension of
meaning.
Understanding when you say understand
most people mean that what they mean by
that is they're familiar with it. It
doesn't really mean that they comprehend
it at all with the comprehension of the
meeting because comprehension is
abstract. Abstract. What does the thing
mean? You can see what it is. You can
give a history of it. But what does that
mean? Yeah. So it boils down then
morality and ethics break down to the
conflict between egotism and narcissism.
And we see in the world, especially in
this recent political thing,
that fraud and false witness is part of
the game. They don't even feel guilty
about it. Make a completely false claim.
Uh false witnesses
present that which is completely
fraudulent.
And they don't even their conscious
doesn't even give a twitch.
Why? Because in their game win at all
costs, the narcissistic gain of winning
to win then for the glamour the glamour
of it all.
So they
disclaim any any restriction due to
truth. So you can in the political world
you can say anything you want. Doesn't
have to be true at all. It's great to be
a politician, isn't it?
You're not constrained by honesty,
truth, veracity, confirmability, or any
of those little ready gutty things.
The fact that it's a complete falsehood
is irrelevant.
Isn't that amazing? It's irrelevant.
So, we're just recovering from the
cultural shock of all this.
Uh
is so we see what's the next one here?
Uh freedom is an inner state. Yes,
freedom is an interstate. So people who
are who try to get over thinking
uh freedom from thinking, freedom from
opinionation
uh find that it's a more difficult than
they thought because the mind is
constantly projecting judgmentalism.
Things are either desirable or not
desirable. Aversion versus attraction.
And the
Buddhism, one of the basic uh teachings
of Buddhism is to transcend attraction
and aversion.
Yeah. Freedom is an inner state.
There's only one thing you're free to do
and that you're not really free to do is
choice. You can choose chocolate or
vanilla. You can choose one or the
other. Uh at least theoretically you
have freedom. However, most people have
been so programmed they don't really
have even freedom over that, you know.
So, we spoke of the congenital
incapacitation diagnosible by age three,
which seems to be prim primarily to me
primarily karmic. So, the congenital
impairment
uh we have permission to ask this is is
primarily karmic or this. Yeah, it's
primarily karmic.
uh you're born that way. Well, it's
certainly diagnosible in a child.
Uh it has nothing to do with good and
bad. It has to do with your karmic
evolution.
So this world being what it is, a world
of maximum karmic opportunity.
Therefore, you would expect people who
are karmically
impaired to be here, and they are.
They keep the taxpayers busy supporting
them in jail and prison.
Well, from Susie's description this
morning and from those of other others
within the room who have experienced it,
uh, illumination is an inner subjective
state.
So what we do with spiritual study is we
prepare the way. The likelihood of
spiritual states is increased by our
alignment. and our spiritual alignment
and intention
uh brings forth powers from the field of
consciousness itself. So consciousness
is the mind of God.
Let's just repeat that one.
Consciousness
is the mind of God. Resist. Wow.
Consciousness is the mind of God.
We mean no offense Lord
to study the matter.
So the radiance of divinity shines forth
as the infinite power of the field of
consciousness itself which has no
beginning and no end.
There is no beginning and no end to the
field of consciousness. It is infinite
in dimension everywhere present
throughout all of time.
It's a field of infinite power. And as
we have cited before,
one cubic centimeter of space
has more energy in it than its
equivalent
as the mass of the universe.
The total mass of the entire universe
is less than the power in one cubic
centimeter of infinite empty space.
All we're saying is that the mind of God
is omnipotent.
Omnisient.
Omnipotent.
No beginning, no end, no then,
no future, no past. They're only what
is. Uhhuh. All right. So
now that we've sort of checked out the
limitations of it,
in today's world, yes,
we can move on to the next thing. our
present
problem you see as protesters and
demonstrators uh act out what we're
talking about no matter what passes no
matter what happens uh as we've said in
previous lectures the protesters and
demonstrators will be there and the FBI
takes always takes pictures of you know
the crowds of protesters and all and
people who are concerned about their
freedom feel bad about that well don't
be out there
cuz the same faces show up at every, you
know, the same faces show up all the
time and the computer in the computer
world picks out, you know, the same
faces show up. Some people just get off
on protesting and demonstrating and the
cal that calibrates at 170.
Why? Because it's totally narcissistic.
I mean, who cares if you protest?
Nobody cares if you protest. Nobody
gives a rap.
No matter what it is, there's a
protester out there. No matter what
passes, there's a protester.
And of course, uh, to me, it's very
funny. But, but the protesters, it's
very, very important that they get out
there and demonstrate. But you see the
narcissism of me me in protesting and
demonstrating. I mean, who cares what
you think? Frankly, nobody
nobody cares what you think. However, if
you keep showing up at the right
demonstrations, the FBI will keep you on
their list
of suspicious people who seem to show up
everywhere where there's a car bombing.
You know what I mean? Same people throw
throw up, show up.
Freedom versus license. So, freedom
is not to do. There was a letter, this
was triggered by a letter to the editor
of the Arizona Republic. It says, "I
will defend to the death people's right
to do whatever they want."
Do I don't want her in my backyard,
but she might do in my backyard. I
don't.
So, the confusion of do versus be. No.
In the United States, you have the
freedom to be, you know, to be. But you
don't have the freedom to do everything
you want. You can't take all your
clothes off and walk down the street.
Well, you can, of course.
In fact, New York City, they defended
some woman's right to strip to the waist
and walk stark naked down the street.
And ACLU took it to court and won.
I don't know if that became a fad in New
York City or not.
So where is freedom? Freedom is an inner
state of mind. There's only one place
you can be free and that's in your own
inner state of mind. You can feel
enslaved in situations where you have
actual freedom
and feel free in states of actual
enslavement and then states where you're
actually free be enslaved by your own
thoughts. You know you become the victim
of your own thoughts. Keep saying oh
lord please let me forget that or see it
differently. I always ask can I see I
would like to see it differently. And
you're asking then for illumination
instead of perception.
Freedom versus license. You're free to
be but you're not free to do.
And the fact that you're not free to do
means that you're that you're not still
free. You can be as you like.
All right. The lure of hedonism is
irresistible in today's world and it's
exploited by the media.
This is a peculiar set of generation
we're in now. We're in a brainwashed
generation.
Brainwashed like never before.
Electronic media have subjected all of
us to brainwashing.
Every one of us here has been
brainwashed. Anybody here think they're
not been brainwashed?
You've been brainwashed into thinking
you're not brainwashed.
Everybody in this room has been
brainwashed.
Everyone in this room has been
Well, the realization that you've been
brainwashed gives you a certain
skepticism about what you're holding in
mind.
Is that my idea or was that impo
imposed? And the brainwashing happens
via the media faster than you can catch
it. Those icky gooey denture helpers.
Next time you see that ad, you're going
to have to laugh at it. It's so icky
gooey, you know. Icky gooey. Uh, so
you've already been programmed. You've
already been programmed.
The lure of hedenism is irresistible to
to to the attraction of pleasure and
especially as the Buddha pointed out the
attraction of of the senses enslavement
by the senses
that takes some spiritual training. It
really takes some conscious effort, at
least it did in my my
life,
um to stop being attracted by the lure
of pleasure, the pleasure of the senses.
Uh curiously, it was the pleasure of the
most high senses that were the most
difficult.
Uh as I said, I love classical music and
classic beauty and things like that. And
I didn't miss that which was crude. Ice
cream and chocolate and all that stuff.
I could get over that. Chocolate took a
little effort. But
the lure of the senses then. So as the
Buddha pointed out, the first bondage,
the first bondage is bondage to the
senses and not just the senses but to
attraction and aversion.
And that takes some inner training to
finally transcend enslavement by the
senses. But it can be done. It can be
done.
The next thing is pre prevalent today's
society is the great ego self. The
arrandisment of the great me. The great
and wonderful me. And in political times
uh you you see bombast
bombast
glib and are they good? You know they
can spellbinders with all the elaborate
languaging and fancy presentation
and uh
so that's political rhetoric.
Political rhetoric is entrancing.
uh bombast.
So I hear candidates on both sides. And
if you turn down the volume a little bit
so you don't hear the exact words, the
energy, the tonality is the same.
them and ran away
and
when called to ask about the truth of
what they're saying, they go into shock.
I remember one candidate for vice
president when presented with the truth
of what his candidate was saying said
you you got to be kidding
because the shock of what the truth of
what was being presented was you've got
to be kidding this has got to be a joke
this has got to be a joke
the truth just blew him over he couldn't
think of another thing he wasn't used to
truth he was presented with the truth
and he just went this must be some kind
of a joke.
Truth has no place in politics. You know
what I'm saying? This has got to be a
joke. A joke. I think that was so funny.
I'll never forget his fate. He was just
indignant and overwhelmed. This has got
to be some kind of a joke.
Oh, funny. All right. So, bombast, you
have to be good at that. I was never too
good at bombast, but I've practiced.
I've practiced the best I can.
Then you have hate websites which are so
shocking I don't want to even refer to
some recent examples. But we'll
eventually get down to the presence of
good and evil in the world. All of these
discussions will eventually take you to
good and evil and the ambiguities of
good and evil. Whether uh
the ex-president's wife falls down and
fractures her pelvis. Who was that? Mrs.
What? Reagan,
>> huh? Reagan. Yeah, there's a hate
website out there that that that gloats
over that. It gives them great glee.
They're glad she fractured it. They hope
that she suffers a lot.
Uh when the White House uh spokesman got
cancer, what was the name?
>> Snow.
Tony Snow.
>> Tony Snow. Yes. When Tony Snow got
cancer, the same hate website came out
and hope that he dies in agony and that
it's a slow death and and you say to
yourself,
"This is incomprehensible.
This can't can't really be out there on
the website." Not only that, but the
source of it is proud of it. Proud that
they are the author of I guess what is
admittedly evil. E admittedly evil. So
uh he evil is legal. Evil not only that
but it's profitable. Yeah. So the
website I'm thinking about I have
permission to ask about this resist
is evil resist. Yeah. That brings us
then confronted with
the seeming ambiguity in the teachings
of Jesus Christ
who said on the one hand evil is in the
eye of the beholder
that's the picture we show up on there
is perception in other words is evil a
perception you project evil onto things
that's all in your own mind there is any
evil out there you say that person is
evil
Then in the Lord's prayer,
it says, "Lord, protect us and deliver
us from evil." Well, if evil is only a
projection, you wouldn't need protection
from it, would you? So, the Lord's
prayer, it says, "And deliver us from
evil."
Deliver us from evil.
And Jesus Christ taught not taught not
to encounter evil. Don't do not go to
war with evil. Uh don't try to defeat
evil. Avoid it. Avoid evil.
So even with evil, it seems to me like
good and evil should be simple as black
and white, shouldn't it? But even here,
don't you see how much is left up to our
own personal consciousness and our own
level of spiritual evolution? What we
see as evil or so. So you can say, well,
what should we feel about a hate
websites
that glories in the fractured pelvis of
an elegant uh old lady?
What should we think about it? How
should we hold it?
Well, we should pray for them maybe. Can
we pray for hate? Can we Can we pray for
the sources of hate and pray that they
see things differently? Let's ask if
that's advisable.
We We have permission to ask this. It's
advisable to pray for the purveyors of
hatred. Resist.
It's It's safe. I don't know if it's
safe. It's safe to pray for the
purveyors of hatred. Resist.
Oh boy.
Well, the Buddha said there's no point
in going to war with them because they
will bring themselves down of their own
nature. There's no point in trying to go
to war with evil because evil is
self-destructive. So, let's ask that uh
we are first to ask this evil is
autonomously self-destructive.
Will eventually burn itself out even if
we don't do anything about it. Oh,
that's a relief.
How can we rest if evil's out there
someplace?
We should be out there trying to defeat
evil. So Jesus Christ said, "Don't go to
war with evil."
Why? Because evil plays by different
rules than you are aware of. That which
is demonic and comes from the lower
astral realms
uh does not play by the same rules as
you do. Yes. Uh, all right. So, hate
websites, I I I still am overwhelmed by
them that they even exist. And when they
quote one of them on the television
news, I'll say, "They're making this up.
Nobody could possibly
hope that Nancy Rean suffers and
fractures her pelvis more and ends up
crippled." And that's help me God is
what this website actually says.
Unbelievable. paid websites.
Yeah. Uh the next
the dilemma what we're talking about of
course is the dilemmas of current
society es especially as aggravated by
the media is what to do about that which
you consider to be uh adverse to life.
Uh and here is a here's where the
ideologist weakens the weakens our life.
The ideologist doesn't see the
difference between your your idea about
a thing and the thing itself.
So the ideologists will say all animals
should be treated with the same respect
and love. So it's safe to step into the
cage of the komodo dragon
and international politics right now.
Should we step into the cage with the
komodo dragon or not?
Uh
it brings then brings back what is
necessary for survival and do we have
the right to do what we need uh to
survive
that which uh threatens life itself
and takes delight in killing
uh killing should we accommodate them?
Europe has tried to accommodate them and
when we were last in Europe uh we saw
the results of accommodating
uh versus survival
and we saw that accommodation led to
really a loss of survival.
So to what degree should we accommodate
that which has sworn
uh to destroy uh the great Satan? Should
we accommodate the destroyers of the
great Satan?
And uh because
you people out there are are the great
Satan.
You don't mind being destroyed, do you?
Anybody object to being destroyed?
>> Oh, how selfish of you?
The only way I'm going to go to heaven
is if I blow you to bits. Is that okay?
Is that okay?
>> No. Oh.
All right. So, sanity intervenes. The
ideologist then cannot differentiate
uh politicized
uh uh theory with an actuality and a
reality and a reality. And so, we owe
the survival of our current America to
the fact that people in Washington could
see the difference and that uh survival
is at stake. Those who they say it so
gingerly they're even afraid to say it
correctly. Those who are what don't like
the United States too much.
That's sort of dopey sounding, isn't it?
They want to blow you to kingdom come.
When now
how anyway
I thought it was so ginger the way they
would send that. They're so afraid they
might offend those who don't like us too
much.
Like blowing you up. Yes, that's not
liking you too much. Blowing you to the
kingdom come. I guess they call that not
liking you too much.
All right. So that's accommodation
versus survival. Uh
so I don't believe in accommodating the
mafia. I believe that uh we should
eliminate the mafia. Mafia. Okay. What's
the next slide? Anyway,
uh respect versus joining. So what is
the proper attitude towards that which
you do not approve of because it would
like to blow you up uh soon if not
sooner is uh you respect them but you
don't have to join them. Ah you can
respect them without joining them. Uh so
the you know political correctness
uh draws a fuzzy line. They can't tell
the difference
uh between joining. They think to
respect means you got to join them. You
don't have to line up with your enemies.
Uh you can respect their viewpoint. I
respect the viewpoint. I respect if you
grew up in a culture that teaches
certain things that women and dogs and
things like that are are unclean that
you're going to have that viewpoint. So
I can respect the fact they have that.
If I was a woman I wouldn't want to move
to that country but
if I wouldn't want to be their doggy
either
that a doggy is unclean and uh etc. So,
I hold my I got a great doggy right now
and I say, "Honey, sweetheart, do you
realize that a lot of people think that
you're unclean?
That you don't deserve to live?" And she
goes,
"I'm glad I'm glad I belong to you and
not on the other side of the world." So,
I respect the fact they consider dogs
unclean and have a derogatory view
towards women. It doesn't mean I have to
join them. Doesn't mean I have to join
them. However, if I was a woman, I don't
think I would move to a country like
that. And I wouldn't move there and take
my doggy with me.
But think, what's the worst place in the
world for a woman to be? What country?
Uh, walking down the street with her
doggy.
Well, those countries, you know, they
have decency police. So she would be
instantly arrested by the decency police
and incarcerated.
You're aware that those countries have
decency police to make sure that these
prejudices
etc. are respected and you get put in
prison. You get put in prison. Yes. Just
like some prisons,
some cultures, Afghanistan, not
Afghanistan, Pakistan, the jails are
full of women who've been raped. When a
rape occurs, the woman is in prison.
How does that grab you?
The woman once she's raped gets put in
prison in Pakistan. The woman does, not
the guy, the woman. I mean, is that
bizarre or what? So, I respect the fact
that they see and think the world that
way. But I do not have to join it. I do
not have to have to join it. the
megalomania in the same culture of the
claims of God's authorization
they're claiming God's authorization for
all kinds of manner of extremism
uh blowing up women and children and uh
various things the megalamania
so you can see the megalamania in that
the megalamania
of claims of God's authorization
so if I kill all these people a busload
of children uh that will please God. So
these are distortions of morality and
ethics
uh from our viewpoint that they are a
180 out of the kind of thing that we
think here. All right. Victimology is
very current and we're looking at the
prevailing ideologies in today's society
and there's a race for victimology.
uh victimology is the uh creates a
specialness and an entitlement.
So to prove that you're a victim uh of
course becomes dear and if you try to
unvictimize the people they go into a
rage.
They go into a rage because the payoff
of being a victim is so enormous in
political society. And if we get a
chance, we'll talk about it later in
personal relationship
because you are you automatically come
into a specialness
and an entitlement.
So the race for being the victim gives
you moral superiority.
So the moral superiority of being the
victim uh and therefore you can figure
out anything you can be a victim of. I'm
a victim of so many things I can't even
recall them all anymore. Anybody
here not a victim of something?
You're victim being a human being born
here.
Victim of gender. You're victim.
Everybody is somehow a victim of
something. And and this is a specialty
in today's political world. Politicize
the specialness and the exploitation of
it. And of course the real payoff is you
get money in the end.
you get the payoff. You get a special
committee and it awards huge grants to
explore
your your victimization and how it all
came about. And of course, how it came
about is in your own head.
All right. So, here we have the
opposite, the worship of freedom. And
it's narcissistic appeal. And we already
mentioned do what you want.
Does freedom mean license? We'll go on
to the next uh slide. Cultural
narcissism.
Uh there are whole cultures that you
have to admire them and make excuses and
and ex extend special privileges.
Free speech in the bill of rights
calibrates at 350.
Free speech in the bill of rights is
350.
Yes.
And that's sort of centrism.
It's sort of conservative centism. 350.
Uh free speech in current society
calibrates at 180.
So all this, you know, hoopla, all the
demonstrators, all the parades,
uh,
exploiting free speech in current
society.
You can have all kinds of sexual
perversions and have a parade about
them. I always thought I'd like to have
a flashers parade down Fifth Avenue.
And of course in a free country you can
go that into the nearest cathedral and
do that before the altar to give it
special appeal.
You can do anything you want. Free
that's freedom. So the freedom of the
flasher
and of course politics gives us endless
examples of all the things we're talking
about. Uh hanging
what's her name? Susan Sarah Palin
hanging an effigy.
Uh I thought was rather bad taste.
>> So did she.
>> Let's ask if we can calibrate.
hanging Mrs. Palin and and effigy
calibrates over 60
70 80 90
calibrates over 90 95 calibrates about
hanging cereal effigy calibrates about
so I can't get too excited about
people's free speech
when they express it in a consciousness
level that calibrates at 90
um which is frankly oh there's a there's
a phrase that's not popular in today's
culture. We should reawaken it.
Uh
that uh that's actually wickedness.
Wow. Okay.
So hiding under the
sheep's clothing of freedom
is actual evil in the form of
wickedness.
So we can't pretend it doesn't exist.
We can say we refuse to join it.
The failure to detect, diagnose
wickedness makes you prone to it.
resist.
All right. So the the failure of
discernment
to discern that which is which is truly
wicked and evil etc. means you then
become vulnerable to it because you
don't know what it is you're embracing.
You think you're embracing freedom of
speech. So the hangers of effigy
of that lady from Alaska
immediately came on television and began
hid behind freedom of speech, freedom of
expression, tried to justify what they
were doing. It was just fun. Just fun.
And they were lying resist.
They were lying. Resist. They were
merely gleefully acting out evil.
Resist.
Ah. So evil takes great glee in its own
demonstrations and expressions.
Yeah. So its core then is necess is
narcissism.
So the core of evil then is severe
Aha. You see Freud in the in the
unconscious
uh
postulated two primary energies.
life and death, aeros versus santos.
Well, we'll get to that later. But deep
in the deep in the unconscious, there
are two main drives.
One is for life, pro-life,
aeros, aeros is love, life and thantos
is death. So that which is evil
then has an attraction in the
unconscious of mankind.
That's your enemy.
The enemy is not out there. Your enemy
is that you give validity and power to
it because you project
your own death wish, your own worship of
evil and death onto the world.
Let's see if Freud was right. Let's see
if Freud was right.
Freud's uh Aeros was correct. Resist.
Freud's Thanotose was correct. Resist.
That's not the answer I wanted, but it's
the answer I get every time I
the joy of killing.
The joy and the fun of killing and
destroying
and uh attacking the PA.
Why would anybody want to attack the PA?
Uh because that which is beautiful
uh summons up hatred from evil.
That which is evil hates innocence and
beauty. Hates innocence and beauty.
That which is of lower consciousness.
I can remember
during uh being out at sea in the war
and we had victory records 78s were sent
to us by by somebody rather once every
six months we got some and we got these
new records and uh what I missed most
when I was in the service was uh things
like beautiful music etc. Well, anyway,
these 78s came and I looked through the
78s and there was the Zer the Largo from
Xerxes and I said, "Oh, wow." So, I
waited until 2 in the morning. I was on
watch all night and quietly up on the
upper deck. We had a Victrola and they
call them photographs nowadays, I guess.
Anyway,
I had a photograph and I quietly played
this 78 real low so only I could hear
it. incredibly be beautiful music you
know incredibly beautiful makes brings
tears to your eyes. So I felt saved by
you know just I like to hear this beauty
again. Uh it's like the one I used to
rebirth through. It was a anyway I can't
think of the name of it right now. So
anyway I carefully played this so nobody
would hear it. Well jeez the next day
somebody came up and said where's the
goddamn records and broke them. Yep.
He said, "We don't want any of that kind
of long hair music around here. We don't
want any of that kind of long hair music
around here."
So, beware long hairs.
A lot of people out there waiting to
bust your record.
But
screw up your uh computer. Yeah.
>> What?
What' you say?
>> It's time.
>> Time for what?
Time for lunch.
>> Oh, I just got started on the subject.
All right, I'll finish it within two
minutes. Uh,
free speech in the Bill of Rights. Free
speech in current society. You see, it
goes all the way down to 180. And, uh,
what I point out to people is is you
don't have to have a war between
chocolate and vanilla
because you can choose one without
becoming the enemy of the other. Just
because you choose chocolate doesn't
mean you have to hate vanilla.
And if you can choose vanilla and you
don't have to hate chocolate, right?
Yeah. Or with strawberry.
So you have choice. Is not necessary to
vilify its opposite. You don't have to
hate vanilla just because you love
chocolate. So, uh, I thank you very much
and we'll break. We'll have lunch and
I'll see you after your
God bless everyone. God bless everyone.
Is this mic on?
>> Mic's on.
>> The mic is on. Well, I better watch my
language.
Uhhuh. All right. We'll we'll resume
wherever we were.
Somebody knows where we were.
As long as somebody knows, I don't worry
about it.
Oh dear. Oh dear. Okay, honey. Is this
where we are? Right here. Yeah.
>> Um,
>> yep.
>> Number five. Charge five.
>> That says four. Okay. Okay. Oh, we No,
we did do five. Yes, we did do five.
Uhhuh.
Was
there anything more you want to say
about?
>> Well, you know, the struggle for moral
moral uh uh authority is uh very fierce.
In fact, you know, it's almost the basis
for war. It's almost the basis for war
uh to prove who has the moral
superiority.
And we see that in our dealings with the
Middle East, you know, who has
uh the morally superior position. And uh
you see that in the president of Iran
for instance, and it's all about who has
the moral high ground. The moral high
ground. Uh not about how many people are
going to die, but who's got the moral
high ground. Who's at fault? Who's at
fault? You know, that's interesting.
Yeah. So now we are up to
confusion of ideology with reality. Yes,
that's fine.
The the difficulty with uh
uh what's usually defined as the far
left is their confusion of an idea with
the actual reality in the world. that
one is an abstract uh concept and the
other is a literal reality.
Uh so a lot of times people get carried
away with the ideology
and the actual reality as is expressed
in the world uh is neglected.
Now the next things are more interesting
biologically. It's called constraint by
mirroring and the discovery which I've
mentioned in previous lectures that
there are uh mirror mirror mirroring
neurons within the brain. So that when
you watch something happen your mind is
also mirroring that and the neurons are
registering it
uh with a differentiation. There is a
differentiation in the neuron whether it
actually happened or you just witnessed
it. But you can practice the thing. So
if you want to learn how to do
something, you don't have to actually go
out and practice it. You can just
witness it. And if you watch it enough
times, you can go step right on the
dance floor and go
because you've watched it and now you've
like practiced it mentally. Uh that's a
very interesting phenomenal phenomena
and of course the mirroring can be uh
positive or negative. So you can also
get negatively mirrored. Uh so you're
mirroring you're watching behavior which
is not beneficial
but your mind will direct you to do the
most familiar thing. So mirroring means
that your neurons are becoming familiar
with the whole thing. So if you watch
somebody shoot a game of billiards,
uh you can learn, you can become better
at it by merely watching. So if you keep
watching uh somebody do, you know, two
cushion billiards or three cushion
billiards, you get the whole feeling and
concept of two cushion, three cushion
uh billiards. So even though you've
never played billiards, uh you're better
at it than a person who's never
witnessed it. So witnessing is a way of
rehearsing.
Uh
mirroring therefore results also in
constraint and constraint. Uh because
that which you mirror may also be on the
positive uh beneficial uh uh human side.
All of this results that there is a
biologic foundation of ethical concern
for others. This is relatively recent
discovery
in maybe the last 20 years. The
importance of it biological foundation
of ethical concern for others. So merely
being uh ethical other people learn by
witnessing your ethical behavior.
So ethical concern for others is not
just religion or just not uh taught
morality but it's imitative.
So I think that's a very interesting way
in which we we call learning by example
serving by example.
Uh certainly uh in the military I
remember uh it was very important you
know people behaved in a certain way and
without even thinking about it you
behaved in exactly the same way. uh what
was integrous and what was
uh loyalty to your brothers uh in in the
service. Uh so we picked that all up
without even thinking about it. And this
is interesting because it has a biologic
foundation. Uh are all of you fa
familiar with the macak monkey
phenomena?
How many are not? Oh dear. Oh dear. Oh
dear. Oh dear. That's
poor Makcock monkeys.
Well to see to see whether you know
morality and ethics is just a just a an
intellectual or spiritual or religious
phenomena
is very interesting is find like
mirroring. It's it's embedded in a
mamalian species. The macock monkey
experiment is you have two cages of
macock monkeys. Now, in this cage here,
if he pushes this button, he gets a
small amount of food. If he pushes this
button, he gets a large amount of food.
So, the macak monkey quickly learns this
one gives you a larger amount of food.
Left to his own devices, the macak
monkey will always push the big more
food lever. You get three cheeseburgers
here and you get one slim hamburger
here. So, he goes for the three
cheeseburgers.
Now you put another monkey in another
cage right next to this macock monkey.
And every time this macock monkey pushes
the big wind lever and gets a bigger
one, a cheeseburger by example, the
monkey in the next cage gets an electric
shock.
So he pulls down the lever to get this
big pile of food and he and it the
monkey in the next page gets a painful
shock.
Very quickly, the macak in this cage
will stop pulling the big lever even
though it gives him far more food that
he likes better and he'll satisfy
himself with the lesser one
so that his partner does not get
shocked. Isn't that interesting? Macock
monkeys then show greater human
compassion
than many people do.
But that's interesting because of the
discovery of oxytocin and the part that
it plays with the endorphins that are
released in the brain by spiritual
energy.
We have that it's rooted in biology.
So isn't that something? Makock monkey
will not let his little let his uh
partner get shocked if he can avoid it.
Will actually take less and prevent his
little brother as not his brother but
the other monkey even though he's a
stranger doesn't want his other to be
shocked. So we certainly have that gives
hope for humankind does it not?
So there's a certain inborn morality,
a biologic morality. So that sort of
closes the escape hatch of not knowing
any better. Yes, you know, you do know
better. And even a monkey knows better
than to inflict pain on another being
unnecessarily
unless forced to do so.
And this oxy. So when with spiritual
evolution one becomes more right brain
the spiritual energy condundalini energy
it's been called classically flows up
the chakra system flows into the right
brain and and releases endorphins
which changes one's pain level. So in a
botific state you can go through surgery
without anesthesia and I've done it a
couple of times go through surgery
without anesthesia
and feel myself lifted like almost out
of the body into a beatotific state and
when the surgery was over I was like
disappointed to have to come back in
like come back into the body into a
normal state out of a votific
But once one is lifted out of the
physical body, one's ether atheric body
is lifted out of the physical body by
the angels.
I have permission to ask that. That's
what I experienced when they took the
thumb off. Resist. Yes. So I went
through surgery twice without
anesthesia.
And uh the first time, as I say, I'd
never been through it before. I had no
idea what was going to happen. And I
just kept surrendering it to God.
surrendering it to God and I went into I
was like several feet above the body in
a beatotific state and uh in fact when
the surgery was over and I had to come
back in the body I was like disappointed
back in the saddle again huh
so what we're saying is that there
really isn't any excuse people can't
really say well I didn't know any
better. Uh that's a lie. You do know
better. You know that that which causes
pain and suffering the fellow human
beings. You do know that because even a
monkey knows it. Uh therefore all the
that throws all the rationalizations out
the wind window.
Uh we already checked out Freud. You
know you you know everybody familiar
with Freud's concepts about the
structure of the human psyche.
Uh the id being uh the animal instincts.
Uh the superego is one's conscience and
the ego is that part of your
consciousness which deals with reality.
Uh so the id is the part that the animal
instincts and we can deny them and
repress them but they then tend to uh
emerge under more disguis disguises and
get projected onto the world and a
fraudian psychoanalysis is a very
extremely educative
phenomena
and uh I've told before the story I was
in psychoanalysis for years and my
analyst was analyzed by uh I forget his
name now anyway whose analyst was Freud.
So Freud was my grandfather.
Abraham Cardner. Yes. So my analyst was
analyzed by Abraham Cardner whose
analyst was Sigman Freud.
So sigman Ford was like great grandpa
and u all these things can be poo pooed
in theory but experientially it's quite
different. Anybody here been through
psychoanalysis classic analysis? It used
to be the thing to do at least in the
upper east side of Manhattan.
The intellectuals hung out. So, uh, who
you were socially depended on who your
analyst was.
And your analyst was either on the east
side, the upper east side, or on the
west side. And if you were really
elitist, your analyst was in the upper
east, east 80s. So, so my analyst was
East 86 Street. So, that made me better
than other people.
Uh so it's a very demanding very
demanding
and I've still you know people you know
is Freudian is it theory people
throw out the theory because they they
don't understand the difference between
theory and reality.
So people who poo poo psychoanalysis, I
tell them, well, why don't you just lay
down on the couch there?
Tell me everything goes through your
mind
instantly.
The anxiety comes up.
The anxiety comes up. I had a laugh. I
had one patient one time, my office,
looked down in the parking lot behind
the office building, and there's a new
patient and I saw a car come in the
exit. This was the entrance this way and
the exit this way. and the car came in
the exit and parked right behind my
office. So I looked out the window and I
see this guy get out. So I says, he
says, 'I'm here for psychoanalysis. And
I said, 'Well, just lay down on the
couch. So he laid down on the couch and
he put his feet up towards me and his
head at the other end.
It was so funny. I could hardly keep
keep from laughing.
Oh yeah. So Freud postulated these two
primary two primary instincts because if
you watch carefully you'll see people
are very entranced by death. I mean
after the French Revolution I forget
14,000 people were guillotined
and millions watched it just fascinated
watching somebody die watching their
head get cut off. So people are just
fascinated by death in all of its. So
that's the attraction of death, you
know, both conscious and unconscious.
Yeah.
The next one we're going to talk about
the herd instinct, the roar of the
crowd.
And the last elections really uh, you
know, were characterized by the herd
instinct and the roar of the crowd. You
would see a politician go out and and go
like this and the whole crowd, thousands
of people. So, it's like, you know,
thousands of high school basketball
students,
and I thought, these are adults deciding
who's going to run the most powerful
country in the world. And everybody was
like a 14-year-old basketball game
cheering and jumping around.
I don't know how cheering and jumping
around is going to save the world, but
anyway, I thought it was interesting.
the herd instinct, the the roar of the
crowd and the attraction of the arena.
And of course, the way the old uh Roman
Empire, Roman emperors kept the people
happy was by putting on grand displays
in the coliseum,
uh fights to the death, gladiators,
fights to the death, having criminals
torn to pieces by lions and all. And I
and I thought life hasn't really changed
that much.
We can hang up what's her name Palin by
her neck, you know, and every people out
there cheering. The cheer of the crowd
is still the same. And we're just about
this far away from the Roman coliseum,
not very far away. And if they didn't
make it illegal, electrocutions, I'm
sure, would be public and everybody
would sign up in advance.
the roar of the crowd and that's what
drives people on to do uh great deeds
also the roar of the crowd. So it can
have a positive influence uh when it
when it's used judiciously.
We were going to talk today about if we
have time later about the pursuit of the
make wrong. One way to victory in in
today's world especially the media world
is the make wrong. Uh and therefore
there's a lot of competition for making
the other person wrong.
uh they make them wrong because of what
they wear or what their mother-in-law
did or because of a um a distant cousin
being arrested in adolescence. The
pursuit of the make wrong is voracious.
I think they they they mentioned in the
recent election, you know, the pile of
people that piled into Alaska to look
for micro mic wrongs
make wrongs the time you were naughty in
third grade or something. Anything will
do. Uh anything will do. But you see,
it's the attraction, the pursuit of it.
So people who are spiritually evolved
become more sophisticated. They see
they're being manipulated. So the thing
that we need to wake up to is that these
these you're being manipulated by all
this. You're being controlled by all of
it. Uh you're being made a fool by all
of it. And so we program you to behave
and think and feel in a certain way and
then we can turn it into money on
election day. So who wins the election
actually? Who has the most money? Isn't
that so? All you have to do is buy $150
million a week worth of advertising and
you brainwash everybody into push this
button, push this button, push this
button with the roar of the crowd,
beep beep beep beep. We out to vote. The
vote beep beep beep beep beep
turns us all into heeps.
Oh, pursuit of the make wrong. So,
making others wrong is u and this is it
calibrates close to injustice
collectors. And justice collecting is
also rivalous. Who's been done wrong the
most for the longest time even if you
have to go back centuries? Well, my
ancestors were made wrong by so and so.
Um, everybody's ancestors here
uh were once made wrong. Yeah.
Everybody's ancestors here were once
slaves. We've mentioned this in previous
lectures. Some people got a resentment
because I was removing a mink wrong from
them
and they were hugging this injustice to
themselves about what had gone on
hundreds of years ago in other
generations.
And we tra trace back out the role of
slavery in human life. Uh every the
ancestors of every person in this room
were slaves. Resist. Every single person
in this room, your ancestors were
slaves. It's just a matter how many
generations you go back. In ancient
Greece and Athens and Rome, uh the
number of free citizens were only
one/tenth. Nine out of 10 people were
slaves. A free person who owned his own
who was who owned him his own self was
only one out of 10. So nine out of 10
were owned by the country. You did not
own yourself. The emperor owned you.
So that that just casts a different
light on it to see a lot of phenomena as
part of the evolution of human
consciousness. Not so it's not a matter
of being right or wrong. It's not a
matter of injustice. It's a matter of
historical
ev development through human evolution.
So the freedom of the individual c
citizen
is a really very relatively recent
development in human society.
Uh we as ordinary citizens became free
only very very recently in human
evolution.
Uh
now the uh current we we were talking
about the willingness to sell your soul
to win and uh I don't know you you know
Dr. Fostus the opera of Dr. Fostess
uh I always ask people have you ever
seen the opera Dr. Fostess? I know it
once you see Dr. Fausis, it somehow by
its theatrical impact gets across to you
the difference between
uh in integrity and honesty and and
dishonesty. The narcissistic endeavor
for power over others and money and
influence.
And although people hypothetically know
there's a cost to this, they don't
actually really know it. And but it ends
up as karmic propensities. So all of us
are born with karmic propensities.
Every human being is born with karmic
propensities. This every human being
nobody escapes it. Wow.
Everyone is born with certain
propensities. So I karma is not
determinative.
Karma doesn't does not decrease your
freedom. Does not order you to do
certain things.
But it increases the likelihood.
And so therefore, it's a dominance of
propensities.
Uh with a certain kind of karma, your
propensity
is to make the other person wrong. With
a different kind of karma, your
propensity is to to find an excuse for
the other person.
And um
you then you you may be looked at as
wishy-washy. But anyway, my propensity
is is to constantly try to see the
innocence of people even when they're in
the middle of a holdup.
I said, "Look, the guy can't help
himself. Look on the neighborhood. They
all carry guns. They all have to rob.
You know, he needs money for drugs. You
know what else can I do?"
Isn't that true? I tend to rationalize
that behavior. H
>> all the time.
>> All the time. Yeah. Right. I mean, I
would, you know, poor Hitler Adolf. Poor
Adolf. I'd find some reason.
Poor Adolf. Poor Adolf. Couldn't help
getting to be the way he was. And then
I'd look back psychologically why Adolf
was the way he was. And although I don't
choose Adolf's way, I would still say,
well, you know, Adolf couldn't help.
Wasn't his name Suggle Gruber?
>> Yes.
>> So that's enough right there.
It really was name.
>> His name was Adolf Shlegruber. Yes.
>> Yes. They wrote mine comp and he uh he
changed it to Adolf Hitler. Condensed it
to Adolf Hitler. Yeah.
>> What was it again?
>> Shickle Gruber.
>> I'm not He was born Adolf Shick Gruber.
He better not slur it. No, it sounds
like Gilgar.
But he wrote uh minec and uh became very
famous eventually. He wrote it while he
was in prison. So many great uh
pieces of literature were written in in
prison. Uh and they foretold uh the
coming events. Yeah. And of course in
our lifetime we got to see them unfold.
But I could see that you know Hitler
called upon God all the time. And if you
watch, you know, he was a spellbinder.
Uh he would have been in the days of
television nowadays, he he would have
won all elections
100 to zero. He was a great spellbinder.
And he and he would say all these things
in the name of God.
So calling forth the authority for your
belief systems in the name of God then
is uh a human frailty. And of course we
see it done now again the same as in
Hitler's time to justify extreme
violence towards others. Yeah. So
uh
in the name of God then is
is utilized by some of the world's
religions to justify.
So you can kill all kinds of harmless
people including children.
So I found it a little hard to take
their blowing up 3,000 children at a
time, you know, in the name of God.
blowing up whole bus loads of children
and considering themselves brave heroes
to have done so I find that was a little
little difficult to take you know to
handle uh even though you understand how
they've been brainwashed. So what
happens how does this come about? It
doesn't come about naturally. It comes
about through indoctrination
otherwise you would the macak monkey
phenomena would would hold you back. The
Makock monkey phenomena would say you
can't I cannot do this. Uh I cannot blow
up this bus load of children. But by
indoctrination this can be overruled.
This can be overruled. So you can
brainwash people overrule
even their biologic uh capacity to
mirror others and show compassion.
So you have to destroy the compassion in
others. So we see cultures in which that
which is uh has a waggy tail
and that which purr
and women are all put down and enslaved.
There are certain cultures in which dogs
with a waggy tail are considered
unclean. Kitties that purr and women
with their softness and their loveliness
are enslaved enslaved
and therefore if a woman gets raped she
is put in prison in Pakistan as I said
the prisons are full of women who are
raped. So the denunciation of that which
is soft, loving, lovely,
endearing
from that viewpoint is considered a
weakness. Just like the Japanese in
World War II, the thing that was scary
about them, not only were they great
fighters,
but they they accepted no surrender.
So surrender was so ignaminious that
they would rather die than surrender and
they did. But that's why they were
scary. Kamicazi you knew he was going to
keep coming even though the 20 mm and
aircraft guns was blowing all around
him. You know he was going to keep
coming. So that was scary. What was
scary was that it's almost like demonic
almost a demonic taking over of normal
human compassion. normal human
compassion.
So if the macak monkey has it then you
have descended below the level of a
macock monkey
uh to override it. Let's see what a
macock monkey calibrates at. A macock
monkey calibrates over 20 30 40 50 60 70
75 80.
Macock monkey calibr
over 70
75 778
>> 80
>> 79 80 mak monkey monkey is around 79.
Yeah. Well, I owned a macock monkey and
uh
it
I owned a Makok monkey. I had a South
South American honey bear
who had a long tail and I lived by
myself and I had this this South
American honey bear uh in a cage hanging
over the bathtub from a hook and um this
South American honey beer, a kinkaju,
the kinkaju's little face got a little
sad and his eyes got pretty uh dim
looking and his fur got listless and uh
he was not happy. So I knew I said,
"Uhoh, he's lonely." So I went out and I
bought a macock monkey. And I put that
in another cage and put that in another
hook over the bathtub. So I was living
alone in this apartment. Here was a
macock monkey hanging one over the
bathtub from this end
and a South American honey bear from the
other. And they hated each other.
And so the South American honeybe So the
macak monkey uh would pick up everything
and throw throw it throw it at the honey
bear. The honey bear has a long tail.
Really a cute little animal. And the
monkey would just throw things and pull
it back your teeth and snarl. And the
South American honey bear thrived. His
coat got all shiny again and his
appetite picked up and his eyes weren't
glassy anymore. So it's like
biologically we always need the
stimulus. So you say well maybe all the
war in the world is stimulating the
appreciation of peace and beauty and the
maternal. See because the the the p the
contrast the paternal and the maternal
uh the maternal is like socialists. It's
like uh the maternal the mother feeds
all the children equally equally and the
paternal paternalistic
is uh rewarding for good behavior. You
don't get paid unless you turn out a
product. You don't get a uh you don't
get your cookies and your allowance if
you didn't perform. So the paternalistic
is more the conventional you might say
ultra-conservative. you only get if you
produce.
And uh them the maternal is more like
classically socialism. Everybody gets
supported no matter what and uh gets a
pay paycheck every month even if they're
in prison at the time.
And they worry about the voting rights
of prisoners. Here's a guy in there for
stabbing six people to death, rapving
his mother-in-law, theft and thievery
and drug dealing. And they're worrying
about his getting the vote.
Worrying about his right to vote.
Uh yes. Okay. That's what you call an
ideologist. It cannot differentiate the
the idea of freedom and equality from
all from the reality of when it is
really grossly inappropriate and not
really applicable. You know what I'm
saying? I don't know that I want to
trust the judge moral judgment of a guy
who's in there for uh kidnapping and
three three murders as well as burglary
and drug dealing.
And then I I was supposed to value his
vote in the presidential election
in presidential election. It's
hysterical.
So that's the confusion then of
the ideational with the with the real is
it takes it out of context. So a sense
of reality then is
not just content but content within a
certain context.
And we had a chart a slide we were going
to show this morning but we ran out of
time on the relationship between content
and context.
The sophisticated person above 200
realizes that morality depends on not
just on content but on the context.
So whether certain things are ethical or
not
cannot be answered when separated from
the context in which they went on. So we
gave as an example in previous lectures
that which is unethical in peace and war
cannot be compared because there the
context is differently whether the
government can check your email or not
is against uh human American tradition
in times of peace in times of war
whether there's somebody set to blow up
your entire city
then that's a different context. So
what's immoral in one context becomes
moral or even necessary in another. So
you might say the government would be
negligent to not do so in a time of war
in an electronic age when all the
communication of what's about to get
blown up and who's going to blow it up
is transmitted electronically
that the government to be moral would be
ethically required to monitor such
things to safeguard the life of the
citizens.
So whether a thing is true or false,
whether it's moral or immoral, whether
it's ethical cannot be decided
unless you state in what context
you see in what context is this. So in
what context is this moral or immoral?
The confusion of ideology with its
actual reality in human existence
is a refinement.
Now
having said that we we are perhaps more
able to
um allow others to differ from us.
It's all right to for others to differ
with us. I always say everybody has the
right to be wrong.
All of the people who disagree with
everything I'm saying have a perfect
right to do so.
Who are they?
Camera. Camera. Camera. The cameras are
flashing. And we'll of course compare
that later and find out who you are.
See that it's reported to the proper
authorities.
the value freedom. Then we see that all
of life is beautiful. All of life is
divine.
So we stop picking that this is holier.
This is more beautifuler. This is more
anything than anything else. We see
eventually what dawns on us as an
illumination from inside
is
the
beauty and perfection. uh of all that
exists and it comes as a revelation much
like the light came into the room uh
when you realize the divinity of all
that exists.
I remember going through what has been
classically called the final doorway of
in which I laid down as a barrier
between myself and the realization of
God
um existence itself life and I gave I
said the one thing I have not
surrendered to God is life itself that I
still have the illusion that I I am the
source of my the ongoingness of my life
and So I lay that down. And as I lay
down, owning myself is the source of
life, a great terror overcame me.
Probably the worst anxiety I've ever
experienced.
It was terror at a great existential
depth.
And to get through it was was almost
impossible. I'd seen a couple of people
been through it. I saw Jesus Christ went
through it. I saw Buddha went through
it.
You could see the few people who have
been through. It was like a high pass
and I began to pull back from it and as
I say a terror of great great extent a
greater terror than I had ever
experienced before and then came forth a
teaching from within my knowingness.
This too is illusion. All fear is
illusion. And I surrendered this fear
that if I let go only myself is the
source of ex existence and life uh that
I would expire forever die forever. So
the terror of non-existence existence
versus non-existence
uh arose and I put my faith in those
that knowingness. I put my faith in the
absolute knowingness.
All fear is illusion. All fear is
illusion. All fear is illusion. So I put
my faith in that premise.
Thank God it was true.
At the time you didn't know whether it
was true. You only had faith in whether
it was true. And the faith came from the
power of the knowingness.
So what does an advanced guru teach?
What happens with the with those of
advanced teaching is that knowingness is
conveyed via
via the the atheric body, the energy
field of the knowingness of the teacher
to the atheric body of the student.
Not the content of it had nothing to do
with that, but the absolute faith and
conviction and power of it. So somewhere
in past lives, there had been a teacher
of an extraordinarily high caliber
because the knowingness was like
concrete and cement that I could trust
it. But even then as I turned my life
over uh to this this teaching that all
feel all fear is illusion. And I let go.
I let go. I stopped holding back. And
the terror did arise. And the terror was
frankly to tell you severe. the terror
of throughout all the ages, all the
lifetimes, all the embodiment, all the
karmic evolutions
uh all came now to this one final point.
And so now
that came out of not out of memory but
out of the energy field of the
consciousness of the teacher. It comes
about as a nonlinear nonverbal
energy field which is in within the oh
it's within the aura of the teacher.
Yes. Okay. So that which we convey today
is within the aura field of the teacher
and it's an historic event.
So I tell you now
all fear is illusion.
I myself knew it. Then I lived through
the truth of it. And therefore I tell
you with the conviction above of the
absolute
that all fear is illusion.
No death is possible.
Thank you Lord God
for the
authority
to make this statement to these
students. So I take responsibility for
that statement.
I take responsibility for the truth of
And if I'm wrong,
I'll never admit it.
You'll be long gone dead. And you won't
even remember
who was that so that lied to me back
there.
My name will be obliterated in your
minds. And
some idiot back there somewhere said
all fear is illusion.
All fear is problematic. All fear is a
conjecture.
All fear is a conjecture. It's a
construction.
And now does the macak monkey transcend
this in is mirroring which now puts out
oxytocin in the right side of his brain.
He actually can will risk his life to to
save his friend here. Isn't that
amazing? He actually puts this thing
there would actually starve himself to
death would absolutely stop existing to
save his friend from suffering.
So we ask ourself
can we do at least what Macak monkey can
do
well to let go the ego to that extent.
Can we let go the ego to the point that
we can allow other people to live to
their fullest extent in the fullest
expression of that who they are and give
it to them as a gift. Give it to them as
a gift. That means we have to surrender
the maker wrong. We have to surren a
surrender the make wrong. I got to give
that up. Oh, I have to give up being
goodter than you. Oh no.
What about the pleasure of the maker
wrong? I mean people live on morongs.
They live they spend their whole life to
justify a maker wrong.
They'll go back from centuries of
history to find something in this life
they can justify to make wrong in this
lifetime even though it was 14
generations ago
on the other side of the world.
So that desperate scratching for a make
wrong. You see how the ego is frantic to
be right, frantic for moral superiority.
And of course in our world that's very
dangerous. You see Iran and its position
with the and various things like that in
which the make wrong and the the
jockeying for moralistic position is
really what requires uh
diplomatic craft to me is how to keep
the other person from getting into the
corner where anything can be interpreted
as a make wrong. So without making them
wrong which would
trigger
a war even how do you uh work
diplomatically? So to me international
diplomacy
is the most interesting of all human uh
or everyday um concerns. how to maneuver
safely in a sea uh in which every little
thing now becomes magnified and any one
of them can trigger a war. And the only
reason I worry about war now is because
of an it's now atomic war and it was bad
enough in World War II but now in an
atomic war civilizations can be
destroyed.
So we as spiritually committed people
by our own spiritual dedication tend to
uplift the world. And as we we uplift
the world not by what we say, not by
what we do, but by what we have become
that we turn down all the payoffs to
feel better than to make the other
people wrong. And we reinforce our
awareness of the inner innocence of all
that lives.
All that live are innocent. Even within
wicked wickedness,
there is the core of innocence.
As we explained karmically in the garden
of Eden,
the temptation was uh I miss I interpret
it differently than the Old Testament
that Eve did not fall for that that what
what happened with Eve was that she not
did not in and Adam they did not defy
God but instead the serpent was aware of
the underlying innocence the inner child
the inner child within Adam and Eve that
Eve
trusting like a little child trust his
mother. Trusted the serpent says, "Trust
me, trust me, trust me." And Eve uh
trusted the serpent.
Uh the other interpretation is that God
knows about the weakness and
vulnerability of that in a sense and
therefore
uh four warns you not to disobey. So it
could be rationalized differently and
I'll ask him next time I see him.
God, what was it?
He'll tell me. So,
those who serve the Lord are served by
the Lord. Those who serve the Lord are
served by the Lord. Those who call upon
Jesus as their savior, Jesus be Jesus
becomes their advocate before the
father.
Those who call upon Krishna as the
highest uh our own Krishna says those
who call upon call upon me are dear to
me are dear to me you become
one with Jesus Christ with Krishna with
all the great beings. So when we call
when we pray to the Lord and we say
glory be to thee oh lord most high
gloria and excelsius deal the lord
cannot refuse
cannot refuse you
that is that is a fact
the lord cannot refuse you when you
worship the lord when you say unto thee
oh lord
All glory and thanks be now and forever.
The Lord God cannot refuse you. Cannot
refuse you.
Isn't that encouraging?
Anybody here doesn't want to believe
that God is the author of all existence?
Glory be to the Lord as the source of
our existence, also the source of our
salvation.
We give thanks for the great saviors of
time, the Buddha, the Jesus Christ, the
the great the great ones of of all time
because they speak for us before the
father. They speak for us before the
father. And if I make any mistakes, if
any of the teachings I've taught in
these classes is in error, I promise
you, I will speak for you before the
father that it was my teaching, my
error, my shortcoming
uh to own to own the source of the error
uh is here.
And uh so that's what we ask of a
spiritual teacher that we don't ask the
commitment of the student to the
teacher. We ask the commitment of the
teacher to the student.
A classic is you're supposed to worship
the teacher and bringing him all kinds
of things like this and pack stack it up
around him.
Now true guru doesn't need anything from
you. Why would you need your money and
your agilation and your worship and your
flowers and your fruits and all such
being complete and total in yourself the
teacher had has no needs whatsoever.
No, the obligation is but from the
teacher to the student from the teacher
to teach this the truth to the highest
level he is capable of teaching. So the
commitment is from the teacher to the
student and not the other way around.
And if it had been seen the other way
around, the number of people who become
enlightened over the generations would
have been greatly increased,
greatly increased
that the teacher dedicates
all that he he has uh to the student. So
therefore, I cons commit myself to your
to you and to your spiritual evolution.
And that's the moral responsibility of
the teacher.
Did you have any questions you wanted me
to cover before you stop?
>> Um, yes.
>> Yes.
>> You had one on make wrongs.
>> Make wrong. Yes. Um, well, we we see the
the mileage that people get out of make
wrong. And of course in in family
relationships
uh family relationships, cousins and
siblings and aunts and uncles and all,
you hear the bitter recriminations that
go on
about how so and so forgot so and so's
birthday. Well, that was 10 years ago
and they're still talking about it. It's
like um you watch how families want to
juice the make wrong. Uh because then
you get to be sort of the moral superior
position. Somehow if you've been made
wrong, now you're morally superior.
So if you your ancestors are not served
right, then you are now morally superior
because of what happened to your
ancestors. Or if you forgot your
mother-in-law's birthday. So
we we watch how the it's the human ego.
It's not we as people we as people don't
decide we're going to do this. It's
downside of of human nature. The
limitation not downside the limitation
of human nature is to try and seek
advantage in everything.
juice everything for the advantage to be
more important and uh
moral superiority is what the world is
willing to die for
a make wrong they'll bomb you out of
existence.
Therefore, it's a very powerful
attraction. Of course, it's a
narcissistic attraction, but it's an
extremely powerful one. The desire to
make wrong, you you'll hear it all day
long on the television. We've heard it
all all day long for a couple years now
till we finally got this stupid election
over with. I couldn't wait till the
election was over because I can't stand
listening to this hour after hour and
the same name repetitively over and over
on the television and the same dialogue.
Uh all of it designed to do a makelog
and make longing to get one leg up. So
to be morally one leg up seemed to be
the core of the whole political
competition, wasn't it? Who's the most
holy and who's the most uh deserving and
uh who done me wrong?
Who' done me wrong? And you see they
resort to the most petty things to try
and get that little little edge of moral
rectitude. you know, who paid for your
clothes or something of incredible uh
idiocy actually
trying to trying to squeeze a little
moral superiority.
Uh
so compassion then when we say
compassion for the human condition, what
is the compassion about? Uh the
compassion is about the degree to which
the narcissistic core of the pe of
people enslaves them.
What I feel sad about is the degree to
which the narcissistic core of the ego
dominates people, destroys their life,
destroys their happiness and leads to
death and destruction, sickness
suffering, war and nuclear annihilation.
man is then is victim of uh Jesus said
the only sin is one of ignorance.
Ignorance of what? Ignorance of the
degree to which the ego and the bottom
side of the ego which Freud you know
called the id dominates human
consciousness
the awareness of it. So it's easier to
forgive when you see people are
controlled by that and that they really
have no awareness of why they are doing
that and they rationalize it. you know
why they think they're doing that kind
of behavior, but in truth they do not
know,
didn't they? I think Jesus said that
himself, didn't he said in truth they do
not know. You or the Buddha, some
big-timer anyway, said
>> some big time.
>> Well, in truth, they do not know. In
truth, they do not know. If they knew
and were conscious and aware, they would
not do that. But be the reason you need
compassion is because of ignorance. Out
of ignorance they do not know. And
therefore
even as people blow up innocent
children, you say how can you have
compassion for blowing up 300 children
uh for the people who blow up these
innocent children?
Because you can see the limitation of
the consciousness of the bomber who
naively believes that he's doing this
for God. For God is destroying the
infidels
and is a warning for those who haven't
who didn't hear it.
As a warning for you who haven't heard
it, you you cannot kill infidels
and unless they've refused.
Therefore, when Bin Laden, when was it
about a year or two ago,
>> invited America to convert to Islam,
when he invited you to convert to Islam,
your refusal to do so or your failure to
do so
means that Islam is now justified in
killing you all.
Everyone in this room, it's now okay to
kill you.
For it to be okay, you have to first
invite others.
Those who are unfamiliar with what I'm
talking about, you read the Quran. The
Quran will tell you,
invite your brother to convert, and if
he refuses, chop off his head. It's your
duty to Allah. Your duty to Allah is to
chop off the head of infidels.
Duty.
So I don't want to disillusion people
about the innocence of what they're up
against.
It is truly innocence. It is truly
innocence because
they're taught to believe this from
childhood. So the biggest threat we we
we face right now nuclear annihilation
will would come via people who think
that way.
But the reason I think I wrote about it
in a recent book that uh the thing
people missed about his message was when
he invited America to become
Islam to convert to Islam.
>> Uh
that opened the door for those who did
not to be annihilated.
And therefore when I say
uh be be compassionate towards the
beliefs of others but it doesn't mean
you have to necessarily join them. You
can respect the beliefs and I have great
respect for Islam. Great respect for it.
Great respect. Great respect doesn't
mean you have to join them and close
your eyes and become blind to that which
is obvious.
Uh, so survival is the name of the human
game and I put my two cents worth in for
human survival.
>> All of you on the side of human
survival. Hey. Hey. Hey. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
Okay.
>> We'll pass the basket.
>> It's 3:00.
>> It's 3:00 and we're going to stop and do
what?
>> We're going to take we're going to take
a quick break. Yes.
>> And then we'll resume with question and
answers. Um for questions, if you'll
line up on this side of the auditorium
for any books or other things you want
signed, please line up on this side. Um
also, it's been brought to my attention
that there is um the Buddha relics are
also going to be in Albuquerque the 5th,
6th, and 7th of December. And if you'd
like to know where if it's coming to
your city, um you can go online, I
guess, to Buddhy Buddha Relics and uh
look it up because they have a whole
schedule.
They have a whole schedule as to when um
they'll be arriving. So they're they're
traveling all around at this time here
in the US. So um if you get a chance to
see them, please do so.