bless
bless you
bless you all
bless you all in
bless you all in the
bless you all in the name
bless you all in the name of
bless you all in the name of the
bless you all in the name of the Lord.
Amen.
Glory
Glory and
Glory and excelsius
Glory and excelsius deal.
Glory
Glory be
Glory and excelsius deal.
Glory be to
Glory be to thee,
Glory and excelsius deal.
Glory be to thee, oh
Glory be to thee, oh Lord
Glory and excelsius deal.
Glory be to thee, oh Lord most
Glory be to thee, oh Lord most high.
Amen.
And
And here
Amen.
And here we
And here we are.
Uh
here
here we
Uh
here we were.
Here
Here we
Here we was.
We
We was
Here we was.
We was here.
We was here. Ah,
Here we was.
We was here. Ah, look
We was here. Ah, look at
Here we was.
We was here. Ah, look at this.
We was here. Ah, look at this. We're
lined
lined up
lined up with
all
all the
lined up with
all the great
all the great benefits
lined up with
all the great benefits of
all the great benefits of society.
Divine
Divine drink
Divine drink diet
Divine drink diet Pepsi.
>> All right.
>> What?
>> What? What's
>> What? What's this
>> What? What's this here,
>> What? What's this here, honey?
>> For
>> For the
>> What? What's this here, honey?
>> For the books.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
>> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see. I
>> Oh, I see. I see.
>> Oh, I see. I see. Oh,
>> Oh, I see. I see. Oh, I'm
>> Oh, I see. I see. Oh, I'm sorry.
>> Pen.
>> Pen. Yes,
>> Oh, I see. I see. Oh, I'm sorry.
>> Pen. Yes, I
>> Pen. Yes, I have
>> Oh, I see. I see. Oh, I'm sorry.
>> Pen. Yes, I have a
>> Pen. Yes, I have a pen.
>> Oh, I see. I see. Oh, I'm sorry.
>> Pen. Yes, I have a pen. Mhm.
>> You
>> You put
>> You put this
>> You put this back
>> You put this back in
>> You put this back in there.
>> Use
>> Use this
>> You put this back in there.
>> Use this one.
>> No,
>> No, that's
>> No, that's a
>> No, that's a light
>> No, that's a light one.
>> No, that's a light one. No,
>> No, that's a light one. No, you
>> No, that's a light one. No, you gave
that
that to
>> No, that's a light one. No, you gave
that to me
that to me to
>> No, that's a light one. No, you gave
that to me to to
that to me to to write
>> No, that's a light one. No, you gave
that to me to to write down
that to me to to write down notes.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
>> Oh, I did.
>> Oh, I did. Yes.
>> This
>> This seems
>> Oh, I did. Yes.
>> This seems like
>> This seems like a
>> Oh, I did. Yes.
>> This seems like a bigger
>> This seems like a bigger table
>> Oh, I did. Yes.
>> This seems like a bigger table than
usual.
>> It's
>> It's over
usual.
>> It's over far
>> It's over far away.
usual.
>> It's over far away. It
>> It's over far away. It seems
usual.
>> It's over far away. It seems like
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I
>> Yes.
>> Okay. I really
>> Okay. I really don't
>> Yes.
>> Okay. I really don't have
>> Okay. I really don't have a
>> Yes.
>> Okay. I really don't have a question
>> Okay. I really don't have a question for
you.
you. It
you. It just
you. It just I'm
you. It just I'm very
you. It just I'm very nearsighted.
you. It just I'm very nearsighted. It
just
just was
you. It just I'm very nearsighted. It
just was very
just was very important
you. It just I'm very nearsighted. It
just was very important for
just was very important for me.
you. It just I'm very nearsighted. It
just was very important for me. She's
what?
>> Very
>> Very nearsighted.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, nearsighted.
>> Oh, nearsighted. Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And
>> Oh, nearsighted. Yes.
>> Yeah. And I
>> Yeah. And I wanted
>> Oh, nearsighted. Yes.
>> Yeah. And I wanted to
>> Yeah. And I wanted to get
>> Oh, nearsighted. Yes.
>> Yeah. And I wanted to get this
>> Yeah. And I wanted to get this close
>> Oh, nearsighted. Yes.
>> Yeah. And I wanted to get this close to
you
you and
you and be
you and be able
you and be able to
you and be able to look
you and be able to look you
you and be able to look you in
you and be able to look you in the
you and be able to look you in the eye
and
and to
you and be able to look you in the eye
and to tell
and to tell you
you and be able to look you in the eye
and to tell you how
and to tell you how much
you and be able to look you in the eye
and to tell you how much I
and to tell you how much I appreciate
what
what you
what you do.
>> What's
>> What's neared
what you do.
>> What's neared got
>> What's neared got to
what you do.
>> What's neared got to do
>> What's neared got to do with
what you do.
>> What's neared got to do with that.
I
I don't
I don't see
I don't see you
I don't see you at
I don't see you at all
I don't see you at all much
I don't see you at all much less
I don't see you at all much less than
nearsighted.
It's
It's a
It's a gray
It's a gray fuzz
It's a gray fuzz over
It's a gray fuzz over there.
>> Is
>> Is it?
It's a gray fuzz over there.
>> Is it? Is
>> Is it? Is it?
>> How
>> How are
>> How are you,
>> How are you, Gray
>> How are you, Gray Fuzz?
>> I'm
>> I'm doing
>> How are you, Gray Fuzz?
>> I'm doing just
>> I'm doing just great.
What
What can
What can I
What can I do
What can I do for
What can I do for you
What can I do for you today,
What can I do for you today, Lovey?
>> Uh,
>> Uh, just
What can I do for you today, Lovey?
>> Uh, just I'm
>> Uh, just I'm doing
What can I do for you today, Lovey?
>> Uh, just I'm doing it
>> Uh, just I'm doing it right
What can I do for you today, Lovey?
>> Uh, just I'm doing it right now.
>> Uh, just I'm doing it right now. I
What can I do for you today, Lovey?
>> Uh, just I'm doing it right now. I just
wanted
wanted to
wanted to be
wanted to be up
wanted to be up close
wanted to be up close to
wanted to be up close to you
wanted to be up close to you and
>> Oh.
>> Oh. Oh,
wanted to be up close to you and
>> Oh. Oh, okay.
>> And
>> And you
>> And you want
>> And you want me
>> And you want me to
>> And you want me to sign
>> And you want me to sign these
>> And you want me to sign these here?
>> Yes.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> Demands,
>> Demands, demands,
>> Demands, demands, demands.
Oh,
Oh, thank
>> Demands, demands, demands.
Oh, thank you
Oh, thank you so
>> Demands, demands, demands.
Oh, thank you so much.
So,
So, anyway,
So, anyway, I
So, anyway, I am
So, anyway, I am honored
So, anyway, I am honored by
So, anyway, I am honored by your
So, anyway, I am honored by your being
here.
>> Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you
>> Okay.
>> Thank you. Thank you very
>> Thank you. Thank you very much.
>> Who
>> Who are
>> Who are these?
>> Who are these? Honey,
do
do we
>> Who are these? Honey,
do we know
do we know who
>> Who are these? Honey,
do we know who these
do we know who these are?
>> Who are these? Honey,
do we know who these are? Who
do we know who these are? Who are
>> Who are these? Honey,
do we know who these are? Who are these?
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
>> I don't know.
>> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see. Okay.
>> I don't know.
>> Oh, I see. Okay. Just
>> Oh, I see. Okay. Just sign
>> I don't know.
>> Oh, I see. Okay. Just sign them
>> Oh, I see. Okay. Just sign them and
>> I don't know.
>> Oh, I see. Okay. Just sign them and be
still.
Just
Just do
still.
Just do as
Just do as I
still.
Just do as I say
Just do as I say and
>> Oh
>> Oh dear.
>> Oh dear. Oh
>> Oh dear. Oh dear.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Hi.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. How
>> Hello. How are
>> Hello. How are you?
>> Hello. How are you? I
>> Hello. How are you? I have
>> Hello. How are you? I have a
>> Hello. How are you? I have a question
about
about spiritual
>> Hello. How are you? I have a question
about spiritual practice.
about spiritual practice. I
>> Hello. How are you? I have a question
about spiritual practice. I think
um
um I've
um I've been
um I've been a
um I've been a student
um I've been a student for
um I've been a student for many
um I've been a student for many years
and
and lived
um I've been a student for many years
and lived in
and lived in a
um I've been a student for many years
and lived in a monastery
and lived in a monastery for
um I've been a student for many years
and lived in a monastery for quite
and lived in a monastery for quite a
um I've been a student for many years
and lived in a monastery for quite a few
years
years and
years and I've
years and I've come
years and I've come to
years and I've come to the
years and I've come to the conclusion
that
there's
there's a
there's a point
there's a point at
there's a point at which
all
all of
there's a point at which
all of that
all of that doesn't
there's a point at which
all of that doesn't matter
and
and what
and what there
and what there is
and what there is is
and what there is is just
and what there is is just to
and what there is is just to be
and what there is is just to be who
and what there is is just to be who I
and what there is is just to be who I am
as
as best
and what there is is just to be who I am
as best I
as best I can
and what there is is just to be who I am
as best I can be.
>> Yes.
>> Be
>> Be to
>> Yes.
>> Be to be
>> Be to be be
>> Yes.
>> Be to be be all
>> Be to be be all that
>> Yes.
>> Be to be be all that you
>> Be to be be all that you can
>> Yes.
>> Be to be be all that you can be
>> Be to be be all that you can be to
>> Yes.
>> Be to be be all that you can be to the
fullest.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. That
fullest.
>> Yes. That fulfills
>> Yes. That fulfills all
fullest.
>> Yes. That fulfills all the
>> Yes. That fulfills all the spiritual
work.
work. Yes.
Well,
Well, my
work. Yes.
Well, my my
Well, my my question
work. Yes.
Well, my my question is
Well, my my question is and
work. Yes.
Well, my my question is and one
Well, my my question is and one of
work. Yes.
Well, my my question is and one of the
ways
ways that
ways that I've
ways that I've tricked
ways that I've tricked myself
ways that I've tricked myself over
ways that I've tricked myself over the
years
years is
ways that I've tricked myself over the
years is I
years is I have
ways that I've tricked myself over the
years is I have a
years is I have a very
ways that I've tricked myself over the
years is I have a very smart
years is I have a very smart ego
ways that I've tricked myself over the
years is I have a very smart ego and
years is I have a very smart ego and I
can
can rationalize
can rationalize things
can rationalize things wonderfully.
So
So there's
can rationalize things wonderfully.
So there's that
So there's that there's
can rationalize things wonderfully.
So there's that there's been
So there's that there's been the
question
question of
question of whether
question of whether or
question of whether or not
question of whether or not that's
question of whether or not that's what
I'm
I'm doing,
question of whether or not that's what
I'm doing, the
I'm doing, the rationalization
versus
versus that's
versus that's in
versus that's in fact
versus that's in fact where
versus that's in fact where I
versus that's in fact where I have
reached
reached a
versus that's in fact where I have
reached a point
reached a point to
versus that's in fact where I have
reached a point to be
reached a point to be which
versus that's in fact where I have
reached a point to be which is
reached a point to be which is to
versus that's in fact where I have
reached a point to be which is to just
be
be now.
>> Uh
>> Uh to
be now.
>> Uh to to
>> Uh to to just
be now.
>> Uh to to just be
>> Uh to to just be should
be now.
>> Uh to to just be should keep
>> Uh to to just be should keep you
be now.
>> Uh to to just be should keep you fully
occupied.
occupied. Yes.
And
And if
occupied. Yes.
And if to
And if to be
occupied. Yes.
And if to be an
And if to be an idiot
occupied. Yes.
And if to be an idiot is
And if to be an idiot is uh
occupied. Yes.
And if to be an idiot is uh what
And if to be an idiot is uh what your
destiny
destiny is,
destiny is, then
destiny is, then be
destiny is, then be an
destiny is, then be an idiot.
destiny is, then be an idiot. I
destiny is, then be an idiot. I mean,
destiny is, then be an idiot. I mean, be
an
an idiot
destiny is, then be an idiot. I mean, be
an idiot to
an idiot to the
destiny is, then be an idiot. I mean, be
an idiot to the best
an idiot to the best of
destiny is, then be an idiot. I mean, be
an idiot to the best of your
an idiot to the best of your ability.
You
You asked
You asked me
You asked me what
You asked me what I
You asked me what I really
You asked me what I really know,
You asked me what I really know, I
couldn't
couldn't tell
You asked me what I really know, I
couldn't tell you.
You
You know what
You know what I
You know what I mean?
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So,
>> Yeah. So, that's
>> Yeah. So, that's the
>> Yeah. So, that's the uh
>> Yeah. So, that's the uh spiritual
>> Yeah. So, that's the uh spiritual idiot.
That
That the
>> Yeah. So, that's the uh spiritual idiot.
That the the
That the the phase
>> Yeah. So, that's the uh spiritual idiot.
That the the phase of
That the the phase of spiritual
>> Yeah. So, that's the uh spiritual idiot.
That the the phase of spiritual idiocy.
Uh,
Uh, what
Uh, what do
Uh, what do you
Uh, what do you know?
Uh, what do you know? I
Uh, what do you know? I don't
Uh, what do you know? I don't know.
Anything
Anything is
Uh, what do you know? I don't know.
Anything is a
Anything is a fact.
>> That's
>> That's what
>> That's what it
>> That's what it feels
>> That's what it feels like.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You
>> That's what it feels like.
>> Yeah. You know
>> Yeah. You know the
>> That's what it feels like.
>> Yeah. You know the Buddha
>> Yeah. You know the Buddha said,
>> That's what it feels like.
>> Yeah. You know the Buddha said, "So
>> Yeah. You know the Buddha said, "So I
have
have heard."
have heard." So
have heard." So I
have heard." So I have
have heard." So I have heard.
>> Remember
>> Remember you
have heard." So I have heard.
>> Remember you say
>> Remember you say that.
have heard." So I have heard.
>> Remember you say that. So
>> Remember you say that. So I
have heard." So I have heard.
>> Remember you say that. So I have
>> Remember you say that. So I have heard.
>> Yes.
>> Mhm.
So
So I
So I have
So I have heard.
Because
Because to
So I have heard.
Because to truly
Because to truly know
So I have heard.
Because to truly know is
Because to truly know is to
So I have heard.
Because to truly know is to be.
Because to truly know is to be. And
So I have heard.
Because to truly know is to be. And if
you
you are,
you are, there's
you are, there's no
you are, there's no questions.
I
I don't
you are, there's no questions.
I don't have
I don't have to
you are, there's no questions.
I don't have to ask
I don't have to ask the
you are, there's no questions.
I don't have to ask the cat,
I don't have to ask the cat, "Who
you are, there's no questions.
I don't have to ask the cat, "Who are
you?"
>> And
>> And the
you?"
>> And the cat,
>> And the cat, the
you?"
>> And the cat, the cat,
>> And the cat, the cat, I
you?"
>> And the cat, the cat, I asked
>> And the cat, the cat, I asked him,
you?"
>> And the cat, the cat, I asked him, I
said, "Who
said, "Who are
said, "Who are you?"
said, "Who are you?" He
said, "Who are you?" He says,
said, "Who are you?" He says, "Oh,
said, "Who are you?" He says, "Oh, I'm
I'm
I'm me."
said, "Who are you?" He says, "Oh, I'm
I'm me." Oh,
I'm me." Oh, okay.
That
That answered
That answered it
That answered it fully.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
That answered it fully.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
What
What is
>> Thank you.
What is this
What is this here?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> Oh, okay. Never
>> Oh, okay. Never mind.
I
I just
>> Oh, okay. Never mind.
I just thought
I just thought it
>> Oh, okay. Never mind.
I just thought it might
I just thought it might be
>> Oh, okay. Never mind.
I just thought it might be an
I just thought it might be an an
>> Oh, okay. Never mind.
I just thought it might be an an evil
spirit.
>> Speak
>> Speak evil
spirit.
>> Speak evil spirit.
>> Go
>> Go ahead.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Some
>> Go ahead.
>> Yes. Some se
>> Yes. Some se uh
>> Go ahead.
>> Yes. Some se uh about
>> Yes. Some se uh about seven
>> Go ahead.
>> Yes. Some se uh about seven years
>> Yes. Some se uh about seven years ago
>> Go ahead.
>> Yes. Some se uh about seven years ago uh
in
in front
in front of
in front of me
in front of me appeared
in front of me appeared rotating
in front of me appeared rotating energy
ball.
ball. little
in front of me appeared rotating energy
ball. little blackish
ball. little blackish and
in front of me appeared rotating energy
ball. little blackish and otherwise
non-visible.
non-visible. It
non-visible. It was
non-visible. It was rotating
non-visible. It was rotating very
non-visible. It was rotating very fast
and
and came
non-visible. It was rotating very fast
and came in
and came in front
non-visible. It was rotating very fast
and came in front of
and came in front of me
non-visible. It was rotating very fast
and came in front of me and
and came in front of me and went
non-visible. It was rotating very fast
and came in front of me and went into
and came in front of me and went into my
third
third eye
>> and
>> and since
third eye
>> and since then
>> and since then even
third eye
>> and since then even if
>> and since then even if I
third eye
>> and since then even if I close
>> and since then even if I close my
third eye
>> and since then even if I close my eyes
>> and since then even if I close my eyes I
see
see it
see it there
see it there like
see it there like a
see it there like a spider
see it there like a spider thing
rotating
>> and
>> and uh
>> and uh also
>> and uh also in
>> and uh also in dim
>> and uh also in dim light
>> and uh also in dim light in
>> and uh also in dim light in the
>> and uh also in dim light in the evening
it
it comes
>> and uh also in dim light in the evening
it comes close
it comes close and
>> and uh also in dim light in the evening
it comes close and is
it comes close and is very
>> and uh also in dim light in the evening
it comes close and is very fast
it comes close and is very fast rotating
becomes
becomes big
becomes big becomes
becomes big becomes small.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. And
becomes big becomes small.
>> Yes. And sometimes
>> Yes. And sometimes it
becomes big becomes small.
>> Yes. And sometimes it turns
>> Yes. And sometimes it turns into
becomes big becomes small.
>> Yes. And sometimes it turns into into
eye.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. What
eye.
>> Okay. What happens
>> Okay. What happens if
eye.
>> Okay. What happens if you
>> Okay. What happens if you uh
eye.
>> Okay. What happens if you uh smudge
>> Okay. What happens if you uh smudge the
space
space you're
space you're in?
space you're in? Bless
space you're in? Bless bless
space you're in? Bless bless it
space you're in? Bless bless it and
space you're in? Bless bless it and burn
incense.
>> Bless
>> Bless it
>> Bless it with
>> Bless it with incense.
>> Huh?
>> Bless
>> Bless it
>> Bless it with
>> Bless it with incense.
>> What?
>> No,
>> No, I
>> No, I I
>> No, I I didn't
>> No, I I didn't follow
>> uh
>> uh the
>> No, I I didn't follow
>> uh the space
>> uh the space the
>> No, I I didn't follow
>> uh the space the space
>> uh the space the space you're
>> No, I I didn't follow
>> uh the space the space you're living
>> uh the space the space you're living in.
>> If
>> If you
>> If you What
>> If you What happens
>> If you What happens if
>> If you What happens if you
>> If you What happens if you smudge
>> If you What happens if you smudge the
space
space you're
>> If you What happens if you smudge the
space you're living
space you're living in?
>> You
>> You know,
>> do
>> do you
>> You know,
>> do you know
>> do you know what
>> You know,
>> do you know what smudge
>> do you know what smudge means?
and
and and
and and to to
>> burn
>> burn incense
and and to to
>> burn incense and
>> burn incense and bless
and and to to
>> burn incense and bless the
>> burn incense and bless the place
and and to to
>> burn incense and bless the place in
>> burn incense and bless the place in the
name
name of
name of God
name of God and
>> and
>> and order
name of God and
>> and order you
>> and order you have
name of God and
>> and order you have the
>> and order you have the right
name of God and
>> and order you have the right to
>> and order you have the right to order
demons.
demons. I
demons. I or
demons. I or you
demons. I or you can
demons. I or you can order
demons. I or you can order them
demons. I or you can order them to
demons. I or you can order them to leave
and
and they
demons. I or you can order them to leave
and they must
and they must obey
demons. I or you can order them to leave
and they must obey you.
and they must obey you. Demons.
>> Oh
>> Oh yes.
>> Oh yes. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Have
>> Have you
>> Yes.
>> Have you ordered
>> Have you ordered the
>> Yes.
>> Have you ordered the demons
>> Have you ordered the demons out?
>> Yes,
>> Yes, I've
>> Yes, I've ordered
>> Yes, I've ordered that.
>> Yes, I've ordered that. Of
>> Yes, I've ordered that. Of course.
>> What?
>> She
>> She said
>> She said yes.
>> Yes.
>> You
>> You ordered
>> You ordered them
>> You ordered them out?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Oh,
and
and you
and you smudged
and you smudged the
and you smudged the place.
>> No,
>> No, you
and you smudged the place.
>> No, you didn't
>> No, you didn't do
and you smudged the place.
>> No, you didn't do that.
>> No,
>> No, I
>> No, I didn't
>> No, I didn't do
>> No, I didn't do that.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, I
>> No, I didn't do that.
>> Yeah, I would
>> Yeah, I would smudge
>> No, I didn't do that.
>> Yeah, I would smudge him.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Order
>> Order them
>> Uh-huh.
>> Order them out
>> Order them out in
>> Uh-huh.
>> Order them out in the
>> Order them out in the name
>> Uh-huh.
>> Order them out in the name of
>> Order them out in the name of Jesus
Christ.
>> Yes.
>> Which
>> Which you
>> Which you have
>> Which you have the
>> Which you have the right
>> Which you have the right to
>> Which you have the right to do
>> Which you have the right to do as
>> Which you have the right to do as a
follower
follower of
>> Which you have the right to do as a
follower of the
follower of the Lord.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And they
>> Yes.
>> And they must
>> And they must obey
>> Yes.
>> And they must obey you.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Hold
>> Hold in
>> Uh-huh.
>> Hold in mind
>> Hold in mind that
>> Uh-huh.
>> Hold in mind that they
>> Hold in mind that they must
>> Uh-huh.
>> Hold in mind that they must obey
>> Hold in mind that they must obey you.
They
They don't
They don't have
They don't have any
They don't have any choice
They don't have any choice of
They don't have any choice of in
They don't have any choice of in the
matter.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. Okay.
>> Mhm. Okay. Thank
>> Mhm. Okay. Thank you.
>> They
>> They have
>> Mhm. Okay. Thank you.
>> They have no
>> They have no choice
>> Mhm. Okay. Thank you.
>> They have no choice in
>> They have no choice in the
>> Mhm. Okay. Thank you.
>> They have no choice in the matter.
>> Mhm.
You
You see
>> Mhm.
You see uh
You see uh in
>> Mhm.
You see uh in in
You see uh in in Catholic
>> Mhm.
You see uh in in Catholic uh
You see uh in in Catholic uh or
Episcopal
Episcopal high
Episcopal high church
how
how during
Episcopal high church
how during the
how during the highest
Episcopal high church
how during the highest parts
how during the highest parts of
Episcopal high church
how during the highest parts of the
how during the highest parts of the uh
the
the service
the service the
the service the uh
the service the uh sensor
the service the uh sensor comes
the service the uh sensor comes up
the service the uh sensor comes up the
sensor
sensor comes
the service the uh sensor comes up the
sensor comes up
sensor comes up with
the service the uh sensor comes up the
sensor comes up with the
sensor comes up with the incense.
the service the uh sensor comes up the
sensor comes up with the incense. Are
are
are you
are you familiar
are you familiar with
are you familiar with that?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. So
>> Yes. So the
>> Yes. So the sensor
>> Yes. So the sensor blesses
>> Yes. So the sensor blesses the
>> Yes. So the sensor blesses the altar
>> Yes. So the sensor blesses the altar and
all
all that
>> Yes. So the sensor blesses the altar and
all that is
all that is around
>> Yes. So the sensor blesses the altar and
all that is around the
all that is around the altar
because
because that
because that which
because that which is
because that which is most
because that which is most divine
because that which is most divine is
most
most attractive
because that which is most divine is
most attractive to
most attractive to that
because that which is most divine is
most attractive to that which
most attractive to that which is
because that which is most divine is
most attractive to that which is not
divine.
divine. See
divine. See so
divine. See so they
divine. See so they so
divine. See so they so the
divine. See so they so the sensor
divine. See so they so the sensor you
know
know smudges
divine. See so they so the sensor you
know smudges the
know smudges the altar
divine. See so they so the sensor you
know smudges the altar and
know smudges the altar and the
divine. See so they so the sensor you
know smudges the altar and the place
know smudges the altar and the place of
the
the altar.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
When
When I
>> Yeah.
When I was
When I was a
>> Yeah.
When I was a boy,
When I was a boy, I
>> Yeah.
When I was a boy, I was
When I was a boy, I was a
>> Yeah.
When I was a boy, I was a boat
When I was a boy, I was a boat boy
>> Yeah.
When I was a boy, I was a boat boy and
When I was a boy, I was a boat boy and I
got
got I
got I was
got I was the
got I was the bishop's
got I was the bishop's boat
got I was the bishop's boat boy.
got I was the bishop's boat boy. So,
got I was the bishop's boat boy. So, I
carried
carried the
got I was the bishop's boat boy. So, I
carried the incense
carried the incense and
got I was the bishop's boat boy. So, I
carried the incense and when
carried the incense and when the
got I was the bishop's boat boy. So, I
carried the incense and when the bishop
needed
needed more,
needed more, his
needed more, his his
needed more, his his helper
needed more, his his helper took
needed more, his his helper took some
needed more, his his helper took some of
the
the incense
needed more, his his helper took some of
the incense and
the incense and poured
needed more, his his helper took some of
the incense and poured on
the incense and poured on the
needed more, his his helper took some of
the incense and poured on the burning
charcoal
charcoal and
charcoal and the
charcoal and the the
charcoal and the the incense
charcoal and the the incense and
charcoal and the the incense and the
charcoal
charcoal suffused
charcoal and the the incense and the
charcoal suffused the
charcoal suffused the whole
charcoal and the the incense and the
charcoal suffused the whole area,
charcoal suffused the whole area, the
cathedral
cathedral instead
cathedral instead of
>> So,
>> So, it
cathedral instead of
>> So, it isn't
>> So, it isn't just
cathedral instead of
>> So, it isn't just a
>> So, it isn't just a superstition,
cathedral instead of
>> So, it isn't just a superstition, it's
recognized.
recognized. Mhm.
>> That
>> That that
recognized. Mhm.
>> That that which
>> That that which is
recognized. Mhm.
>> That that which is divine
>> That that which is divine attracts
recognized. Mhm.
>> That that which is divine attracts that
which
which is
which is otherwise.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, I
which is otherwise.
>> Yes, I know
>> Yes, I know that.
>> And
>> And the
>> And the Buddha,
>> And the Buddha, the
>> And the Buddha, the Buddha,
>> And the Buddha, the Buddha, you
>> And the Buddha, the Buddha, you know,
was
was beset
>> And the Buddha, the Buddha, you know,
was beset by
was beset by demons.
>> Mhm.
>> Jesus
>> Jesus Christ
>> Mhm.
>> Jesus Christ sweat
>> Jesus Christ sweat blood.
>> Yes.
>> So,
>> So, in
>> Yes.
>> So, in a
>> So, in a way,
>> Yes.
>> So, in a way, it's
>> So, in a way, it's a
>> Yes.
>> So, in a way, it's a compliment.
>> Okay.
>> If
>> If the
>> Okay.
>> If the demons
>> If the demons are
>> Okay.
>> If the demons are seeking
>> If the demons are seeking you
>> Okay.
>> If the demons are seeking you out,
>> If the demons are seeking you out, it
must
must be
must be for
must be for good
must be for good cause.
It
>> must
>> must be.
>> must be. Of
>> must be. Of course.
>> Going
>> Going to
>> must be. Of course.
>> Going to vote
>> Going to vote you
>> must be. Of course.
>> Going to vote you out
>> Going to vote you out of
>> must be. Of course.
>> Going to vote you out of office
>> Going to vote you out of office if
>> must be. Of course.
>> Going to vote you out of office if they
can.
These
These are
can.
These are our
These are our books
can.
These are our books in
These are our books in German.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. They're
>> Oh, yeah. They're good.
>> And
>> And here's
>> Oh, yeah. They're good.
>> And here's the
>> And here's the course
>> Oh, yeah. They're good.
>> And here's the course of
>> And here's the course of miracles
>> Oh, yeah. They're good.
>> And here's the course of miracles in
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
>> Oh, I never
>> Oh, I never saw
>> Oh, I never saw it
>> Oh, I never saw it in
>> Oh, I never saw it in German.
>> Oh, I never saw it in German. Uhhuh.
>> Isn't
>> Isn't that
>> Oh, I never saw it in German. Uhhuh.
>> Isn't that wonderful?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Zood.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Yeah. Zood.
>> Okay. Thank you
>> Okay. Thank you very
>> Yeah. Zood.
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Wow.
Dr.
Dr. Dr.
>> Wow.
Dr. Dr. Hawkins,
Dr. Dr. Hawkins, first
>> Wow.
Dr. Dr. Hawkins, first off,
Dr. Dr. Hawkins, first off, I
>> Wow.
Dr. Dr. Hawkins, first off, I just
Dr. Dr. Hawkins, first off, I just want
to
to express
to express my
to express my heartfelt
to express my heartfelt gratitude
to express my heartfelt gratitude for
all
all your
to express my heartfelt gratitude for
all your teachings
all your teachings and
to express my heartfelt gratitude for
all your teachings and all
all your teachings and all that
to express my heartfelt gratitude for
all your teachings and all that all
all your teachings and all that all that
you
you offer.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> My
>> My wife
>> My wife is
>> My wife is undergoing
>> My wife is undergoing major
>> My wife is undergoing major surgery
>> My wife is undergoing major surgery next
week,
week, and
>> My wife is undergoing major surgery next
week, and I
week, and I was
>> My wife is undergoing major surgery next
week, and I was wondering
week, and I was wondering if
>> My wife is undergoing major surgery next
week, and I was wondering if there
week, and I was wondering if there was
one
one thought
one thought that
one thought that I
one thought that I could
one thought that I could hold
one thought that I could hold and
one thought that I could hold and help
her
her in
one thought that I could hold and help
her in her
her in her convolescence
one thought that I could hold and help
her in her convolescence and
her in her convolescence and her
one thought that I could hold and help
her in her convolescence and her speedy
recovery.
recovery. If
recovery. If there's
recovery. If there's something
recovery. If there's something that
resonates
resonates with
recovery. If there's something that
resonates with you,
>> I
>> I would
>> I would certainly
>> I would certainly ask
>> I would certainly ask you
>> I would certainly ask you and
>> I would certainly ask you and all
>> I would certainly ask you and all your
friends
friends uh
>> I would certainly ask you and all your
friends uh to
friends uh to pray
>> I would certainly ask you and all your
friends uh to pray for
friends uh to pray for her
>> I would certainly ask you and all your
friends uh to pray for her and
friends uh to pray for her and and
>> I would certainly ask you and all your
friends uh to pray for her and and hold
that
she
she is
that
she is blessed
she is blessed by
that
she is blessed by God
and
and that
and that whatever
and that whatever may
and that whatever may be
and that whatever may be you
and that whatever may be you surrender
to
to God.
I
I would
I would pray
I would pray for
I would pray for her
I would pray for her well-being
I would pray for her well-being and
I would pray for her well-being and ask
all
all my
I would pray for her well-being and ask
all my friends
all my friends to
I would pray for her well-being and ask
all my friends to pray
all my friends to pray for
I would pray for her well-being and ask
all my friends to pray for her
well-being.
We
We recently
well-being.
We recently pray
We recently pray pray prayed
well-being.
We recently pray pray prayed for
We recently pray pray prayed for about
four
four four
four four or
four four or five
four four or five women
four four or five women who
four four or five women who all
four four or five women who all had
cancer
cancer the
four four or five women who all had
cancer the breast
cancer the breast at
four four or five women who all had
cancer the breast at the
cancer the breast at the same
four four or five women who all had
cancer the breast at the same time
and
and every
and every night
and every night we
and every night we prayed
and every night we prayed for
and every night we prayed for all
and every night we prayed for all of
them
>> very
>> very well.
>> very well. Thank
>> very well. Thank you.
>> May
>> May I
>> very well. Thank you.
>> May I take
>> May I take a
>> very well. Thank you.
>> May I take a picture
>> May I take a picture as
>> very well. Thank you.
>> May I take a picture as well?
>> May I take a picture as well? But
>> very well. Thank you.
>> May I take a picture as well? But don't
forget,
forget, you're
forget, you're still
forget, you're still subject
forget, you're still subject to
forget, you're still subject to karma.
And
And the
forget, you're still subject to karma.
And the exact
And the exact time
forget, you're still subject to karma.
And the exact time and
And the exact time and how
forget, you're still subject to karma.
And the exact time and how you're
And the exact time and how you're going
to
to leave
to leave this
to leave this planet
to leave this planet was
to leave this planet was set
to leave this planet was set at
to leave this planet was set at the
to leave this planet was set at the time
you
you you
to leave this planet was set at the time
you you got
you you got here.
Therefore,
you
you you
Therefore,
you you do
you you do what
Therefore,
you you do what I
you you do what I say.
At
At the
At the same
At the same time,
At the same time, you
At the same time, you surrender
At the same time, you surrender to
At the same time, you surrender to God's
will
will in
At the same time, you surrender to God's
will in the
will in the matter.
At
At the
At the same
At the same time,
At the same time, if
At the same time, if it
At the same time, if it is
At the same time, if it is thy
At the same time, if it is thy will,
At the same time, if it is thy will, oh
Lord,
Lord, I
At the same time, if it is thy will, oh
Lord, I pray
Lord, I pray that
At the same time, if it is thy will, oh
Lord, I pray that so
Lord, I pray that so and
At the same time, if it is thy will, oh
Lord, I pray that so and so
Lord, I pray that so and so may
At the same time, if it is thy will, oh
Lord, I pray that so and so may survive.
uh
uh the
uh the surgery,
uh the surgery, etc.
>> Thank
>> Thank you,
uh the surgery, etc.
>> Thank you, doctor.
>> You're
>> You're trying
>> You're trying to
>> You're trying to tell
>> You're trying to tell God
>> You're trying to tell God what
>> You're trying to tell God what to
>> You're trying to tell God what to do.
He'll
He'll squash
>> You're trying to tell God what to do.
He'll squash you
He'll squash you like
>> You're trying to tell God what to do.
He'll squash you like a
He'll squash you like a worm.
Mortal.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
First,
First, I'd
First, I'd just
First, I'd just like
First, I'd just like to
First, I'd just like to say
First, I'd just like to say uh
First, I'd just like to say uh thank
First, I'd just like to say uh thank you
to
to you
First, I'd just like to say uh thank you
to you and
to you and Susan
First, I'd just like to say uh thank you
to you and Susan for
to you and Susan for the
First, I'd just like to say uh thank you
to you and Susan for the teachings
to you and Susan for the teachings and
also
also for
also for this
also for this audience
also for this audience and
also for this audience and the
also for this audience and the community
and
and my
also for this audience and the community
and my gratitude
and my gratitude um
also for this audience and the community
and my gratitude um for
and my gratitude um for being
also for this audience and the community
and my gratitude um for being able
and my gratitude um for being able to
also for this audience and the community
and my gratitude um for being able to be
a
a part
a part of
a part of this
a part of this energy.
a part of this energy. I
a part of this energy. I really
a part of this energy. I really really
appreciate
appreciate it.
a part of this energy. I really really
appreciate it. So,
appreciate it. So, thank
a part of this energy. I really really
appreciate it. So, thank you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
My
My question
>> Thank you.
My question is
My question is on
>> Thank you.
My question is on intention
and
and I
and I have
and I have an
and I have an intention
and I have an intention to
and I have an intention to be
and I have an intention to be just
and I have an intention to be just a
more
more kind
and I have an intention to be just a
more kind and
more kind and loving
and I have an intention to be just a
more kind and loving person
>> and
>> and when
>> and when I
>> and when I say
>> and when I say that
>> and when I say that it
>> and when I say that it normally
>> and when I say that it normally comes
from
from a
>> and when I say that it normally comes
from a thought
from a thought or
>> and when I say that it normally comes
from a thought or I
from a thought or I might
>> and when I say that it normally comes
from a thought or I might express
from a thought or I might express it
>> and when I say that it normally comes
from a thought or I might express it and
it
it seems
it seems like
it seems like it
it seems like it comes
it seems like it comes from
it seems like it comes from my
it seems like it comes from my mind
it seems like it comes from my mind and
what
what I'm
it seems like it comes from my mind and
what I'm wondering
what I'm wondering is
it seems like it comes from my mind and
what I'm wondering is is
what I'm wondering is is that
it seems like it comes from my mind and
what I'm wondering is is that the
process
process of
process of setting
process of setting intention
process of setting intention does
process of setting intention does it
come
come from
process of setting intention does it
come from your
come from your mind
process of setting intention does it
come from your mind does
come from your mind does it
process of setting intention does it
come from your mind does it come
come from your mind does it come at
process of setting intention does it
come from your mind does it come at a
higher
higher level
higher level and
higher level and as
higher level and as a
higher level and as a spiritual
higher level and as a spiritual student
what
what is
higher level and as a spiritual student
what is the
what is the best
higher level and as a spiritual student
what is the best way
what is the best way to
higher level and as a spiritual student
what is the best way to set
what is the best way to set in
attention.
>> Well,
>> Well, because
attention.
>> Well, because uh
>> Well, because uh your
attention.
>> Well, because uh your spirit
>> Well, because uh your spirit your
spiritual
spiritual intention
spiritual intention then
spiritual intention then is
spiritual intention then is what
determines
determines the
spiritual intention then is what
determines the level
and
and uh
and uh what
and uh what occurs
and uh what occurs as
and uh what occurs as a
and uh what occurs as a result
and uh what occurs as a result of
and uh what occurs as a result of it
and uh what occurs as a result of it is
subject
subject to
and uh what occurs as a result of it is
subject to karmic
subject to karmic influences
and uh what occurs as a result of it is
subject to karmic influences of
subject to karmic influences of many
kinds.
Mhm.
Mhm. Otherwise,
kinds.
Mhm. Otherwise, everything
Mhm. Otherwise, everything that
kinds.
Mhm. Otherwise, everything that you
Mhm. Otherwise, everything that you hold
in
in mind
in mind would
in mind would would
in mind would would would
in mind would would would occur.
uh
uh because
in mind would would would occur.
uh because uh
uh because uh karma
in mind would would would occur.
uh because uh karma you're
uh because uh karma you're not
in mind would would would occur.
uh because uh karma you're not only
uh because uh karma you're not only your
karma
karma but
karma but the
karma but the karma
karma but the karma of
karma but the karma of many
karma but the karma of many other
people's
people's involved
karma but the karma of many other
people's involved and
people's involved and you
karma but the karma of many other
people's involved and you can't
people's involved and you can't just
necessarily
necessarily overrule
necessarily overrule it
necessarily overrule it by
necessarily overrule it by by
necessarily overrule it by by your
necessarily overrule it by by your will.
Yes.
Yes. So
necessarily overrule it by by your will.
Yes. So the
Yes. So the all
necessarily overrule it by by your will.
Yes. So the all of
Yes. So the all of this
necessarily overrule it by by your will.
Yes. So the all of this means
surrendering
surrendering to
surrendering to God's
surrendering to God's will
surrendering to God's will at
surrendering to God's will at the
greatest
greatest depth.
Thy
Thy will,
Thy will, oh
Thy will, oh Lord,
Thy will, oh Lord, not
Thy will, oh Lord, not mine.
And
And a
Thy will, oh Lord, not mine.
And a little
And a little contribution
Thy will, oh Lord, not mine.
And a little contribution to
And a little contribution to the
Thy will, oh Lord, not mine.
And a little contribution to the church
might
might help
might help too.
>> Is
>> Is that
might help too.
>> Is that visa?
Can
Can I
Can I also
Can I also get
Can I also get a
Can I also get a picture
Can I also get a picture taken
Can I also get a picture taken too,
please?
>> Pass
>> Pass the
>> Pass the plate.
>> I
>> I think
>> Pass the plate.
>> I think that's
>> I think that's funny.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You
>> Yeah. You bet.
I
I used
I used to
I used to get
I used to get a
I used to get a kick
I used to get a kick when
I used to get a kick when they
I used to get a kick when they passed
the
the plate
I used to get a kick when they passed
the plate at
the plate at church.
I used to get a kick when they passed
the plate at church. You
the plate at church. You know,
I used to get a kick when they passed
the plate at church. You know, the
the plate at church. You know, the the
priest
priest would
priest would always
priest would always say,
priest would always say, "Blessed
priest would always say, "Blessed are
those
those who
priest would always say, "Blessed are
those who give
it
it a
it a circle."
>> Hi,
>> Hi, Dr.
it a circle."
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes,
>> Susan.
>> All
>> All fear
>> All fear is
>> All fear is illusion.
Okay,
Okay, Dr.
>> All fear is illusion.
Okay, Dr. Hawkins,
Okay, Dr. Hawkins, when
>> All fear is illusion.
Okay, Dr. Hawkins, when I
Okay, Dr. Hawkins, when I was
>> All fear is illusion.
Okay, Dr. Hawkins, when I was a
Okay, Dr. Hawkins, when I was a child,
>> All fear is illusion.
Okay, Dr. Hawkins, when I was a child, I
had
had a
had a very
had a very intense
had a very intense experience
had a very intense experience of
divinity.
>> When
>> When you
>> When you had
>> When you had a
>> When you had a child?
>> When you had a child? When
>> When you had a child? When I
>> When you had a child? When I was
>> When you had a child? When I was a
child,
>> a
>> a child.
>> a child. Oh,
>> a child. Oh, well,
>> a child. Oh, well, you
>> a child. Oh, well, you weren't
>> a child. Oh, well, you weren't a
>> a child. Oh, well, you weren't a child.
Yeah.
>> Uh,
>> Uh, it
>> Uh, it changed
>> Uh, it changed me
>> Uh, it changed me irrevocably.
>> Yes.
>> I
>> I was
>> I was in
>> I was in a
>> I was in a different
>> I was in a different space
>> I was in a different space when
>> I was in a different space when I
>> I was in a different space when I came
back
back down
and
and um
and um I
and um I had
and um I had no
and um I had no way
and um I had no way to
and um I had no way to conceptualize
that.
that. I
and um I had no way to conceptualize
that. I um
that. I um but
and um I had no way to conceptualize
that. I um but when
that. I um but when I
and um I had no way to conceptualize
that. I um but when I started
that. I um but when I started reading
your
your books,
your books, then
your books, then I
your books, then I began
your books, then I began to
your books, then I began to understand
and
and I
your books, then I began to understand
and I think
and I think I
your books, then I began to understand
and I think I jumped
and I think I jumped the
your books, then I began to understand
and I think I jumped the 400s.
>> She
>> She jumped
>> She jumped what?
>> She jumped what? She
>> She jumped what? She jumped
>> She jumped what? She jumped beforehand.
She
She went
>> She jumped what? She jumped beforehand.
She went over.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. Oh,
>> Oh. Oh, yeah.
>> Oh. Oh, yeah. Possible.
>> Uhhuh.
>> You
>> You just
>> You just skipped
>> You just skipped thinking.
>> I
>> I think
>> You just skipped thinking.
>> I think that's
>> I think that's what
>> You just skipped thinking.
>> I think that's what happened.
>> Um,
but
but during
>> Um,
but during the
but during the experience,
>> Um,
but during the experience, I
but during the experience, I was
>> Um,
but during the experience, I was in
but during the experience, I was in a
much
much higher
much higher state
much higher state of
much higher state of consciousness
much higher state of consciousness which
lasted
lasted only
much higher state of consciousness which
lasted only a
lasted only a few
much higher state of consciousness which
lasted only a few minutes.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And I
>> Yes.
>> And I wanted
>> And I wanted to
>> Yes.
>> And I wanted to ask
>> And I wanted to ask you
>> Yes.
>> And I wanted to ask you if
>> And I wanted to ask you if you
>> Yes.
>> And I wanted to ask you if you could
tell
tell me
tell me what
tell me what that
tell me what that level
tell me what that level was
tell me what that level was that
tell me what that level was that I
tell me what that level was that I felt
because
because I
tell me what that level was that I felt
because I still
because I still remember
tell me what that level was that I felt
because I still remember what
because I still remember what it
tell me what that level was that I felt
because I still remember what it felt
like
like or
like or sort
like or sort of
like or sort of what
like or sort of what it
like or sort of what it felt
like or sort of what it felt like.
like or sort of what it felt like. Was
it
it beyond
like or sort of what it felt like. Was
it beyond time
it beyond time and
like or sort of what it felt like. Was
it beyond time and space?
>> I
>> I think
>> I think it
>> I think it might
>> I think it might have
>> I think it might have been,
but
but I'm
>> I think it might have been,
but I'm not
but I'm not sure.
>> I
>> I mean,
>> I mean, it's
>> I mean, it's it's
>> I mean, it's it's been
>> I mean, it's it's been a
>> I mean, it's it's been a few
>> I mean, it's it's been a few years.
>> I mean, it's it's been a few years. I
was
was nine
>> I mean, it's it's been a few years. I
was nine years
was nine years old.
>> Are
>> Are you
>> Are you constantly
>> Are you constantly looking
>> Are you constantly looking for
>> Are you constantly looking for to
>> Are you constantly looking for to get
back
back to
>> Are you constantly looking for to get
back to that
back to that space
>> Are you constantly looking for to get
back to that space again?
>> Not
>> Not necessar.
>> Well,
>> Well, I
>> Not necessar.
>> Well, I just
I
I didn't
I didn't even
I didn't even begin
I didn't even begin to
I didn't even begin to understand
I didn't even begin to understand the
experience
experience until
I didn't even begin to understand the
experience until I
experience until I started
I didn't even begin to understand the
experience until I started reading
experience until I started reading your
books.
books. It
books. It was
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
books. It was
>> Oh, I see
>> Oh, I see what
books. It was
>> Oh, I see what you're
>> Oh, I see what you're saying.
books. It was
>> Oh, I see what you're saying. you
>> Oh, I see what you're saying. you know,
and
and I'm
and I'm I'm
and I'm I'm just
and I'm I'm just looking
and I'm I'm just looking for
>> You
>> You didn't
and I'm I'm just looking for
>> You didn't identify
>> You didn't identify it
and I'm I'm just looking for
>> You didn't identify it as
>> You didn't identify it as a
and I'm I'm just looking for
>> You didn't identify it as a spiritual
experience.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
experience.
>> Oh, I knew
>> Oh, I knew it
experience.
>> Oh, I knew it was
>> Oh, I knew it was a
experience.
>> Oh, I knew it was a spiritual
experience,
experience, but
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So,
experience, but
>> Yeah. So, what
>> Yeah. So, what is
experience, but
>> Yeah. So, what is the
>> Yeah. So, what is the question?
experience, but
>> Yeah. So, what is the question? I
>> Yeah. So, what is the question? I still
don't
don't get
don't get it.
>> I
>> I I
don't get it.
>> I I would
>> I I would like
don't get it.
>> I I would like to
>> I I would like to know
don't get it.
>> I I would like to know the
>> I I would like to know the level
don't get it.
>> I I would like to know the level that
>> I I would like to know the level that I
felt.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, the
felt.
>> Oh, the level.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Okay.
>> Uhhuh.
>> We
>> We have
>> We have permission
>> We have permission to
>> We have permission to ask
>> We have permission to ask the
>> We have permission to ask the level
>> We have permission to ask the level she
reached.
reached. It
>> We have permission to ask the level she
reached. It was
reached. It was over
>> We have permission to ask the level she
reached. It was over 500.
reached. It was over 500. How
>> We have permission to ask the level she
reached. It was over 500. How much?
reached. It was over 500. How much? Oh,
>> it
>> it was
>> it was over
>> it was over 500.
>> it was over 500. And
>> it was over 500. And uh
>> I
>> I can't
>> it was over 500. And uh
>> I can't do
>> I can't do it.
>> it was over 500. And uh
>> I can't do it. It
>> I can't do it. It was
>> it was over 500. And uh
>> I can't do it. It was over
>> I can't do it. It was over 550.
600.
590.
That's
That's a
That's a pretty
That's a pretty botific
That's a pretty botific level.
That's a pretty botific level. 590.
That's a pretty botific level. 590. Yes.
>> Wow.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Well,
>> Uhhuh.
>> Okay. Well, thank
>> Okay. Well, thank you
>> Uhhuh.
>> Okay. Well, thank you very
>> Okay. Well, thank you very much.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Okay. Well, thank you very much. I
>> Okay. Well, thank you very much. I don't
think
>> that's
>> that's a
think
>> that's a transformative
>> that's a transformative level.
think
>> that's a transformative level. 590.
>> It
>> It was
>> It was I
>> It was I don't
>> It was I don't think
>> It was I don't think I
>> It was I don't think I could
>> It was I don't think I could have
finished
finished the
>> It was I don't think I could have
finished the fourth
finished the fourth grade
>> It was I don't think I could have
finished the fourth grade if
finished the fourth grade if I'd
>> It was I don't think I could have
finished the fourth grade if I'd stayed
there.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. No.
there.
>> Yeah. No. No.
You
You have
You have to
>> That's
>> That's funny.
You have to
>> That's funny. You
>> That's funny. You have
You have to
>> That's funny. You have to
>> That's funny. You have to sing
You have to
>> That's funny. You have to sing the
quote.
>> That
>> That was
quote.
>> That was cute.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> S
>> S the
>> Thank you.
>> S the quote,
>> S the quote, please.
>> I
>> I was
>> I was in
>> I was in the
>> I was in the fourth
>> I was in the fourth grade.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> I was in the fourth grade.
>> Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you
>> I was in the fourth grade.
>> Thank you. Thank you so
>> Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. No,
>> Yes. No, that
>> Yes. No, that was
>> Yes. No, that was a
>> Yes. No, that was a very
>> Yes. No, that was a very good
>> Yes. No, that was a very good experience
you
you had.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Children
>> Yes. Children not
>> Yes. Children not uncommonly
>> Yes. Children not uncommonly have
>> Yes. Children not uncommonly have high
spiritual
spiritual experiences.
Hello,
Hello, Dr.
Hello, Dr. Hawkins
Hello, Dr. Hawkins and
Hello, Dr. Hawkins and Susan.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Hello.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you for
>> Thank you for your
>> Thank you for your work.
>> And
>> And I
>> Thank you for your work.
>> And I just
>> And I just want
>> Thank you for your work.
>> And I just want to
>> And I just want to give
>> Thank you for your work.
>> And I just want to give my
>> And I just want to give my gratitude
>> Thank you for your work.
>> And I just want to give my gratitude and
love
love and
love and feel
love and feel so
love and feel so honored
love and feel so honored to
love and feel so honored to be
love and feel so honored to be here.
>> And
>> And this
love and feel so honored to be here.
>> And this is
>> And this is my
love and feel so honored to be here.
>> And this is my first
>> And this is my first Dr.
love and feel so honored to be here.
>> And this is my first Dr. Hawkins
>> And this is my first Dr. Hawkins 101
book
book that
book that I
book that I studied
book that I studied from
book that I studied from in
book that I studied from in the
book that I studied from in the middle
90s.
90s. So
book that I studied from in the middle
90s. So that's
90s. So that's why
book that I studied from in the middle
90s. So that's why I
90s. So that's why I really
book that I studied from in the middle
90s. So that's why I really wanted
>> your
>> your signature
>> your signature on
>> your signature on it.
>> your signature on it. And
>> your signature on it. And I
>> your signature on it. And I have
>> your signature on it. And I have your
other
other ones,
>> your signature on it. And I have your
other ones, but
other ones, but this
>> your signature on it. And I have your
other ones, but this is
other ones, but this is very
>> your signature on it. And I have your
other ones, but this is very special
other ones, but this is very special to
me.
me. And
me. And my
me. And my question
me. And my question is
me. And my question is Psalm
me. And my question is Psalm 139,
me. And my question is Psalm 139, which
is
is my
me. And my question is Psalm 139, which
is my favorite
is my favorite also.
me. And my question is Psalm 139, which
is my favorite also. And
is my favorite also. And Psalm
me. And my question is Psalm 139, which
is my favorite also. And Psalm 139.
>> Oh
>> Oh yeah.
>> Our
>> Our days
>> Oh yeah.
>> Our days are
>> Our days are numbered
>> Oh yeah.
>> Our days are numbered in
>> Our days are numbered in the
>> Oh yeah.
>> Our days are numbered in the book
>> Our days are numbered in the book of
life.
How
How does
life.
How does one
How does one then
life.
How does one then discern
using
using a
using a health
using a health directive
using a health directive like
using a health directive like do
using a health directive like do not
resuscitate
resuscitate and
using a health directive like do not
resuscitate and those
resuscitate and those types
using a health directive like do not
resuscitate and those types of
resuscitate and those types of medical
procedures.
>> It's
>> It's too
procedures.
>> It's too long
>> It's too long to
procedures.
>> It's too long to ask
>> It's too long to ask question.
procedures.
>> It's too long to ask question. What
>> It's too long to ask question. What is
she
she asking?
>> She's
>> She's asking
she asking?
>> She's asking once
>> She's asking once uh
she asking?
>> She's asking once uh about
>> She's asking once uh about resuscitation
uh
uh after
uh after one
uh after one has
uh after one has passed
uh after one has passed over.
uh after one has passed over. Do
uh after one has passed over. Do you
mean
mean revise
uh after one has passed over. Do you
mean revise the
mean revise the body
uh after one has passed over. Do you
mean revise the body or
mean revise the body or do
uh after one has passed over. Do you
mean revise the body or do you
mean revise the body or do you let
uh after one has passed over. Do you
mean revise the body or do you let it
go?
>> You
>> You mean
go?
>> You mean a
>> You mean a bystander?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Making
>> Yes. Making the
>> Yes. Making the determination
>> Yes. Making the determination ahead
>> Yes. Making the determination ahead of
time.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you
>> Oh, you don't
>> Oh, you don't have
>> Oh, you don't have that
>> Oh, you don't have that liberty.
>> Oh, you don't have that liberty. You
>> Oh, you don't have that liberty. You can
only
only support
>> Oh, you don't have that liberty. You can
only support life
only support life as
>> Oh, you don't have that liberty. You can
only support life as you
only support life as you understand
>> Oh, you don't have that liberty. You can
only support life as you understand it.
Otherwise,
Otherwise, you'd
Otherwise, you'd be
Otherwise, you'd be uh
Otherwise, you'd be uh making
Otherwise, you'd be uh making a
Otherwise, you'd be uh making a divine
decision
decision for
Otherwise, you'd be uh making a divine
decision for God,
>> right?
>> right? But
>> right? But in
>> right? But in a
>> right? But in a health
>> right? But in a health directive,
how
how does
>> right? But in a health directive,
how does one
how does one discern
>> right? But in a health directive,
how does one discern for
how does one discern for themsself
whether
whether to
whether to sign
whether to sign off
whether to sign off a
whether to sign off a do
whether to sign off a do not
resuscitate,
do
do not
do not intubate?
>> You
>> You mean
do not intubate?
>> You mean as
>> You mean as a
do not intubate?
>> You mean as a family
>> You mean as a family member?
>> Yeah.
>> On
>> On on on
>> Yeah.
>> On on on yourself
>> On on on yourself or
>> Yeah.
>> On on on yourself or with
>> On on on yourself or with your
>> Yeah.
>> On on on yourself or with your family.
>> She's
>> She's what
>> She's what she's
>> She's what she's talking.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
>> She's what she's talking.
>> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see. Yes.
>> She's what she's talking.
>> Oh, I see. Yes. Why
>> Oh, I see. Yes. Why don't
>> She's what she's talking.
>> Oh, I see. Yes. Why don't you
>> Oh, I see. Yes. Why don't you just
>> She's what she's talking.
>> Oh, I see. Yes. Why don't you just do
what
what you
what you want?
I
I totally
what you want?
I totally agree
I totally agree with
what you want?
I totally agree with that.
I totally agree with that. And
what you want?
I totally agree with that. And so
I totally agree with that. And so for
part
part of
part of it
part of it is
part of it is what
part of it is what Susan
part of it is what Susan just
part of it is what Susan just said.
part of it is what Susan just said. Part
of
of it
part of it is what Susan just said. Part
of it is
of it is I
part of it is what Susan just said. Part
of it is I am
of it is I am power
part of it is what Susan just said. Part
of it is I am power of
of it is I am power of attorney
part of it is what Susan just said. Part
of it is I am power of attorney and
healthc
healthc care
healthc care director
healthc care director of
healthc care director of my
healthc care director of my parents.
healthc care director of my parents. And
so
so some
healthc care director of my parents. And
so some of
so some of these
healthc care director of my parents. And
so some of these things
so some of these things have
healthc care director of my parents. And
so some of these things have been
so some of these things have been talked
about.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And so
>> And so I
>> And so I wanted
>> And so I wanted to
>> And so I wanted to know
>> And so I wanted to know just
>> And so I wanted to know just what
>> And so I wanted to know just what you
thought
thought of
>> And so I wanted to know just what you
thought of that
thought of that because
>> And so I wanted to know just what you
thought of that because our
thought of that because our days
>> And so I wanted to know just what you
thought of that because our days are
numbered
numbered in
numbered in the
numbered in the book
numbered in the book of
numbered in the book of life.
>> Because
>> Because of
numbered in the book of life.
>> Because of what?
>> Our
>> Our days
>> Our days are
>> Our days are numbered
>> Our days are numbered in
>> Our days are numbered in the
>> Our days are numbered in the book
>> Our days are numbered in the book of
life.
life. Personally,
if
if I
if I passed
if I passed over,
if I passed over, I
if I passed over, I don't
if I passed over, I don't want
if I passed over, I don't want someone
bringing
bringing me
if I passed over, I don't want someone
bringing me back.
>> Right.
>> Right. Right.
>> But
>> But there's
>> But there's my
>> But there's my there's
>> But there's my there's my
>> But there's my there's my personal
answer.
>> Right.
>> Right. And
>> Right. And I
>> Right. And I agree.
>> Right. And I agree. That's
>> Right. And I agree. That's my
>> Right. And I agree. That's my answer
also.
>> Decision
>> Decision to
>> Decision to make.
>> Decision to make. It
>> Decision to make. It should
>> Decision to make. It should be
>> Decision to make. It should be your
>> Decision to make. It should be your if
you're
you're making
>> Decision to make. It should be your if
you're making it
you're making it for
>> Decision to make. It should be your if
you're making it for your
you're making it for your parents,
>> Decision to make. It should be your if
you're making it for your parents, it
should
should be
should be your
should be your parents
should be your parents individual
should be your parents individual uh
decision
decision to
should be your parents individual uh
decision to make.
>> Right.
>> Right. I
>> Right. I understand
>> Right. I understand that.
>> Right. I understand that. Again,
>> Right. I understand that. Again, I'm
just
just looking
>> Right. I understand that. Again, I'm
just looking for
just looking for guidance
>> Right. I understand that. Again, I'm
just looking for guidance and
interpretation
interpretation of
interpretation of that.
interpretation of that. Yeah.
>> So,
>> So, so
interpretation of that. Yeah.
>> So, so personally,
>> So, so personally, you
interpretation of that. Yeah.
>> So, so personally, you know,
>> So, so personally, you know, I
interpretation of that. Yeah.
>> So, so personally, you know, I know
>> So, so personally, you know, I know it's
a
a better
a better place
a better place where
a better place where I'm
a better place where I'm going,
>> so
>> so I
a better place where I'm going,
>> so I don't
>> so I don't want
a better place where I'm going,
>> so I don't want to
>> so I don't want to come
a better place where I'm going,
>> so I don't want to come back
>> so I don't want to come back here.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, that's
>> Yeah, that's individual
>> Yeah, that's individual decision.
>> But
>> But that's
>> Yeah, that's individual decision.
>> But that's your
>> But that's your own
>> Yeah, that's individual decision.
>> But that's your own decision
>> But that's your own decision too,
>> right?
>> right? I
>> right? I understand
>> right? I understand that.
>> I
>> I mean,
>> right? I understand that.
>> I mean, if
>> I mean, if I
>> right? I understand that.
>> I mean, if I was
>> I mean, if I was young
>> right? I understand that.
>> I mean, if I was young and
>> I mean, if I was young and I
>> right? I understand that.
>> I mean, if I was young and I had
>> family
>> family to
>> family to raise
>> family to raise and
>> family to raise and everything,
>> family to raise and everything, then
>> family to raise and everything, then I
would
would say
>> family to raise and everything, then I
would say yes.
would say yes. You
>> family to raise and everything, then I
would say yes. You know,
would say yes. You know, it
>> family to raise and everything, then I
would say yes. You know, it depends
would say yes. You know, it depends on
the
the situation,
the situation, too.
the situation, too. It's
the situation, too. It's not
the situation, too. It's not completely,
you
you know,
the situation, too. It's not completely,
you know, I'm
you know, I'm not
the situation, too. It's not completely,
you know, I'm not saying
you know, I'm not saying that's
the situation, too. It's not completely,
you know, I'm not saying that's the
you know, I'm not saying that's the only
decision.
decision. I'm
decision. I'm just
decision. I'm just saying
decision. I'm just saying it
decision. I'm just saying it depends
decision. I'm just saying it depends on
the
the circumstances
decision. I'm just saying it depends on
the circumstances and
the circumstances and each
decision. I'm just saying it depends on
the circumstances and each one
the circumstances and each one has
decision. I'm just saying it depends on
the circumstances and each one has your
own
own circumstances.
own circumstances. It's
own circumstances. It's the
own circumstances. It's the choices
own circumstances. It's the choices that
you
you make
own circumstances. It's the choices that
you make at
you make at that
own circumstances. It's the choices that
you make at that time.
>> Right?
>> It's
>> It's a
>> Right?
>> It's a patient
>> It's a patient I
>> Right?
>> It's a patient I don't
>> It's a patient I don't like.
>> Right?
>> It's a patient I don't like. I
>> It's a patient I don't like. I used
>> Right?
>> It's a patient I don't like. I used to
say
say uh
say uh do
say uh do not
say uh do not resuscitate.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
say uh do not resuscitate.
>> Thank you. And
>> Thank you. And I
say uh do not resuscitate.
>> Thank you. And I love
>> Thank you. And I love your
say uh do not resuscitate.
>> Thank you. And I love your sense
>> Thank you. And I love your sense of
humor.
Do
Do not
humor.
Do not resuscitate
Do not resuscitate this
humor.
Do not resuscitate this old
Do not resuscitate this old crab.
>> DNR,
>> you
>> you weren't
>> DNR,
>> you weren't a
>> you weren't a very
>> DNR,
>> you weren't a very good
>> you weren't a very good doctor.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
>> Oh, I killed
>> Oh, I killed I
>> Oh, I killed I I
>> Oh, I killed I I pushed
>> Oh, I killed I I pushed a
>> Oh, I killed I I pushed a lot
>> Oh, I killed I I pushed a lot of
>> Oh, I killed I I pushed a lot of them
off
off the
>> Oh, I killed I I pushed a lot of them
off the planet.
>> Hello.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Go
>> Hello.
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> Personally,
>> Personally, I
>> Personally, I don't
>> Personally, I don't have
>> Personally, I don't have a
>> Personally, I don't have a question.
>> Personally, I don't have a question. You
have
have answered
>> Personally, I don't have a question. You
have answered all
have answered all my
>> Personally, I don't have a question. You
have answered all my questions
have answered all my questions more
>> Personally, I don't have a question. You
have answered all my questions more than
enough.
enough. I
enough. I just
enough. I just wanted
enough. I just wanted to
enough. I just wanted to express
enough. I just wanted to express my
enough. I just wanted to express my love
and
and gratitude
enough. I just wanted to express my love
and gratitude for
and gratitude for your
enough. I just wanted to express my love
and gratitude for your teaching.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you so
>> Thank you so much.
>> And
>> And your
>> Thank you so much.
>> And your work.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> However,
>> However, I
>> Thank you.
>> However, I have
>> However, I have a
>> Thank you.
>> However, I have a friend
>> However, I have a friend in
>> Thank you.
>> However, I have a friend in Romania
>> However, I have a friend in Romania is
>> Thank you.
>> However, I have a friend in Romania is a
student
student of
student of yours
student of yours and
student of yours and she
student of yours and she couldn't
student of yours and she couldn't be
here
here now
student of yours and she couldn't be
here now and
here now and she
student of yours and she couldn't be
here now and she asked
here now and she asked me
student of yours and she couldn't be
here now and she asked me a
here now and she asked me a question
student of yours and she couldn't be
here now and she asked me a question for
you.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. So
you.
>> Yes. So she
>> Yes. So she said
you.
>> Yes. So she said you
>> Yes. So she said you said
you.
>> Yes. So she said you said that
>> Yes. So she said you said that uh
everything
everything happens
everything happens by
everything happens by God's
everything happens by God's will
everything happens by God's will and
what
what then
everything happens by God's will and
what then of
what then of free
everything happens by God's will and
what then of free will
what then of free will and
everything happens by God's will and
what then of free will and what
what then of free will and what is
everything happens by God's will and
what then of free will and what is the
part
part in
part in us
part in us that
part in us that makes
part in us that makes choice
part in us that makes choice moment
part in us that makes choice moment by
moment
the
the what
the what the
the what the mind
the what the mind chooses
the what the mind chooses are
the what the mind chooses are options
but
but of
the what the mind chooses are options
but of course
but of course you
the what the mind chooses are options
but of course you can't
but of course you can't choose
the what the mind chooses are options
but of course you can't choose the
options
because
because the
options
because the options
because the options are
options
because the options are dictated
because the options are dictated by
karmic
karmic and
karmic and time
karmic and time and
karmic and time and evolution
so
so you're
karmic and time and evolution
so you're free
so you're free to
karmic and time and evolution
so you're free to choose
so you're free to choose but
karmic and time and evolution
so you're free to choose but you're
so you're free to choose but you're not
free
free what
free what there
free what there is
free what there is to
free what there is to choose
free what there is to choose you
free what there is to choose you can't
choose
choose to
free what there is to choose you can't
choose to become
choose to become a
free what there is to choose you can't
choose to become a monkey
choose to become a monkey and
free what there is to choose you can't
choose to become a monkey and climb
through
through the
through the tree
through the tree now
through the tree now you
through the tree now you see
through the tree now you see so
through the tree now you see so you're
already
already restricted
through the tree now you see so you're
already restricted in
already restricted in the
through the tree now you see so you're
already restricted in the number
already restricted in the number of
plausible
plausible options
plausible options then
plausible options then you're
plausible options then you're influenced
by
by propensities
so
so that's
so that's also
so that's also karmic
so that's also karmic the
so that's also karmic the karmic
propensity
propensity you
so that's also karmic the karmic
propensity you know
propensity you know to
so that's also karmic the karmic
propensity you know to see
propensity you know to see other
so that's also karmic the karmic
propensity you know to see other people
as
as innocent
as innocent or
as innocent or to
as innocent or to see
as innocent or to see other
as innocent or to see other people
as innocent or to see other people as
evil
is
is considerably
is considerably karmic
is considerably karmic you
is considerably karmic you know
is considerably karmic you know and
is considerably karmic you know and the
options
options that
is considerably karmic you know and the
options that you've
options that you've made
is considerably karmic you know and the
options that you've made in
options that you've made in previous
lifetimes
lifetimes is
that's
that's why
lifetimes is
that's why I
that's why I recommend
lifetimes is
that's why I recommend uh
that's why I recommend uh you
lifetimes is
that's why I recommend uh you know
goodwill
goodwill towards
goodwill towards all
goodwill towards all of
goodwill towards all of life
goodwill towards all of life in
goodwill towards all of life in all
goodwill towards all of life in all of
its
its expressions.
goodwill towards all of life in all of
its expressions. Goodwill
its expressions. Goodwill towards
goodwill towards all of life in all of
its expressions. Goodwill towards all
its expressions. Goodwill towards all of
life
life in
life in all
life in all of
life in all of its
life in all of its expressions
uh
uh as
life in all of its expressions
uh as a
uh as a very
life in all of its expressions
uh as a very positive
karmic
karmic consequence
karmic consequence to
karmic consequence to that
karmic consequence to that decision.
Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
Huh?
>> Hello.
>> Yes.
>> So,
>> So, first
>> So, first of
>> So, first of all,
>> So, first of all, thank
>> So, first of all, thank you
>> So, first of all, thank you both
>> So, first of all, thank you both for
your
your love,
>> So, first of all, thank you both for
your love, your
your love, your teaching,
>> So, first of all, thank you both for
your love, your teaching, lifechanging
guidance.
And
And this
guidance.
And this morning,
And this morning, you
guidance.
And this morning, you said
And this morning, you said that
guidance.
And this morning, you said that uh
freedom
freedom is
freedom is choice
and
and choice,
freedom is choice
and choice, if
and choice, if my
freedom is choice
and choice, if my understanding
and choice, if my understanding is
correct,
correct, is
correct, is the
correct, is the result
correct, is the result of
correct, is the result of the
correct, is the result of the perception
of
of the
correct, is the result of the perception
of the highest
of the highest good,
correct, is the result of the perception
of the highest good, the
of the highest good, the truth.
correct, is the result of the perception
of the highest good, the truth. I
of the highest good, the truth. I can't
understand
understand what
understand what you're
understand what you're saying.
understand what you're saying. There's
something
something about
understand what you're saying. There's
something about the
something about the ego.
>> Choice
>> Choice is
>> Choice is the
>> Choice is the perception
>> Choice is the perception of
>> Choice is the perception of the
>> Choice is the perception of the highest
good.
>> What?
>> She
>> She said
>> What?
>> She said choice
>> She said choice was
>> What?
>> She said choice was the
>> She said choice was the perception
>> What?
>> She said choice was the perception of
the
the highest.
>> Well,
>> Well, to
the highest.
>> Well, to make
>> Well, to make a
the highest.
>> Well, to make a wise
>> Well, to make a wise choice.
the highest.
>> Well, to make a wise choice. Yes.
>> And
>> And now
>> And now what
>> And now what happens
>> And now what happens when
>> And now what happens when one
>> And now what happens when one has
>> And now what happens when one has a
split
split heart
>> And now what happens when one has a
split heart and
split heart and cannot
>> And now what happens when one has a
split heart and cannot find
split heart and cannot find the
>> And now what happens when one has a
split heart and cannot find the truth?
Um
Um what's
Um what's the
Um what's the highest
Um what's the highest good?
>> If
>> If some
Um what's the highest good?
>> If some if
>> If some if someone
Um what's the highest good?
>> If some if someone can't
>> If some if someone can't choose
Um what's the highest good?
>> If some if someone can't choose the
highest
highest good,
>> yes.
>> yes. Then
what
what would
what would be
>> well
>> well they
what would be
>> well they do
>> well they do choose
what would be
>> well they do choose they
>> well they do choose they always
what would be
>> well they do choose they always choose
the
the highest
the highest good.
the highest good. Whatever
the highest good. Whatever you
the highest good. Whatever you choose
the highest good. Whatever you choose is
because
because at
the highest good. Whatever you choose is
because at the
because at the time
the highest good. Whatever you choose is
because at the time that's
because at the time that's what
the highest good. Whatever you choose is
because at the time that's what you
think
think is
think is the
think is the highest
think is the highest good.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. At
think is the highest good.
>> Yeah. At that
>> Yeah. At that moment
>> even
>> even if
>> even if they
>> even if they have
>> even if they have a
>> even if they have a what
>> even if they have a what she
>> even if they have a what she calls
>> even if they have a what she calls a
split
split heart
>> that
>> that prevents
>> that prevents you
>> that prevents you from
>> they're
>> they're ambivalent.
>> Do
>> Do you
>> Do you mean?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You
>> Do you mean?
>> Yeah. You can
>> Yeah. You can you
>> Do you mean?
>> Yeah. You can you can
>> Yeah. You can you can you
>> Do you mean?
>> Yeah. You can you can you you
>> Yeah. You can you can you you you
>> Do you mean?
>> Yeah. You can you can you you you you're
not
not sure
not sure what
not sure what what's
not sure what what's the
not sure what what's the highest
not sure what what's the highest good
because
because you're
not sure what what's the highest good
because you're still
because you're still very
not sure what what's the highest good
because you're still very small
because you're still very small and
not sure what what's the highest good
because you're still very small and and
how
how do
how do you
how do you know?
>> I
>> I don't
how do you know?
>> I don't know
>> I don't know what
how do you know?
>> I don't know what she's
>> I don't know what she's asking.
>> I
>> I think
>> I think that
>> I think that your
>> I think that your karma
>> I think that your karma would
>> I think that your karma would step
>> I think that your karma would step into
that
that and
>> I think that your karma would step into
that and from
that and from your
>> I think that your karma would step into
that and from your karma
that and from your karma would
>> I think that your karma would step into
that and from your karma would determine
what
what would
what would be
what would be the
what would be the highest
what would be the highest good
what would be the highest good at
what would be the highest good at that
time.
time. Whether
what would be the highest good at that
time. Whether it's
time. Whether it's what
what would be the highest good at that
time. Whether it's what someone
time. Whether it's what someone else
chooses
chooses or
chooses or not,
chooses or not, it's
chooses or not, it's not
chooses or not, it's not our
chooses or not, it's not our it's
chooses or not, it's not our it's not
our
our choice.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. be
>> Yeah. be what
>> Yeah. be what you
>> Yeah. be what you understand
>> Yeah. be what you understand to
>> Yeah. be what you understand to be
>> Yeah. be what you understand to be the
highest
highest good.
>> Yeah.
>> Your
>> Your karma
>> Yeah.
>> Your karma might
>> Your karma might determine
>> Yeah.
>> Your karma might determine that
>> Your karma might determine that at
>> Yeah.
>> Your karma might determine that at that
time
time as
time as to
time as to which
time as to which path
time as to which path to
time as to which path to take.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Which
time as to which path to take.
>> Yeah. Which which
>> Yeah. Which which which
time as to which path to take.
>> Yeah. Which which which appears
>> Yeah. Which which which appears to
time as to which path to take.
>> Yeah. Which which which appears to you
to
to be
to be the
to be the highest
to be the highest good.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> I
>> I was
>> I was trying
>> I was trying to
>> I was trying to It's
>> I was trying to It's hard
>> I was trying to It's hard to
>> I
>> I don't know.
>> I was trying to It's hard to
>> I don't know. There's
>> I don't know. There's something
>> I was trying to It's hard to
>> I don't know. There's something about
the
the feedback
the feedback from
the feedback from this
the feedback from this mic.
the feedback from this mic. I
the feedback from this mic. I have
the feedback from this mic. I have a
hard
hard time
the feedback from this mic. I have a
hard time having
hard time having a
the feedback from this mic. I have a
hard time having a hard
hard time having a hard time
>> hearing
>> hearing it.
>> hearing it. Yeah.
>> I'll
>> I'll try
>> hearing it. Yeah.
>> I'll try asking
>> I'll try asking her
>> hearing it. Yeah.
>> I'll try asking her to
>> I'll try asking her to speak
>> hearing it. Yeah.
>> I'll try asking her to speak close
>> I'll try asking her to speak close to
it.
it. Speak
it. Speak close
it. Speak close to
it. Speak close to the
it. Speak close to the mic.
it. Speak close to the mic. I
it. Speak close to the mic. I can
it. Speak close to the mic. I can see
what
what I'm
>> speak
>> speak to
>> speak to it
>> speak to it and
>> speak to it and it
>> speak to it and it blurs
>> speak to it and it blurs out.
>> Hello.
>> Hello. Um
>> speak to it and it blurs out.
>> Hello. Um I
>> Hello. Um I met
>> speak to it and it blurs out.
>> Hello. Um I met you
>> Hello. Um I met you for
>> speak to it and it blurs out.
>> Hello. Um I met you for the
>> Hello. Um I met you for the first
>> speak to it and it blurs out.
>> Hello. Um I met you for the first time
last
last August.
And
And uh
last August.
And uh before
And uh before that
last August.
And uh before that I
And uh before that I was
last August.
And uh before that I was um
And uh before that I was um following
last August.
And uh before that I was um following a
teacher
teacher for
teacher for 15
teacher for 15 years.
And
>> before
>> before before
>> before before that
>> before before that what
>> she
>> she was
>> before before that what
>> she was following
>> she was following a
>> before before that what
>> she was following a teacher
>> she was following a teacher for
>> before before that what
>> she was following a teacher for 15
years.
>> Oh
>> Oh yes.
years.
>> Oh yes. having
>> Oh yes. having a
years.
>> Oh yes. having a hard
>> Oh yes. having a hard time
years.
>> Oh yes. having a hard time hearing.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. Yeah.
>> So
>> So anyway,
>> Mhm. Yeah.
>> So anyway, when
>> So anyway, when I
>> Mhm. Yeah.
>> So anyway, when I came
>> So anyway, when I came here
>> Mhm. Yeah.
>> So anyway, when I came here and
>> So anyway, when I came here and I
>> Mhm. Yeah.
>> So anyway, when I came here and I um
>> So anyway, when I came here and I um met
you,
you, it
you, it became
you, it became clear
you, it became clear to
you, it became clear to me
you, it became clear to me that
you, it became clear to me that I
you, it became clear to me that I was
you, it became clear to me that I was um
going
going in
you, it became clear to me that I was um
going in the
going in the wrong
you, it became clear to me that I was um
going in the wrong direction.
Um
it's
it's been
Um
it's been wonderful
it's been wonderful to
Um
it's been wonderful to have
it's been wonderful to have left
Um
it's been wonderful to have left my
teacher
teacher and
teacher and everything
teacher and everything and
teacher and everything and at
teacher and everything and at some
teacher and everything and at some time
uh
uh disorienting.
>> What?
>> Disorienting.
Is
Is that
Is that English?
>> Oh
>> Oh yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, disoriented.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Disoriented.
>> Yeah. Disoriented. Disoriented.
>> She's
>> She's disoriented
>> Yeah. Disoriented. Disoriented.
>> She's disoriented after
>> She's disoriented after leaving
>> Yeah. Disoriented. Disoriented.
>> She's disoriented after leaving the
teacher.
>> Oh
>> Oh yes.
teacher.
>> Oh yes. So,
>> Oh yes. So, what
teacher.
>> Oh yes. So, what kind
>> Oh yes. So, what kind of
teacher.
>> Oh yes. So, what kind of help
>> Oh yes. So, what kind of help can
teacher.
>> Oh yes. So, what kind of help can you
give
give her
give her or
give her or advice?
>> I
>> I can't
give her or advice?
>> I can't give
>> I can't give her
give her or advice?
>> I can't give her any
>> I can't give her any help
give her or advice?
>> I can't give her any help or
>> I can't give her any help or advice
about
about that.
about that. It's
about that. It's a
about that. It's a natural
about that. It's a natural phenomena.
>> I
>> I I
about that. It's a natural phenomena.
>> I I know
>> I I know what
about that. It's a natural phenomena.
>> I I know what uh
>> I I know what uh what
about that. It's a natural phenomena.
>> I I know what uh what I
>> I I know what uh what I um
about that. It's a natural phenomena.
>> I I know what uh what I um need
>> I I know what uh what I um need to
about that. It's a natural phenomena.
>> I I know what uh what I um need to do.
Actually
Actually my
Actually my my
Actually my my question
Actually my my question is
Actually my my question is um
Actually my my question is um I
Actually my my question is um I still
live
live uh
Actually my my question is um I still
live uh in
live uh in the
Actually my my question is um I still
live uh in the town
live uh in the town where
Actually my my question is um I still
live uh in the town where there
live uh in the town where there is
Actually my my question is um I still
live uh in the town where there is the
organization
>> and
>> and um
I
I am
I am questioning
I am questioning if
I am questioning if uh
I am questioning if uh it
I am questioning if uh it would
I am questioning if uh it would be
beneficial
uh
uh for
uh for me
uh for me to
uh for me to move
uh for me to move on
uh for me to move on move
uh for me to move on move out
uh for me to move on move out of
uh for me to move on move out of this
place
place and
uh for me to move on move out of this
place and stop
place and stop start
uh for me to move on move out of this
place and stop start something
place and stop start something new
somewhere
somewhere else
somewhere else or
>> let's
>> let's stop
somewhere else or
>> let's stop there
>> let's stop there what
somewhere else or
>> let's stop there what is
>> let's stop there what is your
somewhere else or
>> let's stop there what is your question
>> she
>> she wants
>> she wants to
>> she wants to know
>> she wants to know she
>> she wants to know she still
>> she wants to know she still this
organization
organization is
>> she wants to know she still this
organization is in
organization is in this
>> she wants to know she still this
organization is in this town.
organization is in this town. Yeah.
>> And
>> And she
>> And she wants
>> And she wants to
>> And she wants to know
>> And she wants to know if
>> And she wants to know if it
>> And she wants to know if it would
>> And she wants to know if it would be
beneficial
beneficial for
>> And she wants to know if it would be
beneficial for her
beneficial for her to
>> And she wants to know if it would be
beneficial for her to to
beneficial for her to to move
>> And she wants to know if it would be
beneficial for her to to move out
beneficial for her to to move out of
>> And she wants to know if it would be
beneficial for her to to move out of the
town
town and
town and move
town and move somewhere
town and move somewhere else,
town and move somewhere else, you
town and move somewhere else, you know,
or
or to
town and move somewhere else, you know,
or to stay
or to stay in
town and move somewhere else, you know,
or to stay in the
or to stay in the town.
>> What
>> What organization?
>> I
>> I don't
>> What organization?
>> I don't know
>> I don't know this
>> What organization?
>> I don't know this organization
organization
organization that
organization that she
organization that she was
organization that she was in
organization that she was in for
organization that she was in for 15
years.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. Oh,
>> Oh. Oh, a
>> Oh. Oh, a spiritual
>> Oh. Oh, a spiritual organization.
>> Yes.
>> You
>> You feel
>> You feel it's
>> You feel it's time
>> You feel it's time for
>> You feel it's time for you
>> You feel it's time for you to
>> You feel it's time for you to leave
them?
>> She
>> She did
>> She did leave
>> She did leave them.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you
>> She did leave them.
>> Oh, you did
>> Oh, you did leave
>> She did leave them.
>> Oh, you did leave them.
>> I
>> I did
>> I did leave
>> I did leave them.
>> I did leave them. Nevertheless,
>> I did leave them. Nevertheless, I
>> I did leave them. Nevertheless, I live
in
in the
>> I did leave them. Nevertheless, I live
in the same
in the same It's
>> I did leave them. Nevertheless, I live
in the same It's a
in the same It's a small
>> I did leave them. Nevertheless, I live
in the same It's a small a
in the same It's a small a very
>> I did leave them. Nevertheless, I live
in the same It's a small a very small
in the same It's a small a very small um
>> small
>> small town.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So,
>> Yeah. So, you're
>> Yeah. So, you're always
>> Yeah. So, you're always brushing
>> Yeah. So, you're always brushing elbows
with
with them.
So
So what
So what is
So what is the
So what is the comfort
So what is the comfort of
So what is the comfort of you?
So what is the comfort of you? What
So what is the comfort of you? What is
your
your comfort?
>> Are
>> Are there
>> Are there other
>> Are there other people
>> Are there other people there
>> Are there other people there that
>> Are there other people there that live
there
there that
>> Are there other people there that live
there that aren't
there that aren't part
>> Are there other people there that live
there that aren't part of
there that aren't part of this?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. In
>> Yes. In fact,
>> Yes. In fact, there's
>> Yes. In fact, there's a
>> Yes. In fact, there's a large
>> Yes. In fact, there's a large community
developing
developing that
>> Yes. In fact, there's a large community
developing that um
developing that um have
>> Yes. In fact, there's a large community
developing that um have left
developing that um have left because
>> Yes. In fact, there's a large community
developing that um have left because the
the
the teacher
>> you
>> you belong
the teacher
>> you belong to
>> you belong to the
the teacher
>> you belong to the exes
>> you belong to the exes exfollower
of
of Mongabanga.
>> Exactly.
>> Exactly. All
of Mongabanga.
>> Exactly. All right.
>> Well,
>> Well, then
>> Well, then you
>> Well, then you started
>> Well, then you started an
>> Well, then you started an ex
>> Well, then you started an ex of
Mugabanga
Mugabanga organizations.
>> Well, then you started an ex of
Mugabanga organizations. Okay.
You
You have
You have newsletters,
You have newsletters, meetings,
have
have a
You have newsletters, meetings,
have a few
have a few schnups
You have newsletters, meetings,
have a few schnups together.
>> You
>> You might
>> You might find
>> You might find comfort.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, that's
>> You might find comfort.
>> Yeah, that's pretty
>> Yeah, that's pretty common.
>> You might find comfort.
>> Yeah, that's pretty common. Pretty
common
common in
common in Sedona.
common in Sedona. It
common in Sedona. It was
common in Sedona. It was common
common in Sedona. It was common too.
common in Sedona. It was common too. You
know,
know, lots
common in Sedona. It was common too. You
know, lots of
know, lots of people
common in Sedona. It was common too. You
know, lots of people become
know, lots of people become enamored
common in Sedona. It was common too. You
know, lots of people become enamored of
some
some teacher
some teacher and
some teacher and then
some teacher and then become
disillusioned
disillusioned and
some teacher and then become
disillusioned and and
disillusioned and and then
some teacher and then become
disillusioned and and then search
disillusioned and and then search for
higher
higher teaching
higher teaching perhaps.
Yeah,
Yeah, that
higher teaching perhaps.
Yeah, that that's
Yeah, that that's very
higher teaching perhaps.
Yeah, that that's very common
Yeah, that that's very common for
higher teaching perhaps.
Yeah, that that's very common for a
spiritual
spiritual seeker
spiritual seeker to
spiritual seeker to go
spiritual seeker to go through
spiritual seeker to go through a
spiritual seeker to go through a number
of
of teachers
spiritual seeker to go through a number
of teachers and
of teachers and keep
spiritual seeker to go through a number
of teachers and keep evolving.
of teachers and keep evolving. You
spiritual seeker to go through a number
of teachers and keep evolving. You know,
what
what suffices
what suffices at
what suffices at one
what suffices at one level
what suffices at one level will
what suffices at one level will not
suffice
suffice at
what suffices at one level will not
suffice at another.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> At
>> At one
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> At one level
>> At one level you
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> At one level you want
>> At one level you want people
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> At one level you want people they
>> At one level you want people they want
to
to teach
to teach you
to teach you that
to teach you that will
to teach you that will tell
to teach you that will tell them
to teach you that will tell them what
to teach you that will tell them what to
do.
another
another level.
another level. They
another level. They want
another level. They want a
another level. They want a teacher
another level. They want a teacher that
does
does not
another level. They want a teacher that
does not tell
does not tell them
another level. They want a teacher that
does not tell them what
does not tell them what to
another level. They want a teacher that
does not tell them what to do.
>> Hello.
>> Yes.
>> Uh
>> Uh obviously
>> Uh obviously I'm
>> Uh obviously I'm very
>> Uh obviously I'm very Chinese
>> and
>> and uh
>> Uh obviously I'm very Chinese
>> and uh I
>> and uh I came
>> Uh obviously I'm very Chinese
>> and uh I came back
>> and uh I came back here
>> Uh obviously I'm very Chinese
>> and uh I came back here from
>> and uh I came back here from Shanghai
and
and I
and I live
and I live in
and I live in Shanghai
and I live in Shanghai for
and I live in Shanghai for the last
and I live in Shanghai for the last six
months.
>> Came
>> Came back
>> Came back from
>> Came back from where?
>> Shanghai,
>> Shanghai, China.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, Shanghai.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Uh
>> I
>> I I've
>> I I've been
>> I I've been in
>> I I've been in Shanghai.
>> No,
>> No, it's
>> I I've been in Shanghai.
>> No, it's very
>> No, it's very Shanghai.
>> I I've been in Shanghai.
>> No, it's very Shanghai. 1940s
1946 whenever
1946 whenever the
1946 whenever the war
1946 whenever the war was
1946 whenever the war was over
>> 49
>> we
>> we went
>> we went to
>> we went to Shanghai
>> and
>> and I
>> we went to Shanghai
>> and I used
>> and I used to
>> we went to Shanghai
>> and I used to shop
>> and I used to shop along
>> we went to Shanghai
>> and I used to shop along the
>> and I used to shop along the bund
>> bund
>> bund yes
>> the
>> the bund
>> bund yes
>> the bund and
>> the bund and uh
>> and
>> and I
>> and I loved
>> and I loved I
>> and I loved I loved
>> and I loved I loved China
>> and I loved I loved China and
>> and I loved I loved China and I
>> and I loved I loved China and I love
Shanghai
>> well
>> well I
>> well I I
>> well I I have
>> well I I have a
>> well I I have a mixed
>> well I I have a mixed uh
>> well I I have a mixed uh feeling
>> well I I have a mixed uh feeling coming
here
uh
uh one
uh one feel
uh one feel one
uh one feel one feel
uh one feel one feel is
uh one feel one feel is that
uh one feel one feel is that you
uh one feel one feel is that you might
see
see uh
uh one feel one feel is that you might
see uh uh
see uh uh the
uh one feel one feel is that you might
see uh uh the black
see uh uh the black black
uh one feel one feel is that you might
see uh uh the black black spot
see uh uh the black black spot in
uh one feel one feel is that you might
see uh uh the black black spot in my
soul.
>> My
>> My what?
>> Oh
>> Oh boy.
>> I
>> I see
>> Oh boy.
>> I see the
>> I see the black
>> Oh boy.
>> I see the black spot
>> I see the black spot on
>> Oh boy.
>> I see the black spot on his
>> I see the black spot on his soul.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. Oh.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. But
>> Oh. Oh.
>> Yeah. But I
>> if
>> if I
>> if I got
>> if I got my
>> if I got my soul
>> if I got my soul eraser
>> if I got my soul eraser with
>> if I got my soul eraser with me.
>> Yeah.
>> But
>> But then
>> But then uh
>> But then uh I
>> But then uh I I
>> But then uh I I uh
>> But then uh I I uh I
>> But then uh I I uh I learned
>> But then uh I I uh I learned about
>> But then uh I I uh I learned about you
four
four years
>> But then uh I I uh I learned about you
four years and
four years and uh
>> But then uh I I uh I learned about you
four years and uh two
four years and uh two months
>> But then uh I I uh I learned about you
four years and uh two months ago
four years and uh two months ago through
uh
uh a
uh a power
uh a power of
uh a power of intention
uh a power of intention of
uh a power of intention of wind
uh a power of intention of wind dial's
book.
book. among
uh a power of intention of wind dial's
book. among all
book. among all these
uh a power of intention of wind dial's
book. among all these thousands
book. among all these thousands of
uh a power of intention of wind dial's
book. among all these thousands of words
I
I I
I I see
I I see the
I I see the David
I I see the David Hogan's
I I see the David Hogan's name
I I see the David Hogan's name in
I I see the David Hogan's name in the
book
book and
I I see the David Hogan's name in the
book and I
book and I think
I I see the David Hogan's name in the
book and I think comically
book and I think comically uh
I I see the David Hogan's name in the
book and I think comically uh I
book and I think comically uh I went
about
about the
about the book
about the book and
about the book and uh
about the book and uh read
about the book and uh read that
about the book and uh read that and
after
after that
about the book and uh read that and
after that I
after that I read
about the book and uh read that and
after that I read it
after that I read it many
about the book and uh read that and
after that I read it many times.
after that I read it many times. I
about the book and uh read that and
after that I read it many times. I think
the
the 45
the 45 points
the 45 points has
the 45 points has pushed
the 45 points has pushed me
the 45 points has pushed me uh
the 45 points has pushed me uh up
the 45 points has pushed me uh up a
the 45 points has pushed me uh up a lot.
And
And uh
the 45 points has pushed me uh up a lot.
And uh I
And uh I uh
the 45 points has pushed me uh up a lot.
And uh I uh bought
And uh I uh bought maybe
the 45 points has pushed me uh up a lot.
And uh I uh bought maybe 15
And uh I uh bought maybe 15 books
the 45 points has pushed me uh up a lot.
And uh I uh bought maybe 15 books or
And uh I uh bought maybe 15 books or 20
sent
sent it
sent it to
sent it to a
sent it to a friend
sent it to a friend and
sent it to a friend and uh
sent it to a friend and uh surprisingly
and
and later
sent it to a friend and uh surprisingly
and later not
and later not surprisingly
sent it to a friend and uh surprisingly
and later not surprisingly that
and later not surprisingly that only
sent it to a friend and uh surprisingly
and later not surprisingly that only one
that
that I
that I know
that I know got
that I know got read.
>> One
>> One soul
that I know got read.
>> One soul saved
>> One soul saved is
that I know got read.
>> One soul saved is worth
>> One soul saved is worth a
that I know got read.
>> One soul saved is worth a lifetime.
But
But but
But but anyway,
But but anyway, uh
I'm
I'm very
But but anyway, uh
I'm very uh
I'm very uh blessed
But but anyway, uh
I'm very uh blessed and
I'm very uh blessed and uh
But but anyway, uh
I'm very uh blessed and uh I
I'm very uh blessed and uh I didn't
But but anyway, uh
I'm very uh blessed and uh I didn't get
uh
>> brainwashed
>> brainwashed too
uh
>> brainwashed too much
>> brainwashed too much until
uh
>> brainwashed too much until until
>> brainwashed too much until until I
uh
>> brainwashed too much until until I I
need
uh
uh reading
need
uh reading glass.
>> Yes.
>> At
>> At about
>> Yes.
>> At about 49
>> At about 49 years
>> Yes.
>> At about 49 years old.
>> And
>> Yes.
>> And before
>> And before that
>> Yes.
>> And before that I
>> And before that I didn't
>> Yes.
>> And before that I didn't read
>> And before that I didn't read a
>> Yes.
>> And before that I didn't read a book.
>> And
>> Yes.
>> And you
>> And you probably
>> Yes.
>> And you probably the
>> And you probably the first
>> Yes.
>> And you probably the first book
>> And you probably the first book and
>> Yes.
>> And you probably the first book and then
I
I read
I read all
I read all of
I read all of your
I read all of your books.
>> Wow.
>> Wow. And
I read all of your books.
>> Wow. And then
>> Wow. And then I
I read all of your books.
>> Wow. And then I went
>> Wow. And then I went to
I read all of your books.
>> Wow. And then I went to W
>> Wow. And then I went to W Paul
I read all of your books.
>> Wow. And then I went to W Paul and
>> Wow. And then I went to W Paul and uh
and
and in
and in Chinese
and in Chinese version
and in Chinese version of
and in Chinese version of course
and in Chinese version of course I
couldn't
couldn't find
and in Chinese version of course I
couldn't find English
couldn't find English version.
and in Chinese version of course I
couldn't find English version. Anyway
couldn't find English version. Anyway uh
went
went to
went to Bvaga
went to Bvaga that
went to Bvaga that really
went to Bvaga that really blow
went to Bvaga that really blow me
went to Bvaga that really blow me away.
>> Went
>> Went where
>> he
>> he read
>> he read the
>> Bavaga.
>> Oh
>> Oh yes
>> Oh yes many
>> Oh yes many times.
>> Oh
>> Oh yes.
>> Oh yes many times.
>> Oh yes. Yes.
>> And
>> And Rick
>> And Rick Vida
>> And Rick Vida is
>> And Rick Vida is very
>> And Rick Vida is very hard
>> And Rick Vida is very hard to
>> And Rick Vida is very hard to read
>> And Rick Vida is very hard to read and
glamour
glamour is
>> And Rick Vida is very hard to read and
glamour is very
glamour is very hard
>> And Rick Vida is very hard to read and
glamour is very hard to
glamour is very hard to read
>> And Rick Vida is very hard to read and
glamour is very hard to read also.
glamour is very hard to read also. And
>> And Rick Vida is very hard to read and
glamour is very hard to read also. And I
went
went went
went went bought
went went bought the
went went bought the great
went went bought the great great
went went bought the great great book
went went bought the great great book of
western
western world
went went bought the great great book of
western world the
western world the great
went went bought the great great book of
western world the great books
western world the great books and
went went bought the great great book of
western world the great books and uh
western world the great books and uh uh
I
I I
I I enjoy
I I enjoy it
I I enjoy it and
I I enjoy it and I
I I enjoy it and I read
I I enjoy it and I read the
I I enjoy it and I read the St.
Augustine's
Augustine's confession.
I I enjoy it and I read the St.
Augustine's confession. It
Augustine's confession. It was
>> that
>> that a
>> that a good
>> that a good one.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I
>> that a good one.
>> Yeah. I thought
>> Yeah. I thought I
>> that a good one.
>> Yeah. I thought I thought
>> Yeah. I thought I thought everything
every
every uh
every uh pastor
every uh pastor should
every uh pastor should read
every uh pastor should read that
every uh pastor should read that first
before
before they
every uh pastor should read that first
before they preach.
before they preach. But
every uh pastor should read that first
before they preach. But anyways,
before they preach. But anyways, I
every uh pastor should read that first
before they preach. But anyways, I have
only
only one
only one question
only one question to
only one question to uh
only one question to uh ask
only one question to uh ask allowed
only one question to uh ask allowed to
ask
ask one
only one question to uh ask allowed to
ask one question
ask one question but
>> one's
>> one's enough.
>> one's enough. Okay.
about
about nothingness.
uh
uh somewhere
uh somewhere you
uh somewhere you you
uh somewhere you you mentioned
uh somewhere you you mentioned that
nothingness
nothingness is
uh somewhere you you mentioned that
nothingness is not
nothingness is not existence
uh somewhere you you mentioned that
nothingness is not existence or
nothingness is not existence or is
uh somewhere you you mentioned that
nothingness is not existence or is not
nothingness is not existence or is not a
reality
and
and I
reality
and I thought
and I thought uh
reality
and I thought uh I
and I thought uh I I
reality
and I thought uh I I I
and I thought uh I I I I
reality
and I thought uh I I I I thought
and I thought uh I I I I thought about
that
that and
that and uh
that and uh during
that and uh during my
that and uh during my study
that and uh during my study of
that and uh during my study of uh
creation
creation of
that and uh during my study of uh
creation of the
creation of the universe
that and uh during my study of uh
creation of the universe I
creation of the universe I thought
that and uh during my study of uh
creation of the universe I thought maybe
it's
it's it
it's it is
it's it is existence
uh
uh in
it's it is existence
uh in a
uh in a no
it's it is existence
uh in a no mind
uh in a no mind mind
and
and the
and the mind
and the mind cannot
and the mind cannot have
and the mind cannot have uh
and the mind cannot have uh nothingness
and
and somewhere
I
I think
I think it's
I think it's uh
I think it's uh you
I think it's uh you also
I think it's uh you also in
I think it's uh you also in St.
Augustine
Augustine book
I think it's uh you also in St.
Augustine book and
Augustine book and he
I think it's uh you also in St.
Augustine book and he said
Augustine book and he said before
I think it's uh you also in St.
Augustine book and he said before God
there's
there's nothing.
there's nothing. So
there's nothing. So it
there's nothing. So it seems
there's nothing. So it seems like
there's
there's everything
there's nothing. So it seems like
there's everything has
there's everything has to
there's nothing. So it seems like
there's everything has to be
there's everything has to be from
nothing
nothing although
nothing although it's
nothing although it's not
nothing although it's not the
nothing although it's not the ultimate
uh
uh uh
nothing although it's not the ultimate
uh uh will
uh uh will and
nothing although it's not the ultimate
uh uh will and uh
uh uh will and uh so
nothing although it's not the ultimate
uh uh will and uh so I
uh uh will and uh so I thought
nothing although it's not the ultimate
uh uh will and uh so I thought the
nothingness
nothingness has
nothingness has to
nothingness has to be
nothingness has to be in
nothingness has to be in a
nothingness has to be in a no
nothingness has to be in a no mind
nothingness has to be in a no mind mind
which
which I
nothingness has to be in a no mind mind
which I think
which I think is
nothingness has to be in a no mind mind
which I think is one
which I think is one post
nothingness has to be in a no mind mind
which I think is one post no
which I think is one post no mind
nothingness has to be in a no mind mind
which I think is one post no mind mind
which I think is one post no mind mind I
I
I explain
>> no
>> no mind
I explain
>> no mind mind
>> no mind mind is
I explain
>> no mind mind is different
>> no mind mind is different than
nothingness
>> I
>> I would
nothingness
>> I would say
>> I would say I
nothingness
>> I would say I would
>> I would say I would think
nothingness
>> I would say I would think I
>> I would say I would think I don't
nothingness
>> I would say I would think I don't know
>> I would say I would think I don't know I
think
think I
think I would
think I would think
think I would think But
think I would think But it's
think I would think But it's a
think I would think But it's a mind
think I would think But it's a mind with
no
no mind.
think I would think But it's a mind with
no mind. It's
no mind. It's not
think I would think But it's a mind with
no mind. It's not it's
no mind. It's not it's different
think I would think But it's a mind with
no mind. It's not it's different from
nothingness.
nothingness. But
nothingness. But nothing
>> mind
>> mind with
nothingness. But nothing
>> mind with a
>> mind with a capital
nothingness. But nothing
>> mind with a capital M
>> mind with a capital M with
nothingness. But nothing
>> mind with a capital M with no
>> mind with a capital M with no mind
nothingness. But nothing
>> mind with a capital M with no mind with
a
a small
a small M.
a small M. Yeah.
a small M. Yeah. That
a small M. Yeah. That means
a small M. Yeah. That means no
conceptual
conceptual mind
but
but there
but there is
but there is still
but there is still awareness.
but there is still awareness. So
but there is still awareness. So capital
M
M mind
but there is still awareness. So capital
M mind with
M mind with no
but there is still awareness. So capital
M mind with no thought
with
with no
with no small
with no small mind
with no small mind is
with no small mind is still
with no small mind is still awareness.
In
In fact,
with no small mind is still awareness.
In fact, when
In fact, when the
with no small mind is still awareness.
In fact, when the mind
In fact, when the mind stops
there
there with
there with a
there with a successful
there with a successful spiritual
there with a successful spiritual work,
there
there is
there with a successful spiritual work,
there is only
there is only awareness.
Awareness
Awareness with
Awareness with no
Awareness with no subject
Awareness with no subject and
Awareness with no subject and no
Awareness with no subject and no object.
No
No entity
Awareness with no subject and no object.
No entity who
No entity who is
Awareness with no subject and no object.
No entity who is aware.
No entity who is aware. It's
Awareness with no subject and no object.
No entity who is aware. It's only
awareness
awareness being
awareness being that
awareness being that which
awareness being that which it
awareness being that which it is.
Awareness
Awareness is
awareness being that which it is.
Awareness is awareness
Awareness is awareness is
awareness being that which it is.
Awareness is awareness is awareness.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. I
>> Thank you very much. I need
>> Thank you very much. I need to
>> Thank you very much. I need to take
>> Thank you very much. I need to take a
picture
picture so
>> Thank you very much. I need to take a
picture so I
picture so I can
>> Thank you very much. I need to take a
picture so I can take
picture so I can take back
>> Thank you very much. I need to take a
picture so I can take back to
picture so I can take back to Shanghai.
And
And also
And also I
And also I tried
And also I tried to
And also I tried to translate
And also I tried to translate your
And also I tried to translate your power
versus
versus for
And also I tried to translate your power
versus for them
versus for them 18
And also I tried to translate your power
versus for them 18 way
versus for them 18 way then
And also I tried to translate your power
versus for them 18 way then I
versus for them 18 way then I gave
And also I tried to translate your power
versus for them 18 way then I gave up
because
because uh
because uh it's
because uh it's it's
because uh it's it's very
because uh it's it's very hard
because uh it's it's very hard to
translate
translate but
because uh it's it's very hard to
translate but uh
translate but uh uh
because uh it's it's very hard to
translate but uh uh maybe
translate but uh uh maybe it
because uh it's it's very hard to
translate but uh uh maybe it won't
translate but uh uh maybe it won't sell
either
>> is
>> I
>> I give
>> I give away
>> I give away fortune
>> I give away fortune cookies
>> I give away fortune cookies with
>> I give away fortune cookies with each
copy.
>> Is
>> Is Carol
>> Is Carol here?
Thank
Thank you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Is
>> Is Carol
>> Thank you.
>> Is Carol Davis
>> Is Carol Davis here?
>> You
>> You see
>> You see why
>> You see why I
>> You see why I love
>> You see why I love I
>> You see why I love I love
>> You see why I love I love the
>> You see why I love I love the Chinese
people
people when
>> You see why I love I love the Chinese
people when I
people when I was
>> You see why I love I love the Chinese
people when I was there.
people when I was there. I
>> You see why I love I love the Chinese
people when I was there. I was
>> in
>> in connection.
>> I
>> I was
>> in connection.
>> I was in
>> I was in love
>> in connection.
>> I was in love with
>> I was in love with China
>> in connection.
>> I was in love with China and
>> I was in love with China and the
>> in connection.
>> I was in love with China and the Chinese
people.
>> Dr.
>> Dr. Hawkins,
people.
>> Dr. Hawkins, such
>> Dr. Hawkins, such a
people.
>> Dr. Hawkins, such a privilege
>> Dr. Hawkins, such a privilege to
people.
>> Dr. Hawkins, such a privilege to be
here.
here. Yes.
here. Yes. Um
here. Yes. Um the
here. Yes. Um the question
here. Yes. Um the question I've
here. Yes. Um the question I've got
relates
relates to
here. Yes. Um the question I've got
relates to an
relates to an area
here. Yes. Um the question I've got
relates to an area that
relates to an area that I
here. Yes. Um the question I've got
relates to an area that I find
relates to an area that I find comes
here. Yes. Um the question I've got
relates to an area that I find comes up
a
a lot
a lot in
a lot in my
a lot in my work,
a lot in my work, which
a lot in my work, which is
a lot in my work, which is really
working
working principally
a lot in my work, which is really
working principally in
working principally in businesses
a lot in my work, which is really
working principally in businesses with
leaders,
leaders, helping
leaders, helping them
leaders, helping them to
leaders, helping them to be
leaders, helping them to be more
effective.
effective. And
leaders, helping them to be more
effective. And in
effective. And in a
leaders, helping them to be more
effective. And in a lot
effective. And in a lot of
leaders, helping them to be more
effective. And in a lot of the
effective. And in a lot of the spiritual
teachings,
teachings, there's
teachings, there's talk
teachings, there's talk about
teachings, there's talk about dharma
teachings, there's talk about dharma and
our
our purpose
teachings, there's talk about dharma and
our purpose in
our purpose in life.
teachings, there's talk about dharma and
our purpose in life. And
our purpose in life. And I
teachings, there's talk about dharma and
our purpose in life. And I wondered
whether
whether you
whether you support
whether you support the
whether you support the idea
whether you support the idea that
whether you support the idea that when
we
we come
whether you support the idea that when
we come here,
we come here, we
whether you support the idea that when
we come here, we do
we come here, we do have
whether you support the idea that when
we come here, we do have a
we come here, we do have a purpose.
whether you support the idea that when
we come here, we do have a purpose. And
specifically
specifically whether
specifically whether when
specifically whether when we're
specifically whether when we're seeking
our
our purpose
specifically whether when we're seeking
our purpose and
our purpose and this
specifically whether when we're seeking
our purpose and this is
our purpose and this is something
specifically whether when we're seeking
our purpose and this is something which
I
I experience
I experience a
I experience a lot
I experience a lot and
I experience a lot and I
I experience a lot and I also
I experience a lot and I also find
I experience a lot and I also find that
when
when I'm
I experience a lot and I also find that
when I'm working
when I'm working with
I experience a lot and I also find that
when I'm working with people
when I'm working with people to
I experience a lot and I also find that
when I'm working with people to help
them
them to
them to advance,
them to advance, they
them to advance, they also
them to advance, they also seem
them to advance, they also seem to
them to advance, they also seem to find
this
this challenge
them to advance, they also seem to find
this challenge coming
this challenge coming up
them to advance, they also seem to find
this challenge coming up a
this challenge coming up a lot.
them to advance, they also seem to find
this challenge coming up a lot. the
this challenge coming up a lot. the more
the
the more
the more we
the more we want
the more we want something,
the more we want something, the
the more we want something, the more
there
there seem
the more we want something, the more
there seem to
there seem to be
the more we want something, the more
there seem to be obstacles
there seem to be obstacles in
the more we want something, the more
there seem to be obstacles in the
there seem to be obstacles in the way.
And
And I've
And I've heard
And I've heard from
And I've heard from a
And I've heard from a lot
And I've heard from a lot of
And I've heard from a lot of personal
development
development teachers
And I've heard from a lot of personal
development teachers that
development teachers that that's
actually
actually indication
actually indication that
actually indication that you
actually indication that you are
actually indication that you are on
actually indication that you are on your
purpose.
purpose. So
actually indication that you are on your
purpose. So the
purpose. So the greater
actually indication that you are on your
purpose. So the greater the
purpose. So the greater the resistance
you're
you're feeling
you're feeling to
you're feeling to actually
you're feeling to actually doing
something,
something, the
you're feeling to actually doing
something, the more
something, the more that
you're feeling to actually doing
something, the more that is
something, the more that is a
you're feeling to actually doing
something, the more that is a good
indication
indication that
indication that the
indication that the path
indication that the path you're
indication that the path you're on.
>> That's
>> That's a
indication that the path you're on.
>> That's a question.
>> That's a question. So
indication that the path you're on.
>> That's a question. So is
>> That's a question. So is is
>> is
>> is there
>> is there something
>> is there something like
>> is there something like dharma
>> is there something like dharma which
>> is there something like dharma which is
is
is our
>> is there something like dharma which is
is our purpose
is our purpose and
>> is there something like dharma which is
is our purpose and we
is our purpose and we come
>> is there something like dharma which is
is our purpose and we come here
is our purpose and we come here to
fulfill
fulfill a
fulfill a purpose
fulfill a purpose and
fulfill a purpose and if
fulfill a purpose and if so
fulfill a purpose and if so is
fulfill a purpose and if so is the
degree
degree of
fulfill a purpose and if so is the
degree of resistance
degree of resistance that
fulfill a purpose and if so is the
degree of resistance that we're
degree of resistance that we're feeling
towards
towards moving
towards moving in
towards moving in cert
towards moving in cert in
towards moving in cert in a
towards moving in cert in a certain
direction
direction an
towards moving in cert in a certain
direction an indication
direction an indication of
towards moving in cert in a certain
direction an indication of how
direction an indication of how close
towards moving in cert in a certain
direction an indication of how close to
that
that path
that path we're
that path we're on?
>> I
>> I can't
that path we're on?
>> I can't answer.
>> I can't answer. It's
that path we're on?
>> I can't answer. It's too
>> I can't answer. It's too complicated
that path we're on?
>> I can't answer. It's too complicated a
question.
>> Okay.
>> Shorter
>> Shorter and
>> Shorter and sweeter.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Shorter
>> Shorter and sweeter.
>> Okay. Shorter and
>> Okay. Shorter and sweeter.
>> Shorter and sweeter.
>> Okay. Shorter and sweeter. I
>> Okay. Shorter and sweeter. I suppose
>> Shorter and sweeter.
>> Okay. Shorter and sweeter. I suppose the
it's
it's whether
it's whether or
it's whether or not
we
we experience
it's whether or not
we experience greater
we experience greater resistance
it's whether or not
we experience greater resistance to
taking
taking action.
>> You
>> You where
taking action.
>> You where do
>> You where do you
taking action.
>> You where do you get
>> You where do you get that
taking action.
>> You where do you get that from?
>> You where do you get that from? You
don't
don't get
don't get where
don't get where you
>> from
>> from from
don't get where you
>> from from many
>> from from many from
don't get where you
>> from from many from many
>> from from many from many people
don't get where you
>> from from many from many people that
I've
I've I've
I've I've read
I've I've read about
I've I've read about in
I've I've read about in the
I've I've read about in the personal
development
development field
I've I've read about in the personal
development field that
development field that if
I've I've read about in the personal
development field that if you
development field that if you are
I've I've read about in the personal
development field that if you are if
you're
you're if
you're if you're
you're if you're moving
you're if you're moving if
you're if you're moving if you're
seeking
seeking towards
you're if you're moving if you're
seeking towards to
seeking towards to move
you're if you're moving if you're
seeking towards to move towards
something
something that's
something that's important
something that's important to
something that's important to you
something that's important to you that
you'll
you'll feel
something that's important to you that
you'll feel a
you'll feel a lot
something that's important to you that
you'll feel a lot of
you'll feel a lot of resistance
something that's important to you that
you'll feel a lot of resistance to
taking
taking positive
taking positive action.
>> Well,
>> Well, that's
taking positive action.
>> Well, that's a
>> Well, that's a belief
taking positive action.
>> Well, that's a belief system.
>> Well, that's a belief system. There's
taking positive action.
>> Well, that's a belief system. There's no
quite
quite the
quite the opposite.
quite the opposite. The
quite the opposite. The closer
quite the opposite. The closer you
quite the opposite. The closer you get,
the
the more
quite the opposite. The closer you get,
the more excited
the more excited and
quite the opposite. The closer you get,
the more excited and delighted
the more excited and delighted you
quite the opposite. The closer you get,
the more excited and delighted you get.
I
I I
I I know
I I know that
I I know that I
I I know that I would
I I know that I would certainly
I I know that I would certainly have
experienced
experienced that
I I know that I would certainly have
experienced that once
experienced that once you
I I know that I would certainly have
experienced that once you start
experienced that once you start to
I I know that I would certainly have
experienced that once you start to make
progress,
progress, you
progress, you start
progress, you start to
progress, you start to get
progress, you start to get that
progress, you start to get that the
self-belief,
self-belief, the
progress, you start to get that the
self-belief, the self-esteem
self-belief, the self-esteem starts
progress, you start to get that the
self-belief, the self-esteem starts to
grow.
grow. Um,
grow. Um, but
grow. Um, but often
grow. Um, but often my
grow. Um, but often my experience
grow. Um, but often my experience is
that
that people
grow. Um, but often my experience is
that people have
that people have major
grow. Um, but often my experience is
that people have major a
that people have major a major
grow. Um, but often my experience is
that people have major a major block
that people have major a major block to
moving
moving forward.
>> The
>> The best
moving forward.
>> The best thing
>> The best thing to
moving forward.
>> The best thing to do
>> The best thing to do is
moving forward.
>> The best thing to do is don't
>> The best thing to do is don't set
moving forward.
>> The best thing to do is don't set a
particular
particular goal
particular goal or
particular goal or demand
particular goal or demand or
expectation.
Let's
Let's say
Let's say you
Let's say you you
Let's say you you want
Let's say you you want to
Let's say you you want to be
Let's say you you want to be as
Let's say you you want to be as loving
as
as possible
Let's say you you want to be as loving
as possible towards
as possible towards all
Let's say you you want to be as loving
as possible towards all that
as possible towards all that exists.
Let's say you you want to be as loving
as possible towards all that exists. So
you
you hold
you hold that
you hold that in
you hold that in mind
you hold that in mind as
you hold that in mind as an
you hold that in mind as an ideal.
you hold that in mind as an ideal. It's
an
an ideal.
you hold that in mind as an ideal. It's
an ideal. So
an ideal. So it's
you hold that in mind as an ideal. It's
an ideal. So it's not
an ideal. So it's not a
you hold that in mind as an ideal. It's
an ideal. So it's not a direction.
an ideal. So it's not a direction. It's
not
not a
not a goal.
not a goal. You
not a goal. You can't
not a goal. You can't measure
not a goal. You can't measure whether
you're
you're closer
not a goal. You can't measure whether
you're closer or
you're closer or farther
not a goal. You can't measure whether
you're closer or farther from
you're closer or farther from it.
not a goal. You can't measure whether
you're closer or farther from it. You
see?
>> So
>> So you're
see?
>> So you're trying
>> So you're trying you're
see?
>> So you're trying you're you're
>> So you're trying you're you're trying
see?
>> So you're trying you're you're trying to
be
be literal.
The
The general
be literal.
The general feeling
The general feeling of
be literal.
The general feeling of being
appreciative
appreciative of
appreciative of all
appreciative of all of
appreciative of all of life,
loving
loving towards
appreciative of all of life,
loving towards all
loving towards all of
appreciative of all of life,
loving towards all of life
loving towards all of life to
appreciative of all of life,
loving towards all of life to the
loving towards all of life to the best
that
that you're
that you're capable,
you
you know,
that you're capable,
you know, is
you know, is a
that you're capable,
you know, is a generality.
you know, is a generality. There's
that you're capable,
you know, is a generality. There's not
you know, is a generality. There's not a
specific.
specific. It
specific. It doesn't
specific. It doesn't mean
specific. It doesn't mean I
specific. It doesn't mean I have
specific. It doesn't mean I have to
specific. It doesn't mean I have to love
this
this Diet
specific. It doesn't mean I have to love
this Diet Pepsi
this Diet Pepsi can,
specific. It doesn't mean I have to love
this Diet Pepsi can, you
this Diet Pepsi can, you know,
specific. It doesn't mean I have to love
this Diet Pepsi can, you know, as
this Diet Pepsi can, you know, as much
as
as I
as I do
as I do my
as I do my wife.
as I do my wife. You
as I do my wife. You see?
>> Mhm.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, now
>> Thank you.
>> Okay, now I'll
>> Okay, now I'll take
>> Thank you.
>> Okay, now I'll take my
>> Okay, now I'll take my wife
>> Thank you.
>> Okay, now I'll take my wife before
>> Okay, now I'll take my wife before the
Diet
Diet Pepsi
Diet Pepsi can.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, that's
Diet Pepsi can.
>> Oh, that's sweet.
>> I
>> I thought
>> I thought she
>> I thought she always
>> I thought she always I
>> I thought she always I thought
>> I thought she always I thought it
>> I thought she always I thought it would
touch
touch your
>> I thought she always I thought it would
touch your heart,
touch your heart, love.
>> It
>> It did.
>> Can
>> Can I
>> It did.
>> Can I get
>> Can I get some
>> It did.
>> Can I get some photo
>> Can I get some photo with
>> It did.
>> Can I get some photo with my
>> Can I get some photo with my fiance?
>> Huh?
>> He
>> He wants
>> Huh?
>> He wants a
>> He wants a picture.
>> Huh?
>> He wants a picture. We
>> He wants a picture. We we'd
>> Huh?
>> He wants a picture. We we'd like
>> He wants a picture. We we'd like you
>> Huh?
>> He wants a picture. We we'd like you to
bless
bless our
bless our spiritual
bless our spiritual paths
bless our spiritual paths and
bless our spiritual paths and just
bless our spiritual paths and just get
bless our spiritual paths and just get a
photo
photo together.
>> I
>> I can't
>> I can't hear
>> I can't hear what
>> I can't hear what he's
>> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> What
>> What do
>> I can't hear what he's saying.
>> What do you
>> What do you want?
>> Trouble
>> Trouble hearing
>> Trouble hearing up
>> Trouble hearing up here
>> Trouble hearing up here on
>> Trouble hearing up here on stage
>> Trouble hearing up here on stage for
some
some reason.
>> Trouble hearing up here on stage for
some reason. I
some reason. I don't
>> Trouble hearing up here on stage for
some reason. I don't know.
>> There's
>> There's an
>> There's an echo
>> There's an echo from
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You
>> There's an echo from
>> Yeah. You might
>> Yeah. You might just
>> There's an echo from
>> Yeah. You might just want
>> Yeah. You might just want to
>> There's an echo from
>> Yeah. You might just want to take
>> Yeah. You might just want to take a
picture.
picture. That's
picture. That's easy
picture. That's easy enough.
Yeah.
Yeah. Uhhuh.
>> Wonderful.
Yeah.
>> Wonderful. Thank
>> Wonderful. Thank you
Yeah.
>> Wonderful. Thank you so
>> Wonderful. Thank you so much.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you
>> Thank you. Thank you so
>> Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you so much. Thank you.
>> Uhhuh.
>> One
>> One more.
>> One more. We're
>> One more. We're getting
>> One more. We're getting He
>> One more. We're getting He already
signed
signed this.
>> How's
>> How's it
>> How's it done?
>> No.
>> No. Sign
>> How's it done?
>> No. Sign it
>> No. Sign it here.
>> How's it done?
>> No. Sign it here. They
>> No. Sign it here. They drove
>> How's it done?
>> No. Sign it here. They drove down
>> No. Sign it here. They drove down that
they
they wanted
they wanted you
they wanted you to
they wanted you to sign
they wanted you to sign it
they wanted you to sign it there.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> What?
>> What? What?
>> What? What? Oh,
>> What? What? Oh, why
>> What? What? Oh, why you
>> What? What? Oh, why you got
>> What? What? Oh, why you got it?
>> What? What? Oh, why you got it? Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I
>> What? What? Oh, why you got it? Okay.
>> Okay. I just
>> Okay. I just wanted
>> What? What? Oh, why you got it? Okay.
>> Okay. I just wanted to
>> Okay. I just wanted to say
>> What? What? Oh, why you got it? Okay.
>> Okay. I just wanted to say thank
>> Okay. I just wanted to say thank you.
>> Yes.
>> So,
>> So, and
>> Yes.
>> So, and I
>> So, and I have
>> Yes.
>> So, and I have a
>> So, and I have a picture
>> Yes.
>> So, and I have a picture that
>> So, and I have a picture that needs
>> Yes.
>> So, and I have a picture that needs to
be
be taken.
>> You
>> You bet.
be taken.
>> You bet. Yes.
>> You bet. Yes. It's
be taken.
>> You bet. Yes. It's my
>> You bet. Yes. It's my pleasure.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, indeed.
>> W
Thank
Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Thank
Thank you.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Thank you. Yes.
Okay.
Okay. Come
Okay. Come on.
Okay. Come on. We
Okay. Come on. We got
Okay. Come on. We got lots
Okay. Come on. We got lots of
Okay. Come on. We got lots of people.
>> Woofy.
>> Woofy. Woofy
Okay. Come on. We got lots of people.
>> Woofy. Woofy woof.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. Uh,
>> Yep. Uh, I
>> Yep. Uh, I just
>> Yep. Uh, I just think
>> someone
>> someone lost.
>> Yep. Uh, I just think
>> someone lost. Is
>> someone lost. Is this
>> Yep. Uh, I just think
>> someone lost. Is this someone's
>> someone lost. Is this someone's pen?
>> You
>> You got
>> You got You
>> You got You got
>> You got You got a
>> You got You got a freebie.
>> You got You got a freebie. Hand
>> You got You got a freebie. Hand it
>> You got You got a freebie. Hand it over.
>> I
>> I just
>> You got You got a freebie. Hand it over.
>> I just I
>> I just I just
>> You got You got a freebie. Hand it over.
>> I just I just think
>> I just I just think it'll
>> You got You got a freebie. Hand it over.
>> I just I just think it'll be
>> I just I just think it'll be good.
>> Quite
>> Quite a
>> Quite a collection,
>> Quite a collection, Phil.
>> Yes.
>> I
>> I just
>> I just think
>> I just think it'll
>> I just think it'll be
>> I just think it'll be good
>> I just think it'll be good for
>> I just think it'll be good for me
>> I just think it'll be good for me to
hear
hear you
>> I just think it'll be good for me to
hear you say
hear you say it.
>> I just think it'll be good for me to
hear you say it. Um,
hear you say it. Um, is
>> I just think it'll be good for me to
hear you say it. Um, is there
hear you say it. Um, is there a
>> I just think it'll be good for me to
hear you say it. Um, is there a one
hear you say it. Um, is there a one true
God
God that's
God that's infinite
God that's infinite love
God that's infinite love and
God that's infinite love and peace?
>> Is
>> Is there
God that's infinite love and peace?
>> Is there one
>> Is there one true
God that's infinite love and peace?
>> Is there one true God
>> Is there one true God with
God that's infinite love and peace?
>> Is there one true God with that
>> Is there one true God with that is
infinite
infinite love
infinite love and
infinite love and peace?
>> That
>> That is
infinite love and peace?
>> That is true.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Whose
>> Whose pen
>> Thank you.
>> Whose pen is
>> Whose pen is that?
>> Thank you.
>> Whose pen is that? I'm
>> Whose pen is that? I'm sorry.
>> Thank you.
>> Whose pen is that? I'm sorry. I
>> Whose pen is that? I'm sorry. I was
joking
joking about
joking about it.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, we'll
joking about it.
>> Okay, we'll leave
>> Okay, we'll leave it
joking about it.
>> Okay, we'll leave it there.
>> Yes.
Well,
Well, um,
>> Yes.
Well, um, first
Well, um, first of
>> Yes.
Well, um, first of all,
Well, um, first of all, I'd
>> Yes.
Well, um, first of all, I'd like
Well, um, first of all, I'd like to
thank
thank you
thank you for
thank you for your
thank you for your teaching,
thank you for your teaching, and
thank you for your teaching, and I'd
also
also like
thank you for your teaching, and I'd
also like to
also like to know
from
from your
from your experience,
what
what are
from your experience,
what are some
what are some of
from your experience,
what are some of the
what are some of the most
from your experience,
what are some of the most important
things
things someone
things someone can
things someone can do
to
to increase
things someone can do
to increase their
to increase their intention
on
on the
on the spiritual
on the spiritual path?
What
What can
on the spiritual path?
What can he
What can he do
on the spiritual path?
What can he do that
What can he do that what
>> that
>> that would
>> that would increase
>> that would increase one's
>> that would increase one's intention
>> that would increase one's intention on
the
the spiritual
>> that would increase one's intention on
the spiritual path?
the spiritual path? What's
>> that would increase one's intention on
the spiritual path? What's one
the spiritual path? What's one one
lesson?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
lesson?
>> Oh, I don't
>> Oh, I don't think
lesson?
>> Oh, I don't think you
>> Oh, I don't think you can
lesson?
>> Oh, I don't think you can fiddle
>> Oh, I don't think you can fiddle with
intention.
You
You either
intention.
You either wish
You either wish well
intention.
You either wish well towards
You either wish well towards all
intention.
You either wish well towards all of
You either wish well towards all of life
and
and all
and all its
and all its expressions.
and all its expressions. You
and all its expressions. You don't
and all its expressions. You don't if
you
you don't,
and all its expressions. You don't if
you don't, you
you don't, you need
and all its expressions. You don't if
you don't, you need a
you don't, you need a doctor.
When
When you
When you see
When you see the
When you see the beauty
When you see the beauty of
When you see the beauty of all
existence,
the
the automatic
the automatic response
the automatic response is
the automatic response is to
the automatic response is to appreciate
and
uh
uh love
uh love all
uh love all that
uh love all that exists
uh love all that exists for
uh love all that exists for its
intrinsic
intrinsic beauty.
You
You love
You love your
You love your doggy,
You love your doggy, you
You love your doggy, you love
You love your doggy, you love your
kitty,
kitty, you
You love your doggy, you love your
kitty, you love
kitty, you love the
You love your doggy, you love your
kitty, you love the neighbors,
and
and you
and you love
and you love mankind
for
for all
and you love mankind
for all its
for all its limit
and you love mankind
for all its limit despite
for all its limit despite all
and you love mankind
for all its limit despite all its
limitations.
So
So that's
limitations.
So that's a
So that's a decision
limitations.
So that's a decision of
So that's a decision of your
limitations.
So that's a decision of your intention
of
of goodwill
of goodwill towards
of goodwill towards all
of goodwill towards all of
of goodwill towards all of life.
Good
Good will
of goodwill towards all of life.
Good will towards
Good will towards all
of goodwill towards all of life.
Good will towards all of
Good will towards all of life.
Yes.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> What
>> What did
>> What did the
>> What did the angels
>> What did the angels say
>> What did the angels say on
>> What did the angels say on Christmas
Eve?
What
What did
What did the
What did the angels
What did the angels say?
What did the angels say? Goodwill
What did the angels say? Goodwill too.
>> Yes.
>> Hello.
>> Hi.
>> I'm
>> I'm so
>> I'm so happy
>> I'm so happy to
>> I'm so happy to be
>> I'm so happy to be here.
>> I'm so happy to be here. I'm
>> I'm so happy to be here. I'm so
grateful.
grateful. First,
>> I'm so happy to be here. I'm so
grateful. First, first
grateful. First, first I
>> I'm so happy to be here. I'm so
grateful. First, first I got
grateful. First, first I got you
>> I'm so happy to be here. I'm so
grateful. First, first I got you a
picture.
picture. It
picture. It means
picture. It means so
picture. It means so much
picture. It means so much to
picture. It means so much to me.
picture. It means so much to me. And
it's
it's Krishna
picture. It means so much to me. And
it's Krishna and
it's Krishna and Rada.
picture. It means so much to me. And
it's Krishna and Rada. And
it's Krishna and Rada. And Rada
picture. It means so much to me. And
it's Krishna and Rada. And Rada is
it's Krishna and Rada. And Rada is so
beautiful
beautiful there.
beautiful there. And
beautiful there. And you
beautiful there. And you remind
beautiful there. And you remind me
beautiful there. And you remind me of
Rada.
Rada. And
beautiful there. And you remind me of
Rada. And Krishna
Rada. And Krishna is
beautiful there. And you remind me of
Rada. And Krishna is so
Rada. And Krishna is so handsome.
beautiful there. And you remind me of
Rada. And Krishna is so handsome. And
you
you remind
you remind me
you remind me of
you remind me of Krishna.
you remind me of Krishna. Mhm.
>> And
>> And I
you remind me of Krishna. Mhm.
>> And I just
>> Rama
>> Rama and
>> Rama and Krishna.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And it
>> And it says
>> And it says love
>> And it says love divine
>> And it says love divine and
>> And it says love divine and the
>> And it says love divine and the lotus
he's
he's given
>> And it says love divine and the lotus
he's given her
he's given her is
>> And it says love divine and the lotus
he's given her is is
he's given her is is what
>> And it says love divine and the lotus
he's given her is is what I
he's given her is is what I think
>> And it says love divine and the lotus
he's given her is is what I think you
give
>> all
>> all of
give
>> all of us
>> all of us devotees.
>> I
>> I can't
>> I can't see.
>> Here's
>> Here's a
>> and
>> and and
>> and and a
>> and and a and
>> and and a and a
>> and and a and a card
>> and and a and a card and
>> and and a and a card and a
>> and and a and a card and a card.
>> and and a and a card and a card. And
>> what
>> what do
>> and and a and a card and a card. And
>> what do I
>> what do I do?
>> and and a and a card and a card. And
>> what do I do? Sign
>> what do I do? Sign this.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know. Do
>> I don't know. Do you
>> I don't know. Do you want
>> I don't know. Do you want him
>> I don't know. Do you want him to
>> I don't know. Do you want him to sign
the
the book,
>> please?
And
And this
>> please?
And this this
>> this
>> this is
>> this is our
>> this is our book.
>> It's
>> It's been
>> this is our book.
>> It's been loved.
>> It's
>> It's been
>> It's been read
>> It's been read at
>> It's been read at all.
>> It's
>> It's in
>> It's been read at all.
>> It's in tatters.
>> And
>> And and
>> And and this
>> And and this ego
>> And and this ego has
>> And and this ego has so
>> And and this ego has so many
>> And and this ego has so many questions,
but
but I
>> And and this ego has so many questions,
but I just
but I just wanted
>> And and this ego has so many questions,
but I just wanted to
but I just wanted to see
>> And and this ego has so many questions,
but I just wanted to see your
but I just wanted to see your beautiful
face.
face. And
face. And I
face. And I just
face. And I just wanted
face. And I just wanted to
face. And I just wanted to say
face. And I just wanted to say I
face. And I just wanted to say I love
you
you and
face. And I just wanted to say I love
you and thank
you and thank you
face. And I just wanted to say I love
you and thank you so
you and thank you so much.
face. And I just wanted to say I love
you and thank you so much. And
you and thank you so much. And I've
face. And I just wanted to say I love
you and thank you so much. And I've and
I
I know
I know everything
I know everything else
I know everything else will
I know everything else will be
I know everything else will be revealed.
I
I have
I know everything else will be revealed.
I have no
I have no doubt.
I know everything else will be revealed.
I have no doubt. I
I have no doubt. I just
I know everything else will be revealed.
I have no doubt. I just want
I have no doubt. I just want to
I know everything else will be revealed.
I have no doubt. I just want to look
I have no doubt. I just want to look at
you.
you. I
you. I want
you. I want to
you. I want to look
you. I want to look at
you. I want to look at both
you. I want to look at both of
you. I want to look at both of you.
That's
That's it.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. I
>> Thank you very much. I appreciate
>> Thank you very much. I appreciate it.
Yes.
>> Mhm.
>> That's
>> That's for
>> Mhm.
>> That's for you,
>> That's for you, Susan.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> I
>> I just
>> Thank you.
>> I just have
>> I just have one
>> Thank you.
>> I just have one quick
>> I just have one quick question.
>> Yes.
>> Um
>> I
>> I was
>> I was just
>> I was just wondering
>> I was just wondering when
>> I was just wondering when you
>> I was just wondering when you die,
>> I was just wondering when you die, what
happens
happens to
>> I was just wondering when you die, what
happens to you?
happens to you? Not
>> I was just wondering when you die, what
happens to you? Not when
happens to you? Not when I
>> I was just wondering when you die, what
happens to you? Not when I die
happens to you? Not when I die or
>> I was just wondering when you die, what
happens to you? Not when I die or those
people.
people. But
people. But you
people. But you personally
>> what
>> what makes
people. But you personally
>> what makes you
>> what makes you think
people. But you personally
>> what makes you think I'm
>> what makes you think I'm gonna
people. But you personally
>> what makes you think I'm gonna die?
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, I
>> Yeah, I know.
>> Well,
>> Well, you're
>> Well, I
>> Well, I hope
>> Well, I hope not.
>> Well, I hope not. I
>> Well, I hope not. I hope
>> Well, I hope not. I hope not
>> Well, I hope not. I hope not anytime
soon.
compared
compared to
compared to Methusula.
compared to Methusula. I'm
compared to Methusula. I'm just
compared to Methusula. I'm just born
>> like
>> like can
compared to Methusula. I'm just born
>> like can you
>> like can you pick
compared to Methusula. I'm just born
>> like can you pick to
>> like can you pick to go
compared to Methusula. I'm just born
>> like can you pick to go into
>> like can you pick to go into another
body
body whoseever
body whoseever body
body whoseever body you
body whoseever body you want
body whoseever body you want or
>> uh
>> uh these
body whoseever body you want or
>> uh these are
>> uh these are sort
body whoseever body you want or
>> uh these are sort of
>> uh these are sort of unanswerable.
Uh
Uh you
Uh you have
Uh you have multiple
Uh you have multiple options
Uh you have multiple options multiple
options.
options. The
Uh you have multiple options multiple
options. The decision
options. The decision is
Uh you have multiple options multiple
options. The decision is based
options. The decision is based on
multiffactors.
The
The awareness
multiffactors.
The awareness of
The awareness of the
multiffactors.
The awareness of the reality
The awareness of the reality of
multiffactors.
The awareness of the reality of that
which
which you
which you are.
Uh
Uh the
which you are.
Uh the desire
Uh the desire to
which you are.
Uh the desire to be
Uh the desire to be of
which you are.
Uh the desire to be of service
Uh the desire to be of service to
others.
uh
uh with
others.
uh with who
uh with who you
others.
uh with who you want
uh with who you want to
others.
uh with who you want to pal
uh with who you want to pal out
others.
uh with who you want to pal out with
uh
and
and then
uh
and then a
and then a higher
uh
and then a higher vision
and then a higher vision of
uh
and then a higher vision of what
and then a higher vision of what is
possible
also
also whether
possible
also whether you
also whether you wish
possible
also whether you wish to
also whether you wish to which
possible
also whether you wish to which realm
also whether you wish to which realm you
wish
wish to
wish to be
wish to be of
wish to be of service
that's
that's I
wish to be of service
that's I remember
that's I remember some
wish to be of service
that's I remember some uh
that's I remember some uh realms
wish to be of service
that's I remember some uh realms and
what
what my
what my job
what my job was
what my job was there
what my job was there and
what my job was there and uh
what my job was there and uh I
what my job was there and uh I remember
when
when I
what my job was there and uh I remember
when I was
when I was a
what my job was there and uh I remember
when I was a greeter
and
and uh
and uh then
and uh then there's
and uh then there's a
and uh then there's a level.
Uh
Uh I
and uh then there's a level.
Uh I look
Uh I look forward
and uh then there's a level.
Uh I look forward to
Uh I look forward to chatting
and uh then there's a level.
Uh I look forward to chatting with,
Uh I look forward to chatting with, you
know,
know, Socrates
know, Socrates and
know, Socrates and people
know, Socrates and people like
know, Socrates and people like that.
>> Oh,
>> that
>> that chat
>> that chat out
>> that chat out together.
>> that chat out together. And
>> that chat out together. And uh
>> that chat out together. And uh so
>> that chat out together. And uh so I
guess
guess that's
>> that chat out together. And uh so I
guess that's a
guess that's a temptation
>> that chat out together. And uh so I
guess that's a temptation I
guess that's a temptation I may
>> that chat out together. And uh so I
guess that's a temptation I may have
guess that's a temptation I may have to
bypass.
bypass. But
bypass. But uh
>> yeah,
>> yeah, you
bypass. But uh
>> yeah, you have
>> yeah, you have multiple
bypass. But uh
>> yeah, you have multiple options.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> All
>> All right.
>> Oh, okay.
>> All right. So,
>> All right. So, there's
>> Oh, okay.
>> All right. So, there's multiple
>> All right. So, there's multiple spaces.
There's
There's multiple
There's multiple options
There's multiple options in
There's multiple options in heaven.
There
There isn't
There's multiple options in heaven.
There isn't just
There isn't just a
There's multiple options in heaven.
There isn't just a heaven
There isn't just a heaven and
There's multiple options in heaven.
There isn't just a heaven and a
There isn't just a heaven and a and
There's multiple options in heaven.
There isn't just a heaven and a and a
non-heaven.
non-heaven. There
non-heaven. There is
non-heaven. There is various
non-heaven. There is various levels
non-heaven. There is various levels of
heaven
heaven and
non-heaven. There is various levels of
heaven and uh
heaven and uh and
non-heaven. There is various levels of
heaven and uh and various
heaven and uh and various potentialities
in
in each
in each level.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Okay.
in each level.
>> Okay. Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you.
in each level.
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you. And
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you. And um
in each level.
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you. And um could
>> Okay. Okay. Thank you. And um could you
I
I know
I know you're
I know you're not
I know you're not a
I know you're not a priest,
I know you're not a priest, but
I know you're not a priest, but can
I know you're not a priest, but can you
like
like bless
I know you're not a priest, but can you
like bless this
like bless this or
I know you're not a priest, but can you
like bless this or say
>> I
>> I can
>> I can bless
>> I can bless anything.
>> I can bless anything. again.
>> It
>> It may
>> I can bless anything. again.
>> It may not
>> It may not may
>> I can bless anything. again.
>> It may not may not
>> It may not may not take,
>> I can bless anything. again.
>> It may not may not take, but
I
I need
I need your
I need your arm.
>> Get
>> Get this
I need your arm.
>> Get this out
>> Get this out of
I need your arm.
>> Get this out of the
>> Get this out of the way.
I need your arm.
>> Get this out of the way. I
>> Get this out of the way. I don't
I need your arm.
>> Get this out of the way. I don't want
>> Get this out of the way. I don't want it
falling
falling and
falling and breaking.
>> I
>> I need
falling and breaking.
>> I need your
>> I need your arm.
falling and breaking.
>> I need your arm. I
>> I need your arm. I need
falling and breaking.
>> I need your arm. I need your
>> I
>> I have
>> I have permission
>> I have permission to
>> I have permission to bless
>> I have permission to bless this
>> I have permission to bless this object
in
in the
>> I have permission to bless this object
in the name
in the name of
>> I have permission to bless this object
in the name of the
in the name of the Lord.
>> I have permission to bless this object
in the name of the Lord. Amen.
in the name of the Lord. Amen. I
>> I have permission to bless this object
in the name of the Lord. Amen. I bless
this
this object
this object in
this object in thy
this object in thy name,
this object in thy name, O
this object in thy name, O Lord,
this object in thy name, O Lord, out
this object in thy name, O Lord, out of
reverence
reverence and
this object in thy name, O Lord, out of
reverence and love
reverence and love for
this object in thy name, O Lord, out of
reverence and love for for
reverence and love for for thee.
this object in thy name, O Lord, out of
reverence and love for for thee. Amen.
This
This is
This is Christian.
This is Christian. Therefore,
This is Christian. Therefore, I
This is Christian. Therefore, I will
make
make the
This is Christian. Therefore, I will
make the sign
make the sign of the
This is Christian. Therefore, I will
make the sign of the cross.
make the sign of the cross. Thank
This is Christian. Therefore, I will
make the sign of the cross. Thank you.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, thank
>> Oh, thank you
>> Oh, thank you so
>> Oh, thank you so much.
>> Oh, thank you so much. Thank
>> Oh, thank you so much. Thank you.
>> Oh, thank you so much. Thank you. Thank
you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you,
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> Thank you, Susan. Thank
>> Thank you, Susan. Thank you.
>> Sure.
>> This
>> This is
>> This is wonderful.
>> This is wonderful. Thank
>> This is wonderful. Thank you.
>> Oh
>> Oh my
>> This is wonderful. Thank you.
>> Oh my goodness,
>> Oh my goodness, that's
>> This is wonderful. Thank you.
>> Oh my goodness, that's so
>> Oh my goodness, that's so beautiful.
It's
>> a
>> a great
It's
>> a great picture.
Hi
Hi Susan.
>> Hi
>> Hi Dr.
Hi Susan.
>> Hi Dr. Hawkins.
>> A
>> A few
>> A few years
>> A few years ago
>> A few years ago um
>> A few years ago um I
>> A few years ago um I went
>> A few years ago um I went through
>> A few years ago um I went through a
healing
healing crisis
>> A few years ago um I went through a
healing crisis and
healing crisis and a
>> A few years ago um I went through a
healing crisis and a health
healing crisis and a health crisis.
>> A few years ago um I went through a
healing crisis and a health crisis. And
>> few
>> few years
>> few years ago
>> few years ago you
>> few years ago you went
>> few years ago you went through
>> few years ago you went through a
>> few years ago you went through a health
crisis.
>> A
>> A health
>> A health and
>> A health and healing
>> A health and healing crisis.
>> A health and healing crisis. And
>> A health and healing crisis. And in
>> A health and healing crisis. And in that
during
during that
>> A health and healing crisis. And in that
during that time
during that time I
>> A health and healing crisis. And in that
during that time I uh
during that time I uh experienced
>> A health and healing crisis. And in that
during that time I uh experienced a
during that time I uh experienced a a
lot
lot of
lot of condundalining
lot of condundalining and
lot of condundalining and a
lot of condundalining and a lot
lot of condundalining and a lot of
lot of condundalining and a lot of the
uh
uh energetic
lot of condundalining and a lot of the
uh energetic rewiring
uh energetic rewiring and
lot of condundalining and a lot of the
uh energetic rewiring and that
uh energetic rewiring and that type
lot of condundalining and a lot of the
uh energetic rewiring and that type of
things
things that
things that you
things that you talked
things that you talked about.
things that you talked about. I
things that you talked about. I had
things that you talked about. I had also
practiced
practiced um
things that you talked about. I had also
practiced um your
practiced um your teachings
things that you talked about. I had also
practiced um your teachings with
practiced um your teachings with fixity
of
of focused
of focused and
of focused and through
of focused and through the
of focused and through the grace
of focused and through the grace of
of focused and through the grace of God
and
and and
of focused and through the grace of God
and and through
and and through the
of focused and through the grace of God
and and through the divine
and and through the divine grace
of focused and through the grace of God
and and through the divine grace of
and and through the divine grace of God
is
is um
is um I
is um I was
is um I was uh
is um I was uh bumped
is um I was uh bumped up
is um I was uh bumped up into
experiencing
experiencing the
is um I was uh bumped up into
experiencing the presence
experiencing the presence that
is um I was uh bumped up into
experiencing the presence that you
experiencing the presence that you have
described
described of
described of no
described of no mind
described of no mind awareness
described of no mind awareness for
described of no mind awareness for about
two
two years
described of no mind awareness for about
two years then
two years then um
being
being released
being released from
being released from this
being released from this energy
being released from this energy uh
being released from this energy uh I've
been
been trying
being released from this energy uh I've
been trying to
get
get grounded
get grounded and
get grounded and come
get grounded and come back
get grounded and come back to
what
what feels
get grounded and come back to
what feels like
what feels like density.
get grounded and come back to
what feels like density. I
what feels like density. I feel
get grounded and come back to
what feels like density. I feel like
what feels like density. I feel like I'm
trapped
trapped between
trapped between floors
trapped between floors on
trapped between floors on an
trapped between floors on an elevator
cuz
cuz the
trapped between floors on an elevator
cuz the density
cuz the density feels
trapped between floors on an elevator
cuz the density feels very
cuz the density feels very heavy
trapped between floors on an elevator
cuz the density feels very heavy uh
cuz the density feels very heavy uh of
like
like cement
like cement and
like cement and and
like cement and and yet
like cement and and yet I'm
like cement and and yet I'm no
like cement and and yet I'm no longer
really
really held
like cement and and yet I'm no longer
really held in
really held in the
like cement and and yet I'm no longer
really held in the unified
really held in the unified field
like cement and and yet I'm no longer
really held in the unified field of
awareness.
So
So my
awareness.
So my question
So my question for
awareness.
So my question for you,
So my question for you, you
awareness.
So my question for you, you having
talked
talked about
talked about this
talked about this as
talked about this as an
talked about this as an experience
talked about this as an experience that
you've
you've been
talked about this as an experience that
you've been through
you've been through is
talked about this as an experience that
you've been through is that
you've been through is that now
talked about this as an experience that
you've been through is that now I
you've been through is that now I feel
like
like I
like I am
like I am continuing
like I am continuing to
like I am continuing to surrender.
Uh
Uh but
like I am continuing to surrender.
Uh but I
Uh but I feel
like I am continuing to surrender.
Uh but I feel like
Uh but I feel like I'm
like I am continuing to surrender.
Uh but I feel like I'm am
Uh but I feel like I'm am walking
through
through that
through that fear
through that fear that
through that fear that you
through that fear that you talk
through that fear that you talk about
the
the fear
through that fear that you talk about
the fear of
the fear of existence
through that fear that you talk about
the fear of existence cuz
the fear of existence cuz right
through that fear that you talk about
the fear of existence cuz right now
the fear of existence cuz right now uh
the
the resonance
the resonance of
the resonance of the
the resonance of the density
does
does not
the resonance of the density
does not resonate
does not resonate with
the resonance of the density
does not resonate with me
does not resonate with me and
the resonance of the density
does not resonate with me and I
does not resonate with me and I need
the resonance of the density
does not resonate with me and I need to
um
um and
um and fear
um and fear is
um and fear is coming
um and fear is coming up
um and fear is coming up and
and
and uh
um and fear is coming up and
and uh I'm
and uh I'm concerned
um and fear is coming up and
and uh I'm concerned about
and uh I'm concerned about survival
because
because I'm
because I'm not
because I'm not aligning
because I'm not aligning with
because I'm not aligning with density
and
and I'm
because I'm not aligning with density
and I'm feeling
and I'm feeling a
because I'm not aligning with density
and I'm feeling a lot
and I'm feeling a lot of
because I'm not aligning with density
and I'm feeling a lot of of
and I'm feeling a lot of of fear
because I'm not aligning with density
and I'm feeling a lot of of fear and
>> fear
>> fear of
>> fear of what
>> fear of what dying
Uh
Uh no
>> fear of what dying
Uh no fear
Uh no fear of
>> fear of what dying
Uh no fear of survival.
Uh no fear of survival. Um
>> fear of what dying
Uh no fear of survival. Um because
Uh no fear of survival. Um because I
seem
seem to
seem to be
seem to be getting
seem to be getting bumped
seem to be getting bumped out
seem to be getting bumped out of
seem to be getting bumped out of it.
seem to be getting bumped out of it. I
have
have difficulty
seem to be getting bumped out of it. I
have difficulty uh
have difficulty uh being
seem to be getting bumped out of it. I
have difficulty uh being like
have difficulty uh being like the
density
density of
density of bureaucracy.
density of bureaucracy. It
density of bureaucracy. It doesn't
density of bureaucracy. It doesn't it
doesn't
doesn't align
density of bureaucracy. It doesn't it
doesn't align with
doesn't align with my
density of bureaucracy. It doesn't it
doesn't align with my energy.
doesn't align with my energy. Just
density of bureaucracy. It doesn't it
doesn't align with my energy. Just kind
of the
of the world
of the world the
of the world the mind
of the world the mind world.
>> I
>> I don't
of the world the mind world.
>> I don't know
>> I don't know what
of the world the mind world.
>> I don't know what the
>> I don't know what the question
of the world the mind world.
>> I don't know what the question is.
>> I don't know what the question is. So
well
well the
well the question
well the question is
well the question is is
well the question is is that
well the question is is that if
well the question is is that if you
could
could I
well the question is is that if you
could I if
could I if you
well the question is is that if you
could I if you could
could I if you could um
perhaps
perhaps you
perhaps you know
perhaps you know it
perhaps you know it discuss
perhaps you know it discuss how
perhaps you know it discuss how you
perhaps you know it discuss how you seem
to
to come
perhaps you know it discuss how you seem
to come back
to come back and
perhaps you know it discuss how you seem
to come back and you
to come back and you when
perhaps you know it discuss how you seem
to come back and you when you
to come back and you when you were
coming
coming out
coming out of
coming out of that
coming out of that that
coming out of that that space
>> how
>> how you
coming out of that that space
>> how you reentered
>> how you reentered the
coming out of that that space
>> how you reentered the world
>> how you reentered the world and
coming out of that that space
>> how you reentered the world and how
>> how you reentered the world and how you
function
function in
function in the
function in the world
function in the world after
function in the world after you
function in the world after you came
back
back from
function in the world after you came
back from your
back from your high
function in the world after you came
back from your high state.
>> Oh
>> Oh um
>> Oh um uh
asking
asking for
>> Oh um uh
asking for God's
asking for God's will
>> Oh um uh
asking for God's will in
asking for God's will in the
>> Oh um uh
asking for God's will in the matter.
Well,
Well, Lord,
I'm
I'm willing
Well, Lord,
I'm willing to
I'm willing to be
Well, Lord,
I'm willing to be uh
I'm willing to be uh whatever
Well, Lord,
I'm willing to be uh whatever you
I'm willing to be uh whatever you would
have
have me
have me be
have me be to
have me be to the
have me be to the world.
have me be to the world. And
have me be to the world. And the
inspiration
inspiration to
have me be to the world. And the
inspiration to teach
inspiration to teach then
have me be to the world. And the
inspiration to teach then came
inspiration to teach then came out
have me be to the world. And the
inspiration to teach then came out of
that
that question.
that question. It
that question. It would
that question. It would be
that question. It would be okay
that question. It would be okay with
that question. It would be okay with me
if
if I
that question. It would be okay with me
if I didn't
if I didn't teach.
that question. It would be okay with me
if I didn't teach. The
if I didn't teach. The world's
that question. It would be okay with me
if I didn't teach. The world's gone
along
along without
along without me
along without me this
along without me this far.
So,
So, the
along without me this far.
So, the the
So, the the way
along without me this far.
So, the the way of
So, the the way of the
along without me this far.
So, the the way of the mystic
So, the the way of the mystic is
along without me this far.
So, the the way of the mystic is is
So, the the way of the mystic is is your
option.
You
You can
option.
You can return
You can return to
option.
You can return to the
You can return to the world
option.
You can return to the world and
You can return to the world and be
option.
You can return to the world and be of
service
service that
service that way
service that way or
service that way or you
service that way or you cannot
service that way or you cannot return
service that way or you cannot return to
the
the world
service that way or you cannot return to
the world and
the world and be
service that way or you cannot return to
the world and be of
the world and be of service
service that way or you cannot return to
the world and be of service that
the world and be of service that way
service that way or you cannot return to
the world and be of service that way to
radiate
radiate to
radiate to the
radiate to the world
radiate to the world a
radiate to the world a certain
radiate to the world a certain energy
without
without any
radiate to the world a certain energy
without any actual
without any actual doing
radiate to the world a certain energy
without any actual doing this.
without any actual doing this. And
radiate to the world a certain energy
without any actual doing this. And I
always
always felt
always felt that
always felt that there
always felt that there was
always felt that there was a
prior
prior agreement
always felt that there was a
prior agreement about
prior agreement about what
always felt that there was a
prior agreement about what the
prior agreement about what the decision
would
would be.
would be. Let
would be. Let me
would be. Let me have
would be. Let me have the
would be. Let me have the arm
would be. Let me have the arm a
would be. Let me have the arm a second.
>> Okay.
>> Don't
>> Don't do
>> Don't do this
>> Don't do this arm.
>> Don't do this arm. Use
>> Don't do this arm. Use that
>> Don't do this arm. Use that arm
>> Don't do this arm. Use that arm because
your
>> there
>> there there
>> there there well
>> there there well just
>> there there well just one
>> there there well just one last
>> there there well just one last time.
Okay.
Okay. That
>> there there well just one last time.
Okay. That there
Okay. That there was
>> there there well just one last time.
Okay. That there was prior
Okay. That there was prior agreement.
Yeah.
Yeah. I
Yeah. I intuitively
Yeah. I intuitively knew
Yeah. I intuitively knew that
Yeah. I intuitively knew that there
Yeah. I intuitively knew that there was
a
a prior
Yeah. I intuitively knew that there was
a prior agreement
a prior agreement that
Yeah. I intuitively knew that there was
a prior agreement that subsequent
a prior agreement that subsequent to
that
that state
that state was
that state was to
that state was to remain
that state was to remain in
that state was to remain in the
that state was to remain in the world
and
and to
that state was to remain in the world
and to share
and to share with
that state was to remain in the world
and to share with others
and to share with others that
that state was to remain in the world
and to share with others that which
and to share with others that which is
helpful
helpful in
helpful in the
helpful in the role
helpful in the role of
helpful in the role of the
helpful in the role of the teacher
because
because you
helpful in the role of the teacher
because you can
because you can easily
helpful in the role of the teacher
because you can easily become
because you can easily become a
helpful in the role of the teacher
because you can easily become a recluse
and
and I
and I did
and I did for
and I did for some
and I did for some years
and I did for some years have
and I did for some years have nothing
and I did for some years have nothing to
do
do with
and I did for some years have nothing to
do with the
do with the world
and I did for some years have nothing to
do with the world whatsoever.
uh
uh we're
uh we're going
uh we're going to
uh we're going to transcend
uh we're going to transcend the
uh we're going to transcend the world
and
and leave
uh we're going to transcend the world
and leave the
and leave the body
uh we're going to transcend the world
and leave the body or
and leave the body or one
uh we're going to transcend the world
and leave the body or one can
and leave the body or one can be
uh we're going to transcend the world
and leave the body or one can be here
and leave the body or one can be here in
the
the world
the world and
the world and and
the world and and serve
the world and and serve uh
the world and and serve uh so
the world and and serve uh so the
what
what happens
the world and and serve uh so the
what happens to
what happens to the
the world and and serve uh so the
what happens to the mystic
what happens to the mystic then
the world and and serve uh so the
what happens to the mystic then is
what happens to the mystic then is a
option
uh
uh and
option
uh and some
uh and some may
option
uh and some may continue
uh and some may continue to
option
uh and some may continue to serve
uh and some may continue to serve as
option
uh and some may continue to serve as a
teacher.
teacher. See
teacher. See you
teacher. See you can
teacher. See you can also
teacher. See you can also serve
teacher. See you can also serve by
teacher. See you can also serve by not
teaching.
teaching. Yes.
teacher. See you can also serve by not
teaching. Yes. You
teaching. Yes. You can
teacher. See you can also serve by not
teaching. Yes. You can also
teaching. Yes. You can also just
teacher. See you can also serve by not
teaching. Yes. You can also just by
being
being that
being that which
being that which you
being that which you are
being that which you are radiate
being that which you are radiate out
being that which you are radiate out the
energy
energy of
being that which you are radiate out the
energy of divinity
as
as through
as through your
as through your beingness.
as through your beingness. Mhm.
>> And
>> And had
as through your beingness. Mhm.
>> And had you
>> And had you already
as through your beingness. Mhm.
>> And had you already surrendered
>> And had you already surrendered that
fear
fear of
fear of illusion
fear of illusion that
fear of illusion that you
fear of illusion that you talked
fear of illusion that you talked about
earlier
earlier that
fear of illusion that you talked about
earlier that fear
earlier that fear as
fear of illusion that you talked about
earlier that fear as being
earlier that fear as being a
fear of illusion that you talked about
earlier that fear as being a illusion?
>> Well,
>> Well, you're
>> Well, you're looking
>> Well, you're looking at
>> Well, you're looking at everything
>> Well, you're looking at everything as
though
though it's
>> Well, you're looking at everything as
though it's an
though it's an act
>> Well, you're looking at everything as
though it's an act of
though it's an act of the
>> Well, you're looking at everything as
though it's an act of the will.
>> You
>> You know,
>> You know, it's
>> You know, it's not
>> You know, it's not an
>> You know, it's not an act
>> You know, it's not an act of
>> You know, it's not an act of the
>> You know, it's not an act of the will
whether
whether the
>> You know, it's not an act of the will
whether the sun
whether the sun will
>> You know, it's not an act of the will
whether the sun will arise
whether the sun will arise this
>> You know, it's not an act of the will
whether the sun will arise this morning
and
and if
and if it'll
and if it'll be
and if it'll be a
and if it'll be a sunshiny
and if it'll be a sunshiny day
and if it'll be a sunshiny day or
and if it'll be a sunshiny day or not.
So
So you're
and if it'll be a sunshiny day or not.
So you're you're
So you're you're trying
and if it'll be a sunshiny day or not.
So you're you're trying to
So you're you're trying to phrase
everything
everything as
everything as though
everything as though it's
everything as though it's an
everything as though it's an act
everything as though it's an act of
everything as though it's an act of the
will
will as
everything as though it's an act of the
will as a
will as a consequence
everything as though it's an act of the
will as a consequence of
will as a consequence of an
everything as though it's an act of the
will as a consequence of an act
will as a consequence of an act of
everything as though it's an act of the
will as a consequence of an act of the
will.
will. Uh
will. Uh when
will. Uh when you
will. Uh when you surrender
will. Uh when you surrender your
will. Uh when you surrender your will,
there
there is
will. Uh when you surrender your will,
there is no
there is no decision
will. Uh when you surrender your will,
there is no decision because
there is no decision because there
will. Uh when you surrender your will,
there is no decision because there is
there is no decision because there is no
will
will to
will to make
will to make a
will to make a decision.
>> What
>> What is
will to make a decision.
>> What is is
so
so what
so what sits
so what sits here
so what sits here is
so what sits here is what
so what sits here is what sits
so what sits here is what sits here
so what sits here is what sits here and
there
there you
so what sits here is what sits here and
there you don't
there you don't doesn't
so what sits here is what sits here and
there you don't doesn't require
there you don't doesn't require a
decision.
Understand?
>> It
>> It it
>> It it automatically
>> It it automatically becomes
>> It it automatically becomes what
>> It it automatically becomes what it
becomes.
If
If the
If the caterpillar
If the caterpillar is
If the caterpillar is destined,
If the caterpillar is destined, so
If the caterpillar is destined, so it'll
become
become a
If the caterpillar is destined, so it'll
become a butterfly.
If
If not
If not destined,
If not destined, it
If not destined, it will
If not destined, it will not
If not destined, it will not become
If not destined, it will not become a
butterfly.
Yeah.
So
So the
Yeah.
So the the
So the the option
Yeah.
So the the option then
So the the option then of
Yeah.
So the the option then of being
So the the option then of being what
Yeah.
So the the option then of being what I
am
is
is merely
am
is merely the
is merely the fulfillment
am
is merely the fulfillment of
is merely the fulfillment of an
am
is merely the fulfillment of an option.
But
But it's
But it's a
But it's a it's
But it's a it's true
But it's a it's true that
But it's a it's true that one
But it's a it's true that one has
But it's a it's true that one has to
But it's a it's true that one has to say
yes
yes to
But it's a it's true that one has to say
yes to it
yes to it because
But it's a it's true that one has to say
yes to it because you're
yes to it because you're not
But it's a it's true that one has to say
yes to it because you're not forced
yes to it because you're not forced to
do
do anything
do anything against
do anything against your
do anything against your will.
It's
It's a
do anything against your will.
It's a joy
It's a joy to
do anything against your will.
It's a joy to be
It's a joy to be in
do anything against your will.
It's a joy to be in the
It's a joy to be in the world
do anything against your will.
It's a joy to be in the world and
It's a joy to be in the world and to
teach
teach and
teach and to
teach and to share
teach and to share and
teach and to share and to
teach and to share and to write
teach and to share and to write books
and
and give
teach and to share and to write books
and give lectures.
and give lectures. It's
teach and to share and to write books
and give lectures. It's also
and give lectures. It's also a
teach and to share and to write books
and give lectures. It's also a great
and give lectures. It's also a great joy
not
not to.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
not to.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Whether
>> Whether you
>> Whether you do
>> Whether you do or
>> Whether you do or you
>> Whether you do or you don't
>> Whether you do or you don't at
>> Whether you do or you don't at a
>> Whether you do or you don't at a certain
point
point is
>> Whether you do or you don't at a certain
point is irrelevant.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. Yes.
>> Thank you very much. Yes. Hi,
>> how
>> how are
>> Thank you very much. Yes. Hi,
>> how are you?
>> how are you? Thank
>> Thank you very much. Yes. Hi,
>> how are you? Thank you
>> how are you? Thank you so
>> Thank you very much. Yes. Hi,
>> how are you? Thank you so much.
>> Yes.
>> Uh
>> Uh question
>> Yes.
>> Uh question on
>> Uh question on a
>> Yes.
>> Uh question on a calibration
>> Uh question on a calibration of
>> Yes.
>> Uh question on a calibration of an
avatar.
avatar. Is
avatar. Is there
avatar. Is there any
avatar. Is there any way
avatar. Is there any way you
avatar. Is there any way you can
avatar. Is there any way you can help
avatar. Is there any way you can help us
with
with a
avatar. Is there any way you can help us
with a particular
with a particular number?
avatar. Is there any way you can help us
with a particular number? Calibration
number.
>> That's
>> That's not
number.
>> That's not an
>> That's not an answerable
number.
>> That's not an answerable question.
>> That's not an answerable question. What
avatar
avatar are
avatar are you
avatar are you talking
avatar are you talking about?
>> Mother
>> Mother mirror.
>> Who?
>> Mother
>> Mother mirror.
>> Who?
>> Mother mirror. M
>> Mother mirror. M I
>> Who?
>> Mother mirror. M I R
>> Mother mirror. M I R A.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know
>> I don't know if
>> I don't know if I've
>> I don't know if I've heard
>> I don't know if I've heard of
>> I don't know if I've heard of Mother
Mirror.
Mirror. Is
>> I don't know if I've heard of Mother
Mirror. Is this
Mirror. Is this a
>> I don't know if I've heard of Mother
Mirror. Is this a world
Mirror. Is this a world famous
>> I don't know if I've heard of Mother
Mirror. Is this a world famous person
who
who draws
who draws tens
who draws tens of
who draws tens of thousands
who draws tens of thousands of
who draws tens of thousands of people?
>> He
>> He does
who draws tens of thousands of people?
>> He does a
>> He does a lot
who draws tens of thousands of people?
>> He does a lot of
>> He does a lot of uh
who draws tens of thousands of people?
>> He does a lot of uh world
>> He does a lot of uh world travels
who draws tens of thousands of people?
>> He does a lot of uh world travels uh
>> He does a lot of uh world travels uh in
the
the states
the states in
the states in Europe
the states in Europe and
>> an
>> an Indian
the states in Europe and
>> an Indian avatar.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Self
>> Yeah. Self profession.
>> So
>> So you
>> Yeah. Self profession.
>> So you are
>> So you are you
>> Yeah. Self profession.
>> So you are you a
>> So you are you a follower
>> Yeah. Self profession.
>> So you are you a follower of
>> So you are you a follower of this
>> Yeah. Self profession.
>> So you are you a follower of this lady?
>> Yes.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, and
>> Oh, and you
>> Oh, and you want
>> Oh, and you want to
>> Oh, and you want to know?
>> Yes.
>> Are
>> Are these
>> Are these millions
>> Are these millions of
>> Are these millions of people
>> Are these millions of people deluded?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. That's
>> Are these millions of people deluded?
>> Yes. That's the
>> Yes. That's the question.
>> That
>> That is
>> That is the
>> That is the question.
>> That is the question. That's
>> That is the question. That's why
>> That is the question. That's why we
>> It's
>> It's not
>> That is the question. That's why we
>> It's not the
>> It's not the millions.
>> That is the question. That's why we
>> It's not the millions. So
>> it's
>> it's not
>> it's not the
>> it's not the mill.
>> it's not the mill. It's
>> it's not the mill. It's It's
>> it's not the mill. It's It's not
>> it's not the mill. It's It's not the
millions,
millions, but
>> it's not the mill. It's It's not the
millions, but it's
millions, but it's a
>> it's not the mill. It's It's not the
millions, but it's a lot
millions, but it's a lot of
>> it's not the mill. It's It's not the
millions, but it's a lot of people.
millions, but it's a lot of people. I
think
think I
think I know
think I know what
think I know what they
think I know what they mean.
think I know what they mean. Uh,
think I know what they mean. Uh, I
think I know what they mean. Uh, I have
permission
permission to
think I know what they mean. Uh, I have
permission to ask
permission to ask about
think I know what they mean. Uh, I have
permission to ask about this
permission to ask about this lady.
think I know what they mean. Uh, I have
permission to ask about this lady. She's
over
over 200.
over 200. She's
over 200. She's over
over 200. She's over 300.
over 200. She's over 300. She's
over 200. She's over 300. She's over
400,
500.
He's
He's in
500.
He's in the
He's in the 400s.
500.
He's in the 400s. This
He's in the 400s. This is
500.
He's in the 400s. This is a
He's in the 400s. This is a a
500.
He's in the 400s. This is a a lady
He's in the 400s. This is a a lady who's
famous
famous because
famous because of
famous because of her
famous because of her goodwill
>> or
>> or smiling,
>> and
>> and her
>> and her willingness
>> and her willingness to
>> and her willingness to love,
>> and her willingness to love, silence,
and
and eye
>> and her willingness to love, silence,
and eye contact.
and eye contact. That's
right.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. the
right.
>> Yeah. the the
>> Yeah. the the those
right.
>> Yeah. the the those that
>> Yeah. the the those that are
right.
>> Yeah. the the those that are that
>> Yeah. the the those that are that way
right.
>> Yeah. the the those that are that way of
course
course are
course are of
course are of great
course are of great great
course are of great great service
uh
uh because
course are of great great service
uh because of
uh because of the
course are of great great service
uh because of the confirmation
uh because of the confirmation of
course are of great great service
uh because of the confirmation of a
certain
certain spiritual
certain spiritual reality
certain spiritual reality and
certain spiritual reality and because
certain spiritual reality and because uh
they
they are
certain spiritual reality and because uh
they are uplifting
they are uplifting to
certain spiritual reality and because uh
they are uplifting to people
they are uplifting to people that
calibrate
calibrate below.
calibrate below. Don't
calibrate below. Don't forget
calibrate below. Don't forget over
calibrate below. Don't forget over half
the
the population
calibrate below. Don't forget over half
the population is
the population is below
calibrate below. Don't forget over half
the population is below 200.
the population is below 200. So
calibrate below. Don't forget over half
the population is below 200. So for
the population is below 200. So for over
half
half the
half the population,
half the population, this
half the population, this would
half the population, this would be
almost
almost like
half the population, this would be
almost like a
almost like a Jesus
half the population, this would be
almost like a Jesus Christ.
almost like a Jesus Christ. You
half the population, this would be
almost like a Jesus Christ. You see
almost like a Jesus Christ. You see this
compared
compared to
compared to where
compared to where they're
compared to where they're at
compared to where they're at at
compared to where they're at at 70.
somebody
somebody who
compared to where they're at at 70.
somebody who was
somebody who was what
compared to where they're at at 70.
somebody who was what did
somebody who was what did I
compared to where they're at at 70.
somebody who was what did I say
somebody who was what did I say she
compared to where they're at at 70.
somebody who was what did I say she was
at
at 45500
at 45500 or
at 45500 or something
>> high
>> high 400
>> anyway
>> anyway so
>> anyway so wherever
>> anyway so wherever she
>> anyway so wherever she is
>> anyway so wherever she is is
>> anyway so wherever she is is enormous
compared
compared to
>> anyway so wherever she is is enormous
compared to where
compared to where the
>> anyway so wherever she is is enormous
compared to where the masses
compared to where the masses are
>> anyway so wherever she is is enormous
compared to where the masses are uh
where
where she
where she is
where she is compared
where she is compared to
where she is compared to the
where she is compared to the Buddha
where she is compared to the Buddha is
not
not the
where she is compared to the Buddha is
not the same
not the same league
where she is compared to the Buddha is
not the same league you
not the same league you know
where she is compared to the Buddha is
not the same league you know but
not the same league you know but those
are
are two
are two different
are two different realms
are two different realms two
are two different realms two different
realms
>> I
>> I have
>> I have a
>> I have a question
>> I have a question as
>> I have a question as well
>> I have a question as well um
>> I have a question as well um over
>> I have a question as well um over the
last
last several
>> I have a question as well um over the
last several months
last several months um
>> I have a question as well um over the
last several months um I've
last several months um I've had
>> I have a question as well um over the
last several months um I've had many
different
different experiences
different experiences which
different experiences which um
different experiences which um more
different experiences which um more I
basically
basically look
different experiences which um more I
basically look for
basically look for God
different experiences which um more I
basically look for God more
basically look for God more I
different experiences which um more I
basically look for God more I encounter
evil
evil and
evil and it's
evil and it's um
evil and it's um very
evil and it's um very painful
evil and it's um very painful and
evil and it's um very painful and um
turmoil
turmoil is
evil and it's um very painful and um
turmoil is significant
turmoil is significant and
>> you
>> you have
>> you have to
>> you have to rephrase
>> you have to rephrase there's
>> you have to rephrase there's something
about
about the
>> you have to rephrase there's something
about the vibration
about the vibration in
>> you have to rephrase there's something
about the vibration in this
about the vibration in this room
>> okay
>> okay she
>> okay she said
>> okay she said that
>> okay she said that she's
>> okay she said that she's having
>> okay she said that she's having you
>> okay she said that she's having you know
the
the more
>> okay she said that she's having you know
the more she
the more she looks
>> okay she said that she's having you know
the more she looks for
the more she looks for God
>> okay she said that she's having you know
the more she looks for God it
the more she looks for God it seems
>> okay she said that she's having you know
the more she looks for God it seems like
the
the more
the more it
the more it brings
the more it brings up
the more it brings up the
the more it brings up the opposite
>> that
>> that which
the more it brings up the opposite
>> that which is
>> that which is not
the more it brings up the opposite
>> that which is not God
>> you're
>> you're looking
>> you're looking in
>> you're looking in the
>> you're looking in the wrong
>> you're looking in the wrong place
>> you're looking in the wrong place huh
>> that
>> that was
>> you're looking in the wrong place huh
>> that was the
>> that was the concern
Um
>> what
>> what do
Um
>> what do you
>> what do you what
Um
>> what do you what do
>> what do you what do you
Um
>> what do you what do you expect
>> what do you what do you expect the
awareness
awareness of
awareness of God
awareness of God would
awareness of God would be
awareness of God would be like?
Um
Um ideally
awareness of God would be like?
Um ideally it
Um ideally it would
awareness of God would be like?
Um ideally it would be
Um ideally it would be um
awareness of God would be like?
Um ideally it would be um well
>> huh
>> I
>> I didn't
>> it
>> it would
>> it would be
>> it would be uplifting
>> right
>> but
>> but um
>> but um I
>> but um I would
>> but um I would what
>> but um I would what would
>> but um I would what would be
>> but um I would what would be uplifting
>> the
>> the experience
>> the experience of
>> the experience of God
>> the
>> the experience
>> the experience of God
>> the experience of
>> the experience of God would
>> the experience of God
>> the experience of God would be
>> the experience of God would be joyous
and
and uplifting
>> however
>> oh
>> oh oh
>> oh oh I
>> oh oh I see
>> oh oh I see what
>> oh oh I see what you're
>> oh oh I see what you're saying
>> however
>> however I
>> oh oh I see what you're saying
>> however I work
>> however I work in
>> oh oh I see what you're saying
>> however I work in a
>> however I work in a prison
>> oh oh I see what you're saying
>> however I work in a prison as
>> however I work in a prison as a
pharmacist
pharmacist and
pharmacist and I
pharmacist and I just
pharmacist and I just came
pharmacist and I just came back
pharmacist and I just came back from
pharmacist and I just came back from a
training
training which
pharmacist and I just came back from a
training which taught
training which taught me
pharmacist and I just came back from a
training which taught me how
training which taught me how to
pharmacist and I just came back from a
training which taught me how to shoot
the
the prisoners
the prisoners if
the prisoners if they
the prisoners if they run
the prisoners if they run and
>> how
>> how to
the prisoners if they run and
>> how to shoot
>> how to shoot them
>> well
>> well Yeah,
>> well Yeah, you
>> well Yeah, you get
>> well Yeah, you get you
and
and um
>> Oh,
>> Oh, shoot
>> Oh, shoot them
>> Oh, shoot them up.
>> Oh, shoot them up. Yes.
>> Oh, shoot them up. Yes. Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So,
>> Oh, shoot them up. Yes. Yes.
>> Yeah. So, um
>> Yeah. So, um and
>> Oh, shoot them up. Yes. Yes.
>> Yeah. So, um and I'm
>> Yeah. So, um and I'm a
>> Oh, shoot them up. Yes. Yes.
>> Yeah. So, um and I'm a pharmacist,
>> Yeah. So, um and I'm a pharmacist, so
>> Oh, shoot them up. Yes. Yes.
>> Yeah. So, um and I'm a pharmacist, so I
have
have a
have a lot
have a lot of
have a lot of So,
have a lot of So, and
have a lot of So, and then
have a lot of So, and then we
have a lot of So, and then we see
have a lot of So, and then we see videos
of
of different
have a lot of So, and then we see videos
of different prisoners
of different prisoners and
have a lot of So, and then we see videos
of different prisoners and most
population
population of
population of child
population of child molesters
population of child molesters is
population of child molesters is the
growing
growing population
population of child molesters is the
growing population and
growing population and then
population of child molesters is the
growing population and then there
growing population and then there are
like
like psychopaths
like psychopaths like
like psychopaths like you
like psychopaths like you know
like psychopaths like you know and
>> what
>> what she
like psychopaths like you know and
>> what she asking
>> what she asking is
like psychopaths like you know and
>> what she asking is getting
>> what she asking is getting too
complicated
complicated and
complicated and long.
>> She's
>> She's working
complicated and long.
>> She's working in
>> She's working in a
complicated and long.
>> She's working in a very
working
working in
working in a
working in a below
working in a below 200
working in a below 200 prison,
working in a below 200 prison, right?
Yet
Yet she
working in a below 200 prison, right?
Yet she is
Yet she is above
working in a below 200 prison, right?
Yet she is above 200,
Yet she is above 200, right?
>> Can
>> Can we
>> Can we check?
>> The
>> The pro
>> Can we check?
>> The pro the
>> The pro the problem
>> Can we check?
>> The pro the problem you're
>> The pro the problem you're above
>> Can we check?
>> The pro the problem you're above 200
>> The pro the problem you're above 200 or
you
you wouldn't
you wouldn't be
you wouldn't be here.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> All
>> All right.
>> All right. So,
>> All right. So, so
>> All right. So, so she's
>> All right. So, so she's working
>> All right. So, so she's working in
>> All right. So, so she's working in this
environment
environment that
>> All right. So, so she's working in this
environment that isn't
environment that isn't very
>> All right. So, so she's working in this
environment that isn't very healthy
environment that isn't very healthy and
yet
yet she's
yet she's trying
yet she's trying to
yet she's trying to keep
yet she's trying to keep healthy,
yet she's trying to keep healthy, you
know,
know, and
yet she's trying to keep healthy, you
know, and they're
know, and they're training
yet she's trying to keep healthy, you
know, and they're training her
know, and they're training her to
yet she's trying to keep healthy, you
know, and they're training her to shoot
prisoners
prisoners if
prisoners if they
prisoners if they escape.
prisoners if they escape. So,
prisoners if they escape. So, you
prisoners if they escape. So, you know,
it
it isn't
prisoners if they escape. So, you know,
it isn't a
it isn't a real
prisoners if they escape. So, you know,
it isn't a real uh
it isn't a real uh spiritual
prisoners if they escape. So, you know,
it isn't a real uh spiritual inducive
it isn't a real uh spiritual inducive uh
environment.
depends
depends on
environment.
depends on what
depends on what you
environment.
depends on what you call
depends on what you call spiritual.
environment.
depends on what you call spiritual. Uh
you
you know,
you know, in
you know, in other
you know, in other words,
you know, in other words, your
you know, in other words, your presence
there
there is
you know, in other words, your presence
there is uplifting
there is uplifting to
you know, in other words, your presence
there is uplifting to the
there is uplifting to the prisoners.
>> I
>> I would
>> I would hope
>> I would hope so.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Just
>> I would hope so.
>> Yeah. Just by
>> Yeah. Just by the
>> I would hope so.
>> Yeah. Just by the virtue
>> Yeah. Just by the virtue of
>> I would hope so.
>> Yeah. Just by the virtue of that
>> Yeah. Just by the virtue of that which
you
you are,
you are, you're
you are, you're uplifting
you are, you're uplifting to
you are, you're uplifting to the
prisoners.
>> So
>> So when
>> So when they
>> So when they ask
>> So when they ask me
>> So when they ask me to
>> So when they ask me to do
>> So when they ask me to do a
>> So when they ask me to do a strip
search,
search, do
>> So when they ask me to do a strip
search, do I
search, do I do
>> So when they ask me to do a strip
search, do I do it
search, do I do it to
>> So when they ask me to do a strip
search, do I do it to keep
search, do I do it to keep the
>> So when they ask me to do a strip
search, do I do it to keep the job
search, do I do it to keep the job or
>> So when they ask me to do a strip
search, do I do it to keep the job or do
I
I leave?
>> What?
>> When
>> When they
>> When they ask
>> When they ask her
>> When they ask her to
>> When they ask her to do
>> When they ask her to do a
>> When they ask her to do a strip
>> When they ask her to do a strip search,
does
does she
>> When they ask her to do a strip search,
does she do
does she do it
>> When they ask her to do a strip search,
does she do it to
does she do it to keep
>> When they ask her to do a strip search,
does she do it to keep the
does she do it to keep the job
>> When they ask her to do a strip search,
does she do it to keep the job or
does she do it to keep the job or does
she
she leave?
>> Well,
>> Well, that's
she leave?
>> Well, that's up
>> Well, that's up to
she leave?
>> Well, that's up to her.
>> Well, that's up to her. I
she leave?
>> Well, that's up to her. I don't
>> Well, that's up to her. I don't care
she leave?
>> Well, that's up to her. I don't care if
this
this trip
this trip search
this trip search me
this trip search me but
those
those are
this trip search me but
those are personal
those are personal propensities
this trip search me but
those are personal propensities you
those are personal propensities you know
working
working in
working in that
working in that kind
working in that kind of
working in that kind of environment
working in that kind of environment you
know
know you
working in that kind of environment you
know you must
know you must have
working in that kind of environment you
know you must have some
know you must have some kind
working in that kind of environment you
know you must have some kind of
know you must have some kind of a
working in that kind of environment you
know you must have some kind of a inner
decision
decision about
decision about such
decision about such things
decision about such things I
decision about such things I mean
decision about such things I mean who
the
the heck
decision about such things I mean who
the heck would
the heck would want
decision about such things I mean who
the heck would want to
the heck would want to work
decision about such things I mean who
the heck would want to work in
the heck would want to work in a
decision about such things I mean who
the heck would want to work in a place
with
with all
with all killers
with all killers and
with all killers and rapers
with all killers and rapers and
criminals
criminals so
with all killers and rapers and
criminals so you
criminals so you must
with all killers and rapers and
criminals so you must have
criminals so you must have some
with all killers and rapers and
criminals so you must have some kind
criminals so you must have some kind of
dedication
dedication to
dedication to your
dedication to your job
dedication to your job I
dedication to your job I wouldn't
dedication to your job I wouldn't want
They
They one
dedication to your job I wouldn't want
They one time
They one time asked
dedication to your job I wouldn't want
They one time asked me
They one time asked me to
dedication to your job I wouldn't want
They one time asked me to be
They one time asked me to be the
dedication to your job I wouldn't want
They one time asked me to be the a
doctor
doctor in
doctor in a
doctor in a in
doctor in a in a
doctor in a in a in
doctor in a in a in the
doctor in a in a in the county
doctor in a in a in the county jail
and
and I
doctor in a in a in the county jail
and I turned
and I turned it
doctor in a in a in the county jail
and I turned it down.
>> Well,
>> Well, and
>> Well, and I
>> Well, and I went
>> Well, and I went for
>> Well, and I went for benefits.
>> Well, and I went for benefits. So,
>> now
>> now you
>> Well, and I went for benefits. So,
>> now you you
>> now you you you
>> Well, and I went for benefits. So,
>> now you you you said
>> now you you you said yes,
>> Well, and I went for benefits. So,
>> now you you you said yes, but
>> now you you you said yes, but I
>> Well, and I went for benefits. So,
>> now you you you said yes, but I said
>> now you you you said yes, but I said no.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. See,
>> so
>> so can
>> Yeah. See,
>> so can we
>> so can we check
>> Yeah. See,
>> so can we check if
>> so can we check if I
>> Yeah. See,
>> so can we check if I have
>> so can we check if I have to
>> Yeah. See,
>> so can we check if I have to be
>> so can we check if I have to be there
>> Yeah. See,
>> so can we check if I have to be there or
>> what?
>> She
>> She wants
>> what?
>> She wants us
>> She wants us to
>> what?
>> She wants us to see
>> She wants us to see if
>> what?
>> She wants us to see if she
>> She wants us to see if she should
>> what?
>> She wants us to see if she should be
there
there or
there or not.
>> There
>> There isn't
there or not.
>> There isn't any
>> There isn't any should.
there or not.
>> There isn't any should. No.
Well,
Well, can
Well, can we
Well, can we Well,
Well, can we Well, thank
Well, can we Well, thank you.
>> You
>> You got
Well, can we Well, thank you.
>> You got to
>> You got to be
Well, can we Well, thank you.
>> You got to be dedicated
>> You got to be dedicated to
Well, can we Well, thank you.
>> You got to be dedicated to that
>> You got to be dedicated to that kind
Well, can we Well, thank you.
>> You got to be dedicated to that kind of
a
a job
a job or
a job or quit
a job or quit it.
>> She's
>> She's a
a job or quit it.
>> She's a pharmacist.
>> I'm
>> I'm a
>> I'm a pharmacist.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well,
>> I'm a pharmacist.
>> Yeah. Well, you
>> Yeah. Well, you So,
>> I'm a pharmacist.
>> Yeah. Well, you So, you're
>> Yeah. Well, you So, you're dedicated.
So,
So, what's
So, what's that
So, what's that got
So, what's that got to
So, what's that got to do
So, what's that got to do with
So, what's that got to do with it
So, what's that got to do with it then?
>> Flowers
>> Flowers are
So, what's that got to do with it then?
>> Flowers are good,
>> Flowers are good, benefits
So, what's that got to do with it then?
>> Flowers are good, benefits are
>> Flowers are good, benefits are good.
>> Um,
>> Um, well,
>> Um, well, I
>> Um, well, I guess
>> Um, well, I guess I
>> Um, well, I guess I have
>> Um, well, I guess I have to
>> Um, well, I guess I have to figure
>> Um, well, I guess I have to figure this
one
one out.
>> You
>> You You
>> You You mix
>> You You mix them
>> You You mix them up
>> You You mix them up a
>> You You mix them up a drram
>> You You mix them up a drram of
>> You You mix them up a drram of hemlock.
>> Yes.
>> Black
>> Black is
>> Black is witch's
>> Black is witch's blue,
>> Black is witch's blue, so
>> Black is witch's blue, so it's
>> Black is witch's blue, so it's good
enough
enough for
>> Black is witch's blue, so it's good
enough for Socrates.
enough for Socrates. Why
>> Black is witch's blue, so it's good
enough for Socrates. Why not
enough for Socrates. Why not for
>> Black is witch's blue, so it's good
enough for Socrates. Why not for you?
Thank
Thank you.
>> Um,
>> Um, there
Thank you.
>> Um, there is
>> Um, there is another
Thank you.
>> Um, there is another spiritual
>> Um, there is another spiritual teacher
who
who I've
who I've been
who I've been following
who I've been following and
who I've been following and I
who I've been following and I got
who I've been following and I got a
who I've been following and I got a lot
of
of side
who I've been following and I got a lot
of side effects
of side effects and
who I've been following and I got a lot
of side effects and I'm
of side effects and I'm not
who I've been following and I got a lot
of side effects and I'm not sure
of side effects and I'm not sure if
who I've been following and I got a lot
of side effects and I'm not sure if it's
my
my karma
my karma coming
my karma coming up
my karma coming up or
my karma coming up or is
my karma coming up or is it
my karma coming up or is it the
my karma coming up or is it the wrong
teacher.
teacher. Amada
my karma coming up or is it the wrong
teacher. Amada and
teacher. Amada and that's
my karma coming up or is it the wrong
teacher. Amada and that's a
teacher. Amada and that's a uh
my karma coming up or is it the wrong
teacher. Amada and that's a uh amadea
>> deva
>> amadva
>> amadeva
>> he
>> he he
>> amadeva
>> he he teaches
>> he he teaches mantras
>> amadeva
>> he he teaches mantras and
>> he he teaches mantras and um
>> amadeva
>> he he teaches mantras and um you
>> he he teaches mantras and um you know
mantras
mantras to
mantras to ganes
>> I
>> I I'm
mantras to ganes
>> I I'm sorry
>> I I'm sorry we
mantras to ganes
>> I I'm sorry we don't
>> I I'm sorry we don't know
mantras to ganes
>> I I'm sorry we don't know who
>> I I'm sorry we don't know who he
mantras to ganes
>> I I'm sorry we don't know who he is
>> can
>> can we
do
do we're
>> can we
do we're we're
do we're we're not
>> can we
do we're we're not going
do we're we're not going to
>> can we
do we're we're not going to do
do we're we're not going to do spiritual
teachers
teachers you
teachers you can't
>> I
>> I can't
teachers you can't
>> I can't do
>> I can't do spirit
>> now
>> now look
>> now look if
>> now look if you
>> now look if you can't
>> now look if you can't intuit
>> now look if you can't intuit it
>> now look if you can't intuit it whether
a
a person
>> now look if you can't intuit it whether
a person is
a person is good
>> now look if you can't intuit it whether
a person is good or
a person is good or not
>> now look if you can't intuit it whether
a person is good or not good
a person is good or not good you
>> now look if you can't intuit it whether
a person is good or not good you should
give
give up
give up the
give up the whole
give up the whole enterprise
Thank
Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you. Thank
>> Okay. Thank you. Thank you
>> Okay. Thank you. Thank you so
>> Okay. Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, we
>> Okay. Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Yeah, we can't
>> Yeah, we can't do
>> Okay. Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Yeah, we can't do that.
>> Yeah, we can't do that. That's
>> Okay. Thank you. Thank you so much.
>> Yeah, we can't do that. That's I
>> Yeah, we can't do that. That's I mean
did
>> Hi.
>> Yeah,
>> Dr.
>> Dr. Hawkins,
>> Yeah,
>> Dr. Hawkins, my
>> Dr. Hawkins, my deepest
>> Yeah,
>> Dr. Hawkins, my deepest thank
>> Dr. Hawkins, my deepest thank you
>> Yeah,
>> Dr. Hawkins, my deepest thank you from
my
my friends
my friends and
my friends and me
my friends and me for
my friends and me for your
my friends and me for your teachings
my friends and me for your teachings and
for
for your
my friends and me for your teachings and
for your love.
>> Um
>> Um you
>> Um you said
>> Um you said earlier
>> Um you said earlier on
>> Um you said earlier on that
>> Um you said earlier on that how
>> Um you said earlier on that how we
>> Um you said earlier on that how we leave
the
the earth
>> Um you said earlier on that how we leave
the earth is
the earth is comically
>> Um you said earlier on that how we leave
the earth is comically predetermined.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. The
>> Yes. The win.
>> Yes. The win. The
>> Yes. The win. The win.
>> Yes. The win. The win. Yes.
>> The
>> The win.
>> And
>> And uh
>> And uh are
>> And uh are there
>> And uh are there not
>> And uh are there not the
>> And uh are there not the intentions
>> And uh are there not the intentions and
the
the choices
>> And uh are there not the intentions and
the choices and
the choices and the
>> And uh are there not the intentions and
the choices and the goodwill
the choices and the goodwill towards
everything
everything is
everything is it
everything is it not
everything is it not also
everything is it not also predetermined?
>> What?
>> No.
>> No. Um
>> No. Um she
>> No. Um she says
>> No. Um she says that
>> No. Um she says that the
>> No. Um she says that the goodness
>> No. Um she says that the goodness and
what
>> the
>> the intentions
>> and
>> and the
>> the intentions
>> and the intentions
>> and the intentions is
>> the intentions
>> and the intentions is that
>> and the intentions is that also
predetermined.
>> No.
Because
Because also
>> No.
Because also in
Because also in your
>> No.
Because also in your books
Because also in your books you
>> No.
Because also in your books you say
Because also in your books you say at
one
one stage
one stage that
one stage that um
it's
it's the
one stage that um
it's the intentions
it's the intentions and
one stage that um
it's the intentions and then
it's the intentions and then um
one stage that um
it's the intentions and then um in
>> that
>> that comes
>> that comes out
>> that comes out of
>> that comes out of the
>> that comes out of the karmic
>> that comes out of the karmic evolution
of
of where
>> that comes out of the karmic evolution
of where you
of where you are.
>> that comes out of the karmic evolution
of where you are. You
of where you are. You see
>> that comes out of the karmic evolution
of where you are. You see yes
of where you are. You see yes you
>> that comes out of the karmic evolution
of where you are. You see yes you you
evolve
evolve to
evolve to the
evolve to the point
evolve to the point where
evolve to the point where you
evolve to the point where you have
goodwill
goodwill towards
evolve to the point where you have
goodwill towards all
goodwill towards all of
evolve to the point where you have
goodwill towards all of life
goodwill towards all of life and
evolve to the point where you have
goodwill towards all of life and all
goodwill towards all of life and all its
expressions
expressions but
expressions but that's
expressions but that's pretty
expressions but that's pretty advanced
level
level already.
But
But then
But then you
But then you say
But then you say in
But then you say in your
But then you say in your books
But then you say in your books that
But then you say in your books that it's
um
um less
But then you say in your books that it's
um less the
um less the intentions
But then you say in your books that it's
um less the intentions and
um less the intentions and the
But then you say in your books that it's
um less the intentions and the will.
It's
It's more
It's more the
It's more the um
It's more the um power
It's more the um power of
It's more the um power of the
It's more the um power of the energy
field.
>> It's
>> It's less
>> It's less the
>> It's less the intentions
>> It's less the intentions and
>> It's less the intentions and more
>> It's less the intentions and more of
>> It's less the intentions and more of the
power
power of
>> It's less the intentions and more of the
power of the
power of the energy
>> It's less the intentions and more of the
power of the energy field.
>> She's
>> She's mixing
>> She's mixing stuff
>> She's mixing stuff up
>> She's mixing stuff up in
>> She's mixing stuff up in the
>> She's mixing stuff up in the books.
>> She's mixing stuff up in the books. Yes.
>> And
>> And trying
>> She's mixing stuff up in the books. Yes.
>> And trying to
>> And trying to come
>> She's mixing stuff up in the books. Yes.
>> And trying to come up
>> And trying to come up with
>> She's mixing stuff up in the books. Yes.
>> And trying to come up with this
>> And trying to come up with this with
this
question.
question. So
this
question. So it
question. So it it
this
question. So it it doesn't
question. So it it doesn't make
this
question. So it it doesn't make any
sense.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, that
sense.
>> Yeah, that makes
>> Yeah, that makes sense.
sense.
>> Yeah, that makes sense. Um
>> I
>> I I
>> I I would
>> I I would like
>> I I would like to
>> I I would like to know
>> I I would like to know where
>> I I would like to know where really
>> I I would like to know where really free
will
will exists
>> in
>> in in
>> in in what?
>> She
>> She she
>> in in what?
>> She she doesn't
>> She she doesn't understand
>> in in what?
>> She she doesn't understand free
>> She she doesn't understand free will
>> in in what?
>> She she doesn't understand free will and
where
where does
where does free
where does free will
where does free will exist?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you
where does free will exist?
>> Oh, you have
>> Oh, you have the
where does free will exist?
>> Oh, you have the option
>> Oh, you have the option of
where does free will exist?
>> Oh, you have the option of choice.
You
You you
You you don't
You you don't have
You you don't have any
You you don't have any you
You you don't have any you are
You you don't have any you are compelled
to
to constantly
You you don't have any you are compelled
to constantly make
to constantly make choices
and
and the
and the and
and the and the
and the and the choices
and the and the choices that
and the and the choices that you
and the and the choices that you make
reflect
uh
uh your
uh your karma
uh your karma and
uh your karma and your
uh your karma and your spiritual
evolution.
You
You will
You will make
You will make higher
You will make higher choices
You will make higher choices if
You will make higher choices if you
You will make higher choices if you are
higher
higher and
You will make higher choices if you are
higher and make
higher and make lower
You will make higher choices if you are
higher and make lower choices
higher and make lower choices if
You will make higher choices if you are
higher and make lower choices if you're
lower.
lower. So
lower. So those
lower. So those would
lower. So those would be
lower. So those would be options
lower. So those would be options and
lower. So those would be options and you
choose
choose depending
lower. So those would be options and you
choose depending on
choose depending on how
lower. So those would be options and you
choose depending on how you
choose depending on how you see
lower. So those would be options and you
choose depending on how you see it.
choose depending on how you see it. And
how
how you
how you see
how you see it
how you see it is
how you see it is a
how you see it is a reflection
how you see it is a reflection of
how you see it is a reflection of your
level
level of
how you see it is a reflection of your
level of consciousness.
You
You might
You might see
You might see it
You might see it as
You might see it as a
You might see it as a a
You might see it as a a moment
You might see it as a a moment that
You might see it as a a moment that you
know
know you
You might see it as a a moment that you
know you might
know you might see
You might see it as a a moment that you
know you might see it
know you might see it as
You might see it as a a moment that you
know you might see it as forgiveness
know you might see it as forgiveness or
you
you might
you might see
you might see it
you might see it as
you might see it as a
you might see it as a need
you might see it as a need for
retaliation.
retaliation. Depends
you might see it as a need for
retaliation. Depends completely
retaliation. Depends completely on
you might see it as a need for
retaliation. Depends completely on what
your
your level
your level of
your level of consciousness
your level of consciousness is.
>> Okay.
You
You might
You might choose
You might choose to
You might choose to forgive
You might choose to forgive or
You might choose to forgive or you
You might choose to forgive or you might
choose
choose to
You might choose to forgive or you might
choose to execute
choose to execute them.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Off
>> Off with
>> Off with their
>> Off with their heads.
>> Yes.
>> We're
>> We're running
>> We're running out
>> We're running out of
>> We're running out of time.
>> We're running out of time. So,
>> We're running out of time. So, I
>> We're running out of time. So, I would
just
just like
>> We're running out of time. So, I would
just like to
just like to ask
>> We're running out of time. So, I would
just like to ask for
just like to ask for a
>> We're running out of time. So, I would
just like to ask for a blessing
just like to ask for a blessing for
where
where I'm
where I'm at
where I'm at and
where I'm at and where
where I'm at and where I'm
where I'm at and where I'm to
where I'm at and where I'm to go.
>> God
>> God bless
where I'm at and where I'm to go.
>> God bless you.
>> God bless you. It
where I'm at and where I'm to go.
>> God bless you. It is
>> God bless you. It is very
where I'm at and where I'm to go.
>> God bless you. It is very charming
>> God bless you. It is very charming of
you
you to
you to merely
you to merely ask
you to merely ask her
you to merely ask her a
you to merely ask her a blessing.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> I
>> I bless
>> I bless you
>> I bless you in
>> I bless you in the
>> I bless you in the name
>> I bless you in the name of
>> I bless you in the name of the
>> I bless you in the name of the Lord.
Amen.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Hi
>> Hi Doc
>> Thank you.
>> Hi Doc Susan
>> Hi Doc Susan and
>> Thank you.
>> Hi Doc Susan and uh
>> Hi Doc Susan and uh thank
>> Thank you.
>> Hi Doc Susan and uh thank you
>> Hi Doc Susan and uh thank you for
everything
everything and
everything and thank
everything and thank you
everything and thank you for
everything and thank you for everyone
here.
here. My
everything and thank you for everyone
here. My question
here. My question is
everything and thank you for everyone
here. My question is is
here. My question is is as
everything and thank you for everyone
here. My question is is as I've
here. My question is is as I've been
everything and thank you for everyone
here. My question is is as I've been on
the
the spiritual
the spiritual path
the spiritual path and
the spiritual path and meditating,
the spiritual path and meditating, I
become
become quite
the spiritual path and meditating, I
become quite solidly
become quite solidly aware
the spiritual path and meditating, I
become quite solidly aware of
become quite solidly aware of the
witness
witness observer
witness observer on
witness observer on not
witness observer on not only
witness observer on not only when
witness observer on not only when I'm
meditating
meditating but
witness observer on not only when I'm
meditating but also
meditating but also when
witness observer on not only when I'm
meditating but also when I'm
meditating but also when I'm walking
around.
around. Yes.
>> And
>> And it's
around. Yes.
>> And it's it's
>> And it's it's been
around. Yes.
>> And it's it's been starting
>> And it's it's been starting to
around. Yes.
>> And it's it's been starting to where
>> And it's it's been starting to where I
start
start to
start to become
start to become aware
start to become aware of
start to become aware of something
that's
that's witnessing
start to become aware of something
that's witnessing the
that's witnessing the witness
start to become aware of something
that's witnessing the witness observer.
So
So is
So is my
So is my question
So is my question is
So is my question is is
So is my question is is there
So is my question is is there another
step
step further
So is my question is is there another
step further when
step further when you
So is my question is is there another
step further when you start
step further when you start to
So is my question is is there another
step further when you start to really
get
get solid?
get solid? There
get solid? There is
>> there's
>> there's witnessing
get solid? There is
>> there's witnessing and
>> there's witnessing and observing
get solid? There is
>> there's witnessing and observing but
>> there's witnessing and observing but no
witness
witness and
witness and or
witness and or observer.
witness and or observer. The
witness and or observer. The phenomena
occur
occur without
witness and or observer. The phenomena
occur without subject
occur without subject or
witness and or observer. The phenomena
occur without subject or object
occur without subject or object without
subject
subject or
subject or verb.
>> All
>> All right.
subject or verb.
>> All right. Thank
>> All right. Thank you.
subject or verb.
>> All right. Thank you. Because
>> All right. Thank you. Because I
subject or verb.
>> All right. Thank you. Because I that
seems
seems to
seems to be
seems to be starting
seems to be starting to
seems to be starting to happen
seems to be starting to happen but
seems to be starting to happen but not
it's
it's like
seems to be starting to happen but not
it's like it's
it's like it's fleeting.
seems to be starting to happen but not
it's like it's fleeting. Let
it's like it's fleeting. Let go
seems to be starting to happen but not
it's like it's fleeting. Let go of
it's like it's fleeting. Let go of the
noun,
noun, let
noun, let go
noun, let go of
noun, let go of the
noun, let go of the pronoun,
>> and
>> and let
noun, let go of the pronoun,
>> and let go
>> and let go of
noun, let go of the pronoun,
>> and let go of the
>> and let go of the verb.
>> That
>> That that's
>> That that's happened
>> That that's happened a
>> That that's happened a little
>> That that's happened a little bit
>> That that's happened a little bit where
there's
there's no
>> That that's happened a little bit where
there's no um
there's no um there's
>> That that's happened a little bit where
there's no um there's just
there's no um there's just total
awareness
awareness of
awareness of me
awareness of me observing
awareness of me observing my
awareness of me observing my mind
awareness of me observing my mind body.
>> All
>> All right.
awareness of me observing my mind body.
>> All right. So,
>> All right. So, you
awareness of me observing my mind body.
>> All right. So, you let
>> All right. So, you let go
awareness of me observing my mind body.
>> All right. So, you let go of
>> All right. So, you let go of the
awareness of me observing my mind body.
>> All right. So, you let go of the me
after
after a
after a while.
>> Okay.
>> There
>> There isn't
>> There isn't any
>> There isn't any me
>> There isn't any me observing.
Observingness
Observingness is
>> There isn't any me observing.
Observingness is a
Observingness is a phenomena
>> There isn't any me observing.
Observingness is a phenomena complete
and
and total
and total in
and total in itself.
and total in itself. It
and total in itself. It does
and total in itself. It does not
and total in itself. It does not need
and total in itself. It does not need a
subject
subject or
and total in itself. It does not need a
subject or an
subject or an object.
and total in itself. It does not need a
subject or an object. Observingness
is
is a
is a autonomous
is a autonomous phenomena.
is a autonomous phenomena. It's
is a autonomous phenomena. It's a
manifestation
manifestation of
is a autonomous phenomena. It's a
manifestation of consciousness.
But
But if
But if I
But if I tell
But if I tell you
But if I tell you that
But if I tell you that you're
But if I tell you that you're going
But if I tell you that you're going to
make
make a
But if I tell you that you're going to
make a pronoun
make a pronoun out
But if I tell you that you're going to
make a pronoun out of
make a pronoun out of consciousness,
>> aren't
>> aren't you?
>> It's
>> It's tricky.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. So that's
>> Yeah. So that's that's
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. So that's that's why
>> Yeah. So that's that's why I'm
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. So that's that's why I'm asking
>> Yeah. So that's that's why I'm asking it
because
because I'm
because I'm I'm
because I'm I'm getting
because I'm I'm getting stuck
because I'm I'm getting stuck there.
because I'm I'm getting stuck there. I'm
starting
starting to
because I'm I'm getting stuck there. I'm
starting to go
starting to go there
because I'm I'm getting stuck there. I'm
starting to go there and
starting to go there and then
because I'm I'm getting stuck there. I'm
starting to go there and then I
starting to go there and then I mess
because I'm I'm getting stuck there. I'm
starting to go there and then I mess it
up.
>> This
>> This doing
up.
>> This doing that.
>> This doing that. Yeah.
>> There
>> There is
>> There is only
>> There is only this
>> There is only this being
>> There is only this being this.
that
that doesn't
>> There is only this being this.
that doesn't require
that doesn't require a
>> There is only this being this.
that doesn't require a known
that doesn't require a known noun,
>> There is only this being this.
that doesn't require a known noun, a
pronoun
pronoun or
pronoun or a
pronoun or a verb.
So,
So, let
pronoun or a verb.
So, let go
So, let go all
pronoun or a verb.
So, let go all nouns,
So, let go all nouns, pronouns,
pronoun or a verb.
So, let go all nouns, pronouns, and
verbs,
verbs, and
verbs, and especially
verbs, and especially adjectives
and
and adverbs
verbs, and especially adjectives
and adverbs as
and adverbs as well.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Watch
>> Watch them
>> Watch them adverbs
>> Watch them adverbs shinking
>> Watch them adverbs shinking up
>> Watch them adverbs shinking up on
>> Watch them adverbs shinking up on you
from
from behind.
I
I caught
I caught an
I caught an adverb
I caught an adverb on
I caught an adverb on the
I caught an adverb on the lawn
I caught an adverb on the lawn the
I caught an adverb on the lawn the other
day
day and
I caught an adverb on the lawn the other
day and I
day and I smashed
I caught an adverb on the lawn the other
day and I smashed it
day and I smashed it before
I caught an adverb on the lawn the other
day and I smashed it before I
day and I smashed it before I had
I caught an adverb on the lawn the other
day and I smashed it before I had a
chance
chance to
chance to get
chance to get up
chance to get up any
chance to get up any speed.
chance to get up any speed. Yes.
>> I'm
>> I'm just
chance to get up any speed. Yes.
>> I'm just bringing
>> I'm just bringing um
chance to get up any speed. Yes.
>> I'm just bringing um love
>> I'm just bringing um love from
chance to get up any speed. Yes.
>> I'm just bringing um love from the
Melbourne
Melbourne Australian
Melbourne Australian study
Melbourne Australian study group.
>> Yes.
>> Which
>> Which there's
>> Which there's a
>> Which there's a few
>> Which there's a few of
>> Which there's a few of us
>> Which there's a few of us here.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And uh
>> And uh just
>> And uh just ask
>> And uh just ask you
>> And uh just ask you to
>> And uh just ask you to shake
>> And uh just ask you to shake this
>> And uh just ask you to shake this hand
over
over this
>> And uh just ask you to shake this hand
over this modern
over this modern man.
>> Yes.
>> How
>> How do
>> Yes.
>> How do you
>> How do you do?
>> Glad
>> Glad to
>> Glad to meet
>> Glad to meet you,
>> Glad to meet you, sir.
>> Thank
>> Thank you,
>> Glad to meet you, sir.
>> Thank you, Susan.
>> Thank you, Susan. Thank
>> Glad to meet you, sir.
>> Thank you, Susan. Thank you,
>> Thank you, Susan. Thank you, doctor.
He's
He's from
He's from where?
He's from where? Melbourne.
>> Melbourne,
>> Melbourne, also.
>> Yes.
Hi.
Hi. Hello.
>> I'm
>> I'm also
>> I'm also from
>> I'm also from Australia.
>> We
>> We got
>> I'm also from Australia.
>> We got another
>> We got another Aussie
>> from
>> from Byron
>> from Byron Bay.
>> from Byron Bay. Just
>> from Byron Bay. Just want
>> from Byron Bay. Just want to
>> from Byron Bay. Just want to thank
>> from Byron Bay. Just want to thank you
very
very much
>> from Byron Bay. Just want to thank you
very much and
very much and very
>> from Byron Bay. Just want to thank you
very much and very grateful
very much and very grateful to
>> from Byron Bay. Just want to thank you
very much and very grateful to be
very much and very grateful to be here
for
for your
for your wonderful
for your wonderful work.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Like
>> Like a
>> Thank you.
>> Like a photo,
>> Like a photo, please.
>> All
>> All the
>> All the way
>> All the way from
>> All the way from Australia.
>> All the way from Australia. Why
>> All the way from Australia. Why don't
the
the people
>> All the way from Australia. Why don't
the people who
the people who live
>> All the way from Australia. Why don't
the people who live in
the people who live in Australia
>> All the way from Australia. Why don't
the people who live in Australia fall
off
off the
off the globe
off the globe when
off the globe when the
off the globe when the globe
off the globe when the globe is
off the globe when the globe is shaped
this
this way
off the globe when the globe is shaped
this way when
this way when Australia's
off the globe when the globe is shaped
this way when Australia's at
this way when Australia's at the
off the globe when the globe is shaped
this way when Australia's at the bottom?
How
How come
How come they
How come they don't
How come they don't just
How come they don't just drop
How come they don't just drop off?
How come they don't just drop off? Huh?
What
What keeps
How come they don't just drop off? Huh?
What keeps you
What keeps you people
How come they don't just drop off? Huh?
What keeps you people there
What keeps you people there upside
How come they don't just drop off? Huh?
What keeps you people there upside down?
>> That's
>> That's right.
>> You
>> You keep
>> That's right.
>> You keep us
>> You keep us up,
>> That's right.
>> You keep us up, though.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, they're
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah, they're upside
>> Yeah, they're upside down
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah, they're upside down there
>> Yeah, they're upside down there in
Australia.
>> We've
>> We've got
Australia.
>> We've got to
>> We've got to go
Australia.
>> We've got to go there
>> We've got to go there somewhere.
>> Nobody.
>> Nobody. Uh,
>> hello
>> hello Susan.
>> Nobody. Uh,
>> hello Susan. Hello,
>> hello Susan. Hello, Dr.
Now
Now I
Now I really
Now I really have
Now I really have a
Now I really have a multitude
Now I really have a multitude of
questions
questions I
Now I really have a multitude of
questions I would
questions I would like
Now I really have a multitude of
questions I would like to
questions I would like to ask
Now I really have a multitude of
questions I would like to ask you
questions I would like to ask you but
they
they told
they told me
they told me one.
they told me one. So
they told me one. So I'm
they told me one. So I'm working
they told me one. So I'm working on
they told me one. So I'm working on a
thesis
thesis in
they told me one. So I'm working on a
thesis in spirituality
thesis in spirituality and
they told me one. So I'm working on a
thesis in spirituality and leadership
ethics
ethics and
ethics and my
ethics and my question
ethics and my question is
ethics and my question is can
ethics and my question is can I
ethics and my question is can I use
kinesiology
kinesiology to
ethics and my question is can I use
kinesiology to calibrate
kinesiology to calibrate organizations
just
just as
just as you
just as you do
just as you do people?
>> Sure.
>> That's
>> That's what
>> That's what I
>> That's what I wanted
>> That's what I wanted to
>> That's what I wanted to know.
>> That's what I wanted to know. Oh
>> thank
>> thank you.
>> Yep.
Thank
Thank you
>> Yep.
Thank you for
Thank you for your
>> Yep.
Thank you for your work.
>> Hello.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. Uh
>> Hello.
>> Hi. Uh my
>> Hi. Uh my question
>> Hello.
>> Hi. Uh my question is
>> Hi. Uh my question is how
>> Hello.
>> Hi. Uh my question is how do
>> Hi. Uh my question is how do you
>> Hello.
>> Hi. Uh my question is how do you hold
>> Hi. Uh my question is how do you hold a
thought
thought in
thought in mind
thought in mind and
thought in mind and how
thought in mind and how do
thought in mind and how do you
thought in mind and how do you let
thought in mind and how do you let go
thought in mind and how do you let go of
a
a thought?
>> Well,
>> Well, that's
>> Well, that's a
>> Well, that's a weird
>> Well, that's a weird question.
How
How did
>> Well, that's a weird question.
How did you
How did you hold
>> Well, that's a weird question.
How did you hold that
How did you hold that question
>> Well, that's a weird question.
How did you hold that question in
How did you hold that question in mind
as
as you
as you walked
as you walked up
as you walked up here
as you walked up here to
as you walked up here to ask
as you walked up here to ask it?
>> By
>> By by
as you walked up here to ask it?
>> By by decision
>> By by decision and
as you walked up here to ask it?
>> By by decision and intention.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. By
>> Okay. By decision
>> Okay. By decision and
>> Okay. By decision and by
>> Okay. By decision and by intention.
>> Okay. By decision and by intention. You
made
made a
>> Okay. By decision and by intention. You
made a decision
made a decision to
>> Okay. By decision and by intention. You
made a decision to do
made a decision to do that.
>> Okay. By decision and by intention. You
made a decision to do that. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> So
>> So by
>> Yes.
>> So by by
>> So by by decision
>> Yes.
>> So by by decision and
>> So by by decision and you
>> Yes.
>> So by by decision and you have
>> So by by decision and you have power
over
over your
over your mind
over your mind to
over your mind to make
over your mind to make decisions
over your mind to make decisions and
choices.
choices. So
over your mind to make decisions and
choices. So you
choices. So you choose
over your mind to make decisions and
choices. So you choose to
choices. So you choose to have
over your mind to make decisions and
choices. So you choose to have that
linger
linger until
linger until you
linger until you got
linger until you got to
linger until you got to ask
linger until you got to ask it.
linger until you got to ask it. Yes.
>> It's
>> It's your
linger until you got to ask it. Yes.
>> It's your free
>> It's your free option
linger until you got to ask it. Yes.
>> It's your free option to
>> It's your free option to choose
linger until you got to ask it. Yes.
>> It's your free option to choose or
reject
reject it.
>> And
>> And you
reject it.
>> And you can
>> And you can hold
reject it.
>> And you can hold it
>> And you can hold it and
reject it.
>> And you can hold it and then
>> And you can hold it and then you
reject it.
>> And you can hold it and then you can
release
release it
release it also.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Mhm.
>> Perfect.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You
>> Perfect.
>> Yeah. You can
>> Yeah. You can say
>> Perfect.
>> Yeah. You can say no
>> Yeah. You can say no to
>> Perfect.
>> Yeah. You can say no to it
>> Yeah. You can say no to it if
>> Perfect.
>> Yeah. You can say no to it if you
>> Yeah. You can say no to it if you want.
>> Okay.
>> I'm
>> I'm not
>> Okay.
>> I'm not going
>> I'm not going to
>> Okay.
>> I'm not going to think
>> I'm not going to think that
>> Okay.
>> I'm not going to think that thought.
>> I'm not going to think that thought. My
god.
god. No
god. No way.
I'm
I'm not
god. No way.
I'm not going
I'm not going to
god. No way.
I'm not going to let
I'm not going to let thoughts
god. No way.
I'm not going to let thoughts knock
I'm not going to let thoughts knock me
all
all around.
>> That
>> That was
all around.
>> That was a
>> That was a good
all around.
>> That was a good one.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. Oh,
>> Oh. Oh, darn
>> Oh. Oh, darn thought.
>> Oh. Oh, darn thought. Yes,
>> Oh. Oh, darn thought. Yes, that
>> Oh. Oh, darn thought. Yes, that was
>> Oh. Oh, darn thought. Yes, that was a
good
good one.
>> Oh. Oh, darn thought. Yes, that was a
good one. Mhm.
Yes.
>> I'm
>> I'm from
Yes.
>> I'm from Australia
>> I'm from Australia also.
>> Just
>> Just another
>> Oh,
>> Oh, well
>> Just another
>> Oh, well sort
>> Oh, well sort of.
>> Just another
>> Oh, well sort of. I
>> Oh, well sort of. I have
>> Just another
>> Oh, well sort of. I have no
>> Oh, well sort of. I have no question.
>> Just another
>> Oh, well sort of. I have no question. I
would
would just
would just like
would just like to
would just like to be
would just like to be in
would just like to be in your
would just like to be in your presence
and
and perhaps
would just like to be in your presence
and perhaps have
and perhaps have a
would just like to be in your presence
and perhaps have a photo.
and perhaps have a photo. Is
would just like to be in your presence
and perhaps have a photo. Is that
and perhaps have a photo. Is that okay?
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Love.
>> Thank you. Love. Give
>> Thank you. Love. Give me
>> Thank you. Love. Give me a
Y.
Y. Okay.
>> Thank you. Love. Give me a
Y. Okay. You
Y. Okay. You want
>> Thank you. Love. Give me a
Y. Okay. You want it
Y. Okay. You want it back
>> Thank you. Love. Give me a
Y. Okay. You want it back now?
Thank
Thank you. She
Thank you. She wants
Thank you. She wants it
Thank you. She wants it back.
>> All
>> All right.
>> It's
>> It's so
>> It's so great
>> It's so great to
>> It's so great to see
>> It's so great to see so
>> It's so great to see so many
>> It's so great to see so many from
Australia.
Thank
Thank you
Thank you so
Thank you so much.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello.
>> Hi.
>> I
>> I uh
>> I uh I'm
>> I uh I'm from
>> I uh I'm from England
>> I uh I'm from England and
>> I uh I'm from England and uh
>> I uh I'm from England and uh yeah.
>> I uh I'm from England and uh yeah. uh
I've
I've read
>> I uh I'm from England and uh yeah. uh
I've read all
I've read all your
>> I uh I'm from England and uh yeah. uh
I've read all your books
I've read all your books and
>> I uh I'm from England and uh yeah. uh
I've read all your books and I'd
I've read all your books and I'd just
like
like to
like to thank
like to thank you
like to thank you and
like to thank you and also
like to thank you and also for
introducing
introducing me
like to thank you and also for
introducing me to
introducing me to other
like to thank you and also for
introducing me to other teachers
introducing me to other teachers such
like to thank you and also for
introducing me to other teachers such as
Huang
Huang Poe
Huang Poe and
Huang Poe and Manam
Huang Poe and Manam Mahashi
Huang Poe and Manam Mahashi for
Huang Poe and Manam Mahashi for they've
also
also helped
Huang Poe and Manam Mahashi for they've
also helped me
also helped me as
Huang Poe and Manam Mahashi for they've
also helped me as well
also helped me as well and
Huang Poe and Manam Mahashi for they've
also helped me as well and I'd
also helped me as well and I'd just
Huang Poe and Manam Mahashi for they've
also helped me as well and I'd just like
a
a blessing.
>> Uh
>> Uh very
a blessing.
>> Uh very good.
Yeah,
Yeah, the
Yeah, the spiritual
Yeah, the spiritual pathway
Yeah, the spiritual pathway is
gratifying
gratifying and
Yeah, the spiritual pathway is
gratifying and pleasurable
and
and enjoyable.
Yes.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Hi.
>> Thank you for
>> Thank you for this
>> Hi.
>> Thank you for this opportunity.
Um,
Um, Dr.
Um, Dr. Hawkins,
Um, Dr. Hawkins, can
Um, Dr. Hawkins, can you
Um, Dr. Hawkins, can you clarify
Um, Dr. Hawkins, can you clarify for
Um, Dr. Hawkins, can you clarify for me
uh
uh if
Um, Dr. Hawkins, can you clarify for me
uh if there
uh if there is
Um, Dr. Hawkins, can you clarify for me
uh if there is no
uh if there is no crossover
Um, Dr. Hawkins, can you clarify for me
uh if there is no crossover between
uh if there is no crossover between the
animal
animal realm
animal realm and
animal realm and the
animal realm and the human
animal realm and the human realm
animal realm and the human realm in
reincarnation
reincarnation terms?
animal realm and the human realm in
reincarnation terms? For
reincarnation terms? For example,
animal realm and the human realm in
reincarnation terms? For example, uh
reincarnation terms? For example, uh dog
spirits
spirits can
spirits can only
spirits can only reincarnate
spirits can only reincarnate within
spirits can only reincarnate within the
dog
dog consciousness
spirits can only reincarnate within the
dog consciousness realm,
dog consciousness realm, let's
spirits can only reincarnate within the
dog consciousness realm, let's say.
dog consciousness realm, let's say. How
did
did monkeys
did monkeys evolve
did monkeys evolve into
did monkeys evolve into humans?
did monkeys evolve into humans? How
did monkeys evolve into humans? How did
that
that crossover
did monkeys evolve into humans? How did
that crossover happen?
>> No.
>> No. Who
>> No. Who said
>> No. Who said it
>> No. Who said it did?
>> I
>> I I
>> No. Who said it did?
>> I I understood
>> I I understood that
>> No. Who said it did?
>> I I understood that creation
>> I I understood that creation and
evolution
evolution are
evolution are one
evolution are one in
evolution are one in the
evolution are one in the same
evolution are one in the same thing.
evolution are one in the same thing. And
I
I I
evolution are one in the same thing. And
I I I
I I I can
evolution are one in the same thing. And
I I I can get
I I I can get my
evolution are one in the same thing. And
I I I can get my head
I I I can get my head around
evolution are one in the same thing. And
I I I can get my head around that.
>> What
>> What did
>> What did you
>> What did you think?
>> Creation
>> Creation and
>> What did you think?
>> Creation and evolution
>> Creation and evolution are
>> What did you think?
>> Creation and evolution are one
>> Creation and evolution are one of the
can't
can't get
can't get understand
can't get understand that
can't get understand that concept.
>> Oh
>> Oh yeah.
can't get understand that concept.
>> Oh yeah. Mhm.
Creation
Creation is
Creation is what
Creation is what evolution
Creation is what evolution looks
Creation is what evolution looks like.
What
What creation
Creation is what evolution looks like.
What creation looks
What creation looks like
you
you can
you can create
you can create a
you can create a thing
you can create a thing already.
you can create a thing already. You
you can create a thing already. You can
create
create a
you can create a thing already. You can
create a cake
create a cake already
you can create a thing already. You can
create a cake already cooked
or
or you
or you can
or you can put
or you can put the
or you can put the batter
or you can put the batter in
or you can put the batter in and
or you can put the batter in and you
or you can put the batter in and you put
it
it in
or you can put the batter in and you put
it in the
it in the oven
or you can put the batter in and you put
it in the oven and
it in the oven and you
or you can put the batter in and you put
it in the oven and you turn
it in the oven and you turn it
or you can put the batter in and you put
it in the oven and you turn it up
it in the oven and you turn it up and
you
you see
you see it
you see it rise
you see it rise and
you see it rise and become
you see it rise and become its
fulfillment
fulfillment of
you see it rise and become its
fulfillment of its
fulfillment of its potential.
So
So we
So we inherited
So we inherited was
So we inherited was a
So we inherited was a potential
So we inherited was a potential and
evolution
evolution is
So we inherited was a potential and
evolution is the
evolution is the uh
So we inherited was a potential and
evolution is the uh is
evolution is the uh is the
So we inherited was a potential and
evolution is the uh is the emergence
evolution is the uh is the emergence of
of
of what
of what it
of what it looks
of what it looks like.
>> Okay.
>> So
>> So the
>> So the universe
>> So the universe was
>> So the universe was created
in
in an
>> So the universe was created
in an evolutionary
in an evolutionary design.
>> So the universe was created
in an evolutionary design. You
in an evolutionary design. You might
>> So the universe was created
in an evolutionary design. You might say
it
it was
it was created
it was created to
it was created to be
it was created to be evolutionary.
Yes.
Yes. God's
it was created to be evolutionary.
Yes. God's will
Yes. God's will was
it was created to be evolutionary.
Yes. God's will was that
Yes. God's will was that there
it was created to be evolutionary.
Yes. God's will was that there would
Yes. God's will was that there would to
be
be was
be was to
be was to be
be was to be no
be was to be no end.
be was to be no end. That
be was to be no end. That evolution
be was to be no end. That evolution is
an
an ongoing
be was to be no end. That evolution is
an ongoing continuous
an ongoing continuous progression.
>> And
>> And then
>> And then when
>> And then when we
>> And then when we look
>> And then when we look back
>> And then when we look back then
>> And then when we look back then we
>> And then when we look back then we then
we
we say
>> And then when we look back then we then
we say okay
we say okay this
>> And then when we look back then we then
we say okay this is
we say okay this is because
>> And then when we look back then we then
we say okay this is because of
we say okay this is because of that
>> And then when we look back then we then
we say okay this is because of that and
etc
etc etc.
>> It's
>> It's not
etc etc.
>> It's not because
>> It's not because of
>> oh
>> oh no
>> oh no it's
>> oh no it's not
>> oh no it's not because
>> oh no it's not because of
>> oh no it's not because of no
>> oh no it's not because of no you
>> oh no it's not because of no you think
of
of causality.
>> oh no it's not because of no you think
of causality. No,
of causality. No, emergence
>> oh no it's not because of no you think
of causality. No, emergence means
of causality. No, emergence means uh
this
this potentiality
this potentiality actualizes
this potentiality actualizes when
this potentiality actualizes when local
conditions
conditions are
this potentiality actualizes when local
conditions are appropriate.
This
This is
This is a
This is a potential
This is a potential and
This is a potential and it
This is a potential and it actualizes
if
if lo
This is a potential and it actualizes
if lo if
if lo if conditions
This is a potential and it actualizes
if lo if conditions are
if lo if conditions are favorable.
This is a potential and it actualizes
if lo if conditions are favorable. It's
not
not forced
not forced to
not forced to if
not forced to if it
not forced to if it doesn't
not forced to if it doesn't rain,
not forced to if it doesn't rain, it's
not
not going
not forced to if it doesn't rain, it's
not going to
not going to not
not forced to if it doesn't rain, it's
not going to not going
not going to not going to
not forced to if it doesn't rain, it's
not going to not going to the
not going to not going to the ceiling
will
will not
will not grow
will not grow without
will not grow without rain.
will not grow without rain. So,
but
but it's
will not grow without rain. So,
but it's set
but it's set up
will not grow without rain. So,
but it's set up from
but it's set up from evolution
will not grow without rain. So,
but it's set up from evolution that
but it's set up from evolution that the
seed
seed plus
seed plus warmth
seed plus warmth plus
seed plus warmth plus the
seed plus warmth plus the sun
seed plus warmth plus the sun plus
moisture
has
has the
has the potentiality
has the potentiality to
has the potentiality to emerge
has the potentiality to emerge as
has the potentiality to emerge as the
see
>> but
>> but it's
>> but it's not
>> but it's not forced
>> but it's not forced to
>> but it's not forced to do
>> but it's not forced to do so.
>> but it's not forced to do so. Mhm.
>> but it's not forced to do so. Mhm. And
obviously
obviously it's
>> but it's not forced to do so. Mhm. And
obviously it's up
obviously it's up to
>> but it's not forced to do so. Mhm. And
obviously it's up to local
obviously it's up to local conditions
because
because if
because if it
because if it doesn't
because if it doesn't rain
because if it doesn't rain the
because if it doesn't rain the seed
because if it doesn't rain the seed will
not
not evolve,
because if it doesn't rain the seed will
not evolve, you
not evolve, you know.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I
>> Yeah. Yeah. I can
>> Yeah. Yeah. I can see
>> Yeah. Yeah. I can see that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I can see that. I
>> Yeah. Yeah. I can see that. I think
>> Yeah. Yeah. I can see that. I think the
rest
rest of
>> Yeah. Yeah. I can see that. I think the
rest of it
rest of it will
>> Yeah. Yeah. I can see that. I think the
rest of it will get
rest of it will get clear
>> Yeah. Yeah. I can see that. I think the
rest of it will get clear in
rest of it will get clear in time.
>> No,
>> No, don't
>> No, don't you
>> No, don't you think
>> No, don't you think don't
>> No, don't you think don't think
>> No, don't you think don't think of
>> No, don't you think don't think of it
>> No, don't you think don't think of it in
terms
terms of
>> No, don't you think don't think of it in
terms of causality.
This
This phase
This phase does
This phase does not
This phase does not cause
This phase does not cause the
This phase does not cause the next
This phase does not cause the next phase
which
which does
This phase does not cause the next phase
which does not
which does not cause
This phase does not cause the next phase
which does not cause the
which does not cause the next.
This phase does not cause the next phase
which does not cause the next. So
which does not cause the next. So you're
superimposing
superimposing a
superimposing a Newtonian
dialogue
dialogue upon
superimposing a Newtonian
dialogue upon it
dialogue upon it of
superimposing a Newtonian
dialogue upon it of causality.
Nothing
Nothing is
Nothing is causing
Nothing is causing anything.
Nothing is causing anything. Everything
is
is merely
Nothing is causing anything. Everything
is merely becoming
the
the ful
the ful fulfillment
the ful fulfillment of
the ful fulfillment of his
the ful fulfillment of his own
potentiality,
but
but it's
but it's not
but it's not being
but it's not being caused
but it's not being caused to
but it's not being caused to do
but it's not being caused to do so.
>> So,
>> So, so
but it's not being caused to do so.
>> So, so a
>> So, so a a
but it's not being caused to do so.
>> So, so a a dog's
>> So, so a a dog's soul,
but it's not being caused to do so.
>> So, so a a dog's soul, as
>> So, so a a dog's soul, as it
but it's not being caused to do so.
>> So, so a a dog's soul, as it were,
I
I mean,
I mean, would
I mean, would that
for
for its
I mean, would that
for its the
for its the potentiality
I mean, would that
for its the potentiality of
for its the potentiality of of
I mean, would that
for its the potentiality of of where
it's
it's at
it's at in
it's at in in
it's at in in a
it's at in in a field
it's at in in a field of
it's at in in a field of consciousness,
would
would that
it's at in in a field of consciousness,
would that potentially
would that potentially come
it's at in in a field of consciousness,
would that potentially come back
would that potentially come back in
it's at in in a field of consciousness,
would that potentially come back in in
the
the body
the body of
the body of a
the body of a person?
What?
What? What?
the body of a person?
What? What? No,
What? What? No, not
the body of a person?
What? What? No, not in
What? What? No, not in the
the body of a person?
What? What? No, not in the body
What? What? No, not in the body of
the body of a person?
What? What? No, not in the body of a
person.
person. And
person. And that's
>> You
>> You know,
person. And that's
>> You know, a
>> You know, a dog
person. And that's
>> You know, a dog doesn't
>> You know, a dog doesn't become
person. And that's
>> You know, a dog doesn't become a
>> You know, a dog doesn't become a person,
though.
>> No,
>> No, actually,
though.
>> No, actually, sorry.
>> No, actually, sorry. I've
though.
>> No, actually, sorry. I've just
>> No, actually, sorry. I've just I've
though.
>> No, actually, sorry. I've just I've just
got
got it.
>> Okay.
>> I
>> I think
>> I think I've
>> I think I've just
>> I think I've just got
>> I think I've just got it.
>> I think I've just got it. I
>> I think I've just got it. I think
>> I think I've just got it. I think Yeah,
I
I am
>> I think I've just got it. I think Yeah,
I am I
I am I am
>> I think I've just got it. I think Yeah,
I am I am being
I am I am being really
>> I think I've just got it. I think Yeah,
I am I am being really linear
I am I am being really linear with
>> I think I've just got it. I think Yeah,
I am I am being really linear with this.
>> I
>> I am
>> I am being
>> I am being really
>> I am being really linear
>> I am being really linear with
>> I am being really linear with it.
>> I am being really linear with it. It's
beginning
beginning to
>> I am being really linear with it. It's
beginning to I'm
beginning to I'm getting
>> I am being really linear with it. It's
beginning to I'm getting a
beginning to I'm getting a sense
>> I am being really linear with it. It's
beginning to I'm getting a sense of
beginning to I'm getting a sense of it.
>> Okay.
>> Anyway,
>> Anyway, so
>> Okay.
>> Anyway, so because
>> Anyway, so because we'll
>> Okay.
>> Anyway, so because we'll just
>> Anyway, so because we'll just go
>> Okay.
>> Anyway, so because we'll just go around
in
in circles.
>> So,
>> So, if
in circles.
>> So, if you
>> So, if you if
in circles.
>> So, if you if you
>> So, if you if you read
in circles.
>> So, if you if you read one
>> So, if you if you read one of
in circles.
>> So, if you if you read one of our
>> So, if you if you read one of our books,
All
All right.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You
All right.
>> Yeah. You have
>> Yeah. You have the
All right.
>> Yeah. You have the potential
>> Yeah. You have the potential to
All right.
>> Yeah. You have the potential to pick
>> Yeah. You have the potential to pick up
another
another one
another one of
another one of them,
another one of them, but
another one of them, but whether
another one of them, but whether or
another one of them, but whether or not
you
you do
another one of them, but whether or not
you do is
you do is up
another one of them, but whether or not
you do is up to
you do is up to you.
>> Is
>> Is up
>> Is up to
>> Is up to you.
>> Is up to you. I'm
>> Is up to you. I'm I'm
>> Is up to you. I'm I'm getting
>> Is up to you. I'm I'm getting a
>> Is up to you. I'm I'm getting a sense
>> Is up to you. I'm I'm getting a sense of
of
of the
>> Is up to you. I'm I'm getting a sense of
of the answer,
of the answer, but
>> Is up to you. I'm I'm getting a sense of
of the answer, but I've
of the answer, but I've just
>> Is up to you. I'm I'm getting a sense of
of the answer, but I've just got
of the answer, but I've just got a
senseofoof
senseofoof woof.
>> Yeah,
>> it'll
>> it'll clarify.
>> it'll clarify. Can
>> it'll clarify. Can I
>> it'll clarify. Can I have
>> it'll clarify. Can I have a
>> it'll clarify. Can I have a picture,
please?
>> I
>> I can
>> I can woof
>> I can woof if
>> I can woof if I
>> I can woof if I want.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> I can woof if I want.
>> Thank you both
>> Thank you both very
>> I can woof if I want.
>> Thank you both very much.
>> Woof
>> Woof woof
>> Woof woof woof.
That
That was
>> Woof woof woof.
That was interesting.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. Uh
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> Hi. Uh I
>> Hi. Uh I just
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted to
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted to thank
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted to thank you
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> Hi. Uh I just wanted to thank you so
much
much for
much for your
much for your work
much for your work and
much for your work and for
much for your work and for your
much for your work and for your presence
and
and thank
much for your work and for your presence
and thank you
and thank you Susan.
much for your work and for your presence
and thank you Susan. Uh
and thank you Susan. Uh I
much for your work and for your presence
and thank you Susan. Uh I just
and thank you Susan. Uh I just have
much for your work and for your presence
and thank you Susan. Uh I just have uh
one
one question.
>> Yes.
>> About
>> About the
>> About the Buddha.
>> About the Buddha. Uh
>> About the Buddha. Uh it
>> About the Buddha. Uh it is
>> About the Buddha. Uh it is said
>> About the Buddha. Uh it is said that
>> About the Buddha. Uh it is said that uh
before
before he
>> About the Buddha. Uh it is said that uh
before he got
before he got enlightened
>> About the Buddha. Uh it is said that uh
before he got enlightened he
before he got enlightened he was
>> About the Buddha. Uh it is said that uh
before he got enlightened he was uh
beset
beset by
beset by many
beset by many temptations
beset by many temptations and
beset by many temptations and uh
beset by many temptations and uh he
refused
refused uh
beset by many temptations and uh he
refused uh all
refused uh all of
beset by many temptations and uh he
refused uh all of them.
>> He
>> He was
>> He was beset
>> He was beset by
>> He was beset by temptations
>> He was beset by temptations the
>> He was beset by temptations the demons.
Yes.
Uh
Uh and
Uh and then
Uh and then the
Uh and then the story
Uh and then the story goes
Uh and then the story goes that
Uh and then the story goes that after
Uh and then the story goes that after he
got
got enlightened
uh
uh he
uh he decided
uh he decided to
uh he decided to teach
uh he decided to teach and
uh he decided to teach and uh
uh he decided to teach and uh Mara
uh he decided to teach and uh Mara the
evil
evil one
uh he decided to teach and uh Mara the
evil one came
evil one came back
uh he decided to teach and uh Mara the
evil one came back with
evil one came back with one
uh he decided to teach and uh Mara the
evil one came back with one more
evil one came back with one more time
and
and uh
and uh he
and uh he said
and uh he said why
and uh he said why bother
nobody's
nobody's going
and uh he said why bother
nobody's going to
nobody's going to understand
and uh he said why bother
nobody's going to understand you
nobody's going to understand you because
this
this is
this is a
this is a teaching
this is a teaching that's
this is a teaching that's very
this is a teaching that's very high
this is a teaching that's very high so
why
why bother
this is a teaching that's very high so
why bother just
and
and the
and the Buddha
and the Buddha said
and the Buddha said um
somebody
somebody will
and the Buddha said um
somebody will understand.
somebody will understand. There
and the Buddha said um
somebody will understand. There will
somebody will understand. There will be
others
others who
others who will
others who will understand.
others who will understand. So
others who will understand. So I
others who will understand. So I just
wanted
wanted to
others who will understand. So I just
wanted to ask
wanted to ask you
others who will understand. So I just
wanted to ask you if
wanted to ask you if you
others who will understand. So I just
wanted to ask you if you could
contextualize
contextualize this
contextualize this story
contextualize this story like
contextualize this story like why
contextualize this story like why why
was
was this
contextualize this story like why why
was this temptation?
was this temptation? Uh
>> what
>> she
>> she wants
>> what
>> she wants to
>> she wants to know
>> what
>> she wants to know why
>> she wants to know why Myra
>> what
>> she wants to know why Myra tempted
>> she wants to know why Myra tempted him
after
after he
after he was
after he was a
after he was a teacher
>> because
>> because that's
after he was a teacher
>> because that's the
>> because that's the the
because
because that
because that is
because that is the
the the
the the because
because that is the
the the because evil
the the because evil seeks
because that is the
the the because evil seeks to
the the because evil seeks to bring
because that is the
the the because evil seeks to bring down
that
that which
that which is
that which is spiritually
that which is spiritually beyond
that which is spiritually beyond it
and
and it
that which is spiritually beyond it
and it looks
and it looks for
that which is spiritually beyond it
and it looks for chinks
and it looks for chinks in
that which is spiritually beyond it
and it looks for chinks in your
and it looks for chinks in your armor.
self-doubt
self-doubt would
self-doubt would be
self-doubt would be one.
Uh
Uh questioning
self-doubt would be one.
Uh questioning the
Uh questioning the validity
self-doubt would be one.
Uh questioning the validity of
Uh questioning the validity of your
awareness.
awareness. I
awareness. I still
awareness. I still don't
awareness. I still don't quite
awareness. I still don't quite get
awareness. I still don't quite get what
it
it causes
awareness. I still don't quite get what
it causes a
it causes a question.
>> Well,
>> Well, I
>> Well, I think
>> Well, I think what
>> Well, I think what many
>> Well, I think what many of
>> Well, I think what many of spiritual
teachers
teachers fall
>> Well, I think what many of spiritual
teachers fall into,
you
you know,
you know, sins
you know, sins like
you know, sins like sex,
you know, sins like sex, money,
fame.
fame. Many
you know, sins like sex, money,
fame. Many spiritual
fame. Many spiritual teacher
you know, sins like sex, money,
fame. Many spiritual teacher has
fame. Many spiritual teacher has done
that.
that. You
that. You read
that. You read about
that. You read about it
that. You read about it on
that. You read about it on the
that. You read about it on the internet
every
every single
that. You read about it on the internet
every single day.
every single day. So,
that. You read about it on the internet
every single day. So, it
every single day. So, it is
that. You read about it on the internet
every single day. So, it is there.
every single day. So, it is there. It's
out
out there.
out there. It
out there. It is
out there. It is a
out there. It is a temptation.
out there. It is a temptation. Yes.
I
I mean
out there. It is a temptation. Yes.
I mean why
I mean why it
out there. It is a temptation. Yes.
I mean why it happens
I mean why it happens I
out there. It is a temptation. Yes.
I mean why it happens I can't
I mean why it happens I can't answer
that
>> but
>> but it
that
>> but it happens
>> but it happens even
that
>> but it happens even after
>> but it happens even after enlightenment
>> what
>> it
>> it happens
>> what
>> it happens even
>> it happens even after
>> what
>> it happens even after enlightenment
>> it happens even after enlightenment the
temptations
>> no
>> no not
temptations
>> no not true
>> no not true enlightenment
>> oh
>> okay
>> you
>> you get
>> you get spiritually
>> you get spiritually advanced
>> you get spiritually advanced gurus
>> you get spiritually advanced gurus but
then
then they
are
are not
are not truly
are not truly enlightened
are not truly enlightened because
are not truly enlightened because they
wouldn't
wouldn't be
are not truly enlightened because they
wouldn't be susceptible
wouldn't be susceptible to
are not truly enlightened because they
wouldn't be susceptible to seduction
money
money fame
money fame fortune
money fame fortune all
money fame fortune all the
money fame fortune all the stuff
money fame fortune all the stuff they
money fame fortune all the stuff they go
for
for internet
money fame fortune all the stuff they go
for internet stuff
>> so
>> so that's
>> so that's what
>> so that's what the
>> so that's what the Buddhist
>> so that's what the Buddhist said
>> Mhm.
Okay.
>> Do
>> Do you
Okay.
>> Do you did
>> Do you did you
Okay.
>> Do you did you understand?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. It's
>> Yes. It's just
>> Yes. It's just my
>> Yes. It's just my question
>> Yes. It's just my question is
>> Yes. It's just my question is if
>> Yes. It's just my question is if if
my
my understanding
>> Yes. It's just my question is if if
my understanding is
my understanding is that
>> Yes. It's just my question is if if
my understanding is that he
my understanding is that he was
>> Yes. It's just my question is if if
my understanding is that he was truly
enlightened,
enlightened, so
enlightened, so why
enlightened, so why was
enlightened, so why was he
enlightened, so why was he tempted
again?
>> But
>> But he
>> But he didn't
>> But he didn't take
>> But he didn't take her
>> But he didn't take her up
>> But he didn't take her up on
>> But he didn't take her up on it.
>> But he didn't take her up on it. In
other
other words,
>> But he didn't take her up on it. In
other words, that
other words, that came
>> But he didn't take her up on it. In
other words, that came up,
other words, that came up, but
>> But he didn't take her up on it. In
other words, that came up, but he
other words, that came up, but he said
no
no to
no to it.
>> Okay.
>> Do
>> Do you
>> Do you Okay.
>> Do you Okay. Because
>> Do you Okay. Because he
>> Do you Okay. Because he was
>> Do you Okay. Because he was truly
enlightened.
>> Okay.
Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> Okay. Thank you
>> Okay. Thank you so
>> Okay. Thank you so much.
>> Right.
>> Nothing.
>> Nothing. I
>> Nothing. I didn't
>> Nothing. I didn't understand
>> Nothing. I didn't understand the
question
question or
>> Nothing. I didn't understand the
question or the
question or the answer.
>> Don't
>> Don't get
>> Don't get me
>> Don't get me involved.
>> All right.
>> All right. Thank
>> Don't get me involved.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> I
>> I guess
>> I guess she
>> I guess she thinks
>> I guess she thinks that
>> I guess she thinks that once
>> I guess she thinks that once you're
enlightened,
enlightened, you
>> I guess she thinks that once you're
enlightened, you don't
enlightened, you don't have
>> I guess she thinks that once you're
enlightened, you don't have the
temptations
temptations and
temptations and that's
temptations and that's not
temptations and that's not so
>> right.
>> Whether
>> Whether or
>> Whether or not
>> Whether or not experienced
>> Whether or not experienced is
>> Whether or not experienced is a
temptation.
>> All right.
>> All right. Hello.
>> All right. Hello. Hi.
And
And first
>> All right. Hello. Hi.
And first I
And first I would
>> All right. Hello. Hi.
And first I would like
And first I would like to
>> All right. Hello. Hi.
And first I would like to express
And first I would like to express my
appreciation
appreciation for
appreciation for your
appreciation for your work.
appreciation for your work. Thank
appreciation for your work. Thank you
very
very much
appreciation for your work. Thank you
very much for
very much for being
>> Yes.
>> being
>> being so
>> Yes.
>> being so devoted
>> being so devoted to
>> Yes.
>> being so devoted to humanity
>> being so devoted to humanity and
>> Yes.
>> being so devoted to humanity and being
so
so there
so there for
so there for us.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I
so there for us.
>> Okay. I have
>> Okay. I have uh
so there for us.
>> Okay. I have uh one
>> Okay. I have uh one question.
My
My friend
My friend had
My friend had a
My friend had a surgery
My friend had a surgery and
My friend had a surgery and the
My friend had a surgery and the doctors
discovered
discovered she
My friend had a surgery and the doctors
discovered she had
discovered she had a
My friend had a surgery and the doctors
discovered she had a cancer.
>> She
>> She had
>> She had what?
>> Cancer.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Her
>> Yes. Her family
>> Yes. Her family learned
>> Yes. Her family learned about
>> Yes. Her family learned about it
>> Yes. Her family learned about it but
decided
decided not
>> Yes. Her family learned about it but
decided not to
decided not to tell
>> Yes. Her family learned about it but
decided not to tell her
decided not to tell her because
>> Yes. Her family learned about it but
decided not to tell her because they
believed
believed she
believed she would
believed she would commit
believed she would commit suicide.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. Uhhuh.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I
>> Okay. I learned
>> Okay. I learned about
>> Okay. I learned about it
>> Okay. I learned about it by
>> Okay. I learned about it by chance.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And
>> And they
>> And they wanted
>> And they wanted to
>> And they wanted to tell
>> And they wanted to tell her
>> And they wanted to tell her the
>> And they wanted to tell her the truth
for
for some
>> And they wanted to tell her the truth
for some time,
for some time, but
>> And they wanted to tell her the truth
for some time, but then
for some time, but then I
>> And they wanted to tell her the truth
for some time, but then I decided
for some time, but then I decided not
to.
>> Yes.
So
So my
So my friend
So my friend died
So my friend died never
So my friend died never knowing
that
that she
So my friend died never knowing
that she had
that she had the
So my friend died never knowing
that she had the cancer.
>> Yeah.
>> And
>> And I
>> Yeah.
>> And I wanted
>> And I wanted to
>> Yeah.
>> And I wanted to ask
>> And I wanted to ask you,
>> Yeah.
>> And I wanted to ask you, was
>> And I wanted to ask you, was this
>> Yeah.
>> And I wanted to ask you, was this the
right
right decision
right decision for
right decision for me
right decision for me not
right decision for me not not
right decision for me not not to
right decision for me not not to tell
her?
>> There's
>> There's no
>> There's no right
>> There's no right or
>> There's no right or wrong
>> There's no right or wrong about
>> There's no right or wrong about it.
That's
That's trying
>> There's no right or wrong about it.
That's trying to
That's trying to put
>> There's no right or wrong about it.
That's trying to put it
That's trying to put it in
>> There's no right or wrong about it.
That's trying to put it in terms
That's trying to put it in terms that
are
are absolute.
Uh
Uh there's
are absolute.
Uh there's no
Uh there's no no
are absolute.
Uh there's no no right
Uh there's no no right or
are absolute.
Uh there's no no right or wrong.
In
In other
In other words,
In other words, every
In other words, every decision
In other words, every decision you
In other words, every decision you make
doesn't
doesn't involve
In other words, every decision you make
doesn't involve right
doesn't involve right or
In other words, every decision you make
doesn't involve right or wrong.
You
You know,
You know, whether
You know, whether I
You know, whether I should
You know, whether I should put
You know, whether I should put this
shirt
shirt on
You know, whether I should put this
shirt on or
shirt on or another
You know, whether I should put this
shirt on or another shirt
shirt on or another shirt is
You know, whether I should put this
shirt on or another shirt is not
shirt on or another shirt is not a
matter
matter of
matter of right
matter of right and
matter of right and wrong.
matter of right and wrong. It's
matter of right and wrong. It's only
matter of right and wrong. It's only a
matter
matter of
matter of right and wrong. It's only a
matter of choice.
matter of choice. So,
matter of right and wrong. It's only a
matter of choice. So, you're
matter of choice. So, you're free
matter of right and wrong. It's only a
matter of choice. So, you're free to
choose
choose to
choose to tell
choose to tell her
choose to tell her or
choose to tell her or free
choose to tell her or free to
choose to tell her or free to choose
choose to tell her or free to choose not
to
to tell
choose to tell her or free to choose not
to tell her.
to tell her. If
choose to tell her or free to choose not
to tell her. If it
to tell her. If it was
choose to tell her or free to choose not
to tell her. If it was pre-ordained
to tell her. If it was pre-ordained that
she
she would
she would know,
she would know, then
she would know, then she
she would know, then she would
she would know, then she would have
known.
Besides,
Besides, intuitively,
Besides, intuitively, she
Besides, intuitively, she knew
Besides, intuitively, she knew anyway.
>> I
>> I think
Besides, intuitively, she knew anyway.
>> I think so,
>> I think so, too.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. She
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. She didn't
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. She didn't want
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. She didn't want to
consciously
consciously acknowledge
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. She didn't want to
consciously acknowledge it
consciously acknowledge it because
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. She didn't want to
consciously acknowledge it because then
that's
that's a
that's a whole
that's a whole new
uh
uh story,
that's a whole new
uh story, you
uh story, you know.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, that's
>> Yes, that's that's
>> Yes, that's that's that's
>> Yes, that's that's that's another
>> Yes, that's that's that's another thing.
>> Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> And
>> And um
>> Thank you very much.
>> And um also
>> And um also um
>> Thank you very much.
>> And um also um can
>> And um also um can I
>> Thank you very much.
>> And um also um can I ask
>> And um also um can I ask you
>> Thank you very much.
>> And um also um can I ask you uh
>> And um also um can I ask you uh for
>> Thank you very much.
>> And um also um can I ask you uh for a
blessing
blessing for
blessing for me?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. What?
>> A
>> A blessing.
>> A blessing. God
>> A blessing. God bless
>> A blessing.
>> A blessing. God bless you
>> in
>> in the
>> in the name
>> in the name of
>> in the name of the
>> in the name of the Lord.
>> in the name of the Lord. Amen.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> in the name of the Lord. Amen.
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> in the name of the Lord. Amen.
>> Thank you very much. Thanks.
>> Thank you very much. Thanks. Bless.
>> Someone
>> Someone gave
>> Someone gave me
>> Someone gave me a
>> Someone gave me a card.
>> Someone gave me a card. I
>> Someone gave me a card. I just
>> Someone gave me a card. I just leave
>> Someone gave me a card. I just leave it
there.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
Yes.
>> Just
>> Just want
>> Just want to
>> Just want to thank
>> Just want to thank you
>> Just want to thank you very
>> Just want to thank you very much
>> Just want to thank you very much and
>> Just want to thank you very much and ask
for
for your
>> Just want to thank you very much and ask
for your blessing.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much. And
>> Thank you very much. And what?
>> And
>> And ask
>> Thank you very much. And what?
>> And ask for
>> And ask for a
>> Thank you very much. And what?
>> And ask for a blessing.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, God
>> Oh, God bless
>> Oh, God bless you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> In
>> In the
>> In the name
>> In the name of
>> In the name of the
>> In the name of the Lord.
>> In the name of the Lord. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Could
>> In the name of the Lord. Amen.
>> Amen. Could I
>> Amen. Could I take
>> In the name of the Lord. Amen.
>> Amen. Could I take a
>> Amen. Could I take a picture?
>> Yeah.
Thank
Thank you.
Hello.
>> Hello.
>> I
>> I do
>> I do not
>> I do not have
>> I do not have a
>> I do not have a question.
>> I do not have a question. I
>> I do not have a question. I just
>> I do not have a question. I just wanted
to
to come
>> I do not have a question. I just wanted
to come and
to come and thank
>> I do not have a question. I just wanted
to come and thank you.
>> Yes.
>> And
>> And ask
>> Yes.
>> And ask for
>> And ask for a
>> Yes.
>> And ask for a blessing.
>> I
>> I bless
>> I bless you
>> I bless you in
>> I bless you in the
>> I bless you in the name
>> I bless you in the name of
>> I bless you in the name of the
>> I bless you in the name of the Lord.
Amen.
Amen. And
>> I bless you in the name of the Lord.
Amen. And thank
Amen. And thank you,
>> I bless you in the name of the Lord.
Amen. And thank you, Susan.
>> Can
>> Can we
>> Can we get
>> Can we get a
>> Can we get a picture?
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> God
>> God bless
>> God bless you
>> God bless you there.
Yes.
Thank
Thank you
Thank you so
Thank you so much
Thank you so much that
Thank you so much that we
Thank you so much that we are
Thank you so much that we are here
Thank you so much that we are here could
have
have been
Thank you so much that we are here could
have been here
have been here and
Thank you so much that we are here could
have been here and to
have been here and to see
Thank you so much that we are here could
have been here and to see you
and
and maybe
and maybe ask
and maybe ask question
maybe
maybe a
and maybe ask question
maybe a blessing
maybe a blessing for
and maybe ask question
maybe a blessing for her
maybe a blessing for her baby
and maybe ask question
maybe a blessing for her baby was
expecting
>> when
May
>> May
>> I
>> I just
>> I just bless
>> I just bless the
>> I just bless the baby
>> I just bless the baby in
>> I just bless the baby in your
>> I just bless the baby in your womb.
Amen.
God
God bless
God bless the
God bless the baby.
God bless the baby. Yes.
Do
Do you
God bless the baby. Yes.
Do you play
Do you play classical
God bless the baby. Yes.
Do you play classical music
Do you play classical music for
God bless the baby. Yes.
Do you play classical music for the
baby?
>> You
>> You do?
baby?
>> You do? Good
>> You do? Good for
baby?
>> You do? Good for you.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Play
>> Yeah. Play it.
>> Yeah. Play it. Play
>> Yeah. Play it. Play it
>> Yeah. Play it. Play it because
>> Yeah. Play it. Play it because it
teaches
teaches them
>> Yeah. Play it. Play it because it
teaches them so
teaches them so much.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. The
>> Yeah. The baby
>> Yeah. The baby in
>> Yeah. The baby in the
>> Yeah. The baby in the womb
>> Yeah. The baby in the womb picks
>> Yeah. The baby in the womb picks up
>> Yeah. The baby in the womb picks up the
energy
energy of
>> Yeah. The baby in the womb picks up the
energy of classical
energy of classical music.
>> Yeah.
Nice
Nice to
Nice to meet
Nice to meet you.
>> Hello.
>> Um,
>> Um, I'm
>> Um, I'm having
>> Um, I'm having a
>> Um, I'm having a severe
>> Um, I'm having a severe aversion
>> Um, I'm having a severe aversion when
>> Um, I'm having a severe aversion when I
go
go into
>> Um, I'm having a severe aversion when I
go into like
go into like happier
>> Um, I'm having a severe aversion when I
go into like happier states.
>> Aversion
>> Aversion to
>> Aversion to happier
>> Aversion to happier states.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. No.
>> Aversion to happier states.
>> Yeah. No. No.
>> Yeah. No. No. All
>> Aversion to happier states.
>> Yeah. No. No. All it's
>> Yeah. No. No. All it's like
>> Aversion to happier states.
>> Yeah. No. No. All it's like all
>> Yeah. No. No. All it's like all hell
breaks
breaks loose.
breaks loose. And
>> what
>> what do
breaks loose. And
>> what do you
>> what do you mean?
>> Um,
>> Um, I
>> Um, I don't
>> Um, I don't know.
>> Um, I don't know. physical
>> Um, I don't know. physical problems,
headaches,
headaches, emotional
>> Um, I don't know. physical problems,
headaches, emotional problems.
headaches, emotional problems. Seems
like
like everything
like everything in
like everything in the
like everything in the world
like everything in the world breaks
like everything in the world breaks in
my
my house.
like everything in the world breaks in
my house. My
my house. My car
like everything in the world breaks in
my house. My car breaks
my house. My car breaks down.
So,
So, I'm
So, I'm wondering
So, I'm wondering if
So, I'm wondering if if
So, I'm wondering if if um
So, I'm wondering if if um there's
anything
anything you
So, I'm wondering if if um there's
anything you can
anything you can tell
So, I'm wondering if if um there's
anything you can tell me
anything you can tell me to
So, I'm wondering if if um there's
anything you can tell me to help
anything you can tell me to help me
So, I'm wondering if if um there's
anything you can tell me to help me get
through
through that
through that or
through that or to
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you
through that or to
>> Oh, you just
>> Oh, you just go
through that or to
>> Oh, you just go walk
>> Oh, you just go walk straight
through that or to
>> Oh, you just go walk straight ahead.
>> Oh, you just go walk straight ahead. The
basic
basic rule
basic rule in
basic rule in spirituality
is
is to
basic rule in spirituality
is to walk
is to walk straight
basic rule in spirituality
is to walk straight ahead
is to walk straight ahead no matter
what.
what. Walk
what. Walk straight
what. Walk straight ahead
what. Walk straight ahead no matter
what.
what. Because
what. Walk straight ahead no matter
what. Because each
what. Because each thing
what. Walk straight ahead no matter
what. Because each thing you
what. Because each thing you walk
through
through brings
through brings up
through brings up other
through brings up other things.
forgiveness,
forgiveness, surrendering
through brings up other things.
forgiveness, surrendering it
forgiveness, surrendering it to
through brings up other things.
forgiveness, surrendering it to God,
uh
uh putting
uh putting the
uh putting the physical
uh putting the physical above
uh putting the physical above the
spiritual.
spiritual. Each
uh putting the physical above the
spiritual. Each one
spiritual. Each one has
uh putting the physical above the
spiritual. Each one has a
spiritual. Each one has a lesson.
uh putting the physical above the
spiritual. Each one has a lesson. When
the
the lesson
the lesson is
the lesson is served,
the lesson is served, it
the lesson is served, it stops.
You
You might
the lesson is served, it stops.
You might say
You might say the
the lesson is served, it stops.
You might say the phenomenon
You might say the phenomenon is
the lesson is served, it stops.
You might say the phenomenon is a
resistance
resistance to
resistance to the
resistance to the lesson.
Uh
Uh so
resistance to the lesson.
Uh so it
Uh so it will
resistance to the lesson.
Uh so it will stop
Uh so it will stop when
resistance to the lesson.
Uh so it will stop when it
Uh so it will stop when it served
resistance to the lesson.
Uh so it will stop when it served its
purpose.
>> There's
>> There's a
purpose.
>> There's a lot
>> There's a lot of
purpose.
>> There's a lot of purpose.
>> There's a lot of purpose. I
purpose.
>> There's a lot of purpose. I think
>> it
>> it seems
>> it seems so
>> it seems so at
>> it seems so at the
>> it seems so at the time.
Thank
Thank you.
>> But
>> But in
>> But in retrospect,
>> But in retrospect, it's
>> But in retrospect, it's easier.
>> It
>> It seems
>> But in retrospect, it's easier.
>> It seems like
>> It seems like sometimes
>> But in retrospect, it's easier.
>> It seems like sometimes things
>> It seems like sometimes things happen
>> But in retrospect, it's easier.
>> It seems like sometimes things happen in
clusters,
clusters, you
clusters, you know.
>> Oh
>> Oh yes.
>> Hello
>> Hello Dr.
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins and
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins and Susan.
>> I'm
>> I'm blessed
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins and Susan.
>> I'm blessed to
>> I'm blessed to be
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins and Susan.
>> I'm blessed to be here.
>> I'm blessed to be here. Thank
>> Hello Dr. Hawkins and Susan.
>> I'm blessed to be here. Thank you
>> I'm blessed to be here. Thank you for
everything
everything that
everything that you
everything that you do.
>> Yeah.
>> My
>> My question
>> My question is
>> My question is at
>> My question is at what
>> My question is at what point
>> My question is at what point does
>> My question is at what point does making
money
money become
>> My question is at what point does making
money become a
money become a quest
>> My question is at what point does making
money become a quest for
money become a quest for gain?
At
At what
At what point
>> when
>> when does
At what point
>> when does when
>> when does when does
At what point
>> when does when does it
>> when does when does it cross
At what point
>> when does when does it cross over
>> when does when does it cross over from
just
just making
just making money
just making money to
just making money to pay
just making money to pay your
just making money to pay your bills
just making money to pay your bills and
become
become a
just making money to pay your bills and
become a quest
become a quest for
just making money to pay your bills and
become a quest for for
become a quest for for gain
just making money to pay your bills and
become a quest for for gain because
become a quest for for gain because you
recommend
recommend that
recommend that we
recommend that we give
recommend that we give up
recommend that we give up gain?
>> Oh
well
well a
well a gain
well a gain is
well a gain is the
well a gain is the way
well a gain is the way you're
well a gain is the way you're holding
it.
Uh
what
what is
Uh
what is money?
what is money? Then
Uh
what is money? Then you
what is money? Then you have
Uh
what is money? Then you have to
what is money? Then you have to define
what
what is
what is money
what is money and
what is money and what
what is money and what does
what is money and what does it
represent.
Yeah.
Yeah. And
Yeah. And is
Yeah. And is it
Yeah. And is it a
Yeah. And is it a a
Yeah. And is it a a pleasure
Yeah. And is it a a pleasure or
Yeah. And is it a a pleasure or is
Yeah. And is it a a pleasure or is it
Yeah. And is it a a pleasure or is it a
necessity?
necessity? Is
Yeah. And is it a a pleasure or is it a
necessity? Is it
necessity? Is it a
Yeah. And is it a a pleasure or is it a
necessity? Is it a goal
necessity? Is it a goal in
Yeah. And is it a a pleasure or is it a
necessity? Is it a goal in itself?
Is
Is it
Is it a
Is it a badge
Is it a badge of
Is it a badge of merit?
Is it a badge of merit? You
Is it a badge of merit? You know,
Is it a badge of merit? You know, some
people
people it's
Is it a badge of merit? You know, some
people it's a
people it's a badge
Is it a badge of merit? You know, some
people it's a badge of
people it's a badge of merit,
Is it a badge of merit? You know, some
people it's a badge of merit, a
people it's a badge of merit, a bigger
house,
house, a
house, a bigger
house, a bigger car,
house, a bigger car, etc.,
house, a bigger car, etc., etc.
house, a bigger car, etc., etc. So,
money
money is
house, a bigger car, etc., etc. So,
money is a
money is a fun
house, a bigger car, etc., etc. So,
money is a fun thing
money is a fun thing spiritually
house, a bigger car, etc., etc. So,
money is a fun thing spiritually because
it
it has
it has so
it has so many
it has so many different
it has so many different meanings.
it has so many different meanings. You
see,
see, with
it has so many different meanings. You
see, with your
see, with your worth
it has so many different meanings. You
see, with your worth more,
see, with your worth more, if
it has so many different meanings. You
see, with your worth more, if you
see, with your worth more, if you were
worth
worth more,
worth more, God
worth more, God would
worth more, God would provide
worth more, God would provide with with
more,
more, etc.
Uh
so
so at
Uh
so at each
so at each point
Uh
so at each point along
so at each point along the
Uh
so at each point along the way
so at each point along the way your
relationship
relationship with
relationship with money
relationship with money takes
relationship with money takes on
relationship with money takes on a
different
different significance
and
and therefore
and therefore it's
and therefore it's an
and therefore it's an interesting
and therefore it's an interesting point
of
of reference
and therefore it's an interesting point
of reference periodically
of reference periodically throughout
your
your life.
your life. See
your life. See and
your life. See and uh
your life. See and uh then
your life. See and uh then in
your life. See and uh then in the
your life. See and uh then in the end
when
when you
your life. See and uh then in the end
when you lose
when you lose all
your life. See and uh then in the end
when you lose all interest
when you lose all interest in
your life. See and uh then in the end
when you lose all interest in it
when you lose all interest in it becomes
important
important because
important because you
important because you can't
important because you can't survive
without
without it.
important because you can't survive
without it. So
without it. So you
important because you can't survive
without it. So you say
without it. So you say well
important because you can't survive
without it. So you say well you
without it. So you say well you can't
just
just kiss
just kiss it
just kiss it all
just kiss it all goodbye
just kiss it all goodbye and
just kiss it all goodbye and well
just kiss it all goodbye and well you
going
going to
just kiss it all goodbye and well you
going to live
going to live in
just kiss it all goodbye and well you
going to live in a
going to live in a poor
just kiss it all goodbye and well you
going to live in a poor folks
going to live in a poor folks home.
just kiss it all goodbye and well you
going to live in a poor folks home. They
won't
won't let
won't let you
won't let you in
won't let you in there.
>> Right.
So
So it
So it has
So it has different
So it has different meaning
So it has different meaning and
significance
significance and
So it has different meaning and
significance and value.
Yes.
Yes. And
Yes. And Rama
Yes. And Rama Krishna
Yes. And Rama Krishna wouldn't
Yes. And Rama Krishna wouldn't let
Yes. And Rama Krishna wouldn't let let
any
any of
Yes. And Rama Krishna wouldn't let let
any of his
any of his students
Yes. And Rama Krishna wouldn't let let
any of his students touch
any of his students touch money.
Yes. And Rama Krishna wouldn't let let
any of his students touch money. He
thought
thought money
thought money was
thought money was contaminated.
And
And I've
thought money was contaminated.
And I've always
And I've always disagreed
thought money was contaminated.
And I've always disagreed with
And I've always disagreed with that.
It's
It's said
It's said it's
It's said it's not
It's said it's not the
It's said it's not the money.
It's said it's not the money. It's
It's said it's not the money. It's the
energy
energy with
It's said it's not the money. It's the
energy with which
energy with which you
It's said it's not the money. It's the
energy with which you hold
energy with which you hold it.
It's said it's not the money. It's the
energy with which you hold it. It's
energy with which you hold it. It's your
relationship
relationship to
relationship to the
relationship to the money,
relationship to the money, not
relationship to the money, not the
relationship to the money, not the money
itself.
itself. The
relationship to the money, not the money
itself. The money
itself. The money itself
relationship to the money, not the money
itself. The money itself is
itself. The money itself is just
relationship to the money, not the money
itself. The money itself is just a
itself. The money itself is just a piece
of
of paper.
It's
It's just
of paper.
It's just a
It's just a piece
of paper.
It's just a piece of
It's just a piece of paper.
of paper.
It's just a piece of paper. Yeah.
>> And
>> And that
>> And that so
>> And that so it
>> And that so it changes.
>> It
>> It changes.
>> And that so it changes.
>> It changes. It
>> It changes. It changes
>> And that so it changes.
>> It changes. It changes constantly.
>> Okay.
>> You
>> You can
>> Okay.
>> You can see
>> You can see it
>> Okay.
>> You can see it is
>> You can see it is a
>> Okay.
>> You can see it is a gift
>> You can see it is a gift from
>> Okay.
>> You can see it is a gift from God.
>> You can see it is a gift from God. You
say,
say, "Thank
say, "Thank you,
say, "Thank you, Lord,
say, "Thank you, Lord, for
say, "Thank you, Lord, for this
say, "Thank you, Lord, for this gift
without
without which
say, "Thank you, Lord, for this gift
without which I
without which I would
say, "Thank you, Lord, for this gift
without which I would not
without which I would not be
say, "Thank you, Lord, for this gift
without which I would not be able
without which I would not be able to
continue
continue physically
continue physically or
continue physically or I'd
continue physically or I'd have
continue physically or I'd have to
continue physically or I'd have to keep
my
my old
continue physically or I'd have to keep
my old job,
my old job, which
continue physically or I'd have to keep
my old job, which was
my old job, which was a
continue physically or I'd have to keep
my old job, which was a killer."
my old job, which was a killer." You
know
know what
know what I
know what I mean?
>> I
>> I like
know what I mean?
>> I like that.
>> I like that. That's
know what I mean?
>> I like that. That's great.
>> I like that. That's great. Thank
know what I mean?
>> I like that. That's great. Thank you
very
very much.
>> So
>> So is
very much.
>> So is is
>> So is is valuable.
very much.
>> So is is valuable. It's
>> So is is valuable. It's valuable.
very much.
>> So is is valuable. It's valuable. What
does
does money
does money mean
does money mean to
does money mean to me
does money mean to me now?
does money mean to me now? What
does money mean to me now? What did
does money mean to me now? What did it
mean
mean to
does money mean to me now? What did it
mean to me
mean to me in
does money mean to me now? What did it
mean to me in the
mean to me in the past?
What
What value
What value could
What value could it
What value could it have
What value could it have for
What value could it have for me
What value could it have for me in
What value could it have for me in the
future?
And
And it's
And it's important
And it's important in
And it's important in today's
And it's important in today's society.
You
You can't
And it's important in today's society.
You can't ignore
You can't ignore it.
And it's important in today's society.
You can't ignore it. You
You can't ignore it. You can't
And it's important in today's society.
You can't ignore it. You can't ignore
money.
money. I
money. I think
money. I think that's
money. I think that's a
money. I think that's a false
money. I think that's a false attitude.
You
You can't
money. I think that's a false attitude.
You can't live
You can't live in
money. I think that's a false attitude.
You can't live in this
You can't live in this world
money. I think that's a false attitude.
You can't live in this world without
money.
>> Right?
There
There used
There used to
There used to be
There used to be a
There used to be a consciousness
expansion
expansion program
There used to be a consciousness
expansion program years
expansion program years ago
There used to be a consciousness
expansion program years ago and
expansion program years ago and somebody
would
would creep
would creep around
would creep around through
would creep around through the
would creep around through the uh
would creep around through the uh aisles
of
of the
would creep around through the uh aisles
of the theater
of the theater and
would creep around through the uh aisles
of the theater and whisper
of the theater and whisper in
would creep around through the uh aisles
of the theater and whisper in people's
ears,
ears, you
ears, you can't
ears, you can't live
ears, you can't live in
ears, you can't live in this
ears, you can't live in this world
without
without money.
really
really creates
really creates creates
really creates creates kind
really creates creates kind of
really creates creates kind of a
conundrum
conundrum if
really creates creates kind of a
conundrum if you're
conundrum if you're if
really creates creates kind of a
conundrum if you're if you
conundrum if you're if you have
really creates creates kind of a
conundrum if you're if you have a
business
business and
business and you
business and you need
business and you need to
business and you need to pay
business and you need to pay your
business and you need to pay your bills
but
but yet
business and you need to pay your bills
but yet you
but yet you you
business and you need to pay your bills
but yet you you don't
but yet you you don't want
business and you need to pay your bills
but yet you you don't want it
but yet you you don't want it to
business and you need to pay your bills
but yet you you don't want it to become
always
always a
always a question
always a question of
always a question of well
always a question of well how
always a question of well how much
always a question of well how much am
always a question of well how much am I
going
going to
always a question of well how much am I
going to make
going to make when
always a question of well how much am I
going to make when I
going to make when I do
always a question of well how much am I
going to make when I do this?
going to make when I do this? How
always a question of well how much am I
going to make when I do this? How much?
>> So
>> So it's
>> So it's a
>> So it's a matter
>> So it's a matter of
>> So it's a matter of balance.
>> So it's a matter of balance. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Thank
>> So it's a matter of balance. Yes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> It's
>> It's worth
>> It's worth effort
>> It's worth effort but
>> It's worth effort but not
>> It's worth effort but not your
>> It's worth effort but not your life.
>> Okay.
>> Not
>> Not worth
>> Not worth your
>> Not worth your dedicating
>> Not worth your dedicating your
>> Not worth your dedicating your life
>> Not worth your dedicating your life to
but
>> thank
>> thank you
>> thank you so
>> thank you so much.
Huh?
>> That
>> That was
>> That was a
>> That was a good
>> Yes.
>> If
>> If he
>> If he holds
>> If he holds my
>> If he holds my necklace,
>> If he holds my necklace, will
>> If he holds my necklace, will I
uh
>> will
>> will there
>> will there be
>> will there be a
>> will there be a transfer
>> will there be a transfer of
>> will there be a transfer of energy?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, will
>> will there be a transfer of energy?
>> Oh, will there
>> Oh, will there be
>> will there be a transfer of energy?
>> Oh, will there be a
>> Oh, will there be a transfer
>> will there be a transfer of energy?
>> Oh, will there be a transfer of
>> Oh, will there be a transfer of energy
if
if you
if you hold
if you hold her
if you hold her necklace?
if you hold her necklace? I
if you hold her necklace? I don't
if you hold her necklace? I don't know
that
>> she
>> she has
>> she has a
>> she has a necklace.
>> she has a necklace. Would
>> she has a necklace. Would it
>> she has a necklace. Would it trans
energy?
>> No.
>> No. No.
>> No. No. Uh
it's
it's permissible
>> No. No. Uh
it's permissible to
it's permissible to ask
>> No. No. Uh
it's permissible to ask about
it's permissible to ask about this.
Um
Um to
Um to hold
Um to hold it
Um to hold it does
Um to hold it does transmit
Um to hold it does transmit energy
Um to hold it does transmit energy to
it.
it. Is
Um to hold it does transmit energy to
it. Is this
>> um
it
it uh
>> um
it uh is
permissible
permissible to
permissible to do
permissible to do so.
Uh,
Uh, it's
permissible to do so.
Uh, it's best
Uh, it's best to
permissible to do so.
Uh, it's best to do
Uh, it's best to do so,
>> but
>> but if
>> but if you
>> but if you don't
>> but if you don't want
>> but if you don't want to,
>> but if you don't want to, it's
>> but if you don't want to, it's okay.
>> Do
>> Do you
>> but if you don't want to, it's okay.
>> Do you want
>> Do you want to
>> but if you don't want to, it's okay.
>> Do you want to or
>> Do you want to or not?
>> I'm
>> I'm thinking.
>> All
>> All right.
>> Well,
>> Well, answer
>> Well, answer while
>> Well, answer while he
>> Well, answer while he thinks.
>> All
>> All right.
The
The energy
The energy of
The energy of my
The energy of my doing
The energy of my doing so
The energy of my doing so calibrates
over
over 500,
600,
700.
The
The energy
The energy of
The energy of my
The energy of my doing
The energy of my doing so.
The energy of my doing so. Therefore,
to
to do
The energy of my doing so. Therefore,
to do so
to do so is
The energy of my doing so. Therefore,
to do so is permissible
to do so is permissible as
The energy of my doing so. Therefore,
to do so is permissible as an
to do so is permissible as an act
The energy of my doing so. Therefore,
to do so is permissible as an act of
love.
love. Resist.
love. Resist. Okay.
love. Resist. Okay. As
love. Resist. Okay. As an
love. Resist. Okay. As an act
love. Resist. Okay. As an act of
love. Resist. Okay. As an act of love.
Yes.
Yes. Thank
love. Resist. Okay. As an act of love.
Yes. Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Wait
>> Okay. Wait a
>> Okay. Wait a second.
>> Okay. Wait a second. It
>> Okay. Wait a second. It says
>> as
>> as an
>> Okay. Wait a second. It says
>> as an act
>> as an act of
>> Okay. Wait a second. It says
>> as an act of love.
>> as an act of love. Is
>> Okay. Wait a second. It says
>> as an act of love. Is it
>> as an act of love. Is it a
>> Okay. Wait a second. It says
>> as an act of love. Is it a part
>> as an act of love. Is it a part of
>> Okay. Wait a second. It says
>> as an act of love. Is it a part of our
karma
karma to
karma to be
karma to be able
karma to be able to
karma to be able to find
karma to be able to find enlightenment
in
in this
karma to be able to find enlightenment
in this lifetime?
>> No.
>> No. There's
>> No. There's no
>> No. There's no karmic
>> No. There's no karmic destination
>> No. There's no karmic destination in
>> No. There's no karmic destination in one
lifetime.
lifetime. No.
>> When
>> When does
>> When does it
>> When does it become
>> When does it become a
>> When does it become a karmic
destination?
destination? Do
>> When does it become a karmic
destination? Do you
destination? Do you want
>> When does it become a karmic
destination? Do you want to
destination? Do you want to hold
>> When does it become a karmic
destination? Do you want to hold this
destination? Do you want to hold this or
not?
>> I
>> I just
not?
>> I just did.
>> Okay.
>> I
>> I don't
>> Okay.
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know. I
>> Okay.
>> I don't know. I couldn't
>> I don't know. I couldn't tell
>> Okay.
>> I don't know. I couldn't tell you
whether
whether one's
whether one's karmically
whether one's karmically destined
whether one's karmically destined to
become
become lightened.
whether one's karmically destined to
become lightened. I
become lightened. I don't
whether one's karmically destined to
become lightened. I don't think
become lightened. I don't think it's
destined
destined that
destined that way.
destined that way. Uh
destined that way. Uh it
destined that way. Uh it is
destined that way. Uh it is not
destined that way. Uh it is not destined
necessarily
necessarily to
destined that way. Uh it is not destined
necessarily to become
necessarily to become manifest
destined that way. Uh it is not destined
necessarily to become manifest in
necessarily to become manifest in a
particular
particular lifetime.
particular lifetime. No,
particular lifetime. No, because
particular lifetime. No, because that
would
would be
particular lifetime. No, because that
would be determination
would be determination which
particular lifetime. No, because that
would be determination which would
would be determination which would be
against
against freedom.
against freedom. So
against freedom. So it
against freedom. So it would
against freedom. So it would be
against freedom. So it would be a
against freedom. So it would be a choice
and
and an
against freedom. So it would be a choice
and an option.
and an option. Okay.
against freedom. So it would be a choice
and an option. Okay. It's
and an option. Okay. It's a
against freedom. So it would be a choice
and an option. Okay. It's a choice
and an option. Okay. It's a choice and
an
an option.
an option. Okay.
an option. Okay. It's
an option. Okay. It's okay.
an option. Okay. It's okay. You
an option. Okay. It's okay. You can
an option. Okay. It's okay. You can be
enlightened.
>> We
>> We got
>> We got no
>> We got no okay
>> We got no okay from
>> We got no okay from upstairs.
Hi,
Hi, Doc.
>> Yes.
>> Hi,
>> Hi, Susan.
>> Hello.
>> First,
>> First, just
>> Hello.
>> First, just to
>> First, just to thank
>> Hello.
>> First, just to thank you
>> First, just to thank you um
>> Hello.
>> First, just to thank you um you
>> First, just to thank you um you Susan
and
and your
and your verit
and your verit staff.
and your verit staff. Um
and your verit staff. Um my
and your verit staff. Um my question
and your verit staff. Um my question is
quite
quite simple
and your verit staff. Um my question is
quite simple really.
quite simple really. I'd
and your verit staff. Um my question is
quite simple really. I'd like
quite simple really. I'd like to
and your verit staff. Um my question is
quite simple really. I'd like to know
quite simple really. I'd like to know um
whether
whether or
whether or not
whether or not I'm
whether or not I'm sort
whether or not I'm sort of
whether or not I'm sort of slipping
whether or not I'm sort of slipping into
insanity
insanity or
whether or not I'm sort of slipping into
insanity or my
insanity or my spontaneous
whether or not I'm sort of slipping into
insanity or my spontaneous dancing
insanity or my spontaneous dancing and
singing
singing and
singing and uh
singing and uh sort
singing and uh sort of
singing and uh sort of uting
singing and uh sort of uting strange
languages
is
is okay
is okay or
is okay or am
is okay or am I
is okay or am I going
is okay or am I going insane?
>> What's
>> What's his
is okay or am I going insane?
>> What's his question?
>> He
>> He he
>> He he feels
>> He he feels like
>> He he feels like he
>> He he feels like he said
>> He he feels like he said he
>> He he feels like he said he does
>> He he feels like he said he does uh
dancing
dancing and
>> He he feels like he said he does uh
dancing and singing
dancing and singing and
>> He he feels like he said he does uh
dancing and singing and um
dancing and singing and um he
>> He he feels like he said he does uh
dancing and singing and um he says
dancing and singing and um he says am
>> He he feels like he said he does uh
dancing and singing and um he says am I
going
going insane?
>> Dancing
>> Dancing and
going insane?
>> Dancing and singing.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. In
>> Yeah. In the
>> Yeah. In the supermarket,
>> Yeah. In the supermarket, doc,
>> Yeah. In the supermarket, doc, you
>> Yeah. In the supermarket, doc, you know,
>> in
>> in the
>> Yeah. In the supermarket, doc, you know,
>> in the supermarket.
>> That's
>> That's the
>> That's the proper
>> That's the proper place
>> That's the proper place to
>> That's the proper place to do
>> That's the proper place to do it.
>> We've
>> We've danced
>> That's the proper place to do it.
>> We've danced in
>> We've danced in many
>> That's the proper place to do it.
>> We've danced in many a
>> We've danced in many a supermarket.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Only
>> Only it's
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Only it's getting
>> Only it's getting louder
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Only it's getting louder and
>> Only it's getting louder and longer.
>> Well,
>> Well, they
>> Well, they have
>> Well, they have music
>> Well, they have music in
>> Well, they have music in the
>> Well, they have music in the background,
so
so you
>> Well, they have music in the background,
so you can't
so you can't resist
>> Well, they have music in the background,
so you can't resist it.
so you can't resist it. You
>> Well, they have music in the background,
so you can't resist it. You just
so you can't resist it. You just have
>> Well, they have music in the background,
so you can't resist it. You just have to
do
do a
do a few
do a few turns
do a few turns around
do a few turns around each
do a few turns around each other,
do a few turns around each other, and
you
you hear
do a few turns around each other, and
you hear a
you hear a clerk
do a few turns around each other, and
you hear a clerk coming,
you hear a clerk coming, so
do a few turns around each other, and
you hear a clerk coming, so you
you hear a clerk coming, so you quickly
go
go back
go back looking
go back looking at
go back looking at the
go back looking at the shelves.
>> So,
>> So, is
go back looking at the shelves.
>> So, is it
>> So, is it okay,
go back looking at the shelves.
>> So, is it okay, Doug?
It's
It's okay
It's okay to
It's okay to go
It's okay to go into
It's okay to go into a
It's okay to go into a state
It's okay to go into a state of
It's okay to go into a state of joy,
It's okay to go into a state of joy, you
know.
>> Mhm.
>> And
>> And is
>> Mhm.
>> And is that
>> And is that what
>> Mhm.
>> And is that what it
>> And is that what it is?
>> That's
>> That's all
>> That's all it
>> That's all it is.
>> Cuz
>> Cuz it
>> That's all it is.
>> Cuz it was
>> Cuz it was intimated.
>> That's all it is.
>> Cuz it was intimated. It
>> Cuz it was intimated. It was
>> That's all it is.
>> Cuz it was intimated. It was someone
intimated
intimated it
intimated it was
intimated it was sort
intimated it was sort of
intimated it was sort of getting
intimated it was sort of getting into
the
the 500s,
intimated it was sort of getting into
the 500s, which
the 500s, which I
intimated it was sort of getting into
the 500s, which I was
the 500s, which I was skeptical
intimated it was sort of getting into
the 500s, which I was skeptical about.
>> It's
>> It's just
>> It's just joyfulness.
>> It's just joyfulness. The
>> It's just joyfulness. The joy
>> It's just joyfulness. The joy of
>> It's just joyfulness. The joy of one's
own
own existence.
>> It's just joyfulness. The joy of one's
own existence. Huh.
>> And
>> And it
>> And it just
>> And it just happens.
>> It
>> It just
>> And it just happens.
>> It just happens.
>> It just happens. Oh,
>> And it just happens.
>> It just happens. Oh, yeah.
>> It just happens. Oh, yeah. We've
>> And it just happens.
>> It just happens. Oh, yeah. We've danced
all
all over
all over the
all over the world.
all over the world. Parking
all over the world. Parking lots,
>> supermarkets.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Walmarts.
Oh,
Oh, if
Oh, if it's
Oh, if it's okay
Oh, if it's okay for
Oh, if it's okay for you.
>> I
>> I mean,
Oh, if it's okay for you.
>> I mean, if
>> I mean, if you
Oh, if it's okay for you.
>> I mean, if you haven't
>> I mean, if you haven't danced
Oh, if it's okay for you.
>> I mean, if you haven't danced at
Walmart,
Walmart, you
Walmart, you haven't
Walmart, you haven't lived
Walmart, you haven't lived yet.
>> The
>> The eye
Walmart, you haven't lived yet.
>> The eye doctor.
>> The
>> The eye
>> The eye doctor.
>> We
>> We were
>> The eye doctor.
>> We were at
>> We were at the
>> The eye doctor.
>> We were at the eye
>> We were at the eye doctor.
>> The eye doctor.
>> We were at the eye doctor. Oh,
>> We were at the eye doctor. Oh, yeah.
>> The eye doctor.
>> We were at the eye doctor. Oh, yeah. We
danced
danced in
danced in the
danced in the waiting
danced in the waiting room
danced in the waiting room with
danced in the waiting room with the
danced in the waiting room with the eye
doctor.
>> Yep.
>> It
>> It was
>> Yep.
>> It was good
>> It was good for
>> Yep.
>> It was good for you,
>> It was good for you, T.
>> Wherever
>> Wherever we
>> Wherever we can
>> Wherever we can get
>> Wherever we can get away
>> Wherever we can get away with
>> Wherever we can get away with it,
>> Wherever we can get away with it, we
>> Wherever we can get away with it, we may
>> sneak
>> sneak in
>> Wherever we can get away with it, we may
>> sneak in a
>> sneak in a few
>> Wherever we can get away with it, we may
>> sneak in a few dances.
>> The
>> The office
>> The office helped
>> The office helped it.
>> May
>> May I
>> The office helped it.
>> May I shake
>> May I shake your
>> The office helped it.
>> May I shake your hand?
>> It's
>> It's just
>> It's just It's
>> It's just It's just
>> It's just It's just the
>> It's just It's just the joy
>> It's just It's just the joy of
>> It's just It's just the joy of one's
>> It's just It's just the joy of one's own
existence.
existence. See,
>> the
>> the joy
>> the joy of
>> the joy of one's
>> the joy of one's own
>> the joy of one's own existence.
>> the joy of one's own existence. And
>> the joy of one's own existence. And it
occasionally
occasionally it
>> the joy of one's own existence. And it
occasionally it breaks
occasionally it breaks out
>> the joy of one's own existence. And it
occasionally it breaks out into
occasionally it breaks out into physical
exuberance.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, it
exuberance.
>> Yeah, it does.
>> Yeah.
>> Hi.
>> Yes.
>> Um
>> Um first
>> Um first of
>> Um first of all,
>> Um first of all, I
>> Um first of all, I would
>> Um first of all, I would like
>> Um first of all, I would like to
>> Um first of all, I would like to thank
you
you for
>> Um first of all, I would like to thank
you for being
you for being um
>> Um first of all, I would like to thank
you for being um a
you for being um a teacher
>> Um first of all, I would like to thank
you for being um a teacher to
you for being um a teacher to all
>> Um first of all, I would like to thank
you for being um a teacher to all of
you for being um a teacher to all of us
and
and thank
and thank you
and thank you for
and thank you for all
and thank you for all the
and thank you for all the energy
and thank you for all the energy with
which
which you
and thank you for all the energy with
which you are
which you are teaching
and thank you for all the energy with
which you are teaching us.
which you are teaching us. Um
and thank you for all the energy with
which you are teaching us. Um my
question
question is
question is a
question is a little
question is a little bit
question is a little bit silly.
question is a little bit silly. Um
question is a little bit silly. Um I
have
have always
question is a little bit silly. Um I
have always been
have always been taught
question is a little bit silly. Um I
have always been taught and
have always been taught and um
question is a little bit silly. Um I
have always been taught and um I
have always been taught and um I believe
that
that we
that we have
that we have all
that we have all come
that we have all come from
that we have all come from God
that we have all come from God and
that we have all come from God and that
that
that is
that we have all come from God and that
that is our
that is our ultimate
that we have all come from God and that
that is our ultimate destination
that is our ultimate destination that
that we have all come from God and that
that is our ultimate destination that we
should
should find
should find God.
And
And the
should find God.
And the question
And the question is
should find God.
And the question is um
And the question is um why
should find God.
And the question is um why did
And the question is um why did we
should find God.
And the question is um why did we come
onto
onto this
onto this earth
onto this earth with
onto this earth with an
onto this earth with an animal
onto this earth with an animal brain?
>> Why
>> Why is
onto this earth with an animal brain?
>> Why is what?
>> Why
>> Why do
>> Why do we
>> Why do we come
>> Why do we come to
>> Why do we come to this
>> Why do we come to this earth
>> Why do we come to this earth with
>> Why do we come to this earth with an
animal
animal brain?
>> That's
>> That's the
>> That's the evolutionary
>> That's the evolutionary design.
>> And
>> otherwise
>> otherwise it
>> otherwise it wouldn't
>> otherwise it wouldn't be.
>> otherwise it wouldn't be. But
>> otherwise it wouldn't be. But what
>> otherwise it wouldn't be. But what would
it
it be
>> otherwise it wouldn't be. But what would
it be like
it be like if
>> otherwise it wouldn't be. But what would
it be like if we
it be like if we had
>> otherwise it wouldn't be. But what would
it be like if we had all
it be like if we had all instead
>> otherwise it wouldn't be. But what would
it be like if we had all instead of
coming
coming onto
coming onto this
coming onto this earth
coming onto this earth with
coming onto this earth with an
coming onto this earth with an animal
brain
brain just
coming onto this earth with an animal
brain just come
brain just come onto
coming onto this earth with an animal
brain just come onto this
brain just come onto this earth
coming onto this earth with an animal
brain just come onto this earth with
brain just come onto this earth with an
ethic
ethic brain?
>> What
>> What if
ethic brain?
>> What if we
>> what
>> what if
>> what if we
>> what if we did
>> what if we did not
>> what if we did not have
>> what if we did not have if
>> what if we did not have if we
>> what if we did not have if we came
>> what if we did not have if we came on
with
with a
>> what if we did not have if we came on
with a etheric
with a etheric brain?
>> Oh
>> well
>> well then
>> Oh
>> well then there
>> well then there wouldn't
>> Oh
>> well then there wouldn't be
>> well then there wouldn't be any
>> Oh
>> well then there wouldn't be any point
>> well then there wouldn't be any point to
man
man be
man be to
man be to be
man be to be in
man be to be in this
man be to be in this world
>> to
>> to be.
So
So it's
So it's part
So it's part of
So it's part of the
So it's part of the evolutionary
progression.
progression. The
So it's part of the evolutionary
progression. The h
progression. The h human
So it's part of the evolutionary
progression. The h human the
progression. The h human the human
So it's part of the evolutionary
progression. The h human the human is
part
part of
part of the
part of the evolutionary
part of the evolutionary chain
part of the evolutionary chain from
animal
animal to
part of the evolutionary chain from
animal to angelic.
animal to angelic. Huh?
Man
Man is
Man is both
Man is both protoplasmic
and
and angelic
Man is both protoplasmic
and angelic and
and angelic and etheric.
Man is both protoplasmic
and angelic and etheric. Yes.
>> And
>> And does
>> And does that
>> And does that also
>> And does that also mean
>> And does that also mean that
>> And does that also mean that once
>> And does that also mean that once we
reach
reach a
>> And does that also mean that once we
reach a state
reach a state of
>> And does that also mean that once we
reach a state of enlightenment,
reach a state of enlightenment, we
>> And does that also mean that once we
reach a state of enlightenment, we won't
we
we will
we will not
we will not theoretically
we will not theoretically come
we will not theoretically come back?
>> We
>> We would
we will not theoretically come back?
>> We would straight
>> We would straight go.
we will not theoretically come back?
>> We would straight go. Does
>> We would straight go. Does that
we will not theoretically come back?
>> We would straight go. Does that mean
that
that once
that once we
that once we reach
that once we reach uh
that once we reach uh uh
that once we reach uh uh enlightenment,
does
does that
that once we reach uh uh enlightenment,
does that mean
does that mean we
that once we reach uh uh enlightenment,
does that mean we get
does that mean we get to
that once we reach uh uh enlightenment,
does that mean we get to choose
does that mean we get to choose whether
we
we come
we come back
we come back or
we come back or not?
>> Uh
well,
well, can't
well, can't say.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Um
well, can't say.
>> Okay. Um I
>> Okay. Um I just
well, can't say.
>> Okay. Um I just have
>> Okay. Um I just have one
well, can't say.
>> Okay. Um I just have one more
>> Okay. Um I just have one more request.
Um
Um would
Um would you
Um would you bestow
Um would you bestow a
Um would you bestow a blessing
Um would you bestow a blessing onto
Um would you bestow a blessing onto my
niece
niece who
Um would you bestow a blessing onto my
niece who will
niece who will be
Um would you bestow a blessing onto my
niece who will be six
niece who will be six years
Um would you bestow a blessing onto my
niece who will be six years old
niece who will be six years old in
Um would you bestow a blessing onto my
niece who will be six years old in 11
days
days from
days from now
days from now and
days from now and for
days from now and for myself
days from now and for myself to
days from now and for myself to get
days from now and for myself to get to
where
where I
days from now and for myself to get to
where I need
where I need to
days from now and for myself to get to
where I need to be?
to
to bless
to bless her
to bless her niece.
to bless her niece. And
>> her
>> her niece,
>> yes,
>> yes, she
>> yes, she wants
>> yes, she wants to
>> yes, she wants to bless
>> yes, she wants to bless her
>> yes, she wants to bless her niece.
>> yes, she wants to bless her niece. She's
going
going to
>> yes, she wants to bless her niece. She's
going to be
going to be 11.
>> yes, she wants to bless her niece. She's
going to be 11. And
>> no,
>> no, she's
>> no, she's going
>> no, she's going to
>> no, she's going to be
>> no, she's going to be six.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, six.
>> no, she's going to be six.
>> Oh, six. Six
>> Oh, six. Six in
>> no, she's going to be six.
>> Oh, six. Six in a
>> Oh, six. Six in a few
>> no, she's going to be six.
>> Oh, six. Six in a few days.
>> Oh, six. Six in a few days. And
>> no, she's going to be six.
>> Oh, six. Six in a few days. And then
>> Oh, six. Six in a few days. And then to
bless
bless her
bless her that
bless her that she
bless her that she goes
bless her that she goes to
bless her that she goes to where
bless her that she goes to where she's
supposed
supposed to
bless her that she goes to where she's
supposed to be.
>> You're
>> You're supposed
>> You're supposed You're
>> You're supposed You're asking
>> You're supposed You're asking me
>> You're supposed You're asking me to
confirm
confirm God's
>> You're supposed You're asking me to
confirm God's will.
confirm God's will. I
>> You're supposed You're asking me to
confirm God's will. I mean,
confirm God's will. I mean, do
>> You're supposed You're asking me to
confirm God's will. I mean, do you
confirm God's will. I mean, do you think
that's
that's necessary?
that's necessary? I
that's necessary? I need
that's necessary? I need to
that's necessary? I need to vote
that's necessary? I need to vote on
God's
God's blessing
that's necessary? I need to vote on
God's blessing to
God's blessing to bless
that's necessary? I need to vote on
God's blessing to bless him.
>> Bless
>> Bless the
>> Bless the child.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Oh,
>> Bless the child.
>> Yes. Oh, we
>> Yes. Oh, we have
>> Bless the child.
>> Yes. Oh, we have permission
>> Yes. Oh, we have permission to
>> Bless the child.
>> Yes. Oh, we have permission to bless
this
this child.
this child. So,
this child. So, we
this child. So, we bless
this child. So, we bless this
this child. So, we bless this child
this child. So, we bless this child in
the
the name
this child. So, we bless this child in
the name of
the name of the
this child. So, we bless this child in
the name of the Lord.
the name of the Lord. Amen.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. And
>> Okay. And one
>> Okay. And one for
>> Okay. And one for me,
>> Okay. And one for me, please.
>> She
>> She wants
>> Okay. And one for me, please.
>> She wants a
>> She wants a blessing
>> Okay. And one for me, please.
>> She wants a blessing also.
>> Huh?
>> She
>> She wants
>> Huh?
>> She wants a
>> She wants a blessing
>> Huh?
>> She wants a blessing also.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, God
>> Oh, God bless
>> Oh, God bless you.
>> Oh, God bless you. Amen.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
The
The enlightened
The enlightened being
The enlightened being has
The enlightened being has a
The enlightened being has a choice
whether
whether to
The enlightened being has a choice
whether to continue
whether to continue or
The enlightened being has a choice
whether to continue or not
whether to continue or not to
The enlightened being has a choice
whether to continue or not to continue
to
to be
to be reborn
to be reborn in
to be reborn in the
to be reborn in the physical
to be reborn in the physical domain
to be reborn in the physical domain or
not.
To
To be
To be enlightened
To be enlightened means
To be enlightened means to
To be enlightened means to have
To be enlightened means to have that
choice.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
Yes.
Hello.
My
My heart's
My heart's pounding
My heart's pounding and
my
my stomach
My heart's pounding and
my stomach is
my stomach is turning
My heart's pounding and
my stomach is turning and
my stomach is turning and I'm
My heart's pounding and
my stomach is turning and I'm just
praying
praying for
praying for clarity
praying for clarity from
praying for clarity from Holy
praying for clarity from Holy Spirit
because
because I
praying for clarity from Holy Spirit
because I have
because I have a
praying for clarity from Holy Spirit
because I have a question
because I have a question that
praying for clarity from Holy Spirit
because I have a question that feels
important
important to
important to me
important to me and
important to me and it's
important to me and it's about
important to me and it's about the
calibration
calibration process.
When
When you
When you say
When you say that
When you say that someone
When you say that someone like
When you say that someone like Einstein
is
is 499
When you say that someone like Einstein
is 499 for
is 499 for example,
When you say that someone like Einstein
is 499 for example, is
is 499 for example, is that
When you say that someone like Einstein
is 499 for example, is that indicative
of
of a
of a range
of a range of
of a range of frequency?
of a range of frequency? For
of a range of frequency? For he
of a range of frequency? For he would
of a range of frequency? For he would be
capable
capable of
of a range of frequency? For he would be
capable of in
capable of in some
of a range of frequency? For he would be
capable of in some situations
capable of in some situations a
of a range of frequency? For he would be
capable of in some situations a very
much
much higher
much higher calibration.
much higher calibration. He
much higher calibration. He may
much higher calibration. He may act
much higher calibration. He may act in
much higher calibration. He may act in a
way
way that
much higher calibration. He may act in a
way that is
way that is a
much higher calibration. He may act in a
way that is a higher
way that is a higher calibration
much higher calibration. He may act in a
way that is a higher calibration and
sometimes
sometimes a
sometimes a lower
sometimes a lower one.
>> No,
>> No, because
sometimes a lower one.
>> No, because you're
>> No, because you're confusing
sometimes a lower one.
>> No, because you're confusing appearance
and
and essence.
and essence. uh
and essence. uh the
and essence. uh the essence
and essence. uh the essence doesn't
change
change just
and essence. uh the essence doesn't
change just because
change just because the
and essence. uh the essence doesn't
change just because the appearance
change just because the appearance does.
>> The
>> The essence
>> The essence of
>> The essence of uh
>> The essence of uh Einstein
>> The essence of uh Einstein and
>> The essence of uh Einstein and Freud
calibrates
calibrates at
>> The essence of uh Einstein and Freud
calibrates at 499.
>> Mhm.
>> The
>> The essence
>> Mhm.
>> The essence of
>> The essence of Carl
>> Mhm.
>> The essence of Carl Young
>> The essence of Carl Young calibrates
>> Mhm.
>> The essence of Carl Young calibrates at
I
I forget
I forget 515
I forget 515 520
I forget 515 520 something
I forget 515 520 something like
I forget 515 520 something like that.
>> Well,
>> Well, I
I forget 515 520 something like that.
>> Well, I also
>> Well, I also wanted
I forget 515 520 something like that.
>> Well, I also wanted to
>> Well, I also wanted to thank
I forget 515 520 something like that.
>> Well, I also wanted to thank you
>> Well, I also wanted to thank you for
I forget 515 520 something like that.
>> Well, I also wanted to thank you for the
gift
gift of
gift of your
gift of your teaching.
gift of your teaching. It's
gift of your teaching. It's it's
gift of your teaching. It's it's true
grace
grace and
gift of your teaching. It's it's true
grace and I've
grace and I've been
gift of your teaching. It's it's true
grace and I've been on
grace and I've been on a
gift of your teaching. It's it's true
grace and I've been on a spiritual
grace and I've been on a spiritual path
a
a very
a very long
a very long time
a very long time and
a very long time and I
a very long time and I find
a very long time and I find what
a very long time and I find what I'm
learning
learning from
a very long time and I find what I'm
learning from you
learning from you is
a very long time and I find what I'm
learning from you is very
learning from you is very practical
a very long time and I find what I'm
learning from you is very practical and
very
very helpful.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> And
>> And I
>> And I would
>> And I would also
>> And I would also like
>> And I would also like to
>> And I would also like to give
>> And I would also like to give you
>> And I would also like to give you my
blessing
blessing if
>> And I would also like to give you my
blessing if I
blessing if I may.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, good.
>> Oh, good. Thank
>> Oh, good. Thank you.
>> May
>> May the
>> Oh, good. Thank you.
>> May the Lord
>> May the Lord bless
>> Oh, good. Thank you.
>> May the Lord bless you
>> May the Lord bless you and
>> Oh, good. Thank you.
>> May the Lord bless you and keep
>> May the Lord bless you and keep you.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Amen.
>> Okay. Amen. How much
>> Okay. Amen. How much time
>> Okay. Amen. How much time do
>> Okay. Amen. How much time do we
>> Okay. Amen. How much time do we have?
It's
It's almost
>> Okay. Amen. How much time do we have?
It's almost 5
It's almost 5 o'.
>> All
>> All right.
>> All right. We
>> All right. We only
>> All right. We only have
>> All right. We only have four
>> All right. We only have four minutes,
>> All right. We only have four minutes, so
we're
we're not
>> All right. We only have four minutes, so
we're not going
we're not going to
>> All right. We only have four minutes, so
we're not going to get
we're not going to get to
>> All right. We only have four minutes, so
we're not going to get to all
we're not going to get to all the
questions
questions today.
questions today. I'm
questions today. I'm sorry.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Freud
questions today. I'm sorry.
>> Yeah. Freud was
>> Yeah. Freud was at
questions today. I'm sorry.
>> Yeah. Freud was at 499.
And
And uh
>> hello.
>> Yes.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Yes.
>> Thank you for
>> Thank you for letting
>> Yes.
>> Thank you for letting me
>> Thank you for letting me ask
>> Yes.
>> Thank you for letting me ask a
>> Thank you for letting me ask a question.
And
And I
And I want
And I want to
And I want to know
And I want to know if
And I want to know if you
And I want to know if you can
And I want to know if you can tell
And I want to know if you can tell us
something
something about
And I want to know if you can tell us
something about how
something about how to
And I want to know if you can tell us
something about how to raise
something about how to raise a
And I want to know if you can tell us
something about how to raise a child
something about how to raise a child in
today's
today's world.
>> How
>> How to
today's world.
>> How to what?
>> How
>> How to
>> How to raise
>> How to raise a
>> How to raise a child
>> How to raise a child in
>> How to raise a child in today's
>> How to raise a child in today's world?
>> Do
>> Do you
>> How to raise a child in today's world?
>> Do you want
>> Do you want to
>> How to raise a child in today's world?
>> Do you want to raise
>> Do you want to raise a
>> How to raise a child in today's world?
>> Do you want to raise a child
>> Do you want to raise a child in
>> How to raise a child in today's world?
>> Do you want to raise a child in today's
world?
>> Yes.
>> How
>> How to
>> How to raise
>> Oh,
>> Oh, how
>> How to raise
>> Oh, how to
>> Oh, how to how
>> How to raise
>> Oh, how to how to?
>> Oh, how to how to? Of
>> How to raise
>> Oh, how to how to? Of course
>> Oh, how to how to? Of course that's
>> How to raise
>> Oh, how to how to? Of course that's a
very
very complex
very complex question
and
and uh
very complex question
and uh it
and uh it depends
very complex question
and uh it depends on
and uh it depends on how
very complex question
and uh it depends on how you
and uh it depends on how you see
very complex question
and uh it depends on how you see your
your
your role
your role as
your role as a
your role as a parent.
your role as a parent. Yeah.
your role as a parent. Yeah. What
your role as a parent. Yeah. What is
your
your role
your role as a parent. Yeah. What is
your role as
your role as a
your role as a parent. Yeah. What is
your role as a parent
your role as a parent and
your role as a parent. Yeah. What is
your role as a parent and what
your role as a parent and what is
your role as a parent. Yeah. What is
your role as a parent and what is your
awareness
awareness of
awareness of reality,
awareness of reality, spiritual
awareness of reality, spiritual reality,
consciousness?
Uh
Uh there's
Uh there's no
Uh there's no way
Uh there's no way it
Uh there's no way it can
Uh there's no way it can be
Uh there's no way it can be answered
because
because the
Uh there's no way it can be answered
because the question
because the question would
Uh there's no way it can be answered
because the question would be
because the question would be answered
completely
completely differently
completely differently for
completely differently for different
people.
We
We certainly
We certainly can
We certainly can assume
We certainly can assume that
unconditional
unconditional love
We certainly can assume that
unconditional love is
unconditional love is a
We certainly can assume that
unconditional love is a priority
and
and to
and to teach
and to teach the
and to teach the child
and to teach the child that
and to teach the child that which
and to teach the child that which he
needs
needs to
and to teach the child that which he
needs to know
needs to know to
and to teach the child that which he
needs to know to succeed
needs to know to succeed and
and to teach the child that which he
needs to know to succeed and be
needs to know to succeed and be happy
and to teach the child that which he
needs to know to succeed and be happy in
this
this world.
this world. Uh
this world. Uh beyond
this world. Uh beyond that
this world. Uh beyond that nothing
this world. Uh beyond that nothing is
really
really required
this world. Uh beyond that nothing is
really required is
really required is it?
this world. Uh beyond that nothing is
really required is it? No.
really required is it? No. Teach
this world. Uh beyond that nothing is
really required is it? No. Teach him
really required is it? No. Teach him how
to
to be
to be successful
to be successful and
to be successful and happy
to be successful and happy in
to be successful and happy in the
to be successful and happy in the world
and
and spiritually
to be successful and happy in the world
and spiritually oriented.
and spiritually oriented. So
to be successful and happy in the world
and spiritually oriented. So he
and spiritually oriented. So he has
heard
heard of
heard of reality
heard of reality and
heard of reality and uh
heard of reality and uh energized
heard of reality and uh energized to
heard of reality and uh energized to uh
pursue
pursue it.
heard of reality and uh energized to uh
pursue it. Yes.
Thank
Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> An
>> An appreciation
>> An appreciation for
>> An appreciation for beauty
>> An appreciation for beauty and
>> An appreciation for beauty and all
>> An appreciation for beauty and all of
its
its expressions
is
is one
is one of
is one of the
is one of the most
is one of the most greatest
is one of the most greatest things
is one of the most greatest things you
can
can do
is one of the most greatest things you
can do for
can do for a
is one of the most greatest things you
can do for a child.
can do for a child. Yes.
>> Hi,
>> Hi, doctor.
>> Hi, doctor. Uh
>> yes,
>> thank
>> thank you
>> thank you for
>> thank you for listening
>> thank you for listening to
>> thank you for listening to this
>> thank you for listening to this one's
question.
question. The
>> thank you for listening to this one's
question. The question
question. The question has
>> thank you for listening to this one's
question. The question has to
question. The question has to do
>> thank you for listening to this one's
question. The question has to do with
question. The question has to do with a
feeling
feeling of
feeling of weepiness.
Um
Um not
feeling of weepiness.
Um not sadness.
Um
Um almost,
Um almost, you
Um almost, you know,
Um almost, you know, I
Um almost, you know, I could
Um almost, you know, I could see
Um almost, you know, I could see a
Um almost, you know, I could see a a
tree
tree and
Um almost, you know, I could see a a
tree and just
tree and just go
Um almost, you know, I could see a a
tree and just go into
>> Oh,
>> Oh, that's
>> Oh, that's joy.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, it
>> Oh, that's joy.
>> Yeah, it it's
>> Yeah, it it's very
>> Oh, that's joy.
>> Yeah, it it's very joyful.
>> Yeah, it it's very joyful. Um
>> Oh, that's joy.
>> Yeah, it it's very joyful. Um the
question
question is
question is insight
question is insight into
question is insight into that.
question is insight into that. Um
question is insight into that. Um how
question is insight into that. Um how to
work
work with
question is insight into that. Um how to
work with that?
work with that? How
question is insight into that. Um how to
work with that? How to
>> don't
>> don't have
>> don't have to
>> don't have to work
>> don't have to work with
>> don't have to work with it.
>> Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Like
>> Like a
>> Thank you.
>> Like a beautiful
>> Like a beautiful day
>> Thank you.
>> Like a beautiful day in
>> Like a beautiful day in May.
>> Thank you.
>> Like a beautiful day in May. Nothing
>> Like a beautiful day in May. Nothing to
work
work with.
It
It just
work with.
It just says
It just says enjoy,
work with.
It just says enjoy, appreciate,
and
and thank
and thank God
and thank God that
and thank God that you're
and thank God that you're able
and thank God that you're able to
and thank God that you're able to see
and
and witness
and thank God that you're able to see
and witness it.
>> Good
>> Good shot.
>> Oh
>> Oh Lord,
>> Good shot.
>> Oh Lord, thou
>> Oh Lord, thou hast
sent
sent me
sent me thy
sent me thy love.
sent me thy love. Amen.
>> Yes.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know. I
>> I don't know. I don't
>> I don't know. I don't really
>> I don't know. I don't really have
>> I don't know. I don't really have a
question.
question. Just
>> I don't know. I don't really have a
question. Just came
question. Just came here
>> I don't know. I don't really have a
question. Just came here actually
question. Just came here actually to
>> I don't know. I don't really have a
question. Just came here actually to be
in
in your
in your presence
in your presence and
in your presence and thank
in your presence and thank you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
in your presence and thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank
>> Thank you. Thank you
in your presence and thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you so
>> Thank you. Thank you so much.
in your presence and thank you.
>> Thank you. Thank you so much. I
>> Thank you. Thank you so much. I prefer
the
the chocolate.
>> That's
>> That's what
the chocolate.
>> That's what ambrosia
>> That's what ambrosia was.
the chocolate.
>> That's what ambrosia was. Ambrosia,
which
which is
which is spoken
which is spoken of
which is spoken of antiquity.
which is spoken of antiquity. That's
ambrosia.
ambrosia. It
which is spoken of antiquity. That's
ambrosia. It was
ambrosia. It was actually
which is spoken of antiquity. That's
ambrosia. It was actually chocolate.
>> Please
>> Please forgive
>> Please forgive my
>> Please forgive my naivity.
>> Please forgive my naivity. I've
>> Please forgive my naivity. I've only
been
been pursuing
>> Please forgive my naivity. I've only
been pursuing my
been pursuing my spiritual
>> Please forgive my naivity. I've only
been pursuing my spiritual path
been pursuing my spiritual path for
about
about a
about a year
about a year now.
about a year now. And
about a year now. And um
about a year now. And um just
about a year now. And um just had
about a year now. And um just had my
60th
60th birthday,
about a year now. And um just had my
60th birthday, so
60th birthday, so I'm
about a year now. And um just had my
60th birthday, so I'm in
60th birthday, so I'm in a
about a year now. And um just had my
60th birthday, so I'm in a hurry.
>> But
>> But she
>> But she I
>> But she I can't
>> But she I can't hear
>> But she I can't hear understand
>> But she I can't hear understand what
you're
you're saying.
>> She
>> She said
>> She said she
>> She said she just
>> She said she just had
>> She said she just had her
>> She said she just had her 60th
>> She said she just had her 60th birthday.
So
So she's
>> She said she just had her 60th birthday.
So she's in
So she's in a
>> She said she just had her 60th birthday.
So she's in a hurry.
So she's in a hurry. She's
>> She said she just had her 60th birthday.
So she's in a hurry. She's been
So she's in a hurry. She's been pursuing
>> 60th.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Oh,
>> but
>> but I
>> but I I'm
>> but I I'm my
>> but I I'm my question
>> but I I'm my question is
>> but I I'm my question is probably
>> but I I'm my question is probably a
little
little naive,
>> but I I'm my question is probably a
little naive, but
little naive, but I'm
>> but I I'm my question is probably a
little naive, but I'm a
little naive, but I'm a bit
>> but I I'm my question is probably a
little naive, but I'm a bit puzzled
about
about karma
about karma and
about karma and how
about karma and how you
about karma and how you can
about karma and how you can overcome
centuries
centuries of
about karma and how you can overcome
centuries of karma.
centuries of karma. Um,
about karma and how you can overcome
centuries of karma. Um, my
daughter-in-law
daughter-in-law has
daughter-in-law has had
daughter-in-law has had a
daughter-in-law has had a lot
daughter-in-law has had a lot of
daughter-in-law has had a lot of abuse
from
from her
daughter-in-law has had a lot of abuse
from her mother
from her mother and
daughter-in-law has had a lot of abuse
from her mother and as
from her mother and as far
daughter-in-law has had a lot of abuse
from her mother and as far as
from her mother and as far as we
daughter-in-law has had a lot of abuse
from her mother and as far as we can
understand,
understand, this
understand, this has
understand, this has been
understand, this has been going
understand, this has been going on
understand, this has been going on down
the
the centuries,
understand, this has been going on down
the centuries, you
the centuries, you know,
understand, this has been going on down
the centuries, you know, from
the centuries, you know, from her
understand, this has been going on down
the centuries, you know, from her mother
and
and her
and her mother.
and her mother. Yes.
>> And
>> And um
and her mother. Yes.
>> And um I
>> And um I think
and her mother. Yes.
>> And um I think how
>> And um I think how how
and her mother. Yes.
>> And um I think how how can
>> And um I think how how can she
and her mother. Yes.
>> And um I think how how can she overcome
that?
that? How
that? How can
that? How can what
>> how
>> how can
that? How can what
>> how can she
>> how can she overcome
that? How can what
>> how can she overcome if
>> how can she overcome if if
that? How can what
>> how can she overcome if if it's
>> how can she overcome if if it's her
karma
karma to
karma to have
karma to have an
karma to have an say
karma to have an say a
karma to have an say a mother
karma to have an say a mother who
verbally
verbally abuses
karma to have an say a mother who
verbally abuses her
verbally abuses her and
karma to have an say a mother who
verbally abuses her and this
verbally abuses her and this has
karma to have an say a mother who
verbally abuses her and this has been
going
going on.
going on. How
going on. How can
going on. How can you
going on. How can you break
going on. How can you break through
centuries
centuries of
going on. How can you break through
centuries of of
centuries of of karma?
>> This
>> This is
>> This is an
>> This is an evolutionary
>> This is an evolutionary pattern
>> This is an evolutionary pattern in
>> This is an evolutionary pattern in this
family.
family. Is
>> This is an evolutionary pattern in this
family. Is that
family. Is that right?
>> Yes,
>> Yes, that's
>> Yes, that's right.
>> And
>> And there
>> Yes, that's right.
>> And there may
>> And there may not
>> Yes, that's right.
>> And there may not be
>> And there may not be anything
>> Yes, that's right.
>> And there may not be anything you
>> And there may not be anything you can
>> Yes, that's right.
>> And there may not be anything you can do
about
about it
about it except
about it except treat
about it except treat the
about it except treat the depression.
It's
It's a
about it except treat the depression.
It's a karmic
It's a karmic propensity.
about it except treat the depression.
It's a karmic propensity. Yes.
It's a karmic propensity. Yes. It
about it except treat the depression.
It's a karmic propensity. Yes. It often
runs
runs in
runs in families
runs in families and
runs in families and it
runs in families and it often
runs in families and it often runs
>> through
>> through generations.
>> But
>> But should
>> But should you
>> But should you know
>> But should you know there's
>> But should you know there's a
>> not
>> not being
>> But should you know there's a
>> not being depressed
>> not being depressed but
>> But should you know there's a
>> not being depressed but the
>> not being depressed but the propensity
or
or the
>> dilemma
>> dilemma isn't
or the
>> dilemma isn't there?
>> dilemma isn't there? If
or the
>> dilemma isn't there? If it's
>> dilemma isn't there? If it's your
mother,
mother, do
mother, do you
mother, do you turn
mother, do you turn your
mother, do you turn your back
mother, do you turn your back on
mother, do you turn your back on that
because
because that
mother, do you turn your back on that
because that brings
because that brings you
mother, do you turn your back on that
because that brings you down
because that brings you down or
mother, do you turn your back on that
because that brings you down or do
because that brings you down or do you
try
try to
try to try
try to try to
try to try to help?
>> They're
>> They're giving
try to try to help?
>> They're giving me
>> They're giving me a
try to try to help?
>> They're giving me a lecture
>> They're giving me a lecture instead
try to try to help?
>> They're giving me a lecture instead of
asking
asking a
asking a question.
>> See
>> See a
asking a question.
>> See a therapist.
>> I
>> I ask
>> I ask no
>> I ask no questions
>> I ask no questions of
>> I ask no questions of a
>> I ask no questions of a therapist.
>> I ask no questions of a therapist. Um
>> I ask no questions of a therapist. Um so
the
the mother
>> I ask no questions of a therapist. Um so
the mother does
the mother does but
>> I ask no questions of a therapist. Um so
the mother does but but
the mother does but but she
>> I ask no questions of a therapist. Um so
the mother does but but she won't.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. But
>> Yes. But all
>> Yes. But all right
>> Yes. But all right then
>> Yes. But all right then the
>> Yes. But all right then the child
>> Yes. But all right then the child who's
this
this is
>> Yes. But all right then the child who's
this is involved
this is involved with
>> Yes. But all right then the child who's
this is involved with needs
this is involved with needs to
>> Yes. But all right then the child who's
this is involved with needs to see
this is involved with needs to see a
therapist
therapist because
therapist because what
therapist because what this
therapist because what this is
therapist because what this is is
therapist because what this is is this
is
is a
therapist because what this is is this
is a physical
is a physical um
therapist because what this is is this
is a physical um mental
is a physical um mental problem
therapist because what this is is this
is a physical um mental problem on
is a physical um mental problem on a
mother
mother daughter
mother daughter relationship.
mother daughter relationship. So
mother daughter relationship. So um
mother daughter relationship. So um it
really
really needs
mother daughter relationship. So um it
really needs to
really needs to be
mother daughter relationship. So um it
really needs to be solved
really needs to be solved by
mother daughter relationship. So um it
really needs to be solved by analyst
really needs to be solved by analyst or
professional
professional because
professional because it
professional because it isn't
professional because it isn't a
spiritual
spiritual question.
professional because it isn't a
spiritual question. This
spiritual question. This isn't
professional because it isn't a
spiritual question. This isn't it
spiritual question. This isn't it has
nothing
nothing to
nothing to do
nothing to do with
nothing to do with the
nothing to do with the spiritual.
nothing to do with the spiritual. It
nothing to do with the spiritual. It has
to
to do
nothing to do with the spiritual. It has
to do with
>> brain
>> brain chemistry.
>> brain chemistry. Brain
>> brain chemistry. Brain chemistry.
>> brain chemistry. Brain chemistry. brain
chemistry.
chemistry. Yeah.
>> That
>> That runs
>> That runs in
>> That runs in this
>> That runs in this family.
>> Genetic
>> Genetic brain
>> That runs in this family.
>> Genetic brain chemistry.
>> So
>> So it's
>> So it's not
>> So it's not karma
>> So it's not karma that
>> So it's not karma that that
>> So it's not karma that that that
>> So it's not karma that that that she
call
call it
>> So it's not karma that that that she
call it karma
call it karma spiritually
>> So it's not karma that that that she
call it karma spiritually but
>> yes
>> the
>> the fulfillment
>> yes
>> the fulfillment of
>> the fulfillment of that
>> yes
>> the fulfillment of that karma
>> the fulfillment of that karma in
>> yes
>> the fulfillment of that karma in the
physical
physical domain
physical domain is
physical domain is brain
physical domain is brain chemistry
physical domain is brain chemistry and
brain
brain chemistry
physical domain is brain chemistry and
brain chemistry is
brain chemistry is to
physical domain is brain chemistry and
brain chemistry is to considerable
brain chemistry is to considerable uh
extent
extent genetic.
>> So
>> So any
extent genetic.
>> So any kind
>> So any kind of
extent genetic.
>> So any kind of therapy
>> So any kind of therapy group
extent genetic.
>> So any kind of therapy group or
>> So any kind of therapy group or um
extent genetic.
>> So any kind of therapy group or um you
know
know there
know there are
know there are abusive
know there are abusive therapy
know there are abusive therapy groups
for
for for
know there are abusive therapy groups
for for um
for for um abused
know there are abusive therapy groups
for for um abused children
for for um abused children and
know there are abusive therapy groups
for for um abused children and abused
people.
They
They do
people.
They do have
They do have um
people.
They do have um you
They do have um you know
people.
They do have um you know just
They do have um you know just like
Alcoholic
Alcoholic Anonymous
Alcoholic Anonymous they
Alcoholic Anonymous they have
Alcoholic Anonymous they have groups
that
that you
Alcoholic Anonymous they have groups
that you can
that you can go
Alcoholic Anonymous they have groups
that you can go and
that you can go and talk
Alcoholic Anonymous they have groups
that you can go and talk to
>> but
>> but she
>> but she won't
>> but she won't see
>> but she won't see a
>> but she won't see a therapist.
>> but she won't see a therapist. So
>> well
>> well then
>> but she won't see a therapist. So
>> well then the
>> well then the daughter
>> but she won't see a therapist. So
>> well then the daughter whoever
>> well then the daughter whoever is
involved
involved in
involved in this
involved in this needs
involved in this needs to
involved in this needs to go
involved in this needs to go and
involved in this needs to go and see
involved in this needs to go and see it.
>> Yes.
>> It
>> It doesn't
>> It doesn't have
>> It doesn't have to
>> It doesn't have to be
>> It doesn't have to be her
>> It doesn't have to be her the
>> It doesn't have to be her the mother.
>> It doesn't have to be her the mother. It
has
has to
>> It doesn't have to be her the mother. It
has to be
has to be the
>> It doesn't have to be her the mother. It
has to be the daughter
has to be the daughter that
>> It doesn't have to be her the mother. It
has to be the daughter that goes
has to be the daughter that goes and
takes
takes the
takes the initiative
takes the initiative to
takes the initiative to do
takes the initiative to do it
takes the initiative to do it to
takes the initiative to do it to break
>> to
>> to break
takes the initiative to do it to break
>> to break the
>> to break the chain.
takes the initiative to do it to break
>> to break the chain. Right.
>> to break the chain. Right. So
takes the initiative to do it to break
>> to break the chain. Right. So could
>> to break the chain. Right. So could I
please
please ask
please ask you
please ask you for
please ask you for a
please ask you for a blessing
please ask you for a blessing for
please ask you for a blessing for her
and
and her
please ask you for a blessing for her
and her little
and her little baby
please ask you for a blessing for her
and her little baby son?
>> Could
>> Could she?
>> Could she? So,
>> Could she? So, it's
>> Could she? So, it's a
>> Could she? So, it's a blessing
>> Could she? So, it's a blessing on
>> Could she? So, it's a blessing on her
and
and her
>> Could she? So, it's a blessing on her
and her son.
>> For
>> For my
>> For my daughter-in-law
>> For my daughter-in-law and
>> For my daughter-in-law and my
>> For my daughter-in-law and my little
grandson,
grandson, if
>> For my daughter-in-law and my little
grandson, if I
grandson, if I could
>> For my daughter-in-law and my little
grandson, if I could have
grandson, if I could have your
>> For my daughter-in-law and my little
grandson, if I could have your blessing
for
for them.
>> I
>> I have
for them.
>> I have permission
>> I have permission to
for them.
>> I have permission to bless
>> I have permission to bless the
for them.
>> I have permission to bless the people
that
that she
that she holds
that she holds in
that she holds in mind.
that she holds in mind. Okay.
that she holds in mind. Okay. So,
that she holds in mind. Okay. So, we
that she holds in mind. Okay. So, we do
bless
bless them
that she holds in mind. Okay. So, we do
bless them as
bless them as you
that she holds in mind. Okay. So, we do
bless them as you so
bless them as you so asked
that she holds in mind. Okay. So, we do
bless them as you so asked in
bless them as you so asked in the
that she holds in mind. Okay. So, we do
bless them as you so asked in the name
of
of the
of the Lord.
of the Lord. Amen.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
of the Lord. Amen.
>> Thank you. May
>> Thank you. May I
of the Lord. Amen.
>> Thank you. May I shake
>> Thank you. May I shake your
of the Lord. Amen.
>> Thank you. May I shake your hand?
>> Yes.
Yes.
Yes. Depression
>> Yes.
Yes. Depression is
Yes. Depression is genetic
considerably
considerably in
considerably in the
considerably in the physical
considerably in the physical domain.
It's
It's linked
considerably in the physical domain.
It's linked also
It's linked also with
considerably in the physical domain.
It's linked also with other
It's linked also with other associated
problems
and
and may
problems
and may represent
and may represent itself
problems
and may represent itself most
and may represent itself most frequently
maybe
maybe as
maybe as alcohol
maybe as alcohol or
um
um drugs
maybe as alcohol or
um drugs or
um drugs or alcohol
maybe as alcohol or
um drugs or alcohol or
um drugs or alcohol or drugs
to
to try
to try and
to try and escape
to try and escape the
to try and escape the depression.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yes.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, that's
>> Yes.
>> Okay, that's it.
>> Okay, that's it. You
>> Yes.
>> Okay, that's it. You want
>> Okay, that's it. You want to
>> Yes.
>> Okay, that's it. You want to stand
>> Okay, that's it. You want to stand real
quick?
>> Ah,
>> Ah, yes.
quick?
>> Ah, yes. Is
>> Ah, yes. Is that
quick?
>> Ah, yes. Is that the
>> That's
>> That's it.
>> That's it. We're
>> That's it. We're going
>> That's it. We're going to
>> That's it. We're going to shake
>> That's it. We're going to shake hands
and
and um
>> What
>> What are
>> What are we
>> What are we going
>> What are we going to
>> What are we going to do
>> What are we going to do now?
>> You're
>> You're going
>> What are we going to do now?
>> You're going to
>> You're going to bless
>> What are we going to do now?
>> You're going to bless everybody
>> You're going to bless everybody who's
come.
>> Oh
>> Oh my
come.
>> Oh my god.
>> Oh my god. Bless
come.
>> Oh my god. Bless everybody
>> Oh my god. Bless everybody here.
Oh
Oh yes.
I
I I
Oh yes.
I I give
I I give thanks
Oh yes.
I I give thanks to
I I give thanks to Almighty
Oh yes.
I I give thanks to Almighty God
I I give thanks to Almighty God for
Oh yes.
I I give thanks to Almighty God for all
of
of you
of you here.
of you here. present.
What
What a
of you here. present.
What a great
What a great gift.
of you here. present.
What a great gift. What
What a great gift. What a
of you here. present.
What a great gift. What a great
What a great gift. What a great gift.
of you here. present.
What a great gift. What a great gift. Oh
Lord,
Lord, I
Lord, I give
Lord, I give thanks
Lord, I give thanks for
Lord, I give thanks for all
Lord, I give thanks for all that
Lord, I give thanks for all that are
here
here this
Lord, I give thanks for all that are
here this moment
here this moment and
Lord, I give thanks for all that are
here this moment and I
here this moment and I bless
Lord, I give thanks for all that are
here this moment and I bless them
here this moment and I bless them all
Lord, I give thanks for all that are
here this moment and I bless them all in
thy
thy name.
thy name. Amen.
Thank
Thank you
thy name. Amen.
Thank you so
Thank you so much
thy name. Amen.
Thank you so much for
Thank you so much for being
thy name. Amen.
Thank you so much for being here
Thank you so much for being here and
thy name. Amen.
Thank you so much for being here and it
was
was a
was a most
was a most enjoyable
was a most enjoyable day.
was a most enjoyable day. Amen.
Yes.
Yes. Uhhuh.
Oh
boy.
Yeah.
Hallelujah.
I
the
Oh,
Hallelujah.
Gloral.
Amen.
What
What a
Amen.
What a gift.
What a gift. What
Amen.
What a gift. What a
What a gift. What a gift
Amen.
What a gift. What a gift you
What a gift. What a gift you are
Amen.
What a gift. What a gift you are to
What a gift. What a gift you are to me.
What
What a
What a gift
What a gift this
What a gift this group
What a gift this group is
What a gift this group is to
What a gift this group is to us.
What a gift this group is to us. Hey,
how
how much
What a gift this group is to us. Hey,
how much we
how much we love
What a gift this group is to us. Hey,
how much we love them.
That
That one
That one forever.
Hang
Hang on
That one forever.
Hang on to
Hang on to the
That one forever.
Hang on to the table.
Hang on to the table. That's
That one forever.
Hang on to the table. That's what
Hang on to the table. That's what I
That one forever.
Hang on to the table. That's what I do.
We'll
We'll have
We'll have to
>> love
>> love is
We'll have to
>> love is what
>> love is what blesses
We'll have to
>> love is what blesses the
>> love is what blesses the world
>> because
>> because of
>> because of its
>> because of its nature.
>> I'm
>> I'm going
>> because of its nature.
>> I'm going to
>> I'm going to have
>> because of its nature.
>> I'm going to have to
>> I'm going to have to stop.
All
All right,
All right, we
All right, we have
All right, we have music
All right, we have music somewhere.
We'll
We'll get
All right, we have music somewhere.
We'll get it
We'll get it turned
All right, we have music somewhere.
We'll get it turned down.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
God
God bless
God bless you
God bless you all.
God bless you all. I
God bless you all. I thank
God bless you all. I thank you
God bless you all. I thank you now
God bless you all. I thank you now and
forever.
That
That which
That which we
That which we are
That which we are is
That which we are is one
That which we are is one forever.
That which we are is one forever. Amen.
Let
Let me
That which we are is one forever. Amen.
Let me have
Let me have your
That which we are is one forever. Amen.
Let me have your arm
Let me have your arm a
That which we are is one forever. Amen.
Let me have your arm a second.
As
As a
As a group,
As a group, we
As a group, we are
As a group, we are one
As a group, we are one forever.
We
We are
As a group, we are one forever.
We are one
We are one forever.
As a group, we are one forever.
We are one forever. It
We are one forever. It says
As a group, we are one forever.
We are one forever. It says yes.
Pow
Pow pow.
Pow pow. I
Pow pow. I guess
Pow pow. I guess that's
Pow pow. I guess that's showing
guess
guess that's
Pow pow. I guess that's showing
guess that's showing
guess that's showing the
Pow pow. I guess that's showing
guess that's showing the evil
guess that's showing the evil one
something.
something. Pop
something. Pop pop pop.
something. Pop pop pop. Take
something. Pop pop pop. Take that.
Pow.
>> The
>> The evil
>> The evil one
>> The evil one went
>> The evil one went flying
>> The evil one went flying through
>> The evil one went flying through the
>> The evil one went flying through the air
begging
begging for
>> The evil one went flying through the air
begging for mercy.
Don't
Don't let
Don't let these
Don't let these people
Don't let these people after
Don't let these people after me.
Don't let these people after me. Okay,
if
if you
Don't let these people after me. Okay,
if you change
if you change your
Don't let these people after me. Okay,
if you change your ways.
>> They're
>> They're going
>> They're going to
>> They're going to go
>> They're going to go over
>> They're going to go over here
>> They're going to go over here and
>> They're going to go over here and and
shake
shake hands
>> They're going to go over here and and
shake hands now.
>> Okay.
The
The evil
>> Okay.
The evil one
The evil one promised
>> Okay.
The evil one promised to
The evil one promised to change
>> Okay.
The evil one promised to change his
ways.
In
In which
ways.
In which case,
In which case, we'll
ways.
In which case, we'll let
In which case, we'll let him
ways.
In which case, we'll let him off
In which case, we'll let him off the
hook.
>> This
>> This this
hook.
>> This this microphone
>> This this microphone and
hook.
>> This this microphone and feedback
>> This this microphone and feedback is
quite
quite different
quite different than
quite different than anything
quite different than anything I've
quite different than anything I've had
before.
>> There's
>> There's a
>> There's a rail
>> There's a rail here.
>> There's a rail here. We're
>> There's a rail here. We're going
>> There's a rail here. We're going to
>> There's a rail here. We're going to take
you
you down
>> There's a rail here. We're going to take
you down to
you down to the
>> There's a rail here. We're going to take
you down to the bottom
you down to the bottom step
>> There's a rail here. We're going to take
you down to the bottom step dock.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> First
>> First step,
>> a
>> a step.
>> One
>> One more.
>> Actually,
>> Actually, two
>> Actually, two more.
>> Actually, two more. One.
>> Okay.
>> And
>> And last
>> And last one.
>> And last one. And
>> And last one. And then
>> And last one. And then you
>> And last one. And then you got
>> And last one. And then you got the
>> And last one. And then you got the rail
to
to stand
>> And last one. And then you got the rail
to stand on.
>> Pow.
>> Pow. Pow.
>> Right
>> Right there.
>> Okay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Okay.
>> Thank you so
>> Thank you so much.
>> God
>> God bless
>> God bless you,
>> God bless you, loves.
>> I'm
>> I'm going
>> God bless you, loves.
>> I'm going to
>> I'm going to have
>> God bless you, loves.
>> I'm going to have a
>> I'm going to have a picture.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, wait.
>> Oh, wait. Okay.
>> Oh, wait. Okay. I'll
>> Oh, wait. Okay. I'll do
>> Oh, wait. Okay. I'll do it
>> Oh, wait. Okay. I'll do it again.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Thank
>> Oh, wait. Okay. I'll do it again.
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> Yes. Thank you. That's
>> Oh, wait. Okay. I'll do it again.
>> Yes. Thank you. That's a
>> Yes. Thank you. That's a nice
>> Oh, wait. Okay. I'll do it again.
>> Yes. Thank you. That's a nice one.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
Thank
Thank you.
>> Thank
>> Thank you,
Thank you.
>> Thank you, honey.
>> Hi.
>> Yay.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> I
>> I love
>> Thank you.
>> I love his
>> I love his shirt.
>> Thank you.
>> I love his shirt. Steal
>> I love his shirt. Steal that
>> Thank you.
>> I love his shirt. Steal that shirt.
>> This
>> This is
>> This is my
>> This is my bride
>> This is my bride to
>> This is my bride to be.
>> This is my bride to be. Would
>> This is my bride to be. Would you
>> This is my bride to be. Would you bless
our
>> Hi,
>> Hi, bride
>> Hi, bride to
>> Hi, bride to believe.
>> Hi, bride to believe. God
>> Hi, bride to believe. God bless
>> Hi, bride to believe. God bless you,
sweetheart.
>> You're
>> You're adorable.
>> God
>> God bless
>> You're adorable.
>> God bless your
>> God bless your love.
>> Love
>> Love is
>> Love is what
>> Love is what keeps
>> Love is what keeps you
>> Love is what keeps you going.
>> Love is what keeps you going. See,
>> it
>> it wasn't
>> Love is what keeps you going. See,
>> it wasn't for
>> it wasn't for Susan.
>> Love is what keeps you going. See,
>> it wasn't for Susan. Of
>> it wasn't for Susan. Of course,
>> Love is what keeps you going. See,
>> it wasn't for Susan. Of course, I
>> it wasn't for Susan. Of course, I don't
like
like to
like to tell
like to tell her
like to tell her that.
like to tell her that. Oh,
like to tell her that. Oh, she
like to tell her that. Oh, she might
like to tell her that. Oh, she might get
a
a swelled
like to tell her that. Oh, she might get
a swelled head.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. God
>> Yeah. God bless
>> Yeah. God bless you.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, hi.
>> Hi.
>> Good
>> Good to
>> Hi.
>> Good to see
>> Good to see you
>> Hi.
>> Good to see you again.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. You
>> Thank you. You too.
>> Good
>> Good to
>> Thank you. You too.
>> Good to see
>> Good to see you.
>> Thank you. You too.
>> Good to see you. Hi.
>> God
>> God bless
>> God bless you.
>> Ah,
>> Ah, God
>> God bless you.
>> Ah, God bless
>> Ah, God bless you,
>> God bless you.
>> Ah, God bless you, sweetheart.
>> Yeah.
God
God bless
>> Yeah.
God bless you.