Is he back?
>> We're waiting on the sound guy.
>> Good.
>> Can I ask? Sure. Sit right down here and
you can ask me a question.
>> Okay.
>> Yes.
>> My question is about
You got to speak into the mic, honey.
Show her how to do that. Right.
>> My question is about letting go patterns
in the mind that have to do with thought
disorder or um cognitive disability like
memory and learning disabilities.
>> Where? I know that's some of what we
just talked about, but like letting go
of the identity of it and
of being able to heal from it, like of
people saying it's impossible, like it's
impossible for you to heal from.
>> What's impossible?
>> Um, like the labels of major depression
or cognitive disorder or thought
disorder.
>> I don't get what is the question. Okay.
My question um overcoming something that
is labeled as impossible or incurable.
>> You reinforce the fact of of it being
incurable. Yeah.
However, some things cannot be altered
altered,
you know, just because of the
limitations
of the linear domain.
What do you see?
I see a full hand, but my mind tells me.
>> Tell me what you see here. Come on.
>> Four fingers.
>> You're seeing four fingers, not five.
Yes.
>> And what can I do about that?
>> Learn.
>> That's not just labeling.
>> Yeah. It's a reality of what it is.
>> Yeah. So, it's not just labeling. Yeah.
That was a mistake that Thomas Zah made
about
uh years ago and closed up all the
mental hospitals. Now they're left to
die and starve and
prostitute. He robbed and end up in
crime and addiction on the streets. He
didn't do anybody a favor.
>> Yep.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah, there is a reality to it. Yes.
>> Okay.
Where the hell did they get this?
>> Um, if each one of you could stick to
just one question. One question because
we want to try and answer everybody.
>> That was one question with three parts.
>> Where do these books come from? Whose
books are these?
>> Over there.
>> Huh?
>> Behind you is where they came from.
>> Who's behind me? Please.
>> The whole line. A whole a whole line of
people that want their book signed.
>> Oh, a book is just I thought I thought
there were people associated with these
things.
>> There are this is the guy that had the
orthomolecular psychiatry.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Sorry.
No questions here.
>> Yes.
What does this say here?
>> The Zen teaching of
that person
>> wing pull.
>> Uhhuh. The Zen teaching of Hanging Po.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Is that yours?
>> No, it's not.
>> Someone went over here.
>> I don't want this piece this way where I
can't see who I'm talking to her about.
>> All right. It's uh Josh's book.
>> Oh. Oh, okay.
>> Oh, you
>> Where'd you get this?
>> Amazon.
>> Thank you. The Zen teachings of Wang Poe
is available on
>> Amazon.
>> Amazon. It's hard to wrench a simple
answer out of these people, isn't it?
Where did you get it? Walmarts. Oh,
okay. So, this is from Amazon Comm.
And what do you look up? Wang Poe or
what?
>> I guess so. Under books.
>> Oh,
all right.
>> Go ahead. You got the microphone.
>> She just said she didn't really have a
question.
>> Yeah, no question, I guess.
>> Oh, all right.
>> I just wanted to hang out with you for a
little bit.
>> Oh, I see.
>> So, you want to talk about something
else?
>> Okay. Thank you, honey.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> All right. Now, I see what they're up
to. I don't know where where where are
they getting these books. They've been
off out of sale for years.
>> Oh, this is signed by Lionus Paul.
That's a signed copy.
>> Whose book is that?
>> That guy over there.
>> This is not working where I cannot see
who I'm talking to or about. No good.
>> That's his book.
>> I can't see him anyway. I forget.
>> Yes.
>> Got a couple books for you right here.
>> Okie dokie.
>> And I do have a question for you as
well.
>> Front of my eyes. That's helps a lot.
I'm wondering if the u uh kind of line
of treatment I have lined out for myself
is for the highest good and if you could
check on that
>> line of treatment that he has lined up
>> for my ailment.
>> Are these your books?
>> These are mine right here. Yeah, I have
to
Okay.
Okay. You want to check on his whether
the line of treatment he has?
>> We have permission to ask this for the
high in the name of the highest good. In
the name of the highest good. the line
of treatment that he's lined up for
himself is appropriate to the illness
would be helpful and would be helpful to
the illness. Is this
>> good news?
>> Mhm.
>> And um I'm wondering also if the the
research I want to do with kinesiology
and um the iris is is the for the
highest good.
>> The research you're going to do with
kinesiology
>> and the iris. Yes.
>> And the iris.
>> Yeah. developing glasses for doing that.
>> Oh,
I'm not clear on the question. He's
doing research on something for the
iris.
>> He's doing research on the iris and he
wants to develop glasses for this
>> doing kinesiology.
>> Doing kinesiology that this project he's
working on. Okay. This is a We have
permission to ask this. This is a
plausible project. Resist. Yes.
Plausible.
>> Yep.
>> Very good. Thank you so much.
>> Let me get a picture.
>> Hello.
>> Plausible versus a plausible. Huh.
Yeah.
>> Hello.
>> Hi.
>> I have one one question.
And there are there's a group of 20 or
more of us here from a spiritual
community.
>> From where?
>> From a spiritual community.
>> Spiritual. I thought you said
Bridgeport, Connecticut.
It is my Cuban accent.
And the question is um
is um is this like a beginning of a new
uh rising in our work internal work?
It's a beginning of
>> I don't get what the qu what the
question is.
>> Is this a ch like an opening or a
>> right? Is this um
>> what is happening to us now at this
moment?
>> What is happening to you?
>> Yes. At this moment in our lives is it
one step um
>> and what kind of things are you
referring to happening to you?
>> Just the internal evolution changes
happening.
>> Changes happening.
>> Yes.
>> Are they supportive of your evolution?
>> Yeah. The changes in their life are
supportive of their spiritual evolution.
Resist.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Then we thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> I'm glad we got a favorable answer.
Think you weren't on your way down the
tubes or something
kind of thing.
Yes.
>> Hello.
>> My question is um that I was abused as a
child and I want to learn how to balance
trust and fear.
>> What's being abused as a child got to do
with it?
>> Uh because it's a um
it breaks trust.
>> Yes. Well, you've had time to overcome
it, right?
>> Well, I still have these patterns in my
life.
>> She has certain patterns in her life
that keep
>> Yeah. Are they solo patterns or patterns
that involve other people?
>> Involve other people.
All your relationships turn out to be
disastrous. Is that it?
>> Not relationships.
>> Huh?
Not just uh not personal relationships,
just interactions.
>> How does it happen? You get on a subway
and everybody's rude to you. No,
>> I mean, what is it about? That's too
general.
>> Okay. I don't know um
whether to trust or to be cautious of
situations and and people.
So you're lacking discernment. You can't
tell which is which. Yes. Huh?
>> Yes. Exactly.
>> Yeah.
Well, I would sp pray for spiritual
guidance in the matter and ask for a
miracle in the matter
that that you need discernment to tell
what is dangerous and what is. So what
you don't know is what you're projecting
onto the world.
>> Do you know how to do kinesiology on
your own?
>> I have tried. Yes.
because you could use kinesiology to
diagnose situations
>> just like we did with the uh Olympic
games, you know, we calibrate. What is
the level of the Olympic games? You
know,
>> so is it safe or not safe? So, you might
just ask safe versus not safe for you.
>> Mhm.
>> Is this safe for me versus not safe?
Yeah.
>> Okay. And
>> you can't tell the difference.
You have a counselor. You have somebody
you consult with.
>> Yes.
>> So you have a an impairment of reality
testing. Is that so? Yeah,
>> I guess so.
>> Are you are you getting better with it?
>> Well, it's it's quite recent.
>> What's quite recent understanding?
>> What's quite recent?
Uh it's a recent understanding with this
uh of the cause of a of a pattern of
behavior.
>> Oh, it's a recent understanding. So she
just learned about it that she has this
pattern of behavior.
>> Oh, I see.
>> So she, you know, she's just wondering
if
>> So you and you have a therapist you're
working on this. Okay. And you know how
to do the O-ring on yourself. So you can
So between the therapy, the therapist
self-standing and and testing it out by
muscle testing, you should have pretty
good guidance, wouldn't you say?
>> I guess so. Yes.
>> You can't look. I mean, there's no
guarantees in this world. There's just
only likelihoods.
There's only likelihoods and
propensities,
but because of free will, etc.,
Everything is primarily a tendency, a
proclivity, not necessarily an absolute.
Like you're using all the things that
man has learned.
What more can you do? That sounds pretty
good to me.
>> Thank you.
>> Sounds pretty good to me that you're
doing all you can do.
>> Thank you.
Yeah, she's doing what you can do within
the
possibilities of the human domain.
>> I I just want to hold your hand for a
minute.
>> Would that be okay?
>> Yes.
>> What does this say here?
>> Um, this is in
>> What is the title there? What language
is that?
>> I don't know.
>> What language is this? Are those your
books? Oh, they're not her books.
>> What language?
>> How would you know?
>> Romanian. This is the Romanian.
>> Oh, the Romanian. Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> No wonder. Yes.
>> Did you sign this one? I can't.
>> All the books are translated into all
the world's major languages.
It's translated into languages I never
even heard of.
Uh
>> yes.
>> Hello.
>> So I I have a question. Um
recently I I've started to understand or
experience my spirit leaving my body but
not completely kind of flying out the
top of my head and then something
catches it and it comes back in again.
>> Yeah. Leaving the body but reluctantly.
Huh.
>> Yeah.
still giving one toe hold on right
>> the physical body. Yeah.
>> So um and I I noticed that there I think
there's been a pattern of it since I was
a child like through uh anxiety and
stressful situations at home that I
would I would leave
>> the body.
>> Uhhuh.
>> But I didn't recognize it as that when I
was a child.
>> Yes. Um, so
>> some people have it only just before
they fall fall asleep sometimes.
Yeah.
>> Is it fine?
>> Is it okay?
>> Yes, it's okay.
>> It's okay.
>> Yeah.
>> You can leave the body when you like.
>> Can you leave it completely and come
back in or
>> Yep.
>> You can go out and have a good time,
come back home.
>> Yeah.
Can I meet you someplace?
>> Huh?
>> Yes, it's possible to leave the body and
by agreement meet other people in other
dimensions.
In fact, uh there's a course taught in
the east
uh journeys out of the body.
>> Monroe Institute can teach you how to do
that at will, how to leave the body at
will and return at will.
It's lots of fun.
>> Yeah.
I'd also just like to thank you really
very much for your love and presence and
guidance and efforts and
bearing all your ailments throughout the
years
being here today with us.
>> Yes, you can study uh atro institute
>> and I think I think there's a home
course now you can buy on DVDs or CVDs
or whatever they call those discy
things.
>> Disy things.
>> Yeah. You go into an altered state, you
can leave the body and explore things
and come back in the body, you know.
Mhm.
>> Uh oh. I'll see you there then.
>> Well, you see, you're in control of it.
What you're afraid of is not being in
control of it.
>> But if you learn how to do it at will,
then you're not afraid because you can
choose to return anytime you want.
So, how how would I learn to not be
afraid of it?
>> I explain to you. You take you do
the training. I explained to you because
you're in control of it. You're not
afraid of it because nothing happens
without your without your okay. Nothing
happens unless you okay it
what you're afraid of is loss of
control. Lots of control. But if you're
controlling it, then you're not afraid
of losing. So,
>> how did where do you get these pictures?
My god,
>> someone brought those.
>> I don't know.
>> I think you can download them from your
>> Oh, probably from our website.
>> All right.
>> Okay. Well, thank you.
>> Look into it. You got a computer at
home?
>> Yes.
>> You know how to look up what I told you?
Mhm.
>> Look it up and follow what they have to
say.
>> Okay.
>> You don't have to travel there anymore.
Apparently, they've got it available on
on discs, you know, and you can learn
all their states of consciousness
and you can leave the body at will and
either travel or stay home.
>> Save on plane fairs.
>> Yeah, you can travel or you can just
stay at home.
>> All right.
>> Stay in the kitchen.
the kitchen.
>> Well, wherever you feel safe in the
house, you know,
>> the bed in that kitchen.
>> I don't know. This doesn't write very
well on this.
>> I know this
>> plastic slicks things.
>> Yes. Okay.
>> Got it.
>> Yes.
>> Hello.
>> I don't know if I will be able to answer
the question correctly. To ask to ask
the question correctly.
Um you talk a lot quite a bit about uh
praying and
>> about what?
>> Praying.
>> Yeah.
>> And God and uh trusting.
>> How how do you do that? How do I do
that? How
>> I don't know what praying is. And
>> you don't know what praying means?
>> I don't know how to do it. I don't know.
>> Where you lived on some other planet
when you were young?
Maybe I I I don't have a religious uh
>> She doesn't have a religious background.
>> What culture were you brought up in?
>> I I am from Argentina.
>> From Argentina,
>> it is a Catholic country, but I didn't
have a
>> a spiritual background.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Okay. You know, when you you
pray, you uh
you uh ask God for his presence that you
wish to address him and you address your
communications to God
and uh
and then you say, "Amen."
>> Yes. I I guess I knew that much.
>> Um
>> it's really quite simple. You don't have
to go to school to learn how to pray.
>> But I guess
>> dear God, let me just win this game
period.
>> I know. I mean, maybe it's obvious, but
I guess praying to what or to
um what are you praying to? and and he
don't want of course he don't want I
don't want to pray for myself but so to
>> he he once you take him through how do
you pray
how do you pray
>> or to what
>> what do you ask what do you ask
>> help or do you you know how do you pray
>> or to what do you pray I mean what is
this
>> you never went to church
>> I've been there but
>> yeah what did you do while you were in
church daydream or what?
>> I was trying to to experience
>> the whole congregation prays together in
church.
You know the Lord's prayer. Do you know
the Lord's prayer?
>> Not completely.
>> Well, learn it completely and then after
that maybe the doorway will open for you
to pray.
>> Um David likes the Yeah.
>> 21st Psalm.
>> Well, that's too complicated. The the
Lord's Prayer. Start that.
And when you get it down perfectly, the
way to other prayer will open up.
Okay.
>> One, two, three. Can you do one, two,
three?
>> Well, let's just say the Lord's prayer
right now.
>> No, no, no.
>> Okay. Here.
>> All right. We'll do it.
>> All right.
>> You know how to say the Lord's Prayer.
I don't believe it's from this planet.
>> Our Father, who all do it,
>> be thy name.
>> Thy kingdom come, thy will be done on
earth as it is in heaven.
>> Give us this day our daily bread. And
forgive us our trespasses
>> as we forgive our trespasses.
>> Oh, the trespass.
from us all evil. For thine is the
kingdom and
>> the power and the glory forever and
ever. Amen.
>> There you got it. Forever.
Okay.
Thank you.
I can't sign this.
>> Try.
>> Hello.
>> Yes.
>> Try that. Try to sign it because we
don't have the felt pin.
>> Okay.
>> I have an attraction towards um
continuously surrendering uh processing
things out in a continuous fashion. Do
you have what an attraction to
constantly surrendering what
>> I guess intent?
>> I don't see anybody's saying.
>> I'm sorry.
>> What is it?
>> I find that I'm often surrendering
intent like surrendering to the p
just surrendering and allowing things to
be and in doing so processing things
out.
>> Good.
Sometimes it seems as if I need to
energize a prayer.
>> Yeah.
>> But that to do so is very dualistic from
the surrender.
>> Yeah. Letting go of a thing doesn't
require any mentation. It's just a
willingness.
>> Willingness to surrender it. Yes.
>> What about the willingness to surrender
to allow to pray?
surrender. What
>> it's like there's an aversion towards
>> praying separately from the surrender.
towards playing accept
>> as in um
it seems like to energize a a specific
individual to pray uh to say oh Lord
please help me seems to bring up a huge
amount of aversion and that to do so
would be actually abandoning the grace
um which is supporting the surrender
>> I don't Understand?
>> Okay.
>> All prayer is good.
>> Do you know do you know how to let a
thing go?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So that's the essence of it is
really the willingness to let it go.
Not to control what happens after you
let it go.
You let it go. You let it go.
You don't say around to tailor it. Yes.
>> What do you say?
>> That simple. Yeah.
>> When you ask a prayer and you said that
it's called something, you have a name
for it. Um when you want this
specifically to have it, you you call it
um
>> Well, no, I don't I mean that's I'm not
interested in that. But there's there's
an aversion towards um praying um like
oh Lord please help me. It seems as if
that is pulling me away from just
surrendering and allowing things to be
and
>> well then surrender without praying
about it. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> It just sometimes it seems like I have
to cover both sides of the coin if that
makes sense.
>> No.
>> Okay. Good. Good. Just making sure.
Thank you. Okay.
>> No. He goes, "No."
>> He wants to let it go and not let it go
at the same time.
>> Yeah. It's hard for him to let it go.
>> Hi.
>> Uhhuh.
>> You mentioned that um you need uh to
have a calibrated level of consciousness
of around 600 to achieve a level of
discernment.
and also that we've all been programmed
and we're all extremely
gullible.
Um, so my question is
what is it that
I can trust within myself?
You can trust that how you are seeing
and interpreting a thing
is how you are seeing and interpreting a
thing.
That way you disappear it.
You know, you disappear it
because by naming it, you're
disappearing it. And
you ask God to reveal the essence and to
remove the illusion of perception. Yeah.
You're trying to see beyond perception
to essence. And you ask God's help to
reveal it to you.
That's part that's part of the ritual of
the course of miracles, too. You asked
to see beyond appearance to the essence,
the reality behind it. Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> It's one of the things you learn by
doing kind of becomes easier and easier
and more automatic.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
Hello. It's my um first time here and um
I flew all the way from Poland. I felt a
very strong magnetic pull to come here
and um I understand from you know one
point of view there's a lot of questions
that I could ask but then I don't really
have any questions. I just wanted to
thank you so much both of you.
>> All right. Thank you very much
sweetheart.
>> Thank you. Uh from Warso. Warso.
>> I've never been in Poland. Yep.
>> Thank you.
>> Where I grew up, Wonky, they brought
part of Poland over and planted in
Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
>> I love Polish sausage.
>> Yeah, I love Polish.
I love Polish weddings.
>> Polish weddings.
>> Yeah. Gone for four days. Polit for four
days.
>> Four days.
>> Three days here.
>> Three days.
>> All right. Here.
>> All right. Thank you, dear. Yeah. Thank
you for coming from Poland. a long way.
>> Thank you.
>> Hello.
>> Um I have one question. Um
do you think uh I can just read your
book and video and for for my work or do
I still need to find a spiritual teacher
to guide me? What is she asking?
>> Can she just read our books and and look
at our videos? Yeah.
>> Or should she find a spiritual teacher
to guide her also?
>> Oh, I think she ought to just study
first. Usually the first steps is to
study and become familiar with the the
vocabulary and the concepts
and because you wouldn't know what
teacher to pick. I would I would first
be a student and learn what you can
about spirituality and the various
spiritual pathways etc. First learn all
you can learn and then they say when the
student is ready the teacher appears.
So it's too early to pick out a teacher
at this level you know.
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
Hi.
>> Hi.
>> Yes.
>> Um, I'm hoping you can uh help. Um, I've
got a bit of a dilemma actually which
I'm hoping you could solve for me. Uh,
but I've got to pre give you
>> He's too close.
>> Too close. Oh,
>> I listen to your videos and everyone's
too far away so when I come up here. Um,
>> but
>> yeah. Uh but uh anyways, I've read all
of your books. Uh they're phenomenal. Uh
I'm in the process of trying to become
enlightened. I know I don't have a say
in that. Uh but there's continually
surrendering and uh getting below the
thoughts and not thinking. Uh on the
other hand, um I have some studying
requirements. I'm in the process of
doing a thesis uh which in my mind
requires studying and basically
reloading the mind. And I was wondering
if you could give me some advice on how
to basically balance those two. There
are two different tasks with with two
different goals.
The writing you say you're doing
writing?
>> Uh, no thesis. Yes.
>> What?
>> He's doing a thesis.
>> A thesis. So I'm studying. And
>> so the intention of the thesis is
academic.
>> Yes.
>> All right. And then what is the other
thing you're worried about? Setting the
spiritual reality.
>> Try trying to become enlightened.
>> They're not trying two different
processes. But I thought they were sort
of conflicting in that it
>> No, they're just two different levels.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. The intellectual is in the 400s
and the spiritual is 500 and up.
>> Oh, okay. Well, I knew that, but
>> yeah. So, you can be both at the same
time.
>> Okay.
>> You can be smart, educated, and also
holy.
I guess right now one of one out of
three isn't bad. So,
Now people often wonder is there a
conflict between spiritual and
intellectual?
Reason is supposed to reinforce faith
and faith is supposed to illuminate
reason.
>> Yeah.
>> Hello. I uh I'm interested in choosing a
career path and uh earlier you touched
on the subject of whether or not a job
you know is this a good job and you know
you talked about being precise and uh
good in what way. I was just wondering
if it would be an appropriate question
to ask whether or not well to make a
list of possible career choices and then
ask uh
>> sure
>> if the list if uh the one was on the
list you know the one that was the most
um the best use of my talents and the
that served the highest good would that
be an appropriate question to ask. So
you look yes of course and you can use
kinesiology
you look at your area of interest and uh
then you can ask which would be the best
pathway for you at this time in your
life you know which may be different
than a later time.
>> Okay.
>> So I'd say at this time in my life it
would be most advantageous
to follow and then you can pick which
ones seem to stand out to you as
meaningful.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> You bet.
Hi.
>> Would you sign this please?
>> Mhm.
>> My question is I try to teach my
children right from wrong. But it seems
that with that sometimes you go into
positionality and judgmentalism. So, I
want them to know which things are good
and which things are not, but not to
then go and say, "Oh, that's bad." Do
you see what I mean?
It feels like a little bit of a cont.
>> You want to teach them right from wrong,
but you don't want them to get into
calling things wrong.
>> Yeah. And
>> at the same time, you're teaching them
right from wrong.
>> Yes.
>> So, uh,
how about good and not so good?
Some things are gooder than others.
>> Yeah. I I feel like society sends lots
of really wrong messages through the
media and just examples you see. So I
feel a real strong need to counteract
that and and to be strong with what I
tell them.
>> There there again comes duality,
positionality, and judgmentalism. See
what I mean?
>> Labeling it right and wrong or good or
bad. And it's still either way you do
it, it's still right and wrong and good
and bad. And it's not it's not you're
not influencing by telling them this is
good and this is bad. You're not
influencing them.
>> I sometimes see them
>> being judgmental a little bit.
>> Then they need to then then depends on
what they're judgmental about. If they
decide they're not going to watch this
program,
>> that's good.
>> Especially if it has nudity in it,
>> right? But but if if they're watching,
you know, cartoons and there's violence.
I mean, you know,
>> Yeah. I've I've come to a place where
I'm trying to be um like sometimes I'll
say to them, they'll say, "Look at that,
Mom." And I'll say, "Yeah, but that's
okay cuz they can do that if they want
to." I mean, it's okay for them to be
that.
>> But isn't that what they are? I mean,
isn't that all they are?
>> We as parents have to set the boundaries
for our children. It has to be clear.
behavioral bond.
>> Forget about being judgmental.
>> Stop being judgmental.
>> Okay?
>> You better be judgmental.
>> Okay? But but as an adult and and a
spiritual student, I'm supposed to to
work towards that.
>> Well, they they have to have the basics
first.
>> So, forget about it when you're a kid.
>> Forget about post-graduate school when
you're still getting through grade
school. So,
>> okay.
>> They got to know right from wrong.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you. That's what we have jails
from. You know, they were never taught
right from wrong.
>> I just want them to be tolerant and
compassionate.
>> Wait until they're older.
>> Well, it's also right or wrong regarding
your own behavior or behavior of others.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> Exactly. I have no qualms.
>> Hi.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
>> I would like to uh thank you for all of
your teachings and everything that you
are. and I just wanted to come here to
see if I could get your blessing on the
spiritual path.
>> God bless you on the spiritual path.
Amen.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Yes.
>> Hello. May I shake your hand?
>> Thank you very much for all of your
work. Mhm.
>> My question has to do with uh I notice
that when I have some interactions with
other individuals
that um occasionally I have some
thoughts which arise which are unbidden
and are totally inappropriate for the
situation.
>> How do you mean appropriate? Socially
expressed or internally unexpressed?
uh internally unexpressed.
>> Then why do you call it inappropriate
>> and well
yeah the the the other part is is that
occasionally there have been times when
I've actually acted out on those
thoughts.
>> Yeah.
And um I'm just wondering if you might
have some insight into that because
>> No, because I don't know whether they're
correct thoughts or incorrect thoughts
or whe they're sort of psychotic
thoughts or I mean what kind of thoughts
are you talking about?
>> Well, it it uh situationally
inappropriate. For example, I might uh
be talking to somebody and um you know,
I might say to myself internally, a
thought completely unbidden would arise.
Yeah. Would say
>> um I'm thinking of an example here. Um
>> this guy's an idiot is what you're
thinking.
>> Well, sometimes. Yeah. might be like an
idiot.
>> And what is your question? Is it okay to
say it? I wouldn't say it. No.
>> Well, no. Right.
>> Spend your life in court.
>> Right. Right. So, I I guess that's uh
>> Now, we learn how to screen our impulses
and screen our thoughts. Well, I guess,
you know, I I I think I'm having a
slight realization about this is that
>> could it be narcissism that would want
me to express
something like that?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Sure.
>> So, almost as if it were
>> you wanted to know what you think and
feel like, who cares?
>> Yeah.
>> You know, get a blog. Go on those. Get a
blogger.
Get a blog site.
>> This guy's an idiot. This guy's a son of
a [ __ ] and I hate this guy and this
guy's
they just go off, you know, the deep
end, you know.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, you can have good time blog
yourself in your face
>> or not.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Now you don't have to express, you know,
your own
weird thoughts about the thing.
Yeah, you can disqualify them because uh
you know a large part of the mind is
ambivalent about everything. See,
you eat a sandwich, you say that's a
great sandwich, now you feel guilty that
you ate the sandwich. You know what I'm
saying? It's like the mind never lets
you alone. So, you have to learn how to
live with it. You know, everybody's sort
of ambivalent about their own mind most
of the time
because the mind is always forcing you
to make a choice out of a variety of
thoughts. You know, you've got to pick
one of them to either feel, express,
validate, or dismiss as, you know, not
too well,
>> not really well,
>> right? And
>> crazy thought.
Yeah. And to have
>> irrational thoughts. So the the
unconscious comes up with a a stream of
>> irrational thoughts and symbolisms and
primitivisms
and as you get older you those get
screened out. You dismiss them
progressively. They weaken and
disappear.
>> I see. Thank you very much.
bring greetings from Gary and Maria.
>> Oh,
>> from Camel Canada, British Columbia
>> and they said to say hi, send their
love.
>> Yes.
>> And uh my question like earlier you were
talking about spiritual guides and I was
wondering what what you refer to as
spiritual guides.
>> You're wondering what
>> what what you mean when you refer to
spiritual guides? It would mean uh the
feeling as though there is an entity
friendly and privy to your interest who
is interested in guidance like a spirit
spirit energy spiritual energy.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. That's what I thought. I just
wanted to clear that up. Thank you very
much.
>> Thank you.
People
call them guardian angels. You know the
guardian angels.
>> Hi. Yeah. Um I just want to thank you
for your work and great joy that you've
brought to my life.
>> Um thank you and um thank you for all
the support that you give us all.
>> Thank you.
>> Um it's very overwhelming to be here. Um
uh my question oh sorry
um my question or uh one of the things I
wonder about is a question of how to
trust or have faith. You say that when
we have heard of enlightenment then
we're guaranteed to evolve and reach
towards enlightenment. Um
and so so it's guaranteed. But how much
um does becoming enlightened rely on how
much we do good work or how much we
release our guilt and our
>> allse
it's a
all of it together it's a in mathematics
you know it's the
the output the final output after all
the positives and negatives and
everything have been entered in.
So just the fact that we know of
enlightenment now means we've earned the
right to become more evolved
or this it's important to keep releasing
the guilt and and feel worthy of
achieving it.
>> Don't worry about the achievement. Just
worry about the pathway.
>> If you're on the pathway of spiritual
evolution, that's sufficient. Yeah.
>> Okay.
to be on the pathway. All that's
important is whether you're on the
pathway and then the rest of it is due
to a multitude of factors.
>> Okay, great. Uh thank you and if I could
receive your blessing.
>> Yeah, commitment to a spiritual
pathway in your life is all it requires.
The rest takes care of itself.
Okay.
>> Thank you again.
Yes.
>> Boom.
Boom.
>> Oh, that was a flash.
>> That's a big
>> Mr. Bobblehead.
My question is uh how do people go about
disassembling and relinquishing
attachments after they've identified
them?
>> Oh, what is this?
>> How do people go about disassembling
attachments once they have identified
them?
>> Well, you can ask yourself
Uh do you want to let go of this
attachment? And then what is the
attachment to? Uh what chakra is it
appealing to? For one thing, see as
you're a young man.
>> Excellent.
you you'll find you're not attached to
people that you consider to be ugly.
>> Well, that's true.
So, the the desiraability is a
projection.
The energy field of glamour is projected
and that person becomes bigger than
normal, bigger than life.
And then when the attachment is over,
they become diminish in importance and
no longer that significance in life.
Yes. So you can live like you couldn't
live with without a certain relationship
and a decade later you can't remember
what the person's name was.
So just be aware that that is the nature
of human
species, you know.
>> Excellent. Thank you.
The patient said to me, I can't I just
couldn't live without what's her name.
>> It's Susan.
>> Okay.
>> Hi. Um you talk about level 500 as being
a major barrier. Um
>> not a barrier.
level. It demarcates a different level,
but it's not a barrier. Yeah.
>> Between rationality and the higher
spiritual levels. You say that most
people don't cross it.
>> Oh, yes. Well, that's true. The cons the
level of consciousness of mankind is at
what is it? I forget. No, it's all
depressing when I think of
>> 204.
>> 204. Yeah. Yeah. So, yeah. So a certain
percentage, a smaller and smaller
percentage as you go up the scale of
consciousness,
you include a smaller and smaller
percentage of mankind
from 500 and up. You saw we projected it
on the screen this morning, the graph.
>> So from 500 up and then it diminishes
diminishes down to just only a very few
from 600 and up. Sometimes none of 600
and over. Well, my question, I guess,
then is I'm I'm a pretty rational person
and I'm if I'm not going to be able to
figure out how to get there from here, I
I was wondering if you could recommend a
practice to help transcend that level
from rationality to the higher levels.
>> All spiritual work is designed to
support the evolution. All spiritual
work is designed and uh its intention
and purpose is to reach higher levels of
truth and awareness through prayer,
through forgiveness, through meditation,
through attending church services, to
mantras.
They are all designed to advance one's
level of consciousness. Yes. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> All of them are meant towards the
ultimate goal. goal. Yes.
All of them help.
And you don't know which one's going to
be the most important. You see,
because for some people, when you put
this brick in the wall, then the wall
stands. And other people, you take out
that brick and the wall falls. So,
there's no way of absolute knowing which
of the techniques or capacities
are playing a dominant part.
Generally, you can go you go with what
you're attracted to. You're attracted
and you feel comfortable and you feel
you belong there.
>> Yeah.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you that I could come up here.
I'm involved with a method um a healing
method which is not very well known in
the world but I think it has a very
great potential but because it is the
only one to my knowledge which found
ways to trace back a place where the
onset of the dysfunction is stored so
you can actually have a connection
between what happened some memories of
the past which are stored in physical
body
>> stop a second stop a second
>> are we doing a commercial here
>> no no I want I I want to know whether
following this path. I have been very
much involved that with that because I
think it has a big potential put a lot
of energy of my life in that and I would
like to know whether this is a good path
to follow or not because it has not been
develop developing to the the way I
wanted it.
>> Do you know what she's asking?
>> It's a method that she's been involved
with and she wants to know if she should
she should continue practicing this
method.
>> It's worthwhile going for it or should I
drop it?
>> Well, do you feel a benefit from it?
Yes, it just
>> then why are you asking the question?
>> Because uh uh it does not evolve. I I do
not find students who want to learn it
and uh it does not evolve the way I
would like to in relation to the effort
which I put in and I just think it might
be
>> you're making what is the question?
I don't get what the question is. You
got a method and it's working. So what
is your complaint?
>> I would like more people to benefit from
it. So I would
>> Oh, you want to inflict your will upon
them and get them to do the same thing,
right?
>> That's what you're up to.
>> And I'd rather like Okay.
>> You're trying to sign them up for
something that you find favorable and
beneficial. And although that may be a
good thing,
it's not 100% pure.
>> Okay.
Thank you.
>> Yeah.
You have mixed goals. Mixed goals. See,
you're mixing goals.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you for everything.
I want to ask um
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay.
Um I want to ask that uh and some of
more of people are here uh who actually
follow this uh this teaching and my
question is is that uh he made a
decision today uh for one of my friends
who's in this school to not come back
uh because
>> tell me what he said so far.
>> He said
a friend of his made a decision not to
come back. Come back where
>> no
>> this spiritual teacher we are following
>> the spiritual teacher they're following
>> who we are following
>> who they are following
>> yes you and somebody else are following
some spiritual teacher yes so what is
the question now
>> and and he made the decision that he was
not he didn't want to come back for that
>> his yeah the friend could not
>> decided against it yeah what about
>> I want to know if his uh his decision
was based on on on truth truthly just
based on his
>> I don't get the question
>> not all not all spiritual teachers are
for everybody.
Um
people he he's asking his friend he
wants to know if his if his decision not
to come back was or not to
>> he's not allowed to come back.
>> He's not allowed to come back
>> to this teaching
>> to this particular teaching if that was
I'm confused.
>> What is he stealing money from poor
children or what?
>> Not allowed to come back.
>> He's following a teacher. You and him
are both following this.
>> All right. And then he he got through
his own
mind.
>> Well, he said that by by coming here uh
we are interfering with his direction
and so I didn't he didn't say it in
these words. He didn't say
>> by by your group coming here or or
>> Yes. Yes.
>> that that you were interfering with his
direction. We don't interfere with
anyone's direction.
I come up here because uh I would like
to ask it for all of them but I actually
don't know how to ask the question
correctly.
>> Well,
>> anybody knows
>> what is the
>> the spiritual teacher who we've been
following for many years who some people
have left the group has banned students
coming here saying that it's a wrong
direction which is clearly not. So I
guess they're looking for some
affirmation that this is the right
direction.
>> I see.
What's the question?
>> They're they are all following a certain
spiritual teacher.
>> Who is they?
>> This group that has come here.
>> Oh, there's a whole group here.
>> Oh, I didn't know that.
>> Put your hands up here.
>> And they and they are.
>> Okay. Where are they from?
>> Where are you from?
>> I'm from Holland.
>> All over.
>> But they're Yes. This teaching is uh all
over the world, but
>> um here they are most they live in
California,
>> right? and I live in Holland right now.
So,
>> well,
>> so what is the question? I still don't
get what is the question.
>> Well, they're saying this this
particular teacher is saying that coming
here would interfere with their pathway
uh that he has them on, I guess.
>> Oh, it's a threat to the teacher.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh,
what pathway? In as much as we don't
have any particular pathway, how did
this interfere? You know, you just
calibrate what's the level of the
highest truth and you follow the highest
truth. How does that interfere?
>> How does that interfere?
>> He doesn't know.
>> I don't think it interferes, but
>> I don't understand.
>> Um well, they
>> it puts some spiritual teachers noses
out of joint when he heard that they
were coming to hear these lectures. For
one thing, we calibrate the level of
consciousness of all the teachers. And
there's a number of teachers that are
not at all pleased by that problem, that
problem that creates.
Some are not even at 200. You see what I
mean? They have many followers. So that
doesn't even
So if I was a teacher whose integrity
was in doubt, I would wouldn't want you
running here either.
What you do is you learn how to
calibrate to calibrate the level of the
teacher and then have it affirmed by
others. You see,
>> but that's his fear.
>> What?
>> That's what this teacher is fearing that
we're going to calibrate.
>> Well, I'm not worried about the teacher.
That's his problem. I'm talking about
the students. It's the students that
hear, not the teacher.
>> You're responsible for your own
spiritual destiny.
Is this teacher going to appear and
speak in your behalf before the father?
>> I don't think so.
>> I don't hope so.
>> Will this teacher speak for you before
Almighty God that I have led them in
this direction? Oh Lord,
>> no.
Then what do you want with a teacher
like that
who won't eat the bread that he bakes
himself?
If you can't If you won't eat the bread
that you bake yourself, you shouldn't be
a cook.
What is it Jesus Christ promises to be
before the father? I will be your what?
Blank
>> advocate. Advocate. Right. Yes. Okay.
No, a spiritual teacher must be
responsible and be willing to appear
before God and take the responsibility
that I have taught them this out of my
best intention. And if I am incorrect, I
pray for forgiveness. Oh Lord, you have
to take responsibility as a teacher.
So never follow a teacher who doesn't
take responsibility, accountability for
what you have taught.
So we could in a sense calibrate his
intention with this decision this
morning.
>> So that's what you I would say you know
calibrate it amongst yourselves until
you're satisfied and understand why
you're getting that kind of a reading.
>> Yeah. Good.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> I can see the dilemma now. Okay.
>> Right. Yeah.
>> Hello.
>> Hi.
>> My question isn't nearly as deep as
everybody else's. Um, but I was
wondering if it was possible um to
calibrate the level of consciousness of
the two presidential candidates.
I don't know if that's possible or not.
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know who the presidential
candidates are.
>> Are you going to make me say it?
>> One is a wrinkled old man,
white hair,
conservative,
a veteran of but we're a Vietnam war.
He was a prisoner of war. Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> And was severely injured and tortured.
Yes. So the principles that he chose to
live by seemed to be profoundly
important because they were done for
their own sake, not because of some
gain. So he didn't say I choose to live
by this and believe in this because by
doing that I will then become president
of XYZ company. There was no gain to
that. Yeah.
>> So look to see what gain there is by
people's proclamations of what they say
and they believe. You see? Yes. If you
know how to use the the muscle testing
that we use, you'll find out very
quickly which is above 200 and which is
not above 200. Yes.
and advise people to use it on their own
because I don't want to be quoted
>> and within 30 minutes it's going to be
on the internet.
I
>> mean, I can't put that on my blog.
>> No, you leave it off your blog.
>> No, thanks.
>> The Anthony. Yeah.
>> Well, you didn't say anything about the
other candidate.
>> What other candidate?
>> I'm not going there.
Hello.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. I have a question about the course
of miracles.
Um, I've been doing the course of
miracles for about a year, but I'm only
on lesson 230, so
>> that's fast enough.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> I was just asking me if it um
if there is a a lack of benefit if
sometimes I don't do a lesson in a day
or
>> No, that's natural. You you start out
feeling very I must do one every day.
But then you find that some lessons are
more meaningful than others and you want
to spend a couple days really absorbing
that and and really getting the total
meaning of it.
Yeah.
>> All right.
>> Yeah. Take your time.
>> Yeah. Sometimes, you know, you get
stalled and you spend a whole week on
one lesson and
>> and then others don't seem to be as
significant to your life and you move
back to one a day again.
>> Okay.
>> But the course is a lot of fun,
>> isn't it?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. I think the course of mira is a
lot of fun.
>> Thank you.
>> I see nothing as it is. I see only the
past. I mean, wow.
I mean, it's mindboggling. Some of those
things are so mindboggling.
And yeah, thank you.
And we tracked people doing a course of
miracles and we found by lesson 90 or
so, they had transcended the
susceptibility to be negatively
influenced by negative stimuli.
They could look at fluorescent lights
and they no longer went weak. Yes. So
there was a confirmable physiologic
change. Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> I have a question about the will. Uh
from my understanding the personal will
calibrates as high as the personal level
of conscious consciousness and then
there's the divine will. And my question
is, how do I discern subjectively the
experience between both?
>> Yeah. Why would there be a difference?
>> Uh because I
>> Huh.
>> somehow believe I can make a wrong
choice. I can follow the wrong will.
>> Oh. Oh. You're trying to decide what is
aligned with the will of God, right?
>> Oh, yes.
Well, I'd say the higher the higher it
calibrates by using the technique that
we use, the higher it calibrates, the
closer it is aligned with the will of
God as we speak of it abstractly.
>> Yeah. I I cannot calibrate by myself. I
tried, but I
>> Yes.
>> Do you have friends that know how to do
it?
>> No.
>> Good golly.
>> So,
>> I don't know how to tell you your
spiritual education. your spiritual
education.
Uh
what differentiates the two is whether
you you're looking to a thing uh for for
gain or not for gain. See
spiritual progress is progress but it
not it's not necessarily a gain. You
know
>> yes
>> uh gain means you project a
desiraability upon something within the
world and then yearn for it. You see
now spiritual goals are more nonlinear
you know more nonlinear
>> to be the most loving
that you can be to all towards all of
life and all its expressions I mean
that's enough for a lifetime
>> okay that'll keep you busy for a decade
or two
>> even those that don't deserve it.
>> This is sticking around on you.
>> Even those that don't deserve it. That's
a funny one.
>> I forgive them all. Even the ones who
don't deserve it.
>> Yeah.
>> I just wanted to thank you and ask for
your blessing.
>> Yes. And I also uh I've been trying to
practice the being like kindness and
lovingness to to all things and all
people in my daily life in a routine.
And um I guess I found myself people
pleasing a lot in a way that is
>> oh yeah
>> maybe I'll be I'll be with somebody and
trying to uh just be kind and see the
essence and innocence and love it and at
the same time when I'm they're not
receptive to that I will become
uncomfortable and become
>> I'll I'll purposely drop to a maybe a
lower level of consciousness to make
them comfortable and then I stay in that
level and feel shame about it and uh and
I also see if you had any advice
>> well do do a spiritual practice for its
own sake not because of the consequences
not because of the payoff
do it for its own sake
if God says you love everything that's
green
you just love everything that's green
you don't look for consequences okay
so I wouldn't look for some kind of a
significance or consequence or an
additional meaning. You do a thing for
its own sake because it's a basic
spiritual dictim.
Yeah.
>> And so if I am with somebody and I get a
negative response from being to to being
there with them and loving who they are,
stay with it. Stay with that state of
being instead of uh accommodating a
different uh intent from them.
I don't get the question.
>> And so, so
>> he's being loving towards somebody and
now he's being coming now he gets
judgmental about it. But what if that
person doesn't what? Respond.
>> Yeah.
>> You don't you can't look for a response.
Payoff.
>> Yeah.
>> No, no, you're just loving towards the
little toad because he's there.
>> And the toad is not going to kiss you.
You know, kiss a toad.
We got little toads behind our house and
we just go out and and love them.
But they still are toads.
>> Yeah. I don't pick them up because you
might get warts.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Yeah. Shake it into
>> You can play with life through your
child. You know, everybody thinks
they've got to be so serious about
everything. You know, life is
entertaining, hilarious.
I think you need to people need to get
their child up and going. You know, the
child naively, innocently just has a fun
time with life. And we get the uh the
old grandpa and I said, "Oh, you
shouldn't have said that." You know,
uh get more into your child. The child
doesn't you know the child has a certain
you know
>> thank you
>> yes
>> I don't have a question I would just
wanted to spend a moment with you
>> yes
a momentto
>> thank you so much
>> thank
Hello.
>> I'm going to make it quick. I just
wanted to come up and say thank you
person personally for the work and the
wisdom that you put into the world.
>> Thank you for your thanks.
>> Thank you for your feedback and
appreciation.
Hello.
>> I don't have a question. Um,
I'd like to have a moment to simply sit
here and silence with the both of you.
>> Yes.
>> With all this blessed company here
today,
>> the silence is always present.
Don't be confused by the sounds of the
world
behind the you
the only reason you can hear the sounds
of the world is because of the silence.
Silence is always present
and learn to be to listen beyond the
sound and be aware of the silence.
If it weren't for the silence, you
wouldn't be able to hear the sound. You
know what I mean?
So,
because of the noise, you can't hear the
silence. That's the problem. See?
>> Yes.
>> Thank you, Dr. Huckets for hanging
around on this planet and playing your
part so beautifully and helping to raise
the consciousness of all of us.
I have
wow you can get lost in those eyes. Uh
I have an intention
uh to establish a space a physical place
where I want to pursue uh the
facilitating of the experience of peace
for myself and for anyone else that may
choose to
>> and I would like to know if pursuing
this intention would be for the best and
highest good of all.
>> Yes.
Thank you.
>> That which is aligned with and dedicated
to God and the realization of the God.
What more could you ask?
>> Thank you.
>> Yep.
Hello.
>> Wanted to thank both of you and I have a
question. I have this intense energy
running up the left side of my body and
wrapping around my head. And also um
feels like my chakras are misaligned and
it's very painful. And I was wondering
what you would recommend for any relief
or anything that would I've gone to some
12step groups and that has seemed to
help
but I was wondering if there was any.
>> You do yoga exercises.
>> No, I haven't actually. maybe yoga
breathing exercises
and to breathe the energy up the
channels along the around the spine you
know to I would try breathing exercises
if you find a yoga teacher a classical
yoga not an exercise yoga but a real
yoga teacher to assist you in that you
know
>> thank you thank you very much Yes,
>> it's honor honor to be here, sir.
>> Yes.
>> Uh, thanks for everything you do. Uh
uh I'm interested in current events and
I was wondering uh I guess specifically
about the high uh oil and gasoline
prices and uh a little mundane but uh uh
I was just curious about it and uh I
understand um Bill O'Reilly uh
particularly dislikes the uh oil
companies and the market speculators.
Uh, but
>> the president of Shell Oil,
>> the former president of Shell Oil was on
>> what's his name's program? That's
>> O'Reilly.
>> No, not O'Reilly. The other guy.
>> Um, I don't know.
>> Huh?
>> I don't know.
>> No, no, it's not. It's on a different uh
network.
>> All right.
>> Dennis Dennis Beck. Right.
>> Dennis Beck had the former president of
Shell Oil on last night. You can
probably pick up the program off his
website in which he gives a very uh
detailed and authoritative explanation
of the variations in the price of oil
having to do with availability and many
other factors. It's it's not a
simplistic problem. It's relatively
complicated, but I think you can get it
off Glenn Beck has his own thing and you
can get a readout on it. It was the best
explanation I've ever heard. I'm not
that interested in the details. So, I
went off and fed the kitty for a while
and came back and he was still talking
about it,
but it was uh profound and and some kind
of dentist gets real authorities on and
they really go into depth on it on it.
And last night he did or yes I think it
was last night or the night before he
went into great depth. The president of
Shell Oil whose name I cannot remember
gives you the inside view you know
because uh O'Reilly you know thinks that
they're getting great profits the
profits of Shell Oil are something like
6%.
uh in would it help to there was an
exercise and described in one of the
books where you listed all sorts of
different problems and then
>> uh boil it down you I guess meditated
over it and boiled it down to for
example
>> uh overpopulation caused yes you know
all these different uh various problems
would that help in any sort of analysis
like these economic problems or
>> does it help
>> overpopulation is the cause of all the
world's problems, the price of oil,
riots here and there, etc.
Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> I mean, uh,
a productive population is
self-supporting and not a burden to
others. you see and it supports uh
freedom and integrity and industry and
all the things that you know the United
States stands for in at least in theory
you know. Yeah.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Yes.
This is my first time here and I feel
such a great blessing to be in your
presence.
And today I had a question, but today at
lunch I talked with my boyfriend up in
Bend, Oregon who had a question. So I
deferred to his question and his
question is a curiosity of um research
indicates that dreaming is a result of
of stress and having to resolve.
>> Wait a second. Dreaming is what research
indicates that what
>> dreaming
>> resolves the stresses of the day or
conflicts that a person may have. His
question was over
>> well I wouldn't make a broad blanket
comment like that.
>> Okay.
>> It sometimes does depending on the
person depending on their intention.
You will sometimes find the dream
clarifies just as often as it does not.
>> Uhhuh. His question was over the
calibrated level of 600
>> does one need to dream after one attains
enlightenment does the body or the mind
still produce dreaming state or is
sleeping just flat
>> stillness?
>> What is the question?
>> Does anyone in the 600s do they still
have a dream state when sleeping?
Why do you want to know that?
>> Oh, I don't know of any that do. Maybe
they do.
>> Uh
>> I haven't asked anybody over 600 if they
still dream.
>> Anyone still dreams?
>> Uh yeah.
>> Uh
dreams are few and far between. The
older you the more advanced you get,
they they do disappear. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> They do disappear.
Okay, I think that would answer his
question.
>> Sometimes it's a vignette of a thought
form. It's not really your dream. It's a
thought form you picked up while you're
out of body and floating around in the
astral circus.
>> And that just is recognized in the in
the sleep state. Then
>> it's recognized in the sleep state,
>> the thought form that you picked up.
>> Yes. Yes. You may become aware of a a
passing thought form. Especially right
before sleep, you know, hypnogogic
hallucinations occur there. Hypnogogic
hallucinations. You're half awake and
half asleep.
>> And the the sensor the the sensor is the
guard guard is not up yet. So there's a
brief moment there. It's called
hypnogogic state, you know.
>> Okay.
>> Half asleep, half awake.
>> Okay. And may I please shake your hand
and tell you thank you so much.
>> Thank you for thanking me. It's my joy.
Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Good afternoon.
>> Hello.
>> You know we have 20 minutes and there's
still big lights.
>> We have what? 20 minutes or so.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> So, I'm going to try to talk very
quickly. First of all, I'd like to ask
you if I may send your greetings and
your blessings to Penny and Coco.
>> Are they uh
>> the gorilla?
>> Two gorillas.
>> Coco's the gorilla and Penny's the human
scientist that is owned by Coco.
>> Pennies is the scientist.
>> Oh, yes.
>> And Koko's the gorilla.
Oh, I certainly would be happy. And of
course, we've calibrated Coco and Coco
is higher than uh a large percentage of
the human population.
>> That That's what I heard. In fact, I
heard about you because Penny and her
sister Jenny knew about you and that
Koko is in the book. So, I'm very
delighted to have the opportunity to
meet you.
>> Yes, Koko is the consciousness.
Koko is if I remember correctly, what is
Koko Calbert? something.
>> Forget now.
>> 405.
>> Yeah, Koko understands.
>> Oh, Koko really understands.
>> Understands and does by sign language.
>> Yes. I
>> And what I would thought was when he
said sweet soft kitty, good good kitty.
I just went, "Oh,
>> well,
>> but not all the kitties are good."
>> Well, not all kitties are good kitties.
>> Well, I every time I talk to Penny, I
ask her to tell me a Coco story. And I
know you're short on time. Can I share
real quick one? Yeah. Well, um I was
talking to Penny and I said, "So tell me
a Koko story." And she said, "Oh, well,
just two days ago, a couple of days ago,
I was late coming back from lunch and I
I knew I needed to get back." And she
said, "So when she got back, she went
directly to Coco. And Coco picked up a
sign out of a stack of signs that she
had. And the one she picked up and
showed Penny was I worried.
>> I worry.
>> So to me that meant that she could sort
through English language written on a
stack of papers she could read.
>> Yeah. I worry
>> and that she could understand her
emotions probably better than what some
of us can.
>> Yeah. She picks up the emotion of that
statement
>> and and was able to to
>> convey it. So I was thrilled. I just
love Coco.
>> I think that's wonderful. Oh, I just
>> And yeah, me too. And I'm thrilled that
she brought me to you.
>> She is wonderful.
>> I love Coco.
>> And I do have a question. And I was
going to try to make it very generic and
quick, but I'm here. I'll still try to
talk fast.
>> I have a huge dilemma for in three years
ago, there were eight hurricanes in
Florida. I no longer have a house.
>> Eight hurricanes in Florida.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Eight hurricanes in 14 months.
>> Yes. I no longer have a house or a home.
I have six storage units of dresses and
things. I've been trying to find a place
to live. I need a home. And I try to
live my feet on the path and follow the
highest and greatest good. And so for
three years, I've been having wonderful
opportunities to be with people and
contribute not only to my highest
greatest good, but to theirs. and I'm
tired. I need a home. I need to find a
place to live.
>> Every time it seems as if I ask guides
and guardian angels, I have more than
one and they don't all agree and I get
pulled in half a dozen different
directions. So, is there better method
of finger testing or
>> Sure. Sure.
>> What help? I How do I've tried
pendulums? They don't always give me
>> Well, the highest good. You want to know
what's for your highest good?
>> Where I can go that it will be for
>> Why don't you just go where you want to
go? Well, I tried that. I went,
>> thank you for laughing. I went to
Tennessee to Nashville. I thought,
"Okay, I'm tired of trying to follow the
path." Yeah. of of listening for the
answer. I'm just going to move to
Nashville and I'm going to make it work
and this will be a good thing.
>> Yeah.
>> It fell through very badly in very many
ways. And it was expensive and a
disaster to my heart. Never mind. So, I
decided
>> Nashville, Tennessee. Yeah.
>> I wouldn't advise that.
>> I don't. No, I don't need that. I don't
need that. So now I'm back to following
the path and and you know if if my
guardian angels are arguing about you
know
>> try Prescott.
>> So do you think arm testing I'm kind of
down to two places of
Sedona or Florida? Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> And and I
>> you want to live where the hurricanes
are?
>> No, not really. Which is why I'm not
taking a job in the Grand Cayman Islands
even though I really need a job too.
>> Grand Cayman.
>> That's right. in the path.
>> Oh. Uhhuh.
>> Good job. Hurricanes.
>> Yeah. And they must have a lot of jobs
available in that area.
>> Yeah.
>> The same reason they have them in the
salt mines in Russia. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Don't want that either. No pretty
clothes there.
>> So, arm testing, muscle testing.
>> What
>> a location. I I'm just not getting an
easy direct path to a location and I I
need to be in one place. I' I've now
been four months in Cave Creek. That is
>> Maybe you're asking an impossible
question. What is the question you're
asking?
>> How do I determine that a place?
>> No, no, no. You asked what is for your
highest good.
>> Yes.
>> Period.
>> Okay.
>> Don't give me the rest of the story.
Do I
>> serve your highest good
>> my feet to take me there or do I have to
throw a dart at a map? What's the I've
been looking for three years.
>> Well, you said you came down to two
places. You'd like to
>> You said two places.
>> Yeah.
>> So, what's your problem about it? I
don't get it.
>> I I can't determine whether it's again
another Nashville. It's of my own mind
or it's the highest and greatest good.
>> Have you ever asked if it's the highest?
She's afraid to make a decision for fear
it'll be a wrong one.
>> Oh, I've made so many decisions in the
last 3 years and none of them took.
Yeah.
>> Oh, I see. So, you just keep flipping
flopping around the world and nothing
works. Wherever you go,
>> whoever needs me most when I finish what
I'm doing in that next moment, that's
who I go help next. And I need to help
myself be in one place so that I can do
more.
>> So, what is the question now?
How do I make a decision for the highest
and greatest good?
>> Which one is attract? Don't you Why
don't you just pick one that you find
attractive and that makes the arm go
strong? Is a adequate place.
>> Makes my arm go strong. Okay. I've not
had anybody to do muscle testing.
>> Oh, okay. Uh-huh.
All right. Um I don't know what people
do.
>> She's asking about herself, so it's hard
for her to make
>> Yeah. Yeah. What's of my mind?
>> And what does she mean by being happy?
She mean being fulfilled? Does she mean
becoming enriched? Does she mean
becoming educated? Does she mean making
a wonderful relationships?
>> Or you want heaven on earth?
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. Well, you got to wait to get
to heaven on earth.
>> I know. I figured the highest and
greatest good. And I really do want to
contribute.
>> You want to hold the two places in mind?
First one and then the other.
>> Yes.
>> All right.
>> Do one.
>> Let's see. We have permission to help
her with this decision.
Okay, hold the first one in mind.
>> Okay,
>> that location would serve her highest
good. Resist. Okay, now hold the other
location in mind.
>> Okay,
>> that location would hold her highest
good. Resist.
>> Highest good is what you make it.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Not a location. Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> That's the answer.
>> And blessings. And I'm going to send
this photograph to Coco and Penny.
>> Send Coco my greetings.
>> I will for sure. I'll send lots of love.
>> Coco is beautiful and charming.
>> She is.
>> Yeah,
>> she wears pearls.
>> She likes pearls.
She has a pearl necklace and she loves
lacy curtains.
>> Oh, really?
>> Yes.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. I don't have a
question. I just wanted to thank you for
all your work.
>> Yes.
>> And to let you know that you are my
teacher.
>> Thank you.
>> So both places would be adequate.
>> Yeah.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. Thank you so much.
>> Just like to be in your presence and
hold your hand for a moment.
>> Yes. Mhm.
>> Thank you.
So, I was wondering um a lot of my
friends are into this uh Anastasia
thing. I don't know if you've heard of
it, but
>> Anastasia thing. What is that? A cookie
or?
>> Yeah. Okay. So, Anastasia is this lady
who lives in the Russian Taigga forest
and she um she just lives this certain
like natural life and I'm just wondering
if she muscle tests above 200 or not.
>> This is somebody who lives in Australia.
>> Oh, um the Russian Tyga.
>> Huh?
>> The Russian
>> Tyga.
>> Ta.
>> Tyga. Yeah.
>> There's this guy Vladimir
Miger who writes books about her.
>> I don't know what he's asking. I want to
ask if Anastasia muscle tests above 200.
>> You want to know if that person who
claims to be the princess Anastasia is
actually the princess Anastasia? Is that
your question?
>> No. No. No. She's not a princess. She's
just a lady who lives in the woods.
>> Her name is Anastasia who lives in
Russia. And
>> what do we want to know about her for?
>> Because his friends are following her.
He wants to know if she's above 200.
>> Oh, it's his teacher.
>> Well, I don't know if she's a teacher.
She's a naturalist.
>> A naturalist.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know that we want to do a
naturalist. No.
>> Okay. Um can I ask one more question?
Like how is there a way that I can um
um decide if something like without
muscle testing if something that that
I'm that I want is for my highest good
or if it's like a self-destructive ego.
Well, you can just ask through prayer,
you know, dear Lord, I ask for a
miracle, a confirmation of this choice,
>> direction,
>> whether it serves the highest good.
>> You know, very few people do muscle
testing on the planet and yet they live
complete lives, you know. So your
intuition and your your primary goals in
life what you want to achieve and
accomplish you see
>> so it isn't always just uh from an
esoteric viewpoint but you know more
practical viewpoint.
>> So I can just ask for it to be shown to
me through through prayer whether it's
for my highest good or not.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Well thank you.
>> Yes.
Nice to see you, Susan. Dr.
>> I want to thank you so much for your
work. I've just um discovered it about a
year ago and I've read all of your books
now and um so I'm very excited to be
here in just
>> Thank you so much. Yes.
>> And I did have a question. Um, in your
book you mentioned, you know, how rare
it is to be enlightened and that at this
time there are numerous people on our
planet that are enlightened. Is
>> there are numerous people that are what
>> that are that are enlightened?
>> Where do you where do you get that?
>> In your book it said there were several
people above that calibrated.
>> Well, I thought that was several.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh, I see. I'm not I didn't know
what she was referring to. In the past,
there had only been maybe one at a time
and now we have like 12.
>> No, I think there's three. Yeah.
>> That are way up there.
>> Yeah. But anyway, what's the question?
>> Is is that because um there's so much
information now that or more teachers
available so that enlightenment?
>> No.
>> Why is it that there's so many now?
>> I don't know.
>> Okay.
>> Well, our population is growing. So, of
course, there's going to be more people
to counter the balls.
>> Okay. And let's just ask. We have
permission to ask this. Above 600, there
are currently three.
>> Great.
>> All right. Well, thank you very much and
thank you so much for your work.
>> You see, a group like this
counterbalances, you know, frankly, the
negativity of the rest of mankind.
>> Yeah.
Hi, good afternoon to you both.
>> Uh my question is in one of your books
you suggested it's a good idea to try to
find yourself in the map of
consciousness and I'm having a lot of
difficulty with that because I see
myself uh on a lot of different levels.
>> No, I didn't say you should find
yourself on a level of consciousness.
>> You I I thought
>> I did not say that anywhere in any book.
>> Oh, no. I for some reason that that's
what I thought you said to
>> where did I say that? I never said it
>> on the map.
>> I don't advise people to try and
calibrate their own level of
consciousness. In fact, I discourage
them. You're never going to get a
correct answer.
>> Oh, okay. Because I thought it would be
very helpful for me to see the pro the
things that I project out into the
world. Well, you look at the scale of
consciousness and you pick out the
description of how you experience the
world primarily and how you see the
world and what you feel your uh purpose
in life is and you you'll you'll settle
out on it without any numerical
designation
>> even even though for for myself at least
I see myself on sometimes below 200 and
sometimes above.
>> No, you don't fluctuate. That's just a
passing mood or a passing thought.
>> But your life doesn't change that fast.
Your life doesn't change overnight, you
know.
>> So, h how do I ascertain something like
that? Like, how do I find that?
>> Well, let's start with what do you do?
>> I'm trying to be a psychologist. I'm
finishing my PhD.
>> So, you're in the 400s already, correct?
>> I don't know.
>> Huh? Well, what you're asking the
question without studying it.
It says, you know, mental, the
intellectual is in the 400s. So you just
go up intellectual middle
>> getting a PhD you're automatically in
the 400s right
>> I mean I I didn't know that but since
you say that I guess
>> yeah are you familiar with the scale of
consciousness
>> all right well then then then you're not
thinking
>> all right I just I just didn't think I
for some some of the things you say that
there's corresponding emotions that that
go along with it
>> yeah that's the different column though
but it also It tells you 300 is
integrity and empowerment. 400s is the
intellect. 500 is love. 600 is
enlightenment. It says right there on
the page.
>> Right.
>> I No, I think what it says on the page.
I just I just didn't know that it's it's
that simple that you just
>> Oh, yeah. It's very simple. Yeah.
>> And then you can just find yourself and
you're done. I was thinking
>> Yeah. Nobody works on PhD unless
they're, you know, in the five four in
the 400s. Yeah.
>> Thank you so much. Well, the guys in,
you know, Ice Road Truckers are not
working on their PhDs.
>> Thank you. I wonder if we can take a
picture.
>> Yeah.
>> No, they can't say a sentence without
being bleeped.
>> They bleep. They bleep. Well, that's
just trucker talk.
That's macho talk, you know, guys
together.
Plasty, F and salt, plasty, f and sugar.
This f and coffee is too strong.
Everything begins with an F
>> or something.
>> Macho jargon. Yeah.
>> I am from Romania.
>> Huh?
>> She's from Romania. Oh yes.
>> Good.
>> Sorry.
>> Uh I want you to thank for uh thank you
for uh being who you are in my name and
uh of
uh my friends in the name of my friends
from Romania.
Uh they are very glad I'm here. Uh I am
very glad. I feel very happy. I want you
to give Uh, I want to give you my love.
I want a hug from you.
>> She wants a hug from you.
>> Oh, we don't do physical contacts much,
you know.
>> You know, you our books are in Romanian,
too. You know that. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> I
um read them.
>> Yeah.
Uh, I want to know if I'm I can do um
kinesiology testing.
>> You want to know if you can do
kinesiology testing?
>> Yeah.
>> She wants to know if she can do
kinesiology.
>> Oh, you need somebody to teach you how
to do it. We we explain to you how to do
it.
>> You want a hug? Give me your hand.
>> There's a hug for you. All right. Now,
>> thank you very much.
I use two fingers. I press down on her
elbow and I say, "Resist."
Then I say,
"The question that I have in mind, the
answer is yes."
Or I could say, "The question I have in
mind, the answer is no." See,
now she doesn't know what the question
is.
So I'm not salultting the mind in the
you know what I mean I'm not prejudging
and projecting
because she does not know what I am
holding in mind deception is not
possible
because skeptics will say well yeah
because of suggestion and all they don't
understand it she doesn't even know what
I'm holding in mind or who I'm holding
in mind or if you if I even am See, so
the answer I get has to do with quantum
mechanics.
Doesn't have anything to do with
suggestion or stage stage uh magicians
or something like that. It just has to
do with the reality of quantum
mechanics.
The science of it is explained in the
book Mindful Universe
put out by the professor of physics at
Berkeley. This is the most recent book
that explains it scientifically. See,
and uh and it says without consciousness
no planet, no no universe could even
exist. That the universe itself is
nothing but an expression of
consciousness.
So that brings that that's about as
educated as a person needs to get.
And if you can digest mindful universe,
you're doing pretty good.
>> Okay, we have to stop. It's five
o'clock.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Are you everyone's hands?
>> What
are you
What
>> I don't Yes.
>> Are you going to shake everyone's hands?
>> I didn't know that we did that before.
Did we do that? I thought we closed the
meeting. What time is it?
>> It's 5:00.
>> We have to be out of here at 5:00.
>> So, what we should do is turn the music
back on. Yes. You want to turn the music
back on? Is it possible?
Oh, I don't see how we're going to shake
everybody's hand. It's not a physical
possibility. I don't think
there's a whole long line of people.
However, I'd be willing to try it and do
it.
Now come over here if you want to shake
my hand.
>> A great pair. You will enjoy that.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> You're welcome.
>> Last time you did at the bottom of the
step.
>> Yes. Here, honey. I got to save this.
Would you like to do it here?
Allelujah.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.