We shall resume.
The question is if there is no personal self,
how do phenomena come about?
Well, they come about spontaneously.
through the process not of evolution or causation
but through emergence
which the science has recently caught up with.
But the because of the evolutionary nature of the
universe and of human uh life potentiality becomes
actuality when local conditions are favorable.
Yeah,
it comes about and of course we'll have a slide just
quickly reviewing advanced theoretical physics
which you're all dying to know about.
Mindful universe just came out Henry Stap it was
available off the internet now it's available as a book
and the price has come down
and it's quite reasonable now uh for those
that really want to understand better the mathematics.
Yeah, potentiality emerges then.
So the idea of a personal self is the big barrier to
enlightenment.
The presumption
that there is a personal self making all decisions.
Uh and that this arm just went that way
because I decided it.
I didn't decide it.
I didn't even think about it.
It happened of its own.
But see, it does it again.
Let's stop that.
Put this thing away.
All right.
It goes out and waves like that.
If you don't watch it, I say, you see what it does?
It does it by itself.
One day you'll c you'll catch it.
You'll catch that the phenomena are occurring independent
of any personal decision.
There isn't any personal you uh making decisions
and uh etc.
There is no personal self.
So long as you believe
that there's a personal self making these decisions,
you will then have to take karmic responsibility for them,
you'll be at the subject of karma.
And the Buddha warned against it.
The Buddha warned against it.
You see if you uh choose hum humanness then you have to
take the karma that goes within goes with humanness
and so the Buddha war you know recommended to avoid
reincarnating because you will reincarnate into the world
of suffering sickness old age
and death poverty sickness suffering old age and death.
The Buddha sounds a little bit like a pessimist, right?
He never won met anybody that won the lottery
or met a lovely woman and got to marry her
and everything like that.
The Buddhist sort of had a stringent view of human life.
Well,
it's because he was naive
and protected from the realities of life.
And then he got away from his parents somehow
and wandered into town and he saw old people sickness,
poverty, and death.
And he never got over the trauma of that.
He needed psychotherapy.
Old age sickness, poverty and death.
Yeah.
To avoid the negative karma.
He avoid he recommended
that you not reincarnate in the human domain.
And the way you do
that is by uh not having either attractions or aversions.
And no attractions and no aversions.
Uh uh so for whatever it's worth, we salute the Buddha.
And uh however, we're all here.
I noticed that.
So I guess we didn't take him too seriously in the
previous lifetime.
Oh, I can hear us singing.
Oh, the boot of that old fogy.
Who listens to him anyway?
All right.
So there we are back in the in the world
which modern academia uh is now ignoring.
And I won't go into my rant
and raving about modern academia
because I've already done that in previous lectures.
But uh the fact
that academia has deserted uh the world of uh
intellectual integrity of course is why it's now sinking
the in the sinking ship of of relativism.
With the exception of community colleges
and places who are still uh calibrated in the mid 400s
but the great universities in the east the great fabled
names have all shunk below 200.
Can you believe the greatest insul below 200?
It's unbelievable.
I said myself.
Uh I have permission to ask this.
That's a fact.
Resist.
I wish she was lying, but she's not.
The great great universities I mean the great fabled
names have been taken over by politically correct super
supervisors to make sure that they calibrate below 200.
All right.
So that's what the pope said
that the fall of western civilization uh is due to two
things uh on the inroads of Islam
which have destroyed Europe and uh relativism
which is destroying uh the United States and academia.
Yeah.
However,
so the best place to send your people say
where should I send my my kids?
I think in some recent book they gave a list of all the
universities is still calibrated in the 400s
and uh community colleges uh calibrated in the 400s.
So,
the safest place to send your your your kid is a
community college and uh if he goes to Yale or Harvard,
pray.
Why?
Because they have the prestige.
That's why the political left headed for them.
They headed for those that have the most prestige.
And uh so the community college is where you want to go.
And uh we can personally recommend them.
Can we recommend them?
Stand up and recommend them.
>> I recommend Community College.
Then when you go to Cal 440
when he goes to Calbury's 440 right now Yale
and Harvard I think calibrate 190.
So all right.
So it's because you've deserted uh the greatest
accomplishments of uh mankind.
The intellectual integrity, you know,
historically goes back to ancient uh someplace rather the
ancient Greece of course,
Athens and Plato and Aris Aristotle and Socrates.
Uh these are the great uh the great minds of history.
And uh and so you ignore them at your own peril.
Uh because this is integrity
and when you desert integrity,
what happens is you fall into non-integrity.
So evolution is also uh doesn't mean it's progressive uh
progressively positive.
It goes through dips and we see
that mankind recently the consciousness level of mankind
which was up to 207 has dropped down to 204 consciousness
level of mankind was up to 207 and it's now down to 204.
It's at 204.
Yeah.
Okay.
So, as I said, we were disappointed.
We thought evolution was going to keep going forward
and instead it took a downturn.
Uh, so that's apparently the nature of evolution.
It comes, it fluctuates.
It's not just a smooth ride.
Uh-huh.
So, we can't just lay back then and figure that, well,
all we have to do is depend on the evolution of
consciousness and we're all going to be fine.
Uh, because that's not so.
All right.
So, we'll we'll move on.
All those are the great names.
The difference between um perception
and essence has to do with context and content.
So here we have an event.
Here's the content in a situation
and the perceived event is is uh occurring within the
linear domain.
The situation however is nonlinear.
So the context is event of event is the context in
which it happens.
So much argumentation that goes on in politics
and economics etc of what's the right move to make.
It all depends on the situation.
So what a thing is depends not only on content
but context and the content includes the overall
situation including even the world's situation.
Is it all right to to check out what's
that security thing right now hung up in Congress?
They can't get it approved anyway.
The idea is to protect the lives of Americans.
So,
is it an infringement of human liberty
or is it a a safeguard of human liberty?
It all depends on how you view the context.
How you view the context.
I myself don't care
if they listen in on my phone conversations.
Can't you hear the government pouring all these people
with these things on banks of them,
buildings of them listening
and and then what did you put in after the mustard?
Did you fry it?
You say it's his testicles.
We should take him to the doctor.
I mean,
rows and rows of Secret Service listening to this with
earphones.
The government's listening to me, baby.
Yeah.
Well, better watch your mouth there.
That's what I say.
You're worried about the government listening to your
conversation, watch what you say.
Send the telegram.
Go ahead.
What's the next one?
What's the next slide?
Yeah.
So we talk about we differentiate the context the overall
context the spirit the time the age the era uh the
political situation the financial situation before you
make up a decision then the content is just not Newtonian
and measurable at all it depends on the circumstances
depends on the approximate field is the country at war
or not at war you Just see
that makes all the difference in the world doesn't it?
I mean you you can't draft people
when the world is not at war.
You hard enough to draft them when it is.
You know what I'm saying?
So the overall context is what gives meaning.
So there's truth as content depending on context.
But then out of content and context you derive meaning.
So beyond literal content and the context in
which it happens is meaning
and that is not understood by the public at large.
Is it legal to do that?
Well, it depends on the situation.
But what I want to know is well, so what does that mean?
What does that mean?
What it means is what's significant.
Not the event and not the circumstances,
but what's the meaning of that?
What was the Boston Tea Party?
What was the meaning of that?
They dumped tea in the ocean.
Is that all there was to it?
No, that was a protest.
That was a protest.
Taxation without representation or whatever it was.
Even that's not too interesting.
So, what does that mean?
So, what does it mean?
No taxation without representation.
What does that mean?
What does it mean?
So out of all this diffuse jibberjabber
and carrying on
and BS the significance then is what is the meaning of it.
So what man really wants to know is what is the meaning
of it?
And the subtrafuge go here's
where the subtrafuge goes on to avoid acknowledging what
is the real meaning of that.
Americans staying alive.
Americans staying alive against enemies
that want to destroy you in every way possible
and preach hatred of the great white Satan.
So what is the meaning of that?
What is the meaning of such legislation?
So you can't go just on content.
You can't even go on context while we are at war with
that culture.
You have to look to meaning.
What are the highest priorities?
So there you come into value
and spiritual spiritual significance to keep people free
and unencumbered to the degree
that you can allow them freedom uh is what we do for each
other as human beings.
We want to see each other survive
and prosper as well as we can.
Yeah.
So that's goodwill.
So the best meaning
that we can attach to a thing is does this serve good
will?
And I think that one of the best spiritual teachings I
ever heard was merely people say what can I do to become
enlightened and serve the world.
Um come from goodwill and selfless service
and unconditional love towards all of life.
Unconditional love towards all of life.
So even the person sawing the head off of a missionary
lady is doing it.
How can you have compassion for such cruelty?
Because that person doesn't know any better.
They've been indoctrinated indoctrinated.
Indoctrinated to think
that what they're doing is serving God.
So uh we don't see it that way.
We don't see it that way.
But we can understand
that if you were brought up to believe that.
So we can see that people get brainwashed into certain
activities and then we can forgive them
because the meaning is
that they are trying to serve truth
and divinity as they have been taught to serve truth
and divinity.
So that allows us to be compassionate.
People say how can you be compassionate towards what we
perceive as evil?
You see because they cannot help being the way they are
at the time they are being that way.
And you know, I practiced psychiatry for 50 years.
And uh many people I saw doing things
that in the rise of the world would be reprehensible.
And they had no choice in the matter.
No choice in the matter.
I'd say, "Why?
" I said, "I don't know.
I just blacked out and I did it.
I just blacked out.
" Functional hypoglycemia.
One of the biggest ones.
People eat all kinds of sugar.
Their blood sugar drops.
And when people's blood sugar drops,
they're quite dangerous.
You want to stay off the road with them.
They drive over other people.
They go into mad rages.
They explode and kill.
They get depressed and and commit suicide.
So, you know, the old book, what was that called?
Sugar blues was sugar blues was very big in the 12step
group some years ago.
And it spoke of functional hypoglycemia.
You know, eat you eat a lot of blood sugar sugar,
your blood puts out a lot of insulin.
That brings your blood sugar rocketing down.
And when your blood sugar rockets down,
people get depressed.
They get agitated.
They get homicidal.
They do the bizarre things besides getting drunk
and killing their wives and driving over their children.
They do.
They get drunk, kill their wives,
and drive over their wives
and children just due to eating too much sugar.
hyperinsulinism.
So,
I thought we should mention
that because I don't think I've mentioned it these
lectures that if you keep getting arrested for those
things,
you should go on a high protein boy diet
and avoid sugar and sweets.
But I've seen people, you know, eat sugar and sweets.
Their blood sugar goes up like this
and then their their body pours out insulin.
You go into hyperinsulinism.
Pretty soon you start to shake.
And people in hyp hyperinsulinism with low blood sugar
can go into a rage just this fast.
Just just go into a rage or just kill themsel
or just give up 10 years of sobriety
and go get drunk for the hell of it, you know.
So or drive over children and various things.
So it's one of the easiest things to cure.
And I used to when I people made an appointment in the
office, I'd say what's your problem, you know,
anxiety and depressional.
I said, "Between now and the time you see me next Tuesday,
I want you to give up sugar and sweets.
" They say,
"I don't know what I was going to see you for is going
away now.
" I just thought I'd throw that in.
You know, that'll be an extra $20 by the way.
whatever ills you give up sugar
and sweets for a period of time and just see
if it cures it.
It cures about I'd say, you know,
at least half the phone calls I used to get in the office.
I had a huge practice.
I mean, I had 50 people working for me.
I had a huge practice
and I'd say almost half the time by the time they got to
the office,
whatever was ailing them was gone
because our society pushes a lot of sugar
and sweets at every turn, you know,
and uh it's a very common disorder.
All right.
So the next thing is then after this after we got rid of
the sugar blues quantum mechanics and the
and the test muscle response uh what we're seeing is
potentiality becoming actualized by the introduction of
intention.
So intention then is what collapses the wave function
from potentiality into actuality.
All that exists then exists prior to its actual existence
as a potentiality.
That potentiality then gets the we collapse collapse the
wave function by collapse collapse the wave function by
intention.
So the power of spirituality is its intention collapses
the potentiality into actuality of beneficial uh good
things.
You see potentiality collapsing is actuality.
This group here is doing
that right now by sitting here by virtue of the energy
field that you radiate out into the world especially
collectively.
This group by just breathing in
and out is potentiating the spiritual evolution of
mankind.
If that's a fact, resist.
Thank you for breathing in and out
and raising the consciousness level of mankind.
and saving mankind from predition.
And and you're doing so by virtue of your intention.
So I I mentioned Henry Stap's new book is uh is now
available uh Mindful Universe uh
and it it it's very uh useful.
Yeah.
So we'll go to the next I won't go into that.
Uh now uh this one I want to reemphasize
because again we're not talking airy fairy.
We're talking about alterations in brain function.
The spiritually oriented person whose intention is benign
has a different brain function,
different neurotransmitters.
So when you see people doing horrible things,
you know that they are run by this side of the brain.
They're being run by their animal nature
and that they're they're being run by emergency emotions.
And a person who is spiritually oriented changes his
brain chemistry.
, he's releasing endorphins.
And endorphins are the uh are the neurotransmitters
that make you feel beautiful and good.
So when you're listening to great music
and you feel like crying because it's so beautiful,
the brain,
the right brain is releasing endorphins
and you are getting a preview of what heaven is like.
The high spiritual states especially accompanied by
incredible music are um a preview of the worlds to come.
A preview of heaven.
Preview of heaven.
Previews of heaven.
Wow.
on channel 8.
What more could you ask for PBS?
Give you a preview of heaven.
Great some teners were on the other night
and the week before that I think it was Celtic woman
and uh the be the beauty of such things.
Remember river dance?
The river dance had a Irish u Irish bag pipes
and that eerie sound that's really a Celtic ancient
Celtic song you know takes you back to timelessness a
timeless keening
and the hair in the back of your head goes up oh I'm
being lifted up into the hair by invisible angels.
Channel 8.
Thank God for Channel 8, right?
No, but it it features beauty.
And I think the commercials are way too long.
But uh if they make the commercials shorter,
I would send them more money.
That's a fact.
I've got to send that to them.
By the time they hang me up waiting
and waiting for the program to start,
I'm so annoyed I put the checkbook away.
I bet they don't know that.
We should send them a thing.
Please make the commercial shorter
and we'll send you more money.
Everybody for shorter commercials on PBS, raise your hand.
Hey.
Hey, that's unanimous.
Unanimously PBS has just one won a great one win.
Uh we figured out how to send them more money
and we don't have to listen to their long draggy
commercials.
Well,
a lot of the guests they have on
that do the commercials are really wonderful people
and I'm frankly I do enjoy them very much.
It's just that after 10 or 15 minutes of it,
I got their message.
The message is make out a check.
Okay,
I can make out a check
and now let's have the program back on again.
So,
that's one thing
that always annoys me is commercials don't see the
downside of their commercial.
They're so naive and they spend huge amounts of money.
I could save any advertising, any corporation,
huge amounts of money,
get twice as much profit from that advertisement.
Uh because they they send out such negative uh
commercials.
So if I went back in the business world,
that's what I'd do be consultant to advertising agencies,
etc.
How to get the most kick
and buck out of your advertising dollar
and not annoy the customers so that they buy elsewhere.
So this is the right brain and the left brain.
Uh that's profoundly important
because when you say why don't other people think like I
do or why don't they behave or react the way I do?
It's because they're coming from a different side of the
brain.
They're coming from survival.
The left brain is survival animal world.
And then the right brain is over here.
And we come from positive emotions.
Now we'll ask about Kelsey's emotions are comparable to
our right brain.
You're safer with the dog than you are with most of the
people on the planet.
This sheeper dog comes from comparable right brain feels
responsible.
Wherever I go around the house,
the dog has to check where where are you?
The m the miss goes in the other room.
She goes and checks where's the misses.
Then she has to come back and check where I am.
Then she has to see where the cats are.
By that time,
it's time to go and check where the MS is again.
Then she's got to go and see if Gabe is here yet.
that keeping trackness is somehow very heartwarming.
You know, the heartwarmingness,
it's almost like a maternal instinct.
It's almost like a maternal instinct
that has to watch all the children and make sure
that they're all okay
and that nobody's choking on their gaga or whatever.
When I was a little tiny kid,
I had a gaga and uh to break you from sucking your thumb,
you get a gaga.
It's a little piece of fuzzy felt or something
and you can rub it on yourself like this when you're gaga.
Well, my mother mother hated the gaga.
After a while, they wanted to get the gaga away.
And uh it was better than sucking your thumb,
but the gaga got him.
So, we had a model forward where the top was down,
you know.
So,
we're driving along and I took the gaga
and I threw it over the side
and my father had to put the brake on
and back up to get the gaga.
So, that was fun.
So, couple of miles farther down.
I threw the gaga over the side again
and my father father had to put the brake on father
father had to put the brake on and back up
and get the gaga again.
" And I and I giggled.
So I did it one more time.
So that's what I mean.
Don't fool around with God.
Give him two shots, but on the third shot,
you better watch your butt, you know,
because you may not back up
and get your gaga the third time.
So,
that's the the h that's the the lesson of Gaga land
and uh which side of the brain you want to live on.
Okay, so let's move to the next side of the brain.
Oh,
this has to do with a sort of in a way it contradicts a
lot of social theories.
You see uh the Marxian dialectic they divides everything
into perpetrator and victim
and then it projects perpetrator is always society
and victim is always the minority until they become the
majority and then they switch sides.
But anyway,
for a period of time everybody gets to be in the minority.
All right.
So it says all these things such as rate of unemployment,
poverty,
happiness or criminality are all um due to society.
It's society's fault
that uh these you cheat on your classwork
or whatever you do.
All right?
So the research we did shows that no,
it's really related to that which you really are.
These um social problems are really problems of the the
consequences of levels of consciousness.
The lower levels of consciousness have everything wrong
with them.
50 to 100.
This is the usual prison population.
This is the prison population.
Uh the recitism in these uh kinds of prison populations
is almost 100%.
the likelihood of you getting out of jail for robbery,
the likelihood is close to 100%
that you'll be back again before very long.
Uh why?
Because and the reason you can't learn from experience is
because your consciousness level is down here.
The rate of unemployment here is practically 100%.
Uh the rate of poverty is a majority.
How many of these people think life is okay?
Close to 0%.
Those that think it's okay is only
because they're stoned at the moment.
The rate of criminality is close to 100%.
So this has to has great significance in our judicial
system,
prison system and an understanding of these things might
give us some hope.
Uh I forget what percent of the United States population
has more than any country.
United States has more people in jail
or prison than any country in the world.
More than anybody got 3% or 1% I forget what it is.
Anyway, more people in prison in the United States.
This is the land of freedom.
And of course that's pointed out to be critical of us.
So the land of freedom has more people in prison than all
the other countries in the world.
Could be we have better police.
That's why you kill somebody who go nobody gives a rap
they care they arrest you
and everything put you in prison.
All right.
So the rate of a you see all these sociologic problems
are really not due to some causality out there.
They're due to what you have become in here.
Just as happiness is a consequence of what you have
become within yourself.
that the opposite of it is also a consequence of what you
have learned.
You know,
so people who are the so-called psy psychopath ridicules
all the things that spiritual work stands for.
All the things that we consider the most valuable,
self-sacrifice, service to others, uh love,
uh respect for divinity, etc.
uh are ridiculed.
Okay.
So we'll go to the next uh the rate of happiness here you
see.
So we said the rate of happiness is not a sociologic
condition.
It's a it's a consequence of that which you have become.
Uh people who live down here uh down here the percent of
people happy uh in shame uh guilt uh apathy uh hatred uh
grief people who live in fear uh people who are
constantly craving wanting something people who are
constantly angry and people who live out of pride.
You see that the great majority of those people are
unhappy.
The rate of happiness suddenly jumps at level 200.
Below 200 uh about 22% of
that is the most uh will say that they're happy.
Uh that's probably because they're stoned
and after the martini wears off they will get anyway from
200 and up you suddenly see the percent of happiness
jumps enormously.
So the first benefit you get from a spiritual integrous
ethical orientation towards life uh is a greater rate of
happiness.
This comes from self approval.
Yeah.
The inner knowingness.
the meaning of your life.
So the meaning of your life is
that your life is significant that you serve
so yourself and others uh
and that you're helpful to the life of others
and the enjoyment of life to safety and security.
So dedicating your life to ethics and integrity
and truth etc has an immediate benefit.
You don't have to become enlightened.
All you have to do is get to be happier.
So I've never recommended the sackcloth
and ashes type of religiosity.
You know Ramano Maharshi uh was a great uh teacher etc.
But he he was he lived in the Hindu tradition of aeticism
and the the more bent over and skinny and etc
that you got the the more holy you got.
It isn't necessary to starve yourself to death
and live in a hut and live on grass and carbon dioxide
or something.
The spiritual awareness happens independently of all of
that, not as a consequence of all that.
That's true.
Resist.
Sometimes you see the westerner gets impressed by the
more bizarre aspects of it.
I can take off all my clothes
and you'll see I'm very skinny.
>> We can all take our clothes off and get very skinny.
But that is a s that is a side issue.
I just want to clarify
that some of the things in the spiritual literature
people focus on what is irrelevant aside issue.
It's the dedication to service to unconditional
lovingness to being all
that you can be for the benefit of the world.
You see and Raman Mahari loved all kinds of animals
and he thought that the ca the calves
and the cows had souls.
I don't know if a cow has a soul or not.
I have permission to ask this.
A cow has a soul.
Is it?
He was right.
>> So, does it have like a cow soul?
>> Yes.
Well, it has animal soul.
Well, we And that's why we picked up Kelsey.
We just looked at this dog.
This one dog radiated out from the whole bunch of them
and you just felt the heart uh energy radiate out.
All right.
So we can love the animals
and realize they have their own animal souls
and love them for what they are.
So a truly evolved person tends to be loving towards all
of life and all of its expressions.
The beautiful flowers, the rabbits hopping along,
the squirrels in the tree, the cows munching away,
the horses,
and uh the cats and the dogs and the birds flying around.
So you tend to love life in all of its expressions.
You tend to love life in all its expressions.
All of its expressions.
So the spiritually evolved person loves life in all of
its expressions.
Resist.
All of its expressions.
And you can't really do
that unless you have a sense of humor.
Can't really do that without a sense of humor.
Resist.
Right?
Because you have no other way.
No way to contextualize
that which appears to be its opposite.
You know, uh what appears to be it.
So the sense of humor is a very valuable spiritual tool
and it's a should be represented more than it is.
Uh without a sense of humor you can't feel compassionate
towards many things but once you recontextualize it
and see the humor of it you can see the the humanness of
that uh then it's okay.
You can you can say yeah I don't believe
but I can understand why people are that way.
That allows you to include it in.
So that's the great value of humor.
The humorists all live to be very old.
You know,
the classic humorists uh almost all live into their 90s
just as the classical musicians and composers
and concert conductors etc.
You live well into their 90s and so does uh what was it?
George George Burns was what 99 when he finally fell over.
So uh the way to live long is to love music and be funny.
Enjoy humor.
Value humor.
Learn how to see the humorous side of life.
You know, the paradoxes of life are very comical.
You see what I'm saying?
Yeah.
All right.
So, the rate of happiness.
We're concerned with being happy.
Uh, I want everybody to be happy.
I insisted they be happy.
Anybody here not want to be happy?
Come on, guys.
I know you're hiding there.
I see you there.
I see I see you there.
I see you.
Come pick.
Come up here.
Just gave up.
You said you wanted to be happy.
All right.
So, the rate of happiness then.
So, even if you don't become enlightened,
the trip is a wonderful trip.
You'll enjoy it life much more.
You'll get more gratification
and fulfillment by becoming the completion
and fulfillment of that which you are.
And so we grow through the heart.
Uh through the heart.
Okay.
The next Yeah.
So spirituality is really the way of the heart.
The way of the heart.
Uh we add the world of the intellect.
Oh, how did that get in there?
I haven't seen those in a long time.
Let's go back and get them.
What was that one?
Uh oh, the Lou.
Yeah.
Oh, this.
No, wait a minute.
No, before that.
Before that.
What was that one?
Is that Is that one we're supposed to show?
The one before this one?
>> No, the one before that.
>> There.
There.
Hold on.
Yeah, hold on.
Oh, yes.
I know what this is.
This is the application of consciousness research to
international relationships and international politics.
Uh and it you put together the level of consciousness
scale and you put uh where are you coming from?
What's the consciousness level let's say about the US
and what's the consciousness level the people were
negotiating with.
Now you this is a generally applicable you can do my my
business my company uh my anything
and this is the community we're dealing with.
So here's the community calibrates at so and
so our organization calibrates at this
so you can see what is necessary.
If you're at level 425,
talking to somebody at level uh 75 is not going to make
any sense to them
because you you don't live in the same reality.
These people are worried worrying about staying alive
till tomorrow with food and stuff like this
and you're talking about you know democracy or something.
They think that's interesting except you can't eat it.
Okay, we'll go to the next slide.
You can't eat democracy.
You know, you can only eat food.
Then we'll go to the next one.
It's better to have a uh dictator who gives you food than
democracy with no food.
You understand what I'm saying?
All right.
So, let's go to the next slide.
33 39.
We jump all over the place.
I don't know what's in She's gone mad.
The lady with the PowerPoint.
She's gone mad.
>> What?
33.
>> Well, I don't know.
Oh, what was the next one?
I marked >> 33.
Did we do 33?
>> Okay.
>> Consciousness rate of happiness was >> we did that.
Yeah.
>> D the um >> Yes.
>> international relationship.
>> Yes, we did that.
>> Okay.
So, we're on the right one.
>> We're on the right track.
Oh my god, I'm relieved.
I thought we were on the wrong track.
>> This is the heaven track.
I thought we were on the other one maybe for a moment.
I don't want to aggravate the powers that be.
Uh all right.
This is something that we need to clarify.
What is the nature of true spiritual teachers?
And um that because society is somewhat confused about
this.
Uh the nature of spiritual truth then
if we study this we'll find
that spiritual truth is universally true at all times in
all places.
is not dependent on being in New York City
or or uh California.
It's non-exclusive.
It's all inclusive,
non sectarian and non it's non sectarian.
It's available open to everybody.
So you see spiritual truth is open to everyone.
It doesn't cost anything.
There are no secrets to be revealed, hidden, sold.
No magical formulas or mysteries.
The integrity is that of purpose.
There's nothing to gain or lose.
So a spiritual teaching is what it is for its own sake.
It merely wants to share what it's learned for the
benefit of everyone.
Truth is not the exposition of limitation.
Uh it's independent of opinion.
Well,
we say we say truth is nonlinear
and not subject to the limitations of reason
or the intellect or form.
Truth is not anti- anything.
You know, they they all calibrate in the mid300s.
they they all calibrate in the mid300s.
So, we don't care who wins the election.
They're one side and there are the other one.
They're all about the same.
Falsehood and ignorance are not its enemies,
but merely represent the absence of truth.
So we're not anti-f falsehood.
We just sort of bemoone the fact
that the truth is missing.
There's no requirements or demands.
You know there many sex uh you know many uh demand all
kinds of strange things.
You got to eat weird things and eat just worms
and shave your hair and and do chant makes strange sounds.
Uh anyway there are no requirements for membership.
There's no dues.
There's no regulations.
no oaths, no rules or conditions.
The spir true spiritual teacher has no interest in
controlling the personal lives of aspirants.
Uh telling them how to run their sex lives, etc.
A lot of times there there's there's been some recent
exposees even in local papers where where I am, you know,
of of uh where where I am, you know,
of of uh denominations
that do the exact opposite of all this.
" Tell you who to go to bed with,
and you have to get his permission in order to drive your
car.
And and uh it's it's very bizarre the extremes.
And and the head of the six says
that he's higher than God.
He's higher than God.
Oh, okay.
I'd like to meet somebody higher than God.
But uh All right.
So we don't tell people how to clothe, how to dress,
their sex lives, their love life, their economics,
who they should go out with, who they should marry, etc.
lifestyles or what they should eat or not eat.
Except if you eat a lot of sugar and sweets, be careful.
Free of force or intimidation.
There is no brainwashing, no agilation of great leader,
no great leader, no training rituals, indoctrinations,
no intrusions into private life,
agilations of great leaders.
These countries in the world with the agilation of the
great leader is the whole what holds the society together.
The great leader picture is everywhere.
People worship great leader, great leader, great leader.
Now when you calibrate great leader,
I will not mention who great leader is.
Great leader calibrates over 200 resist.
Great leader doesn't even calibrate 200.
My dog calibrates to 255.
Bring Kelsey.
You can worship Kelsey here.
All right.
So great sacrifice in the name of then political power is
oppression.
Oppression.
So you see how lucky our country is.
We bemoan it and criticize each other
and during political times like this people get nasty
with each other and say horrible things.
But compared to other countries, our world is heavenly.
The most negative thing you can say about our political
system would be a heavenly gift in another culture.
Yeah.
So let's go to the next one.
Non-binding.
You don't have to sign any contracts.
uh the reason I didn't join the prestigious uh uh
organization every all the men in my family belonged to
it for generations
and then it came my turn to become a member of it
and I said and I found out
that you had to take an oath and swear by an oath
and when I heard you had to swear by an oath I declined.
Um,
it turns out when you swear by an oath
that is binding through numerous lifetimes.
Yeah, that's a fact.
It's binding through numerous lifetimes.
So,
a contract that you swore to several gener lifetimes ago
was binding in this lifetime.
" And it was so the missing thumb was the consequence of
a karmic bondage that I swore to in a previous lifetime.
Yeah.
The karma came forth in this lifetime
and the circular saw I do circular saws for years.
No problem.
All of a sudden of its own.
Okay.
That was that was the karmic debt.
Resist.
And it is now paid off.
I put two thumbs to give to my country.
You know what I'm saying?
So therefore, I recommend swear no oaths.
And it says somewhere in Christian literature,
I think that is also a teaching of Christianity to swear
no oaths.
square nodes, etc.
Because they're binding,
you don't remember it in this lifetime
and suddenly it's pola time.
Yeah.
All right.
True spiritual integrity.
That means you are completely free.
Free to come and go as you want.
There's nothing God has signed.
There's no consequences.
There are no dues.
There's a commonality of purpose.
A commonality is what bring us brings us together.
The only thing that brings us together is
that we're all interested in spiritual evolution for its
own sake.
" Oh, glory be to thee, oh Lord most high,
out of worship and love.
And by the acknowledgment that God is our source
and that we are answerable to God uh by
that is our own our our own souls are saved.
You see we uh achieve salvation via the acknowledgement
of divinity.
Now the strange thing about the calibration system
that we use is it cannot be used by atheists.
Huh?
And I didn't discover
that until uh relatively few years ago.
But there were people who were using the technique
and would report negative results.
And I thought, you know,
this guy's into alternate medicine.
I mean,
he should you assume he's probably been using this for
years and you find out
that he doesn't he doesn't know he doesn't get the right
answer.
And then I found out the reason he is negative is
because he's an atheist.
Oh, well,
the fact that he's a professor with the fancy beard
and all,
you figure you forgot the reason he can't get truth out
of something that we get truth out of all day around the
clock is because he's an atheist.
Oh, okay.
So, the technique that we use cannot be used by atheists.
If you deny the very source and backbone
and structure of truth itself,
then you're denied the fruits of truth.
We don't.
So if you deny truth or divinity as the source of truth,
then you cannot use you wouldn't get the same answers we
get.
I don't know if you get any answers at all
and you might get the opposite.
Anyway, that explains it.
Okay.
If you refute divinity,
then you cannot find uh the answers to questions such as
we do routinely.
And we don't ask, you know,
just profound questions all the time.
I'll just say, you know, I really should take that cypro.
I'll say, I think I'm getting the flu.
Yes.
No.
Yeah.
I should take cypro.
Yes.
I should take two a day.
I should take three a day.
No.
I should take it for how long?
Eight days, nine days, 10 days.
So, we prescribe medicine for ourel, treat oursel,
have all kinds of things.
You know what I mean?
Decide what's the best diet for the dog.
You know use we use this routinely as part of our life
and it just really makes life so much easier.
Makes right life so much easier.
You know we should we shouldn't take the traffic on
so and so parkway is is going to be impossible.
We get yes it's better to take the other parkway.
So I mean we use it for you know it doesn't have to be
profound stuff like the will of God or something.
It just be I'd be more comfortable with with these pants
on than corduriz.
Yes.
In Long Beach.
Yeah.
So I put these on.
You'd be more comfortable than quarters will be too warm.
Yes.
Okay.
You know what I mean?
All right.
I just wanted to see the practicality.
It's a very domestic thing to do.
I want to take it out of the idea of being charming
or you know anything exceptional or esoteric.
It's very domestic.
Calibrating those of consciousness is very domestic,
very practical.
very down to earth.
You know what I'm saying?
And you just make it part of your lifestyle.
And I'll say that can that that
that canned dog food is what's giving the dog diarrhea.
Resist.
I got the answer there.
I have to go and pay a vet.
Right.
She was eating grass.
That's what did it.
All right.
So you make it you make re spiritual reality uh
fulfilling.
You make it part of your life.
Uh it's benign and uh it becomes a blessing in your life.
So the way we use it at the way I try to teach it is uh
practical domestic use take away any oo
or ah there's nothing mystical
or magical there's nothing esoteric you don't have to go
and take courses on how to do it it's very simple thing
truth because it matches you see the infinite
potentiality when it's matched with the reality by virtue
of quantum mechanics when I say this is
and it already has a reality, her arm goes strong.
If I say this is and this is not,
there's no reality and the arm goes weak.
It's impersonal.
So what you're doing is matching potentiality with
actuality in in the quantum dimension of the infinite
field of consciousness.
What gives her arm strength is the truth.
If I say if I'm holding in mind is over 200
and that's true, then her arm goes strong.
So truth makes you go strong.
Falsehood makes you go weak.
Goodness makes you go strong.
Wickedness makes you go weak.
It's very very simple.
You don't have to go to college to learn that.
You know what?
>> What?
What did you say?
>> It's 12:30.
>> She said it's 12:30.
She's making threats behind my back.
" So where are we?
Oh,
we we're talking about um in integrous spiritual teachers
and teachings and uh we we we non-binding it means
freedom to participate to come
and to go means to inspire people in the direction
that that you know is spiritual evolution
and uh non-involvement in world affairs.
In other words,
we're signed we're not signed up with anything
that it should win and somebody else should lose.
The intention is bi is benigning and and non-dualistic
and and non-dualistic all transpires by virtue of karmic
propensity within the field by
which potentiality manifests as actuality rather than
cause and effect.
So that's where we ended up.
We were talking about things occur as a consequence not
of a volitional in a Newtonian paradigm
but as a consequence of emergence potentiality becoming
actuality which is activated by intention.
So spiritual intention then by itself actualizes your own
spiritual potential.
The minute you acknowledge the divinity of God as the
author of uh all existence,
uh you've already brought into play a very powerful
energy field.
Let's say um that which we do at each of these uh yes
calibrates over 600 800 750 800 All right.
So the opening invocation calibrates to 750.
That sets the intention of the lecture.
Glory be to thee, oh Lord most high.
Acknowledges divinity as the source of all existence.
Merely acknowledging
that God is the source of all existence
and that one is answerable therefore to divinity.
Every hair on your head shall be counted.
Let's see.
Is a fact.
Resist.
Calibrates at 1,00.
Calibrates at 1,00 calibrates at 900.
950.
Okay, that's good enough.
900.
The last 50 is God's grace.
Despite all the hairs on your head,
that may not vote in your favor.
Uh the last 50 points is is the generosity of the grace
of God resist.
Oh even though you don't acknowledge it yourself
and own it and realize it,
God grant God's grace uh releases you from
that because he sees your limitation.
Uh all right.
Well, that certainly is enheartening.
That takes care of the fear of death.
Anybody still have a fear of death here?
I'm gonna kill anybody that's still afraid of death.
Anybody that's had a near-death experience,
it's laughable that one should be afraid of death.
You know, in fact,
it's quite the con the opposite is the consequence.
You think you're leaving and then
when you realize you're not,
that that's that's when the pain comes in.
You're going back to where you were.
Oh god, I thought I was leaving.
Oh well.
All right.
I've left uh been almost I've been almost left a number
of times.
And I always remember there's a feeling of disappointment.
You're all ready to leave
and you're in this butic state
and then you get the bad news.
Unfortunately, you're not dying.
Oh.
Oh, well.
So, well, we tried to cover all the uh important slides.
Now,
we still have some more to do before we get to the
question and answer period.
So, let's see.
What's the next one?
>> What?
Well, we were talking about uh spiritual integrity,
equality of all uh the students and the teachers.
Um beyond proof uh divinity is not provable.
It's demonstrable.
We confirm it here.
We confirm it by our own uh unique techniques.
Uh but it's not provable.
So spiritual reality because it deals with context.
The only thing that's provable is contempt.
And so anything
that you can actually prove is not the ultimate truth to
begin with.
Anything you can prove is really in the linear Newtonian
paradigm.
Uh it's limited.
That which is unlimited context unlimited context cannot
be proven.
It just is.
And then what happens is you begin to there's the
realization that one is not the linear content of
consciousness.
that one is consciousness itself that which is aware.
So awareness awareness itself is then uh the function.
So when people say how can I give up the ego
which we may talk about a little bit later
if we have time.
How can we uh give up the ego?
You give up yourself as a as as primary cause.
You give up the illusion
that you your you your your personal self is what's
deciding and making the decisions.
A more advanced understanding you begin to see
that everything is happening spontaneously.
And the illusion
that there's a personal self causing it is itself an
illusion.
It's a spontaneous illusion.
So you don't have to feel guilty that you have an ego.
Everybody has an ego or we wouldn't be here, would we?
Without the ego, you wouldn't stay alive long enough.
So,
the ego serves a purpose
and it keeps our animal keeps our animal going,
keeps our animal alive.
Um,
tells you to stay out of the way of the lions
and things like this.
So, we owe our physical survival to ego.
But then it becomes a limitation.
So at a certain level of consciousness
that which served us well at the lower levels now becomes
the barrier.
How to transcend the illusion of a personal self?
The idea of a personal self occurs spontaneously.
So we don't have to feel guilty that we have it.
It's normal.
It's a natural consequence.
We see phenomena happen and we presume
that there's a personal self that makes it happen.
We presume that a personal self waves this arm.
But if we're fast enough, if we're fast enough,
and this is all a matter of speed,
you will catch that that happened just prior to your
taking credit for it.
" Let's see.
That is 110,000 of a second resistance.
So the leading edge of the ego then is 110,000 of a
second ahead of reality.
And you reach a point of consciousness
where you can transcend
that onetenth of 110,000 of a second.
And you catch that the ego is taking credit for what has
already happened.
And I think I've told you in previous lectures I
discovered that when I was still an adolescent
or uh no yeah probably adolescent 18 or 19.
Anyway,
a rabbit I was driving the car fort and uh
and a rabbit ran across the road.
Instantly the foot went down on the brake
and saved the rabbit
and I caught the ego claiming credit for that.
I caught the ego saying I put my foot on the brake.
The foot was already on the brake
when the eye jumped in and claim credit for that.
So I caught I caught the ego at it at a very young age
before I knew anything about consciousness
or anything like that.
Ego jumped in and instantly claimed credit for saving the
rabbit's life.
No, it happened before before the eye made a decision.
The instant breaking happened instantly
and then the eye complimented itself
which is egotism which we'll talk about uh later Susan
and I if we have time for it.
We want to just finish the review of these uh particular
lectures.
All right.
So mystical is a word uh
that we will talk there's a few slides on mysticism later.
Mysticism is that emergence as the ego collapses.
Uh the mysticism then is an inner knowingness.
It's the inner awareness of the nonlinear.
As the linear as you're less do less
and less dominated by the egotism of the linear domain
and thinkingness
and you give up thinkingness is a bad habit
and the you let go of thinkingness.
awareness takes over.
Instead,
this can be achieved through meditation
and uh contemplation as well.
You can adopt a contemplative style
and way of being aware within the world
so that you're not, you know,
not thinking in a linear dimension at all.
Instead,
you're sort of automatically adjusting to the overall
field in an appropriate way.
And if you're honest with yourself,
you'll see that this is happening of its own.
The awareness of consciousness itself is such
that you automatically get out of the way of the trolley
car.
Uh because that's the sense of reality
that comes out of the infinite field.
So the field knows
that you shouldn't be standing on the trolley car tracks
and it moves you off.
And it isn't that the ego decided, man,
it's dangerous standing here.
" You remember ever saying that to yourself?
I don't think I should be standing on these trolley
tracks.
I think I will get off before the cable car gets here.
No, you do it automatically.
So that which we often disregard
because we say it's just automatic is is the effect of
perception.
It's the is is the effect of perception.
It's the effect of the knowingness of the infinite field
of consciousness itself.
As we let go the illusion
that we're being dominated by logic and cause
and effect and the linear domain,
we begin to see that we've been taking credit,
that actually everything is happening autonomously by
itself.
Only once in a while does the mind come in uh in any kind
of a meaningful way.
You know,
shall I have a ham sandwich or a cheese sandwich?
That was the ego's big moment today.
The fact that you are, that you're there,
that you're eating, all this has been decided for you.
The fact that you need to work to make a living
and pay the bills, all this,
all this phenomena is outside your your sness.
So,
what you're allowed to choose today is whether you want a
cheese sandwich or a ham sandwich.
And that's the limit of your freedom.
the idea of free choice.
You see,
free choice is one of the great illusions of the world.
And people give up all kinds of stuff for what they call
freedom of speech, etc.
And uh anyway, they quickly bring freedom.
The way to eliminate freedom of speech is to give people
real freedom of speech
and they will quickly get rid of free speech.
All right?
The origination of truth is a spontaneous knowingness.
It's like a radiance.
It's like an illumination.
And therefore, there is no personal self, no cause,
effect, no verbs, no me causing of that.
All right,
we'll go to the next
because we want to finish all these slides.
Okay.
Truth is always affirmative.
It it doesn't say not this, not that.
It says this instead of that.
It's invitational.
It's not sentimental.
Emotionality is based on perception.
So, a lot of truth gets lost in the emotionality.
Uh this happens in politics very much.
You know,
something gets to be a popular belief system
and next thing you know, there's a bandwagon.
Everybody's getting on there.
They're waving flags, you know,
an earthwarming uh rally or something like this.
Except the earth doesn't pay attention to the
earthwarming rally.
Anyway,
so but people get very emotionally committed to causes
and the narcissistic core of the ego loves to ride the
bandwagon on causes.
Whatever is a current popular cause,
uh how to get rid of your garbage or whatever it is.
uh people sign up by the drove
and become very emotional about it.
So you say why do they have to become emotional about it?
It's because the core of the ego is narcissistic.
It has to do with me me my cause my belief system uh is
now becomes very important.
So by exaggerating the importance of a belief system all
you're doing is increasing the magnitude of the egotism.
uh how important your views are on things.
As you get more sophisticated,
you lose interest in what people's opinions are
because they're all stupid.
And for amusement,
you can click on to the what do you call it?
Internet system, gang machine.
What do you call that system anyway?
Blo blogger system.
And you can find endless amusement there.
uh from the from the benign to the ridiculous.
Very ridiculous, you know.
Uh all right.
So truth is not sentimental.
It doesn't uh climb on the bandwagon.
We don't have to save the world through enlightenment.
We'll have a save the world through enlightenment rally
in Central Park.
will bring parades and banners and bugles
and and important politicians
and uh save the world through spiritual advancement
and consciousness awareness.
You can imagine how many people will sign up
and people who get what we're really about wouldn't be
there, would they?
All right.
So it's truth does not do anything or cause anything.
It's nonvolitional.
It's invitational.
People are either attracted to it
and it's meaningful to them or not.
It's nonpredictive.
It doesn't predict the future.
So the prediction of what's going to happen 2020
something rather >> 12 >> 2012 >> December >> get your
mortgage paid up by December.
Right before Christmas, right?
Oh golly.
God doesn't even care about Christmas.
He's going to put bring the world to an end right before
Christmas.
Oh, that's not very kindly.
I think I'll have to speak to him upstairs.
You could wait till after Christmas.
have the world in December 26, 2012.
See, Because it's based on an idea of causality.
See, because the world is evolutionary.
What's going to be next cannot be decided now
because what happens is the phenomena of the future are
the result of decision joint decisions made now.
There's no way of knowing what will happen
because nobody knows what choices
because of freedom of choice
because of freedom of the will.
It's impossible to predict the future of anything
because otherwise you there would be no freedom of the
will.
If there was no freedom of the will,
there would be no answerability.
There'd be no such thing as karma etc.
Neither would there be liberation.
So the future cannot be predicted
because the future is the consequence of the present
and the present hasn't happened yet.
What will be in the future depends on all the choices
that people make
and those seeing this as of right now those are
unknowable.
There's no way of knowing
which way the wind will be blowing on that day
because the factors
that contribute to the direction of the wind haven't
occurred yet.
Is that obvious?
Anybody got any problem about that?
Nobody.
Oh well.
It reminds me that was
that old joke about the kid in the back said the world's
going to end in in 20 20 billion years.
The guy who puts his hand up 20 billion years.
Yes, that's Oh my god, I thought you said 20 million.
So,
the reason I can safely predict
that the world is not coming to to an end in the year
2012 because if it is,
nobody would be around to tell me I'm wrong.
So,
I'm betting that the world will still be here in the year
2012, December 21st or whatever it is.
And besides,
God wouldn't be that much of a killjoy
and knock Christmas out.
I don't you wait till December 27th anyway after you open
your stockings and all that kind of stuff.
I mean, that would be mean, wouldn't it?
So,
it's not predictive and it's not predictive
because of the freedom of the will.
Karmic responsibility is
because you have the freedom of choice.
Freedom of choice is what differentiates the
consciousness level of humans.
Huh?
It's because of freedom of choice
that you can reach salvation.
Salvation is be is a consequence of one's own personal
choice.
So God doesn't force anybody to do anything.
Each one of us by virtue of the choices and decisions
that we make from moment to moment uh decide our own
karmic future and propensities.
So I always compare the infinite field of conscious
consciousness uh to a giant electromagnetic field
and I compare human beings uh our little spirits to
little fragments of metal fragments
and we have a positive and a negative pole.
So as we make positive choices our polarity moves in this
direction and as we make negative choices our polarity
moves in this direction.
So based on the choices you make then like a little iron
magnetic filing your position in the infinite magnetic
field shifts.
So if you constantly choose the negative you shift down
towards this level of the field closer
and closer to the hells
and as you choose on this side the other polarity comes
up and because of the infinite power of the field.
So therefore God is not personal
and judgmental God is the infinite field of power out of
which your choices are what decide your your fate.
your your fate.
Your choices are you know your fate is strictly up to
your own choices.
Your fate is not up to an arbitrary god
but strictly within your own hands.
Resist.
Strictly within your own power.
Your karmic destiny is strictly within your own personal
power.
Resist.
Wow.
So there's no point of uh fearing a god who would act in
contrary to his own laws.
So the law of divinity is an infinite field of infinite
power within that infinite field of infinite power.
Your choices decide your own fate.
So everyone lives then by the ultimate freedom of his own
choices which by virtue of the infinite power of the
field of divinity determines the outcomes.
We say that God is omnisient, all- knowing, omnipotent,
all powerful, allpresent, all knowing, all powerful.
Because of the nature of the field,
then our karmic destiny is within our own hand.
There is nobody else steering the canoe except ourself.
Therefore,
God neither needs to be feared nor hated nor held
responsible.
And we alone are responsible for our own destiny.
We alone are responsible for our own karmic destiny.
And is by virtue of that that we reach freedom
and eventually resist otherwise.
If you weren't responsible,
you'd never be able to reach freedom either.
So all right.
So becoming enlightened then is just progressively seeing
all the things that we're talking about until they become
automatic.
Uh so we said that one quality of spiritual truth is it's
not p not predictive
because there's no possible way of knowing the future
if the future depends on the choices
that are being made currently by everyone on earth.
All right?
It's non authoritarian.
We let the truth speak for itself.
It's non- egoistic.
Um it's educational.
So it's primarily what we do is educational freestanding
uh and educational.
It's also devoid of induced altered states of
consciousness.
Now many people
when they become enamored of the whole spiritual
dimension are are somewhat you know bottled by all the
capabilities.
Uh and uh there are some towns that are famous for that.
you know they call them new age land
where everything that's esoteric
and sort of far out has a big following you see
and uh this is natural
because when you find begin to find out there's something
uh to life other than just the pragmatic everyday uh
so whats and the ego and logic etc and you find
that there are other dimensions
and then be people becoming enamored of other dimensions.
It's not something I recommend.
Uh why?
Because you can get lost there for a long long time.
By a long long time, I long long time.
By a long long time, I mean, you know, 500 lifetimes.
I mean,
you can get lost there for a long long time
when you start wandering off into other dimensions.
So,
what is esoteric
and what is spiritual are two different things.
So without consciousness calibration,
you can't really tell without consciousness.
And so therefore,
I don't recommend psychics
and people from other dimensions.
People from other realms and other dimensions even
if they're even if they're
so uh is the wrong direction to go be.
Why?
Because it, you know,
as it says in the Christian literature,
it's not that the other dimensions don't exist.
It's not that they don't exist.
It's just that they will lead you into the end endless
dimensions of which there is no return.
So you can keep wandering from one dimension to the next
dimension and stay there for you know millennia
because there's no return.
So there's an infinite number of other dimensions.
Let's ask that.
We have permission to ask
that there is an infinite number of other dimensions.
Resist.
Wow.
I'm glad we didn't go there for our vacation after all.
and our the town
where we come from has many woo woo people.
So, it's a woo woo heaven.
And uh no the the Bible says uh it doesn't say
that they don't exist.
It just says that not to go there.
Other you know other dimensions do exist.
So So the child in you wants to explore them.
And of course, many lifetimes later,
you're still out there
because how do you find your way back?
Having just, you know,
worked your way into another dimension.
To get back,
you would have to know how to get back from
that dimension to this dimension.
Uh, and for some there is no return.
For some, there is no return.
So,
it's not exactly something you wish wish upon yourself to
be lost.
the wandering through eternity through endless dimensions
which is what happens to some lost souls resist
which is what happens to some lost souls.
They walk through endless dimensions almost through
eternity and never to return to spiritual truth as it is.
Each dimension has its own god, its own hierarchy,
its own celebrities, its own rules and regulations.
So spiritual tradition says it is not it isn't
that there are no such dimensions.
There are but wisdom teaches not to go there.
Why?
Because you're not equipped to go there.
You're not equipped for those dimensions.
If you're equipped for those dimensions,
you wouldn't be here as a human.
You would be there as a wo wo following the great god who
if you're prostrate yourself will drive across you on
wheels.
has all kinds of channel books tell you about all these
dimensions and therefore I think uh it's best to avoid
channel books okay it's best to avoid channel books
resist all right for the spiritual safety then is the
first thing that we're interested in it isn't
that they're not correct it isn't
that they may not be true it's just
that that spiritual tradition says it's not wise to go
there.
Not wise to go there.
I got lost in the desert one time
and I realized it was not wise to go where I was.
No road back,
no way of knowing where there was a road
and the truck was out of water and I was out of water.
Wow.
So, yeah, do not go there.
All right.
uh non-egoistic teachers are respected uh
because their intention is educational.
It's self-supporting.
Uh we never solicit and never ask for donations
or anything like this.
It's freestanding uh and devoid of induced
or altered states of consciousness.
Uh you can induce these states by all kinds of uh
breathing exercises, postures, diets.
uh um invoking of other entities etc.
that's not going to take you to enlightenment at least
not uh in this lifetime.
So this advice is uh of the highest order resist all
right that advice is of the highest order.
So okay we didn't say not to do we just said it's not
going to serve the highest order.
Okay,
people who have followed the highest order of things have
uh uh over time been confirmably enlightened.
Uh and so this is a rather well-known list of spiritual
teachers.
Uh I think we repeated it again in the newest book
so that people don't have to go back
and refer to some previous book.
And these are very uh no matter how many we list,
somebody will always send me in the mail at least once a
week.
" And I'll say, "You got a hundred teachers.
Wasn't that good enough?
You got to find Nuknuk Bum Bum.
" Not that that person couldn't be so,
but it just always boggles my mind what a person will go
to to avoid the obvious.
Why?
Because these just sound mundane
and what they like is something that's wild and crazy.
All kinds of Arabian robes on and spooky postures
and wild dances and things like this
and these people just sound like hard work, you know,
instead of all the fancy dancing.
All right,
so these are very well-known teachers over time
and we've calibrated them all.
It's a very reliable list and uh these are all names
that everyone here uh recognizes.
Swami Bhananda, Eric Butterworth, John Galvin, Confucious,
uh the Dalai Lama currently living.
So these are the great names.
They calibrate up into the 700s, uh, 600s,
all the great names
and many of these we have tried to visit them at times
when they were available and meet them if we could,
you know, the current pope uh, etc.
So you don't have to be Catholic to realize
that the pope has follows some kind of spiritual
discipline and is answerable to God to the best of his
own uh intention at 570.
570 is very integrous
and uh I think the G valley Lama also calibrates around
570.
So that that's about the highest you can reach
and still function in the world.
uh beyond 570 uh there wouldn't be any interest in
functioning as the head of a world church.
You see that's a whole whole different dimension.
So the mystic is not interested in uh running a church
or a big uh spiritual organization.
um for instance at a a Bill Wilson P calibrated around
570 and uh he spiritually energized the 12step movement
uh but it wasn't run by him
and he left uh eventually of course and the move
so it it runs by virtue of the truth of its own spiritual
reality the 12step groups calerate around 540
which is the energy of healing
so healing begins to spontaneously take place in the
presence of the 12step groups.
So the 12step groups uh we speak very highly of
because uh they're devoid of worldliness and materiality.
So we'll go on to the next one.
It says uh these are all the well-known teachers.
Now has anybody got anybody on their mind
that they want calibrated who isn't up there?
>> Huh?
Right.
>> Oprah >> Oprah's about 500.
>> Oprah's about 500.
She's very uh very up there, but she's not 540.
She hasn't reached saint to it yet.
>> She's integrous and loving.
She's integrous and loving.
>> And I I've spoken to her.
>> Who's Baba?
Uh Baba G is a a fantasy.
>> Baba G is a fantasy.
Baba G Calibrates a minus his little supposedly live
alive for 500 years in the Himalayas and all this crap.
And I saw all kinds of negative effects of the belief in
Baba G and Baba G's uh uh people were were coming in you
know they got orders from Baba G
that the world was coming to an end
that New York City was going to break under 14th Street
and California was going to drop off in the ocean
and that was all Baba G.
There is no such entity as Baba G.
It's pure BS.
You may quote me.
>> What?
>> Eli Jackson.
>> I never heard of such a person.
>> Yeah.
>> Eart.
Yeah.
>> I don't want to do Edart.
>> Oh, we don't want to do Eart.
No.
Well, we've taught you all how to do this yourself.
>> The trouble with contemporary authors
and all is people have their favorites and then
if you don't say something favorable,
they're going to get on their blog.
Everybody's got to get on their blog.
You have a couple more drinks and I guess we'll tell
that guy where to go.
You know what I mean?
We'll tell that Hawkins guy where to go.
Yeah.
There we have another drink.
And here you dumb ass.
You dumb ass.
Some of the blogs we get, I'll tell you.
It's really embarrassing to be a human being.
Get to heaven.
Are you from a human being?
Uh, no.
No.
I just look like one.
I was there long enough to study them there.
Yeah.
And the ill will
that comes across is sometimes just absolutely
mindboggling.
Some former president's wife is in a serious area falling
down half dead.
What was her name?
The >> Nancy.
>> Nancy.
Yeah.
So the blog sites are wishing she would die suffering
and die soon.
And I thought, you know,
I can't imagine such malevolence
and we're supposed to hold this up
and die for free speech.
I'm supposed to die for this idiot to get on the blog
site and say a thing about Nancy Rean such as
so it said which I wouldn't say about anybody much lean.
So the downside of free speech is
that if you don't uh honor it
and keep it within certain parameters,
uh in the end you will lose it.
Isn't that right, George?
What?
George sent me something this week.
What was that a quote from?
>> Oh, doc, that was a few days ago.
I >> Oh, two days ago.
And that's forever ago in his life.
Anyway,
he sent me something uh that was very interesting
that those who don't revere and don't hold to ethics
and morality will soon lose their freedom.
So, the downside of freedom of speech is that, you know,
it's a two-edged sword.
Freedom of speech is a two-edged sword.
And people don't realize it's two-edged,
not just one-edged.
It's two-edged that you can catch your opponent,
but you can also kill yourself with the same weapon.
So,
free speech will kill somebody yourself
or somebody else unless integrity
and moral is used within the limitations of integrity
and morality, ethics and responsibility.
Yeah.
Uhhuh.
All right.
So, that's enough lecturing for today.
So, Pope Paul etc.
is 570.
Uh, Father Peformed miracles.
Wang Po who's one of my uh, old uh, heroes.
Wang Po was one of my old heroes.
Wang Po and followed the pathway of negation
which I myself followed uh, for some lifetimes actually.
And uh the the it negates it's the pathway of negation
not this not that.
The difficulty with the pathway of negation as we said
before is it will eventually take you to the void
eventually will take you to an infinite
and very impressive space.
If you negate everything that can be said
or conceptualiz conceptualized as truth,
you will get rid of a lot of falsehood to the apherisms
of have to do with negating all conceptual thought.
So Wayne Poe taught uh to let go of all conceptual
thought.
The difficulty is
that you end up in the infinite void
where Wang Po himself uh landed.
>> 15 minutes.
>> All right.
>> If we're going to do a dialogue >> now.
>> Oh, I don't know.
I was going to fill in with that.
I didn't know.
Yeah.
No, we'll have a few minutes.
>> Anyway, hang which we've described before.
I myself had been into a great a very infinite space
and the infinite space in
which I uh came on spontaneously was a field of infinite
love beyond description.
The totality of nonlinear the presence eliminated all
sense of a personal self or beginning
or endings all sense of time.
There was the realization of the divinity of the essence
of one's own existence.
The self with a capital S
which shines forth as infinite love,
timeless beyond all dimension.
So that which I am in reality experience infinite
foreverness of infinite lovingness.
So in path following the pathway of negation again in
this lifetime I again ended up in the negative in the in
the nonlinear domain of the void at n level 960
and realized the error.
I realized the error
because the infinite field of infinite love was not there.
Therefore,
I rejected it and went back and retraced my steps
and reemerged into what I had experienced before.
So, the ultimate state is one of infinite lovingness,
not of voidness.
So, the void is impressive.
The void is extremely impressive, extremely impressive.
But it is what's missing is the the love of God.
So no spiritual state is complete without the presence
then of an infinite field of love
which illuminates everything.
Everything is illuminated
because the essence of all existence is divinity
which itself is not different than infinite love.
Yeah.
So we'll go on to the next uh thing.
What does this say?
I can't read it.
I can't read what it says.
Yeah.
Huh?
I can't read it.
>> Oh, the difference between infatuation and love.
No, we didn't have that one checked.
That one's not supposed to be on there.
>> Yeah, I did.
>> I did.
Well, that was a mistake.
The difference between infatuation and love.
>> You have it right there.
>> I didn't check that.
Somebody did.
>> Yes, you did.
>> There's some other ones checked.
>> Yeah.
uh 72 spiritual practices.
>> Oh, yeah.
Okay.
All right.
Well,
that's an interesting lecture uh infatuation versus love
because what the the media Hollywood's version of it,
you know,
has to do with infatuation uh
which is an ego condition uh you know and true love
that is a way of being with the other person
and it's not a uh not an attachment.
So what the world calls love is usually an insatiable
cravingness and attachment primarily through the solar
plexus of control and possession and owning.
And if you don't reciprocate, I'll kill you.
All right,
let's move to the next
because I uh these are spiritual practices.
We just want to review the the positive effect of
spiritual practices.
Each one of them timehonored uh has uh a calibratable
calibratable reality.
Uh everything that we do everything we do in lectures you
know as you fold your hand like this you u invoke the
presence of God you acknowledge God as the creator etc.
That has a very powerful effect.
So one reason that a collection of people such as is here
today counterbalances probably the majority of man the
negativity of mankind is
because we f we follow such things
because of their the their inner reality.
The inner reality of invoking the presence
and dedicating the meeting to the divinity automatically
contextualize gives it a very powerful contextualization.
So a group like this
which is already personally spiritually oriented then
comes together as a group orientation
and a group uh choice uh becomes extremely powerful
and as we calibrated before this group alone
counterbalances uh a critical degree of negativity of all
of mankind.
uh bathing in the Ganges, the confirmation, uh baptism,
devotional acts.
You'll notice devotional because their intent,
because of the intention,
devotional acts tend to calibrate around 540,
whether it's foiling your hands or kneeling to pray.
Um and many of them tend to calibrate around 540.
Daniel flection, burning of the incense.
Uh, Gregorian chants calibrate even higher.
Uhhuh.
Uh, the Jesus prayer.
Um, kneeling to pray.
The Lord's Prayer.
650.
All right.
So, the Lord's Prayer.
Probably a great percentage of this audience does the
Lord's Prayer.
I hope everybody says their prayers before bed.
Does everybody say their prayers before bed?
>> Everybody say the Lord's prayer before bed.
Okay.
And what if you die and you're sleeping?
You didn't say the Lord's prayer.
You know what I mean?
We were kids.
We always said if we die before we wake,
we ask the Lord to take care of our spirit.
That was a a safeguard in case we forgot to say the
Lord's prayer.
Uh M.
uh pronounced asm then is a sound uh
that invokes a a relatively high degree of calibration.
740 when we do an ohm >> do an >> do an >> do my own work.
>> Yeah.
>> Everybody loves it.
>> Everybody wants to do an >> we'll all do we'll all do
an oh together.
Okay.
We'll raise the roof right off this hotel.
Nail down the roof.
Okay, let's do an M together.
For thee, O Lord, do we invoke.
Oh.
Wonderful.
Thank you so much.
>> That was wonderful.
>> And there are variations of Om.
Om shaya.
All right.
The prayerful hand class such as we just did is 540.
The prayer of St.
Francis of Aisi.
Lord, let me be a an avenue of thy will.
Saying the rosary,
surrender a death to one's will to God is extremely
important.
Now when we talk about willpower,
when we talk about willpower, when you use willpower,
your your willpower is going the power your your
willpower is going the power of the willpower is going to
be the power of whatever your level of consciousness is
right now.
So let's say you calibrate at 340.
If you try to use something called willpower against
anything,
uh now your willpower is going to be at level 340.
If on the other hand you surrender
and you say I myself am powerless
and you turn your will over to the power of God surrender
the world will God calibrates much uh higher surrender at
depth one's will to God's will is 850
so if you surrender your will to God's will in the matter
then the personal will is supplanted by the will of God
so to Invoke the will of God then is much different than
trying to handle it on your own.
Now when you invoke the will of God,
you are surrendering the outcome.
" That's because you're trying to impose your will
and and now call it God's will.
When you surrender to God's will,
you'll either recover or you won't.
So God's will may not be the same as your will.
So people say well I prayed to God
and I used willpower
and what happened is uh something uh
that I didn't want to happen
but what you happened was of a higher nature even
though it may have looked to your ego like a loss
that you lost a certain position
or you lost a certain relationship
because in the higher dimension for you to move on
that was a necessary step to So
when we surrender to God's will rather than our personal
will, we bring in enormous power.
Surrendering to God's will
and invoking the will of God calibrates at 850.
Surrender to God's will at 850.
Uh now we know that the addictions uh many of the
addictions uh calibrate extremely high.
So, you're addicted to alcohol, drugs, sex,
whatever it happens to be.
Uh, eating tomatoes at 3 in the morning, whatever it is,
when you try to battle it with your personal will,
you can see that your your your power is limited.
So, the the your your power is limited.
So, the the the great 12step groups and such as those,
you know,
one step is you surrender your will to to God as you
understand them.
So you surrender your personal will to God's will.
So it's important to realize the difference in power
between your your will and God's will.
But if you surrender it to God's will then you can't
determine the outcome.
You can't determine the outcome.
You have to surrender to God's will
and whatever will be will be
because not going the way you would choose might serve a
higher purpose than the way in
which you you were hoping it would resolve.
You see having it come out in a certain way might be uh
just what the ego has been looking for.
So surrendering to God's will then is extremely powerful
and I always like to emphasize it.
Surrender at depth one's will to God is 850.
The person doing that their own will may be only at 350.
So when you give up bucking it with your own personal
will to that of the ego,
you open the open the soothways for the power of God.
All right.
Walking the labyrinth is sort of a very interesting
phenomena and uh calibrates at 503.
We were at Shark Cathedral
and got to uh witness the phenomena.
And of course they what they do is they the labyrinth
they leave the chairs out across there
so you can't walk the labyrinth
because in Char Cathedral
if they didn't put chairs over the labyrinth everybody be
walking around the labyrinth all day long they wouldn't
be able to sell any souvenirs anyway they do allow at
certain times walking the labyrinth alone is over 500
What is held in mind tends to manifest calibrates over
500.
So it's not a great discovery, nor is it something new.
It's everybody's known
that what you're holding in mind tends to manifest.
>> Five minutes.
Do we have any charts left?
Is this it?
Oh.
Oh, I see.
Uhhuh.
Oh, yes.
This is talking about the state of illumination itself
which comes about as a inner profound radiating sense of
peace.
It's experienced as though there's an inner light.
It's called luminous for a good reason.
It is feeling as though a light has come up from within.
So instead of light coming from without the way the world
looks or coming from your thinkingness now there's an
inner radiance and in a high state as you walk through
nature you see the radiance shining forth from all of
nature and you become aware
that as you walk by the trees and the grasses
and the flowers that they're aware of your existence.
Yeah.
Uh that which I witnessed and experienced is a fact.
All of nature is aware of the divinity of the essence of
that which you are.
Resist.
Yeah.
You see, you see it as you walk forth.
You realize that the trees and the grasses
and everything that you think is unconscious is conscious.
What is it conscious of?
It's conscious of uh your existence as a reflection of
divinity.
So the the trees actually reverence your presence.
The trees actually reverence your presence.
Resist.
Yeah.
It's not poetic.
It's actual uh fact.
Uhhuh.
So the illuminated state is one of
which the re the divinity of all
that exists radiates forth.
It's eulgent.
What happens is you let go of the ego progressively.
Uh suddenly there's a collapse.
There's a feeling as though you're dying.
The feeling of the dying is merely the the illusion of
the personal self.
The real you is not dying.
In fact, the real you is not even capable of dying.
So anytime you think you're dying, you're wrong.
The real you can't die.
So feeling that one is dying is the dissolution of the
ego and it can be quite terrifying.
Therefore having let go of everything the only thing left
is the sense of self.
The sense of self,
all that was left of that is the source of life.
That within me is the s source of life itself.
And if I turn over life to God, I will surely die.
And then came the knowingness from some lifetime.
The aura of the teacher.
So the value of the aura of the teacher is the
knowingness transcends all eons of time.
The knowingness exists as a vibration and a frequency
and then when it's needed it shines forth.
So in that state I thought there I have turned everything
over to divinity.
There's nothing left except uh life itself.
This too I must surrender to thee.
Oh Lord, this too my life I must surrender to thee.
And then I surrendered the core of the ego
which is convinced that it is the source of your life
and a terrible state of terror befell me as I felt myself
dying.
And then on the other side suddenly the door of splendor
opened up and all of existence shown forth as uh the
revelation of the presence of God.
All that is is a rad is a reflection of the radiance of
divinity in its infinite beauty and perfection.
Yes.
And that is uh then the completion of the road of the
mystic.
Yes.
Illuminated state.
Uhhuh.
The emergence into a oneness.
But there is a radiance and a shining forth.
There's a radiance and a shining forth.
" Because it's self-revealing.
The divinity of all that exists shines forth.
The divinity of this room, of the people here,
the divinity of this person here,
the divinity of all all of you out there,
the divinity of the essence of this meeting
and our reason for being here.
We are each other's blessing
because we all represent consciousness,
divinity expressing itself through the human domain.
As that which we are to merely be here,
we are serving God and serving each other.
We are serving divinity.
So we acknowledge the divinity of thy presence, O Lord,
and give thanks.
Amen.
>> Amen.
Oh, what do we do now?
What's next?
>> Um, we're going to take a quick break.
Um, we're going to take a quick break right now.
If you want to start lining up, you can.
Oh, and uh, we'll take it'll be about 15 minutes.
>> We're going to take a quick break.
Then we're going to do questions and answers.