Hey, come back here. Come back here.
Those of you are trying to escape.
Come back here. We have your number.
Number 292, you're going to get it.
Imagine if you were part of that Olympic
festival, the 7,000 people, and
everybody moves like this and you go
like that.
Never heard from again.
motivation is so profoundly important.
Yes.
We thought of two funny stories or one
funny story. This where this Fourth of
July parade is going by and everybody
this is in America. Fourth of July
parade goes by the troops
and one one idiot is out of step with
all of them. And the mother sitting in
the audience says, "Look, they're all
out of step except Herbert.
That's America. America. They're all out
of sight except Herbert.
Intention is profoundly important."
Uh
the athlete, the athlete, of course,
what's his motivation?
Now we saw the crowd was to be part of
the one. You see, but the athlete, isn't
he just looking for me me? Uh well, and
there we made a major discovery. The
athlete who runs for the
the athlete who runs for out of runs for
the sake of his country, his college,
his class, his wife, his children, the
athlete who runs for the sake of a
higher good. You see the the the name of
the university
uh the country
that the athlete will do his will do him
will do him. The athlete who runs for
the goodness of others uh has a over8
seconds.9
seconds one second has a 9/10 of a
second lead. So you see two runners, one
is running for the university or running
for the China or running for the pride
of Germany, whatever.
And at the starting gun, the one with a
higher motivation already has 9/10 of a
second lead. Isn't that something to
know?
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
>> Hey, there we go.
So it it influences our performance.
The intention. So if you look at the
intention behind your performances,
always look for a higher good to which
you can see yourself blending into
increasing your joy and the significance
and the meaning of what you are doing.
You see, if you invent a bad a better
gadget, it's to make uh other people
happy, uh convenient, uh be kind to the
housewives fingers, whatever. If the
chopper chops it, then she won't chop
her fingers. So, you think of all the
wives who won't cut themseling knife
with this chopping machine. In other
words, try to hold the highest
motivation you can uh behind all of your
efforts to do it for the glory of of God
of course is the highest of all. So
those who dedicate all of their energies
and efforts
to thee, oh Lord most high.
So when we give this lecture, we do it
in the name of the O Lord most high. The
O Lord most high. So in the very
beginning we state we make a declaration
of our intention that a group such as
this meets uh for the glory of God and
to reflect that glory in in all all his
ways and we carry that in into the daily
world by our reverence for life itself.
So we have reference for all that
exists, all that exists, even if we
don't understand why it exists. I don't
know why the Komoda dragon is what he
is, but he serves there some kind of an
evolutionary purpose. And uh so we rever
revere all of life and all of its
expressions every and then that by doing
that the beauty of all that exists
reveals itself
in this lifetime. The beauty of all that
exists revealed itself very suddenly
very suddenly from an ordinary state of
consciousness. It's like the veil was
removed and I was stunned speechless and
thoughtless.
It took years to think again.
Think again. Yeah. Then I began to
realize that even thoughts can be of a
higher purpose and it's okay to think.
My respects the Wangpole.
How many people here are familiar with
Wang Po? Oh, good for you. You're going
to heaven. How pe how many people are
not familiar with Wang Poe? Boo
boo
poo poo.
Well, Hang Po was one of my heroes when
I was young.
Socrates and
and Huang Po were my heroes. Other
people were into baseball, I guess.
Socking of our I told you about my my
childhood. You know, the coach told me
to stay off the field.
He said, "They'll break you up break you
up in small pieces, the first tackle."
And so I was forbidden to go out on the
field during uh contact sports, you
know,
and the doctor wouldn't approve me. He
said with clavicles like that, they'll
bust the first time somebody bucks you.
So
I was uh I was stuck with Wang Poe and
Plato and Socrates and
Uripides and all those old-fashioned uh
people. Yes. me.
Well, I'm glad I'm not running for
office is all I can say
because I understand if you're wrinkled
and old.
I got the biggest kick out of those
political blogs. He's he's old and he's
wrinkled
and has white hair. So, you don't want
to vote for somebody who has white hair
and is old and wrinkled. Of course not.
You know, but I thought that is so
funny. You know that would get rid of
all some of the greatest minds in
history. So when you get wrinkle, they
throw you away.
That's why I go to the beauty parlor.
There's a wrinkle there. I saw one.
Oh yeah.
So we talked we've talked in previously
previously about uh allegiance.
Allegiance
is no longer to the truth. Allegiance is
to a popularity.
And in its more more elaborate term,
it's a dedication to an ism.
Environmentalism.
Environmentalism will eventually kill
all of life on the planet if carried to
its ultimate extreme.
All that carbon and the atmosphere is
good. If it wasn't for all the carbon
and the calatus and the prairies,
life would come to an end. I think it's
so funny. Anyway, religious to isms
and I point out it go in many lectures,
you know, the the book extraordinary
extraordinary popular delusions in the
madness of crowds, you know, becau
because of its recurrent meaning. The
fact that everybody believes it doesn't
have anything to do with the fact that
it's truthful or not, you know, and
global warming is probably the the
biggest uh current illusion. It's very
popular so everybody's in for it. Uh but
of course what we've taught in previous
lectures is now scientifically
validated. In fact this week it said
the temperature of the earth is due to a
cyclic changes in the surface magnetic
activity of the sun. Now we said that
few years ago. So I just you like to see
confirmation because otherwise you sound
like a a madman.
You sound like a nut. And uh I'm a
respectable nut. I doctor's degree. So
the other thing that's currently
popular, these extraordinary delusions
become very popular and they become
dominant. You wonder how society even
survives. Well, it doesn't
frequently. It doesn't.
mankind has been at war 93% of uh of uh
of past time. Uh one of the current the
other current popular delusion
environmentalism
is um cultural Marxism. Cultural Marxism
is now uh very popular and has to do
with victim perpetrator illusion. It has
to do with the see car marks you see on
the calibrated levels of the
consciousness
they're all in the mid to high 400s and
marks calibrated at 130 so he stands out
like a sore thumb
and cultural Marxism that is now the
refined Marxism with the name Marxist
removed and is the product now of a
philosophic school a German philosophic
school, the Frankfurt school. So the
Frankfurt school then taught all all. So
the modern universities
are an output of cultural Marxism.
Um by virtue of Herbert Marcus. So all
of them calibrate like 180 or 190. So
you see the modern university.
This is an exceptional university. This
is a
a division of NAU and uh we find that
the community colleges now calibrate in
the 400s and the great universities
calibrate below 200.
All the great universities with the
great names all calibrate below 300.
Let's see if that's true.
All the great name, what do you call
those universities? uh elite Ivy League
all calibrate below 200 resist
all calibrate below 200.
The rise and fall of civilizations then
becomes apparent that a new mass
delusion overtakes the populace.
Harvard, Yale,
Princeton,
all the great universities
calibrate below 200.
I'm glad I don't have any college age
kids.
But if I did, I'd send him to this
college. Yes. Because this college
calibrates around 440.
So
not being a populist. So they re they
target these great universities because
of the power of their name. So
propagandists know that the name Harvard
will impress lots of people. Yale,
Princeton, you see
what's the name of this college here?
>> Huh?
>> Yavapai College. Could you get elected
president if you went to Gavapai
College?
You'd be out of step with the popular
world. The popular world calibrates 170.
Steel doesn't melt. Calibrates at 160.
I hate to say it, but steel does melt.
That's how they make railroad ties.
Railroad tracks. Uhhuh.
So you see this endless struggle for
dominance
and for control. So politics is all
about the struggle for dominance and the
struggle for control. And of course once
you have dominance and struggle and
control, you can then milk the milk it
for uh zillions of dollars. And it's f
what always amazes me is this politician
has been you know
has been sued arrested put away etc for
um you know taking massive bribery you
know Alaska let's say or some place and
and then what amazes me is the next
election he's reelected
put away for fraud
skull dodgery
high crimes and misdemeanors
and he's reelected.
Therefore, Socrates dictim is that uh
that a democracy cannot last more than a
couple hundred years. Our democracy is
what 300 years old.
that rarely and in fact practically
never does a democracy last more than
two or 30 hundred years because the
people cannot tell truth from falsehood
because they are so easily deceived by
the wolf and sheep's clothing.
Anything that's plausible and especially
with today's media, you can be
brainwashed innocently while you're
brushing your teeth.
Or you're brushing your teeth, you're
being brainwashed.
always turn your TV off when you're
brushing your teeth
because you're being control, you're
being manipulated. So the mind of modern
man then is not only fallen to a
critical level but is uh susceptible and
this is because of the innoc inner
innocence of the child.
The innocence of the child. So mankind
has intuited this and throughout time
has saw it. Uh great teachers those are
the great teachers Jesus Christ and
Socrates and and Buddha and modus Moses
and uh
the the great teachers of all time. So
when traditional wisdom was revered, you
were somewhat protected from modern
fallacy and nonsense
because it was always compared in the
back of your mind with the teaching of
Jesus Christ let's say or Socrates or
some great being.
Uh and without a traditional education
now there is no inner guideline. There
is no inner guideline.
So we see the Marxist ideology projected
onto all of society.
The Marxist duality is perpetrator and
victim. And in that indoctrination,
the minority is always the victim of the
majority.
That's the way Markx looked at it. So we
have the victim now. The victimology
and the moral high ground is to claim
yourself a greater victim than somebody
else.
So I'm glad wrinkled old men are getting
to be victims. Gives me a shot.
Gives me a shot at being victim. Oh boy.
I had to wait a long time to be victim,
you know.
Oh.
All right. So, what's the appeal? What
you say to yourself? What is the appeal
of politics? Aside from the juice that
they get out of it, it's obviously the
struggle for do dominance and the inner
inner narcissism projected onto the
world.
We mentioned the 9/10en of a second
advantage. Yes. Yes, we did mention
that. Yes. I wanted to make sure I
didn't forget that. Uh,
of course, whether you're a liberal or a
conservative is partly a reflection of
your of your age. You see, if you're not
a liberal when you're young, you've got
no heart. If you're still liberal when
you're old, you've got no brain.
Whereas because the mind is struck by
the glamour of causes. So let's say if
environmentalism
is a laudatory cause, everybody wants to
get on the bandwagon
and prevent cattle from passing gas on
the plane.
Serreptitiously they pass methane of
course and so the environmentalists want
us all to become vegetarians and that'll
stop the cattle flatus from
contaminated and I I don't know what you
do on a subway car but anyway
All right. So, it's proof versus spoof.
Proof versus spoof.
The media are experts at spoof and how
to program you so that you'll believe
the exact opposite of truth.
And once you know how to calibrate
things, of course, it's fun to watch the
daily news and calibrate what is the
level of that testimony of that witness.
Uh, did that person commit that crime or
not? Are they guilty or not guilty? Is
the body under the cement slab? You know
what I'm saying?
Of course, you can't tell others about
what you've discovered. So, and the
other thing about our technique for
telling truth from whole so it is
discretion. People
do not welcome truth.
People do not welcome truth. They
welcome what they have a narcissistic
investment in.
They are not interested in truth.
And if you want to get yourself killed,
just go around spouting truth everywhere
you go.
You're lucky if you get across the room.
Truth is not popular. No. What's popular
is popularity. Oh, okay.
What's popular? So, everyone wants to be
part of the crowd. Everybody it's so
it's really the herd instinct. So, if we
view mankind then with his limitations
and his evolution out of the animal
kingdom.
Then we see what captivates the mind of
the most of humanity most of the time is
the herd instinct. If everybody believes
that, if everybody believes the catalus
is going to bring the planet to a a
halt, then you can see how you become a
vegetarian. Yeah.
What's the death rate of vegetarians?
All the vegetarians I ever knew are
dead. So, I don't know.
They used to all the health nuts I ever
knew. That's a fact. every one of them.
And I used to I've told you about them
before. We called them the brown
baggers.
And they would all sit in the back of
the lunch room, you know, and they had a
brown bag. And in there there was
organic brown rice.
And then they would go out and jog. So
between organic brown rice and jogging,
they're all dead.
All the all my brown bagger colleagues
are dead. Resist.
All of them.
They're all dead. Huh?
If you believe everything out there is
going to kill you, it will.
All right.
Okay. So the credibility of authority is
also uh today authority is viewed with
great suspicion and it's more important
to be aligned with some cause and uh and
the other thing that spiritual people
have to walk by the trap. You see,
there's a walking through the swamp
and there's a depiction of the soul um
evolving soul walking through the swamp
and the seductions at one side and the
seductions at the other. The seductions
that you walk through and one is the
seduction of the astral circus and the
astral circus also has very high in
glamour and people who channel all kinds
of entities etc.
And it isn't whether they do so or not.
Occasionally one is Integris. There's
one very famous one. She calibrates
around 350 and she is extremely psychic
as a fact. It's a possibility.
But the entity on the other side, I
always say if it was an evolved entity,
it wouldn't be hanging out here trying
to control people on the planet. I would
have gone on to a higher realm rather
than speaking through some trans medium.
So I did things that come about in a
somewhat unnatural way then very often
serve some other purpose and you really
have to calibrate the integrity. It's
not just the entity on the other side
but what does the entity on the other
side calibrate at?
So it's best to avoid that which is uh
the glamour of specialness. The glamour
of specialness. You know I listen to
yogi baba on the other side. You know
he's been there 10,000 years and uh and
now what
that the entity on the other side
gets a a vitalization out of power over
others. got all these stupid
uh humans listening to their advice. So
if you have a teacher on the other side,
always calibrate that teacher. It's not
that there aren't any good teachers on
the other side, but you should know that
within the context that that is an
entity on the other side who's getting
off on controlling people. And you
should always always uh calibrate Master
Hoo
proof versus spoof. Okay. As the
attraction of the astral circus.
Uh and of course that is put down you
know to naive people as new aism.
When we're new to the uh spiritual
world, the what strikes us there is a
certain reality to the paranormal to
things that are not within the
scientific domain of proof and u that
there are things that are inexplicable.
So the Bible says and it it agrees that
there are things there is the beyond the
paranormal
and it doesn't condemn it. It just says
don't go there. Don't go there. You're
not equipped. You're not equipped to
handle entities from other dimensions.
Nobody here is equipped to handle
entities from other dimensions. Let's
see if that's a fact. Nobody here is
equipped to handle entities from other
dimensions. Resist.
So out of humility then the teacher says
avoid that which is beyond your
comprehension because they come from
other dimensions and their idea of
reality and their motivations and in
their style of functioning is totally
out of your domain
and the presumptions that you make are
facious. you've projected that onto the
entity. It is no particular interest in
your survival or your spiritual
evolution or your enlightenment.
A successful student
would quickly quit the teacher from the
other side. So the last thing a teacher
on the other sides is for you to become
spiritually ariodite because they just
lost the follower.
Yeah, that's true.
We have paradigm blindness. We have
paradigm blindness. The other difficulty
the human mind has, not only its
narcissism,
uh the trusting uh child, the trusting
child within but what we call paradigm
blindness.
What is true in one paradigm is not true
in another paradigm.
And paradigm includes then the overall
level of consciousness.
What's true in one paradigm is not true
in another paradigm. So the difficulty
of the doubter the traditional skeptic
is usually coming from lower mind which
deals only in the linear linear
provability
and spiritual dimensions are nonlinear
not provable.
That which is provable
is of a different dimension. So you
cannot disprove
the nonlinear using arguments from the
linear. And that's why the skeptic only
calibrates about 170. And all the
debunkers, there's only one or two
debunkers that are actually integrous.
There's only a few of them. The rest of
them just get a ego kick out of trying
to imitate what's real. And then because
they've imitated it, they assume they
have disproven it. Yeah. Because you can
imitate a thing doesn't mean you've
disproven it. It just means you've
learned how to imitate a thing. And the
great Randy, for instance, is a stage
magician. Stage magician.
Therefore, coming from the linear, you
can neither prove nor disprove the
nonlinear. In all spiritual reality,
all understanding of divinity and
spiritual truth, you know, is of a
different dimension than the linear. The
linear is provable and demonstrable.
The nonlinear is more profound and
diffuse and of course greatly alters.
You can show its effect like the
starting time at the the starting gun.
9/10 of a second is quite a delay. Quite
a delay when you're in a 100 yard dash.
9/10 of a second will lose you the race.
So it's a profound influence on our
behavior and our understanding our
motivation.
The most
powerful motivation is to live with
kindness and love towards all living
things. You try to understand and even
things we don't approve of, you can
still recognize the intention.
If China considers conformity,
conformity,
dedication of the personal to the to the
allness of of the country, it sounds
somewhat egotistical to critical to crit
criticize it. So I didn't agree with any
negative comments or chiding
uh spoken by any attendees at it because
you're speaking of a different culture
and therefore we have a re certain
intrinsic reverence towards all
cultures.
The more you know about a culture, the
greater the reverence. The Native
American culture is extremely reverent.
And
you could say, well, they're just
ignorant savages. What do they know?
But they are profoundly spiritual. So
before you kill a deer, you apologize to
the deer. You dedicate it to the highest
good. And therefore because of the
intention the killing of the deer for
food you know is no longer a negative
act but uh it becomes
uh spiritualized. So the spirituality of
the native American is extremely high
and of course all of mankind has
intuited a higher power since the
beginning of recorded time.
All all cultures and civilizations
even though widely separated from each
other in time and space
uh acknowledge the divinity of divinity.
There is no successful still existent
culture that does not acknowledge the
divinity of divinity.
And some people try to substitute the
state. But then what do they worship?
They worship the state. Whether you
worship communism, the state of
communism, or whether you worship
divinity, you are still worshiping
something greater than your personal
self. So that's already a step even if
you do it for the communist ideal. Then
workers, you have nothing to lose but
your chains becomes uh uplifting becomes
uplifting. So a thing is not either this
or that in and of itself
but what we make of it and how we
comprehend it and how we contextualize
it. So context makes all the difference.
It's context that makes a difference
about that 9/10 of a second uh starting
delay. You know when the gun fires off
9/10 of a second you you've just missed
winning the the race. Just missed it.
You've just
9 9/10 of a second you've just lost the
100 yard dash. Huh? So, how does man how
does mankind get into such a
difficult uh interpretation?
The the the defectiveness of humankind
uh makes you humble.
I uh there's the example of what I call
the lying eyes.
If you take witnesses of a crime and
then you do a you know they show the
pictures of all these various criminals
the identification of the guilty guilty
person is facious 50% of the time.
There was a great project to free
prisoners on death row and uh it was
very important because the guy's on
death row because he was identified by
two or three witnesses. Then it turns
out all of them were lying eyes.
The lying eyes caliber is occurs let's
see what percent of the time
identification of criminal suspects
witnesses are wrong over 50% of the time
50% of the time
55% of the time
50% of the time 50% of the time three
people say I saw him do it now he's in
prison and 50% of the time he's wrong.
Even your own perception, you can't
trust.
Everybody's going to be a mess after
this lecture.
Can't tell truth from spoof. You can't
believe your own lying eyes.
Can't trust wrinkled old men. I don't
know.
All right. How do we arrive at this?
Well, there are several explanations.
Probably the most the most uh profound
of them and the one that I tend to agree
with is uh the effect of karma. Yes. The
most profound effect of all is karma.
Most profound effect of all is karma.
and say, "Well, Christianity uh doesn't
believe in karma. Western civilization
doesn't believe in karma."
Christianity does believe in karma. It's
because of the Garden of Eden. If it
wasn't for the garden, the fall of man
in the Garden of Eden, you wouldn't need
a savior. There wouldn't be any sin.
Though, what was the problem in the
Garden of Eden? The problem is usually
presented as disobedience of God's edict
not to eat of the tree of wisdom. Yes.
But the serpent came along and
said to the woman, "Eat. It's okay.
You'll be fine."
And she did.
That was the fall of man. And then they
noticed they had no clothes on.
and they were naked and hid in shame.
So, how did that come about? What
explains the fall of man in that uh
historic tradition?
Is it evil? Was it disobedience? No. I
see the innocence of Eve.
What the serpent knew was the innocence,
the inner innocence of the child. The
serpent said, "Oh, it'll be all right.
Trust me, you this is a fine thing to
do. And so the serpent wasn't saying
defy God. The serpent was saying to the
inner child and Eve, trust me,
everything will be fine. Yes. And that
was the beginning in the Christian
tradition then. So when they say
Christianity doesn't believe in karma,
don't you believe them. If it wasn't for
original sin and the Garden of Eden,
there wouldn't be any need for penance.
There wouldn't be any need for penance.
There'd be nothing to feel guilty about
and we'd all be enlightened.
We'd all be enlightened.
So the serpent then was
the source of falsehood. So falsehood
came in and spoofed Eve's innocence.
And being herself an innocent woman, why
should she suspect that the serpent was
up to some nefarious intention?
So that's why I teach about the serpent
to beware of the serpent.
Beware of the serpent because that which
is cunning and sly and deceptive
tends to be able to sense where you're
vulnerable. And that vulnerability
again is that intrinsically we all have
the innocence of the child within us.
The pure subjectivity of consciousness
itself.
The structure of the mind is such that
it cannot tell one from another. The
computer, the mind's computer can become
programmed with falsehood as easily. So
we all have intrinsically the innocence
of the computer. The computer doesn't
say, "Oh, I think I'll record this and
not record this."
The computer of the human mind
automatically
records all that it is presented with
whether it's facious or true. It has no
means of discernment.
Spiritual evolution then comes from
studying advanced spiritual teachings
and advancing by intention. So by one's
intention one already is progressing
already progressing by virtue of
intention and then when one reaches a
certain level of consciousness that
which is the that which is the sheep's
clothing and that which is innocence uh
become apparent. That's at level 600. At
level 600 the third eye of the Buddha
body is what it's classically called.
That's when the atheric bodies of both
the crown chakra
opens and now one instantly can
recognize falsehood and deception. Yes.
From that time on you're protected.
You're protected by the presence of the
divine spirit in the capacity
to discern essence.
So that's the story of the garden of
Eden.
Because of the innocence. Because of the
innocence. Then Christ taught that
sin is nothing but primarily ignorance.
Sin is ignorance. Sin is error. So the
original meaning of the term sin is
error. Error. To be an error.
To realize the innocence of the inner
child of everyone who exists.
It gives us a capacity
to be forgiving towards all people no
matter what. So the person who thinks
that he's doing God a favor, worshiping
God by killing me
because I'm a non-believer.
I still recognize the, you know, the
validity of his intention. If the way to
worship God is to kill all
non-believers,
then I can see the innocence,
I differ with the correctness of it, but
I can see the innocence.
So
if he kills you, you just say it's okay.
I understand.
That's what we did. We did that.
I told you about a past life I remember
during the Crusades. And this same
entity and I have had interactions over
many lifetimes.
And I killed him for Jesus and he killed
me for Allah.
It was during the Crusades through and
through and through and through and we
both fell over and our body went out of
the physical body and we broke out
laughing at each other.
He said, "I did it for Allah." And I
said, "I did it for Jesus." And then we
laughed and laughed and
the naivity of the human mind as a out
of his devotion to God he killed me and
I acknowledged that and therefore I've
had great respect for that entity and uh
we killed each other for God and for
so even those who blow us up even those
who blow us up if they are doing it from
that intention I can forgive them.
However, I'm not going to hang out with
them
or invite them to lunch.
What is it we're supposed to do with
those people? There's some politically
correct thing. We're supposed to
accommodate them. Yes. All right. All
right. Let other people accommodate
them. Frankly, I'm going to eat it in a
different restaurant than where they
hang out.
This may be the day they're going to
blow up the restaurant to get rid of all
these.
So truth depends on con context.
The the overall intention then sets an
overall field. So the nonlinear sets the
field whether a thing is good or evil
cannot be discerned by looking at the
thing itself but only in context. Only
in context.
uh
yeah and we have in in today's society
of course the conspiracy theorists and
the logic proof delusional disorder. So
many of society's problems you say they
closed the mental hospitals many years
ago that was also cultural Marxism
come came through a guy named Thomas Zaz
popularized it to say that mental
illness was only a label
and therefore they closed all the mental
hospitals. So all the people who were
dangerous
are now wandering the street and uh
killing people right and left. So it
used to be out of compassion that you
you protected people from their own
limitation.
I could tell them in if I let this guy
out, I know exactly what he's going to
do. So it isn't just the safety of
others. So the criteria was that this
person is safe with his own self, the
capacity to survive and look after your
own basic needs. So some we kept in the
hospital until they got well enough that
they could survive on their own, that
they had enough uh wits they could
survive on their own. So it wasn't just
because of labeling, it was survival. So
now they become drug addicted and and uh
hang out on the sidewalk and commit
crimes and uh get murdered and murder
each other and they all end up in jail.
So we saw at the bottom of the list of
the levels of consciousness.
The average consciousness in prison is
around 65. Yes. Is that right? The
average consciousness in prison is
around 65. Yeah, that's correct number.
Consciousness level 65.
Can a person survive out there with a
consciousness level of 65?
Out of humanitarian consideration, we'd
say this person needs to be protected
until they're more capable of protecting
themsel, remembering to take their
medication, remembering to see the
doctor staying out of the way of crime,
etc. Yeah. So the intention then is the
good and the welfare of all. The good
and the welfare all. So out of kindness.
So the one spiritual dictim that we stay
by is out of love and consideration and
reverence for all of life. And let that
be the overall context of your own
valition.
We the reason we do all that we do is
for the for the good of all all. People
say, "What can I do to, you know, help
help the world?" And um, well, you could
stay out of out of the way.
Get off the highway. No,
the intention then the intention,
it's what you have become. So, we showed
by the the chart we showed with the
pyramid. It's what you have become that
compensates for the negativity.
So, the negativity of the world would be
so overwhelming. It would destroy
mankind except for people like
yourselves sitting here now. You realize
that without you, millions would die.
Millions. Yes. Without this crowd here
assembled. This crowd here assembled. I
have permission to ask this. Millions
would die.
Millions would die were it not because
in the pyramid there's that small top.
Then there's the balance, the little
bitty pyramid over here and the great
mass of mankind here to give greater
worth and value. That your spiritual
work, you know, is not just for your own
spiritual
advancement.
But by seeking spiritual truth, you are
serving all of mankind
by your own search for enlightenment and
for spiritual truth. You are serving all
of mankind.
Millions would die were it not for you.
By your own search for enlightenment,
you benefit all of mankind.
You benefit all of mankind.
The depiction of a Buddhist type
meditation is gazing at your own navl
there for is incorrect.
It is for the good and the welfare of
all mankind that we seek the highest
truth and seek to become at one with
that truth. We seek to become the
expression of that truth. So as you pass
all be all beautiful things you
acknowledge their beauty and at a
certain level of consciousness you have
to be care you have to actually avoid
that because the beauty of things just
knocks you out. Just like a loving
glance between two people. It's just you
cannot handle it. It just makes you
weep. And you you're careful not to look
at the flowers because they're stunning
perfection.
Oh god. Oh
that was created by God.
That was created by God.
That flower
was created by God.
So you sense the divinity
within all of creation.
And out of reverence for divinity,
you're then reverent towards all of
creation,
all of a
previous life. And you say to the
headsman, don't feel about badly about
what you're doing. It's your duty to the
crown.
So you put your head on the block and as
the headsman comes down, you bless them.
You're doing your duty. You recognize
it's his honor. It's his honor that he
serves the crown.
and people of that era. It was it was a
mark of honor to serve the crown rather
than your own personal self. So even the
headspin as he comes over you can bless
him
and you tell him don't feel badly about
what you're doing. You're a man of honor
and you're serving the crown.
He goes home feeling happy.
Her
wife says, "Harold,
how did it go today?"
He said,
"That was her answer. How'd it go today,
Harold?"
Snap. Off it goes. You know, and we've
demonstrated how if you live within the
present instant, no such thing as a
problem can arise.
Every instant is complete and total
within itself.
There no problem can exist in the in the
present.
You have some illness. Well, is it going
to kill you now? No. Then what are you
sobbing and crying about? You know what
I'm saying?
If you leave live in this instant, this
instant now that you're not capable of a
problem. It's only when you project
yourself into the future and fear and
control or you project yourself into the
past with regret and blame and guilt. If
you live in this instant,
no problem is possible in this instant.
Let's see if that's a fact.
That's a fact. The Lord
God said,
>> huh?
Yeah. Anyway, so
by understanding, you see, understanding
causality
that all things come into being by
virtue of that which they are. And you
see the whole scientific view of
causality
is there's a this causing a this causing
a this which goes back through time. And
if you check it out, you find any single
event has 10 million causes. If it
wasn't for this room, this couldn't be
here. I wouldn't be here. We wouldn't be
talking. You wouldn't be able to hear my
voice, etc.
It takes uh 10 million items to account
for any occurrence.
All occurrences are happening
spontaneously as a consequence of the
evolution of consciousness as a
consequence of that which you are.
So the ultimate realization or the
teaching the uh the purpose of our
teaching is to bring to your awareness
that there is no one doing doing what is
happening. The presumption of the ego is
there is a me a separate eye that is
causing this to happen.
a more advanced consciousness. If you
catch it, you will realize that that
happened on its own. There is no
personal self.
Is that my personal self?
Look in the mirror. Look at this. Is
that me?
All that happens autonomously
as a consequence of that which you have
become. Uh this is the content and the
context is the level of consciousness.
There is no personal separate self
separate from the one.
That's one reason why when you become a
part of an Olympic demonstration,
there's a feeling of elation
because at least momentarily
you've escaped the narcissistic egotism
and limitation of a personal eye being
the star. Yeah.
What's happening is now selflessness
the self with a capital S
evolving then so all things come about
as a consequence of the totality
of all that has ever been including that
which you have become. Everything is
happening spontaneously.
There is no personal self that's a cause
of anything.
If there's no personal self that's a
cause of anything, then what is the
karma? What happens to the dilitterious
karmic con consequences?
There isn't any.
You leave this world stupid, you come
back to the next life stupid.
What's the problem?
So evolution proceeds over great
expanses of time. great expanses of
time. And the karmic the karmic
inheritance
is one of propensity. Propensity. Nobody
is forced to do anything. You're dealing
with likelihoods.
So karmic propensities. I always I don't
speak of karma. I always speak of karmic
propensity.
The inclination is to get even with the
son of a He deserves it.
And then because of spiritual training
and interference, there's a hesitation.
Perhaps there is another way of looking
at it.
Sermon on the mountain flashes through
your mind and you forgive him and you
say, "I will not pull the trigger." Yes,
I will not pull the trigger.
Everything is happening within itself.
So you can picture yourself. I like I
like picturing picturing yourself as a
magnetic filing and the will of God the
whole field of consciousness is is power
is infinite unlimited and therefore
what happens and what happens within you
and around you and to you is a
consequence of what you have become
interacting in a field. So here's a
powerful magnetic field in which all of
us are polarized. this is our good side
or good karma side or our bad karma
side. We say screw you. We go down to
the bad karma side. We say, "Oh yeah,
but you couldn't help it." Now we go to
the good karma side. So we're constantly
moving in this infinite field.
So it's a field of propensities and
likelihoods. It's not a field of
causality.
Even if you have the karma of some
greatly negative thing, you're not
coerced. You don't have to. So we all
have within ourself a spiritual freedom.
We are always free to choose choose
differently this time. Let's see if
that's a fact. We always we exist in a
constant state of spiritual freedom.
Is she telling me the truth?
We all live in a state of absolute inner
freedom
in an energy field of infinite power.
And when we align with that power, we
then radiate out a goodness to the world
which benefits all of mankind.
So by alignment and by intention, a
group such as this is profoundly
affecting the lives of millions of
people.
That should get rid of the question,
what can I do to help the world?
Don't do anything.
Just be what you are to the fullest
capacity. And therefore, you're
fulfilling God's will for you. Let's see
if that's a fact. That is fulfilling
God's will for you. That each person
become the most of the which they can
become.
By fulfilling your potent potential then
you are serving God and your fellow man
and you are and you are doing all that
you can for mankind. Now if that don't
puff you up babies
that should last through lunchtime.
All you people out there saving the
world.
What time we do back honey?
>> Come back at 2 o'clock. We uh we resume
at 2:00. We resume at 2:00 and avoid all
sin between now and 2:00.