First question.
He's a graduate student, and he's studying neurofeedback,
and he wants to know what does it calibrate at.
Neurofeedback.
Neurofeedback with what?
Please explain.
What is neurofeedback?
Okay, all right.
We have permission to ask about this, yes.
We can calibrate the neurofeedback.
It's over 440, 460, 450.
450 is my guess.
Yes, 450.
450.
After you do this many, many times,
you begin to almost intuit what the number is going to be.
You get like a feeling for it, you know.
So 450.
That's science.
Science is in the 400s.
It's a Newtonian paradigm of reality.
Yes.
I'll read this question in Korean so other Koreans can understand.
Oh, yes, okay.
Jesus died on the cross to redeem all human sins,
as the Church says.
If that's true,
did all of you here, including me,
suffer the same sin?
We are told in Korean,
Christian theology,
that the meaning of Jesus Christ's crucifixion on the cross,
the purpose of that was to redeem ourselves from our sin.
Is that true?
And if that is so,
through that sacrifice,
Jesus Christ's sacrifice,
are we all redeemed?
Those who believe on his name are redeemed by his sacrifice.
Now, he was,
incarnate, incarnate.
Those who believe on Jesus Christ are redeemed by Jesus Christ's sacrifice.
Incarnate means that his divinity was a direct gift from God.
Jesus Christ was incarnate as a direct gift from God.
Yes.
So, Jesus Christ's divinity,
was like a spark,
Yes. So, Jesus Christ's divinity was like a spark,
a special recognition from God,
that Jesus would serve a certain purpose for mankind,
to redeem mankind.
Yes.
Jesus Christ's incarnation,
was a direct gift from God.
So,
it was a gift from God to save mankind.
All right. So,
the biblical story is that man fell from grace
by disobeying God's laws.
And by Jesus Christ's sacrifice,
man redeemed himself,
became redeemed.
So that all who believe on his name,
or acknowledge his divinity,
are thereby also redeemed.
So, yes.
In the Bible,
it says that man fell from grace
by disobeying God's laws.
Yes.
So, it's a historical fact,
that man fell.
It's a biblical,
in the Bible,
it says,
man fell from innocence and grace
by disobeying God.
It's in the Scripture.
That's in the Scripture.
It's in the Bible.
It says,
man fell from innocence and grace
by disobeying God.
That's in the Scripture, yes.
And by Christ's sacrifice,
he redeemed mankind.
So, those who believe in Christ,
Jesus is their advocate,
advocate before the Father.
Jesus said,
I will,
I will plead for you before God.
Jesus said,
when you are the 1st,
you are the 2nd.
That's the promise.
The promise is true.
Yes.
Well, he only asked about Jesus.
And when we calibrate the level of Jesus Christ,
we get 1000,
which is the maximum possible.
If we measure Jesus,
So those who believe in Krishna, then Krishna says those who believe in me belong to me.
Buddha says you're on your own.
So the meaning of yuna is that if you were a little bit foolish in this life, then you can do well in the next life.
My question is about on your own.
You said you're on your own every moment, but it doesn't feel like you've grown up in a Buddhist family.
Can you say that by realizing the pain that occurs every moment, you're letting go of that pain?
I heard that we need to surrender to God every instant.
And I grew up in Buddhist family and this teaching doesn't jive well with me.
And then can I understand that dedication as meaning that when every feeling of pain,
when every feeling of pain as they arises, I should, by recognizing it, I surrender it to God.
Is that the same? Am I understanding it correctly?
You surrender everything to God all the time, including feelings and occurrences and thoughts.
What?
You surrender everything to God continuously as it arises.
Am I clearly being aware of it? Is that the act of surrendering?
I have to think back years ago.
As a thing arises, you surrender it to God.
You let go wanting to control it or change it or make it different or squeeze it for some profit.
It just is as it is.
Whatever happens, whatever it is, surrender it to God.
Don't try to gain any profit from it.
Surrender everything to God voluntarily.
That was Dr. Hopkins' experience in the past.
That is sort of like a practice.
Eventually, there's nothing to surrender to God.
Everything just is as it is.
You see the birds flying along.
And you let the bird be. You let all of life be like the bird.
Nice interpreter.
Nice table.
Wonderful wife.
Nice water.
Good soda.
Nice Kleenex.
Everything just is as it is.
It doesn't involve you.
The phenomena are all occurring of their own.
All is occurring of its own nature.
Everything is happening of its own nature.
Because all that seems to be occurring is only an observation.
And creation is continuous.
Creation is constantly unfolding.
And you witness the unfolding of creation.
Yeah.
.
So you don't have to get involved in it.
If it rains, it rains, if it shines, it shines.
It's all the same.
It's a nice rainy day.
It's a nice sunny day.
It's a nice warm day.
Oh, it's a nice cool day.
It's a good day. It's a good day because it's cool.
It's all okay.
Everything is okay.
That happens of its own.
Everything happens of its own.
In the beginning, you release it, you release it, you release it.
And then after that, it lets go of its own because you don't get attached, so you don't have to let it go.
Because you're not attached, you don't have to let it go.
You consciously let go of it, but if you keep doing it, you just don't have any obsession with it, so you naturally accept everything as it is.
But for me, when I hear the word God, I don't have any special image at all.
When he thinks of God, he cannot conceptualize.
No image appears.
Right, good.
And to what is surrendering?
What you're looking at, what you're looking at is God.
This is God.
Everything is God.
Everything is the expression of divinity.
You see the sacredness of all that exists.
The sacredness of all that exists.
The sacredness of this table.
This is God's expression as a table.
God's expression is Kleenex.
God's expression is water.
Everything is divinity.
It's an expression of the sacredness as a table, and the sacredness as a Kleenex.
Everything is the sacredness.
With an enlightened state, the divinity of everything shines forth
with complete beauty and holiness.
Beauty and perfection, everything is perfect.
There's nothing you have to do or fix, and with that realization, you see the beauty
of all that exists.
You see the beauty of all that exists, beauty.
Charm, the charm of all that exists.
Thank you.
Next question.
He's the one with hearing disability.
And he has a hearing disability.
His question is, he's asking you to pray for his mother, who died of cancer.
I think I understand quite recently.
Could you pray for his mother, deceased mother?
Why should I do that?
Why?
God doesn't like her, or what?
He just wanted to get more of a blessing, actually.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, I see, oh yes.
Does anyone have sign language?
Did she have a name?
Who did you pray for?
Did you pray for your mother?
What's your name?
My mother?
Name, name.
Kim Gyeong Nam.
Yes.
Mother's soul is okay.
His mother's soul is okay.
He says his mother's soul is okay.
Not to worry.
He says you don't have to worry.
The question is, would a writer's way be fit for my job?
If it's suitable, a documentary or a simple literature.
Oh, oh, oh.
She's asking whether becoming a professional writer is appropriate for her.
If so, she works for a TV station as a writer.
And then she's asking whether that job, that vocation is good for her.
If so, for documentary or for pure literature.
Mundane question.
Why the question?
She wants to be a good writer.
Good writer.
And also she's asking for your advice to be a good writer.
To be a good writer?
Well, let's see.
We have permission to ask about this lady.
She has the talent to be a good writer.
Yes.
So, you see, writing, you become energized by what they call the muse.
M-U-S-E in English.
Muse.
The muse is like inspiration.
Inspiration.
So, when my muse is present, I feel energized and interested in writing.
I get up at 3.
Or 4 o'clock in the morning and start to write, yes?
I get up 3 or 4 o'clock.
I have to jump out of bed.
I can't wait to write.
To be a good writer, you need inspiration.
We usually say that inspiration is what we feel.
You need inspiration.
In the case of Dr. Hawkins, if you have that inspiration, you can wake up at 3 o'clock in the morning and write.
So, for some years, I wrote books.
Because the muse.
was initiating the desire to write.
But now my views is quiet, thank goodness.
I wrote eight or nine books, nine stop.
Eight books, or nine books, I don't know what.
And then, now maybe I'm thinking about writing
another little book, commentaries, thoughts
and commentaries about things, you know.
But not a big book like before, you know.
So, follow your muse.
So don't, don't try and make yourself right
when you don't feel the incentive, the energy, the desire.
Is that in Korean?
Muse?
Muuu sse.
Is that a familiar.
No, actually we say feel.
You get a feel first up.
Oh, yeah.
Well, in English it's almost like, almost like a fantasy that you're muse.
I must write.
I must dance.
I must sing.
I must be an actor.
Inspires you.
That's it.
He's a student who is studying psychoanalysis?
Psychology.
Psychology. And then his question is, what is the meaning that dreams can provide?
Dream?
Yeah. Provide to us.
And if we can analyze dreams and apply their values to our life, what are the methods of doing that?
Oh, dreams are very important in psychoanalysis. Psychoanalysis, either Freudian, Jungian, there are others too,
but Freud and Jung are the two main types of interpretations.
And a great deal is learned from the unconscious.
Because without psychoanalysis, a person is not familiar with their unconscious.
And in psychoanalysis, the unconscious becomes more into awareness.
And it's very, very useful. And it's very, very true.
Dreams are very important in psychology.
We have to understand that.
Freud and Jung are the two main scholars.
So we can learn a lot from the unconscious in psychology,
but through psychoanalysis, we can learn a lot from the unconscious.
And what we learn from that is very accurate.
He says it's close to the truth.
I was in psychoanalysis for, I don't know, five, six years, a long time.
Every day of the week, you go and lay on the couch.
And talk about what goes through your mind.
And all the things that are repressed out of awareness now come up in awareness.
My psychoanalysis was Freud.
My psychoanalyst was Professor at Columbia University.
His psychoanalyst was psychoanalyzed by Freud.
So Freud is like my psychoanalytic grandfather.
Professor Hawkins, you went to bed at least once a week before a certain period of time,
and after you lay on the couch, you raised your consciousness to the level of consciousness,
and you raised your consciousness to the level of consciousness,
and the person who did that for Professor Hawkins was a professor at Columbia University,
and the professor who taught him was Freud.
And I wanted to talk about Freud to Professor Hawkins
because he was the grand-grandfather of the psychological analysis.
Also, through psychoanalysis you understand the things that go on in the world to a greater degree.
With database analysis we begin to understand the things that are going on in the world to a greater degree.
Freud said that in the unconscious, there is eros and also thanatos.
One is the attraction to life and the other is the attraction to death.
These two things he said.
You see every day in the news somewhere there is a riot with people killing other people.
Every day.
Where is it this morning?
They are killing some, oh, today it's Greece.
Every day they're killing somebody someplace, and the people can't wait for the killing.
People rush to the killing.
They just can't wait to get shot.
Rush to your death, attracted to the death.
There's a death instinct.
I saw it, I first saw it in a dog pack.
I had my chickens out in the yard with the fence around, and three dogs came into the
yard and they began attacking the chickens.
They would kill this chicken, then they would kill this chicken, then they would kill this
chicken.
They just were on a killing bloodlust to kill, kill, kill.
Yeah.
.
. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
And in today's world, like, Islamics blow up a whole busload of children, 34 children,
and they blow it up, kill all 34 children.
How can you explain such a thing?
So, Freud says that's the thanatos in the unconscious and they just invent the religion
in order to give it a freedom of expression.
.
And we see it in the teenage killers.
In the United States, periodically, some teenage gets a gun and goes into his school
room and shoots all his classmates.
And then he commits suicide.
That's how can you explain it?
You can't explain it.
Yeah.
With intelligence or logic or rationality, you can only explain it with Freud's theory of Thanatos.
There is no other explanation.
This cannot be explained by intelligence or logic.
It can only be explained by Freud's idea of Thanatos, which is attracted to death.
It can only be explained by that instinct, which is attracted to death.
Yes, we have some time.
If so, I would like to know if there is a daily method that ordinary people can use to grow up with this dream.
Dreams, just from intuitive, you can trust your intuition to look at your intuition to what this could be referring to.
So the dream might say to you, really, to look at this area, look at this area of your life and see what are your various motives.
Examine it, pay attention to it.
So the dream might serve a purpose that you pay attention to it.
So...
It's hard to do that, but if you make a suggestion, you can use your intuition to look at your dream and see what part of your life you want to observe in your dream, so you can dream and use your intuition to observe the things that you are missing in your life, as an opportunity to observe them.
With, I guess, spiritual progression, what I'm thinking of is do the spiritual progression.
Anyway, with spiritual progression, eventually...
As you get more and more enlightened, you hit a point where the dreams stop.
I never dream anymore.
It might be because you don't need to repress anything.
Yeah, could be so.
Thank you.
Oh, yeah.
The teachings that we hear from you, could they be used to help us to move beyond the level 700?
As work as a karma, they could help us go beyond the level 700.
You don't have to worry about going...
Don't worry.
You don't have to worry about going to level 700.
You start the spiritual process, and then it goes where it goes.
And you don't try and control.
There is no particular goal.
The person overall says, I want to become enlightened.
Yeah.
So that's a certain orientation.
And wherever you are in the process is okay.
If you start spiritual work, don't try to control it anymore.
It's okay.
Wherever you are.
And then the state comes on spontaneously.
That state of consciousness occurs spontaneously.
What's important is that...
The important thing is to be oriented in that direction.
As a life goal to become enlightened appeals to 1 in 10 million people on the street.
The desire to become enlightened, making that your prime goal in life,
only 1 in 10 million people on the street, 1 in 10 million has that orientation.
That's one reason it's rare. It's few people choose it.
The Buddha said,
Fortunate is to be born a human.
More fortunate than that is to be born a human and then to hear of enlightenment, to hear of it.
Rarer still is to hear of enlightenment.
And then pursue it.
So we give thanks for the Buddha, for the message.
And then when we worship the Buddha, we pick up that energy that drives you through to the state of enlightenment.
That's why we revere the Buddha.
So Jesus Christ taught salvation. The Buddha taught enlightenment.
Jesus Christ taught salvation. The Buddha taught enlightenment.
This is a different question.
10 years ago, the dark side of the inner world began to be seen and it has become more and more severe.
It is very painful because of this. How should we deal with these parts?
About 10, since about 10 years ago, some dark spots within me, some dark side inside was spotted.
Dark side was what?
Was witnessed, was noticed by me.
Oh, he noticed. He noticed the dark spot in himself.
The dark spot in himself.
Oh, yeah.
And it's getting severe and severe. And I've been sort of agonizing about it.
It's getting worse?
Yeah, it's getting worse and worse.
What does he mean? Evil? Hate? What does he mean by dark spot?
What do you mean?
The emotions and thoughts below 200. He's experiencing those emotions.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
And he wants to overcome.
What? Yeah.
That's why you lead a spiritual life, to overcome them.
Because it takes years for them to rise up and you stop repressing them.
You start to accept them.
First, you accept the things you don't like.
I hate people.
I want to kill them.
Good.
No, you want to kill people. So what?
They have to be the way I want them to be.
So I want to control them, make them different.
Yeah.
After a while, you say, I don't want to make them different.
They can be how they are.
And then you say, people can't help being what they are.
And then you realize that people can't change their own existence.
They don't change that easily.
That's what I admit.
You take a religious maniac and he wants to blow up a busload of children.
He blows up a busload of children.
There's a religious evangelist who tries to blow up a busload of children.
TheIC MADASSAH
He's suffering fromŌĆöhis mind has been indoctrinated to think that way.
So the perpetrator is at the same time the victim.
He's the victim of that kind of thinking.
He doesn't have to savor growing up.
He has knowledge for that.
When you take it, can you stand up for yourself?
Yeah,
So, Jesus Christ said, there's only one sin, ignorance.
So, we forgive people because they don't know any better.
Out of that arises the Buddha's compassion for all things.
Compassion for all human beings. Compassion for their limitation.
First of all, acknowledge that you have those things.
It's not an expression. Acknowledge it and be at ease.
Or do you just need to look at the negative emotions as they pass by?
Watch them subside without acting them out.
He can forgive himself for thinking those thoughts.
He has to forgive himself.
See, when you start looking at the unconscious, you have to accept what comes up.
What comes up is usually...
...not so pleasant.
Otherwise, you wouldn't have repressed it into your unconscious.
When you check your consciousness,
first, acknowledge the negative emotions that come up.
Because if they weren't so negative,
they wouldn't have been suppressed unconsciously.
So, when you raise your consciousness to those things,
even if they're negative, it's important to acknowledge them at ease.
When you find the way to your heart,
with the help of your teacher,
you are studying to meet the true self through the inner conversation with the God of the nature.
Can you give me some advice?
Can you explain about the consciousness of the nature before the Creator?
By seeking the way through heart,
she met a teacher.
By seeking what?
The way through heart.
The way through the heart?
Yes.
The way through love, yes.
Then, he met a teacher who taught her that to meet your true self,
you have to have inner conversation with God.
She's doing that.
Good.
Is there good advice?
Yes.
One more question.
This teacher is talking about some original consciousness prior to the Creator.
Is this possible?
Some original consciousness prior?
Prior to Creator.
Prior to the Creator?
Yes, prior to the Creator.
Makes no sense.
I don't understand. How?
You mean thoughts created God?
What's the question?
Yes, but he's giving explanations.
Her teacher is giving explanations about some original consciousness prior to the Creator.
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
And she's doubting it.
Whether that is possible.
Yes.
My understanding of it is the same as pretty much revealed in Scripture.
In the beginning was the Godhead.
The beginning was the Godhead.
The Godhead.
Out of which arose God.
Out of which arose creation.
The first emanation from God was light, is symbolized as light.
Out of the Godhead arose consciousness as light.
Out of the light of God arose consciousness.
Out of consciousness arose the universe.
That is correct.
Out of the consciousness arose the universe.
And the universe was created to be evolutionary.
It's evolutionary by nature.
The universe was created to evolve.
It was created to evolve in its essence.
So evolution is continuous and ongoing and eternal.
That is why evolution is continuous and eternal.
It is measured by facts.
Thank you.
Do you have any advice that she's seeking to meet her true self through inner conversations
with God?
That's one style.
Yes.
It's like divinity seeking to recognize its own divinity.
It's a paradox.
Like divinity seeking to recognize its own divinity.
It's a paradox that she brought.
That it was brought up.
Yes.
He's a dentist. He's been a dentist practicing for 10 years, and his observation is that
people have bad habits like clenching your teeth and those things. These bad habits exert
certain forces through your oral muscles, and then his guess is that leads to all the
oral problems. He wants to know whether, through kinesiology, he wants to know whether that
is correct.
Well, I'm not sure about the question. People form nervous habits.
Yeah, by clenching their teeth.
Yeah, I suppose clenching teeth is a way to diverge.
But anger, irritation, and he may be correct that by doing that, they do eventually pay
a certain price. Yes, I think it's true.
Clenching their teeth all the time.
Kinesiology?
What?
If his observation is correct, he wants to know, confirm that through kinesiology.
Yeah, so he could say, confirm what?
Whether those bad habits leads to oral problems.
Oral diseases.
Yeah, yeah.
It does, yeah.
That's true.
Yeah, yeah.
And another question. He's doing Course in Miracle all by himself, without teacher.
Is there any sort of dangers that he should be aware of?
Dangers?
Yeah, doing alone, doing it all by himself, without teacher.
No, no, it's fine.
Any danger?
Yeah.
That's one thing you can't do.
Yeah, it's not dangerous to forgive people.
For sure.
And I forgot one more question for him.
Yeah.
He then, he told his patients, stop doing that bad habits.
And patients do not listen to him.
No.
And he wants to know how, how can he make his patients stop those bad habits more effectively.
Sometimes they do it without even, it's in their subconscious, because they don't know
how to do it.
Yeah.
He tells them no, because they do some clutching the teeth is sometimes done
in the sleep form, and you do it subconsciously rather than even consciously.
Yeah.
You'd have to retrain the patient, and use hypnosis perhaps.
Oh, and because there are a lot of cases of doing something goatie just like that has
been difficult, you need to re-educate the patient, to examinez the patient, and do some
will help you a lot.
You keep cleansing during the day, right?
That's almost all you do.
Yes, I do that almost all day.
You have to fix it after you recognize it.
It's like hypnosis.
Bad habits are good for your business.
Oh, thank you.
That is true.
Yes.
I have a question.
Is the true state of knowingness the same as the state of absolute love?
Are those two the same?
Yes.
Two different states.
Two different styles of trying to describe it.
They are the same.
Oh, knowingness on the level that he's asking this is very much the field in which this love occurs.
Agape.
That type of love is called agape.
It's an impersonal way of being in the world, you know?
The two are the same, and they are two different ways of expressing the same thing.
The state of the question you are asking is the same.
That is, the two levels.
The condition is that the level of love you get from this type of love, which is called agape.
So you're talking about love as the quality of your personality in terms of your personality in this world and What character are you speaking to?
Yes.
I'm talking about all of them.
’┐Į
Thank you.
Some unconscious patterns of bad behavior is repeating.
And it happens so fast, like an instant.
In an instant, it happens.
So it feels like an irremovable mountain.
How can I overcome this?
You can.
You're conquered.
You fail.
Collapse.
Give up.
Plead with God.
Ask God.
What kind of behavior?
I think this is exactly what I'm talking about.
What kind of behavior are you talking about?
For example, in a couple's relationship,
when they fight, they keep fighting in the same pattern.
They keep fighting with the same problem.
I have a complaint about my wife's insecurity.
My wife has a complaint about my lack of self-esteem and understanding.
I have a complaint about that.
So even if we keep fighting with different topics,
the focus keeps repeating.
For example, the fight, I mean, they have a fight with his wife.
He fights, but over the same thing.
She complains about the fact that he's not generous enough.
Yeah.
And he's not satisfied.
That she is always sort of agitated.
Yeah.
And whatever the subject is, it ends up always with the same complaint.
So this pattern is repeating.
But it, yeah, that's his way.
Well, stay that way.
Don't try to change.
Argue.
Be unhappy.
Lay on the floor and cry.
Hit the floor.
She's crying.
Huh?
Yeah, good.
Good.
Cry, cry, cry.
Yeah.
Let her cry.
And because this way she's trying to change him.
This is the way she's trying to get her way in the world.
Oh.
Like the baby.
The baby cries and cries.
And makes things happen.
She better grow up.
And accept how the world is.
You have to stop being eight years old.
Stop being eight years old.
Yeah.
Grow up.
Thank you very much.
Oh, that isn't even tough.
That's just a minor problem.
You don't know what tough is.
I mean, it doesn't create agony or, you know, something severe.
It's just that you're always blubbering and crying instead of, you know, cutting the potatoes
for dinner.
You get tears in the potatoes.
She has to give up.
You know, see, within each one, there is the adult, the child, and the parent.
That is a good pattern.
Within everybody, there is the child, the adolescent, the adult, and the parent.
These sort of archetypes are in everybody's personality, and you give too much energy
to the child, you give too much energy to the child.
In you is also the parent.
So you say to the parent in you,
Tell the child to stop that and grow up.
Because there is greater happiness, greater happiness to be found when you let go of being childish.
You then experience the happiness of the adult.
And so indulging the child within you, you cheat your adult of the satisfaction of being
a well-functioning, respectable adult, you see?
So by indulging the child in her, she's cheating the adult in her.
She wants to ask herself how she can help him be a better person, to make herself happy.
So is she saying he's stingy?
Yeah.
He's stingy.
No, not generous and kind enough.
Oh, emotionally.
Emotionally, not money-wise.
Oh, oh, oh.
And she needs to know that's how he is and accept that.
Yeah.
And then he will feel free to share his emotions with her.
There's another story.
There's another style of therapy called psychodrama.
Psychodrama.
It might also be helpful.
What does he think about what she says?
What does he think?
Yeah, he's not saying anything.
He's not saying anything.
No.
She is always sort of emotionally agitated.
Yeah.
And fretting about things.
Oh, oh, oh.
So what she needs to do is go off to where the emotion is.
To where she cries and gets all the emotions out.
Then come back and talk with him.
Don't cry in front of him.
Don't, you know, no emotions in front of him.
Oh, yeah.
Then she can sit down and talk with him after she's got all that emotion out of her.
And he will respond better.
When you're emotionally agitated and anxious,
go somewhere else and cry.
And then after you calm down,
it would be much better if you told your husband.
That's okay.
He's smiling. He smiles.
He smiles.
He's smiling at me.
Is he, you know, is he happy with this relationship?
Or...
Are you happy with this relationship?
I'm happy.
They feel happy about their relationship, but...
Don't lie.
They are, yeah.
Because he smiles.
He's smiling.
He smiles.
So, so...
Yeah.
But she has a lot of emotions, you know,
it could be from the baby.
Yeah, yeah.
And actually one reason,
there is one reason for her emotional agitation.
She feels that I'm not a good person.
She feels I'm not a good person.
Yeah.
And she wants to...
So what she needs to do is channel that energy
into becoming a good person
so that she feels happy with herself, too.
It's hard to know what she means by good person.
Well...
Yeah.
She probably feels upset that she's got him upset.
So it was...
It's a ball that keeps rolling.
Very low self-esteem.
Oh, oh, yeah.
She has very low self-esteem.
Yeah.
All right.
Okay.
Yeah.
So that if she can help him be a good person,
I think that would...
Okay.
If she channeled her energies into that,
it would be best.
Then she takes all the emphasis off herself
and onto him.
Yeah, yeah.
That would be better.
Okay.
And then, more questions?
Oh.
There's another couple.
Another couple, okay.
Hi.
I don't have a question.
Just...
I'm here.
Can you hear me?
Okay?
What's the question?
I don't hear.
I don't have a special question.
Oh, you don't have a question.
Because I'm here today...
last year, I was a cancer patient,
and I was here to, you know...
And I went through the operation and chemotherapy.
And while I was going through the process, I met your teaching.
And today I'm here just to express how grateful we are to have your presence in this life.
And how grateful we are to have your teaching in this life.
So that's it.
Thank you.
So let us express our gratitude with the Korean traditional style of the bowing.
Would you allow us to have the Korean way?
Korean way of bowing.
They want to express their gratitude through the Korean way.
Oh, Korean way.
Would that be okay?
Yeah, how do you do?
Oh, you just sit here.
No, no, you just sit.
It's new.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
So you just sit and we will have a bow.
Oh, yes, I know what you mean.
Now it's the divinity within.
Yeah, now it's the divinity within.
I hear the voice inside me when I ask God a question during meditation or prayer.
If I keep talking, the person asking the question disappears, the voice answering disappears, and there are often times when there is an answer that I want.
This is a desirable method.
Is it true that the root of the sound that responds comes from God?
While I'm meditating and praying and ask a question to God, I hear a voice within.
Within me, I hear a voice.
And if I continue the conversation, then the person asking disappears and the person, the entity answering the question also disappears.
And the answer.
seeking exists just as as an answer with no entities talking is this a desirable
way it's useful useful and is the voice coming from God I don't know it depends
on what you call God because God is all that is yes everything is coming from
God is it like a special transmission is it like is it like a special transmission
from God was this yes so it is the expression of God because it's a
response to your and treating via prayer and devotion yeah
you should assume some ņ×łļŗżļŖö ņ▓½ļ▓łņ¦ĖļĪ£ ĻĘĖ ņ¦łļ¼ĖņŚÉ ļīĆĒĢ£ ņØ┤Ļ▓ī
ņŗĀņ£╝ļĪ£ ņśżļŖöĻ░Ć ņŗĀņ£╝ļĪ£ļČĆĒä░ ņśżļŖöĻ░ĆņŚÉ ļīĆĒĢ£ ņ¦łļ¼ĖņØĆ ļŗ╣ņŗĀņØ┤ ņŗĀņØä
ļ¼┤ņŚćņ£╝ļĪ£ ņāØĻ░üĒĢśļŖöĻ░ĆņŚÉ ļŗ¼ļĀżņ×łņŖĄļŗłļŗż.
ņØ┤Ļ▓āņØ┤ ņŗĀņØś ņØīņä▒, ņØ╝ļŗ©ņØĆ ņ▓½ļ▓łņ¦ĖļĪ£ ĻĘĖ ņ¦łļ¼ĖņŚÉ ļīĆĒĢ£ ņØ┤Ļ▓ī ņŗĀņ£╝ļĪ£ļČĆĒä░ ņśżļŖöĻ░ĆņŚÉ ļīĆĒĢ£ ņ¦łļ¼ĖņØĆ ļŗ╣ņŗĀņØ┤ ņŗĀņØä ļ¼┤ņŚćņ£╝ļĪ£ ņāØĻ░üĒĢśļŖöĻ░ĆņŚÉ ļŗ¼ļĀżņ×łņŖĄļŗłļŗż.
ņ×łļŖöļŹ░ ņÖ£ļāÉĒĢśļ®┤ ļ¬©ļōĀ Ļ▓āņØ┤ ņŗĀņØ┤ĻĖ░ ļĢīļ¼ĖņŚÉ ĻĘĖļ¤¼ĒĢ£ļŹ░ ņ¦ĆĻĖł ņ¦łļ¼ĖņØä ĒĢśņģ©ņ¢┤ņÜö
ĻĘĖļ¤¼ļ®┤ ņØ┤Ļ▓ī ņ¢┤ļ¢ż ņŗĀņ£╝ļĪ£ļČĆĒä░ ĒŖ╣ļ│äĒĢ£ ļŗĄņØĖĻ░Ć
ņÜ┤ļÅÖļĀź ĒĢÖņ£╝ļĪ£ ļ¦×Ļ▓ī ļéśņÖöĻ▒░ļōĀņÜö ļ¦ÉņöĆĒĢśņŗ£ļŖö Ļ▓āņØĆ ņŗĀņØś ĻĖ░ļÅäļź╝ ĒåĄĒĢ┤ņä£
ņŗĀņŚÉĻ▓ī Ļ░äņ▓ŁņØä ĒĢśĻ│Ā ņ×łĻĖ░ ļĢīļ¼ĖņŚÉ ņŗĀĻ╗śņä£ ĻĘĖļĀćĻ▓ī ļŗĄļ│ĆņØä ĒĢśņŗĀļŗżĻ│Ā ļ¦ÉņöĆĒĢ┤
ņŻ╝ņŗ£ļäżņÜö
ĻĘĖļ¤░ļŹ░ ļé┤Ļ░Ć ņØ┤ ņāØĻ░üņØä ĒĢĀ ņØ╝ņØ┤ ņĢäļŗī ļé┤Ļ░Ć ĻĘĖĻ▓āņŚÉņä£ ņŗĀņ£╝ļĪ£ļČĆĒä░ ņśżļŖö Ļ▓āņØ┤ ļéśņŚÉĻ▓ī ĒŖ╣ļ│äĒĢ£ Ļ▓āņØĖ Ļ▓āņØä Ļ░Ćņ¦ÉņØä ĻĖ░ņŚ¼ĒĢśĻ▓ĀļŗżļŖö Ļ▓āņØĆ ĒŖ╣ņĀĢĒĢ£ ļ░śņØæņØä coconut
ņĀ£Ļ░Ć ņØ┤Ļ▓āņØä ĒŖ╣ņĀĢĒĢ£ Ļ▓āņØä Ļ░Ćņ¦Éņ£╝ļĪ£ Error this is that the music is pulling a god so it's a god's voice
ņØ┤ļ¤░ Ļ▓āņŚÉ ĒĢ£Ļ░Ćņ¦Ć ļŗ©ņĀÉņØĆ ļéśņü£ ņĀÉņØĆ ĻĘĖ ņØīņä▒ņØ┤ ņŗĀņ£╝ļĪ£ļČĆĒä░ ņś©ļŗżĻ│Ā ĒĢ┤ņä£ ņØ┤Ļ▓āņØä ĒŖ╣ļ│äĒĢśĻ▓ī ņĢä ņØ┤Ļ▒┤ ņŗĀņØś ļ¬®ņåīļ”¼ņĢ╝
Because they're from God, you know it'd be to make a special. Oh, oh. Yeah, that's one really super. Yeah.
ņØ┤ļ¤░ Ļ▓āņŚÉ ĒĢ£Ļ░Ćņ¦Ć ļŗ©ņĀÉņØĆ ļéśņü£ ņĀÉņØĆ ĻĘĖ ņØīņä▒ņØ┤ ņŗĀņ£╝ļĪ£ļČĆĒä░ ņś©ļŗżĻ│Ā ĒĢ┤ņä£ ņØ┤Ļ▓āņØä ĒŖ╣ļ│äĒĢśĻ▓ī ņØ┤Ļ▒┤ ņŗĀņØś ļ¬®ņåīļ”¼ņÖĆ ņØ┤ļĀćĻ▓ī ņāØĻ░üĒĢśļŖö Ļ▓ā ĻĘĖĻ▓āņØĆ ĒĢśļéśņØś ĻĘĖĻ▓ā ņØ┤ļ¤¼ĒĢ£ ļ░®ļ▓ĢņŚÉ ļŗ©ņĀÉņØ┤ ļÉĀ ņłśĻ░Ć ņ×łņŖĄļŗłļŗż
Yeah, so you don't want to make God into a personality who's giving you advice.
Hey, Joe, you better quit eating those things too much, you're going to get way too much.
He reminds me of a joke.
We've been waiting for it.
This guy, this guy, Pete, his name is Pete.
And everything goes wrong with his life.
His car breaks down.
His business fails.
His health is bad.
His wife leaves him.
He stands out on the sidewalk and he says,
God, God.
Why me?
And a voice comes out of the heavens and says,
I don't know, Pete, there's something about you that just pisses me off.
It's actually, you told that joke yesterday?
When he asked the question.
He must be Pete then.
Alright, you got it.
I changed the name to Pete.
Maybe you won't recognize the joke.
So, just to make, he wants to know if whoever is speaking to him is a higher being or is he tapping into his thoughts?
Well, you're tapping into intuition, intuition and non-logical styles of understanding things, comprehension.
So, there's a certain advantage to it, yes.
You know, because if logic was sufficient, you wouldn't be working on a problem or, you know, you would have had it solved already.
Yeah.
Because what you're getting at right now is that it's not non-scientific, it's not logical.
It's coming from some kind of voice, some kind of choreography.
So, you're saying that it has an advantage.
That's how you're getting the answer.
Ah.
This is a very long, could be a long question.
She had three very profound experiences throughout her life.
At age four, she was in a room and through a tiny window she was looking outside.
And she saw a golden light.
And then with that instant, she acquired some supernatural abilities.
At age four?
At age four.
Supernatural, what does that mean?
See through people and able to read people's mind.
At age four?
Yeah, and yes, after that moment.
Oh.
Then she saw a person sitting next to her and she knew that it was a person from her past life.
Oh, yeah.
Her past life.
It was a Buddhist monk.
And she then came a thought asking, which one is me?
This person or that person?
And then the answer said, only consciousness is you.
And then a very sharp, almost screaming voice said, what am I?
And intuitively she knew that this voice will dominate my life from now on.
That was the first experience.
And second experience happened at age seven.
At age seven or eight on a spring day.
And she felt a sunshine on her back.
And she knew that she was entering the world of enlightenment.
And from then on, she knew intuitively all the Buddhist teachings because she was probably a Buddhist in her past life.
And there is this non-verbal knowledge.
Non-verbal knowingness that the universe itself is love.
And she saw how petty human love is compared to that infinite love.
And all the world is a smile.
When a flower blooms, she sees a smile there.
And then she said, then question came up.
I think she thought I came here just after I passed the level 600.
And why am I not living as an enlightened person?
And her understanding is, I experienced enlightenment but a mind attached to it.
That was the first thing.
Say that again.
And then she was, she thought that she passed the level 600.
Yes.
Then her question was.
All right, hold on.
She did transcend level 600.
Yes.
So?
Then her question is, why am I not living?
As an enlightened person.
Why is she not leaving?
What's enlightenment got to do with leaving?
Emotional.
No.
Living a life.
Living a life as an enlightened person.
Yes.
Then her answer was, to my enlightened state, a mind was attached.
That's her answer.
I experienced union mystica with a mind attached to it.
So in other words.
She's still of mind, not of spirit.
She's still of mind.
So her mind was stronger than her spirit.
In other words, her mind's controlling.
She identifies her reality as the mind instead of spirit?
Right.
That's her understanding.
Of why she's not.
It's a bad understanding.
Okay.
The third experience happened at age 13.
Ah.
There's two words, positive and negative.
And she forgot all about this.
And she spent her past 50 years experiencing the whole gamut of emotions below 200.
From 20 to 175.
Yeah.
And then she did 12 steps group for eight years.
Through that, she regained the memory of those three experiences, profound experiences.
And the question she's asking is.
Now she really wants that all her struggle throughout 50 years, spiritual struggle.
Really want that to come to a spiritual fruition.
But she is not able to do it.
So asking for your help.
What does she mean by fruition?
She wants to.
But she's still going through emotions below 200.
She wants to get out of there.
Well, then she wasn't over 600.
She could have been in a past life.
Because in a past life she.
Might have fallen.
All right.
We have permission to ask where she's at now.
Now she's over 200, 400, 500.
Now she's trying to figure things out in the 400s.
All right.
So she's trying to understand intellectually in the 400s.
She should stop trying to understand it intellectually.
Because no matter what she thinks, it's going to be nonsense anyway.
Don't try to figure it out intellectually.
Stop trying to manipulate your mind.
Let it be what it is.
It's too much self-consciousness.
Just be and stop thinking about it.
And she also said.
Yeah.
She understood that those experiences inflated her spiritual ego.
And she thinks now that is over.
Almost she's feeling humility now.
Yeah.
So then asking for your help.
These experiences, these profound experiences inflated her spiritual ego.
Yes.
Oh, yes.
I see.
The spiritual ego.
Got inflated.
Made something out of that.
Yeah.
But now it stopped doing that.
Huh?
Yeah.
The levels of those experiences.
She wants to know.
What experiences?
The three profound experiences.
The three experiences she had.
The levels.
This is too complicated.
It's too complicated.
Too complicated.
What's the first experience?
Was the light she saw at four.
The light she saw at age four.
All right.
Was over 600, 700, 650.
Okay.
What's the next experience?
The next experience was.
Love.
The.
In which she got the understanding that.
Entire universe itself is a lot.
Okay.
So that calibrated over 700.
750.
About 700, yeah.
All right.
That's number two.
What's number three?
Two different.
Three is.
Two words.
Positive and negative.
Negative.
Three was what?
Two words.
Positive and negative.
I don't know what that means.
That's meaningless to me, out of context.
I would have to look at the context.
Whether she has the power to write down all the spiritual experiences she underwent throughout her life.
Whether she has the power to write that down.
Write it down for what?
For others to look at it.
Why?
Because that could be helpful to others.
How is it helpful?
She doesn't know what it means, so what's the message she's going to say?
I don't know what this means.
Stop thinking about it.
Just let it be what it is.
Without thinking about it.
She's ruminating.
She's ruminating, thinking, judging, processing it all.
Just let it be.
I make a song.
I go, la la la la la la la la la la la.
That's all there is to that.
Now I say, that was a good song, that was a bad song, that was a famous song.
Oh, that's a rerun of a song from a childhood.
Oh, that's a song that signifies the human condition.
Oh, that's a song from the unconscious.
Oh, that's a song.
That's all spinning with the mouth.
Yeah.
La la la la la la la la la la.
That's all there is to it.
If there's a song like this, that's all there is to it.
When did you hear this song?
What kind of song is this?
No thinking.
No talking.
Just let it be what it is.
La la la la la la la la la la.
Boom.
That's it.
Not good.
Not bad.
Just is.
Is.
That's it.
Not good.
Not bad.
Just is.
Is.
That's it.
Not good.
Not bad.
Just is.
Is.
Good or bad.
Just as is.
Boom, bap, bap, boom, bap, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
Okay.
Letting speed, just to let them be.
Yeah.
Let them be.
She'll directly ask you a question.
Yeah.
She speaks English.
Yes.
Hi.
Um ... It seems like this one is experiencing constant accident.
conflict at home so and i've been um praying as you said praying um as god's help and um knowledge
not knowledge for god's will and power to carry that out and also uh as for miracle and uh
constantly trying to uh see it differently and all those things for a couple of years now
stressful like how it's more like i'm creating and experiencing more uh conflict with my spouse
oh your spouse yes yes and the basic uh basic thing
is that i'm trying to make sure that i'm not the only one who's having a hard time
and i'm trying to make sure that i'm not the only one who's having a hard time
is more like there's a huge differences
between our belief system,
and his belief system is there's no life after death,
and there's no God.
Oh, oh, oh.
And when I'm coming here almost 10 years,
I mean, constantly, and every time,
I mean, there's a lot of,
I mean, this one is creating lots of conflict at home
because of that, and I've been praying,
and I don't want to create any more bad karma,
and I could see his viewpoint, and I understand,
and I could feel his pain, and I cannot agree with it.
What's his pain, what pain?
He doesn't believe in God, so what's his pain about?
His pain is that you are a believer in God?
Huh?
His pain is you.
I'm living, I mean.
Why don't you keep it to yourself?
I believe in God, I don't care if anybody else agrees with me
or knows about it, I don't make a,
I don't stand up and say,
you're a believer in God.
I don't want us to all believe in God.
It's my private inner self.
How does that create conflict?
Well, he doesn't want me to go away and really,
because.
Go away where?
Here.
I'm here.
Oh, oh, oh.
And spiritual practice.
Oh, I see, yes.
And trying to prevent him from.
Oh, oh, yeah.
Showing her religious beliefs.
Well, yeah, so you tell him,
I have to accept your atheism,
and you, in return, you must accept my theism.
And if you don't like it,
then you must live with somebody else, perhaps.
Yeah, I did.
Yeah.
And I'm praying for, what is the highest good,
I mean, either should I stay with this guy or no?
And I'm praying for a couple of years now,
and I don't get any answer.
I mean.
You will.
I know, and I believe that, but it's.
Well, the answer you're getting is to live with it.
Huh?
Patience.
Tolerance.
You have to have tolerance.
They both have to have tolerance, you know.
Yeah.
Tolerance for each other's wisdom.
Yeah, uh-huh.
You know.
Well, I don't want to control him,
and sometimes, it feels like he's,
it seems like he's a better human being than me.
I mean, he's a very respectable guy in some way,
and he's very responsible, and I respect that,
and maybe I, I don't know.
It's very difficult.
Yes, it is.
Yes, and I cannot, anything I could do,
but this, I cannot give up.
I mean, this is my, yes.
That's all right.
Yeah, but it's, but it seems like it's,
the conflict is getting worse, so.
So, answer yourself and you pray, right?
So, he should not stop you.
Actually, he can stop me, but he's getting angry,
and creating a lot of conflict at home.
I mean, he can't stop me.
I mean, he can.
He knows that.
Okay, well, but he's not.
He's not stopping you.
He can't stop you.
There's just a question in his mind.
I know it's hard, but you're inner.
So if you can show him your spiritual belief, he will accept.
That's very common for the man to be the businessman, logical, you know,
and the woman goes to church.
That's very common.
The woman and the children go to church, and he figures, you know,
that's for women and children.
Because his mind is on business and logic.
That's just the different archetypes that the male and female come from sometimes.
Doc, do you think you could calibrate,
is that the highest good that I'm leaving him?
The highest good that you should leave him?
Yes.
Make God happy?
Yeah, that too, yes.
That's a decision.
You can't really calibrate a decision like that, no.
So the best way is I keep praying.
You have to show him.
Why do they have to agree?
I don't see why they have to agree about it.
You have to understand the culture.
A Korean man can stop a woman from doing anything they want.
Oh, I see.
So it's a culture thing.
He isn't stopping her, though.
No.
Okay.
So he's allowing her to be.
So the solution is love.
Yes.
All right.
So the answer to it is love.
If you love him enough to accept the way he is and vice versa.
The only way to cross over is with love.
Show him the love in you as well.
Yeah.
The compromise is via love.
Without love, you can't solve it.
Okay?
So love will either solve it or it won't.
And if there's not enough love, then you won't solve it because there isn't enough love.
If love is more important than anything else, then you'll stay with it.
If other things are more important, then that will dissolve the relationship.
So it depends on what you want from a relationship.
If I don't find love in a relationship, goodbye relationship.
Because what's a relationship all about?
It's all about love.
And if there isn't love, then there's no reason for it.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Send him over.
I'll talk to him.
Yeah, I will.
I try.
And we have a last question.
Yeah.
Oh, wow.
He's here.
I have to take a break either way.
Yeah, okay.
After this, you take a break?
Yeah, yeah.
They may have to go to the bathroom too.
Everybody may need help.
Yeah.
I have two questions.
He has two questions.
Oh.
Okay.
The first question is, when I was four years old, my family got into a car accident.
It was a car accident.
When he was four?
Yeah.
He was four years old, entire family got into a car accident.
Mm-hmm.
Everybody got hurt, but only his mother died.
A few years later, his father got remarried, and he's got a stepmother, and then he divorced again.
Mm-hmm.
And after a few years after that, his father got remarried, and he's living with the second stepmother until now.
How old is he now?
26.
Through these experiences, what sort of karmic understanding he could get from this?
The nature of human life, you see, the nature of human life,
takes many forms.
And there are various diversions.
And to accept that, there are multitudinous patterns
of which the conventional ones are only one alternative.
There are probably more people living
in unconventional circumstances
than there are in conventional circumstances.
In America, what, 50% of marriages end in divorce, 50%.
So what's the norm?
The norm is to get divorced.
Right?
Yeah, many times your parents get married two or three times.
You know?
In America, parents get married two or three times.
But that's really his father's karma, too.
In fact, this is more related to his father's karma.
The second question.
I want to live with courage and dignity.
And I want to follow the teaching of the doctor.
I want to serve.
To achieve that, I am praying.
He wants to live his life with dignity and courage, and he wants to devote his life to
your teachings, and what is the best way of doing it?
The books all tell you how to do it.
Through prayer, meditation, and being loving towards all of life.
And to be non-judgmental about things about which you have an aversion, but to not be
judgmental about things that you have aversion to.
But to not be judgmental about things that you have aversion to.
Because that is the way it is for those people and their karma, see?
But it's not your way.
It doesn't mean it's wrong, it just means it's not your way.
I don't believe in blowing up busloads of children.
That's not my way, see?
I don't believe in blowing up buses of children, either.
I believe in aÕÆī and to one of the best ways of living, which is to not be judgmental
towards it.
And that is sentient, to remain a person, not to have a roots of hatred.
But in the same way, to pass on to other people those who come to you with a sense of resentment,
to feelness of resentment.
For the reason of not having a inner strength.
The reason of not having a inner strength.
Hello.
Do you still believe in positive actions?
Yes.
I believe in positive actions.
For the reason of not having a conscience.
Like, do you believe in such things?
I believe in positive actions.
You see, you see how the, how is the Komodo dragon, the Komodo dragon, one bite and you're
dead.
You don't have to hate the Komodo dragon.
Just don't put your foot in its cage.
So you can respect everything being what it is.
You don't have to hate it.
You don't have to agree with it.
You accept that it's part of divine creation.
And people would say, well, why would God create a Komodo dragon?
I don't know.
Who cares?
Don't put your foot in there.
You see.
.
Yes. So we need to take a short break. How do we work it now?
After that, we will ask your blessings for some people.
For the people?
Baby and people, some people with sickness.
Some people want your healing.
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
After the break.
Oh, okay, yes. All right, so now we take a break?
Yes.
Okay.
Thank you.
That's very nice, very nice.
I wish I could have answered some of the questions more fully.
But anyway, I give thanks for your being here.
Your being here is like a blessing.
I love these people here.
I love the Korean people in general and these people here in particular.
God bless you.
I bless you in the name of the Lord.
Amen.
Beautiful people, yeah.
We have some blessings to do at this time.
Oh, okay.
And there is a, if you want to turn around here, there is women that are expecting.
Oh, oh.
And they, I don't know if you want to sit down for this, David.
Oh, no.
No.
We'll stand up, we'll stand up.
We'll take a, we'll get a sip of water.
Little boy who cut class to come.
Let's see, why are we seeing him?
Not again, just giving this blessing because he wanted to come and.
Oh, God bless you and thank you for coming.
God bless you.
Thank you for coming.
Give me a hug.
Good, good, good, good.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Have a good week.
Have a good day.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
And then the baby.
Oh!
Hi, sweetheart.
God bless you.
In the name of the Lord, amen.
What a divine being.
He's so cute.
A divine being.
How much?
Oh, a child of God.
That was so good.
Thank you for such a lovely child.
Oh, God created another one.
I tried that before.
It's so beautiful.
Oh, God created another one!
I tried that before with him and he didn't like it.
Oh, he likes you. He loves you, David.
Yes, well, you were created by God, that's why.
Oh, God bless the baby in your womb. Amen.
God's creation.
All creatures are creatures of God.
So you hold within your womb the creation of God
and you have reverence for it
and reverence that you have been chosen as a mother.
I'm not a mother.
I wasn't chosen by God to be a mother.
You were chosen by God to be a mother.
Yes, otherwise you wouldn't be pregnant.
And a great blessing.
He's a soldier?
Yes.
Oh.
And you know the conflict between North Korea and South Korea.
Oh, yes?
Yes.
So he's one of the men who are defending.
Oh, good.
You're in the army?
Captain.
Huh?
A captain.
In the army?
Uh-huh.
Oh, very good.
I was in the Navy in World War II.
World War II.
So, serviceman.
Service.
Service is a great thing to experience,
to be part of a whole army, part of a whole ship.
It's a great experience.
Great experience.
And you make friendships that last many years.
I was on a ship.
We had a small ship, 26.
26.
And after the war, we sent each other cards for many years.
For many years.
For 50 years.
I got Christmas.
For years and years.
Every year I got Christmas cards from other crew members.
And gradually as the years went by, the number of cards got fewer and fewer.
This year I got.
Say none.
This year I didn't get any.
So you see the love, the bond, lasts a lifetime.
So it is a different kind of love than romantic love.
Love of your fellow man.
And it's a great love.
It lasts 50 years.
Yes.
There were several other people that wanted to shake hands.
Oh yeah.
Fine.
You tell me whatever you want.
It's fine with me.
Whatever you want, it's fine with me.
Glad to meet you.
I'm honored to meet you.
Thank you so much for being here.
Thank you.
wine you look beautiful today lovely oh thank you so much for being here beautiful woman you're a
beautiful woman thank you for being here I bless you thank you so much for allowing me to do so
god bless you for being here look how tall he is thank you so much for being here yes hello
hello god bless you god bless you thank you for being here thank you for being here yes
you have a smiley face smiley face
thank you she smells so nice oh how beautiful your dress today you look beautiful yes ah another
beauty another beauty beautiful costume you lovely yes he's concerned whether the joke was
a real or the joke was a real or was it just a joke just a joke
it's a funny joke you know
a man feels sorry for himself you know if he finds that you're sorry for himself
see it you know life is full of challenges all the time it's full of challenges all the
time all kinds of challenges see you lose your eyesight I can't see anymore can't see
anymore can't see anymore you get old you get old you lose your thumb those are the vicissitudes of
life many of them are the undoing of Karma negative Karma you know so we meet them as best we can
vicissitudes of life yeah this is it yes that's a nice jacket I like that jacket would that fit me
Would that fit me?
That would fit me pretty near.
Thank you.
God bless.
God bless you.
God bless you, sir.
Three heart.
You're charming.
You're a charming girl.
Charming.
Yes.
God bless you.
Thank you.
That's nice and warm, isn't it?
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Hi.
I'll have to stand on my tiptoes.
There.
God bless.
He's asking for his daughter, who's suffering from the illness.
The illness.
His daughter is having an illness.
What is the illness?
Tuberous sclerosis.
Some DNA defect.
Oh.
Yes.
Yeah.
Okay.
God bless her.
Anyway.
She fulfills her destiny that way.
Can we get rid of some negative karma?
Yeah.
That's fulfilling that.
That's.
That's fulfilling that destiny.
Whatever befalls us, you know, has to do with destiny.
And destiny, you know, karma means one's destiny, that all that we have inherited as human beings, you see.
Through the undoing of negative karma, we fulfill our destiny and we reach salvation.
I guess salvation, you know.
And to try and accept it with grace.
to try and accept one's karma
with grace. Yes. That's a nice
chapter too. I like that one.
Thank you.
Yes. God bless you.
You have
a smiley face. Smiles.
Good smile.
That cheers up the world.
You smile at people
when you walk down the street and they go
Yes.
Thank you for smiling.
Uh-huh.
He's tall too.
Tall young man.
How old are you?
40.
40? 40? Yeah.
Oh. I thought he was
younger than that.
Okay. Now what?
You have courage.
Hi. How are you?
I have a special one for you.
Good to see you.
God bless you.
This is lovely.
Is this a
Korean necklace?
They can hug me as long as they're gentle about it.
Here's a handsome young man.
God bless him.
Look how nice he looks.
Beautifully dressed.
Oh, that's lovely. Thank you.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you.
Oh.
You told me I'd be able to serve you,
but I love you.
Ah.
Thank you for coming, yes.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Oh, great.
Oh, these people came such a long way.
I'm honored by the long trip you made to be here.
Yes.
Isn't that lovely?
Always.
Oh, they always look at each other.
I did.
Oh.
Oh, I'm so lucky.
Who else can we hug?
We're running out of people to hug.
Oh, hi, hi.
Side by side.
Thank you.
Yes.
Good to see you.
Side by side.
Yes.
They come tall, too, huh?
Thank you.
Uh-huh.
Glad to see you.
Yes.
It's wonderful to see all you people.
How does that saying go?
The mountain won't go to Muhammad.
Muhammad goes to them.
Or is it the other way around?
Thank you so much.
Oh.
Yes, I love you all.
Yes.
Thank you so much, sir.
Very special people.
I don't know why it's so special, but something.
Thank you so much.
Something about being Korean is wonderful.
You want a hug?
No.
I'll be good writer, like you.
Okay.
God bless you.
It's a handsome man.
Handsome.
Handsome, good-looking.
Yes.
Thank you.
Thank you all for being here.
I mean, what an honor to have people travel so long.
Oh.
Yes.
Give him a long love.
Thank you.
Gloria in excelsis Deo, could you?
Yeah, let me see, where's my table at?
But it is a new cause that I don't know if it's a new or a new cause.
Yeah, uh-huh.
Actually, I guess,
we don't know if it's a karma or whether it is a lesson,
you know, such as respecting life or,
or,
I can't see where it is, but I think it's on the line.
So, you can't always say it's all the way there,
everything is done,
but it's up to us to take the license and move forward,
and maybe we have other people that have the same problem,
we don't know.
Well, that's why I'm so, that's why I'm so,
maybe I'm, I mean, I don't know what's going on.
You're talking about this?
Yes, that's what I thought,
but I have,
I'm not sure, I'm not sure, I'm not sure.
Bowing to you.
What?
Bowing, we'll be bowing to you as we do on the New Year's Day.
Oh, oh, oh.
As an expression of our love to you.
Oh, how very nice, how very nice.
Maybe my way is that I love you.
Susan, yeah, yeah, can we do this?
.
Oh, how beautiful.
Thanks to you, Lord.
Amen, I bless you all, in the name of the Lord, amen.
I bless you all in the name of the Lord, amen.
So at this moment, last for eternity,
this moment will always be.
.
It expresses the oneness that we are all together one.
You know, I'm greatly honored by your being here, and my heart is overflowing.
Thank you so much for your love.
Thank you.
Yes, so tremendous.
Where's Dr. Moon?
You.
Come here, sweetheart.
Thank you for bringing you here.
They're so adorable.
Yes, we do.
Do you have our e-notes?
They're so adorable.
Okay, so we'll get you that I got.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
I told her all these people here are adorable.
More than lovable, adorable.
Could we take a picture all together?
Yes.
Where do we go?
Outside.
Outside is better.
We want to bring that suit.
Yes, we'll go outside.
Thank you.
take that take that take this take this there
oh oh hurry hurry hurry hurry hurry up there's more
god bless you all so much thank you so much
just take a picture yes take a picture whatever you wish whatever you wish