>> after another.
>> after another. >> Yep.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> If it isn't here, it's there. You got to
>> If it isn't here, it's there. You got to
>> If it isn't here, it's there. You got to be someplace.
be someplace.
be someplace. >> Yep.
>> No matter who you are, you got to be
>> No matter who you are, you got to be someplace.
Where's the microphone?
Where's the microphone? >> It's on you.
>> It's on you.
>> It's on you. >> Oh, it's on me.
>> Oh, it's on me.
>> Oh, it's on me. >> I have to talk in this.
>> I have to talk in this.
>> I have to talk in this. >> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see. I thought it was just ladies day. She
I thought it was just ladies day. She
I thought it was just ladies day. She gets the microphone and I get to listen.
>> What is this thing behind me here?
>> What is this thing behind me here? >> It's called a pillow that you're
>> It's called a pillow that you're
>> It's called a pillow that you're supposed to sit on.
supposed to sit on.
supposed to sit on. >> Oh, okay.
All right.
All right. >> Yay. Well, we were saying we we want to
>> Yay. Well, we were saying we we want to
>> Yay. Well, we were saying we we want to become less and less dedactic over the
become less and less dedactic over the
become less and less dedactic over the years, you know, because all the
years, you know, because all the
years, you know, because all the research that was done took, you know,
research that was done took, you know,
research that was done took, you know, took a lot of research
took a lot of research
took a lot of research and uh now we want to become more and
and uh now we want to become more and
and uh now we want to become more and more nonlinear, you know, less dedactic
more nonlinear, you know, less dedactic
more nonlinear, you know, less dedactic and more like a uh what you want to call
and more like a uh what you want to call
and more like a uh what you want to call it that we have at night uh
it that we have at night uh
it that we have at night uh >> sings.
>> sings.
>> sings. >> Yeah. Yeah. More and more spontaneous
>> Yeah. Yeah. More and more spontaneous
>> Yeah. Yeah. More and more spontaneous and nonlinear,
and nonlinear,
and nonlinear, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? And uh so one thing was our discussing
And uh so one thing was our discussing
And uh so one thing was our discussing uh matters the way we often discuss
uh matters the way we often discuss
uh matters the way we often discuss them,
them,
them, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Um
>> Um
>> Um >> uh
>> uh
>> uh >> we've had um we had this open discussion
>> we've had um we had this open discussion
>> we've had um we had this open discussion one time in in Sedona and everybody
one time in in Sedona and everybody
one time in in Sedona and everybody liked it and we covered prayer. I don't
liked it and we covered prayer. I don't
liked it and we covered prayer. I don't know if any of you have that DVD, but it
know if any of you have that DVD, but it
know if any of you have that DVD, but it was really good and we wanted to cover
was really good and we wanted to cover
was really good and we wanted to cover it thoroughly. Well, we've we were
it thoroughly. Well, we've we were
it thoroughly. Well, we've we were talking about this and he says, "Well,
talking about this and he says, "Well,
talking about this and he says, "Well, the next thing I wanted to cover is
the next thing I wanted to cover is
the next thing I wanted to cover is guilt
and we thought that it might fit in with
and we thought that it might fit in with this lecture." Um,
this lecture." Um,
this lecture." Um, >> well, husbands and wives get into guilt
>> well, husbands and wives get into guilt
>> well, husbands and wives get into guilt trading in a way.
trading in a way.
trading in a way. >> Yes, they do.
>> Yes, they do.
>> Yes, they do. >> I mean, who who left the door to the
>> I mean, who who left the door to the
>> I mean, who who left the door to the refrigerator open? You know what I'm
refrigerator open? You know what I'm
refrigerator open? You know what I'm saying?
saying?
saying? >> Was it me with them gremlins again? Did
>> Was it me with them gremlins again? Did
>> Was it me with them gremlins again? Did it?
it?
it? >> I don't know. We We have a new
>> I don't know. We We have a new
>> I don't know. We We have a new refrigerator that's smart. It beeps at
refrigerator that's smart. It beeps at
refrigerator that's smart. It beeps at you when you leave the door open.
you when you leave the door open.
you when you leave the door open. We haven't had one in 30 years. We It
We haven't had one in 30 years. We It
We haven't had one in 30 years. We It was on its way out. So we got a new one.
was on its way out. So we got a new one.
was on its way out. So we got a new one. >> 30 years we got another one.
>> 30 years we got another one.
>> 30 years we got another one. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> So anyway, it beeps at you. The doors
>> So anyway, it beeps at you. The doors
>> So anyway, it beeps at you. The doors left over. It goes
left over. It goes
left over. It goes and go, "What's that?"
and go, "What's that?"
and go, "What's that?" >> Anyway, guilt. All right. My question is
>> Anyway, guilt. All right. My question is
>> Anyway, guilt. All right. My question is when is guilt in a act uh when is guilt
when is guilt in a act uh when is guilt
when is guilt in a act uh when is guilt positive
positive
positive >> and when is guilt negative in one's life
>> and when is guilt negative in one's life
>> and when is guilt negative in one's life >> because there's good guilt I mean you
>> because there's good guilt I mean you
>> because there's good guilt I mean you know when you're guilty because uh you
know when you're guilty because uh you
know when you're guilty because uh you might have hurt someone's feelings you
might have hurt someone's feelings you
might have hurt someone's feelings you know and you say why did I do that
know and you say why did I do that
know and you say why did I do that >> you know why I wish I could change that
>> you know why I wish I could change that
>> you know why I wish I could change that incident in my life and then there's um
incident in my life and then there's um
incident in my life and then there's um bad guilt where you just continually
bad guilt where you just continually
bad guilt where you just continually build you know continually beat yourself
build you know continually beat yourself
build you know continually beat yourself up over something that had done or said
up over something that had done or said
up over something that had done or said that
that
that >> you know so when
>> you know so when
>> you know so when >> when is appropriate well when you see on
>> when is appropriate well when you see on
>> when is appropriate well when you see on the calibrated level of consciousness
the calibrated level of consciousness
the calibrated level of consciousness guilt is what 90 or something
guilt is what 90 or something
guilt is what 90 or something >> it's down the down below 200
>> it's down the down below 200
>> it's down the down below 200 >> uh so the idea is how to turn it around
>> uh so the idea is how to turn it around
>> uh so the idea is how to turn it around into something useful
into something useful
into something useful >> right
>> right
>> right >> that
>> that
>> that Well, you know, because it's because
Well, you know, because it's because
Well, you know, because it's because where we get guilt from in the
where we get guilt from in the
where we get guilt from in the beginning, you know, is our parents
beginning, you know, is our parents
beginning, you know, is our parents being a naughty boy or a naughty girl or
being a naughty boy or a naughty girl or
being a naughty boy or a naughty girl or doing something naughty.
doing something naughty.
doing something naughty. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> So, it's part of the Freudian super ego,
>> So, it's part of the Freudian super ego,
>> So, it's part of the Freudian super ego, you know. So, guilt becomes the
you know. So, guilt becomes the
you know. So, guilt becomes the introjected parent.
introjected parent.
introjected parent. So you know if the psyche is like child
So you know if the psyche is like child
So you know if the psyche is like child uh adult and parent the simplest
uh adult and parent the simplest
uh adult and parent the simplest psychological division is the inner
psychological division is the inner
psychological division is the inner child the inner adult and the inner
child the inner adult and the inner
child the inner adult and the inner parent.
parent.
parent. >> So the what you have is the interjected
>> So the what you have is the interjected
>> So the what you have is the interjected parent
parent
parent uh the super ego the conscience becoming
uh the super ego the conscience becoming
uh the super ego the conscience becoming punitive
punitive
punitive and of course that's the way the child
and of course that's the way the child
and of course that's the way the child hears it and that's the way the parents
hears it and that's the way the parents
hears it and that's the way the parents mean it too. If you keep it up, you're
mean it too. If you keep it up, you're
mean it too. If you keep it up, you're going to get a spanking or something.
going to get a spanking or something.
going to get a spanking or something. So, it naturally lowers your
So, it naturally lowers your
So, it naturally lowers your self-esteem.
self-esteem.
self-esteem. So, the idea is how can you teach your
So, the idea is how can you teach your
So, the idea is how can you teach your super ego to be more become more benign
super ego to be more become more benign
super ego to be more become more benign more benign
>> and uh in my own life I had quite a
>> and uh in my own life I had quite a battle with it.
battle with it.
battle with it. As I've said before in lectures, I had a
As I've said before in lectures, I had a
As I've said before in lectures, I had a super ego that was overly active and uh
super ego that was overly active and uh
super ego that was overly active and uh I had to go for counseling on
I had to go for counseling on
I had to go for counseling on scrupulosity, you know, and I I lived in
scrupulosity, you know, and I I lived in
scrupulosity, you know, and I I lived in dread of a sin and uh
dread of a sin and uh
dread of a sin and uh and I don't know what I thought would
and I don't know what I thought would
and I don't know what I thought would happen. I guess you went to hell or
happen. I guess you went to hell or
happen. I guess you went to hell or something, but I I was scared to death
something, but I I was scared to death
something, but I I was scared to death of a sin. And um
of a sin. And um
of a sin. And um >> God could see this sin. It was like a a
>> God could see this sin. It was like a a
>> God could see this sin. It was like a a stain on your window shield back here.
stain on your window shield back here.
stain on your window shield back here. Anyway, this this little blot of sin
Anyway, this this little blot of sin
Anyway, this this little blot of sin would appear and God would see this sin
would appear and God would see this sin
would appear and God would see this sin on your soul.
on your soul.
on your soul. >> So, it was sort of scary.
>> So, it was sort of scary.
>> So, it was sort of scary. >> It's like you're afraid of your own
>> It's like you're afraid of your own
>> It's like you're afraid of your own thoughts. You might think of something
thoughts. You might think of something
thoughts. You might think of something sinful. You know what I'm saying?
sinful. You know what I'm saying?
sinful. You know what I'm saying? >> Well, let's say um
>> Well, let's say um
>> Well, let's say um All right.
All right.
All right. is um a a sin is wouldn't you consider
is um a a sin is wouldn't you consider
is um a a sin is wouldn't you consider though like a sin as something that you
though like a sin as something that you
though like a sin as something that you wouldn't be remorseful for?
wouldn't be remorseful for?
wouldn't be remorseful for? >> Well, that would make it a sin sin,
>> Well, that would make it a sin sin,
>> Well, that would make it a sin sin, wouldn't it?
wouldn't it?
wouldn't it? >> Not only did you sin, but you didn't
>> Not only did you sin, but you didn't
>> Not only did you sin, but you didn't even feel guilty.
even feel guilty.
even feel guilty. >> Once you recognize once you once you
>> Once you recognize once you once you
>> Once you recognize once you once you recognize a sin though, then it's then
recognize a sin though, then it's then
recognize a sin though, then it's then the guilt of course comes in. But if you
the guilt of course comes in. But if you
the guilt of course comes in. But if you didn't recognize it as a sin, I mean,
didn't recognize it as a sin, I mean,
didn't recognize it as a sin, I mean, I'm trying to
I'm trying to
I'm trying to >> if you didn't label it uh theologically.
>> if you didn't label it uh theologically.
>> if you didn't label it uh theologically. Yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. >> Well, you might say that regret would be
>> Well, you might say that regret would be
>> Well, you might say that regret would be a better regret is a better alternative
a better regret is a better alternative
a better regret is a better alternative to guilt.
to guilt.
to guilt. >> You can you can wish you hadn't done you
>> You can you can wish you hadn't done you
>> You can you can wish you hadn't done you can regret it, but you don't have to go
can regret it, but you don't have to go
can regret it, but you don't have to go into self-punitive
into self-punitive
into self-punitive >> okay
>> okay
>> okay >> uh mode, you know. Well, everybody's
>> uh mode, you know. Well, everybody's
>> uh mode, you know. Well, everybody's always said or done something that they
always said or done something that they
always said or done something that they said, "Oh, why did I do that?" And it
said, "Oh, why did I do that?" And it
said, "Oh, why did I do that?" And it plagues you, you know, years and years
plagues you, you know, years and years
plagues you, you know, years and years and years and you go, "How do you drop
and years and you go, "How do you drop
and years and you go, "How do you drop that?"
that?"
that?" >> So, how do you drop it once you've
>> So, how do you drop it once you've
>> So, how do you drop it once you've already paid this years of,
already paid this years of,
already paid this years of, you know, of guilt? So, how then how do
you know, of guilt? So, how then how do
you know, of guilt? So, how then how do you drop that?
you drop that?
you drop that? >> How do you drop that? Because I mean,
>> How do you drop that? Because I mean,
>> How do you drop that? Because I mean, it's obvious. Well, you can change it
it's obvious. Well, you can change it
it's obvious. Well, you can change it change it to something less punitive
change it to something less punitive
change it to something less punitive like regret.
like regret.
like regret. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> And then uh you have to move to
>> And then uh you have to move to
>> And then uh you have to move to forgiveness. You have to move to
forgiveness. You have to move to
forgiveness. You have to move to forgiveness.
forgiveness.
forgiveness. >> So then you had to forgive yourself
>> So then you had to forgive yourself
>> So then you had to forgive yourself then for this action and of saying
then for this action and of saying
then for this action and of saying either not knowing better just like you
either not knowing better just like you
either not knowing better just like you would with someone else.
would with someone else.
would with someone else. >> Yes. You'd also have to feel that you're
>> Yes. You'd also have to feel that you're
>> Yes. You'd also have to feel that you're entitled to forgiveness.
entitled to forgiveness.
entitled to forgiveness. >> Ah
>> Ah
>> Ah >> some people are so busy berating themsel
>> some people are so busy berating themsel
>> some people are so busy berating themsel they don't feel they deserve
they don't feel they deserve
they don't feel they deserve forgiveness.
forgiveness.
forgiveness. All right.
All right.
All right. >> So there's no end to their uh
>> So there's no end to their uh
>> So there's no end to their uh >> you know jail sentence,
>> you know jail sentence,
>> you know jail sentence, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Lifetime of guilt over something.
>> Lifetime of guilt over something.
>> Lifetime of guilt over something. >> So So then you got these burden that
>> So So then you got these burden that
>> So So then you got these burden that you're carrying around,
you're carrying around,
you're carrying around, you know, on your shoulders going, why
you know, on your shoulders going, why
you know, on your shoulders going, why did I do that? That happened back when I
did I do that? That happened back when I
did I do that? That happened back when I was five years old and I still can't get
was five years old and I still can't get
was five years old and I still can't get rid of it,
rid of it,
rid of it, >> you know.
>> you know.
>> you know. >> Yes. Some of those last a lifetime,
>> Yes. Some of those last a lifetime,
>> Yes. Some of those last a lifetime, don't they? Yes.
don't they? Yes.
don't they? Yes. And uh of course the religion tends to
And uh of course the religion tends to
And uh of course the religion tends to intensify it to some degree because
intensify it to some degree because
intensify it to some degree because >> a lot of what you feel guilty about is
>> a lot of what you feel guilty about is
>> a lot of what you feel guilty about is labeled as sin on top of it.
labeled as sin on top of it.
labeled as sin on top of it. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> Not only was it bad, wrong, and guilty,
>> Not only was it bad, wrong, and guilty,
>> Not only was it bad, wrong, and guilty, but it's sinful on top of it. You know,
but it's sinful on top of it. You know,
but it's sinful on top of it. You know, >> so then you could begin to get more
>> so then you could begin to get more
>> so then you could begin to get more sophisticated about what is sinful
sophisticated about what is sinful
sophisticated about what is sinful and begin to see that guilt is really
and begin to see that guilt is really
and begin to see that guilt is really self-indulgence.
self-indulgence.
self-indulgence. Oh,
Oh,
Oh, >> so you can stop feeling guilty
>> so you can stop feeling guilty
>> so you can stop feeling guilty and uh start feeling guilty about the
and uh start feeling guilty about the
and uh start feeling guilty about the fact that your guilt is self-indulgent.
>> Get the juice out.
>> Get the juice out. >> Well, it's really narcissistic, isn't
>> Well, it's really narcissistic, isn't
>> Well, it's really narcissistic, isn't guilt? Guilt is really wallowing in
guilt? Guilt is really wallowing in
guilt? Guilt is really wallowing in narcissism.
narcissism.
narcissism. >> Oh, wicked, wicked me. So, who's the
>> Oh, wicked, wicked me. So, who's the
>> Oh, wicked, wicked me. So, who's the who's the main person on stage there?
who's the main person on stage there?
who's the main person on stage there? It's me.
It's me.
It's me. >> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see. >> Oh, me made the guilt. Me made the
>> Oh, me made the guilt. Me made the
>> Oh, me made the guilt. Me made the mistake. me is guilty. Me is
mistake. me is guilty. Me is
mistake. me is guilty. Me is >> I'm the bad person.
>> I'm the bad person.
>> I'm the bad person. >> It's the big me. So yeah, capital me
>> It's the big me. So yeah, capital me
>> It's the big me. So yeah, capital me >> is the is center stage again.
>> is the is center stage again.
>> is the is center stage again. >> You can see how the narcissistic
>> You can see how the narcissistic
>> You can see how the narcissistic ego
ego
ego loves to wallow in sin. You know,
loves to wallow in sin. You know,
loves to wallow in sin. You know, remember the flagagulates and uh
remember the flagagulates and uh
remember the flagagulates and uh >> mortification and
>> mortification and
>> mortification and all this kind of stuff you go through.
all this kind of stuff you go through.
all this kind of stuff you go through. Well, what's the guil difference between
Well, what's the guil difference between
Well, what's the guil difference between guilt and shame?
guilt and shame?
guilt and shame? >> Shame shame uh we get from society. You
>> Shame shame uh we get from society. You
>> Shame shame uh we get from society. You see?
see?
see? >> Yeah. And the guilty one if if they're
>> Yeah. And the guilty one if if they're
>> Yeah. And the guilty one if if they're not careful gets expelled from society.
not careful gets expelled from society.
not careful gets expelled from society. So shame in a way is you're expelled
So shame in a way is you're expelled
So shame in a way is you're expelled from society or expelled from the group.
from society or expelled from the group.
from society or expelled from the group. You're sent off and it's it's really a
You're sent off and it's it's really a
You're sent off and it's it's really a banishment.
banishment.
banishment. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Shame is really banishment from
Shame is really banishment from
Shame is really banishment from integrous company. You know, you should
integrous company. You know, you should
integrous company. You know, you should be ashamed of yourself showing around
be ashamed of yourself showing around
be ashamed of yourself showing around here.
It's banishment. In the uncon conscious,
It's banishment. In the uncon conscious, banishment means death because the only
banishment means death because the only
banishment means death because the only way you survived over evolutionary time
way you survived over evolutionary time
way you survived over evolutionary time was belonging to a family, belonging to
was belonging to a family, belonging to
was belonging to a family, belonging to a tribe, etc. Mhm.
a tribe, etc. Mhm.
a tribe, etc. Mhm. >> So if you violated the mores of the
>> So if you violated the mores of the
>> So if you violated the mores of the group and became banished, that was a
group and became banished, that was a
group and became banished, that was a sentence to death because nobody in
sentence to death because nobody in
sentence to death because nobody in those, you know, you couldn't survive
those, you know, you couldn't survive
those, you know, you couldn't survive very long in the wilderness all by
very long in the wilderness all by
very long in the wilderness all by yourself.
yourself.
yourself. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> It's only by group dynamics that a
>> It's only by group dynamics that a
>> It's only by group dynamics that a society evolved. So banishment really
society evolved. So banishment really
society evolved. So banishment really meant uh death in a way.
meant uh death in a way.
meant uh death in a way. Yeah. So if a wolfpack banishes
Yeah. So if a wolfpack banishes
Yeah. So if a wolfpack banishes a bad wolf, he he's banished really to
a bad wolf, he he's banished really to
a bad wolf, he he's banished really to die.
die.
die. >> So churches when they excommunicate
>> So churches when they excommunicate
>> So churches when they excommunicate people, it's pretty serious.
people, it's pretty serious.
people, it's pretty serious. >> Yeah. Excommunication.
That's the unforgivable.
That's the unforgivable. >> Well, I think Jesus teachings is much
>> Well, I think Jesus teachings is much
>> Well, I think Jesus teachings is much better, you know. Yeah,
>> I like his better.
>> I like his better. >> For forgive that ye you may be forgiven.
>> For forgive that ye you may be forgiven.
>> For forgive that ye you may be forgiven. You know, forgive
You know, forgive
You know, forgive as I forgive others, I earn the right to
as I forgive others, I earn the right to
as I forgive others, I earn the right to be forgiven myself.
be forgiven myself.
be forgiven myself. So you you look at rel re re letting go
So you you look at rel re re letting go
So you you look at rel re re letting go of guilt as a form of uh of worshiping
of guilt as a form of uh of worshiping
of guilt as a form of uh of worshiping God. If you really love God, then you
God. If you really love God, then you
God. If you really love God, then you stop berating. After all, you are a
stop berating. After all, you are a
stop berating. After all, you are a creatur creation of God, a creature of
creatur creation of God, a creature of
creatur creation of God, a creature of God.
God.
God. >> So, you stop uh punishing one of God's
>> So, you stop uh punishing one of God's
>> So, you stop uh punishing one of God's creatures. So, you can turn that benign
creatures. So, you can turn that benign
creatures. So, you can turn that benign uh viewpoint. See?
uh viewpoint. See?
uh viewpoint. See? >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> So, this morning was interesting as I
>> So, this morning was interesting as I
>> So, this morning was interesting as I talked about George Soros,
talked about George Soros,
talked about George Soros, I felt this surge of positive
I felt this surge of positive
I felt this surge of positive uh agape kind of love surge up about
uh agape kind of love surge up about
uh agape kind of love surge up about George. I actually fell a love for him
George. I actually fell a love for him
George. I actually fell a love for him and I thought, poor George.
I saw him as lovable. Not, you know, not
I saw him as lovable. Not, you know, not through my intellect, not through reason
through my intellect, not through reason
through my intellect, not through reason or anything, but a surge of lovability,
or anything, but a surge of lovability,
or anything, but a surge of lovability, a gay-haired old man trying to do the
a gay-haired old man trying to do the
a gay-haired old man trying to do the best he can
best he can
best he can >> and uh, you know, whatever you might
>> and uh, you know, whatever you might
>> and uh, you know, whatever you might think about him, etc.
think about him, etc.
think about him, etc. but just as a fellow human being
but just as a fellow human being
but just as a fellow human being struggling to do whatever he perceives
struggling to do whatever he perceives
struggling to do whatever he perceives at the given moment as being beneficial
at the given moment as being beneficial
at the given moment as being beneficial to the world etc.
to the world etc.
to the world etc. >> Well, when
>> Well, when
>> Well, when >> uh
>> uh
>> uh >> for instance um some teachings you know
>> for instance um some teachings you know
>> for instance um some teachings you know of course they have the ten commandments
of course they have the ten commandments
of course they have the ten commandments and if you break one you know it's a sin
and if you break one you know it's a sin
and if you break one you know it's a sin and then you have the guilt of breaking
and then you have the guilt of breaking
and then you have the guilt of breaking that 10 commandment with the sin. Um,
that 10 commandment with the sin. Um,
that 10 commandment with the sin. Um, what is the purpose of of that type of
what is the purpose of of that type of
what is the purpose of of that type of >> the commandments?
>> the commandments?
>> the commandments? >> No. What is the purpose of that type of
>> No. What is the purpose of that type of
>> No. What is the purpose of that type of self-punishment?
self-punishment?
self-punishment? >> I mean, what what is the not that I
>> I mean, what what is the not that I
>> I mean, what what is the not that I would break a ten commandment, don't get
would break a ten commandment, don't get
would break a ten commandment, don't get me wrong, but I mean, what is the what
me wrong, but I mean, what is the what
me wrong, but I mean, what is the what is the um purpose of teaching um that
is the um purpose of teaching um that
is the um purpose of teaching um that kind of self-punishment?
kind of self-punishment?
kind of self-punishment? >> Well, it's you know, penance. In other
>> Well, it's you know, penance. In other
>> Well, it's you know, penance. In other words, uh
words, uh
words, uh if you if you're Catholic or Episcopal
if you if you're Catholic or Episcopal
if you if you're Catholic or Episcopal or something, you go to confession
or something, you go to confession
or something, you go to confession >> and the priest listens to your
>> and the priest listens to your
>> and the priest listens to your confession and he finds out if you're
confession and he finds out if you're
confession and he finds out if you're really contrite and he gives you 10 Hail
really contrite and he gives you 10 Hail
really contrite and he gives you 10 Hail Marys and 10 our fathers
Marys and 10 our fathers
Marys and 10 our fathers and uh then he gives you absolution.
and uh then he gives you absolution.
and uh then he gives you absolution. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So it's psychologically you know
So it's psychologically you know
So it's psychologically you know psychological fraudian mechanism would
psychological fraudian mechanism would
psychological fraudian mechanism would be called undoing undoing. So and you
be called undoing undoing. So and you
be called undoing undoing. So and you undo the guilt through penance and good
undo the guilt through penance and good
undo the guilt through penance and good works and uh sincerity.
works and uh sincerity.
works and uh sincerity. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So how to make the super ego more benign
So how to make the super ego more benign
So how to make the super ego more benign you know.
you know.
you know. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> The conscience more benign. And in his
>> The conscience more benign. And in his
>> The conscience more benign. And in his psychoanalysis, the first thing well,
psychoanalysis, the first thing well,
psychoanalysis, the first thing well, first of all, I went for, you know,
first of all, I went for, you know,
first of all, I went for, you know, training about scrupulosity.
training about scrupulosity.
training about scrupulosity. And the first thing my analyst said to
And the first thing my analyst said to
And the first thing my analyst said to me was, uh, you know, you have we have
me was, uh, you know, you have we have
me was, uh, you know, you have we have to develop a more benign superego. How
to develop a more benign superego. How
to develop a more benign superego. How can you say what you're holding in your
can you say what you're holding in your
can you say what you're holding in your unconscious if every time it comes up,
unconscious if every time it comes up,
unconscious if every time it comes up, you're going to beat yourself up with
you're going to beat yourself up with
you're going to beat yourself up with guilt?
guilt?
guilt? >> So, you need a more benign way of
>> So, you need a more benign way of
>> So, you need a more benign way of viewing.
viewing.
viewing. And and stop making your errors
And and stop making your errors
And and stop making your errors personal. They're due to humanness. It's
personal. They're due to humanness. It's
personal. They're due to humanness. It's a human defect. See, so the reason guilt
a human defect. See, so the reason guilt
a human defect. See, so the reason guilt is narcissistic is they say, "Oh, me,
is narcissistic is they say, "Oh, me,
is narcissistic is they say, "Oh, me, wicked, wicked, guilty me." When you're
wicked, wicked, guilty me." When you're
wicked, wicked, guilty me." When you're really talking about a limitation
really talking about a limitation
really talking about a limitation inherent in mankind,
inherent in mankind,
inherent in mankind, human consciousness hasn't evolved to
human consciousness hasn't evolved to
human consciousness hasn't evolved to the uh level that that would preclude uh
the uh level that that would preclude uh
the uh level that that would preclude uh making any error. You would have to be
making any error. You would have to be
making any error. You would have to be omnisient.
omnisient.
omnisient. >> You'd have to be omnisient to never make
>> You'd have to be omnisient to never make
>> You'd have to be omnisient to never make a mistake. No, never put the butter in
a mistake. No, never put the butter in
a mistake. No, never put the butter in the cheese compartment. It's not
the cheese compartment. It's not
the cheese compartment. It's not possible.
possible.
possible. You left the refrigerator door open
You left the refrigerator door open
You left the refrigerator door open again. No, not me.
again. No, not me.
again. No, not me. The cat did it.
>> We're going to get a doggy and we can
>> We're going to get a doggy and we can blame things on the dog. That'll be
blame things on the dog. That'll be
blame things on the dog. That'll be handy.
handy.
handy. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah. It'd be his fault.
>> Yeah. It'd be his fault.
>> Yeah. It'd be his fault. >> The dog did it.
>> The dog did it.
>> The dog did it. >> The bird's already paid its price.
>> The bird's already paid its price.
>> The bird's already paid its price. >> All right. So you you make a resolution
>> All right. So you you make a resolution
>> All right. So you you make a resolution that I will stop indul indulging in the
that I will stop indul indulging in the
that I will stop indul indulging in the narcissistic
narcissistic
narcissistic self ingrandisment of guilt.
self ingrandisment of guilt.
self ingrandisment of guilt. Instead I will be towards myself the
Instead I will be towards myself the
Instead I will be towards myself the same as I am towards all living things
same as I am towards all living things
same as I am towards all living things and that is with benign goodwill.
and that is with benign goodwill.
and that is with benign goodwill. I will turn benign goodwill and realize
I will turn benign goodwill and realize
I will turn benign goodwill and realize that the limitations of being human. So
that the limitations of being human. So
that the limitations of being human. So in other words, when you do something
in other words, when you do something
in other words, when you do something that's say not quite ethical or
that's say not quite ethical or
that's say not quite ethical or whatever, I'm trying I have a specific
whatever, I'm trying I have a specific
whatever, I'm trying I have a specific thing in mind that I'm thinking of that
thing in mind that I'm thinking of that
thing in mind that I'm thinking of that happened in childhood. So if you do
happened in childhood. So if you do
happened in childhood. So if you do something to another person
something to another person
something to another person >> and you feel guilt about that and yet
>> and you feel guilt about that and yet
>> and you feel guilt about that and yet um eventually it seems like you realize
um eventually it seems like you realize
um eventually it seems like you realize that it was just not it wasn't that you
that it was just not it wasn't that you
that it was just not it wasn't that you intentionally did it. it was just that
intentionally did it. it was just that
intentionally did it. it was just that you were naive and didn't realize that
you were naive and didn't realize that
you were naive and didn't realize that that was actually going to hurt someone
that was actually going to hurt someone
that was actually going to hurt someone else's feelings or hurt them as a
else's feelings or hurt them as a
else's feelings or hurt them as a person. So, you know, there's certain in
person. So, you know, there's certain in
person. So, you know, there's certain in a way I can understand what you're
a way I can understand what you're
a way I can understand what you're saying that it's almost like a learn
saying that it's almost like a learn
saying that it's almost like a learn there's also a learning process involved
there's also a learning process involved
there's also a learning process involved in some guilt too.
in some guilt too.
in some guilt too. >> You learn never to do that again.
>> You learn never to do that again.
>> You learn never to do that again. >> You have to ask who who made the mistake
>> You have to ask who who made the mistake
>> You have to ask who who made the mistake in the first place. It was the child,
in the first place. It was the child,
in the first place. It was the child, the adult or the parent in you. See, and
the adult or the parent in you. See, and
the adult or the parent in you. See, and of course, what really feels worse is
of course, what really feels worse is
of course, what really feels worse is the parent because if you've made
the parent because if you've made
the parent because if you've made somebody wrong for something and then
somebody wrong for something and then
somebody wrong for something and then later discovered that they actually
later discovered that they actually
later discovered that they actually didn't do it. Oh, wow. I mean, that is a
didn't do it. Oh, wow. I mean, that is a
didn't do it. Oh, wow. I mean, that is a now you're really young up, you know,
now you're really young up, you know,
now you're really young up, you know, >> you know, because you've now injured
>> you know, because you've now injured
>> you know, because you've now injured another human being. So you try to be as
another human being. So you try to be as
another human being. So you try to be as benign as you can in your viewpoint of
benign as you can in your viewpoint of
benign as you can in your viewpoint of life and then give yourself uh the same
life and then give yourself uh the same
life and then give yourself uh the same opportunity to be loved and cared for.
opportunity to be loved and cared for.
opportunity to be loved and cared for. You see because the crooked tree is just
You see because the crooked tree is just
You see because the crooked tree is just as loved by God as as the symmetrical
as loved by God as as the symmetrical
as loved by God as as the symmetrical tree is it not? You see
tree is it not? You see
tree is it not? You see >> there's nothing wrong with having a few
>> there's nothing wrong with having a few
>> there's nothing wrong with having a few knots in your branches.
Not in your world.
Not in your world. >> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uhhuh. >> Interesting.
>> Interesting.
>> Interesting. >> Well, some people never make a mistake.
>> Well, some people never make a mistake.
>> Well, some people never make a mistake. It's because they don't do anything in
It's because they don't do anything in
It's because they don't do anything in the world.
>> Well, that's what I'm saying. you can
>> Well, that's what I'm saying. you can learn from some errors you know and then
learn from some errors you know and then
learn from some errors you know and then but those errors uh you know I chose
but those errors uh you know I chose
but those errors uh you know I chose this not that
this not that
this not that >> in other words that one error might
>> in other words that one error might
>> in other words that one error might guide you towards a better understanding
guide you towards a better understanding
guide you towards a better understanding later
later
later >> yeah it's a karmic
>> yeah it's a karmic
>> yeah it's a karmic >> so sometimes I think that um
>> so sometimes I think that um
>> so sometimes I think that um a incident makes you a better person
a incident makes you a better person
a incident makes you a better person even though at the time you felt
even though at the time you felt
even though at the time you felt terrible
terrible
terrible >> yeah at the time you wish you didn't
>> yeah at the time you wish you didn't
>> yeah at the time you wish you didn't hadn't gone through it Right.
hadn't gone through it Right.
hadn't gone through it Right. >> But I think you end up more benevolent
>> But I think you end up more benevolent
>> But I think you end up more benevolent in the end. More benevolent
in the end. More benevolent
in the end. More benevolent >> about your own the limitation of your
>> about your own the limitation of your
>> about your own the limitation of your own humanness as well as everyone else.
own humanness as well as everyone else.
own humanness as well as everyone else. >> Right. Well, in other words, you say,
>> Right. Well, in other words, you say,
>> Right. Well, in other words, you say, "Oh, I wouldn't I won't do that, you
"Oh, I wouldn't I won't do that, you
"Oh, I wouldn't I won't do that, you know, or things that were done to you
know, or things that were done to you
know, or things that were done to you that weren't your fault or whatever it
that weren't your fault or whatever it
that weren't your fault or whatever it was." But you say, "Oh, I wouldn't do
was." But you say, "Oh, I wouldn't do
was." But you say, "Oh, I wouldn't do that to another person because I know
that to another person because I know
that to another person because I know how that feels on the other end,
how that feels on the other end,
how that feels on the other end, >> you So
>> you So
>> you So >> we try not to make the mistake of fa
>> we try not to make the mistake of fa
>> we try not to make the mistake of fa false uh
false uh
false uh >> accusations.
>> accusations.
>> accusations. >> Yes. Right. We try very hard not to
>> Yes. Right. We try very hard not to
>> Yes. Right. We try very hard not to because because we know how painful it
because because we know how painful it
because because we know how painful it is if we make a mistake.
is if we make a mistake.
is if we make a mistake. >> Right. But sometimes those things have
>> Right. But sometimes those things have
>> Right. But sometimes those things have to you have to experience them in order
to you have to experience them in order
to you have to experience them in order to know not to do them.
to know not to do them.
to know not to do them. >> Well that's the whole learning
>> Well that's the whole learning
>> Well that's the whole learning mechanism. So if the karmic uh purpose
mechanism. So if the karmic uh purpose
mechanism. So if the karmic uh purpose of human life you know is the evolution
of human life you know is the evolution
of human life you know is the evolution of consciousness and every time we've
of consciousness and every time we've
of consciousness and every time we've done the arm on it we get yes that is
done the arm on it we get yes that is
done the arm on it we get yes that is the purpose of human life is to undo
the purpose of human life is to undo
the purpose of human life is to undo negative karma and gain positive karma
negative karma and gain positive karma
negative karma and gain positive karma >> then turning that which is negative into
>> then turning that which is negative into
>> then turning that which is negative into something which is positive is one of
something which is positive is one of
something which is positive is one of the reasons we're here. Okay,
the reasons we're here. Okay,
the reasons we're here. Okay, >> one of the reasons we're here.
>> one of the reasons we're here.
>> one of the reasons we're here. >> So then some
>> So then some
>> So then some >> there's probably a lot of people in hell
>> there's probably a lot of people in hell
>> there's probably a lot of people in hell because they condemn themselves to hell.
because they condemn themselves to hell.
because they condemn themselves to hell. See,
See,
See, >> they condemn theel to hell. And uh
>> they condemn theel to hell. And uh
>> they condemn theel to hell. And uh somebody has to tell them when when
somebody has to tell them when when
somebody has to tell them when when enough suffering is enough. How much
enough suffering is enough. How much
enough suffering is enough. How much suffering would does does it take to
suffering would does does it take to
suffering would does does it take to undo one error? A month of it, a year,
undo one error? A month of it, a year,
undo one error? A month of it, a year, 10 years, lifetime, a decade.
10 years, lifetime, a decade.
10 years, lifetime, a decade. >> Like you were saying, you can remember
>> Like you were saying, you can remember
>> Like you were saying, you can remember things from childhood that bothered you
things from childhood that bothered you
things from childhood that bothered you for 30, 40 years,
for 30, 40 years,
for 30, 40 years, >> right? So, you know, how long do you
>> right? So, you know, how long do you
>> right? So, you know, how long do you have to carry those burdens or how long
have to carry those burdens or how long
have to carry those burdens or how long do would you say is is enough is enough,
do would you say is is enough is enough,
do would you say is is enough is enough, you know, depends on what it was. But I
you know, depends on what it was. But I
you know, depends on what it was. But I mean,
mean,
mean, >> right,
>> right,
>> right, >> it's still um
>> it's still um
>> it's still um what part of that is the ego juicing it
what part of that is the ego juicing it
what part of that is the ego juicing it and what part of that is actual
and what part of that is actual
and what part of that is actual >> Yeah. is real.
>> Yeah. is real.
>> Yeah. is real. >> Real.
>> Real.
>> Real. >> Well, Buddhism tends to define guilt as
>> Well, Buddhism tends to define guilt as
>> Well, Buddhism tends to define guilt as self-indulgence, egoistic,
self-indulgence, egoistic,
self-indulgence, egoistic, >> narcissistic.
>> narcissistic.
>> narcissistic. Oh, me me. Oh, one horrible me. How
Oh, me me. Oh, one horrible me. How
Oh, me me. Oh, one horrible me. How could me make that mistake? What's me
could me make that mistake? What's me
could me make that mistake? What's me going to do about me? It's all about me.
going to do about me? It's all about me.
going to do about me? It's all about me. >> So Buddhism tends to view guilt as a
>> So Buddhism tends to view guilt as a
>> So Buddhism tends to view guilt as a narcissistic self-indulgence, frankly.
narcissistic self-indulgence, frankly.
narcissistic self-indulgence, frankly. >> So, it's best that if we make a mistake,
>> So, it's best that if we make a mistake,
>> So, it's best that if we make a mistake, acknowledge it and move on.
acknowledge it and move on.
acknowledge it and move on. >> That's what you do. And also there there
>> That's what you do. And also there there
>> That's what you do. And also there there isn't any personal eye that did that in
isn't any personal eye that did that in
isn't any personal eye that did that in the first place. So as you become a
the first place. So as you become a
the first place. So as you become a Buddha yourself,
Buddha yourself,
Buddha yourself, >> you see it's just an illusion that there
>> you see it's just an illusion that there
>> you see it's just an illusion that there was a personal separate eye that did
was a personal separate eye that did
was a personal separate eye that did this or did that. You say that's all
this or did that. You say that's all
this or did that. You say that's all >> hyperbole. It's all exaggeration. And u
>> hyperbole. It's all exaggeration. And u
>> hyperbole. It's all exaggeration. And u well we were saying this morning happen
well we were saying this morning happen
well we were saying this morning happen things happen as a result of emergence.
things happen as a result of emergence.
things happen as a result of emergence. Mhm.
Mhm.
Mhm. >> That consciousness itself by your
>> That consciousness itself by your
>> That consciousness itself by your alignment
alignment
alignment uh there's powerful attractor fields
uh there's powerful attractor fields
uh there's powerful attractor fields that dominate lesser powerful fields
that dominate lesser powerful fields
that dominate lesser powerful fields which dominate lesser powerful fields.
which dominate lesser powerful fields.
which dominate lesser powerful fields. So something may escape all of them you
So something may escape all of them you
So something may escape all of them you see and still and still uh erupt.
see and still and still uh erupt.
see and still and still uh erupt. Don't forget we have a left brain and a
Don't forget we have a left brain and a
Don't forget we have a left brain and a right brain. So if we were meant to be
right brain. So if we were meant to be
right brain. So if we were meant to be angels in this realm, we would only have
angels in this realm, we would only have
angels in this realm, we would only have right brain. The left brain is very much
right brain. The left brain is very much
right brain. The left brain is very much an animal. So anything I look at to
an animal. So anything I look at to
an animal. So anything I look at to forgive myself is almost always the
forgive myself is almost always the
forgive myself is almost always the animal.
animal.
animal. >> It's the animal that wants to be first
>> It's the animal that wants to be first
>> It's the animal that wants to be first in line. It's the animal that wants all
in line. It's the animal that wants all
in line. It's the animal that wants all the attention. It's the animal that
the attention. It's the animal that
the attention. It's the animal that wants the land share.
wants the land share.
wants the land share. >> Uh it's almost always the animal.
>> Uh it's almost always the animal.
>> Uh it's almost always the animal. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. The spiritual self would only make an
The spiritual self would only make an
The spiritual self would only make an error out of ignorance, let's say.
error out of ignorance, let's say.
error out of ignorance, let's say. >> And but but the human self is is that
>> And but but the human self is is that
>> And but but the human self is is that the leftbrain animal arises. The animal
the leftbrain animal arises. The animal
the leftbrain animal arises. The animal instinct, the amygdala dominates
instinct, the amygdala dominates
instinct, the amygdala dominates and then the super ego is brought in out
and then the super ego is brought in out
and then the super ego is brought in out of guilt that your animal got away with
of guilt that your animal got away with
of guilt that your animal got away with you. So then you have to get acquainted
you. So then you have to get acquainted
you. So then you have to get acquainted with your animal and acknowledge that
with your animal and acknowledge that
with your animal and acknowledge that your animal's there. And although your
your animal's there. And although your
your animal's there. And although your animal causes you a lot of problem, if
animal causes you a lot of problem, if
animal causes you a lot of problem, if it wasn't for your animal, you probably
it wasn't for your animal, you probably
it wasn't for your animal, you probably wouldn't be alive.
So we could acknowledge the animal in us
So we could acknowledge the animal in us instead of denying it and say, "Of
instead of denying it and say, "Of
instead of denying it and say, "Of course you want to be first. Of course
course you want to be first. Of course
course you want to be first. Of course you want to be the alpha male, the alpha
you want to be the alpha male, the alpha
you want to be the alpha male, the alpha female, the richest one, the leader of
female, the richest one, the leader of
female, the richest one, the leader of the pack, the dominant one."
the pack, the dominant one."
the pack, the dominant one." Uhhuh.
Uhhuh.
Uhhuh. >> So one way to get rid of a thing is to
>> So one way to get rid of a thing is to
>> So one way to get rid of a thing is to acknowledge it. not get rid of it, but
acknowledge it. not get rid of it, but
acknowledge it. not get rid of it, but subdue it is to acknowledge the animal
subdue it is to acknowledge the animal
subdue it is to acknowledge the animal and say, "Okay, you could even give your
and say, "Okay, you could even give your
and say, "Okay, you could even give your animal a name."
animal a name."
animal a name." Perky.
Perky.
Perky. Okay, Perky, I hear you. Of course you
Okay, Perky, I hear you. Of course you
Okay, Perky, I hear you. Of course you want to be the winner. Of course you
want to be the winner. Of course you
want to be the winner. Of course you want to be of course you want to win the
want to be of course you want to win the
want to be of course you want to win the beauty contest. Of course you want to be
beauty contest. Of course you want to be
beauty contest. Of course you want to be rich and famous and be in Hollywood.
>> That dominates the thinking of millions
>> That dominates the thinking of millions and millions of people, doesn't it?
and millions of people, doesn't it?
and millions of people, doesn't it? You watch television, it's just the same
You watch television, it's just the same
You watch television, it's just the same theme over and over and over again.
theme over and over and over again.
theme over and over and over again. Seduction, money, dominance, territory.
Seduction, money, dominance, territory.
Seduction, money, dominance, territory. >> And being on camera. Oh, on camera. Be
>> And being on camera. Oh, on camera. Be
>> And being on camera. Oh, on camera. Be on camera. People do anything to be on
on camera. People do anything to be on
on camera. People do anything to be on camera.
So that's the me me of the narcissistic
So that's the me me of the narcissistic ego. So, I think you got to realize
ego. So, I think you got to realize
ego. So, I think you got to realize there's an animal in you and get
there's an animal in you and get
there's an animal in you and get acquainted with this animal.
acquainted with this animal.
acquainted with this animal. >> Instead of turning it into an enemy,
>> Instead of turning it into an enemy,
>> Instead of turning it into an enemy, turn it into a pet. Oh yes, with
turn it into a pet. Oh yes, with
turn it into a pet. Oh yes, with Snookie, I hear you. I know you want to
Snookie, I hear you. I know you want to
Snookie, I hear you. I know you want to be on the center stage. Oh, Snookie, I
be on the center stage. Oh, Snookie, I
be on the center stage. Oh, Snookie, I know you want to win that free trip to
know you want to win that free trip to
know you want to win that free trip to Florida, bathe on the beach
Florida, bathe on the beach
Florida, bathe on the beach with the cameras going, of course.
So, I think there there's a good
So, I think there there's a good technique
technique
technique is uh first of all recognize the animal.
is uh first of all recognize the animal.
is uh first of all recognize the animal. >> There's all the animal instincts
>> There's all the animal instincts
>> There's all the animal instincts and then give your animal a name.
and then give your animal a name.
and then give your animal a name. Pick out a good name for your animal.
Pick out a good name for your animal.
Pick out a good name for your animal. And then a lot of times the reason that
And then a lot of times the reason that
And then a lot of times the reason that it rises up, it wants to be
it rises up, it wants to be
it rises up, it wants to be acknowledged. It doesn't want to be
acknowledged. It doesn't want to be
acknowledged. It doesn't want to be ignored.
ignored.
ignored. >> It would rather be bad and get and get
>> It would rather be bad and get and get
>> It would rather be bad and get and get attention than be ignored. And you'll
attention than be ignored. And you'll
attention than be ignored. And you'll see this with babies and very young
see this with babies and very young
see this with babies and very young children. They'd rather cry and crab and
children. They'd rather cry and crab and
children. They'd rather cry and crab and create a fuss rather than be ignored.
create a fuss rather than be ignored.
create a fuss rather than be ignored. So you would just say, "I hear you. I
So you would just say, "I hear you. I
So you would just say, "I hear you. I hear you, Snookie.
>> Somebody's stealing our microphone. Call
>> Somebody's stealing our microphone. Call the police.
the police.
the police. >> I guess this is this is Yeah.
>> I guess this is this is Yeah.
>> I guess this is this is Yeah. >> Oh, now it's different.
>> Oh, now it's different.
>> Oh, now it's different. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Oh, wow.
>> Oh, wow.
>> Oh, wow. >> Can you hear me better?
>> Can you hear me better?
>> Can you hear me better? >> Oh, much better.
>> Oh, much better.
>> Oh, much better. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So I think what do you think about
So I think what do you think about
So I think what do you think about calling your animal an animal and
calling your animal an animal and
calling your animal an animal and acknowledging its presence and realizing
acknowledging its presence and realizing
acknowledging its presence and realizing without it you probably wouldn't be
without it you probably wouldn't be
without it you probably wouldn't be alive to complain about it. So we
alive to complain about it. So we
alive to complain about it. So we acknowledge the animal in us. I mean you
acknowledge the animal in us. I mean you
acknowledge the animal in us. I mean you wouldn't bother eating.
wouldn't bother eating.
wouldn't bother eating. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> I mean I wouldn't bother eating.
>> I mean I wouldn't bother eating.
>> I mean I wouldn't bother eating. >> You know
>> You know
>> You know got to stop everything that eat sort of
got to stop everything that eat sort of
got to stop everything that eat sort of a nuisance. know
a nuisance. know
a nuisance. know same with sleeping any physiologic body
same with sleeping any physiologic body
same with sleeping any physiologic body animal function you know I I used to
animal function you know I I used to
animal function you know I I used to always have a resentment about it you
always have a resentment about it you
always have a resentment about it you got to stop meditating after a certain
got to stop meditating after a certain
got to stop meditating after a certain number of hours because you're falling
number of hours because you're falling
number of hours because you're falling over
over
over and you haven't eaten in three or four
and you haven't eaten in three or four
and you haven't eaten in three or four days
days
days >> oh yeah you got to do that
>> oh yeah you got to do that
>> oh yeah you got to do that >> yeah so
>> yeah so
>> yeah so you can follow the path of Hindu
you can follow the path of Hindu
you can follow the path of Hindu aseticism
aseticism
aseticism in the United States they probably get
in the United States they probably get
in the United States they probably get you put in a hospital, but uh
you put in a hospital, but uh
you put in a hospital, but uh you look like Raman Mahari. They're
you look like Raman Mahari. They're
you look like Raman Mahari. They're going to hospitalize you frankly sort of
going to hospitalize you frankly sort of
going to hospitalize you frankly sort of kctic like
kctic like
kctic like two weeks from starving to death. But
two weeks from starving to death. But
two weeks from starving to death. But that's a Hindu tradition and therefore
that's a Hindu tradition and therefore
that's a Hindu tradition and therefore you know you can you do that there
you know you can you do that there
you know you can you do that there >> uh and and get and get away with it.
>> uh and and get and get away with it.
>> uh and and get and get away with it. here you would probably get away with it
here you would probably get away with it
here you would probably get away with it into aeticism
into aeticism
into aeticism is an attempt to subdue this animal you
is an attempt to subdue this animal you
is an attempt to subdue this animal you see
see
see but I don't think you can really succeed
but I don't think you can really succeed
but I don't think you can really succeed because whether you like it or not you
because whether you like it or not you
because whether you like it or not you have to breathe
have to breathe
have to breathe and unless you can stop breathing you
and unless you can stop breathing you
and unless you can stop breathing you can't really subdue the animal
can't really subdue the animal
can't really subdue the animal >> the animal insists that you breathe
>> the animal insists that you breathe
>> the animal insists that you breathe so the downside of human life is you
so the downside of human life is you
so the downside of human life is you inherit at the animal, the protoplasmic
inherit at the animal, the protoplasmic
inherit at the animal, the protoplasmic animal
animal
animal which has legitimate needs as well.
which has legitimate needs as well.
which has legitimate needs as well. >> And you have to say it, do I serve God
>> And you have to say it, do I serve God
>> And you have to say it, do I serve God best by starving to death and falling
best by starving to death and falling
best by starving to death and falling off the planet, or do I serve God best
off the planet, or do I serve God best
off the planet, or do I serve God best by staying here and serving my fellow
by staying here and serving my fellow
by staying here and serving my fellow man?
man?
man? To just topple over and leave seems a
To just topple over and leave seems a
To just topple over and leave seems a little narcissistic,
doesn't it? Right. Well, I always
doesn't it? Right. Well, I always thought that um you know us teaching
thought that um you know us teaching
thought that um you know us teaching like we're doing um I always thought
like we're doing um I always thought
like we're doing um I always thought that oh someday we'll get this thing
that oh someday we'll get this thing
that oh someday we'll get this thing where okay that's enough you don't have
where okay that's enough you don't have
where okay that's enough you don't have to do this anymore but that's never come
to do this anymore but that's never come
to do this anymore but that's never come >> do what anymore
>> do what anymore
>> do what anymore >> teach you know I always thought oh
>> teach you know I always thought oh
>> teach you know I always thought oh someday you know when it'll just say oh
someday you know when it'll just say oh
someday you know when it'll just say oh okay we we've done what we should and
okay we we've done what we should and
okay we we've done what we should and that would be it but it doesn't it's
that would be it but it doesn't it's
that would be it but it doesn't it's like it this isn't it it isn't ending
like it this isn't it it isn't ending
like it this isn't it it isn't ending >> well it's like everything you do is
>> well it's like everything you do is
>> well it's like everything you do is teaching The way you are, the way you
teaching The way you are, the way you
teaching The way you are, the way you hold your being
hold your being
hold your being >> is is uh teaching by example all the
>> is is uh teaching by example all the
>> is is uh teaching by example all the time to to uh
time to to uh
time to to uh >> to be cruel or to be kind, to be loving,
>> to be cruel or to be kind, to be loving,
>> to be cruel or to be kind, to be loving, to be considerate, to be thoughtful of
to be considerate, to be thoughtful of
to be considerate, to be thoughtful of others, to take joy in one's existence.
others, to take joy in one's existence.
others, to take joy in one's existence. Yeah. So, everyone teach teaches by
Yeah. So, everyone teach teaches by
Yeah. So, everyone teach teaches by example all the time.
example all the time.
example all the time. >> This is the way to be. That's the way to
>> This is the way to be. That's the way to
>> This is the way to be. That's the way to be. Mhm.
be. Mhm.
be. Mhm. >> There's a good program. Remember that
>> There's a good program. Remember that
>> There's a good program. Remember that one about the dog whisperer?
one about the dog whisperer?
one about the dog whisperer? >> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. >> Yeah. The dog whisperer. And he does a
>> Yeah. The dog whisperer. And he does a
>> Yeah. The dog whisperer. And he does a lot of that, showing the dog who he is
lot of that, showing the dog who he is
lot of that, showing the dog who he is and therefore who they are and therefore
and therefore who they are and therefore
and therefore who they are and therefore how to be. So he's teaching the dog how
how to be. So he's teaching the dog how
how to be. So he's teaching the dog how to be how to be with the owner. Yeah.
to be how to be with the owner. Yeah.
to be how to be with the owner. Yeah. And he also teaches the owner how to be
And he also teaches the owner how to be
And he also teaches the owner how to be with the dog.
with the dog.
with the dog. >> The dog.
>> The dog.
>> The dog. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> That I think that's like almost like
>> That I think that's like almost like
>> That I think that's like almost like role playing. So he shows the owner how
role playing. So he shows the owner how
role playing. So he shows the owner how you have to be for the dog to respect
you have to be for the dog to respect
you have to be for the dog to respect you,
you,
you, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> And and because you're supposed to be
>> And and because you're supposed to be
>> And and because you're supposed to be the leader, the dog looks to you to be
the leader, the dog looks to you to be
the leader, the dog looks to you to be leader.
leader.
leader. >> And if you don't lead, so you have to
>> And if you don't lead, so you have to
>> And if you don't lead, so you have to accept your role.
accept your role.
accept your role. >> So we might say just being human is
>> So we might say just being human is
>> So we might say just being human is already a responsibility, is it not?
already a responsibility, is it not?
already a responsibility, is it not? >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> You're already a teacher just by the
>> You're already a teacher just by the
>> You're already a teacher just by the fact that you're here.
fact that you're here.
fact that you're here. And whatever you do is going to
And whatever you do is going to
And whatever you do is going to influence other people by example.
So we're always always teaching whether
So we're always always teaching whether we know it or not. But just how we are.
we know it or not. But just how we are.
we know it or not. But just how we are. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Just how we are teaches. Yeah.
>> Just how we are teaches. Yeah.
>> Just how we are teaches. Yeah. >> I mean even when I go in there and go
>> I mean even when I go in there and go
>> I mean even when I go in there and go this isn't working right.
this isn't working right.
this isn't working right. I'm still teaching.
I'm still teaching.
I'm still teaching. >> That's it. That's how it is.
>> That's it. That's how it is.
>> That's it. That's how it is. >> Yeah. Because we accept the child in us
>> Yeah. Because we accept the child in us
>> Yeah. Because we accept the child in us and the adult,
and the adult,
and the adult, you know.
you know.
you know. >> Oh, good. Can I look at that as just
>> Oh, good. Can I look at that as just
>> Oh, good. Can I look at that as just throwing a temper tantrum and get by
throwing a temper tantrum and get by
throwing a temper tantrum and get by with
with
with >> Well, a lot of times that's that's
>> Well, a lot of times that's that's
>> Well, a lot of times that's that's right. Sometimes we do that with each
right. Sometimes we do that with each
right. Sometimes we do that with each other. I think it's just her
other. I think it's just her
other. I think it's just her sevenyear-old.
sevenyear-old.
sevenyear-old. >> You have a very active seven-year-old
>> You have a very active seven-year-old
>> You have a very active seven-year-old and that's just her.
>> I'm going to get you for that one. You
>> I'm going to get you for that one. You know,
know,
know, >> I didn't say your seven-year-old wasn't
>> I didn't say your seven-year-old wasn't
>> I didn't say your seven-year-old wasn't charming.
charming.
charming. I just said your seven-year-old
I just said your seven-year-old
I just said your seven-year-old sometimes dominates the field, you know.
Okay.
Okay. >> Well, you're then then your adult your
>> Well, you're then then your adult your
>> Well, you're then then your adult your adult complains about the child and you.
adult complains about the child and you.
adult complains about the child and you. So, I try to side with
So, I try to side with
So, I try to side with >> Well, that's true.
>> Well, that's true.
>> Well, that's true. >> Yes, that's right. Say, "How come I ate
>> Yes, that's right. Say, "How come I ate
>> Yes, that's right. Say, "How come I ate that piece of candy?" You know,
that piece of candy?" You know,
that piece of candy?" You know, >> stop feeling guilty about it. It's just
>> stop feeling guilty about it. It's just
>> stop feeling guilty about it. It's just your seven-year-old, you know.
your seven-year-old, you know.
your seven-year-old, you know. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah.
Just everyone gets a piece of candy, you
Just everyone gets a piece of candy, you know.
know.
know. >> Yeah. That's true. That's true. You feel
>> Yeah. That's true. That's true. You feel
>> Yeah. That's true. That's true. You feel guilty over little things, you know.
guilty over little things, you know.
guilty over little things, you know. Like sometimes I don't don't always have
Like sometimes I don't don't always have
Like sometimes I don't don't always have time to make your espresso. We have four
time to make your espresso. We have four
time to make your espresso. We have four pots of espresso
pots of espresso
pots of espresso and he drinks it all the time. So
and he drinks it all the time. So
and he drinks it all the time. So sometimes it runs out and I'm and I'm
sometimes it runs out and I'm and I'm
sometimes it runs out and I'm and I'm busy doing something else and I don't
busy doing something else and I don't
busy doing something else and I don't see that it's run out. So and then I
see that it's run out. So and then I
see that it's run out. So and then I feel guilty that I didn't get in there
feel guilty that I didn't get in there
feel guilty that I didn't get in there and make it in time. Now, you know, I
and make it in time. Now, you know, I
and make it in time. Now, you know, I know that's just a little thing, but
know that's just a little thing, but
know that's just a little thing, but it's still that's a guilty thing.
it's still that's a guilty thing.
it's still that's a guilty thing. >> Then I have to go through hardship.
>> Yeah, his hardship is Susie. I'm out of
>> Yeah, his hardship is Susie. I'm out of coffee.
coffee.
coffee. >> Sometimes it's really hardship. I have
>> Sometimes it's really hardship. I have
>> Sometimes it's really hardship. I have to make it myself.
Yeah. If you ever cut yourself, espresso
Yeah. If you ever cut yourself, espresso would come out and not blood.
Yes.
Yes. >> He didn't say no, did he?
>> He didn't say no, did he?
>> He didn't say no, did he? >> That's true.
>> That's true.
>> That's true. >> Yeah. He drinks an awful lot of it. He
>> Yeah. He drinks an awful lot of it. He
>> Yeah. He drinks an awful lot of it. He likes it.
likes it.
likes it. >> Well, you simple little espresso all
>> Well, you simple little espresso all
>> Well, you simple little espresso all day.
day.
day. >> But it is true. Sometimes it's it's like
>> But it is true. Sometimes it's it's like
>> But it is true. Sometimes it's it's like some of those things like well for
some of those things like well for
some of those things like well for instance me being guilty of not being
instance me being guilty of not being
instance me being guilty of not being able to make your pot of espresso. It's
able to make your pot of espresso. It's
able to make your pot of espresso. It's because I have other pressing things.
because I have other pressing things.
because I have other pressing things. See it isn't that I'm being neglective
See it isn't that I'm being neglective
See it isn't that I'm being neglective of your needs or neglective of you. It's
of your needs or neglective of you. It's
of your needs or neglective of you. It's just
just
just >> I don't feel like I'm pressing other
>> I don't feel like I'm pressing other
>> I don't feel like I'm pressing other things are pressing on
things are pressing on
things are pressing on >> just self.
>> I don't blame it on you though.
>> I don't blame it on you though. >> Oh yeah. I don't say, "Well, she should
>> Oh yeah. I don't say, "Well, she should
>> Oh yeah. I don't say, "Well, she should have made the espresso." I don't think
have made the espresso." I don't think
have made the espresso." I don't think that.
that.
that. >> No,
>> No,
>> No, >> I think I should have made it instead of
>> I think I should have made it instead of
>> I think I should have made it instead of forcing her to do all the time.
forcing her to do all the time.
forcing her to do all the time. >> Well, good. That makes me feel better
>> Well, good. That makes me feel better
>> Well, good. That makes me feel better >> cuz I'm beating myself up because I
>> cuz I'm beating myself up because I
>> cuz I'm beating myself up because I can't get in there to do it. See, you
can't get in there to do it. See, you
can't get in there to do it. See, you know, you understand?
>> You know, we're all we're always trying
>> You know, we're all we're always trying to make the other one feel better no
to make the other one feel better no
to make the other one feel better no matter what goes on. You know what I'm
matter what goes on. You know what I'm
matter what goes on. You know what I'm saying?
saying?
saying? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> And she stubbed her toe yesterday. Don't
>> And she stubbed her toe yesterday. Don't
>> And she stubbed her toe yesterday. Don't feel guilty about stubbing it. So, you
feel guilty about stubbing it. So, you
feel guilty about stubbing it. So, you couldn't help it and you couldn't see
couldn't help it and you couldn't see
couldn't help it and you couldn't see where you were going. And
where you were going. And
where you were going. And where's that stuff you're supposed to
where's that stuff you're supposed to
where's that stuff you're supposed to get in the drugstore to put on an
get in the drugstore to put on an
get in the drugstore to put on an instant cure or something?
instant cure or something?
instant cure or something? >> Yeah. I know.
>> Yeah. I know.
>> Yeah. I know. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> So, I think uh when people love each
>> So, I think uh when people love each
>> So, I think uh when people love each other, they're they're always trying to
other, they're they're always trying to
other, they're they're always trying to make the other one feel better in some
make the other one feel better in some
make the other one feel better in some way.
way.
way. They're trying to alleviate each other's
They're trying to alleviate each other's
They're trying to alleviate each other's guilt and uh
guilt and uh
guilt and uh >> and then they feel guilty if they're
>> and then they feel guilty if they're
>> and then they feel guilty if they're unable to, you know, make the other
unable to, you know, make the other
unable to, you know, make the other person happier,
person happier,
person happier, >> right? That's true.
>> right? That's true.
>> right? That's true. >> It's not like you're obliged to. It's
>> It's not like you're obliged to. It's
>> It's not like you're obliged to. It's just that your life becomes uh you know,
just that your life becomes uh you know,
just that your life becomes uh you know, like uh
like uh
like uh >> busy.
>> busy.
>> busy. >> Yeah. Busy. And you know, you want to
>> Yeah. Busy. And you know, you want to
>> Yeah. Busy. And you know, you want to share the lovingness with the other
share the lovingness with the other
share the lovingness with the other person in all the little ways that you
person in all the little ways that you
person in all the little ways that you can say.
can say.
can say. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> So, it's nothing to feel guilty about. I
>> So, it's nothing to feel guilty about. I
>> So, it's nothing to feel guilty about. I don't say it's guilty because you just
don't say it's guilty because you just
don't say it's guilty because you just can't fulfill every uh requirement of
can't fulfill every uh requirement of
can't fulfill every uh requirement of every moment. I mean the requirement of
every moment. I mean the requirement of
every moment. I mean the requirement of every moment is just sometimes so
every moment is just sometimes so
every moment is just sometimes so voluminous. The male's here, the
voluminous. The male's here, the
voluminous. The male's here, the telephone is ringing and somebody's at
telephone is ringing and somebody's at
telephone is ringing and somebody's at the door. In the meantime, the cat wants
the door. In the meantime, the cat wants
the door. In the meantime, the cat wants a refill
and somebody left the bathroom door on
and somebody left the bathroom door on top of it and the light running in the
top of it and the light running in the
top of it and the light running in the laundry room, you know, with the water
laundry room, you know, with the water
laundry room, you know, with the water running.
running.
running. >> Yeah. So it's you rush about trying to
>> Yeah. So it's you rush about trying to
>> Yeah. So it's you rush about trying to decide you know what can you do uh
decide you know what can you do uh
decide you know what can you do uh that's most profitable you know
that's most profitable you know
that's most profitable you know but I think the joy of relationship is
but I think the joy of relationship is
but I think the joy of relationship is contributing to the other person's
contributing to the other person's
contributing to the other person's happiness that that is really
happiness that that is really
happiness that that is really >> one of the greatest joys of it you see
and alleviating alleviating guilt is is
and alleviating alleviating guilt is is one of them.
one of them.
one of them. >> Okay. So when you don't have clean socks
>> Okay. So when you don't have clean socks
>> Okay. So when you don't have clean socks you're not going to yell at me? No, I
you're not going to yell at me? No, I
you're not going to yell at me? No, I just wear dirty socks or no socks.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Then you'll feel guilty if I walk around
>> Then you'll feel guilty if I walk around
>> Then you'll feel guilty if I walk around no socks.
no socks.
no socks. >> So, I have to put dirty socks on.
>> So, I have to put dirty socks on.
>> So, I have to put dirty socks on. Otherwise, you would feel guilty that I
Otherwise, you would feel guilty that I
Otherwise, you would feel guilty that I don't have any socks. You understand?
don't have any socks. You understand?
don't have any socks. You understand? >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> I do. I understand.
>> I do. I understand.
>> I do. I understand. That's true. I mean, I understand both
That's true. I mean, I understand both
That's true. I mean, I understand both sides. Yeah,
sides. Yeah,
sides. Yeah, it is that way.
There's some saying that says guilt is
There's some saying that says guilt is good. Guilt is good. You need more of
good. Guilt is good. You need more of
good. Guilt is good. You need more of it. More of it. Then it makes you
it. More of it. Then it makes you
it. More of it. Then it makes you realize how stupid it is.
realize how stupid it is.
realize how stupid it is. >> Guilt is good. Wallowing it. Oh, more
>> Guilt is good. Wallowing it. Oh, more
>> Guilt is good. Wallowing it. Oh, more more guilt. More.
more guilt. More.
more guilt. More. >> So that's why you say when you feel
>> So that's why you say when you feel
>> So that's why you say when you feel guilty then go with it.
guilty then go with it.
guilty then go with it. >> Go with it and just wallow in it and
>> Go with it and just wallow in it and
>> Go with it and just wallow in it and say, "Oh, I'm horrible for not doing
say, "Oh, I'm horrible for not doing
say, "Oh, I'm horrible for not doing that."
that."
that." >> Right.
>> Right.
>> Right. >> Yeah. Because you see the re, you know,
>> Yeah. Because you see the re, you know,
>> Yeah. Because you see the re, you know, the ridiculousness of it via hyperbole,
the ridiculousness of it via hyperbole,
the ridiculousness of it via hyperbole, you know.
you know.
you know. >> Yeah. Because then I'd be laughing and
>> Yeah. Because then I'd be laughing and
>> Yeah. Because then I'd be laughing and on the floor laughing about it because
on the floor laughing about it because
on the floor laughing about it because that would send me into a fit of how
that would send me into a fit of how
that would send me into a fit of how stupid it was.
stupid it was.
stupid it was. >> It would I mean when you really go that
>> It would I mean when you really go that
>> It would I mean when you really go that far down, you know.
far down, you know.
far down, you know. >> Well, there's conscious guilt in which
>> Well, there's conscious guilt in which
>> Well, there's conscious guilt in which you were consciously aware of feeling
you were consciously aware of feeling
you were consciously aware of feeling guilty.
guilty.
guilty. >> And then there's unconscious guilt. So
>> And then there's unconscious guilt. So
>> And then there's unconscious guilt. So people become unwittingly self-punitive
people become unwittingly self-punitive
people become unwittingly self-punitive >> and constantly put themsel in horrible
>> and constantly put themsel in horrible
>> and constantly put themsel in horrible situations.
situations.
situations. out of unconscious guilt. Okay? So, in
out of unconscious guilt. Okay? So, in
out of unconscious guilt. Okay? So, in therapy, you try to bring this up.
therapy, you try to bring this up.
therapy, you try to bring this up. >> You don't have to get yourself arrested
>> You don't have to get yourself arrested
>> You don't have to get yourself arrested for a DWI all the time
for a DWI all the time
for a DWI all the time >> or or whatever, you know, as a
>> or or whatever, you know, as a
>> or or whatever, you know, as a self-punitive measure.
self-punitive measure.
self-punitive measure. So, you give people permission to feel
So, you give people permission to feel
So, you give people permission to feel guilty. Please feel guilty. Feel free to
guilty. Please feel guilty. Feel free to
guilty. Please feel guilty. Feel free to feel guilty. So, you don't have to go
feel guilty. So, you don't have to go
feel guilty. So, you don't have to go through about surreptitious ways
through about surreptitious ways
through about surreptitious ways >> to maneuver the world into being
>> to maneuver the world into being
>> to maneuver the world into being punitive towards you.
punitive towards you.
punitive towards you. >> Okay? I mean, look at these kids in in
>> Okay? I mean, look at these kids in in
>> Okay? I mean, look at these kids in in in Hollywood. They're constantly jumping
in Hollywood. They're constantly jumping
in Hollywood. They're constantly jumping their car right with the camera going.
their car right with the camera going.
their car right with the camera going. Their license has been suspended.
Their license has been suspended.
Their license has been suspended. They're due in the court three hours
They're due in the court three hours
They're due in the court three hours ago. And there they are in front of the
ago. And there they are in front of the
ago. And there they are in front of the cameras getting into their car and
cameras getting into their car and
cameras getting into their car and driving off, you know.
driving off, you know.
driving off, you know. >> Just asking the world to please punish
>> Just asking the world to please punish
>> Just asking the world to please punish me, please punish me, please arrest me,
me, please punish me, please arrest me,
me, please punish me, please arrest me, please do something.
please do something.
please do something. >> Yeah, that's true. They
>> Yeah, that's true. They
>> Yeah, that's true. They >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So in other words then you know someone
So in other words then you know someone
So in other words then you know someone like well
like well
like well who we're thinking of um would be it's
who we're thinking of um would be it's
who we're thinking of um would be it's almost a cry for help then when they get
almost a cry for help then when they get
almost a cry for help then when they get to that point
to that point
to that point >> that that's what we call it
>> that that's what we call it
>> that that's what we call it psychologically it's a cry for help that
psychologically it's a cry for help that
psychologically it's a cry for help that they're so vanquished by guilt and
they're so vanquished by guilt and
they're so vanquished by guilt and helplessness and that they're in they're
helplessness and that they're in they're
helplessness and that they're in they're swamped or they're in an overwhelm.
swamped or they're in an overwhelm.
swamped or they're in an overwhelm. >> Okay?
>> Okay?
>> Okay? >> You know in psychology they call it an
>> You know in psychology they call it an
>> You know in psychology they call it an overwhelm. There's just too many stimuli
overwhelm. There's just too many stimuli
overwhelm. There's just too many stimuli to be able to handle.
to be able to handle.
to be able to handle. >> There's kind of a jiggling here. I'm
>> There's kind of a jiggling here. I'm
>> There's kind of a jiggling here. I'm sorry. I'm trying to figure out what it
sorry. I'm trying to figure out what it
sorry. I'm trying to figure out what it is. Um the So, in other words, that is
is. Um the So, in other words, that is
is. Um the So, in other words, that is But that is like a cry for help when
But that is like a cry for help when
But that is like a cry for help when they get that farther.
>> That's sometimes just sort of a a
>> That's sometimes just sort of a a beatotific saying. It's only a cry for
beatotific saying. It's only a cry for
beatotific saying. It's only a cry for help.
help.
help. >> No, they're just rotten because they're
>> No, they're just rotten because they're
>> No, they're just rotten because they're rotten.
They got get off on being rotten as
They got get off on being rotten as possible. You know what I'm saying?
possible. You know what I'm saying?
possible. You know what I'm saying? You don't have to go to that extremes to
You don't have to go to that extremes to
You don't have to go to that extremes to get a cry for help. All you have to do
get a cry for help. All you have to do
get a cry for help. All you have to do is say, "Uh, I think I'll go see my
is say, "Uh, I think I'll go see my
is say, "Uh, I think I'll go see my therapist tomorrow."
therapist tomorrow."
therapist tomorrow." You know?
You know?
You know? >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> You don't have to commit a crime so you
>> You don't have to commit a crime so you
>> You don't have to commit a crime so you be arrested so that you know sometimes I
be arrested so that you know sometimes I
be arrested so that you know sometimes I think those are subtrifuses that people
think those are subtrifuses that people
think those are subtrifuses that people will lent and project onto the person,
will lent and project onto the person,
will lent and project onto the person, you know.
you know.
you know. >> Okay. So what I'm getting from all this
>> Okay. So what I'm getting from all this
>> Okay. So what I'm getting from all this is
is
is >> guilt is good if it changes behavior.
>> guilt is good if it changes behavior.
>> guilt is good if it changes behavior. >> Yeah. In a positive way. In a positive
>> Yeah. In a positive way. In a positive
>> Yeah. In a positive way. In a positive way more conscious, more aware,
way more conscious, more aware,
way more conscious, more aware, >> more responsible, but for its own sake,
>> more responsible, but for its own sake,
>> more responsible, but for its own sake, it's a dead end,
it's a dead end,
it's a dead end, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> For its own sake. So when guilt is is
>> For its own sake. So when guilt is is
>> For its own sake. So when guilt is is not good is when you continually do the
not good is when you continually do the
not good is when you continually do the same uh actions yet you do not have a
same uh actions yet you do not have a
same uh actions yet you do not have a better response.
better response.
better response. You don't have an have a uh positive
You don't have an have a uh positive
You don't have an have a uh positive response from those actions.
response from those actions.
response from those actions. >> The 12step groups teaches that uh
>> The 12step groups teaches that uh
>> The 12step groups teaches that uh instead of guilt uh what's called for is
instead of guilt uh what's called for is
instead of guilt uh what's called for is a decent regret. Bill W said, you know,
a decent regret. Bill W said, you know,
a decent regret. Bill W said, you know, okay,
okay,
okay, >> don't wallow in guilt, but decent regret
>> don't wallow in guilt, but decent regret
>> don't wallow in guilt, but decent regret is all that's required.
is all that's required.
is all that's required. >> Okay,
>> Okay,
>> Okay, >> so he wasn't using the term narcissism,
>> so he wasn't using the term narcissism,
>> so he wasn't using the term narcissism, but that's what he was really hitting
but that's what he was really hitting
but that's what he was really hitting on.
on.
on. >> Instead of wallowing in, oh, poor me,
>> Instead of wallowing in, oh, poor me,
>> Instead of wallowing in, oh, poor me, oh, how guilty I am.
oh, how guilty I am.
oh, how guilty I am. >> Uh, a decent regret. A decent regret.
>> Uh, a decent regret. A decent regret.
>> Uh, a decent regret. A decent regret. I'm sorry. I'm sorry I did that. I won't
I'm sorry. I'm sorry I did that. I won't
I'm sorry. I'm sorry I did that. I won't do it that way again.
do it that way again.
do it that way again. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> And so you learn it turned into a
>> And so you learn it turned into a
>> And so you learn it turned into a learning tool. Learning tool,
learning tool. Learning tool,
learning tool. Learning tool, >> right? Right. to learn to use the
>> right? Right. to learn to use the
>> right? Right. to learn to use the mistakes as a way of learning a better
mistakes as a way of learning a better
mistakes as a way of learning a better way of handling things.
way of handling things.
way of handling things. >> So guilt is good if it's a learning tool
>> So guilt is good if it's a learning tool
>> So guilt is good if it's a learning tool and it changes a behavior
and it changes a behavior
and it changes a behavior >> if it's converted to a learning tool.
>> if it's converted to a learning tool.
>> if it's converted to a learning tool. Yeah. But in and of itself, it's just a
Yeah. But in and of itself, it's just a
Yeah. But in and of itself, it's just a narcissistic wallowing, you know.
narcissistic wallowing, you know.
narcissistic wallowing, you know. >> But when when guilt is bad is when you
>> But when when guilt is bad is when you
>> But when when guilt is bad is when you wallow in it and carry it with you for
wallow in it and carry it with you for
wallow in it and carry it with you for and year after year after year without
and year after year after year without
and year after year after year without any kind of change or
any kind of change or
any kind of change or >> That's right.
>> That's right.
>> That's right. >> or um resentment on
>> or um resentment on
>> or um resentment on >> or
>> or
>> or >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. on doing that then
on doing that then
on doing that then >> you know so you you take positive action
>> you know so you you take positive action
>> you know so you you take positive action >> right
>> right
>> right >> yeah so a decent regret I think is a
>> yeah so a decent regret I think is a
>> yeah so a decent regret I think is a very good very good uh
very good very good uh
very good very good uh >> compromise
>> compromise
>> compromise >> okay
>> okay
>> okay >> you do regret it so and it's it is out
>> you do regret it so and it's it is out
>> you do regret it so and it's it is out of decency that you have the regret if
of decency that you have the regret if
of decency that you have the regret if you didn't have decency you wouldn't
you didn't have decency you wouldn't
you didn't have decency you wouldn't regret it
regret it
regret it >> exactly
>> exactly
>> exactly >> the mafia doesn't feel guilty that they
>> the mafia doesn't feel guilty that they
>> the mafia doesn't feel guilty that they shoot you
shoot you
shoot you >> they g gain status
So,
So, >> well, what about shame? I mean, shame is
>> well, what about shame? I mean, shame is
>> well, what about shame? I mean, shame is another, you know, it's another guilt
another, you know, it's another guilt
another, you know, it's another guilt tool, you know, that people use.
tool, you know, that people use.
tool, you know, that people use. >> Yeah. Well, we said that that's a
>> Yeah. Well, we said that that's a
>> Yeah. Well, we said that that's a socialization, the cultural
socialization, the cultural
socialization, the cultural >> and that can be, you know, aimed at
>> and that can be, you know, aimed at
>> and that can be, you know, aimed at other people or whatever, you know, it's
other people or whatever, you know, it's
other people or whatever, you know, it's usually shame is usually aimed at other
usually shame is usually aimed at other
usually shame is usually aimed at other people.
people.
people. >> Yeah, it's used
>> Yeah, it's used
>> Yeah, it's used >> by one person aimed at someone else. We
>> by one person aimed at someone else. We
>> by one person aimed at someone else. We shame. Well, that's because of the the
shame. Well, that's because of the the
shame. Well, that's because of the the parental use of that. Shame on you, so
parental use of that. Shame on you, so
parental use of that. Shame on you, so and so for spilling your milk.
and so for spilling your milk.
and so for spilling your milk. >> Oh, well,
>> Oh, well,
>> Oh, well, >> yep.
>> yep.
>> yep. >> I'm thinking of other things other than
>> I'm thinking of other things other than
>> I'm thinking of other things other than parent ch child.
parent ch child.
parent ch child. >> No, I'm just thinking of it origin in
>> No, I'm just thinking of it origin in
>> No, I'm just thinking of it origin in the child.
the child.
the child. >> Yes, the origin is that. But I mean, I'm
>> Yes, the origin is that. But I mean, I'm
>> Yes, the origin is that. But I mean, I'm thinking, you know, children are cruel
thinking, you know, children are cruel
thinking, you know, children are cruel to each other. They can be very nasty.
to each other. They can be very nasty.
to each other. They can be very nasty. >> They can be really savage.
>> They can be really savage.
>> They can be really savage. >> Very savage. And on top of it, I what I
>> Very savage. And on top of it, I what I
>> Very savage. And on top of it, I what I really feel sorry for is when you're
really feel sorry for is when you're
really feel sorry for is when you're young, your uh whole
young, your uh whole
young, your uh whole being is being, you know, formed. you
being is being, you know, formed. you
being is being, you know, formed. you know, your whole perception of life and
know, your whole perception of life and
know, your whole perception of life and who you want to be and everything and
who you want to be and everything and
who you want to be and everything and other. It's so sad to see how much um
other. It's so sad to see how much um
other. It's so sad to see how much um your peer pressure can change that just
your peer pressure can change that just
your peer pressure can change that just by a few nasty, shameful things, you
by a few nasty, shameful things, you
by a few nasty, shameful things, you know, that can be aimed at.
know, that can be aimed at.
know, that can be aimed at. >> Yeah. It can be really cruel.
>> Yeah. It can be really cruel.
>> Yeah. It can be really cruel. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> So, I I mean, I'm not I'm not speaking
>> So, I I mean, I'm not I'm not speaking
>> So, I I mean, I'm not I'm not speaking from experience. I'm just saying that
from experience. I'm just saying that
from experience. I'm just saying that I've seen it done
I've seen it done
I've seen it done >> and um and I just don't understand how
>> and um and I just don't understand how
>> and um and I just don't understand how any child can be that mean to another
any child can be that mean to another
any child can be that mean to another child and not have the uh compassion in
child and not have the uh compassion in
child and not have the uh compassion in themselves.
>> Well, the animal in them hasn't become
>> Well, the animal in them hasn't become socialized as yet.
socialized as yet.
socialized as yet. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> Yes.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. >> So, in the animal world, the stronger
>> So, in the animal world, the stronger
>> So, in the animal world, the stronger take advantage of the weaker.
take advantage of the weaker.
take advantage of the weaker. See, they don't uh give the weaker.
See, they don't uh give the weaker.
See, they don't uh give the weaker. >> Well, is it weak?
>> Well, is it weak?
>> Well, is it weak? >> Help because it's weaker. They
>> Help because it's weaker. They
>> Help because it's weaker. They >> But is it weak or meek?
>> But is it weak or meek?
>> But is it weak or meek? >> Is it weak or meek?
>> Is it weak or meek?
>> Is it weak or meek? >> In other words, the stronger do they
>> In other words, the stronger do they
>> In other words, the stronger do they take advantage of the meeker because and
take advantage of the meeker because and
take advantage of the meeker because and and say, "Oh, they're weak." You know,
and say, "Oh, they're weak." You know,
and say, "Oh, they're weak." You know, >> yes, they often do. I think so. They
>> yes, they often do. I think so. They
>> yes, they often do. I think so. They just confuse.
just confuse.
just confuse. >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> they do.
>> So, it's not that they're weak. It's
>> So, it's not that they're weak. It's just that they aren't going to
just that they aren't going to
just that they aren't going to do what other people's animals would do.
do what other people's animals would do.
do what other people's animals would do. In other words, they're like almost a
In other words, they're like almost a
In other words, they're like almost a higher being that they can understand
higher being that they can understand
higher being that they can understand that that isn't something they want to
that that isn't something they want to
that that isn't something they want to come down to that level.
come down to that level.
come down to that level. >> Some in some children
>> Some in some children
>> Some in some children >> they can refuse it. Yes.
>> they can refuse it. Yes.
>> they can refuse it. Yes. >> They refuse it and so then they're
>> They refuse it and so then they're
>> They refuse it and so then they're mistaken for being meek because they
mistaken for being meek because they
mistaken for being meek because they they would
they would
they would >> Yeah. When you won't join the gang to
>> Yeah. When you won't join the gang to
>> Yeah. When you won't join the gang to beat up the kid in town,
beat up the kid in town,
beat up the kid in town, >> right?
>> right?
>> right? >> Yeah. when you hang back and won't won't
>> Yeah. when you hang back and won't won't
>> Yeah. when you hang back and won't won't join in the beatup.
join in the beatup.
join in the beatup. >> So, what would be the karma of that?
>> So, what would be the karma of that?
>> So, what would be the karma of that? Would it be it's well, we all know it's
Would it be it's well, we all know it's
Would it be it's well, we all know it's going to be good karma if they didn't
going to be good karma if they didn't
going to be good karma if they didn't participate in something like that. But,
participate in something like that. But,
participate in something like that. But, I mean, you know, it's very hard
I mean, you know, it's very hard
I mean, you know, it's very hard sometimes, especially for boys to live
sometimes, especially for boys to live
sometimes, especially for boys to live with that kind of situation when they
with that kind of situation when they
with that kind of situation when they say, "I I don't think that's right. I'm
say, "I I don't think that's right. I'm
say, "I I don't think that's right. I'm not going to do that."
not going to do that."
not going to do that." >> Yeah. The boy gang mentality. You're
>> Yeah. The boy gang mentality. You're
>> Yeah. The boy gang mentality. You're right. Mhm. You may end up being a loner
right. Mhm. You may end up being a loner
right. Mhm. You may end up being a loner because if you're not going to join the
because if you're not going to join the
because if you're not going to join the >> the boy gang culture that leads you to
>> the boy gang culture that leads you to
>> the boy gang culture that leads you to read books.
read books.
read books. >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> I spent a lot of years reading books.
>> I spent a lot of years reading books.
>> I spent a lot of years reading books. >> That means you read books. Is that
>> That means you read books. Is that
>> That means you read books. Is that >> Well, I I read years reading books
>> Well, I I read years reading books
>> Well, I I read years reading books rather than joining that man mentality.
rather than joining that man mentality.
rather than joining that man mentality. Mhm.
Mhm.
Mhm. >> I wasn't into squeezing
>> I wasn't into squeezing
>> I wasn't into squeezing wrestling and fighting and scratching
wrestling and fighting and scratching
wrestling and fighting and scratching people's faces and all such like
people's faces and all such like
people's faces and all such like >> it seems sort of stupid and bor, you
>> it seems sort of stupid and bor, you
>> it seems sort of stupid and bor, you know, frankly it was boring. There's no
know, frankly it was boring. There's no
know, frankly it was boring. There's no point to it. You know, I'd rather read
point to it. You know, I'd rather read
point to it. You know, I'd rather read the mark Marcus Aurelius.
the mark Marcus Aurelius.
the mark Marcus Aurelius. >> So
>> So
>> So the apherisms of Marcus Aurelius, what's
the apherisms of Marcus Aurelius, what's
the apherisms of Marcus Aurelius, what's wrong with our country is that that's
wrong with our country is that that's
wrong with our country is that that's not required reading. To become a
not required reading. To become a
not required reading. To become a president, you have to go to President
president, you have to go to President
president, you have to go to President College. It's a quick progress and you
College. It's a quick progress and you
College. It's a quick progress and you have to master the apherisms of Marcus
have to master the apherisms of Marcus
have to master the apherisms of Marcus Aurelius
Aurelius
Aurelius >> and then you can run for president.
>> and then you can run for president.
>> and then you can run for president. >> You can't really be a president and be
>> You can't really be a president and be
>> You can't really be a president and be unfamiliar with the apherisms of Marcus
unfamiliar with the apherisms of Marcus
unfamiliar with the apherisms of Marcus Aurelius.
Aurelius.
Aurelius. >> That's why we don't have any stunning
>> That's why we don't have any stunning
>> That's why we don't have any stunning presence of recent times because
presence of recent times because
presence of recent times because they're not familiar with the apherisms
they're not familiar with the apherisms
they're not familiar with the apherisms of Marcus Aurelius. What is the
of Marcus Aurelius. What is the
of Marcus Aurelius. What is the responsibility of the ruler and what is
responsibility of the ruler and what is
responsibility of the ruler and what is the uh obligation of the sovereign to
the uh obligation of the sovereign to
the uh obligation of the sovereign to the to those that are ruled? What is the
the to those that are ruled? What is the
the to those that are ruled? What is the obligation of the ruler to the ruled?
obligation of the ruler to the ruled?
obligation of the ruler to the ruled? And it brings forth all kinds of very
And it brings forth all kinds of very
And it brings forth all kinds of very positive character traits. And it's
positive character traits. And it's
positive character traits. And it's because of those character traits and
because of those character traits and
because of those character traits and you follow them that you can claim that
you follow them that you can claim that
you follow them that you can claim that you are sovereign.
you are sovereign.
you are sovereign. >> And uh we see what happens with the
>> And uh we see what happens with the
>> And uh we see what happens with the country when it does not follow those
country when it does not follow those
country when it does not follow those rules of integrity. It fails in its own
rules of integrity. It fails in its own
rules of integrity. It fails in its own sovereignty. You see the United States
sovereignty. You see the United States
sovereignty. You see the United States failing in its own sovereignty. It can't
failing in its own sovereignty. It can't
failing in its own sovereignty. It can't even protect its own border for God's
even protect its own border for God's
even protect its own border for God's sake. I mean, that's the beginning. Any
sake. I mean, that's the beginning. Any
sake. I mean, that's the beginning. Any any anybody in the neighborhood puts a
any anybody in the neighborhood puts a
any anybody in the neighborhood puts a fence around. You say, you don't just
fence around. You say, you don't just
fence around. You say, you don't just let people savage your lawn and eat up
let people savage your lawn and eat up
let people savage your lawn and eat up your
your
your >> Well, yeah. We have havalas and so they
>> Well, yeah. We have havalas and so they
>> Well, yeah. We have havalas and so they come through our yard. So, we put a
come through our yard. So, we put a
come through our yard. So, we put a fence to stop.
fence to stop.
fence to stop. >> All right. So, there's an obligation.
>> All right. So, there's an obligation.
>> All right. So, there's an obligation. So, like the apherisms of America,
So, like the apherisms of America,
So, like the apherisms of America, what is the what are the obligations of
what is the what are the obligations of
what is the what are the obligations of the ruler? What is the obligation of the
the ruler? What is the obligation of the
the ruler? What is the obligation of the rule? Everybody wants to be number one
rule? Everybody wants to be number one
rule? Everybody wants to be number one dog, you know, for the glamour of it.
dog, you know, for the glamour of it.
dog, you know, for the glamour of it. It's really just the glamour of it.
It's really just the glamour of it.
It's really just the glamour of it. There isn't anything great or wonderful
There isn't anything great or wonderful
There isn't anything great or wonderful that's going to come out of this. See?
that's going to come out of this. See?
that's going to come out of this. See? >> Either give, you know, tax rebate or
>> Either give, you know, tax rebate or
>> Either give, you know, tax rebate or don't. But that doesn't change the
don't. But that doesn't change the
don't. But that doesn't change the nature of our civilization at all. You
nature of our civilization at all. You
nature of our civilization at all. You know, has no impact whatsoever.
know, has no impact whatsoever.
know, has no impact whatsoever. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> So, what we need is rulers that have
>> So, what we need is rulers that have
>> So, what we need is rulers that have been trained to be rulers. You see?
been trained to be rulers. You see?
been trained to be rulers. You see? >> Mhm.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. >> And that's why uh the monarchs of Europe
>> And that's why uh the monarchs of Europe
>> And that's why uh the monarchs of Europe fell is because they did not take on the
fell is because they did not take on the
fell is because they did not take on the responsibility of training subsequent
responsibility of training subsequent
responsibility of training subsequent generations and how to be a a ruler.
generations and how to be a a ruler.
generations and how to be a a ruler. Unlike China where China, you know,
Unlike China where China, you know,
Unlike China where China, you know, there were benevolent rulers that ruled
there were benevolent rulers that ruled
there were benevolent rulers that ruled for hundreds of years. China had
for hundreds of years. China had
for hundreds of years. China had hundreds of years of peace by virtue of
hundreds of years of peace by virtue of
hundreds of years of peace by virtue of sovereigns who were benign and took on
sovereigns who were benign and took on
sovereigns who were benign and took on and accepted the responsibility of their
and accepted the responsibility of their
and accepted the responsibility of their role.
role.
role. See? Yep.
See? Yep.
See? Yep. >> Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. >> It takes more to be president than just
>> It takes more to be president than just
>> It takes more to be president than just get a big war chest of money. Yep. It
get a big war chest of money. Yep. It
get a big war chest of money. Yep. It takes learning how to really be a
takes learning how to really be a
takes learning how to really be a sovereign and what's your responsibility
sovereign and what's your responsibility
sovereign and what's your responsibility to the populace.
I always figure you're answerable to the
I always figure you're answerable to the people and to your own self and
people and to your own self and
people and to your own self and ultimately to God. To be given that much
ultimately to God. To be given that much
ultimately to God. To be given that much power would be scary at death door. you
power would be scary at death door. you
power would be scary at death door. you know, did I use that for the welfare of
know, did I use that for the welfare of
know, did I use that for the welfare of mankind
mankind
mankind or did I use that just for my own
or did I use that just for my own
or did I use that just for my own argisment? So, it's quite a moral
argisment? So, it's quite a moral
argisment? So, it's quite a moral responsibility.
responsibility.
responsibility. >> That's why I I brought up the that uh
>> That's why I I brought up the that uh
>> That's why I I brought up the that uh minister who calibrates so high that's
minister who calibrates so high that's
minister who calibrates so high that's counseledled 14 or 12 presidents. What's
counseledled 14 or 12 presidents. What's
counseledled 14 or 12 presidents. What's his name?
his name?
his name? >> Billy Graham.
>> Billy Graham.
>> Billy Graham. >> Billy Graham.
>> Billy Graham. >> Billy Graham. Yes. Calibrates way up
>> Billy Graham. Yes. Calibrates way up
>> Billy Graham. Yes. Calibrates way up there. Almost sly. And uh what a
there. Almost sly. And uh what a
there. Almost sly. And uh what a difficult job he had trying to guide
difficult job he had trying to guide
difficult job he had trying to guide these presidents through all these moral
these presidents through all these moral
these presidents through all these moral dilemmas, all these moral conflicts and
dilemmas, all these moral conflicts and
dilemmas, all these moral conflicts and that was a wonderful job. So where would
that was a wonderful job. So where would
that was a wonderful job. So where would our country have been Billy Graham the
our country have been Billy Graham the
our country have been Billy Graham the guy the presidents the last
guy the presidents the last
guy the presidents the last >> So would you say that that all of us
>> So would you say that that all of us
>> So would you say that that all of us should leave this place with a without
should leave this place with a without
should leave this place with a without guilt then? I mean we should not carry
guilt then? I mean we should not carry
guilt then? I mean we should not carry any more guilt with us at all.
any more guilt with us at all.
any more guilt with us at all. I would say the perfect being would have
I would say the perfect being would have
I would say the perfect being would have learned from the guilt and now that the
learned from the guilt and now that the
learned from the guilt and now that the guilt has served its purpose, you no
guilt has served its purpose, you no
guilt has served its purpose, you no longer need to hang on to it.
longer need to hang on to it.
longer need to hang on to it. You need to hang on to the guilt until
You need to hang on to the guilt until
You need to hang on to the guilt until it motivates you to change your
it motivates you to change your
it motivates you to change your behavior. Once it's done that, there
behavior. Once it's done that, there
behavior. Once it's done that, there would be no point in hanging on to the
would be no point in hanging on to the
would be no point in hanging on to the guilt. It's already
guilt. It's already
guilt. It's already >> you've already paid the price. You know,
>> you've already paid the price. You know,
>> you've already paid the price. You know, >> you paid the price and learned the
>> you paid the price and learned the
>> you paid the price and learned the lesson.
lesson.
lesson. >> There's no point to hang on to it now.
>> There's no point to hang on to it now.
>> There's no point to hang on to it now. >> Okay? So in other words, all of us can
>> Okay? So in other words, all of us can
>> Okay? So in other words, all of us can walk out of here pretty much guilt-free.
walk out of here pretty much guilt-free.
walk out of here pretty much guilt-free. >> I would think that a very, you know,
>> I would think that a very, you know,
>> I would think that a very, you know, spiritually evolved person sees that the
spiritually evolved person sees that the
spiritually evolved person sees that the purpose of this is to benefit
purpose of this is to benefit
purpose of this is to benefit uh the world and God, yourself and your
uh the world and God, yourself and your
uh the world and God, yourself and your fellow human being. And once it served
fellow human being. And once it served
fellow human being. And once it served that, well, what use would it be, you
that, well, what use would it be, you
that, well, what use would it be, you know?
Thank you for asking me all these
Thank you for asking me all these questions.
questions.
questions. >> We uh bat things back and forth like
>> We uh bat things back and forth like
>> We uh bat things back and forth like this.
this.
this. >> I know
>> I know
>> I know >> a lot at home, you know.
>> a lot at home, you know.
>> a lot at home, you know. >> Yeah, we do.
>> Yeah, we do.
>> Yeah, we do. >> What's the most moral decision in a
>> What's the most moral decision in a
>> What's the most moral decision in a certain situation? What serves the
certain situation? What serves the
certain situation? What serves the highest good and what does not? And then
highest good and what does not? And then
highest good and what does not? And then >> and then we use the arm recalibrated.
>> and then we use the arm recalibrated.
>> and then we use the arm recalibrated. You know,
You know,
You know, >> you know what does what what is this
>> you know what does what what is this
>> you know what does what what is this answer? If we follow this answer, what
answer? If we follow this answer, what
answer? If we follow this answer, what does that calibrate? And then when we
does that calibrate? And then when we
does that calibrate? And then when we get a different calibration, we'll say,
get a different calibration, we'll say,
get a different calibration, we'll say, "Oh, suddenly as you get it, you
"Oh, suddenly as you get it, you
"Oh, suddenly as you get it, you suddenly see it." You say, "Oh, I see
suddenly see it." You say, "Oh, I see
suddenly see it." You say, "Oh, I see why
why
why >> this goes around and it comes down.
>> this goes around and it comes down.
>> this goes around and it comes down. >> I see why that's 570 and this is only
>> I see why that's 570 and this is only
>> I see why that's 570 and this is only 430. Oh, I I get it. I get it."
430. Oh, I I get it. I get it."
430. Oh, I I get it. I get it." >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> So just examining a thing already
>> So just examining a thing already
>> So just examining a thing already changes the field. To look at a thing
changes the field. To look at a thing
changes the field. To look at a thing changes the field.
changes the field.
changes the field. >> And that's quantum mechanics. You see,
>> And that's quantum mechanics. You see,
>> And that's quantum mechanics. You see, to look at experiment has already
to look at experiment has already
to look at experiment has already changed the the result. So merely to
changed the the result. So merely to
changed the the result. So merely to look at the guilt has already changed
look at the guilt has already changed
look at the guilt has already changed it. You've collapsed the wave function
it. You've collapsed the wave function
it. You've collapsed the wave function of the potential into the actual. So
of the potential into the actual. So
of the potential into the actual. So merely looking at a deep character
merely looking at a deep character
merely looking at a deep character defect or looking at guilt or something.
defect or looking at guilt or something.
defect or looking at guilt or something. Uh you've already begun to change it.
Uh you've already begun to change it.
Uh you've already begun to change it. You've collapsed the wave function from
You've collapsed the wave function from
You've collapsed the wave function from what could be and it begins to emerge
what could be and it begins to emerge
what could be and it begins to emerge emerge as what could be and will be and
emerge as what could be and will be and
emerge as what could be and will be and becomes you know. So it's all the
becomes you know. So it's all the
becomes you know. So it's all the process of becoming. Mhm.
process of becoming. Mhm.
process of becoming. Mhm. >> So, we're we're we're learning beings.
>> So, we're we're we're learning beings.
>> So, we're we're we're learning beings. I'd say the biggest project we have on
I'd say the biggest project we have on
I'd say the biggest project we have on this planet is is learning.
this planet is is learning.
this planet is is learning. >> We're really here to learn. You don't
>> We're really here to learn. You don't
>> We're really here to learn. You don't have to be a human to enjoy. You can be
have to be a human to enjoy. You can be
have to be a human to enjoy. You can be a dog or anything else to enjoy. Uh but
a dog or anything else to enjoy. Uh but
a dog or anything else to enjoy. Uh but to be a human, you have to be really
to be a human, you have to be really
to be a human, you have to be really committed to the pain of learning, the
committed to the pain of learning, the
committed to the pain of learning, the patience and the pain.
patience and the pain.
patience and the pain. >> And you've karmically earned what you've
>> And you've karmically earned what you've
>> And you've karmically earned what you've learned.
learned.
learned. >> And it is painful to learn. Sometimes
>> And it is painful to learn. Sometimes
>> And it is painful to learn. Sometimes >> we've earned what we learned.
>> we've earned what we learned.
>> we've earned what we learned. >> We've earned what we learned.
>> We've earned what we learned.
>> We've earned what we learned. >> That's it.
>> That's it.
>> That's it. >> Okay.
>> We've earned what we learned.
>> We've earned what we learned. >> Rousey, that makes it okay, doesn't it?
>> Rousey, that makes it okay, doesn't it?
>> Rousey, that makes it okay, doesn't it? >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> it does.
>> it does.
>> it does. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Well, you know what? We've already
>> Well, you know what? We've already
>> Well, you know what? We've already talked an hour.
talked an hour.
talked an hour. >> Oh, no.
>> Oh, no.
>> Oh, no. >> And so, we're going to be having book
>> And so, we're going to be having book
>> And so, we're going to be having book signing next.
signing next.
signing next. >> We're going to take a 15minute break.
>> We're going to take a 15minute break.
>> We're going to take a 15minute break. Mhm.
Mhm.
Mhm. >> And uh if you have questions, if you'll
>> And uh if you have questions, if you'll
>> And uh if you have questions, if you'll line up on the left side, my left, your
line up on the left side, my left, your
line up on the left side, my left, your right.
right.
right. >> I'd just like to know if you enjoyed uh
>> I'd just like to know if you enjoyed uh
>> I'd just like to know if you enjoyed uh dialoguing or
dialoguing or
dialoguing or >> Yeah,
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, >> you did.
You know there's various pedagogical
You know there's various pedagogical techniques and various ways of sharing
techniques and various ways of sharing
techniques and various ways of sharing information and and stirring up the same
information and and stirring up the same
information and and stirring up the same process and everyone. That's what I like
process and everyone. That's what I like
process and everyone. That's what I like is when somebody teaches me how they do
is when somebody teaches me how they do
is when somebody teaches me how they do something and then I can go do it.
something and then I can go do it.
something and then I can go do it. So thank you so much for your time.