Woo! Woo! Woo! Woo!
Oh,
Glory and Excelsius deal. Glory be to
thee, oh Lord most high.
That's the way we start all the
lectures. Yeah. Glory to God in the
highest.
That's hard to beat.
Today we're talking about Oh my god.
Happiness.
Oh well, it won't do much good anyway.
Happiness probably won't work either.
I love Eeyore and Winnie the Pooh.
I love Eeyore. So when all else fails,
just become Eeyore.
No matter what happens that you think is
making you unhappy, you just go, "Oh
well, it wouldn't have been any good
anyway."
And Winnie the Pooh will get you out of
it in a hurry.
The cure of
to the cure of unhappiness is to become
Winnie the Pooh.
Today we're going to talk 101 ways to
happiness.
I hate to tell you that
because after today's lecture, you will
have no excuses.
If you're unhappy, you just refer to
item number 62.
She's on the phone. You say, "Look up
number 62."
Thank you, Gertrude. Okay, goodbye.
That's what we need is a happiness
emergency phone number. 911.
I'm unhappy today about so and so. And
then you have a a dialup that comes look
up number 62.
So, we're going to have to institute a
dialup happiness coded number.
Now,
I don't know what comes next.
Is this the screen?
Oh, now it's a screen. I see.
Well, we always start That's right. We
always start with the map of
consciousness.
Uh,
is this the end of the stage here? Where
is the end of the stage?
Is that the end of the stage?
Oh, there's the end of the stage. Oh,
there's the end of the stage. Okay.
How many people are new here today? Oh
dear. Oh dear.
Well, we're happy that you're here.
We're here because we're here because
we're here because we're here. We're
here because we're here because we're
here because we're here.
That should take care of everything.
All right, for the people that are new,
then we do a review of some of the basic
concepts of consciousness research,
which the world has not really heard
about at all.
And uh so because it's unfamiliar, we'll
do a short review of uh how many slides
do we do review? I don't know.
>> They're circled there. See? No.
All right. So, all right. So, the whole
uh science of consciousness
uh there was no science of consciousness
until the 1980s or something uh when it
uh
sort of appeared of its own. And it came
about as the result of a witnessing of
an event that uh certain things make you
make you go weak and certain things make
you go strong.
And uh
one thing that makes everybody go weak
is looking at fluorescent lights. So if
you tell somebody hold out your arm and
you press down the arm, you say, "All
right, now look at those fluorescent
lights," the arms all go weak.
So I thought, "Gee, that's that's
exciting." So I went back to the clinic.
I had a big clinic and a big staff and
uh so I gave a lecture to the staff what
I'd learned, you know, in this workshop.
And uh I said, "We need some
volunteers."
So there were a couple of young people
there. I said 'n now you folks come over
here
and I said look at that fluorescent
light and I pushed down on their arm and
their arm did not go weak
I thought why is it these people don't
go weak and everybody goes weak the
president of the United States everybody
goes weak the fluorescent light and
these people didn't well in the clinic,
we had a
uh a group that were it was run by the
course of miracles.
What do they call that? Course of
miracles group. Anyway, it was recovery
from hopeless fatal illnesses.
So, in one room of the clinic, we had a
a group that met with people with
hopeless illnesses and uh it was run by
a course of miracles
uh group. So the thing that made these
people strong in the face of such a
negative stimulus was that they're all
doing a course of miracles. I thought,
wow. So spiritually evolved people
are not susceptible to the negativity
all getting their energy field blown up
by negativity like normal people.
So then I did research on it. We and I
had some students that were just
starting the course of miracles and they
went weak looking at the fluorescent
light and then I checked them about once
a week and when they got to about after
they were about 3 months into the course
around lesson 80 to 90 they stopped
going weak in response to negative
stimuli.
So spiritual evolution, spiritual
orientation
makes you immune to the negativity that
afflicts the majority of me mankind.
People are blown out. But people who are
spiritually evolved had gone through
some enormous physiologic change.
So continuing to research on that I
found that there was a range of energy
and we ended up with the calibrated
levels of consciousness from one to a
thousand one to a thousand and it's now
pretty worldwide well known uh the field
of map of consciousness
from one to a thousand that was
arbitrary.
So I said uh it was it became obvious
that it was a relative energy field and
so we calibrated it from 1 to a th00and
and we came up with this well-known
chart now in which the view of God the
view of yourself
uh the way you relate to the world uh
the emotion and the process going on in
consciousness is calibrated from one to
a thousand.
All right.
People say now people are going to say,
well, what level is happiness? Because
you can see here that uh you can go all
the way from
uh loving down through merciful,
inspiring
all the way down to these are the
negative fields below here. Indifferent,
vengeful, punitive, and vindictive.
And uh what level is happiness?
Well, the magical thing about happiness
is that it can be you can be happy at
any of these levels.
You don't have to be goody two shoes.
There are lots of people that are happy
hating people.
Hate makes them happy.
The politicians know that
they gather all thousands of people
based on hate. We all hate that guy.
Yeah, we hate him. And the other side of
the room, they're all hating this
person. Okay. Unified by hate. Oh,
wonderful.
Because ma hate makes them happy. So
that is on one hand man's salvation. On
the other hand, it's man's downfall.
is man's downfall that hate can make you
as happy as benevolence can. Huh?
All right. So here we have the map of
consciousness then in which we have
calibrated the relative energies.
However, there is a difference. They may
be happy but the energy is quite
different. Here you see that
people at the top have enormous energy
and people at the bottom have less en
less and less energy. All right. So
let's switch to the next uh scale of
consciousness. The next uh
all right so this is the world's
population.
Uh the world's population
uh the consciousness level of truth is
200.
Below 200 is falsehood and above 200 is
truth.
So if you calibrate
all of mankind, this is the curve that
you get. And it explains the you know
what you see on television every day.
85% of the world's population calibrates
below level 200. 200 is a level of truth
and integrity.
200 is a level of truth and integrity.
85% of the world's population
will be happy to sell you out.
85% of the world's population is below
200, which explains history and explains
the daily news.
And 85% of the world then is devoted to
non-integrity. You can buy them. You can
buy them for money. You see him every
day on television.
All the politicians, they're all bought
out by money, contributions.
He contribute to their prior contributes
to his re-election committee.
And so people will sell out for money,
which is not exactly news.
All right, let's move to the next. Huh?
We say to yourself, if mankind is at
such a relatively low level of
consciousness,
then how does society survive?
It's because the fif the 15% of people.
So here's how the world this is the mass
of mankind. Only 15% this little pyramid
here is above the level of 200.
This is the great mass of people
uh who are comfortable with
non-integrity and taking advantage of
others etc. live more like animals.
Okay, next one. We say how does the
world survive if the majority of the
people here's the majority of the people
of the mass of mankind.
Yeah, we saw the mass of mankind in a
prizewinning movie recently. Well, you
sell your children and stuff like that.
All right. 85% of mankind is there. So,
how does mankind survive? It's because
this 15% above 200 is so powerful.
The 200 the 15% counterbalances the 85%
otherwise man would self-destruct. Okay.
Next.
This is the animal kingdom.
Consciousness evolved uh
as life evolved on this planet. And if
you calibrate the levels of the various
life forms over time, you see the
bacteria are number one one they
calibrated as one. Then you see fish are
20. You see komodo dragon is 40.
Reptiles are 40. See a snake's 45,
dinosaur 60, a whale's 85, a dolphin's
95,
migrating birds calibrated 100,
and up there we have the dove 145. A
polar bear calibrates 160. You better
look out.
160. He's not only tough, he's smart.
All right. So as you go higher and
higher, you see the even the
hippopotamus is 190.
So you're still below 200. So these all
live by the death of others. All these
animals
survive by by killing you.
And then when you get up to the higher
levels of consciousness, 200 and over,
such as the giraffe,
uh you hit the these are the herbivores.
So below 200 you live by the death of
others. You have to kill in order to
survive.
From 200 and up you come become benign.
The giraffe, the deer,
the domestic pig, the elk, the dairy
cow. These are all peaceful herbivores.
So you go up through the animal kingdom
and you come up to the family cat.
You come up to dogs, 245,
the family dog, 250.
And then you come up to the gorilla. You
see how smart a gorilla is.
And so we get up to the higher and
higher levels occasionally. Here's
Oscar, the cat calibrates at 250. Isn't
that the cat that knows when somebody's
going to die and goes and cuddles with
them? Yeah. In a nursing home or
something. When this cat curls up next
to you at night, you know you're
leaving.
It's got a I forget almost 100% accuracy
rate. And then there's Alex, the famous
trained African gray parrot. We have a
gray parrot at home that calibrates
about 400 and will actually talk to you
just like you're on the phone. Hello,
this is
Then there's Koko the trained gorilla
405.
Here's a song bird's song at 500. And of
importance to us humans is that a
kitty's purr and a dog's wagging tail
both calibrated at 500.
So if you're looking for happiness,
it's obvious you have to get a cat or a
dog.
You can also get a African gray parrot.
And if you got a lot of money, you could
get a train gorilla.
We can't afford a train gorilla,
but we have an African gray parrot and k
lots of kitties and doggies. Lots of
kitties and doggies.
All right. So, they they bring a certain
warmth to your heart. A certain warmth
to your heart. So, when people are
depressed or lonely or unhappy and they
live alone, I ask always asked them, "Do
you have a a cat or a dog?" No.
and they were depressed people living
alone. And I said, 'Well, I was in
practice of psychiatry for 50 years. I
said, 'Uless you get a unless you get a
dog to take care of at home, I can't
help you.
Is that true? Yep. I said, if you're
unless you get a dog to live with, I
can't really help you out of this
depression because it's existential.
There's no actual pill that will cure
it. You have to care about something
besides just yourself.
And the minute you have some a dog or a
kitty or a songb bird or whatever, you
have something other than just wonderful
me to think about.
There's something else in the universe
other than just you.
That doggy wants to go out. Okay.
All right. Next next uh schedule.
So consciousness evolved as you see from
through the animal kingdom through the
millennia
and then finally it hit the the great
evolution. The great evolution was
really the
the beginning of humanity as we
understand it which calibrates in the
400s
and this is the great renaissance. the
great uh great books of the western
world
uh are extremely important because it's
the whole intellectual structure of our
society of our law of our educational
system of our ethics and morals
and therefore it's a very interesting
the great books of the western world
they average around 450
so The 400s then are are the the
emergence of the intellect.
What really distinguishes man is the
intellect. And here you get the great
people of history. You have Aristotle at
498.
Uh
498, Capernicus 455, Darwin at 450,
Daycart 490.
Uh-huh. Then we have angles
at 200
and uh let's see two angles is at 200.
Yes. Well, this is alphabetical. That's
right. And then you have Karl Marx at
130.
So why does extreme that why does the
far left calibrate low? because this is
it's based on
uh
the work of Karl Marx.
It isn't that you're anti-left. It's
just that Karl Marx calibrates at 130.
Therefore,
the far left is always anti what all
this stands for. What this stands for is
moral and intellectual integrity. Yeah.
All right. So, that is the explanation.
Why is it that these things don't work
with each other?
The world view from 130
is enormously different from the the
world of 450.
Uh so Markx then at 130 linked up with
Engles at 200.
And uh that is the story behind
uh communism, socialism, and all the
rest of the rest of that. All right,
that's what's the next thing.
Umh
the question is
when I want to know the truth of
something the the interesting thing is
if I hold something in mind that is
truth and I ask her to hold out her arm.
All right. I'm happy to be here today.
Resist. Oh I am.
Oh, I was really
I'm happy to be here today. Thank you,
sweetheart.
All right. Truth then collapses the wave
function from the hypothetical the
potential to the actual. And this the
explanation of it is not within
Newtonian physics. The answer to it is
in within quantum mechanics.
And this is the basics of quantum
mechanics where the the potential
then becomes the actual and collapses
the wave function.
So we'll get more into that when we talk
about evolution. Uh the potential
becomes the actual because of the
collapse of the wave function from the
hypothetical from the possible to the
actual.
Okay. And that's what we do when we use
that technique.
This has to do with the functions of the
brain. You see that below 200 people
uh
people's brain works different than
above 200. So one reason people below
200 cannot comprehend
a higher level of consciousness
is because
that's the way their brain works. Below
200 you have left brain dominance up
there on you see and they live in a
world of stress fight or flight
and uh
disrupted acupuncture meridians. They're
more prone to disease.
So one of the things to get healthy from
anything is to try to shift to a higher
level of consciousness above 200. Above
200 amazing things happen. right brain
dominance.
Uh the brain produces endorphins
and a positive emotion
and greater immunity increases the
killer cells that kill the bacteria.
So, and above 200 gives you a positive
muscle test response. So, if I hold
something over 200, her arm goes strong.
Now, how does she know what I'm holding
in mind? She doesn't.
That's the part that puzzles the
critics.
How can she know what it is I'm holding
in mind? She doesn't.
She doesn't. It's picked It's picked up
through the nonlinear energy field of
consciousness itself.
All right. So, I'm gonna hold something
in mind.
Okay.
Now, resist.
Okay, now I'm going to hold something in
mind. Resist. First time I held Adolf
Hitler. The second time I held Socrates.
She had no slightest conception of what
I was holding in mind. Nor did I give
her any hints, subliminal or otherwise.
All right. So, if I hold Socrates in
mind, her arm goes strong.
If I hold Adolf Hitler or Stalin in
mind, her arm goes weak.
And yet we're not physically connected.
And she doesn't know what I'm holding in
mind, nor had she this slightest idea
what I was going to think about. Isn't
that a strange phenomena?
It boggles the mind.
It also and because it's infallible,
it allows you to get the answer to
anything you want to know in the whole
universe, anywhere in time or place.
Isn't that amazing?
Here we are just two itty bitty human
beings standing here
and we can know anything anywhere in
time anywhere in the universe.
That's godlike almost, isn't it?
It is.
It's absolutely mindboggling.
In actual in actual practice,
we ask if we have permission to ask a
question, I say I have permission to ask
what I'm holding in mind and then we get
a yes or a no. Occasionally I get a no
and then later on I'll realize why I got
the no but I'll get a no. I'll say can I
ask such such a question and I'll get a
no. Huh? All right.
There's certain rules to get accurate
answers. You're not supposed to have
metal across the mid mid mid uh the
middle of your body. You're not supposed
to be listening to rock music or some
subliminal negative stimulus.
Uh
and the basic thing that makes it work
is integrity. You have to be interested
in knowing what is the truth, not trying
to prove your favorite
uh sympathy.
uh if you're trying to prove something
with it, you get wrong answers. Now, we
I know lots of people get wrong answers
all the time. They can't seem to become
objective. They don't seem to have the
capacity
of scientific detachment and
objectivity.
Therefore, you have to have a to make it
work, you have to have a high regard for
truth for its own sake instead of trying
to prove something. And the limitation
mainly that people run into is they
can't seem to get detached. I tell
people first find out what is the answer
and then figure out what to do about it
later
instead of trying to use somebody's arm
to prove your favorite prejudice or
positionality. You see?
Is that understandable? Anybody got any
questions about that?
You have to have a detached objectivity.
It's like first look through the
microscope and then decide what you're
going to do about what you observe. But
don't try and get people to see round
squirly things under the microscope when
there aren't any there.
That's modern politics. Yes.
Trying to get everybody to see things a
certain way. So first you from a
detached viewpoint first find out what
are the facts
then decide what you're going to do and
how you're going to comprehend and how
you're going to handle the facts but
first get what the facts are. Okay. All
right. So that's a very interesting
thing that the actual brain function is
different.
People below 200 work on this side of
the brain and it's an animal nature and
people on the other side
there's the release of spiritual energy
at calibration level 200
and classically it was called
condundolini energy. Classically it runs
up the energy feels around the spine
around the spinal cord and then runs up
into the brain. And if you're into
spiritual work, you may go through
periods of time of blissing out because
all of a sudden this incredible energy
starts flowing up and into your brain.
And uh it's a superbly pleasurable
experience.
So the release of this condundalini
energy is more than just a theory. It's
an actual fact. It's an actual fact. And
it starts at level 200. Yes.
Therefore, one of the motivations of
spiritual endeavor is to begin to
release the condundolini energy because
you begin to see and experience the
world differently. To a person who is
influenced by the condundolini energy,
New York City is an exciting and and fun
place with lots of friendly, wonderful
people. to a person who's the other side
of the brain, they say it's a very
frightening frightening place and and
there's criminals all around and you
can't trust anybody. That's the same
city. You know, how come one says it's a
wonderful place and the other person
says it is a terrible place?
Anyway, I used to live in New York City.
So,
you can walk down the street. My
experience of it is you can walk down
any street in New York City and strike
up a friendship with anybody in about a
second. You say, "Hey, what do you think
about that?" And the person says, "Yeah,
what the hell is that? I mean, you got a
conversation going complete strers. You
know, I over the years I struck up
conversations with hundreds of strangers
on the sidewalk and uh never had a
problem with it. Right away they say,
"Oh, yeah, right." Uhhuh. Okay. So,
you're never friendless. If you have
kind of lean energy flowing, you're
never friendless. Even the animals like
you.
Even the animals like you. Let's see if
that's a fact. Over 200
permission this over 200. Even the
animals like you resist.
Wow.
You see how people over 200 experience a
totally different world. Even the
animals like you over 200.
We could go further with it, but I'll be
pushing their credility.
Actually, all of nature, all of nature,
we
all of nature recognizes the person who
calibrates over 200. Even the trees, the
plants,
all of nature is aware because you are
reflecting the energy of divinity. All
of nature realizes
and respects you in a totally different.
So when you're over 200, all of nature
is happy to see you. All of animal life
is pleased to see you.
Okay? And if you're below 200, the trees
can't wait till you get out of their
woods.
Even the trees don't like you.
This person gets home and says, "I think
everybody hates me." That's a fact.
Even mother nature has you.
All right. Next, next slide.
All right. Consciousness level and the
level of uh
social problems. You see, there's all
kinds of socialistic uh theories about
the causes of all these things. The rate
of unemployment.
What do you think is the cause of
unemployment?
Is the is the problem out there? Are
there no jobs?
What's the cause of the rate of
unemployment
at this and these people the rate of
unemployment is zero?
Here it's only 2%. The higher the level
of consciousness there is no such thing
as unemployment.
You can go everywhere you want in the
world and instantly create a job.
All right. So the higher the level of
consciousness,
the rate of unemployment is practically
zero. Rate of poverty is zero. Happiness
is about 100%.
And criminality is non-existent.
So those people live by a different they
live a totally different life. They live
in the same world but their life is
totally different. All right. The level
of consciousness of then from 400 to 500
that's the level of uh let's say college
education and the great books of the
western world and all the rate of
unemployment is 2%.
The rate of poverty is 0.4%.
Life is okay according to 70%.
rate of criminality is 2%.
So these uh phenomena which are usually
given some kind of a social uh uh
argument for their existence you see is
not due to something out there. It's due
to what you are.
So as the level of consciousness goes up
unhappiness disappears.
As the consciousness of level goes down,
all of these so-called societal problems
appear.
So is the problem then of unemployment a
problem of society?
If there are no jobs, you create them. I
mean, what's the problem?
If there's no employment, you create an
employment.
What does the town need? It needs a
caliber shop. Put together a sign
caliber shop. Put it up. You're
employed.
Takes me about 24 hours to find
employment in any town I've ever been
in. That's if I'm slow.
I not only had jobs when unemployment
was high, I always had at least two
jobs.
After World War II, the vets all came
home. The rate of unemployment was
staggering. Nobody could find a job. And
I had two of them. Two of them plus a
part-time one.
Anyway,
the level of consciousness then is what
determines your your success in the
world. And if you attach happiness to
these things, you can see that the rate
of happiness goes up as your
consciousness goes up.
All right. So, the next one. Uh-huh.
Uh,
these are the consciousness levels and
rate of happiness.
We're talking about happiness today. So,
I thought you'd like to see what is the
rate of happiness depending on the level
of consciousness.
You see above level 200 it jumps. It's
over half the people are happy. At the
highest levels uh people there it's
100%.
Uh there is uh levels that anybody can
reach. Reason
uh love as a decision. Love is an inner
decision. To be loving
to be loving is an inner decision.
Nobody thinks of it as that. They think
of as some kind of romance uh goody
goodies or what you want to call it.
That's what you see on TV every night.
Miss something or other. She's always
a pair of headlights coming down the
highway.
All right.
Nobody thinks of love and love and
happiness as a decision
you know but happiness as we will see as
we go further is a decision. You're
happy because you decide to be happy and
if you don't decide to be happy nobody
can make you happy. Ain't nobody going
to make you happy if you decided you
ain't going to be happy.
All right. So these levels the lower the
level of consciousness
you see the rate of happiness is
practically zero.
Uh this is the level of most maximum
security prisons. The maximum security
prisons the rate of happiness is
practically zero
about 3 or 4%.
People who live in fear only 10%. People
who are constantly desiring and craving
very 10%. Angry people only 10 or 12% of
them are hangry angry.
Pride you get a bit of a break. You go
up to 22. The fact that you're better
than everybody.
Well, it's true. Everybody is better
than everybody. Everybody secretly
believes they're better than everybody.
Okay, we'll go up to the next one. The
next one. Oh,
who is that there? Can you see it? Are
these lights too bright on there?
Uh,
who is that in there?
That's the wolf and sheep's clothing.
And this is to emphasize the difference
between essence and appearance. The
world judges things on appearance rather
than truth. So when we do a calibrated
level of consciousness, we're talking
about what is the essence. There may be
quite a disparity between the actual
truth of a thing and what it appears
like. So this is modern politics. This
is modern politics.
elect Hobo Wapa and uh he you can see
he's going to be wonderful for our
country and our county and our state
etc. And hidden inside this sheep is
who's really there out to get your
money.
Out to get your money. That's what
they're all after. Money in power. Yeah.
Make a donation and I'll get you
elected.
make a donation and we'll run the
highway right through your property that
you just happen to own.
Okay, next one.
Okay, this is what we're talking about
today. The first was introductory
and uh
we're going to talk about 101 ways to
happiness.
Now, what what time do we take a break?
What time is it now? Because I'm going
to run over.
>> We have about a half hour.
>> Oh, okay. Good. All right. Thank you.
That makes me happy.
You know, my favorite character is
Eeyore.
Eore says,
"Oh, well,
it won't do any good anyway."
What good is happiness?
Oh well, what good does happiness do
anybody?
So there are people who live like
Eeyore.
Nothing's any good. Nothing's going to
work anyway.
And that's the, you know, the pessimist.
So the pessimist lives sort of an
unhappy world.
All right.
So when it the world is very intrigued
with happiness and the media are
preoccupied with it to sell products buy
this car buy this whatever you buy is
going to bring you greater happiness. So
the promise is that it's going to bring
you half whiter teeth
or pretty your hair
or swirl your skirts. All those things
are going to bring you happy make you
happy.
And the illusion is always that the
source of happiness is out there. Huh?
So the first thing to realize that there
is no source of happiness out there. The
source is within not without
that doesn't have the capacity to make
me happy. What makes me happy is that I
project onto that that capacity
uh to make me happy is something.
So desiraability is something you
project out there. Desiraability
the world thinks is something that's out
there.
And they don't realize that it's an
energy that you project onto the object
that makes it desirable. And I've spoken
in previous lectures about the famous
book
which I can't think of at the moment. Uh
Alice Bailey series you know glamour the
the energy of glamour is we project onto
a thing an energy
that we project onto it. Alice Bailey uh
the book on glamour. All right. So these
look desirable because we project onto
it that aesthetics makes a thing
desirable.
So this would look more beautiful
than a a lumpy old log laying here.
Now I think a lumpial log is just as
attractive as the flowers because a
lumpial log is like a lumpial log.
And I look at the lumpy old log and I
say, "Oh, lumpy old log.
What a nice lumpy old log."
And I love the flowers, too. But I don't
think the flowers are better than the
lumpy log because each thing is perfect
in and of itself.
This is a perfect table. Oh,
perfect box of Kleenex. Fantastic.
Perfect diet soda.
M
good nummy.
Good sip of
What is that? Espresso coffee.
See how slightly I get that into the
lecture. So I get a sip.
I was going to show you how eating
flowers makes people happy, but then I
decided I wouldn't ruin the decor.
So, the source is within yourself
and you can induce a state of happiness
with hypnosis.
move and you say when you stand up you
will feel very happy and then you tell
them you go unconscious for what I told
you okay and then the end of the session
say well you can stand up now and I say
how do you feel gez I feel pretty happy
he said he admitted that I I put that in
to him during the hypnotic
hypnotic state when you stand up you're
instantly going to feel happy so then if
every time he stands up he feels happy.
I said, "Come back next week and for
another hundred bucks. I'll show you how
to be happy when you're sitting down.
Come back next week. Another 100 bucks.
I'll show you how to be happy when
you're standing up.
Next week laying down. Next week
sleeping. Next week eating. Going to the
bathroom. You'd be happy.
All right.
These are the secrets of happiness
which I don't want you to tell anybody
about.
That the source is in you and not out
there.
Gee, I thought if I bought that I would
be happy. Huh? If I had that New York
City penthouse.
The secret is that to want what you have
instead of have what you want.
Want what you have instead of wanting
what you don't have.
Want what you have.
How does that grab you?
You got me.
>> Yeah.
We'll have another hypnosis session
tomorrow, dear.
Every time you look at your dear
husband, you will feel happy.
Okay, Snokey,
want what you have.
So, you look over everything you have
and you decide that even if it's frumpy
and and a little beat up and worn, it's
still yours and it's adorable.
I got a little uh I got a little stuffed
dog at home, little stuffed dog with
long ears. His name is Speedy.
And I've had him since I was four years
old. My grandfather gave it to me when I
was four. And I still have Speedy.
Well, Speedy, his ear got torn off. He
had to be sewed back on very soon
because I used to spin around by his
tail and stuff.
Anyway, so Speedy's been repaired. His
ears been put back on and his eye had to
get funny.
So why does why am I so happy with
Speedy? I mean, I've had him now 76
years or something.
I still have Speedy. And whenever I look
at Speedy, I still feel happy. So if you
want what you have,
then look around you and say, "Whatever
it is, it's mine and I love it. Cheap
chrome furniture. So what?" Better than
no furniture. say that
you look at whatever you have
and see that it's desirable.
You look in the mirror and you say
that which I'm seeing in there is
desirable.
Yes. Now, if somebody was on a deserted
island all by himself and you paddled up
in a canoe, they would fall all over
themselves with happiness that you were
there. Look, another human being, you
know.
So, want what you have. Now, one thing
you have is your own existence.
So, what you have to settle for then is
the fact that you exist and that you
have life. And all that it should take
to make you happy is that you are.
What does it take to be happy? And the
fact that you are
you isn't
that enough.
Be satisfied with the fact that you are
everything beyond that is so much
addition doesn't mean much. Is that the
edge of the slave there?
It's just all black here. I don't know.
You might drop off into you know where.
Is anybody here not happy that they are?
Is anybody here unhappy that you are?
There could be somebody.
It could be somebody that hates that
they are.
Is everybody happy that they they are?
>> Hey
So if you start from the beginning,
you're happy all the time. I'm happy
that I am. I'm happy that currently I'm
in a physical body and I get to
experience this plane of existence. And
I'm happy that finally I'll get out of
the body and I won't be confined to this
protoplasmic world. I'll be in another
dimension where other exciting
adventures are waiting.
whole uh universe to explore.
Want what you have instead of craving
what you don't have. So you see that
happiness is an inner decision. Once you
decide to be happy, nobody can do
anything about it.
One source of happiness is just
satisfaction.
Satisfaction that you are. I mean I got
here today. Hey, what more do you want?
All right. There's certain things you
have to give up.
And that's why people just don't like
being happy too much.
You have to give up. Poor me. Uh-oh.
A poor me.
Oh,
poor me.
Look at everything's wrong.
Poor me. I don't even have a thumb on
this hand.
Everybody else has two thumbs. I only
got one.
Poor me.
Only one thumb. God,
he owes me a thumb.
By acceptance and by acceptance we
eliminate the negatives. How do we
accept it? We choose it to be that way.
I choose instead of craving and desiring
and wandering. So you stop grasping for
happiness. You see that ha happiness is
completely within yourself.
Stop rejecting the source of happiness
outside yourself because then you're
going to want to desire it. You got to
get it. You're not going to be happy
unless you have something.
That's a miserable state. You can
remember when you're a kid that your
happiness depended on having certain
clothes to wear to school or
when I was a kid, my mother used to make
when it was raining out, she would make
me wear rubbers to school.
Well, if you're a 12-year-old boy
wearing rubbers to school.
So, on the way to school, I would dart
behind the bush, take my rubbers off,
hide them under the bush, and go to
school and then get my rubbers on the
way back home again.
You imagine a what 11 or 12 year old boy
and you arrive in school with rubbers
on.
Moment baby
put rubbers on your life as hell.
So happiness is hiding your rubbers in a
shrub.
You can put them on on the way home from
school.
Of course, a smart mother says, "How'd
your shoes get wet with your rubbers
on?"
Okay, I shouldn't tell that to mothers.
Never check that out. Then
the kid said he wore his rubs to school.
Believe him. There's lots of better
things, lots of things that it's better
not get too much involved in.
Okay. 101 ways we got to keep moving
now.
What's the next slide?
Surrender your cravings to God. What if
you can't let go of a craving? You have
to have a new Cadillac to be happy. You
have to have a new car. You have to have
something. You have to surrender all
cravings to God. So this is a more
spiritually evolved person.
It says in which the love of God becomes
uh
the priority.
Would I rather crave this thing and be
unhappy or be thankful for my existence?
So prayer now the spiritual evolution
then increases the chances of happiness.
Surrender all cravings to God and you
and you do it in the form of a prayer.
Dear God, I seem to be the victim of
this insatiable craving.
Pistachio and cream cheese.
What makes this work is is the
willingness to let it go. What makes
this work is not that God says, "Gee,
you sure are a swell person. Here's your
pistachio ice cream."
is your willingness to surrender it to
God. It's the surrender. The happiness
is in the willingness. I say to you,
could you surrender this to God? Yes, I
could. That's the beginning of happiness
right there.
Then the next step is merely would.
First step is could you? People say no,
I couldn't let that go. I say, well, if
I hold a loaded gun to your head and if
you don't, I'm going to blow your brains
out. Could you let it go? Yes, I could.
So, realize that it isn't that you
can't, it's just you won't. You can let
go anything that you want to. Now, is
anybody here stuck in something they
would like me to help them out with?
I just happen to have a loaded
I'll give you a little help.
Put your head under my coat here.
boy sure gave up in a hurry, didn't he?
All right. So, the willingness to
surrender all cravings to God.
Uh there's a certain hard to describe
is independent of events.
All right. So is a certain attitude like
Maurice Shiovalier
is avi
and if you lost all your money today I
say why are you happy? I'm happy because
I lost all my money today.
So happiness is also a certain style
and if you want to make it more
attractive realize it is really a
superior style.
Only peasants are unhappy.
Only dumb peasants are unhappy.
When asked how he felt about being 77,
Maurice Shiovalier said, "Considering
the alternative, very good indeed."
And at 82 I have to express the same
sentiment.
Is then a dec part of a decision
to have a certain attitude towards life
towards is it really an existential
position
of being happy and grateful
and enjoying it.
So if you get to be a dog, you have a
certain joy to be. You go.
If you have a kitty, you go.
If you're horse, you go pop.
What do you Whatever you are. If you're
a squirrel, you get the
you're as certain as you want to be in
whatever
uh expression your life is expressing
itself right now. Uh being a human.
Well, that's an exciting trip. Being a
human, I think being a human is
extremely exciting. Don't you think it's
exciting? You never know what's going to
happen. you know any moment
suddenly get a heart attack and fall
over.
You can suddenly win the lottery. I mean
who knows what's going to happen. A
certain joy of bot life
that is independent of what actually
happens out there. In other words, you
do you play the game for the sake of the
game, not for the necessity of winning
the game. that the game of life, the joy
of the game of life, it comes from
playing the game, not from winning or
losing. Because in human life, there is
no way to win or lose.
There's no way to win and no way to
lose. There's no winning or losing in
real human life. Winning and losing is
all a fantasy you project onto
something.
If you think that's wonderful and you
get it, you say, "Oh, I won."
If you've taken vows of poverty, you
just lost.
Please don't give me a camel.
Because then I'll have to tie him up.
Then I'll have to get food for him. Then
I'll have to get a shovel for his poo
poo.
Please do not give me anything. You know
independent this. So this if you look at
it then so be like shar in which you you
celebrate your own existence.
Celebrate your own existence. You see,
if you came to a deserted island where
there was only human being, just think
how overjoyed they would be to see you
paddle up. Wow. They just get so excited
they wouldn't not to do. They haven't
seen anybody in 20 years and here comes
somebody paddling along.
So try to be a source of joy to others.
The way to experience
is to be goodnatured and humorous and
light-hearted and helpful to others. And
because you are that way to others,
that's what you become.
A certain joy of life is independent of
events.
If you're either happy or unhappy, you
can ask yourself
within ourself. We have unconsciously
the child, the adult or the parent. So
who is it that is happy or unhappy?
A lot of times if you become the child
uh the parent in you will get angry and
become guilty. Yeah. So is it the child,
the adult or the parent in you? The
parent is the your conscience.
This is your performance and this is
your inner child.
Part of
is that the inner child is still there.
Why are you happy and skipping?
You kick a pill off the sidewalk.
All right.
So part of happiness
is that your child is still active.
Your adult is well integrated
and you have a loving parent. That your
conscious your conscience is not brutal
and and negative
uh that you have total inner acceptance
of yourself.
If you have within yourself
a negative parent that is critical of
you all the time, then you that's
something you need to see is going on in
you. See that's the inner parent. I have
interjected that thinking it's myself.
That's your inner parent.
And you live in fear of it. You're not
supposed to do that. Not supposed to say
that. Don't do this.
So you see your inner child is just
bubbling over with stuff it wants to do
which your parent will then scold you
for.
You can't moon people in public.
So that's our motto for today. You can
put that on your mirror at home.
You cannot moon people in public. It's a
good reminder. You know, can't moon.
Your kid wants to moon people.
Your parent would punish you and so your
adult has to handle it.
We won't moon anybody today, Doc. Okay.
All the way here. They said you can't
moon anybody on the way to Prescott.
Okay.
All right.
So, differentiating yourself.
Who is it that is being
satisfied or frustrated? The source of
your happiness.
I think you should own your child all
the time within yourself. The sense of
humor, the shar
means you have a child that's feel free
to express itself. As you can tell, my
child gets unruly at times.
And my wife, I mean, my adult has to
a couple weeks ago. Can I tell this
story?
>> Going to see the doctor. Going to see
the doctor.
>> I went to see my internist. I see him a
couple times a year. And I came home
from the internist and I had this
undershirt and it had a hole in it. She
says, "You didn't wear that shirt to the
doctor's office, did you?"
So that was the adult and I was being
the child.
My child wanted to wear the shirt with a
hole in it
and her parent came up and said, "You
didn't wear that shirt to the doctor's
office.
What will the doctor think of her as a
wife?" You understand?
You let your husband wear that shirt to
the doctor's office.
Oh yeah. That's so funny.
All that interaction and the subtleties,
you know, the cintillating subtleties of
these interactions
are are whereby comes from. You know,
the fun of that story, the fun of the
experience, the fun of her response to
it. You know, that's part of the fun of
life is that your wife is upset you wore
a shirt with a hole in it to the
doctor's office. I mean, it's
hysterical. You know what I'm saying?
So, we have to also differentiate the
actual that which is real from that
which is merely symbolic.
Many things this world fights for are
neither
part and parcel of either winning or
losing, winning or gain or loss
except symbolically.
The thing is symbolic.
And look how people kill each other and
do terrible things over things that
intrinsically have no reality.
But they are symbolic.
For symbolic people go to war
for symbolic reasons. They bomb each
other.
This is all symbolic.
So symbols bring up something within
ourself. So when we're upset or
depressed or not happy, it may be
because of the symbolic significance.
Wearing a shirt with a hole in it is
symbolic
of neglect and not caring this and etc.
Symbolic.
So many the things that cause us to be
either happy or unhappy have no
intrinsic reality.
It's because we have superimposed a
meaning and a significance.
Think of the significance of the
American flag. Instantly you go like
this and think of what you feel like if
you see somebody stomping on the
American flag. Just soon kill them. Yep.
So our life is not only actual emotional
the child the adult and the parent
inside
but it is it's appealing to the
archetypes of the
all these things within us on a symbolic
level.
What does it symbolize? Not what is it
but what does it symbolize?
Having a lot of money.
Having a lot of money
in a lot of parts of the world isn't
useless.
They haven't got anything to sell you
with it. Your your money doesn't mean
anything. Other parts of the world
without money, you're nothing.
The meaning of money then is so
symbolic.
There was some place in the world I
visited. as soon as you go ashore,
uh, they have all kinds of things they
want to sell you on the beach.
And, uh,
so they say $25,
$50,
and then when you get to town, you you
really they sell them for 25.
They sell these plastic images of
antiques for 25 cents in Egypt, too, I
think it was.
$50, $50. So, some of the naive
tourists, you know, got them down to $40
and thought they got a terrific bargain.
You get downtown in Caron, there they
are. 15 cents on the sidewalk.
So, was that success or not success? It
It's what it's symbolic of. Symbolic.
Symbolic meaning. All right, we'll go to
the next slide and then we're going to
take a break. Then we'll go to the slide
and the next slide and then we take a
break. I want them to just All right.
This is too advanced for you folks. Take
that off there. We'll have a break
and you better be back on time.
>> How long is the break, honey?
>> 15 minutes.
>> The break is 15 minutes.