oh my god stop making all that noise out there gloria and excelsius deal what a blessing to be
here today with you again in a nice lovely new venue isn't this a beautiful place let's have an
applaud for the place they have been very pleasant and cordial uh in welcoming us here
and we're very thankful to them amen that's enough prayer praying for today
where is the the um oh there it is
well we always start how many people are new how many are new people can you see
them
quite a few quite a few new people all right uh for the sake of the new people also for
those that have been to other lectures i usually do uh i go through a number of slides that
condenses everything we've taught thus far condenses the essence of all the books we've
written and lectures to try to give a a context and and the context is really
based on the scale of consciousness so the first slide we have is the scale of consciousness
so let's see what a what a what you recall looks like
oh my goodness that's pretty good that's pretty good all right can you all see that all right
can we lower the slide can we lower it a little bit can we lower it a little bit that's as low as
we can go
all right no that'll be fine and i left i forgot my pointer too well we'll just ask the lord for
help uh the way the scale of consciousness uh arose was i attended a lecture on kinesiology one
day and uh what was demonstrated was that negative states of consciousness were the ones that were
able to make your body go weak and positive stimuli make your body go weak and positive
stimuli make your body go strong therefore somehow nature was able to discern that which was pro-life
versus that which was anti-life this seemed like a very profound and significant finding
so i went back to the clinic and i used to take courses on everything all over the place
and then i would go back to the clinic and give a lecture on what i had learned to the staff
so i asked a couple of people
it was a big clinic and uh so there was a couple of people standing there and i said come on over
here i want to demonstrate something and the one of the things he demonstrated was
that when you look at fluorescent lights it makes you go weak so if you take a large number of
people and have them look at the fluorescent light and you press down on their arm their body goes
weak so i said ah
fluorescent lights make people go weak so i went back to the clinic as i say i was giving a lecture
on this to the staff and i said now fluorescent lights make you go weak so i had a couple of people
that were standing around as it turned out they were uh well anyway a couple people were standing
around and i said you look up but there was lights and then i pressed down on their arm
and they did not go weak hmm i said what the hell's the matter here
see fluorescent lights or what is it here
anyway they looked at the fluorescent lights and they stayed strong i thought what in the world
can this be and uh it turned out that they were all students of a course of miracles
and we had the second attitudinal healing center in the united states
and they all did it was a group that met and they all had various problems from cancer to
god knows what all and they were doing a lot of work and they were doing a lot of work and they
going to freaking
And they did the Course in Miracles, and when they got to about less than 70 or 75,
about three or four months into the course,
they stopped being, they were no longer weakened by fluorescent lights either.
So we had discovered something that to me was dazzlingly important,
an external stimulus, how you can differentiate.
So that is how the Course in Miracles, I mean,
and this levels of consciousness really began.
And then I had the inspiration to calibrate it on a scale,
a scale of one to a thousand.
So we found that anything over 200 made people strong,
and under 200 made them go weak.
This, as it turned out, further research turned out to be a basic protoplasmic response.
To survive.
To survive in this world, even bacteria have to know what will kill you,
and what's good to eat, and what's poisonous.
So we eventually evolved the scale of consciousness on a level of one to a thousand.
And it's been extremely useful, pragmatically, in fact, profoundly useful.
And so if I press down, so I'll show it, how you work it,
it's very simple.
You find somebody who's not distracted by music or,
and I ask her, and I just use two fingers, and I say, resist.
So I'm pressing down with what, six, eight ounces of pressure.
I'm not trying to strong arm her down to overcome her strength.
I'm trying to feel what is her relative strength.
Okay. Now I'm thinking of somebody, and I'm thinking of that somebody,
that somebody calibrates over 200.
Okay.
Two hundred, resist.
Now I'm thinking of somebody, and that person calibrates over 200, resist.
Okay. First I was thinking of Adolf Hitler, and secondly I was thinking of Abraham Lincoln.
Now she, she does not know what I was holding in mind.
Isn't that magical?
That's the part that people have a hard time with.
If I ask her what I'm holding in mind is true or false,
and the more you use it, the better you get at it.
And my memory for recent events is not always the greatest.
So I'll say to her, I remembered to take my pills this morning.
Let's do it now.
I did remember to take my pills this morning.
Oh, thank God.
So I won't fall over and faint in the middle of the thing.
Atrial fibrillation, if you forget your pill, you just sort of pass out on the floor.
So if I ever pass out, just tell them, Doc, you forgot to take your pill.
Oh, yeah, all right.
Relatively benign condition.
But if you forget your pills, you lay, you lay on the floor and pass out.
Which is not handy if you're driving.
So I gave up driving.
All right.
So I want to just quick review.
We've got some review slides.
And from this review,
you'll get the crux of all the consciousness research we have done and uh the profound
benefits that it that accrues to knowing how to use it for instance all the prisoners uh
where's that prison that they're going to let them all out of cuba huh yes all right so i don't have
to interrogate a single prisoner in guantanamo bay all i have to do is look at the guy's picture
hold it hold it in mind and i asked the arm this person was plotting a damage to the united states
yes or no so without i don't even have to talk to the guy i can see exactly what he's up to where
he's been and what his plans are without ever even speaking to him much less having to torture him
use some kind of horrible water
warning or something it's extremely useful yeah let's just see what's the consciousness level of
mankind today in america uh the consciousness level i permission to do this of mankind is
currently over 200. oh boy 204 205 mankind is over 204 205. mankind is overall is at 204.
the level that differentiates truth from falsehood is 200. so mankind all of mankind is just above the
level of integrity 204. it was below that level it was at 190 until the year 1988 until 1988 mankind
calibrated at one i forget it was below 200. then suddenly it jumped it jumped in the late 80s
over 200. all right america we have a let's let's do america so we know where we're standing with
we have permission to do america america is over 400 405 410 420 425 america is currently over 420
425 420 that's extremely high 420 is extremely high because the 400s of the world of the intellect
see down below
so if we if you look at this consciousness level you see that there are people at the bottom
that feel uh that are full of hatred there are vindictive people and then there's guilt
there's hopeless people depressed people people who live in fear people who are constantly angry
then there's people that are avaricious they're just greedy
uh
so a lot of 만큼
of people live on these levels. People live at a consciousness level of 150, and they're
constantly hating something or somebody. And then at a higher level, you get the level
of pride. And pride prevails. If you watch the television, you see the political goings
on, and much of that has to do with pridefulness, and then anger, and fear of loss. All right,
so then you finally get up to 200. Well, below 200, half the world lives there. Half the
world lives there below 200. Then you get to the level of integrity. So below 200 makes
your arm go weak. And so if I hold, if I hold,
Adolf Hitler in mind, you see, Adolf Hitler, I have permission to calibrate him. Adolf
Hitler calibrates over 90. Oh, my God. He calibrates over 80. Adolf Hitler calibrates
about 80, just to give you an idea of what those numbers stand for. All right. So a calibrated
level of 80, then, is sufficient to kill, how many people died in World War II? 10 million
or 100 million?
Oh, what's this?
What's this?
The number's 10 million or 100.
10 million, 100 million. I think it was 100 million. That level is, you know, so when
we calibrate the various dictators in the world, you'll find they all calibrate below
200. There isn't any dictator who calibrates over 200. All right, so from the map of consciousness,
you can, you, we derive a certain view of God, and a certain view of yourself. And,
and we've given the, the various levels names, you know, acceptance, acceptance, the 300s
are very, very powerful. And many of the giant churches, et cetera, run the 300s. Great enthusiasm,
the 300s are the levels of the fire department and policemen and various very demanding jobs.
Then you get up to the level of the 4,000.
The 400s is, is logic and reason. Logic and reason. Now you're dealing in abstraction
and the intellectual realm. And then when you get up to 500, when you get up to 500,
I don't have a pointer here, but at 500 is, is a very significant level for, level for
spiritual people. It's the level of love. And the idea of, people say, how can I advance
my level of consciousness? And I tell, I just tell them always the same thing. Be as loving
as you can towards all of, all of life and all of its expressions. When you see a little
beetle, walk around the beetle, don't step on him. Walk around him, respect his life.
Respect and loving all of life. As you love all of life, then your perception of the world
begins to change.
And you begin to notice progressively how beautiful and perfect everything is. Everything
you look at is beautiful and perfect, beautiful and perfect. I looked in the mirror this morning
and I said,
Doc, you're just beautiful and perfect. Actually, I didn't, but it makes a good story. But you
should do that every morning. If I were you, that's a new thing we'll do. Look at your
every morning and say you are beautiful and perfect because that's how God sees
you let's ask that question I asked I have permission that's the way God sees
you resist see yourself as God sees you you're beautiful and perfect just the
way you are but one ear is bigger than the other God says well you had to learn
humility some way you were so pompous pompous in your last lifetime so you
buy a bigger hat and pull it down over your ears all right so you move up to
the level of love at 500 that is very profound 540 is almost sainthood and then
as you get up to the level of 600 you run into the levels of bliss and at 600
you no longer
identify your reality as your physicality and the physicality is sort
of an amusement sometimes it's a drag and sometimes it's an amusement but
every time you notice it I notice the body is still I notice the body is still
here so I'm sure that I'm in the body because I see it walking around at the
highest levels you no longer identify with the body it's like consciousness is
present
period and the body is is an it that walks around and if you hit that level
you'll find that everybody talks to the body as though it's you which is very
mystical in the beginning you can't what you wonder who they're talking to who in
the world are they talking to and you realize that they all think you're the
body and once you get that you're you're okay you get used to people talking to
it because they think it's you anyway so those are the levels of enlightenment a
from 600 up are formerly sat chitinanda heavenly bliss and peace all time
stops and at that level you can leave the body if you wish at level 600 you
no longer consider yourself to be in that body and if you wish to leave you
may you realize this there's an open invitation and karma plays a big point
in part there and whether you're going to stay with the body or not but you go
into a state of bliss and whether you live or not is irrelevant so those are
the levels from the lowest of hatred and hatefulness and imagine people people
live in this level they're constantly angry they hate the world they hate
everything so how you see the world today we're going to talk about what is
the world
how you see the world depends on where you are on this level of consciousness
you can see it as a hateful place as an evil place hopeless sad and tragic scary
and frightening disappointing conflictual see the world is demanding
then you can see the world as satisfactory hopeful you realize that
harmony is possible you can see that the world is peaceful you can see that the world is
meaningful you begin to see the world is benign complete beautiful and perfect
and very often the revelation so that shifting from ordinary consciousness into
a very high state of consciousness is a revelation I've described the occurrences
in my own life and the way the world is perceived so we'll be talking a lot today
about how the world is perceived.
There are a couple of experiences.
One is the room lighting up.
Bill Wilson, the founder of AA, describes it very well.
He was an atheist for many years
and then realized that unless he believed in God,
he was certain to die of alcohol.
But he was an atheist,
and so he didn't know what to do.
So he struggled and he struggled.
And one day he just gave up,
and the room lit up.
The room lit up.
With an illumination of light.
And that was a profound, transformative experience.
At another time,
everything in the world becomes extremely beautiful
because the divinity of all that exists reveals itself,
and divinity is perfect and incredibly beautiful.
Beautiful.
Would you mind explaining?
I'll let her describe these two events in her life
because I've described them.
I've described mine so many times.
Well, the light in the room is like Bill Wilson.
And so one time, you tell him about that,
and then tell him about when you're driving around the mountain
because that's how the world's perfection comes about.
So they think it's not just a peculiarity of me personally, you know.
Well, he's weird, you know.
Is that on?
Yes.
Yes, now it is.
Okay.
I had a very high experience.
And it usually, many times people say that it comes
just before you awaken, you know, about four in the morning
and you're just at that time when you're almost going to sleep
or almost waking up.
And that's when a lot of the higher experiences seem to occur.
And then afterwards you think,
am I going crazy or did this really happen?
But in my particular experience,
I had this illumination.
I had this illuminating light that came from the corner of the room,
the corner of the ceiling.
And I was laying there and my eyes were wide open.
I was wide awake.
And all of a sudden this light came into the room and it was blinding.
You couldn't see any object in the room.
It was all engulfing.
And it was like a peaceful energy that came with it.
And almost,
awe-striking energy.
And it came into the room and lit up the whole room.
You couldn't see an object in the room.
Nothing was available sense-wise
except for this energy that was so loving and so earth-moving.
Bill Wilson, who I knew personally,
described it exactly the same.
And when you had that experience and described it,
it was almost like Bill was talking again.
Mm-hmm.
Because the light was coming from the corners of the room and blinding it.
It was coming from one corner.
The whole light just came in from one corner.
And it was like, it wasn't the window.
It wasn't anything.
Very interesting.
That's called illumination.
And then it went into me.
The light just kind of funneled into me.
And after that is when we started teaching the work.
So it was almost like the guiding light, if you want to put it that way.
But it did.
It changed my life.
Several months after that, we live up in Sedona, as you all know.
And I was driving down Upper Red Rock Loop Road.
And all of a sudden, this earth-changing phenomena took place
where you could see every single leaf on every tree.
Every rock seemed to be three-dimensional.
And you're standing, as I'm driving down,
and I literally had to pull off the side of the road
and sit there for a minute.
Because you got the whole impression that the earth
and all your surroundings were a part of you.
And you're a part of it.
It was a very moving experience.
And it's hard to talk about it.
Thank you very much.
So those are the things we're going to be talking about.
What is the world?
It's a place where you can become illuminated,
and become enlightened, for one thing.
So it's a world of great light.
It's a world of great spiritual opportunity.
Actually, it's a place of maximum spiritual opportunity.
Yes?
All right.
So I just thought we'd cover the basics,
and then we'll go on to the next slide.
Yes.
So we're going to go through the review slides rather quickly.
What?
We're going to go through the review slides rather quickly.
These are the enlightened states.
These are the states of enlightenment.
Yes.
And these are the experiences which you can calibrate
all the way up to a thousand.
And these are the states of enlightenment,
and it goes all the way up to the archangels,
and then all the way to divinity itself,
which is infinite.
And I came out of the pits of hell,
in a state of eternal agony in the pits of hell,
which I had fallen into through exploring the levels of consciousness,
and I began exploring the depths of consciousness.
And I went into the levels of hell,
and first it was the higher hell,
people just in agony and having their heads cut off
and stuff like that.
And then I went into the depths of hell.
And therefore, the depths of hell are beyond description.
And I suggest to everybody that they avoid hell at all cost.
Eternal, hell is eternal agony.
Just as the heavenly states are eternal bliss,
the lower levels of hell were eternal agony.
And I remember passing a sign that said,
Abandon all hope, ye who enter here.
Just like Dante says.
And how Dante knew it, I don't know.
But that's what it says.
And then you see suffering and agony
and the hopelessness and despair that is forever.
And as you go deeper into the pits of hell,
you realize what forever means.
The horribleness of forever cut off from the light.
Forever agonizing despair.
And that's why I advise people not to play with hell.
People play with hell, they do.
And it's like a game.
You just don't want to go there.
You don't want to go there.
And in the pits of hell,
in the pits of hell where I was in eternity,
you can only experience eternity in the pits of hell.
When you're in the pits of hell.
So it went on for an eternity.
And I was an atheist at the time.
And I said,
If there is a God, I ask him for help.
And then I went blank.
And then when I came to,
the world had been transformed
into the most incredible, radiant beauty.
The light shone forth from the existence and divinity,
all that exists, the divinity of all that exists,
shone forth in exquisite splendor.
And that was the major transformation
of my own life.
Yes.
I don't know why we got to talking about that.
Oh, yes, because of this.
Because of this slide, yes.
All right, so what's the next slide, huh?
Yes.
So we said that most of the world's population
lives below the level of 200.
Actually, 85% of the world lives below
what to us would be like the upper levels of hell,
despair and poverty and crime and agony and hopelessness.
And that's where 85% of the world's population lives.
Now, they live below level 200, 85% of the world.
And yet, the average level of consciousness
of the world right now is, what did we say?
204, yes.
How can that be?
It's because the few people, these are the few people
who calibrate 250 and over.
You see how few they are compared to the mass
of people in the world?
The great majority of people in the world
live below level 200.
So how can that be?
Well, we'll turn, go to the next slide.
It can be because the 15% who calibrate over 200,
their relative power is so much greater
than the negativity.
So go to the next slide.
The 15% of the world calibrate, 15% calibrate above 200.
Counterbalance is the 85% that calibrate below 200.
Isn't that amazing?
So a group like this has a profound and significant impact
on the consciousness of the world.
Does that sound grandiose?
Let's ask the air.
What I just said is a fact.
Those of you sitting here in this audience right now,
here present, are way over here and you're counterbalancing
a huge mass of the population.
So this audience here present now
is counterbalancing literally millions.
Resist.
This group here now is calibrating,
is counterbalancing the negativity literally of millions.
If that were not so,
then humanity would just self-destruct.
It would self-destruct.
So because of this 15%,
the 85% does not destroy itself.
We'll go to the next slide.
The evolution of consciousness over time,
this is the scale of the animal kingdom.
As you can see, the animals starting way out
from the bacteria, protozoa,
coming up through the fish, the octopus,
the Komodo dragon, the dinosaur,
the whale, migratory birds.
Then we get to the wild animals
and the wolf, the hippopotamus.
Then we get to the domestic pig.
Oh, good.
We finally get up to the piggies.
You see, these are all killers.
In order to eat and live, they have to kill.
Then we get to the peaceful animals
that are herbivorous.
A deer doesn't have to kill anybody to survive.
The elk don't have to kill anybody.
So the lower levels of consciousness
live by the death of others.
So they are destructive to others,
so the only reason they stay alive
is by killing you, a tiger or the lion.
We don't blame them for it,
but you don't want to play with them.
Then we move up the scale,
and you see, you come to the domestic animals,
you come to the family dog,
and the gorilla, and Oscar the cat,
Alex, the trained African gray parrot who talks.
Now, Alex, you see, calibrates over 400.
In other words, Alex actually understands
what you're saying.
When you say to Alex, get me two blue cubes,
Alex understands two blue cubes.
So Alex is a very famous parrot.
And Coco, the trained gorilla, calibrates at 405.
So you are safer with Coco, the trained gorilla,
than you are with 85% of the people on the planet.
All right, and here's where I go soft.
The kitty's purr is 500,
and a dog's wagging tail is 500.
So we've got three kitties home
and a doggie.
So this morning, all the kitties,
all three of them were around me purring away,
giving me something to eat,
and the doggie's tail was wagging like this.
I said, now you have to stay home and guard the house.
So they have become man's companions,
man's companions.
Oh, yes, we have, oh, I'm sorry about,
we have Broccoli, who is a talking parrot.
And Broccoli carries on a conversation all the time.
Never stops talking.
And she calls to the dog.
And she calls the kitties.
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
What's the dog's name?
And she'll say, Kelsey, Kelsey.
And the dog runs over.
Yeah.
Soon as I was telling the dog, get away from the bird.
So then Kelsey will say, and then the bird will say,
get away from that bird.
.
And what else did you, oh, she taught the bird to say,
shop till you drop, put it on the credit card.
Shop till you drop, put it on the credit card.
That is so funny.
Okay, we'll move along.
Otherwise we'll never get through to the new material.
We'll move to the next slide.
Yes.
Oh, this is the next slide.
Sorry.
This is the level of the 400s.
This is the intellectual capital of civilization,
the great books of the Western world,
which all calibrate in the 400s.
So this is the intellect of the 400s,
all the great scientists, Darwin, Copernicus,
all the great philosophers, Hegel, Hobbes,
Immanuel Kant, Locke,
and all the structure of Western civilization.
This is what the Pope is worried is under threat.
He's afraid that the Western society is going to collapse.
And he points to Europe and says that these level of the 400s
are collapsing.
And they are collapsing and calibrating lower and lower.
So Europe no longer calibrates as high as it once did.
And the impact then of the great books of the Western world,
what has been substituted is social Marxism.
So what's being taught in a lot of colleges today
is not the great books of the Western world,
which calibrated in the 400s, but cultural Marxism.
And as you see, Karl Marx calibrates at 130.
So if you're going to substitute 130
for 455, Adam Smith,
the wealth of nations is the basis of capitalism.
So you want to replace what calibrates at 455
with collectivism, which calibrates at 130.
And collectivism, where it has been tried,
has caused collapse.
In China, 10 million people starved to death.
10 million starved to death.
Substituting this for this.
So the calibrated levels of consciousness, then,
are profoundly important.
And the first thing I want to know about somebody,
or a speaker, somebody on television,
is what does this person calibrate at?
Having calibrated thousands of things,
you eventually get pretty good at it,
and you can guess, you know, almost within 10 degrees
of what level this person is speaking.
So what you want to know is how much truth
is there to what they are saying.
Okay, next slide.
We'll skip this one. It's too difficult.
We'll skip this one.
This is sort of an explanation
of why this muscle test works.
You can't understand it based on Newtonian physics,
which is based on cause and effect.
It's a quantum effect.
So the understanding of the phenomena
that I demonstrate here with Susan all the time
has to do with, the understanding is quantum mechanics.
And the only, the best, nearest understanding to it
would be reading the new book, Mindful Universe,
by the professor of physics at Berkeley,
whose name I always forget.
What was his name? Huh?
Henry Stepp, yes.
So if you're really interested in understanding it,
oh, here he is right here. I knew he was someplace.
Henry Stepp, yeah.
So the, what happens is you collapse the wave function
from potential to actual.
So what we're witnessing all the time is emergence.
We're not witnessing causality.
Nothing is causing anything else.
The mind thinks in Newtonian terms of cause.
What's happening is the potentiality becomes an actuality
by an ascent of consciousness.
Who did that?
Who?
You folks did it.
The potentiality becomes an actuality
by an ascent of the will.
Things are not caused.
Potentiality emerges.
What happens is this situation here has a potentiality.
Under the influence of consciousness,
that potentiality becomes an actuality.
what could be does become what it could be
if local conditions are favorable.
If you put water on it, it'll grow.
If you don't put water on it, it won't grow.
So the mind thinks in Newtonian terms of cause and effect.
Actually, it's a quantum reality
in which potentiality actualizes
due to an ascent of the will.
The potentiality becomes an actuality.
You see, but that did it by itself.
The ego jumps in.
The ego jumps in and says,
I decided to put my arm out there.
That's a lie.
Help!
It decided to do that.
What is the it that decided it?
There wasn't time to decide.
Run through your mind.
I think I'll put my arm out to demonstrate a point.
There wasn't time to think it.
No thinking went on.
Let's see if that's true.
You folks probably think
that everything you do is because you think that.
Fess up, do you?
There is that aspect of consciousness
which experiences.
And it presumes, it presumes that it is you.
It presumes.
Actually, you're not the experiencer.
You're the witness of these phenomena.
The phenomena are spontaneous.
The phenomena of life are happening of their own.
Potentiality becoming an actuality.
Because, frankly, of the radiance of divinity.
Because of the radiance of divinity,
all potentiality can become an actuality
when the local conditions are right.
Not because of your consciousness,
but because of the presence of divinity.
The consciousness of divinity
is what allows all potentiality to become an actuality.
The source of all that is.
Yes.
That makes it simple.
That makes it simple, doesn't it?
These are spiritual practices.
We calibrated all of them.
And they're in one of the books, anyway.
It gives you the calibrated level of consciousness
of various spiritual techniques.
Practicing the golden rule.
Turning fair wheels.
See, they all calibrate around 540.
Going to church.
Going to communion.
All these things calibrate around 540.
Gregorian chants.
Om Namah Shivaya.
Genuflection.
Kneeling to pray.
Clasping your hands.
All devotional acts are 540.
So when you experience a culture
where everyone greets the other person thusly,
you're in a different world.
You're in a different world
than Broadway in New York City.
A world in which everyone greets everyone else this way
acknowledges divinity.
I acknowledge divinity within you.
All right.
So we'll go to the next one.
This is too complicated.
We'll go to the next one.
This has to do with brain function.
Now, below level 200,
above and below 200,
you have different brain function.
The brain function above 200
is different than the brain function below 200.
So you say,
why don't people do this, that, and the other thing?
It's because they're operating
from a different side of the brain.
So the animal side of the brain
is interested in conquering,
and acquisition,
and things like that.
And then the spiritual side of the brain
works in a whole different way.
Above 200,
you have right brain dominance.
So what happens
as you become involved in spiritual work
or any spiritual practice
or any spiritual congregation
or attending a lecture like this
is that you,
you summon forth
what's classically been called
the kundalini energy,
a spiritual energy,
which classically is described
as going about the spine.
The kundalini energy then rises
to the various chakras,
to the various chakras
or energy centers.
And they get higher and higher
until finally they reach
the crown chakra.
But we can tell,
so by being as loving as you can
towards all of life
and all of its expressions,
you're summoning forth
the energy field
to radiate up to the heart.
And then you get up to the brow.
You begin to develop spiritual vision.
And finally to the crown chakra
and enlightenment.
So there's actually
a physiologic change in the brain
that occurs as a result
of becoming spiritually oriented,
spiritually committed,
joining spiritual groups.
Practicing spiritual principles.
Just simply praying.
Genuflecting.
All things that are symbolic
of acknowledgement
of the presence of God
as divinity.
Begin to transform you.
So you begin to experience
and see the world differently.
So when we say,
what is the world?
What does it look like?
What do you think the world is?
It pretty much depends considerably
on where your Kundalini energy
is risen.
A person is risen to the third eye,
sees the world differently
than a person who is holding
their energy in the spleen.
Holding it in the spleen,
you see an enemy,
a world of attack and revenge,
attack and revenge,
attack and revenge.
There are whole cultures
on the planet today
that have a dominant effect
on human history right now.
The whole culture lives in the spleen.
The whole culture,
all the people,
the population,
the country,
lives in the spleen chakra.
Not in the heart,
but in the spleen.
Revenge,
get even,
dominate,
kill,
behead,
chop their heads off, etc.
To people who live in the heart,
this seems mysterious and unreal.
And unfortunately,
they often go into denial
and say,
oh, people can't really be that way.
Oh, guess they are.
Whoops.
Little mistake.
Okay, we'll move on.
The level of consciousness
and social problems,
I show this because
this phenomenon is politicized.
In politicizing things,
a condition is blamed
on other people
or our circumstances,
you see.
But now,
when we look at level of consciousness
and the rate of unemployment,
you see,
the rate of unemployment
is not related to available jobs.
It's related to level of consciousness.
At this consciousness level here,
75% of the people are unemployed.
It has nothing to do
with how many jobs there are available.
Nothing to do with that whatsoever.
The rate of unemployment,
the rate of crime,
the rate of death,
the rate of poverty,
the rate of violence,
the rate of criminality.
We can blame them
on external factors,
but you see that they are all
completely related
to the level of consciousness.
What to this person
is something we can do,
let's go out and beat up people,
would not even be thinkable
to these people.
So social problems
reflect completely and 100%
the level of consciousness,
level of consciousness.
Okay, next thing.
The rate of happiness.
Here on the right-hand side,
we see the rate of happiness.
At the lower levels,
30% are happy.
Here we see,
no, I'm sorry,
percent is 4%,
3%.
It's all below 10%.
People who live in fear, 10%.
Angry, 12%.
Pride, a lot of people live in pride.
22%.
All right, so you see
at the higher the level
of consciousness,
the percent of people
who are happy
goes up immensely.
So spiritually oriented,
let's say,
spiritually oriented people,
500 and over,
the chances are probably 90%
that you're relatively happy.
You're so used to being happy
that if you're not happy
for a moment,
you're unhappy.
If for a few minutes
you live where the rest
of the world lives all the time,
you think it's a bad day.
They just think it's a normal day.
You get up depressed,
you hate everybody,
and you're overcome
with greed and obsession
with retaliation
and getting even with people,
and you think that's normal.
That's where they live all day long.
When you get a negative thought
like that,
you ask God to remove it.
Dear God, please help me
to get over this angry thought,
and replace it by a pleasant thought.
Okay, we'll go to the next one.
Oh, we don't need to go into this.
We'll go and move on to the next one.
Did I have that one marked?
I didn't really.
We calibrated the levels
of many of the world's
most famous spiritual teachers,
a hundred or so.
People are always writing me
from someplace in the world,
and I tell them,
look, we calibrated
a hundred bona fide teachers,
and if you can't find
your guru on that hundred,
you're on your own.
Even though there's
a hundred well-respected
and verified teachers,
they always find, you know,
Rama Bumchipupu,
who says I should give him
all my money
and go to bed with him.
What do you think?
All right, next.
Next, that's one more.
No, we'll move on.
Yeah, all right.
So, anyway.
Are you just doing
the ones I circled?
Yes, we have.
I do?
Yep.
Are there many more circled?
A few.
All right, we'll go through
the next ones real quick,
and we won't stop
and play with them.
Well, let's go,
just move real fast
to the next one.
See the great places,
spiritual places in the world.
Next one, Golden Rule
calibrates for 405.
Gregorian Chants, 595.
Okay.
Obligations of spiritual teachers.
Declaration of responsibility,
integrity,
and you can calibrate them all.
We'll go to the next.
All right,
here's the crux
of today's lecture.
Veneration,
perception,
and essence.
Perception and essence.
This is what the world sees
and what it thinks
is going on,
and this is what
we're going to be
talking about
in the next lecture.
Thank you.
certain truth from falsehood
out of this, tell the sheep
and wolf in the sheep's clothing.
Right?
Yes, okay. Are we done yet?
No, we don't. We'll move on.
I can't believe I circled
all those. Move on to the
next one. Move on.
Instantly.
Are we at the end?
Okay.
Great.
Reminds me of the Wizard
of Oz. Do not look
behind this screen.
I've got to keep an eye on the time.
We have about
15 minutes or so to break.
Okay, alright. Freedom, morality
and ethics. That's not today's
lecture. Here's what we're
supposed to do today.
Where's the slides on
what is the world?
Today we're
going to be talking about what is
the world? What is the purpose
of the world?
We discovered it's
God's karmic bailout
plan. I don't know. I can't
get the slides right today.
We need
the world. We're talking about
the world today.
Hey!
157. So we're missing
the first three.
What is the world? Oh boy.
Wow, we're ahead of the game.
Alright. So there's no
point of cursing your existence.
Oh God, why was I
born?
Being born a human is rare.
Fortunate. The consequence
of good karma. If we calibrate
that, that comes out at
455. Now that's
what the Buddha teaches pretty much.
On
the one hand, it's a
good thing to be born a human because
there are karmic improvements
you can make on yourself.
On the other hand, the Buddha warns us
to avoid being reborn as
a human.
Old age
suffering and death.
So
avoid it if you can.
But if you are here, then
be glad
and fortunate
that you are here because of good karma.
Why? Because
here you can overcome
negative karma and gain positive
karma. So to me
the world is a world of maximum
spiritual opportunity.
Where you can gain good
karma and undo negative
karma. Being born
a human is fortunate.
And the consequence of good karma
calibrates at 455.
Alright, so we'll take a negative
view. The world is a trap of illusion.
Therefore,
salvation depends on non-attachment
to its linear and emotional
qualities. That only
calibrates at 230.
That only calibrates at 230.
The perceived world
is the result of the projection
of human consciousness
and therefore akin to a Rorschach
card, 450.
As a psychiatrist
that always appealed to me.
You see, you project
out onto the world what
you think it is
because of who you are.
Not because of what the world
is. However, you can
make gross miscalculations
and say, here kitty, kitty,
kitty to the tiger.
Or play
with the chimpanzee.
Or tame
a white tiger.
Yeah, so
miscalculating with wild animals.
It's because the wild animal
doesn't respond
as a person. So I'll explain
to you the wild animal phenomena.
It happens with white tigers,
trained lions,
the lady and the lion. In the end
the lion kills the lady, or whatever.
These trained animals, they suddenly go
berserk and kill you.
And why you cannot trust them.
It's because
animals have a group consciousness.
Animals have
a perceived
memory.
They have an individual
memory. But their
consciousness is a group consciousness.
I first learned this
when I was watching a flock of birds.
And
I thought the birds are
following each other.
All thousands of birds are
following each other. The sky is black with birds.
I thought,
how can they stay in formation like that?
Each bird stays in formation
like a bunch of flying tigers.
Like a bunch of
airplanes, I mean.
So anyway,
and then I suddenly
got what's going on.
Each bird in that flock
is not following the other birds.
Believe that?
You're dumb.
No, each bird is not
following the other birds
at all. The assumption
is that the bird is following the flock
due to a density and how
close they are to the other birds, etc.
What's happening is that there
is a pattern
in their mind, and each
bird is following not the other
bird at all, but
an energy pattern in their minds.
Isn't that amazing?
Each bird now is
like a radio turn to
the same radio frequency.
So each bird
is following an inner pattern.
That's true.
Each bird
is following an inner imprint,
an inner pattern.
Each bird is therefore
individual and yet
follows a group consciousness.
So all animals
follow a group consciousness.
Therefore,
an ape that seems tame,
now, his memory
track is that this is a safe
place to be,
but his group consciousness
is that of the animal.
And at any moment, the white tiger
will tear your
carotid artery right out
because he's responding
to the group consciousness.
Therefore, any wild animal
cannot be trusted
at the level of absolute trust.
It's only a matter of time
before his
group consciousness
will take over.
And the lion eats the lady.
The white tiger rips out the neck
of the man.
The chimp tears at the lady's face.
So
the animal is only
very partially
who you think it is.
It is more 95%
the instinctual animal.
And therefore,
you can never safely turn your back
on a wild animal.
The fact that you get away
with it many times
doesn't mean it's safe to do.
But I just thought I'd tell you,
they respond to a group consciousness.
Below level 200,
people respond to a group consciousness.
Below 200, yes.
So the people living
in a violent community,
it's only a matter of time
before they become violent.
It's only a matter of time
before they begin doing dog
fighting and various things like that.
The group consciousness
begins to dominate then.
So all of us are
under the influence of a group
cultural consciousness
plus an individual consciousness.
And as you become
spiritually evolved,
your consciousness becomes
progressively more immune
to negativity.
And people say, let's go in town
and shoot them all up.
And you say, I don't feel like it today.
It just doesn't appeal to you anymore.
It's not a matter of being a goody-goody.
It's just that it has no longer
any kind of reality to you.
It has no kind of reality.
The perceived world is a result
of a projection of human consciousness
and therefore like a Rorschach card.
So you project out onto the world
your view of the world.
And depending on what your level of consciousness is,
you can project out onto the world your view of the world.
I always give the example
of going to New York City.
I love New York City.
People will come back from New York City
and say, you know, they're all cold
and unfriendly there.
Another person will come back
and say, everybody was friendly there.
I notice when I go to New York City,
you can stop anybody on the street
and start a conversation
just like you knew them forever.
You say, what do you think of that?
They're going up there and the guy will say,
hell, I think they're spending a lot of taxpayer money on that.
You're right in the middle of a conversation
like you knew you for 20 years.
People are very, very friendly.
That's because you're friendly and benign.
But if you're below 200,
they say, listen, I don't know you
and they'll walk away.
So what you see then
is not what you think is out there
but a projection of your own self.
All right, so we're going to stop here
and take a break for how long?
15 minutes.
I wanted to review
for those that are new,
because quite a few knew,
all that we've summarized
so far,
and that'll bring us up to date
for today's lecture.