All right, so in order to be effective then, it's effectively successful, required in the world.
So when I were talking about, well, I want to be successful in the world,
most of the people in this room, I guess about everybody, is guaranteed success with anything you really want to do.
And you say, well, I haven't been successful in this or that.
Well, you don't really want to do it then, do you?
Did you sleep last night? Yes.
Well, if you really wanted to do it, you would have been up working on it, for God's sake.
When I was working my way through medical school, I didn't go to bed at 8 o'clock at night, for God's sake.
If I got to bed by 3 in the morning, I thought I was really good.
So it takes grit. It takes grit.
Where do you get the grit? You get the grit from the willingness.
The willingness to commit to something gives you the grit.
Okay.
So we're thankful rather than prideful.
We're okay with progress rather than perfection.
We pull into our benefit the willpower.
We pull into our willpower named grit.
And we visualize goals.
So visualizations.
Picture yourself in the goal which you want to be a famous movie star.
Picture yourself then in Hollywood.
You chip away incrementally.
And you prepare yourself in advance.
All right.
So let's go to the next one.
The next characteristics that you need to emphasize in yourself.
These are things that are already within you.
So all we're asking you to do is to increase the,
the voltage of things that are already within you.
Everybody has fortitude.
Everybody dragged themselves out to get here to this lecture and got tickets
and stood in line and found a seat and put up with a speaker and everything else.
That takes fortitude.
Another trick, and we're talking about the tricks of the world of success,
is to picture the result.
Have an image in your mind.
So if you're destined for someplace, get an image of it.
Get an image of it.
Get an image of what you want to accomplish.
Get an image of your factory spinning out piles and piles of whatever it is you manufacture.
Picture the books lining up that you've written.
You know, the poetry that you've had published.
All right.
So picture the result.
Picture yourself as successful.
Then you develop a certain rhythm to your work, a certain work rhythm.
These are all the habits.
These are the, you might say, the habits of successful people.
Fortitude, picturing the result, and you develop a certain work rhythm.
And you develop certain routine schedules.
And inspiration, then, is the fire underneath your feet that keeps you going.
Harness the muse, carpe diem.
Everybody knows what carpe diem means?
Seize the day.
Seize the day means today is the day.
Seize the day is the day in which you will get an interesting idea, and that will seize you.
So what I was seized by myself, carpe diem, was success is not a consequence of what you do, but what you have become.
How's that for carpe diem?
Success is the result of what you have become, and not necessarily what you do.
All kinds of people try for success, and they seem to be futile.
They just never make it.
And I...
All right.
So inspiration, then, harness the muse, carpe diem, seize the day, means to capitalize on opportunities as they arise.
Many people have found that having a special place or setting is very useful to their creating work.
If you're into literary work, like writing books, et cetera, a special place and setting tends to facilitate it, at least with me.
I've got all my reference books and everything all around.
And the cat's walking back and forth across the desk.
I can't write a book without the cat walking over the manuscript.
Special place and setting.
Then there's times when you need expert advice and consultation.
And so you need advice and consultation.
And one form of that is the way we use the arm.
Many times when I'm writing something or I'm preparing a lecture or something,
we'll use the arm to confirm it or calibrate it.
Is that true or not true?
And what's the level of truth?
So much of the stuff, if any doubt arises, we use the arm very often.
The more often you use the arm, the better you get at it.
She knows how to disconnect from any personal involvement in it.
And the arm is just either stronger or weaker.
That's all.
And I don't have to tell her what I'm holding in mind.
So it's a nonverbal phenomenon.
It's a phenomena of energy.
It has to do with the energy field of consciousness.
So truth then has a reality.
So here's the secret of it.
That which is truth has a reality and exists.
And that which is not truth has no reality and therefore does not exist.
So all we're really testing, we're not testing truth against falsehood.
We're testing is versus is not.
All right.
So if I hold a certain person in mind, I say they committed that crime, and her arm says
yes, that's a reality.
It exists.
If it's not, if it is not so, it's not a reality, it doesn't exist, and therefore the arm has
no strength, and it goes weak.
So with a little discipline and a little experimentation, every couple has to work out their own technique.
But if I hold in mind, I'm not going to be able to do it.
If I hold in mind something, then I say to her, I don't tell her what it is.
I don't want to influence her at all.
I'll say what I'm holding in mind is true.
What I'm holding in mind is true.
Resist.
And then she resists.
And does anything come to your mind when I say that, or is it blank?
It's blank?
Yeah.
All right.
So her mind stays blank.
And so she's learned how to just let the arm sort of be on its own.
Well, to be able to tell the truth.
The falsehood about anything in the universe is an incredible gift in and of itself, is
it not?
Nobody ever had that before, except the great ones of history.
Imagine, you can tell the truth and falsehood about anything in the universe, anytime, anywhere.
You can calibrate Cleopatra, Nero, Napoleon.
Am I on?
Thank you.
That brings to mind, remember the Elizabeth Smart case?
I can't get it.
The Elizabeth Smart case.
What about it?
The little girl that was missing, you know, in Utah.
Well, we were getting a lot of emails at the time to track her.
Oh.
And, you know, and we'd say if she's alive, and we'd get yes.
And then we said, is she in state?
And we got no, which was, and we went, whoa, what's this?
Then a couple days later, we did it again, and this is, I think it was a week or so.
And then it says, no, she was in Utah.
And it really blew our mind, because we couldn't figure it out as to where she was or what was happening.
And then, of course, they found her months later.
But I thought, well, maybe we're getting weird answers.
But, you know, they had taken her to Florida and then brought her back into Utah.
So, you know, sometimes you get answers, and you can't make sense of it.
Oh, puzzlements, yes.
Puzzlements.
And you don't know why you're getting answers.
And the other thing about missing persons, we found we couldn't use it to track missing persons.
And the reason was that they were somehow involved with karma.
Yes.
It was their karma.
So we couldn't, you know, somebody said, gee, you could locate missing persons.
And we asked, could we do that?
And it said, no.
And the reason we got a no is because very often it has a karmic background.
Right.
Yeah.
So, anyway, we just seemed.
Seemed like a good idea.
Seemed like a good idea at the time.
Yeah, we could price it.
Missing kids, $10.
Under the age of five, $3.
Okay.
Expert advice and consultation.
So if you find somebody you can work with, very often a spouse is the best and not always.
And then with patience and persistence, success becomes closer and closer.
Okay, we'll move to the next one.
Hang out with successful people.
Yes.
Why?
Because you pick up from their aura a way of being in the world.
Successful people have a recognizable style.
In my life, I've known and met with a lot of the most famous people in the world,
highly successful people.
I was put up for a club one time that was led by all kinds of giants in industry and society,
et cetera.
And the one characteristic they all had in common, whether it was the president of J.P.
Morgan or whatever, was cordiality, cordiality, not some secret formula, every one of them.
Here's a guy worth a zillion times more than I am, and his only interest was whether I
was comfortable in that chair.
Can I get you some coffee?
You want cream?
You want sugar?
And look out, the sun is shining and your eyes here are sitting more this way.
Cordiality.
Multi-billionaire.
And his only interest is whether the light's shining in my eye and do I want sugar in my coffee.
What do you think of that?
That's success.
Success is then a way of being, it's a way really of being cordial.
It's a cordialness towards all of life and all its expressions.
So if I step over the insect, it's an aspect of my cordiality.
Cordiality.
If there's a stray dog and I try to befriend him, I was in France or someplace, I remember
sitting in a little cafe, and there's this hungry kitty over there.
Well, I could not deny this kitty.
This kitty, meow, meow.
So I had to take my lunch and start giving it to the kitty.
Oh, boy.
All right.
So you're cordial towards all of life, whether it's a hungry kitty or it's a bug on the carpet.
Or it's a person in need or in pain or in suffering.
Or somebody needs a ride on the road.
You know, there's a cordiality towards all of life.
So it means that you have an abundance of the life energy.
You have more than what you need for just your own survival.
Everyone here has more than enough.
You've got enough of your own survival and enough energy to radiate out to influence
everything around you.
Just think, the fact that you are has decreased the crime rate wherever you live.
That's a fact.
Resist.
The fact that you are, not what you do.
No sign that says, burglars beware.
You'd better be carrying an S&W.
In the east.
I mean, they don't know what that means.
In Arizona.
I think it's in Arizona.
They said, better have an S&W.
Until these guns cross the other.
You put that up over the W.
Guarded by S&W.
S&W.
All right.
So you don't need an S&W warning sign to keep the crooks away.
What you are just never happens.
So I've got a loaded shotgun by the door.
Never had to shoot anybody.
And get my money's worth.
What am I going to do?
What am I going to do with that?
I was hoping a crook would come by someday.
Second.
I've practiced with this big shotgun.
Now, what you need is a shotgun.
Everybody needs a shotgun.
And a shotgun has a peculiar sound to it.
How many people know the sound of a shotgun?
Yeah, it's unmistakable.
So somebody knocks on my door at 11 o'clock at night.
I pull it out and it goes, ka-chunk, ka-chunk.
Yes?
.
The sound of somebody loading the chamber of a 12-gauge shotgun is unmistakable.
You only have to hear it once in your life and you know that sound.
So we've never had any trouble with robbers or ker-chunk, ker-chunk.
All right.
One way to be successful is cordiality.
Cordiality.
.
was the prime characteristic of all the world's most famous and rich people that I've ever met.
Every one of them was completely cordial, concerned about my welfare, my happiness, my ease.
They want to introduce you to everybody so that you'll have friends to sit and talk with
before they leave you with people.
They make sure you're surrounded by friendliness.
So caringness for others.
The way to be successful, then, is by cordiality and caringness for the happiness of others.
If you're constantly caring for the happiness of others, you don't have to worry about your own.
It's automatic because you create a field, and the field is what uplifts you to a state of happiness yourself.
Hang out with successful people.
Avoid naysayers and energy drainers.
Those are the negative people.
Practice the virtues.
Integrity.
Look for helpful feedback.
Imaginative enterprise.
Be friendly and upbeat.
Express appreciation.
Just saying thank you.
You'll notice when you shop in a supermarket or something like that, the girl rings you up and all that.
If you say to her, gee, thank you, most of them will go, thank you.
I'll say, thank you, thank you.
They look at you like, thank you?
Yeah, thank you for bringing in my purchase.
Oh, oh, gee, that's nice.
So you thank everybody.
Thank you for their efforts in your behalf.
The clerk in the grocery store who rings you up like that, she's like a mechanical being now, you know?
And you say to her, gee, thanks a lot.
And it's just a little bright flick of sunshine in her day.
She feels better.
She doesn't know why.
If you said, did you feel better?
Because of that?
No.
Not because of anything, but by virtue of that which you have become.
You radiate out thankfulness, acknowledgement, and positive energy field to everything and everyone.
To everything.
Everything you radiate it.
Well, as you become more aware, you realize that which you are is recognized by life.
It's life.
It's the life that recognizes you.
As you walk through the woods, as you walk through the woods, the trees are aware of what you are.
Do you know that all of nature knows that which you are?
All of nature.
Okay.
We have permission to ask this.
All of nature, including the trees, are aware of that which you are.
Resist.
Even nature is affected by that.
That which you are.
That which you are, which radiates gratitude.
So as you plant the little plant, the little plant is now being blessed because never in all of its life has it been touched by the radiance of divinity that comes down through the human kingdom.
Here's this little nothing, nowhere plant.
And divinity itself is touching this little plant.
Oh, it's a blessed plant.
So now the little plant is blessed.
As you walk through the fields, and then the fields know that that which is divine is in their presence.
The trees know it.
As you walk down the street, you're radiating that same energy to everyone on the street.
Everyone in your neighborhood is safer because you live where you live by virtue of the radiance of that which you emanate.
So if you picture yourself as radiating out an energy field, then,
which brings peace, happiness, success and safety to all within your aura,
you're then owning your own reality and you're affirming the divinity of your own creation
because it is the presence of God within, which is the source of it.
Yes.
And that energy then is facilitated by lovingness itself.
So loving this towards all of life and all of its expressions.
We notice all the people who work in this hotel seem to be...
blissfully positive no matter who you ask about something they're always like
falling over with happiness than provided there we fix the door so it
works now we were happy we couldn't get the door to work he had a grease gun and
and that works well nothing could be happier than us or but he was radiant
because we were radiantly happy that he'd fix it so we've been loving all the
employees that work for the hotel they all seem to blossom with it they all gee
whiz so we never we don't take anything for granted you know you acknowledge
everyone you acknowledge their presence thank you so much the door works now and
so you avoid naysayers and energy journey as you practice the virtues
ourself we look for helpful feedback imaginative enterprise be friendly and
upbeat express appreciation so we were
in the middle of the night and we were in the middle of the night and we were
ending up on expressing appreciation that which you appreciate is
intensified by virtue of your appreciation so you're not just being
polite you are intensifying that person's joy of their own existence so
you bless everybody by your through loving appreciation to express
appreciation then is to uplift all of life and to bring divinity clarity
to all of us so that we can all be happy together and that we can all be
happy together and that we can all be happy together and that we can all be
me me me it now becomes us us us so like for this lecture there's a whole team of us here there's a
whole whole us a whole whole team of people all together and it wouldn't be the same without all
each and every one of them is individual and when i see a certain face of some of somebody i care a
lot about and i see that person here and i feel happier i feel happier so if i feel happier about
all the people i love one way to make the world happier is to be loving towards everyone in all
of their expressions it's nice to be somebody that people look forward to your coming instead
of hiding the china and locking up the children i put the dog away because don't know it's coming
all right so we influence everything around us
that's important
thing because if you think you're just doing it for yourself it'll seem sort of shallow
no you become the best you can be at in in every way possible for the goodness of the world for the
benefit of the world and that's not being grandiose to realize that naturally things are better
because you you're you're part of the the world in which we all live so that results eventually then
in a group support
and uh so we're here today with the group we're here with a half a dozen people or eight people
or 12 people or whatever it is a whole mess of people anyway we had a small small plane load
got here uh the next part is being acting the part uh dressing the part uh you can change your whole
mood and ambiance by the way you dress and of course that's why there are dress codes in certain
of life and why schools have dress codes because you're dressed like a slob you
act like a slob and if you're just neatly then you have to pretty much act
neatly so it sets it sets the energy of the field that sets the theater so life
is the theater and endless theater so you dress the part that you are playing
in the theater and as you see I am stunningly dressed today the lack of
attire is the expression of male freedom male freedom all the goody
goody guys are the red ties if you notice red ties of the rage you can't be
on TV without red tie so I'm I avoid the red tie people you all have a red tie
you know people can trust them wear a tie but others get dressed over the sake
of the camera you know they have wives too you know they have wives too honey
you got to put it that way
okay so dress the part finding a coach I'm a very big fan of coaching everybody
needs feedback so whatever you do I believe in sharing what you do with
others the people you're friendly with you share it with them because you get
feedback you say I think I'll get there earlier and open the store earlier and
they give you feedback of why that's either good
or not good yeah so you get constant feedback from from people I believe
everybody needs a life coach everybody needs a life coach and people that any
kind of business lead a life coach you need a businessman with 20 more years
experience than you've got you you try out the idea on them that'll save you
all kinds of disasters and mistakes and so finding a coach I think everybody can
use a life coach I think everybody can use a life coach I think everybody can use a life coach
you know that roe herring
go, we go back and see our analysts periodically. You know, just to share how things are going and
areas I wonder if I shouldn't develop a greater compassion in a certain area. So you want some
kind of feedback, objective feedback from others. So you're not just me, me, me in the mirror all
the time. How am I doing? You need somebody's opinion of how you're doing other than just
yourself. And of course, if you have a good spouse, your spouse often, you know, is a very good,
very good fee feeder backer. And for better or worse, anyway, we all need somebody that we can
get a trustable feedback. So we trust them because we know what their intention is. Their
intention is our good and welfare. And if your tie is crooked, you need somebody to tell you
your tie is uncrooked today. So we dress the part and try to find
the right person to help you. So we're going to help you.
So we dress the part and try to find the right person to help you. So we dress the part and try to find
coach. And I believe, I'm a big believer in coaching. There's all kinds of coaching going
now. It is a whole lifestyle of coaching. When enrollment do as the Romans do is something that
many people seem to fail to learn. It's due to narcissism. They insist on doing it their way
when they're in Rome. The way to be successful is when you're in Rome, you do it as the Romans do it.
And if it's fitting in, fitting in in a positive way with your culture, when in Rome, do as the
Romans do. Identify and evaluate the successful. Watch for subtleties. Watch for subtleties. Now,
as I say, class and rank and success is often reflected to others by very, very subtle,
very,
very subtle moves. A slight delay in a gesture of a split second has a totally different meaning.
So as you move forward into the world of success, you'll find that subtleties have greater meaning
than that which is overt. Whether you have a new Cadillac or not doesn't impress people that are
very successful. Everybody's got a new Cadillac. No, you drive an 84 Cadillac, that's got class.
That class is an 84 Cadillac. Everybody can buy a new one. All right. Anyway, the subtleties of
success, you pick up nuances. Nuances has to do with style and a way of being. And the way of
being has to do with the degree of self-confidence as well as the training in the background of
people. Some people are automatic. Some people are automatic. Some people are automatic. Some people are
automatic. Some people are automatic. Some people are automatic. Some people are automatic. Some people are
automatically polite. Automatically polite when it's not even required. You see, it's not
required. You're automatically polite and considerate of others all the time because
that's what you will become. You've become a considerate person towards others. And other
people pick up the subtle ways in which that considerateness is conveyed. Whether they're
hearing you correctly, whether you can sit so that the sunlight is not in their eyes,
those are just examples of being considerate of others. Another one is to cut giant-sized projects
into bite-sized portions. Why? Because giant-sized projects are too dismaying. You know, you don't
have to house clean the whole house. You know, spring house cleaning. Now you've got a house
cleaning the entire house. No, don't house clean. Do not house clean the whole house. Just do the
upstairs bedroom, period.
Oh, okay. You can do the upstairs bedroom, but house cleaning the whole house is heavy
duty. So cut giant-sized projects into small portions. So after you do the small portions,
what's remaining is less than it was. I once dug a ditch a quarter of a mile long by hand.
Ha, ha, ha. I did it by hand. Oh, God. It was a roadway.
It was a dirt roadway, and the rain would wash it out. So I had to dig a ditch on each side of this
road to run the water off. Otherwise, the road was always getting washed off. Well, it was out in the
woods. It went right through some very heavy, heavy woods. There's no way to get machinery in
there, and I don't think I had machinery in those years. So I decided, well, I'll just dig it by
hand. So I got a shovel, and I started digging the ditch on this side by hand, and then I
dug a little bit on this side by hand, and I said, well, I'll just dig 15 feet a day. So I dug
six feet, and then I dug another six feet, and I said, oh, hell, this ain't so bad. So I dig another
15 feet. Before you knew it, I dug 30 feet. Wow. Well, so I said, yesterday, I dug 30 feet.
So today, I'll do 45 feet. So the next day, I did 60 feet. In a matter of time, I dug this whole
quarter of a mile long ditch.
All by myself, with no mechanical tools or anything. If somebody said to you, can you dig a
quarter of a mile ditch, I'd say, I don't think so. I'm not a mesomorph. I'm an ectomorph, you
know. We don't dig ditches, ectomorphs. We think about it. We think about it and call the
mesomorphs, and they come in and do it, you know. And the endomorphs watch the whole project.
All right. So we uplift other people by that which we have become. And our vision, then,
by sharing that which we are, we're sharing your aura. Now, within your aura is much that you have
learned in this world. Within your world is the nonverbal. Within your aura is much of the
nonverbal, which you cannot share. You don't have enough time to sit down and describe to everybody
you've ever known about life in a linear way. The total collectiveness of your entitled life and all
the wisdom and experience of it exists as an energy, as an energy field. So when you share that which
you have become with others, they pick up the energy field of all that knowingness. That's how it is,
that the guru, the spiritual teacher,
transmits enlightenment via an energy field. So it's the aura of the teacher has within itself
the collective wisdom throughout all of time. There is no amount of world time in which all
of this could be laid out in a linear lecture, intelligent class kind of a format. You could
extract some principles from it, but the principles are only basic principles. So the way to
form an enlightenment is instantaneous. From the energy field of the teacher then, it radiates forth
an energy field. That field has within it the total knowingness of all that you need to become
enlightened, which is not really describable. It means becomingness, becomingness. Becomingness of
the divinity within and becoming estándar.
one with that divinity in all of its expression.
So we transmit to others without any verbalization,
without any formality.
So when you ride the subway,
you're influencing all the people in that subway train.
When you stand on the corner,
you're influencing everything around you.
The openness then, your own openness to awareness.
Interesting experiment was done recently.
One of the world's greatest violinists,
I forget where this was reported.
I forget his name too.
Anyway, one of the world's greatest violinists,
you don't need to know his name.
Tell it to me later when I go to bed tonight.
Anyway, in the subway station,
he was always done an experiment,
some, I forget what university.
He was done his experiment by a university.
Anyway, one of the world's greatest violinists
played in the subway in New York City.
And of course, so he's playing in there
and occasional people would come over and give him a dollar
and somebody would give him $5 and somebody would give him 10.
Nobody knew who he was.
He was anonymous.
So here's this anonymous violin player.
At the end of the day, he collected, I don't know,
$50 or something like that.
Not a single person recognized who he was.
Not one single person recognized
that one of the world's greatest, most famous violinists
because he was doing, he was doing, you know, I don't know.
he was doing it for free in a subway station.
So this has to do with framing.
Because of the framing, people could not see the reality.
If you had said one of the world's greatest violinists
will be in the subway station,
everybody would be rushing down and recognize who it is.
But he was anonymous.
So framing, it isn't just the truth of anything that you say
but the way in which it is held
and presented to others.
So the way in which you hold
all that you have learned in life
and hold it for others,
you become not only what you are
but how that is held.
How you hold who you are.
How you frame who you are.
If you frame yourself as thankful gift of God
to the world,
then you are a gift of God
to the world.
If you frame yourself as a miserable worm,
then you are a miserable worm.
Because you become what you say you will be.
So I want all of us to own the infinite dimension
of that which we are for the sake of the world,
for the sake of ourselves.
Each of us.
Let's hold out our hands to God
and own the divinity within us,
that which is within us is the source of all.
to the salvation of all of mankind,
for which we thank Thee, O Lord.
Amen.
Good, we've all owned who we really are.
You're trying to signal something?
What?
It's time.
Time for what?
Lunch.
Oh, good God.
It's time for lunch, people.
I was interested in saving the world.
She said, well, you're saving the world already,
so that's why you can have lunch.
So we'll meet again.
What time?
We'll resume at 2 o'clock, then, after lunch.
2 o'clock.
2 o'clock, we'll meet again for lunch.
Oh, boy.
Looks familiar.
All right, we've got 101, so we'd better move along.
We said identify with a group.
For instance, we came out here to California.
It's actually a whole group of us,
a whole group of us, a dozen or so people all together,
dressed apart because,
part of life is unconsciously role-playing.
We often, you know, act and behave the way we believe that is.
And, of course, you can do that with hypnosis.
You can tell people that they are something or not something,
and they will immediately begin to act and behave that way.
You're afraid of everybody, and you don't have much confidence,
and the person will instantly become hesitant and self,
and deprecating, et cetera.
We mentioned this morning the value of a coach,
somebody that can give you some valid feedback.
In the old days of Christianity, you had a confessor.
Saturday afternoon, you went to confession,
and then your confessor would give you so many Hail Marys
and Our Fathers to say repentance,
but he would also give you some kind of a feedback.
You need to spend more time at your studies
and more time being nice to your mother or other.
When in Rome, you want to blend in, do as the Romans do.
And many social faux pas are just the failure to recognize that edict
because it shows respect for a different culture.
When you're in a different culture, it's respectful to respect their culture.
And if it's okay to wear something on your head, wear it,
and if it's not, don't.
In other words, try to blend in.
Now, the next thing is to identify and evaluate people who are successful.
Become like them.
Adopt what positive aspects they have.
They're reflecting, certainly, something positive.
And we mentioned a few people,
and, of course, one of their great successes is due to the fact that they're enthusiastic.
They're enthusiastic about their ventures.
And then, in trying to, when in Rome, do as the Romans do,
watch for subtleties, subtle little communications.
The other next thing you can do is take a giant-sized project,
and as I mentioned this morning, cut it down to bite-sized portions.
That way, I dug a ditch on both sides of the road for a quarter of a mile by my lonesome
by just doing six feet a day.
And then I said, six feet, that's easy.
I could do 12.
So I do 12.
And the next day, I do 18.
So we benefit from the confidence of that which we have accomplished.
What's the next one?
Activate the ego ideal.
Well, you know, Freud identified the ego ideal as really,
it's an aspect of the conscience,
but the ego ideal is people that we identify with.
You know, very often, the parents are supposed,
they're supposed to serve in that function.
I always wanted to become as affectionate and sociable and likable as my father.
So he was my ego ideal of sociability.
When my father sat down to the piano, a whole crowd would form around him.
People would start to sing in joviality.
So that was his sociability and good-naturedness became an ego ideal.
To be good-natured, to be sociable,
to put your arms around your brother and zing-zongs together.
So that was the ego ideal.
You'll get energy and inspiration in surges.
And you learn to take advantage of them.
Instead of dismissing them and say,
well, I'll do that later today at 4 o'clock.
When the urge comes on you at 8 in the morning to complete a certain project,
I found that it saves me.
It saves a lot of expenditure of time, thought, and energy to sit down and do it.
So 150 or 101 ways to success was partly the result of inspirational urges.
And, for instance, it's not what you do, but it's what you are.
You know, it was an inspirational urge.
I didn't think it.
It just became aware.
It's not what you do, it's what you are.
All right.
The next trick is to always have a notepad.
Have a notepad next to your bed.
Because all the wonderful insights and wonderful phrases and thoughts you've had just before you go to bed,
you say, I'll remember that in the morning.
And in the morning, you forgot what it was.
So I found always have a note next to the bed.
So part of today's lecture is due to a notepad next to the bed.
Enthusiasm.
Yeah.
Have a notepad next to your bed.
To be rational.
You ask, what does the world value, want, or need?
And then try to supply it.
What does the world really value?
What does it really want?
What does it really need?
And does your idea fit it or supply it?
Those are ways to guarantee success, you know.
Capitalize on frenetic energy surges.
Once in a while, you'll get just a frenetic surge of energy.
And the thing to do.
Is to capitalize on it.
Don't try to put it aside and say, I'll do it later when I have time.
At 3 o'clock.
Because at 3 o'clock, that energy surge is not there.
So a lot of times, you know, I'd still do it.
Jump out of bed at 3 in the morning.
I'd go into my study and I'd write a few significant words on there.
And then I'd go back to bed.
And the next morning, it's there.
And so I've learned from experience to write it down when it's hot in your mind.
When it's a hot topic in your mind.
Because in the morning, you won't be that enthused.
In fact, you may want to remember, what the hell was that bright idea?
In fact, Gabe just came over to me and gave me a synoptic condensation of something I was going to say today.
And I don't remember what it was.
What was it, Gabe?
Word to you.
What was it?
ARP.
ARK?
Well, that was a mnemonic.
For Donald Trump, yeah.
ARP.
I don't remember what ARP stood for, though.
But it was a hell of a good idea at the time.
Well, you wonder what makes him run.
He's already got more millions than he could ever spend or utilize.
And the next thing you know, he's going to take over 16 more casinos in South America.
Say, what in the world?
Why does he do that?
It's because it's a game.
You're right.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
That's right.
Okay, you've got it.
It's because it's become a game.
It's a game he enjoys.
Like, he's good at bridge, and he wins at bridge, and you're good at poker, you're good at shooting craps.
He enjoys the game of it.
That's right.
When you look at Donald, you'll see how much he enjoys the game.
He really just loves the game.
He's going to take over all the gambling in South America and build new casinos across the world.
Why does he do it?
He does it because he likes to do it.
He gets the fun of it, the fun of it.
So he just loves doing what he does.
So that's what makes him run.
Yeah, not greed.
He's got enough money already.
You couldn't possibly spend it all.
It's not greed.
It's the fun of the game.
So he's the fun of the game.
Like being good at poker, it's the fun of the game.
Capitalize on these frenetic energy surges, and in between them, just plow the law.
So there's time and space.
There's times when you're just bursting with all kinds of brilliant energy and genius,
strokes of genius, and you write these all down on the notepad next to your bed.
And then until that happens again, you plow it along, plow it along.
101 ways to success.
So 55 of them were inspirational.
10 of them were goofy ideas.
And the rest of them are just plowing along.
What's the next one?
Well, obviously, you expect success.
People who have an inner integrity begin to expect success.
You know that if you put your mind to a project, it's going to turn out all right.
You know that if you're going to make a jug of iced tea for this afternoon, you know that it's going to be good iced tea.
So you can learn to depend on yourself.
Now, kneel down.
Get lost.
Media capacity means it.
It's nice to get a little niche of the world that's all yours.
Donald sort of has that niche.
Donald Trump has that niche in gambling casinos and all.
So I have not done anything much in gambling casinos.
I figure that belongs to Donald.
He sends me notes.
Thanks, Dave, for leaving gambling casinos international to me.
He moves across the...
globe south america then he moved to egypt and asia uh nailed down especially right about your
project is a way of organizing yourself and it'll bring in thoughts that you didn't have until you
actually wrote it down do a sale do these are practice steps here do a sales pitch on video
now that activates a whole lot of energies that you weren't aware of for
see because we're visual auditory cerebral and so these different modalities when you do a sales
pitch you're doing it in movement you're doing it in speech you're doing it as a style of presentation
and as you do a video on some project your understanding of the project will be different
at the end of the video than at the start of the video so if you have a thing that can make videos
at home
you try that whether it's designing a new dress or how are you going to fix up your car whatever
you're going to do give yourself a sales pitch on video now dave i think if you uh this next
lecture if you talk about success if i were you i wouldn't besides the following points
and don't and you know so i remind myself i don't want to forget donald trump let's say
uh do a sales pitch on video you want to promise yourself periodic rewards that at a certain
period of time you're going to acknowledge your own creativity and take pleasure in it and share it
with your family or share it with with your wife and i like to share my stuff with my wife and then
both of us can comment on it and then that starts to hold further development of the thought process
aside from doing a videos you can do photo photos of yourself in a successful role this is a good
way of uh image imaging to your audience and i think that's a good way to do that so i'm going to
talk a little bit more about what you want to do with yourself what you want to really reflect to
the world and uh so if you take some photographs of yourself and you look you begin to notice
you know actually you look like a slob everything's unbuttoned your hair is a mess i mean
so you begin to be aware that that which you are also expresses itself non-verbally
not only in style and language and gesture
but the way you dress in your manner and the manner in which you carry yourself
so making photos of yourself in a successful role
is a way of affirming that aspect that of your life that you're trying to grow into
take a picture of yourself and on your desk you put president i mean you've got a company
going and company you're working for so you just put the science as president you take
a picture of yourself as president you know that creates an image in your head
and that you your your your consciousness will be drawn to that image now you never really thought
about being president of this company before but the minute you do that you begin to see
yeah you could be actually and all of a sudden you see the pathway becoming president this guy's
going to retire this guy isn't worth a crap anyway this guy about sold this one i can tell
all kinds of lies about and they'll believe me anyway
you begin to become that which you think you are
a lot of politicians do that they see themselves as senator from something or other and
congressman from something or other they see them as you know some kind of a big hoop to do
now the big time hoopty do uh news commentaries on television uh actually form the people that
they're supposed to represent see you begin to become that which you think you are a lot of politicians
become your role so the five o'clock news reports that you have gone to congress
buy new cadillacs for all the poor people in south america and uh the next thing you know you're buying
new cadillacs for all the people in south america and you voted into office as the cadillac president
you've just created that role manifested it in an audio visual manner so audio visual
is quite powerful much of what is happening in today's world is not the cause of the nightly news
it's the consequence of it did you ever think of that it's the nightly news that's causing tomorrow's
news yeah you think you're reporting today's news no you're creating today's news by what
attention and energy you give to what subjects the attention and energy you give to certain
subjects then creates the reality of the nightly news and you're creating the nightly news and you're
out of the audio-visual image of it.
So the TV news is quite powerful.
One reason I track it is because it tells me
exactly what's happening in various areas of the world,
which may or may not have surfaced yet,
but I know that they're going to.
All right.
Give yourself a dollar for each great idea.
Okay.
I used to give people a dollar for all kinds of things.
When they'd come up, they'd give me a dollar.
I learned that up in Peru.
I was in Peru up in the Andes.
I don't know how many feet it was,
10,000 feet, 8,000 feet, whatever.
And I'm up in Peru there near Machu Picchu
all by myself, I think, in the middle of nowhere.
And there was this little girl sitting there with a llama.
And a little girl about this big.
And she's holding this llama.
And I had a camera, so I said,
oh, my gosh, it was a beautiful scene.
And here are the Andes Mountains
behind.
This beautiful setting.
Here's this country girl.
And here's this llama.
And she's holding the llama's harness by the eyes.
So I had this camera.
And I said to her, do you mind if I take your picture?
She said, that'll be a dollar.
That'll be a dollar.
And that's where I got the phrase,
that'll be a dollar from her.
And I use it in many a thing, you know.
That'll be a dollar.
People used to ask a question after a lecture.
I said, that'll be a dollar.
So pretty soon, I had a bunch of dollars.
But anyway, it came spontaneously
from this beautiful little girl high up in the Andes.
Uh-huh.
Give yourself a dollar for each great idea.
And then you'll see as time goes on, they pile up.
To thine own self be true.
And that is to the integrity, the reality of that
which you really are.
It's a little bit of a trick.
To be true to that.
If your innate nature is to be kind towards and forgiving,
then be true to that image.
And when the crowd is roaring for the guillotine,
you're not in the crowd.
Because that's not your way of seeing the world.
The way I see the world, people make mistakes.
And I don't behead them for it.
I don't believe in beheading them for it.
But in the days of the guillotine,
I guess there was quite a mob.
And 14,000 people got guillotined.
After the French Revolution,
I think it was 15,000 people were guillotined.
Well, some people were in the crowd
and enjoyed watching the guillotine come down.
And other people avoided it.
So, to thine own self be true.
Put together an inspirational collage.
You know, that's a big thing you can hang on the wall.
And you put various things in that image.
So you're trained to bring about,
a phenomenon in the world using a variety of techniques,
you can see.
Unconscious suggestion, imaging, role playing, pictorial,
a collage of all the things you would have if you were that.
And so, if you want to be successful and have a Cadillac,
you get pictures of Cadillacs and you put them up.
Right now, I've got pictures of jet planes.
I have no ambition to buy a jet plane,
but they just inspire me.
I love the incredible beauty of them.
They're nothing more sleek looking than a jet plane.
I mean, it is probably the sleekest looking thing on the planet.
It's just got this long nose and it just takes off like a wild animal.
It's just breathtaking.
So, right now, I'm in love with jet planes.
Not the big ones that the multimillionaires have.
Those are like big buses.
No, these are the little ones that take half a dozen people, maybe.
Little jet planes are just, to me, a turn on.
I love little jet planes.
So, if I was super rich, I'd buy a little jet plane.
And any time I wanted to go someplace,
I'd run out and jump in my jet plane and take off.
Even if it's 50 miles, I can take a plane.
It's the fun of taking off and then landing.
So, even if you only went 50 miles, I'd go everywhere by jet plane.
Okay.
So, all right.
Give yourself a dollar for your jet plane.
Give yourself a dollar for each great idea.
Now, be true to yourself, your own standards.
Put together an inspirational collage, a collection of things that image what you are holding in mind.
If I keep putting pictures of jet planes up on my bulletin board,
somewhere out of the blue one might emerge, right?
Why not?
Be on the road of enterprise.
So, that means that you should be traveling in the direction
that you have in mind for yourself.
Cultivating the relationships that would be supportive.
Cultivating the intellectual input.
The learning, the courses you could be taking.
And you don't have to be a genius to build a better mouse trap.
Okay, so what does that mean?
It means that this is a consequence of awareness.
You see what the world needs, and you just sort of automatically try to invent something that will,
handle it.
So, over the years, I've invented a number of things just for my own sake.
And, of course, any one of them could become a product that you could then
advertise and sell and manufacture.
Clarity of your goals.
By success, what are the exact goals?
What do you mean by success?
Clarify the goals means to nail down in a concrete fashion exactly what you mean by success.
Move on to the next slide.
So, any of you that are interested in success, it's important to get a page and write down
exactly what you mean by a success in all the details.
Does it mean driving a Cadillac or not?
Does it mean taking a cab and not having to bother with owning a car?
Does it mean having servants?
Does it mean having a great big house?
Does it mean having security and coziness?
I like cozy security.
I like a little cozy place off in the woods someplace, and nobody knows I'm there except
the birds and the animals.
So, to me, success is cozy.
Cozy and nature, you know what I mean?
That's not other people's idea, but I like country simplicity in the middle of the woods
or something.
And, you know, I like that.
You hear the birds and the animals galloping around, and that's it, instead of the sound
of city traffic.
Other people like the sound of city traffic, and when traffic comes to a halt, they feel
depressed.
.
Once I had somebody that would come out.
She lived in New York City, and she would come out to the country and spend the weekend.
The country was quiet and still, and as the weekend went on, she got more and more depressed.
.
Couldn't wait to get back to the city with the sound of garbage cans clanking at 3 in the morning
and traffic going by and horns and all.
So she was back in the city, and she was happy.
But being out in the quiet, beautiful countryside made her very depressed and felt lonely.
So there's city people and there's country people.
So you have to decide, am I a city person or a country person?
Okay, put your heart instead of the ego into the project.
So that means passion.
Heart is passion.
So you put your passion into the project instead of just the ego's idea of gain.
The ego sees success in terms of gain, titles and money and positions, et cetera.
The heart sees it as fulfillment.
So if you put your heart into the project instead of your ego, you'll find that it takes less energy.
To fulfill it for the ego's ends takes energy.
It takes energy.
It takes energy to propel it for ego gain.
If you're doing it out of the passion, out of the love for the project, that doesn't take any energy out of you.
In fact, by the time you finish the project, you'll feel more energetic than you did before you started it.
So I used to make, when I was into archery, I was into archery for years,
I would make my own bows and arrows and make my own bows and arrows.
And there was just passion.
There was just greater gratification in archery with a bow that I had made myself and with arrows that were absolutely perfect that I myself had put together.
So put your heart instead of just the ego into the project.
So your heart means your love for it, your love for it, your passion for it, instead of the gain from it.
So what gain did I ever get out of being good at archery?
Nothing.
I got a couple of archery medals, if I remember rightly.
But once you got a couple of archery medals, a few more don't any good.
So you do it for the love of the sport, not just because you have to be a winner.
So many people in sports understand this very well.
The love of the sport is what puts them out on the practice ground.
And they'll do for love of the sport that which they would never do for money.
Which aspects of your project are ego and which are soul?
The ego and the soul is just a different way of expressing the same thing.
The ego is looking for gain.
And as we mentioned before, not only just gain, but the glamour of the gain.
And the book I mentioned, did I mention the glamour this morning?
No.
Alice Bailey, right?
All right.
I've mentioned Alice Bailey's book on glamour before in other lectures, many other lectures, in fact.
Alice Bailey was a sportsman.
And she wrote a book called, called what?
Glamour.
Yes, right.
The book is called Glamour.
It isn't the thing itself.
It's the glamour.
Now, glamour is not an imagination.
It's an energy.
There is an actual energy that you can calibrate and measure.
And it's called glamour.
And glamour is what you project onto something out there.
You think what's attractive is that Cadillac.
It's not the Cadillac.
It's the glamour that you project onto the Cadillac.
Now it's more, it's greater than life size.
It's not just a car anymore.
It's a royal chariot.
You know what I'm saying?
I have a Cadillac.
I'm a Cadillac owner.
I've had this Cadillac since I got it.
I bought it used in 1984 or something.
What year is that Cadillac?
84?
I think it's 84.
84, yeah.
Anyway, it's an 84 Cadillac and I bought it in 89 or something.
Anyway, this Cadillac still sits up in my property and it's carefully polished and we repainted it and everything.
And I never take it anywhere.
It's just that it is mine.
Even I used to take it out.
We'd take it to town.
And it was the only old Cadillac.
Shiny old Cadillac in town.
And everybody's head would turn.
They'd look at this big old Cadillac going by.
All right.
So, you know, it's what it stood for.
The energy of that old Caddy was just wonderful.
So, yeah, that's putting your heart instead of your ego into the project because money-wise it's not worth all that much.
Which aspects of your project are ego and which ones are the essence of that which you are?
Is success just a feeling or is it a reality?
Is success something real or is it something you would just project onto it?
You say getting to a certain level, you know, in your eyes makes you a success.
Is that just a feeling or is that a reality?
Would other people agree with you?
And would it make any difference?
There are times when it doesn't make any difference whether other people consider you a success or not.
Whether other people admire my old Caddy or not is irrelevant.
I love it.
So it's a feeling rather than a reality.
Self-rewarding versus public adulation.
Is success self-rewarding or are you looking for the hurrah of the crowd?
What are you looking for?
If it's self-rewarding, then you're independent of the public's reaction.
So long as you're wanting public adulation, the public applause,
you're now the victim of the media and everything out there.
If your self-rewarding means you want to be the best congressman you can
because you've taken a vow to do that,
people who take these things, they put their hand on the Bible, they swear by things and all,
I don't see how they can avoid the obligations that they take upon themselves.
Self-rewarding means that you have fulfilled your understanding rather than pleasing the public.
So if I'm going to be a good congressman, I've got to satisfy my own conscience,
not necessarily please the public.
So you're answerable.
A person of integrity is answerable to themself.
Answerable to themself.
A person of less integrity is only interested in the adulation of the crowd.
The cheer of the crowd.
If you're aware that that is your purpose and that is your goal and that's acceptable to you,
there's nothing wrong with it, but at least you're not fooling yourself.
The reason you're doing this, that, and the other thing is you want to get re-elected,
not because you believe in it.
You can hear a politician, he gets home and says to his wife,
man, what a bunch of horseshit I did today, but I won the vote.
He won the vote, even though it's complete and total BS.
Self-rewarding versus public adulation.
Success is adequate to your lifestyle.
Adequate to your lifestyle.
So that means success has to be appropriate to that which you are.
So some people pretend greater success than they have.
Other people are sort of chronically poor-looking,
even though their mattress is stuffed with money, I'd say.
Anyway, number 80, to be light-hearted versus being grim.
That the pathway to success should be pleasant and easygoing instead of white-knuckled.
You see many people trying for success and it's sort of pathetic.
Your heart goes out for them.
To such extremes they go for that which should be automatic.
Because success...
Success is really being adequate rather than being some kind of an olympic star.
And to be adequate means to utilize the faculties that you have just normally,
but use them with a goal in mind.
When one way to success is merely being friendly and pleasant and good partnership.
If you think of somebody you want to accompany you on the road to success,
you don't want somebody who's white-knuckled, boring, and grim.
And so success is really a general, more general kind of an attitude
of being dependable and reliable.
Being pleasant, agreeable, friendly, dependable, and reliable.
Success as being responsible as well as reliable.
It means you're willing to be accountable.
You're willing to be responsible for your efforts and therefore it's important
to stop giving energy to self-doubt.
Why give energy to that which is negative?
The desire is to produce the best possible performance whether you're on a job or you're
on a trip, you're doing a minor repair on the car, whatever it is, there's a pleasure
in knowing that you've done the best possible.
You've done the best possible job you could at the time.
You can't compare it to the hypothetical.
I mean, if you'd had, you know, $100 worth of equipment, you could have done a better job.
But if the car breaks down, you get it going again, you know, the normal person is being, is pleased.
So there's just a normalcy to success.
You watch the whole animal kingdom and they're happy when they have achieved something.
My dog is happy as a clam when she goes to Pippin.
She goes to pick up something she's lost and finds it.
So there's just a normal mammalian kind of a pleasure in being alive and functioning
in a successful, self-rewarding way.
Give up the excuse of trying and make a decision to do a thing.
So trying was never an excuse that was allowable.
You weren't supposed to try to mix things with your tinker toy.
You were supposed to make them.
Make an engine.
Make a locomotive with that and not try to make a locomotive with it, but make a locomotive
out of that.
Oh, okay.
You got from that to do it, not to fake it, but to actually do it.
So that was sort of a commonly known phrase a couple of decades ago.
Give up the excuse of trying and just do it.
Don't try to do a thing.
Do it.
You understand the difference of trying to do it?
Trying to do it puts it in the future.
Doing it puts it in the present.
I'm trying to get, you know, somewhere, rather.
Trying to get somewhere on this book, the only way to do that is to do it.
Don't try to do it.
You can't publish trying.
You can only publish what you've done.
Okay.
Another trick is write down all the negatives and bury them in the backyard.
You see, a lot of these things you say, you know, the adult in you says, oh, that's so
childish.
So forget the adult in you.
And listen to the child.
What?
The child says, we're going to dig a hole in the background and we're going to go and
put it all in there and bury it.
So I remember as a boy in camp, we used to do that.
We'd dig a big hole in the back.
And if you had any resentments against your fellow campers, we would all sit around the
campfire and there'd be this hole.
And then we'd all have to take our resentments against some other kid and put them in this
hole.
And when we were all done putting our resentments in this hole, we covered it up with dirt.
You say, well, that's silly.
It's not silly because you're actualizing something that would otherwise be in the abstract,
non-specific.
So acting out, acting out then symbolically.
We typically do this in religion.
We typically act out by various means.
We do this in religion.
We do this in church.
We do this in religious life.
We do this in worship.
We do this in prayer.
We do this in the church.
It just means that which is symbolized by the body's motions, et cetera, it brings
it to a different level.
When I say, to thee, oh, Lord, most high, that's different than saying, to thee, oh,
Lord, most high.
So you go to culture in India, or you go to South Vietnam, no, where do we go?
We go to Korea?
Yeah.
All right.
Where that's part of it.
That's part of our culture.
of the gentility of the civilization is built in, that each one, I bow to the God within
me, that you acknowledge the divinity of each entity, and there is a profound strength in
that.
There is a communication of spiritual reality that does not exist other than through the
physical, through the physical.
Okay, identify helpful contacts.
Now we're talking, but we're back again to the practical, the value of having feedback
from consultants and experts.
Identify helpful contacts.
Who would be helpful to you in developing your idea and moving it forward?
Each one, some may only add a few ideas.
You know, if I were you, I'd make it blue instead of green.
It'll show up better.
Oh, you're right.
Okay, so do the brain gym.
The brain gym exercise of the road to be traveled.
You know what brain gym is?
The brain gym is you put your neurons through the whole exercise.
You picture yourself sitting down.
You picture yourself picking up the pen.
You picture yourself writing it.
You picture yourself proofreading it.
You picture yourself getting a type.
Now you're going to read the typed copy, and you're going to correct the typed copy.
Then you picture yourself dictating the corrections and then communicating the corrections, and
then you picture yourself, you know, correcting the corrections.
You're going to get a good copy.
So the brain gym goes through all of the things that you have to do.
Somehow the neurons and the dendrites, the dendrites connect with each other depending
on how you have.
So when you picture something happening, these little dendrites loop over and connect with
this dendrite.
And then you picture the continuation of that movement, and that little dendrite, as it
grows, it flops around like this, and it connects with this one.
So you can see pretty soon you've connected up a whole circuitry in your brain in the dendritic
processes, because these dendrites are constantly forming and collapsing.
So as these dendrites are waving around, they're saying, where shall I go?
Where shall I go?
Oh, go here, oh, genius, oh, okay, thank you.
And then this dendrite begins to wave around and says, where shall I go?
And you say, well, come over here and draw the face of a doggie, oh, now it's a doggie
face.
Now draw a kitty sitting on the back of the doggie, oh.
So pretty soon the picture begins to develop and emerge of its own as the dendrites are
waving around.
So one way to stay young and flexible is to realize that your dendrites are constantly
waving around in your brain no matter how old you are.
You don't wave as much maybe when you get older, but I hear them waving, oh, okay.
I hear them waving, oh, gotcha.
So anyway, take advantage of the fact that these dendrites are constantly forming synapses,
a synapse is a connection, so they're available.
So these dendrites are asking you all the time, what should I pay attention to?
What should I do?
And if you picture yourself writing a book and then sit down and begin to write the book,
the dendrites say, oh, he's writing a book, oh, she wants to write a book on cooking.
Oh.
So now the little dendrites begin to form a pattern and they merge with each other.
Instead of just flopping around loose like that, they begin to make synapses.
So the brain now begins to, the brain gym means that your neurons, the dendrites, are
gonna connect up with each other.
And that way form...
a functional unit in your brain.
That's the brain gym exercise.
It pictures you going out on the ball field,
wiping off the bat, pulling up your socks,
lining yourself, et cetera.
It does everything.
Then you energize each step, each step.
So not just the overall pattern, but each step of the way.
Now, when I remember that ditch that I dug,
I would get ferocious with it.
Like, here's this big log, quarter of a mile long or whatever it is,
and its earth had not been moved before,
so it's virgin earth, and I'm getting there, pushing down,
and there I said, I'm going to do six feet today, six feet, that's all.
And I get to six feet, and all of a sudden my mind would look ahead,
and I would see another six feet.
So I just would look ahead and see that six feet,
and I'd say, ah, the hell with it, and I'd go after that six feet.
Next thing you know, I had 12 feet, and I had to stop myself,
or I'd be going on to 18 feet, you know?
So that which you energize develops a certain momentum of itself.
Highly successful people learn how to take advantage of momentum,
how to energize, how to move those dendrites to be connected correctly,
how to get yourself enthused.
The fact you've got enough gambling casinos already is not what it's about.
It's the game of building gambling casinos.
So with yourself,
and your brain gym,
there's a game of working towards fulfilling an end.
So when I get the inspiration about a certain kind of book,
here's what I want to say.
I haven't been able to say it yet,
and I'm already thinking about it in advance.
So I have a book I have in mind that I want to write.
All kinds of little short things that I've noticed in life
that you can't make a whole book out of,
but they're significant,
and things people...
people don't recognize.
So I thought, well, I'd like to write a book on essays.
Essays.
Things you've noticed, especially in the media.
The way things are phrased,
and the trickeries that are put on that people seem to be unconscious of.
All kinds of things that would be fun to comment on.
So I figure when you're old enough,
you can just publish your, you know, essays and commentaries,
and if people don't like them, the hell with it.
But at least you've had your say, you know what I'm saying?
Everybody should have their say before they go.
So if you haven't got a book on essays yet,
you should start a book on essays.
These are your commentaries on life,
and of course it reflects your values,
and many observations that other people don't make.
My favorite is television advertising.
I could write a whole book on television advertising,
and that advertisers would benefit from.
There are ads out there that cost a zillion dollars,
and they're incredible turn-offs.
And if I use the arm and I say,
this ad is an incredible turn-off, she goes strong.
It creates an aversion to their products.
The people, the companies are spending millions of dollars on ads
that create an aversion to their product.
You say to yourself, if they run that ad one more time,
I'm going to kill myself.
Haven't you just been drummed to death by some stupid ad?
Here's a guy whose head comes out of the ceiling upside down,
and his head is next to somebody whose head is outside up,
and he's holding his head like this.
It's the dumbest thing I ever saw.
What it is it's supposed to be selling, I have no idea.
It's so stupid, I'm just there in stupid shock.
It's supposed to be selling something.
I don't know.
This disturbed teenagers write these ads, or somebody.
I don't know who writes them.
For sheer stupidity.
And then they repeat it over and over again.
I thought it was dumb the first time.
I thought it was stupid the second time.
I thought it was idiotic the third time.
I hate their product.
I am never going to buy their crap.
Never.
Especially the 140th time I've seen that dumb ad.
140 times on the same stupid ad.
I hated it in the beginning, and now I loathe it.
Loathe it.
I go all the way around to avoid their product.
And it's super stupid.
I wouldn't buy it.
It was the last thing they had for sale in the grocery store.
So the fact that these advertising companies are creating an aversion for their product
never dawned on them.
Anybody ever hear of that?
No.
It's my idea.
They're spending millions of dollars to create an aversion to their product.
People hate it.
I don't want to hear them.
I hate it.
I don't want to hear the name of that product one more time.
If that idiot with his head coming out of the ceiling upside down wants to sell me anything,
I wouldn't buy it if he gave it to me.
Anyway, don't get me started on TV advertising because I can go for a half an hour on it.
I'm just getting steamed up on it.
Energize.
Avoid ethically dubious schemes.
Alright, if there's anything that makes you tiddly about a thing, it's best to avoid it.
It makes you wonder about some politicians because there's nothing that seems ethically
dubious to them.
We've used the arm on some of them.
It's scary.
Avoid ethically dubious schemes.
I'll tell you one reason.
It's because the person you are now at this age, it may be okay.
Maybe a little okay.
Shady.
But as you get older, your ethical responsibilities seem to be more demanding and heavy.
So a chancy, dubious, morally dubious scheme that you pulled off at 25, at 45, it's going
to bother you.
I'll tell you.
At 45, you're going to say, Jesus, why did I do that?
I mean, I must have really been stooped.
At 65, it's really a burden.
And by 85, you know you're going to meet God pretty soon.
And you've got this black spot on yourself.
I told you when I was a kid, sin was explained to me as a spot on your soul that God could
see.
Holy smokes.
So, I mean, that's a heavy trip for a kid.
You've got this invisible screen behind you.
And any kind of a sin shows up as a black spot on your soul.
Holy smokes.
And there's God up there looking down on you.
And here's this screen behind you.
And sins are showing up as smoke.
Sins are showing up as smudges on your soul.
Soul smudges.
Sin.
Sin smudges.
Oh, geez.
No wonder I went to confession every Saturday.
Went to confession every Saturday.
All right.
Then he'd give you absolution, but I wasn't sure if it was really complete absolution.
It might have been almost complete absolution.
The black was wiped out, but there might be some gray in my soul.
God would look down and see this.
Wiggly gray shade.
And I told you about it after going to the confession.
Going to communion once in the morning on the way to church.
Here's this 30-foot billboard.
And here was the Jansen swimsuit ad.
This is back in the 30s.
It was a one-piece suit.
Very discreet by today's Sanders.
But here's this 100-foot long blonde.
I'm driving by this 100-foot blonde.
In a swimsuit.
And the top's down on the old convertible.
And I'm trying not to have any sinful thoughts.
She's 30 feet long and curvaceous.
But it was an old-fashioned one-piece swimming suit.
By today's standards, you know, it would be nothing.
You could wear it on the street and nobody would even notice.
But in that era, back in the 50s or whenever it was, before that, 30s maybe.
Anyway, I was afraid it might have energized a sinful thought.
Okay.
Put your heart instead of the ego.
We mentioned that.
And to differentiate which is ego and which is reality.
Give up the excuse of trying and just do it.
Write down all the negatives and put them in the backyard, we said.
Have supportive relationships.
Fake it till you make it.
Select a role model.
Decide to be happy no matter what the result.
Uh-huh.
So that would be...
Be happy through the effort.
In other words, by your commitment to express the best of that which you are capable.
To be helpful to society in all of its ways.
The image I have of the perfect life is to be that which lights up the world wherever you go.
So that which is integrous and aligned with the will of God lights up the woods.
And as you walk through the woods,
every tree knows that you're passing.
And that which is lit up by the love of God and acknowledges God as the creator.
When they walk through the woods...
When they walk through the woods,
the whole woods knows it.
Okay.
I'm sorry for interrupting your...interrupting.
Those things are supposed to go on behind the scenes.
Behind the scenes.
When I was a kid, I was very shy.
And so as a kindergartner, I was in this...
I was supposed to be behind this Christmas tree.
Big cardboard Christmas tree.
And on the key word, I was supposed to say,
Robin, hop, hop, hop.
And I was supposed to hop, hop, hop in front of this tree.
And then back around behind the tree again.
So the teacher says,
Okay, Robin, hop, hop, hop.
And I wouldn't come out.
I'd stay behind the tree.
Robin, hop, hop, hop.
She'd say it louder and louder.
But I wouldn't come out from behind the tree.
Robin, hop, hop, hop.
So we were just doing a Robin, hop, hop, hop on the side.
The decision to be happy no matter what the result
means that the source of your happiness is not consequent upon the world or performance.
Success is a style.
It's a way of being in the world.
And this way of being guarantees the outcome.
This way of being guarantees that all outcomes will be all right.
That all of them will be acceptable and positive.
That it's okay to be a shy Robin and not come out from behind the tree.
It's okay.
You say, Why didn't you come out from behind the tree?
Because I'm shy.
Okay.
End of story.
I'm too shy to be a Robin in kindergarten.
If I had to be reborn, I wouldn't go to kindergarten.
I was trying to get you into some rotten kindergarten play.
That's all to pull out the parents and the aunts and the grandparents to go and see little Joey and be a Robin in a play.
I feel sorry for the parents and the grandparents and the aunts and the uncles.
You've got to go and see them and be a Robin in the kindergarten play.
How many of you have been to a kindergarten play?
Oh, God.
Did you ever survive it?
It's a tough one.
Well, because you love little tots and they're all cute, you go and it is sort of a fun exercise.
It is a fun exercise.
Okay.
So you have supportive relationships about you.
And there should be coaches on that.
Select a role model.
Decide to be happy no matter what the result.
To be a happy person means that you live according to certain rules and guidelines and qualifications.
And therefore, you don't have to have a result.
You just have to be that way.
So the fact that you're as friendly as you can be and as helpful as you can be doesn't mean that you have to be popular.
So if you're just doing that to be popular,
that's quite a different thing than just doing that because that's the kind of a person you are.
You're that kind of a person.
Remember that great success is often fortuitous.
Great success is often fortuitous.
In fact, some of the greatest success stories in the world, many of them or a lot of them, one list I once made, all of them were fortuitous.
You just happen to notice something at the right time.
You just happen to notice something at the right time and in the right motion.
And, of course, we give the discovery that eventually led to the development of penicillin to that.
You know, when you notice the petri dish or the dust blew in, the mold didn't grow there.
And discovering why, why is that?
It was the basic discovery that led eventually to the discovery of penicillin
and changed the history of World War II.
So people who used to die from infections now got a shot of penicillin.
And one million units of penicillin will cure just about anything.
So that was fortuitous, fortuitous, fortuitous observations.
So many of the world's, many of the world's greatest discoveries were just fortuitous.
What does that mean?
The person, the witness became enhanced.
Enhanced by the observation that is, you know, the fact that truth makes you go strong
and falsehood makes you go weak is really fortuitous, fortuitous, isn't it?
Neither one of us ever think about it.
But it's so automatic and it's so almost infallible that we've incorporated it.
So it's fortuitous but extremely useful.
It doesn't create any product in the world, much less profit,
but it does show people.
Huh? I've got five minutes?
Oh, she's a rough coach.
Oh, such a mean disciplinarian.
We have 97 to go to.
We have what? Just this one?
This one last sheet thing.
Okay. All right.
I'll pay attention to the facts of life.
Running out of time.
If time doesn't give a rap about us, why should I give a rap about time?
All right.
So, you know, we're all very self-infortuitous.
So you don't congratulate yourself for it.
You give thanks for it.
If you happen to make an observation that leads to great discoveries,
what happens is you're thankful.
You're not prideful.
You're thankful.
I'm very thankful that, you know, we discovered how to discern truth from falsehood in about an instant at no cost.
I mean, I am very thankful to Almighty God for such a wondrous gift.
Have supportive relationships.
Take it till you make it.
Be a role model.
Decide to be happy no matter what the result.
Great success is often fortuitous.
Expect the unexpected.
That sounds familiar.
Avoid winning the lottery at calamity.
You may have seen on television, I'm sure, what happens to people who win the lottery.
You know, these multi-million, they won $13 million or something like that.
What happens to the life of people who win the lottery is 100% calamitous.
Divorce rates, 100%.
Suicide rates extremely high.
Drugs, accident rate.
The most calamitous thing that can happen to you is to win the lottery.
Anybody disbelieve that?
You'd like to try, huh?
It's because it has both conscious and unconscious consequences.
And, of course, the media make it even worse.
You can imagine how many friends you'll have if it's announced on the evening television you just won the lottery.
Yeah, your mailbox is jammed like this.
I'm a poor widow with five children, and I have tuberculosis, and four of my children have polio,
and we're all living in a hogan in South America surrounded by demons,
and a small donation would mean life or death to us.
Oh, yours is the saddest story I've ever heard.
If that don't juggle some money out of you, I don't know what will.
All right.
Yours is the saddest story I've ever heard.
All right, avoid winning the lottery.
I don't believe in buying a lottery ticket because you might win it.
God help me.
You think I'm kidding.
Look up the research literature on winners of the lottery.
Divorce rate 100%, suicide rate five times average, addiction and alcoholism, et cetera.
It's disastrous.
The most disastrous thing that can happen to you in this world is to win the lottery.
Okay.
If that's true.
I said not buying a ticket, winning the lottery.
Idiots buy the tickets.
It's a sucker game.
Get the money out of them.
Winning the lottery is probably the worst thing that can happen to you in our society.
Resist.
That's right.
The worst thing that can happen to you in our society.
It's disastrous.
It's completely and totally destructive.
And almost every single case has been studied.
It led to suicide.
The divorce rate is about 100%.
Suicide rate is, I don't know, 80%.
It's disastrous.
It pulls in energies.
It's not just money, but the energy that all that pulls in.
Not to mention the media attraction.
So I pray to God, dear God, please don't let me win the lottery tonight.
Amen.
Keep a watchful eye on the ego.
The big I am.
When you are successful, the ego tends to jump in and say, boy, aren't I wonderful.
I'm terrific.
And I must be really the best in the world.
Keep a watchful eye on the ego.
All right.
So the ego is the narcissistic egocentricity, which is always hungry.
The egocentricity, the ego keeps itself alive by feeding on the energies.
And, therefore, it's always hopeful of taking over.
Its enemy is spiritual alignment.
Its enemy, the enemy of the ego, is the ego.
It's the enemy of the ego.
It's spirituality.
So without spirituality to balance it, the ego runs everything.
Runs the person's life and runs them eventually into hopelessness.
Okay.
So keep a watchful eye on the ego.
Realize that the ego, the egocentricity is prideful and always looking to win.
Realize the world has gotten along without you thus far.
Uh-oh.
That's one that brings us back to reality.
The world has gotten along without you thus far.
Hell, I didn't know that.
Realize the world has gotten along without Dr. Hawkins thus far.
Oh, geez.
Oh.
Eliminate that one from the slides.
Success is whatever you say it is.
Win the hula hoop.
Eat more hot dogs in ten minutes.
What people will do for publicity.
I was trying to remember the other day.
My memory isn't as sharp as it used to be.
One of the Beatles lived in a, I had an apartment on 5th.
And across the Central Park on the other side were the, oh, the Dakotas.
Two apartment buildings, the Dakotas.
And the top floor of one was a psychoanalyst who I knew was a friend.
And he had a cat and used to walk around the edge of it and drive me crazy.
And the other one was one of the Beatles.
So I forget the name of this crazy guy.
Rang the door of the Beatles.
One of the Beatles answered the door.
And he shot him dead in the chest.
Remember that story?
Which Beatle was it that he got shot?
Who? John?
John Lennon.
Okay.
When asked why he did it, he just wanted to be famous.
He shot John Lennon dead.
Because he wanted to be famous.
Talk about egocentricity.
That's probably the long time, the world winner.
And yet there are more crimes.
More crimes reported recently of the same ilk.
Can you imagine shooting somebody dead in order to be famous?
Well, there was a recent story along the same lines.
I forget who it is.
But it reminded me.
And I couldn't remember which Beatle it was.
So success is whatever you say it is.
Shoot John Lennon.
Win the hula hoop contest.
Look at all these people.
How many hot dogs are you going to eat in ten minutes?
.
And in the end, after all the 101 ways, of course you're going to be successful.
Then you realize that fame is only fame.
Fame is only fame.
It's not the magic chariot to heaven.
It's not going to fill your life with beautiful women clamoring to jump in bed with you.
Fame is only fame.
It's about this thick.
Fame is this fame.
Today's fame is tomorrow's disgrace.
It's the day after that's rerun.
No matter how spectacular your life is, folks, someday you're all going to be a rerun.
Heaven have it, God has a big TV set and he pushes it.
And there goes your rerun on your life, you know.
If you ever figure your whole life is photographed and then you put it on fast forward.
.
You put it on reverse.
Then you push the button the other way.
.
Say you run your life forward and you run it backward for fun.
And sometimes it's best to just push the erase button.
That particular incident will just hit erase.
Okay.
All right.
As life goes on.
So you want to avoid the things that you have to erase later on.
And that's one reason to be integrous.
So we're going to take a break and then in five minutes we're going to reconvene.